<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 2337EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-TwoLebanons     02-19 1013</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Two Lebanons,1049</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lebanese Try Adapt To Two, Rival Governments</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RIMA SALAMEH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Rafik </PERSON> <PERSON> Helou </PERSON>, a retired schoolteacher, has n't received his state pension for nearly five months. That's because he's a Christian and lives in east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> and the social security office is in west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, the Moslem sector He is a victim of a bizarre political crisis in long-suffering <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> in which government institutions, including the army, have been split in two by rival Christian and Moslem Cabinets vying for power. The 64-year-old <PERSON> Helou </PERSON>, who has a heart ailment, has to rely on his sons to pay for medicines for himself and his wife, who suffers from diabetes. The power struggle threatens to cement the de facto partition of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. Many of the country's estimated 4 million people, hardened by 14 years of civil war, have taken this bureaucratic nightmare in their stride, despite three weeks of bloody fighting between rival Shiite Moslem factions in southern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. But for thousands of people like <PERSON> Helou </PERSON>, it has made the daily struggle for survival even more difficult. State employees are still getting paid. <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> still has gold reserves worth an estimated $ 2.5 billion stored at <ORGANIZATION> Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Knox </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>. But with foreign currency earnings dwindling, the central bank has turned to internal borrowing from commercial banks to supplement funds officials are able to collect in taxes, customs duties and other levies. But pensioners like <PERSON> Helou </PERSON> have suffered. The social security department's board of directors has not been able to meet to endorse pension payments because <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> officials are afraid to cross the dividing Green Line into west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Helou </PERSON> said in an interview: `` We need 30,000 Lebanese pounds -LRB- $ 60 -RRB- a month for medicines. I relied on my annual pension of 6 million pounds -LRB- $ 12,000 -RRB-, but with two governments I ca n't get it. `` Fortunately my sons are providing me with the medications for the time being. But how long can this go on?'' The crisis began Sept. 22, when President <PERSON> Amin </PERSON> <PERSON> Gemayel </PERSON>'s 6-year term ended without a successor being named. Minutes before he stepped down, <PERSON> Gemayel </PERSON> named the commander of the Christian army, Gen. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>, as the head of an interim military Cabinet until a new president was elected. Acting Prime Minister <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoss </PERSON>, a Syrian-backed Sunni Moslem, and other Moslem leaders refused to acknowledge <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>. The government lost its authority long ago and real political power has rested with the heavily armed militias on both sides and their foreign allies, such as <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Yet government departments handling social and economic matters continued to function after a fashion, just enough to maintain a semblance of normality. Now even that slender thread is in jeopardy. <PERSON> Ghassan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bitar </PERSON>, a Christian municipal employee, said he and his colleagues have not been paid since September. <PERSON> Bitar </PERSON>, 32, who has two children and a wife five months pregnant, said he had to turn his family <ORGANIZATION> Mercedes-Benz </ORGANIZATION> into a taxi to make ends meet. `` I ca n't leave my family hungry,'' he said. <PERSON> Rana </PERSON> <PERSON> Shehab </PERSON>'s dreams of going to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> to study medicine were shatted Ms. <PERSON> Shehab </PERSON>, an 18-year-old Moslem. `` The only alternative was to enroll in the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION>.'' The university, which once was the most prestigious education center in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, is now a shadow of that since its foreign professors were frightened off by a wave of kidnappings of its American and British lecturers and administrators. But Ms. <PERSON> Shehab </PERSON> noted: `` It's better than nothing.'' An Education Ministry official, <PERSON> Sami </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamadi </PERSON>, said the authorities decided not to issue certificates for students in either west or east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> `` until the government is reunited.'' Even getting in and out of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> has become a problem for some people. `` Airport officials turned me back when they saw my passport was renewed in east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Anis </PERSON> <PERSON> Saeed </PERSON>, a Christian, when he tried to leave through the airport in west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. `` I got my ticket refunded and now I'm going to take the ferry to <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> from the Christian port of <LOCATION> Jounieh </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Saeed </PERSON>, 24. The Lebanese have learned how to survive under the most arduous conditions during the civil war, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s invasion in 1982 and endless factional feuding. But the cloning of what had passed for their government has exasperated many. `` We're fed up,'' said <PERSON> Amal </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamdi </PERSON>, 28, a secretary in west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. `` We want this chaos to end. However, if formal partitioning would lead to security, stability and better living conditions, let it be.'' `` Let's either have formal partition or elect a new president, but let's finish and know where we stand,'' said <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Ayyoub </PERSON>, 36, who works at an east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> trading company. Every government ministry now has two competing heads. The 40,000-man army, the police and municipal departments are similarly split in two. The only institution that has remained intact is the central bank, which is financing both governments. It is in west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Hout </PERSON>, economic adviser to bank governor <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Naim </PERSON>, said the bank's main objective is to provide the basic needs of people of both sides of the sectarian divide. `` We extend advances to both governments to cover wages and salaries for the public sector, to import essential commodities such as fuel and flour and spare parts to maintain such services as electricity and water,'' Hout explained. `` We pay military salaries on both sides, but we wo n't advance money for purchasing armaments.'' The <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> has been pressing to impose his disputed authority on the central bank and in December he closed the only crossing point on the Green Line in a move widely seen as retaliation for the bank's providing $ 100,000 to Moslem units. The 10-day closure kept food and fuel from reaching west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> from the Christian sector, where the main government warehouses are situated. <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> lifted the blockade after Christian business interests complained they were unable to sell their goods in Moslem sectors.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 2339EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BadTimesonBayouI     02-19 1240</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bad Times on Bayou I,1274</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bad Times On The Bayou</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Part I: Economic Downturn Leaves Louisiana Battered</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<HEAD>With LaserPhoto</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> has had the nation's highest unemployment rate for more than a year. More than 40,000 people have left the Bayou state. <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> had a $ 2 billion debt. State and local budget cuts have hurt health care and schools. A two-part series, `` Bad Times On The Bayou,'' examines the depression and the social revolution taking place in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>. First, the economic woes of what was once one of the nation's richest states.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>By SCOTT McCARTNEY</NOTE>
<NOTE>Associated Press Writer</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One day last year, state government was within an hour of not making the payroll. One day in the future, economists warn, this city could be knocking on bankruptcy's door. Bond ratings are just one notch above junk bonds. Times are hard in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>. Charity hospital clinics overflow because the state ca n't afford enough doctors to go around. Windows in City Hall remain cracked and unrepaired. Children go to school in packed classrooms without modern teaching aids such as computers. One town has to turn off street lights to save money. `` We have become a state of mediocrity instead of a state of excellence,'' said Commissioner of Administration <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Stine </PERSON>. `` We've become a welfare state instead of a wealthy state.'' Times are hard in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>. An estimated 30,000 unskilled oil workers are unemployed; some have been out of work so long their benefits ran out long ago. Many of the state's skilled workers have fled to healthier regions. In all, close to 100,000 jobs have been lost. Even worse, antiquated laws from bygone boom days handcuff public officials' efforts to attract new business and raise the money needed to improve education, health care and the economy. French-Cajun optimism, the let-the-good-times-roll attitude that drank up boom after boom and thirsted through only occasional busts, seems to be fading. People have been packing up and moving out. No hope of another oil boom, they say. No hope. `` We seem to find people with short fuses lately,'' said <PERSON> Hubert </PERSON> <PERSON> Chiasson </PERSON>, the manager of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION>' largest unemployment office. `` Do I really see any signs of improvement? No, I really do n't.'' Times are hard in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>. The state was forced to borrow $ 1.3 billion to cover its debt, and another $ 1.2 billion to bail out its insolvent unemployment insurance fund. About 10 percent of the state tax collections now go to pay interest on debt. Sales taxes are already highest in the nation _ 9 percent in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. Businesses fear that they will be taxed to bail the state out. `` It's a spiral _ you ca n't get new business, so you ca n't employ all the people who need jobs,'' said <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>, director of business and economic research at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION>. `` That does n't mean we will spiral down any further, but there will be no new growth.'' In fact, there are indicators that the economy has bottomed out after two years of depression. There are no signs of improvement, however. The price of oil began its crash in 1984, and two years later a leading state business organization proclaimed that <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s recession had become a depression Unemployment reached 14.5 percent in January 1987. The latest figure is about 10 percent _ twice the national average. Despite its abundance of resources, waterway location and reputation for good food and good times, the state proved to be ill-prepared for the day when the oil `` gravy train'' stopped, economists said. The taxing structure dates back to the days of populist <PERSON> Huey </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON>, who believed the people were entitled to a free ride at the expense of business. Most homes are exempt from property taxes; many state services are offered at unusually low rates, such as $ 3 a year for an automobile license plate. Gov. <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> tried to rearrange the fiscal structure, but his first attempt failed in the Legislature last fall. He says he'll try again, and win, because the future of the state depends on it `` We had a state where big money beat big ideas, and that's a loser. We're trying to reverse it,'' <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> said. The state has a huge group _ estimated at 30,000 _ of out-of-work oil workers with no employable skills. Most dropped out of school for the lure of big money on oil rigs. Many do n't even have the money now to pack up and move out. `` How are we going to get our present work force into jobs?'' asks <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Schreiber </PERSON>, director of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION>' World Trade Center and chairman of a governor's task force on labor. `` We have to train and develop our workers.'' <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> has seen its sales tax revenue fall so far that the mayor said the only services left to cut were courts and school crossing guards. The city has lost $ 100 million in revenue _ a full one-third of its entire budget _ since oil prices crashed. `` The current budget is in a crisis,'' Mayor <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Barthelemy </PERSON> said in an interview before opting for an $ 8-per-household `` public safety fee'' and slashing court funding from $ 25 million to $ 15 million, with layoffs in the district attorney's office. But <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> law says the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> ca n't raise property taxes without a general election, and besides, only 15 percent of the homeowners in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> pay property taxes, by law. The <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> ca n't raise the sales tax, by law. It ca n't create an income tax, by law All <PERSON> Barthelemy </PERSON> says he can do is raise fees, such as slapping a surcharge on water bills for `` public safety.'' The city of <LOCATION> Shreveport </LOCATION>, in the northern part of the state, balanced its budget by laying off 115 <ORGANIZATION> Sanitation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> workers, abolishing back door garbage pickups and raising water and sewer rates 25 percent. <LOCATION> Houma </LOCATION>, an oil town near the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, found times were so hard that 3,000 street lights had to be turned off to save money. `` Business has never been as bad,'' said <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Catlett </PERSON>, owner of the <ORGANIZATION> Houma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pawn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shop </ORGANIZATION>. `` I ca n't see any improvement, and I'm usually the first to tell.'' New Orleans school Supt. <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> has had to cope with all the problems of a large, urban school system while his budget has been slashed. The state cut back on its funding, so did the federal government, and the city. He's laid off 300 employees. His teacher-pupil ratio has climbed to 29-to-1 in elementary schools. His counselor-to-pupil ratio is 450-to-1. Voters approved a bond package to help the schools, but it's not enough. This year, the schools are operating with $ 30 million in `` bridge funding'' from the state. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> is worried he'll lose that money next year. That could mean more layoffs, a shorter school year, and a budget so poor `` I really could n't operate the school district.'' <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, like Mayor <PERSON> Barthelemy </PERSON>, Gov. <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>, economists and business leaders, says the key to the future will be reshaping the tax structure to promote new business and remove the handcuffs from local governments. Despite the element of futility, they see good times ahead. `` I am optimistic, and I guess that's how we survive,'' <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said. The governor added, `` We are going to turn this state around.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> is the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> regional reporter, based in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 2340EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ChildrenofWar     02-19 0700</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Children of War,0726</SECOND>
<HEAD>War Takes Toll on Most Innocent of Victims</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 AP writer <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Herbaugh </PERSON>, based in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>, entered <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> on Jan. 27 to cover the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s departure and the post-withdrawal situation. Here is her report on the most innocent victims of war _ the children.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By SHARON HERBAUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Inside the dingy walls of <LOCATION> Indira </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gandhi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Children </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, doctors and nurses wage their own battle to save children from the savagery of the war _ booby-trapped toys, rockets, bombs and bullets. Mriya, a 4-year-old from <LOCATION> Charikar </LOCATION>, 45 miles north of <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, was badly injured three weeks ago by artillery fire as Soviet and Afghan troops attacked Moslem guerrillas trying to topple the government. She suffered broken bones, but she was lucky. Ten of the 12 people living in her house were killed. Six children injured in a guerrilla rocket attack in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> were brought to the 300-bed hospital last week. Doctors were able to save three of them. When the parents of one of survivor were told their 12-year-old son's right leg would have to be amputated, the father sobbed and cried: `` Oh, let him die. Let him die. He's no good anymore.'' Even before civil war broke out in 1978, <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> had the world's highest child mortality rate, according to <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> statisics. At least 340 of every 1,000 children will not reach their fifth birthday, and doctors and nurses working in a country where medical care is far below accepted standards are struggling to keep the number from rising. `` We want to get away from politics as much as possible here,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Salam </PERSON> <PERSON> Jalali </PERSON>, head of the 102-member hospital staff. `` There may be sons of mujahedeen -LRB- guerrilla -RRB- commanders here. We do n't ask. They are children. They are not directly involved in the war.'' Some children have been injured by toys rigged with explosives and left on streets. It is unclear whether the booby traps are the work of Afghan government forces or the guerrillas. More than 1 million people have died in the war, which has severely strained the hospital, built in 1972 by <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and named after its late prime minister. It is always crowded and cockroaches climb the walls. `` Sometimes we put two or three patients in one bed. Sometimes we put them in a corridor or on the floor. But we never refuse a patient, and it's all completely free,'' <PERSON> Jalali </PERSON> said. The cost of medicine and food has soared and consumed the hospital's budget. All medicine is imported and getting it to the hospital is difficult because of fuel shortages and guerrilla attacks on government convoys. A lack of supplies often forces doctors to reuse bandages. The war also has made it harder for <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s poor to afford nutritional food and has diverted attention from child health care. `` They do n't bother about these problems,'' <PERSON> Jalali </PERSON> said. `` They just want to stay alive, and when they finally do bring them to the hospital it's often too late.'' `` Malnutrition is our main problem. This has been going on for years, but now it's worse,'' he said. Emaciated children, their resistance weakened by lack of food, suffer tuberculosis, meningitis and other diseases. In the final weeks of the Soviet troop withdrawal, <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> suffered severe food shortages. Vegetable and fruit stands at city markets now are full, but prices are far beyond the reach of the poor. The situation is worse for children in other parts of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Khagal </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON>, who livesin the <LOCATION> Laghman </LOCATION> province east of <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, weighs about 15 pounds, the normal weight for a 7-month-old baby. He is 4 years old. <PERSON> Mayabim </PERSON>, a 5-year-old from central <LOCATION> Hazarajat </LOCATION> weighs only 20 pounds, and suffers from tuberculosis, meningitis and brain damage. `` We were too far away. It took us too long to get here,'' said his sobbing mother, <PERSON> Gulandam </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> UNICEF </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crescent </ORGANIZATION> _ a Moslem organization similar to the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> _ and other charities also care for children but say more help is needed. `` Peace is a prerequisite, and peace for <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> is not yet on the horizon,'' said <ORGANIZATION> UNICEF </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Reilley </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 2339EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene Advisory   02-19 0020</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene, Advisory</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 EDITORS: There will be no Farm Scene for today because of the holiday. The AP
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 2340EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ToQuoteOrNot Bjt   02-19 0511</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-To Quote Or Not, Bjt,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Quote Seekers Look No Further</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Quotations are the salt and pepper of political speeches, and members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> have long had their own wit and wisdom enlivened by them. As often as not those quotes have come from the quote files maintained for the last 50 years by the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> of the Library of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Now, 2,100 of the best have been gleaned from those files and put between the covers of a book, `` Respectfully Quoted,'' in time for the celebration this year of the 200th anniversary of the convening of the 1st <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1789. While the range is wide, many of the quotations requested by congressmen concern <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> itself, even quotes which are less than flattering to the institution and its members. `` <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is so strange,'' a Russian visitor observed. `` A man gets up to speak and says nothing. Nobody listens. And then everybody disagrees.'' American humorist <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>: `` With <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> _ every time they make a joke, it's a law. And every time they make a law it's a joke.'' Or the opening line from the actor playing <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> in the musical, `` 1776'' _ `` I have come to the conclusion that one useless man is called a disgrace, that two are called a law firm and that three or more become a congress.'' Or this, from <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Twain </PERSON>: `` It could probably be shown by facts or figures that there is no distinctly <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> criminal class except <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.'' Someone once asked the Rev. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> Hale </PERSON>, then chaplain of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, `` Do you pray for the senators, Dr. <PERSON> Hale </PERSON>?'' The quoted reply: `` No, I look at the senators and pray for the country.'' From Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharp </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, D-Miss., at a 1923 farewell dinner: `` I sometimes think I'd rather be a dog and bay at the moon then stay in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> another six years and listen to it. Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, like other politicians, obtain office through elections and the new volume has quotations to offer on that subject: Such as: `` An election is coming. Universal peace is declared, and the foxes have a sincere interest in prolonging the lives of the poultry'' _ <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Eliot </PERSON>, the English author, in 1866. There is much advice on how to govern: _ `` The great art of governing consists of not letting men grow old in their jobs'' _ <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonaparte </PERSON>. _ `` A government which robs <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> to pay <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> can always depend on the support of <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>.'' _ <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>. _ `` There is no Democratic or Republican way of cleaning the streets'' _ <LOCATION> Fiorello </LOCATION> <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Guardia </LOCATION>. Politicians of course make promises. <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> is alleged to have once said: `` We must not promise what we ought not, lest we be called on to perform what we can not.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> says the accuracy of the quote can not be verified. It does vouch, however, for the authenticity of <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Swift </PERSON>'s declaration that: `` Promises and pie-crusts ... are made to be broken.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 2341EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Election     02-19 0660</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Election,0682</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jerusalem Mayor's Dream of Truly Uniting City Seems out of Reach</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KARIN LAUB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mayor <PERSON> Teddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kollek </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>'s peacemaker for a generation, is virtually assured an unprecedented sixth term in elections this month, but his dream of a truly united city seems out of reach. <PERSON> Kollek </PERSON> is expected to lose control of the city council to religious and right-wing parties in the Feb. 28 vote, a development that could heat up the religious and Arab-Jewish conflicts dividing the city of 500,000. The 77-year-old <PERSON> Kollek </PERSON> knows what he's up against. `` You have an increase of the extreme edges on all sides,'' said <PERSON> Kollek </PERSON>, citing rises in religious, nationalist and secular activism. `` To keep a middle line is very complicated.'' During a recent campaign stop in the outdoor <ORGANIZATION> Mahane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yehuda </ORGANIZATION> market, a rowdy stronghold of right-wing sentiments, he looked out of place in his blue wool suit and brown fur hat. But he was thronged by the vendors, some applauding and shouting `` Teddy, <PERSON> Teddy </PERSON>!'' His popularity is expected to help the Vienna-born mayor match his 1983 results, when he won 65 percent in the direct vote. His One <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> slate took 17 of 31 city council seats. But this year, <PERSON> Kollek </PERSON> could lose council control because of the growing strength of the religious parties and the announced election boycott by <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> voters, traditionally <PERSON> Kollek </PERSON> supporters. Working with a hostile council would weaken <PERSON> Kollek </PERSON>, who has been credited for keeping much of the bloodshed of the 14-month-old Palestinian uprising out of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> by trying to cool tempers and arguing with aggressive policemen. The religious-secular conflict heated up in the summer of 1987 when Orthodox Jewish men in black coats and hats hurled stones at Friday night moviegoers to protest the screening of films on the Jewish Sabbath. The `` movie wars'' are part of an intensified ultra-Orthodox campaign for more laws guarding the sanctity of the Sabbath and greater budget allocations for religious education and housing. `` We are fighting for the soul of the nation,'' said Rabbi <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Peretz </PERSON>, leader of the ultra-Orthodox <ORGANIZATION> Shas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, in a campaign video. Shas and others are not targeting the sure <ORGANIZATION> Orthodox </ORGANIZATION> vote _ about 30 percent of the city's 350,000 Jewish residents. They are after less observant Jews seeking reassurance in troubled times, the same voters who were mainly responsible for the religious parties' gains in the November general election. Secular activists warn that the `` black hats'' will turn <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> into an Iran-style theocracy. The city turns into a virtual ghost town on the <LOCATION> Sabbath </LOCATION>, forcing many residents to drive 40 miles to <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> for weekend entertainment. `` The Orthodox are saying ` We took on the <ORGANIZATION> Knesset </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- parliament -RRB- and <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> is next,''' said <PERSON> Anat </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>, a council candidate for the secular <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>. Across town, in <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> east </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, there are no indications that an election campaign is being waged. Many Palestinians have stayed away from elections to show they do n't accept the annexation of east <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, which <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> captured from <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> in the 1967 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war. In 1983, 12,000 of the city's 150,000 Arab residents cast votes, but this year all the Arab residents are expected to boycott the elections. Leaders of the uprising against Israeli rule in the occupied territories have urged activists to `` strike against all who participate in such an election.'' `` Participation in the elections would imply that we accept unilateral annexation,'' said <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Siniora </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> supporter and editor of the Arabic-language Al Fajr newspaper. <PERSON> Siniora </PERSON> acknowledged, however, that <PERSON> Kollek </PERSON> had a better image among Palestinians than his opponents. <PERSON> Kollek </PERSON> said tolerance was the central message of his campaign. `` This is a very complicated city. We have Jews from 103 different backgrounds, 40 different Christian denominations, and we have Arabs who are n't all united either,'' <PERSON> Kollek </PERSON> said. `` If we wo n't be tolerant toward one another, there will be no life in the city.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 2341EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BankBoard-Martin     02-19 0704</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bank Board-Martin,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Interpretation Could Let Official Keep Stock</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD L. VERNACI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government agency regulating the savings and loan industry has relaxed its reading of an internal rule in a way that apparently will allow one of its top officials to keep his stock in a family business. The rule, which had prompted <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> member <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> to promise to get rid of the stock, has been interpreted too literally, according to <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Quillian </PERSON>, deputy general counsel for the board. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> promised when he joined the board in 1987 that he would divest himself of his 29 percent interest in <ORGANIZATION> Pope </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scientific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>. That promise was made to the Office of Government Ethics and incorporated into <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s sworn testimony during his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation hearing Once he made that promise, federal ethics laws required <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> to carry through and rid himself of the stock within 90 days of his confirmation. But he says he did not want to dispose of his holding in the company and, after making his promise, received verbal advice that he could keep the stock. <PERSON> Quillian </PERSON> wrote to <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> last week saying that the interpretation of the agency's rules he gave <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> in 1987 was wrong. The original interpretation resulted from defining the word `` employee'' in the board regulation so broadly that it would, in effect, consider a company in which an employee owned a substantial interest an `` employee'' of the board as well as the actual employee himself. That way, rules on such things as conflicts of interest and ethics would apply not only to board employees, but to the actions of companies in which they held a substantial interest. `` While that is certainly the literal interpretation of that provision, such an interpretation would of course be unenforceable,'' <PERSON> Quillian </PERSON> wrote to <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> last week. `` Accordingly, we have decided after further research and reflection that the definition can not and should not be interpreted literally.'' Pope Scientific, based in <LOCATION> Menomonee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, manufactures laboratory glassware and instruments. While it has done work for the government from time to time, it would have little or no occasion to bring it into contact with the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. In letters to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sentinel </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> complained that under the literal interpretation of the board's rules, `` I would have had to report on federal financial disclosure forms the entire interest of <PERSON> Pope </PERSON> as if I were its sole owner. Until <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> became a member of the bank board in 1987, he was Pope Scientific's chairman. His wife, <PERSON> Ann </PERSON>, owns 51 percent of the company and is its president. His son, <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON>, is vice president. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> also said that `` there is no such requirement'' that would compel him to sell his interest in the company. However, <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, chief counsel for the Office of Government Ethics, said that once <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> made a promise to divest, he either had to do it or explain why not. `` He has a requirement to act on the terms of his ethics agreement unless he provides an explanation for the change in conditions,'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said. Using the range categories on financial disclosure forms, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> listed his 29 percent stake in the company as being worth between $ 100,000 and $ 250,000. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> did sell other financial holdings when he joined the bank board. He had held stock in <ORGANIZATION> MGIC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and was vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Mortgage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guaranty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. He sold that stock, resigned the post and promised not to take part in matters affecting that company or the mortgage insurance industry. The bank board, which regulates and audits the nation's savings and loans, has been overrun with work as that industry has sunk into such deep financial trouble that President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has proposed a massive federal bailout. Some of the board's paperwork has fallen through the cracks. `` For the last any number of months we've been like one-armed paper hangers,'' <PERSON> Quillian </PERSON> said. `` But in the present circumstances it seemed like it was well to drop everything and get this out on paper, which we've now done,'' <PERSON> Quillian </PERSON> said. Asked what the `` present circumstances'' were, he replied: `` You guys writing about it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 2343EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Niger-Food     02-19 0747</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Niger-Food,0766</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rains Bring Plentiful Harvest, But Highlight Deeper Problems</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SYDNEY RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BIRNI N'GAOURE, Niger (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kadi </PERSON> <PERSON> Umarou </PERSON> emerged from a helmet-shaped granary of golden straw, her arms laden with millet stalks, and headed home past a dozen other new granaries built for the best harvest in 20 years. This country on the southern edge of the <LOCATION> Sahara </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Desert </LOCATION>, which has been forced to ask the world for food repeatedly for more than a decade, is feeding itself this year. Rains last spring and summer were plentiful and farmers say conditions for planting had n't been better in 30 years. The government reported a grain surplus of more than 200,000 tons after the harvest last fall, enough to carry the country through this spring's planting. Pastures are green and herds are increasing. Bellies are full and children are smiling. Things are as good as they have been in a long, long time. `` My children eat now when they want. My husband is strong. I am less afraid and still there is more grain,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Umarou </PERSON> said, speaking in the tribal language of Djerma through a translator. But in a region where problems are profound, a year as good as 1988 shows just how bad things really are. <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>, an official with the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Niamey </LOCATION>, about 20 miles away, said bumper harvests in this <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> African </LOCATION> nation are so rare some villagers did n't know what to do. `` In one village, they have gone a whole generation without anything left over so they did n't know how to construct granaries. The government sent a team to teach them,'' <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> said. From <LOCATION> Mauritania </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> coast across to <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> in the east the situation was much the same, with the countries on the vast arid border south of the <LOCATION> Sahara </LOCATION> reporting better than average rainfall in 1988. Record harvests were reported in <LOCATION> Burkina </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Faso </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chad </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mali </LOCATION>. `` If it rained for 20 years you would have healthy people in <LOCATION> Niger </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>. `` But you have to turn that abundance into productive, sustainable, non-agricultural activities. If not, when the rain stops in the 21st year you will need emergency food.'' Many experts in development agencies say wealthy people here tend to invest their money abroad. Exceptions are those who build houses in the capital to rent and others who buy agricultural products and horde them for resale. `` There is a surplus of millet, prices have fallen and there is no government price support,'' said <PERSON> Olav </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakken </PERSON> <PERSON> Jensen </PERSON> of CARE. `` The rich merchants buy it, hold it until there is n't any food and then resell it, often to aid agencies at inflated prices, who distribute it as emergency food. They ca n't go wrong and the poor farmer who needs the cash has no choice but to sell.'' Even one obvious benefit of the good harvest, well-fed youngsters, has a sobering side. `` Of course the children born this year will get a better start,'' said <PERSON> Jensen </PERSON>. `` But then there will be more babies, more marriages by people who have been putting off getting married for years. Even the government has informally asked people to not use their extra income to buy too many wives. But this is precisely what is happening.'' In the eastern province of <LOCATION> Zinder </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Tulane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> has been weighing babies in a project for CARE. He has found some surprising results: the number of children suffering acute malnutrition has decreased since the famine of 1984, but the number of children with chronic malnutrition is on the rise. Those who were starved as infants have not yet recovered, he said, and malnutrition is tied to more than simply how much a child eats. `` Millet is good and children this year are getting lots of millet. But they are not getting the variety of protein and vitamins babies need for muscle growth. A baby needs quality, not just quantity,'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> explained. Still, any respite in the harsh environment ca n't help but boost morale. `` In the first year or two of drought a person can retain some hope,'' said <PERSON> Horacio </PERSON> <PERSON> Soares </PERSON>, director of the agricultural weather station set up to monitor conditions after the disastrous 1072-73 drought. `` But after years and years, you just give up. With rain, people feel happier, they're willing to cooperate with government programs and even push for more help with development.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 2344EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Liberia Bjt   02-19 0781</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Liberia, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Prematurely Terminates Government Management Project</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A highly unusual project in which <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic experts tried to help <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION> straighten out its chaotic governmental finances has ended abruptly, reportedly scuttled by Liberian President <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Doe </PERSON>. One frustrated American participant said <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> could not be persuaded to abandon his practice of maintaining an extracurricular budget outside the government's control. The premature termination roughly halfway into the two-year project, coming as it does on the heels of a congressional freeze on aid to <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION>, may be prompting <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> into action. <PERSON> Doe </PERSON>, a former army sergeant who took power in a bloody 1980 coup, is considering a trip to the funeral of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> in hopes of meeting President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Liberian </LOCATION> officials and dissidents say. Although the evolving situation remains in flux, analysts are concerned it could prompt a renewal of threats against <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> interests in the coastal African nation, which is supported largely by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign aid and investment. The project, which stemmed from <PERSON> Doe </PERSON>'s efforts to boost <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support and introduce some order into his government finances, was billed as a $ 15.5 million program when it was signed in 1987. The unusual arrangement, which gave American experts the right to cosign Liberian government checks, was made possible by the historic links between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION>, a country of 2.3 million residents that was founded in the 19th century by freed slaves. All but one or two of the 17 experts, who have stayed behind to complete computerization programs, are now back in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Berger </PERSON>, Vice President of <ORGANIZATION> Lewis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Berger </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, which conducted the project under contract to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government. The team was frustrated by lack of support from <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> and by his practice of maintaining a budget outside the government's control, <PERSON> Berger </PERSON> said. A statement by the <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> said the project achieved progress in getting the government to meet its payroll on time, pay pensions and increase tax receipts. `` Unfortunately, progress was not uniform and some serious problems could not be resolved,'' said the statement. Dissidents and congressional staffers said the team discovered that <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> manages part of the government budget like a discretionary slush fund which was outside the purview of the American experts. A spokesman at the <ORGANIZATION> Liberian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Yarl </PERSON>, declined to discuss the project, saying only that it had been completed in a satisfactory manner. Specifically, revenues from the government-owned corporations for forestry and petroleum products _ which account for about 40 percent of the state's income _ were handled directly by <PERSON> Doe </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Amos </PERSON> <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>, an exiled <LOCATION> Liberian </LOCATION> political scientist who heads a dissident organization in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> uses these funds to cater to various whims, <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> said. For example, when <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION>'s soccer team beat <LOCATION> Ghana </LOCATION> last year, <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> declared a national holiday and gave the team $ 1 million. But <PERSON> Berger </PERSON> said <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> also used the money for public works projects and to pay back official bank loans. <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> has not protested the recent setbacks in relations with <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Krecke </PERSON> in a telephone conversation from <LOCATION> Monrovia </LOCATION>. But there is concern that <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> may renew past threats against <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> communications facilities and military access rights, officials said. They spoke on condition of anonymity. <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION> experts say he has not acted on these threats in the past because too much of his economy depends on American investments. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has been the bulwark of <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION>'s economy, pouring $ 434 million in financial aid between 1980 and 1986. There also is some $ 400 million worth of private <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> investment in <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION>, much of it in rubber plantations, iron ore mining and forestry. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> maintains a relay station for <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> broadcasts to <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and southern <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, officials said. There is also a diplomatic communications facility that handles traffic from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> posts in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> is involved in running a tracking station for navigation in the region, officials said. Economic aid to <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION>, which suffers from a crushing debt burden and foreign exchange shortages, was frozen last year after the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> failed to certify that the country had made progress in rectifying human rights abuses, officials said. As a result, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has so far withheld $ 22 million in aid _ about one-third of the funds allotted to <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION>, according to AID. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s recently released report on human rights says <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION>'s record `` was set back in 1988 by several adverse developments,'' including the unexplained deaths of several men while in detention for unsubstantiated charges of plotting a coup.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 2345EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Poland-Miners     02-19 0699</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Miners,0722</SECOND>
<HEAD>Six Months After Strikes, Miners Fear Solidarity Might Not be Enough</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH G. SEWARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JASTRZEBIE, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Six months ago, angry miners shut down the deep coal mines ringing this desolate city in southern <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> to demand the government recognize Solidarity. Now the miners seem to be within reach of their goal, but some fear that even a free trade union will not be enough to fight the poverty that caused them to strike in the first place. Since Feb. 6, government and Solidarity representatives have been talking in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>, and they are near agreement on terms to reinstate the union after a seven-year ban. Their eyes shadowed with coal dust, the miners talked quietly last week while waiting to greet Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> at the <LOCATION> Manifest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lipcowy </LOCATION> mine, where the first strike began. `` Things have n't changed much. We do n't know what it is we're going to get and we do n't know when,'' said <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Pilat </PERSON>, whose job during the strikes was to sound the alarm when police prepared to rush the mine gates <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> came to Manifest Lipcowy to tell Solidarity activists how the talks in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>, 220 miles to the north, were proceeding. Local union leader <PERSON> Alojzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Pietrzyk </PERSON> calls <PERSON> Jastrzebie </PERSON>, a city of just more than 100,000 people, a `` concrete reservation.'' But in the 1960s and'70s, thousands of workers flocked to <PERSON> Jastrzebie </PERSON>, attracted by the promise of good wages and housing in the new apartments the government had slapped together. In its haste to attract workers to mine the nearby rich lodes of black coal, the government left a few things out. Stores are few and poorly stocked. A couple of restaurants and a few movie theaters and discos can be found hidden among the high rises. Now there is a housing shortage and young miners are forced to spend years living in workers' hotels. `` There is nothing to do and nothing to buy,'' said one miner, <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Rutkowski </PERSON>. `` Things are really hard and I do n't think they'll get better. What bothers miners most is a pay system that forces them to work for bonus money on Saturday and Sunday to earn enough to survive, and primitive working conditions that claimed the lives of 85 miners in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> last year. It was disgust over management's failure to honor raises negotiated by the official trade union alliance OPZZ that led to the strike at <ORGANIZATION> Manifest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lipcowy </ORGANIZATION> when miners opened their pay envelopes Aug. 15. The strike spread rapidly to other mines in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, and the No. 1 demand became the reinstatement of Solidarity, the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc's first free trade union. It had operated legally for 16 months before being outlawed in 1982. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> agreed to suspend the strikes when authorities proposed talks with the opposition and promised to include Solidarity's future on the agenda But the coal miners were skeptical and it took a visit from <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> and hours of hard bargaining to persuade them to stop the strike on its 19th day. The miners see Solidarity as the only means by which they can present grievances in negotiations with management. During his visit Tuesday, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> told miners: `` I know you are tired with your work, these conditions, with what is happening on the market, with your families, but I would like to talk to you without censorship so I could understand my mistakes and your strivings.'' The workers asked <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> how he could trust the government. He said he lacked specific answers but urged the miners to help rebuild <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. `` Everything shows now there is a civilized solution ... We have to have a bit of responsibility,'' he said. `` I appeal to you to build organizations. ... There are so many problems. You have to approach them in an organized way,'' <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said. Solidarity regional leader <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Kowalczyk </PERSON> needed no pep talk. While some workers hounded <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> for autographs after the meeting, <PERSON> Kowalczyk </PERSON> scurried around and pressed miners to take freshly printed Solidarity sign-up sheets. `` Management says they still do n't want to talk to us, but they are n't stopping us from organizing and there is a lot to do,'' said <PERSON> Kowalczyk </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 2349EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WeatherCutbacks     02-19 0631</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Weather Cutbacks,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>National Weather Service Facing Cuts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> is struggling through a budget crunch, hoping to delay the threatened closing of weather offices until they can be replaced by new automated equipment in a few years. Over the long term the agency seems likely to close a hundred or more of its nearly 250 local offices, replacing them with an extensive network of automated information-gathering equipment. But even as that planning is underway, officials are trying to cope with a money shortage in the current fiscal year that could grow even more severe in 1990. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration annually has proposed closing large numbers of weather offices to save money. And although <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has thwarted that in the past, a hiring freeze has had to be imposed this year and some local offices may be in jeopardy because of the lack of money. The current fiscal year is expected to end with the weather service short between $ 10 million and $ 28 million, although <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> officials who spoke on condition of anonymity said things are looking brighter than they were a few weeks ago. <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> spending proposed by former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for 1990, meanwhile, was set at $ 1.14 billion, down from $ 1.19 billion in the current fiscal year. And while the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> was marked for somewhat of an increase within that budget, that has to include money to cover the purchase of new radar and observation equipment and a supercomputer. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> proposal called for staff cuts, consolidations of offices and for private weather services to take on more specialized forecasting tasks, while the government concentrates on general forecasts and warnings. Full details of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> proposal were not released by the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>, but word on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> was that the plan could have required closing as many as 62 local weather offices this year and 77 more in 1990. Congressional sources said the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration may be reconsidering whether such drastic cuts are necessary. <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> officials said they are discussing with <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> ways to keep offices open, but details were not being made public. However, the two pages slated to include the list of station closings were left blank when the 1990 <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> budget was sent to the printers, according to <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Kane </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations subcommittee that oversees <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION>. Some closings may occur in cases of obvious duplication where stations are relatively close together, he said. Once new automated equipment is in place, more extensive office closings will be easier to defend because weather forecasting would not be hindered, <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> officials say. But that would occur over several years, perhaps as long as a decade. <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> officials say the automated observing equipment is planned for installation in three times as many locations as there are currently weather offices. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employees </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, however, has said that the closings eventually could affect a hundred offices or more. And <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> officials privately admit that after the reorganization is complete they expect to have fewer than 150 local offices, compared to the current 250 or so. Reductions in staff would occur by attrition, they say. The long-term, the <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> modernization plan was originally scheduled to be sent to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last week but that has been delayed. A complicating factor is the fact that many top officials of the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> leave office March 1, and others remain on the job but unsure whether they will be transferred or replaced. The Office of Management and Budget says the <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> budget is part of a group of domestic programs frozen at 1989 levels, included in a $ 136 billion `` pot'' of programs subject to negotiation with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 2348EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Networks-Japan     02-19 0342</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Networks-Japan,0352</SECOND>
<HEAD>CBS Blitzes Other Networks With Massive Far East Trip</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 CBS is blitzing the other networks' coverage of Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s funeral and President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s trip to the <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> this week, taking most of its news broadcasts to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> at a cost of at least $ 2 million. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> also will be on location for <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s funeral. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will attend the funeral Thursday in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, then he goes to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. At a news conference last week, `` Evening News'' anchor <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rather </PERSON> called the coverage `` unprecedented'' by broadcast news, but warranted by <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s death as a symbol of `` the end of the postwar era.'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> will anchor `` ABC World News Tonight'' from <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> all week. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Brokaw </PERSON> will anchor `` NBC Nightly News'' from <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> on Thursday and Friday, then from <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> on Saturday and Sunday. <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> will anchor live coverage of the funeral from <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. The networks have all focused on <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s culture and economy in reports leading up to the funeral and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s trip. CBS, which began on-location coverage Sunday with `` CBS Sunday Morning,'' also is taking the `` CBS Evening News,'' `` CBS This Morning,'' `` 48 Hours'' and `` Face the Nation'' to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. The coverage concludes next Sunday with `` Face the Nation'' from <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. The broadcasts will focus on <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s relationship to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in terms of economy, lifestyles and military interdependence. CBS' `` 48 Hours'' will have live coverage of the beginning of the funeral Thursday night, when it will be Friday morning in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. CBS News figures it will have 18 hours of special coverage from the <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> at a cost of at least $ 2 million, Rather said. `` We thought long and hard about whether should make this kind of commitment to this story at this time,'' he said. `` This is a gamble for us.'' `` But we think in this particular case we can make it work,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RepublicanRomance     02-19 0687</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Republican Romance,0706</SECOND>
<HEAD>For Governor and Congresswoman, Politics is Path to Marriage</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY HARKAVY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AUGUSTA, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 They met in the <ORGANIZATION> Maine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> on the Republican side of the aisle, the raven-haired representative from <ORGANIZATION> Auburn </ORGANIZATION> seated directly behind the handsome young floor leader from <LOCATION> Bangor </LOCATION>. When she decided to run for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1978, they got together to map out campaign strategy. Over the years their shared interest in politics blossomed into something more. The decade-long courtship between Rep. <PERSON> Olympia </PERSON> <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON> and Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> McKernan </PERSON> will culminate this week in an exchange of marriage vows. `` What holds our relationship together is the fact that we love politics,'' said <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON>, now in her sixth term in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` For some, that becomes a dividing factor, but in our case that obviously has n't been the situation.'' `` We both have our own careers and they happen to be in the same field,'' said <PERSON> McKernan </PERSON>, a former two-term congressman who was elected governor in 1986. `` We understand the pressures that are on each other.'' The wedding Friday at the <ORGANIZATION> Greek </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orthodox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Holy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trinity </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Lewiston </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON> is of <LOCATION> Greek </LOCATION> descent _ will begin the second marriage for both. The announcement of their pending nuptials three weeks ago evoked surprise that two of a small state's most prominent political figures could have kept a romance of nearly a decade relatively private. `` A hush-hush affair,'' marveled one of <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON>'s constituents, <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Boisvert </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Lewiston </LOCATION>. `` Nobody seemed to know anything about it. But it's nice.'' <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON>, who turns 42 on Tuesday, was widowed in 1973 when her husband was killed in an accident while driving home from the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>, where he served in the House. She entered politics by running successfully for his seat. The 40-year-old <PERSON> McKernan </PERSON>'s first marriage ended in divorce in 1978. He has an 18-year-old son, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON>. <PERSON> McKernan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON> realize they will spend most of their time 600 miles apart, one in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the other in the state capital of <LOCATION> Augusta </LOCATION>, getting together on weekends and during congressional recesses. They will try, as much as possible, to coordinate their schedules and expect to divide their time between the <ORGANIZATION> Blaine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> _ the executive mansion in <LOCATION> Augusta </LOCATION> _ and <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON>'s home in <LOCATION> Auburn </LOCATION>, 35 miles away. `` The most important factor in any relationship is communication,'' <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON> said, describing their daily telephone conversations. `` Talking about what happens during the day to each of us makes it feel we're not that far away.'' <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON> and <PERSON> McKernan </PERSON> said they believe their careers will insulate them from the problems of other politicians whose marriages broke because they were unable to balance their political responsibilities with the demands of family life. In other marriages, <PERSON> McKernan </PERSON> noted, `` only one of them is involved in politics, and the other one gets left behind a lot.'' They acknowledge their differences in personality. He is deliberate, an outgrowth of his legal training; she tends to rely more heavily on instinct. The romance blossomed while the two were in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, serving as <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>'s delegation in the House. Their private joke on their trips home: `` Your district or mine?'' The relationship was never splashed across the front pages, but neither was it concealed. Whenever the subject was broached by reporters, <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON> and <PERSON> McKernan </PERSON> acknowledged that they dated each other but offered no elaboration. The reaction to their engagement has been positive, they said, with congratulatory calls from President and <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. Referring to his and <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON>'s shared ethnic background, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> told <PERSON> McKernan </PERSON> that `` mixed marriages work _ especially if one of the partners is Greek. <PERSON> McKernan </PERSON> is a Protestant. Their honeymoon will be a weekend in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> with dinner and the theater. Both must be in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> the following week, <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON> to tend to her congressional duties and <PERSON> McKernan </PERSON> for a meeting of the nation's governors. While the wedding itself will be limited to family members and close friends, the couple mailed invitations to 7,500 friends and political supporters for a reception the following week at the <ORGANIZATION> Augusta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 2357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Kemp     02-19 0900</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Kemp,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kemp, Kemp, He's Our Man, Say Black Leaders; For Now, Anyway</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, a liberal Democrat and black veteran of the civil rights wars of the 60s, is willing to put his enthusiasm for white conservative Republican <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> in the language understood on the poor street corners of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. `` He can walk the walk, and he can talk the talk,'' <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said recently of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's housing chief. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>' deliberate use of an expression more familiar in the black neighborhoods he represents than in the white suburbs that produced <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> was meant to communicate. The meaning was clear: Despite their differences, this man <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> is OK. He's all right. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>'s comment last week came after two days of tramping with the former pro quarterback through those <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> neighborhoods in <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s first look at inner city problems since becoming secretary of the Housing and Urban Development. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> went one-on-one with <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>'s black leaders and veterans of the civil rights struggle of the 1950s and 60s _ such as <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, Mayor <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> and the family of the late <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> _ offering them his own brand of bubbly, irrepressible excitement about the power of unleashed free enterprise. All welcomed him warmly and seemed to confirm what <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s supporters were arguing during his unsuccessfully presidential campaign last year: <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, architect of the 1981 income tax cuts now so identified with <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, has a strong reservoir of good will among blacks `` We have serious problems, as you well understand,'' <PERSON> Coretta </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, widow of the late civil rights leader, told him. `` You lift our spirits because you have hope they can be solved.'' Taking control of <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> heads a department important for urban blacks because it administers the federal programs for housing and redevelopment of blighted cities _ programs that are dramatically reduced after eight years under President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> hopes to make <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> the catalyst for new incentives to attract private development into those same neighborhoods. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s support among blacks could be of benefit to the new administration and to the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and new Republican National Chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> set out to win black support away from Democrats. And it could benefit <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> in the future. `` There's no question that a candidate who can attract the support of rock-ribbed conservatives and urban blacks would make one hell of a candidate,'' said <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s political consultant, <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> himself tried to sidestep the political questions. `` That is tangential,'' he said. `` The best politics is to do a good job.'' Many cite <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s background in professional football, where was quarterback, team captain and president of the players' union, as a source of black support. He has maintained friendships with prominent blacks, and has hired <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilkie </PERSON> <PERSON> Gunn </PERSON>, a black conservative and former <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> White House aide, as his chief of staff. `` He knows his safety and indeed his life depended on the ability of black linemen,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>. But it is also due to <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s enthusiastic talk about doing something to solve the housing problem facing the poor. More than just his proposals for enterprise zones and other inducements to attract private business into the inner cities, <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> has raised expectations just by talking about making progress on housing. That trait is even more noticeable coming on the heels of a relative eight-year silence by his predecessor, <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>. `` He has the kind of creative mind that I admire,'' <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, a Democrat and former congressman, said. `` Right now, things are so bad that we've got to work together and solve problems. We can get partisan aga | wv ~ -RRB- o -RCB- 9C -LCB- gkwg -LCB-
</TEXT>
<NOTE>'Q{^:~o9Wy}Dzs[sO[zO</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 s? C -LCB-?? O -RCB- Owv \ -LCB- T ~ s -RCB- | w ~ c9_y -RCB- 7 new job with the highest visibility on He was trailed through <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>'s streets by a bus full of reporters and television cameras. He plans a second tour next week, of homelessness in Northeastern cities. But <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s high visibility and bold talk carries risk. He is given to sweeping statements and boundless expectations, which Democrats are no doubt recording for replay in four years if he falls short. `` I want to eliminate poverty,'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> told one group in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. `` There's not going to be any homelessness unless we turn our backs and let it happen,'' he told another. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> has acknowledged the need for more affordable housing, without promising any more federal spending to build it. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s budget proposal for fiscal 1990 contains no new spending on public housing, and the budget deficit provides little reason for housing advocates to expect even <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> can come up with new spending initiatives Some Democrats have begun to suggest that <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, with his visibility and big talk, has overplayed his hand. `` He has clearly upstaged the president, and that is usually not smart politics,'' <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> McCurry </PERSON> said. `` He runs the risk of overpromising himself early,'' <PERSON> McCurry </PERSON> added. `` He's setting himself up for a long fall.'' Mrs. <PERSON> King </PERSON> seemed to be offering <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> a similar caution as well when they met with the city's black leaders. `` From everything we've heard you say, we think you mean business,'' she said. `` If something happens and there is not the follow through, you're going to have a lot of disappointed people.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Panama-Elections     02-19 0244</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-Elections,0254</SECOND>
<HEAD>Opposition Coalition Kicks Off Presidential Campaign</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALINA GUERRERO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A major opposition candidate on Saturday kicked off his presidential campaign and promised improved social and political rights for women. `` The beginning has begun toward a better <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, of light, fraternity, peace and abundance, where democracy, justice and liberty exists,'' said <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Endara </PERSON>, presidential candidate for the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civilian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opposition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Endara </PERSON>, a 52-year-old attorney, spoke Saturday at a women's convention organized by opposition party members Presidential elections are scheduled for May 7. <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> promised to improve the rights of <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> women. He said that to beat the government-backed coalition in the election, he would follow a program of `` democratic convictions and social justice.'' The government-supported <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> candidate is <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Duque </PERSON>. Also running for the presidency is <PERSON> Hildebrando </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicosia </PERSON> of the Authentic Panamanian Party. <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> previously was spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Arias </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Madrid </ORGANIZATION>, a three-time <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> president who ran three more times and lost. During two of the unsuccessful bids, <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> claimed victory was stolen from him by election fraud. The opposition wants to use the elections to oust <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s de facto ruler, army commander Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is not a candidate in the presidential elections. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has been in power since February 1988 when he orchestrated the ouster of President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>. <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> had tried to fire <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> in the wake of his federal indictment in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> on drug charges.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TeenParty     02-19 0123</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Teen Party,0125</SECOND>
<HEAD>200 Teens Brought to Courthouse After Loud Party</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WHYNOT, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A party in Whynot? Why not? An estimated 200 teen-agers gathered Friday night in a field near this town of about 2,000 people 10 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Meridian </LOCATION>. It was a going-away party for a friend. Authorities, though, told them why not this party in Whynot. The party was over when the <ORGANIZATION> Lauderdale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> received complaints of excessive noise and suspected alcohol use In three trips in a school bus, authorities brought the party-goers to the county courthouse. An estimated 75 to 80 teens were issued citations for allegedly consuming or possessing alcohol, officials said. They were scheduled to appear in Juvenile Court on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 0020EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CBSNotWelcome     02-19 0339</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CBS Not Welcome,0347</SECOND>
<HEAD>Affiliate Says It Won't Let Network News Team Back Next Mardi Gras</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> affiliate is n't inviting the network back to its newsroom next <PERSON> Mardi </PERSON> <PERSON> Gras </PERSON> because the network's report focused on the city's crime problem and was `` misleading and very superficial,'' the affiliate's news director said. `` Our video files will not be open to <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, nor will any editing facilities or satellite equipment be available. Any story you do, you will do on your own. You wo n't have our help,'' <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>, news director of local affiliate <ORGANIZATION> WWL </ORGANIZATION>, said in a letter to <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Burk </PERSON>. <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> wrote to protest a report on `` CBS Evening News'' done by correspondent <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Zant </PERSON> during <PERSON> Mardi </PERSON> <PERSON> Gras </PERSON> earlier this month. The report `` began with a brief mention of our Mardi Gras celebration, and juxtaposed that with a series of murder scenes and a long discussion of our crime problems,'' <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> wrote. Although there has been an increase in murders this year, <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> said that `` to combine the elements of <LOCATION> Mardi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gras </LOCATION> and the crime problem in a very quick piece creates a simplistic, misleading and very superficial look at our city and in no way reflects what the community is doing to solve the problem.'' <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Schweitzer </PERSON>, a network spokesman in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, said Saturday he was not familiar with the situation and could not comment. He referred calls to another spokesman, but a message left on his telephone answering machine was n't returned. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> had almost a slaying a day during January and police said they found the body of the 34th victim of the year Saturday. Police have blamed the increase on drugs. <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, which had sent its own letter of complaint to <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, commended <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> for his strong protest and asked residents to boycott CBS programming for two weeks. <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> thanked the council but asked viewers to delay the boycott until after the ratings period in March. Those ratings are used to set advertising rates.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 0025EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Philippines-Military     02-19 0365</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines-Military,0377</SECOND>
<HEAD>Aquino Offers Peace Talks To Rebels</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BAGUIO, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> told new officers Sunday to shun coup plots and urged them to crush communist rebels and other `` enemies of freedom'' who refuse to settle disputes with her government peacefully. `` Those who sapped the strength of this country will ask you to join them in exploiting its weaknesses,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> told 113 graduating cadets during commencement exercises at the <ORGANIZATION> Philippine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>, 150 miles north of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. `` Ignore them,'' she ordered. `` Ignore them out of patriotism, ingore them out of prudence. This country, this government and this leader have more strength than appearances suggest.'' Graduates of the nation's only military academy spearheaded the six armed attempts to topple Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> since she took power in the February 1986 civilian-military uprising against President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. Troops here and in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> were placed on maximum alert in advance of Sunday's commencement because of rumors that right-wing extremists would launch a new coup attempt. Hundreds of troops, some of them flown here from <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, guarded strategic points near the mountain-top academy. Bomb-sniffing dogs checked cadets before the ceremony began under brillantly clear skies. In March 1987, a bomb exploded on the academy parade ground a few days before the commencement, killing four people and injuring nine others. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> said the bomb was intended for her. In her speech, Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> told the cadets it was their duty to protect democratic gains from both communist rebels and right-wing extremists in their ranks. `` Fight them wherever they appear and threaten our people, our work that we are striving to make of this country,'' she said. She challenged the cadets to join with civilian authorities in healing the nation's wounds and building democracy. `` To the enemies of freedom, the armed opponents of our government on the left and the right, I address these words: Let us sit down and try to settle our differences by talk,'' she said. `` And if we can not, by all means, let us do so by arms. But let us not infect the next generation in civil society and in the armed forces with narrow causes and hatreds of the past.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Duke-Republicans 1stLd-Writethru a0622 02-19 0470</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Duke-Republicans, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0622,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>EDS: INSERTS 2 grafs after pvs 3rd graf bgng ``We repudiate...''
to add response from Duke campaign manager</HEAD>
<HEAD>Republican National Committee Seeks to Censure David Duke</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> said it will seek to censure <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>, the former <PERSON> Ku </PERSON> <PERSON> Klux </PERSON> <PERSON> Klan </PERSON> leader who won a seat in the <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> state <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>, saying he is a `` charlatan'' who does not reflect <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> principles. `` <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> is not a Republican,'' <ORGANIZATION> RNC </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> said in a statement released by the party. `` He's a pretender, a charlatan and a political opportunist who is looking for any organization he can find to try to legitimize his views of racial and religious bigotry and intolerance.'' `` We repudiate him in his views and we will take steps to see that he is disenfranchised from our party if he is declared the official winner in Saturday's election,'' <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> said. `` What does it take to be a Republican, other than registering yourself as a Republican? I think he's -LRB- Atwater -RRB- typical of some the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> leadership ... in that he does n't really have his finger on the pulse of the people, and know what a real Republican is,'' <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>'s campaign manager <PERSON> Howie </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrell </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in a broadcast interview. `` I think that he's way off base, and needs to reassess where he stands. When the dust settles, I think he'll find that he's probably further out of the mainstream of Republicanism than is <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>.'' In unofficial results Saturday night, <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> narrowly defeated homebuilder <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Treen </PERSON> to represent a state <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> district in <LOCATION> Metairie </LOCATION>, a suburb of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> registered with the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> two days before qualifying to run in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> race. <PERSON> Treen </PERSON> also is a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> RNC </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON> said that if <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> is officially certified the winner, <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> will call a meeting of the party's executive committee within the next week to consider a motion of censure against <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> The motion proposes that the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> `` reject and condemn <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>, his beliefs and the hate and fear he promotes, and reaffirm its commitment to equal opportunity for all regardless of race, creed, religion, sex or national origin.'' It also would preclude <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> from receiving any type of aid from the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Such an action would be unprecedented within the party, Ms. <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON> said, adding, `` I would not imagine that there would be a single person -LRB- on the <ORGANIZATION> RNC </ORGANIZATION> executive committee -RRB- who would disagree with this.'' <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, speaking in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> at a <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> function Saturday night, acknowledged the party's involvement in the <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> race `` is a very unusual thing for the national party to do, but this man does not deserve to be in office.'' President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> both aided <PERSON> Treen </PERSON>'s campaign
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BombThreat     02-19 0221</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bomb Threat,0228</SECOND>
<HEAD>British Airways Flight Delayed By Bomb Threat</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The takeoff of a <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> flight to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> was delayed here for more than five hours Saturday night by a bomb threat. British Airways officials halted Flight 226 minutes before its scheduled 6:15 p.m. departure after an unidentified man called the airline's <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> office and told officials there was a bomb aboard the DC-10, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lample </PERSON>, the airline's director of public affairs in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Lample </PERSON> said no explosives were found in a 5-hour search and the aircraft carrying 122 passengers left <LOCATION> Hartsfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Gatwick </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> at 11:41 p.m. `` I do n't know the actual conversation, but since specific threats were made against a specific flight, we took it seriously,'' <PERSON> Lample </PERSON> said. `` It is our policy to take such threats very seriously.'' The passengers were taken off the plane while police and dogs searched the aircraft and luggage, he said. British officials said they were taking very seriously telephone threats made in recent days to <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION>' <LOCATION> Bombay </LOCATION> office to blow up a jetliner unless author <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> emerges from seclusion in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. Some Moslems have said <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>'s book, `` The Satanic Verses,'' blasphemes Islam. British officials have been checking all bags to the airline's flights to and from <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890219-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-19-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Duke-Treen 8thLd-Writethru a0629 02-19 1071</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Duke-Treen, 8th Ld-Writethru, a0629,1104</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ex-Ku Klux Klan Leader Duke Wins Narrow Victory</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 16th graf, `Democrat State ...' to UPDATE
with Duke campaign manager saying he's concerned Treen supporters might
try to tamper with result; picks up 17th graf, `Duke won ...'. Should stands
for AMs.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos NU1,2,7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDA ASHTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
