<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 2337EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Duke-SkiDeath 1stLd-Writethru a0755 01-31 0802</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Duke-Ski Death, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0755,0820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officials Say Spanish Duke's Skiing Death Was An Accident</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Subs grafs 10-11 bgng `But defending' with six grafs to UPDATE
with sheriff refusing to make statement about safety violations, describing
how victim received and acknowledged a warning. Picks up 12th graf pvs,
`Knous said...'.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELLEN MILLER HADDOW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VAIL, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Officials of the World Alpine Ski Championships maintained Tuesday that no safety violations contributed to the death of a cousin of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>'s king, but a champion skiier suggested the victim was on a closed course. The Duke of <LOCATION> Cadiz </LOCATION>, a 52-year-old first cousin of King <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> and member of the international governing body of ski racing, was killed Monday at the <ORGANIZATION> Beaver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Creek </ORGANIZATION> ski resort when he ran into a cable being raised to hold a finish-line banner for the men's downhill course <PERSON> Alfonso </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Borbon </PERSON> <PERSON> y </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Dampierre </PERSON> suffered neck lacerations and apparently died instantly, <LOCATION> Eagle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Coroner <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Meineke </PERSON> said. An official cause of death had not been released by Tuesday afternoon. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Borbon </PERSON> was at one-time married to the granddaughter of Spanish dictator <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Franco </PERSON>. Although he was not in the line of succession to the <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> throne, he was a descendant of <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> XIV </PERSON>, the French <PERSON> Sun </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, and was the Bourbon or `` legitimist'' candidate for king had the monarchy ever been restored in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. King <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> and Queen <LOCATION> Sofia </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> expressed their sorrow over his death. `` There is no reason to believe that any safety violations occurred,'' <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Knous </PERSON>, president of the championships' organizing committee, told a news conference Tuesday. `` It truly appears that this was an accident, a very, very unfortunate and tragic incident,'' <PERSON> Knous </PERSON> said. Sheriff A.J. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> would not say Tuesday night whether <LOCATION> Eagle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> officials agree with <PERSON> Knous </PERSON>. `` We will make no conclusions about safety violations, not until the investigation is done,'' <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. `` I will discuss the investigation with the district attorney. Until then, we are looking at all possibilities.'' But defending world downhill champion <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mueller </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> said the victim and other ski officials ignored normal procedures when they skied down a closed course. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, who said his investigation would take a month, confirmed that the course was closed, but said, `` We believe he -LRB- de <PERSON> Borbon </PERSON> -RRB- had the authority to be on there.'' <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Borbon </PERSON> was skiing Monday with companions when he hit the cable as course workers were moving the finish line and banners uphill from the end of the slalom course to the end of the downhill. Witnesses said one of the companions, former Austrian Olympic champion <PERSON> Toni </PERSON> <PERSON> Sailer </PERSON>, saw the cable and warned <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Borbon </PERSON>, who acknowledged the warning but still slammed into it at neck level, according to <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Knous </PERSON> said there were no safety violations despite the fact that the course was closed following an inspection by the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ski </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION>, known by its French initials as <ORGANIZATION> FIS </ORGANIZATION>. Also there were no banners or identifying material on the cable that the duke hit. He said he could n't comment on whether the duke and his skiing companions should have been on the course at the time. <PERSON> Mueller </PERSON>, 31, one of the favorites in Saturday's race, said: `` Normally, when we prepare for a competition, the course is closed. But here, the <ORGANIZATION> FIS </ORGANIZATION> is skiing down for pleasure. I think that's a big mistake. If the downhill course is closed, it should be closed for all people.'' Downhill training went on as scheduled Tuesday although social events were canceled or postponed. Officials of the championships wore black armbands, and flags throughout the ski resort flew at half-staff. The Spanish ski team, which had been training at another <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> ski resort, still planned to come to <LOCATION> Vail </LOCATION> and compete, <PERSON> Knous </PERSON> said. The championship meet continues through this weekend. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Borbon </PERSON> served as <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>'s ambassador to <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> from 1969 to 1973, was president of the <ORGANIZATION> Spanish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Skiing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> from 1977 to 1984 and an eight-time Spanish skiing champion. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Borbon </PERSON>'s father was the elder brother of King <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON>' father Both men's fathers were the sons of King <PERSON> Alfonso </PERSON> <PERSON> XIII </PERSON>, who abdicated the Spanish throne in 1931. The duke married <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> <PERSON> Franco </PERSON> in 1972 and they divorced in 1982. In February 1984, the older of his two sons was killed in an auto accident in which de <PERSON> Borbon </PERSON> was driving. A judge ruled that <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Borbon </PERSON> had been negligent and stripped him of the custody of his other son. <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez-Ochoa </PERSON>, the slalom gold medalist at the 1972 Olympics and a close friend of the duke, said <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Borbon </PERSON> liked to `` ski fast and drive fast.'' Referring to the duke's divorce, the fatal auto accident and the skiing tragedy, <PERSON> Fernandez-Ochoa </PERSON> described the victim as `` an unlucky person. Bad things happened to him.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-UN-USArrears     01-31 0770</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UN-US Arrears,0791</SECOND>
<HEAD>United States Praises United Nations But Remains In Arrears</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VICTORIA GRAHAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After years of cold-shouldering the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> now sings its praises and increasingly suggests things for it to do. But <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dollars to match the tasks are not forthcoming and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> remains the biggest <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> debtor. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is urging the world body to take on more responsibilities _ from monitoring the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> withdrawal from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> to fighting terrorism and drug trafficking and investigating human rights abuses and chemical warfare. It also is expected to monitor the eventual Vietnamese withdrawal from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> and to play a role in a <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> settlement. But little money is forthcoming from the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to fund the burgeoning <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agenda for the 159-nation organization. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is the largest <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> contributor, assessed one-quarter of the annual budget of $ 800 million. While the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> has registered a series of formidable peacemaking and peacekeeping successes that advance <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> interests, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has been withholding <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dues. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> ended 1988 about $ 402 million in arrears in budget and peacekeeping dues _ 53.5 percent of the total <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> arrears of more than $ 750 million. Largely because of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nonpayment, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> periodically faces financial crises and is having trouble paying for new peackeeping operations. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador here, praised the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> during his election campaign and called for the payment of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dues. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has been withholding a large part of the dues because of budget constraints and disaffection with the world body. The organization was seen as biased against the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, bureaucratically bloated and wasteful. Some money was withheld in an effort to force the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> to reform itself, despite administration and <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> calls for full-funding. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said before leaving office as secretary of state said it is important for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign policy `` to fully fund our contributions to <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> agencies ... and to initiate a plan to pay arrearages ... over a five-year period.'' He said the request for nearly full payment of dues `` is critical to our objectives of resolving regional conflicts. The <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> can play an important role in this regard.'' <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Undersecretary of State <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON>, in charge of international organizations, said, `` Up through last year, the Executive, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> sought full funding. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> failed to appropriate the full amount.'' In a telephone interview, <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON> said some people `` hold the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> in disrepute when it does disreputable things.'' It rightfully is criticized, he said, for overspending and for political moves like a <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> resolution equating Zionism with racism. But he said the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> has improved because the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> took a firm stand. Last year, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> scored spectacular achievements and its peacekeeping forces won the Nobel Peace Prize. In <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> observers are monitoring Soviet withdrawal under a U.N.-mediated agreement. For years, ending Soviet involvement in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> was a prime <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign policy goal. In the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeepers are monitoring a cease-fire while <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> are talking under <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> auspices. The cease-fire enabled the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to scale back its costly naval presence there. In southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> is helping to fulfill another <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> goal: getting Soviet-backed Cuban troops out of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> observers will monitor the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> pullout and peacekeepers will oversee <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s transition to independence from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> under a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> plan. In the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sahara </LOCATION> conflict, a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peace plan has been accepted by <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION>, anti-Moroccan guerrillas and <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> and the world body will supervise free elections there. In <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> has sponsored talks between <LOCATION> Greek </LOCATION> and Turkish Cypriot communities to discuss reunification of the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> island. In his final budget, President <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> requested nearly full <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> funding in the 1990 fiscal year _ $ 205.5 million for the regular budget _ plus an additional $ 46 million to begin paying off <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arrears. The arrears of $ 403 million include $ 307.7 million for the budget and $ 94.1 million for peacekeeping. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has been paying its arrears and now owes $ 9 million to the regular budget and $ 172 million to peacekeeping. For almost eight years the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and the world body were estranged. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> charged it was ineffectual, pro-Soviet, anti-American and wasteful. But in his farewell address to the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> in September, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> praised the world body for helping to end regional conflicts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-PandaDies     01-31 0335</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panda Dies,0344</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ying-Ying, Mexico's Prolific Panda Mother, Dead At Age 14</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRIS ANGELO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The giant panda Ying-Ying, the female of the pair that made <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s panda breeding program the most successful outside <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, has died of unknown causes _ possibly a broken heart _ at age 14. <PERSON> Ying-Ying </PERSON>, who died late Sunday, had been depressed since October, about three months after Pe-Pe, her mate, died of cancer, said <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Elena </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyo </PERSON>, director of the Chapultepec Zoo. She said <PERSON> Ying-Ying </PERSON> had been ill for several days. `` We do n't what she died of,'' Ms. <PERSON> Hoyo </PERSON> said. `` The autopsy did n't determine the cause'' but zoo officials hope laboratory tests will determine the cause. She said <PERSON> Ying-Ying </PERSON> had until Pe-Pe's death spent every day with the panda <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> sent as a gift in 1975, when <PERSON> Ying-Ying </PERSON> was 11 months old. `` She did n't want to live without Pe-Pe,'' Ms. <PERSON> Hoyo </PERSON> said. `` She was very much in love with Pe-Pe. She did n't want to go out into the garden. She ate but not as well as she used to. `` She was n't as aggressive, as sure of herself. Before she would n't let you touch her and recently it did n't matter to her.'' Giant pandas are an endangered species and only about 18 are in captivity outside <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The animals generally have a life expectancy of about 20 years. <PERSON> Ying-Ying </PERSON>, who was nearly 15, gave birth to seven offspring after natural mating with Pe-Pe. Four survived. <PERSON> Ying-Ying </PERSON> accidentally rolled onto the first cub eight days after its birth in 1980, crushing it, and one each of two sets of twins died. <PERSON> Tohui </PERSON>, the oldest of the four surviving offspring, set off panda mania when she was born July 21, 1981, and is the zoo's hope for continuing to produce more pandas. In December, the <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zoo </ORGANIZATION> sent its 16-year-old male panda to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> in hopes the two would mate. Ms. <PERSON> Hoyo </PERSON> said <PERSON> Ying-Ying </PERSON>'s body, like Pe-Pe's, will be stuffed and put on display.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-OpenEnrollment     01-31 0782</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Open Enrollment,0807</SECOND>
<HEAD>Blemishes Surface In Open Enrollment System Hailed By Reagan, Bush</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TONY KENNEDY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOUNTAIN IRON, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has called free choice `` the single most promising idea'' in education. But he'd get an argument from <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> and others involved in the nation's most comprehensive application of the concept. `` I do n't know if anyone can say it is off to a good start,'' said <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON>, superintendent of a school district on northern <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>'s Iron Range. `` We're very close to being out of business.'' The problem is that nearly a third of the district's 1,000 students have applied to attend school in neighboring <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, next year. The exodus is possible because of a statewide open enrollment program that will give all public school students freedom to choose where they attend school. <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON>'s district stands in contrast to the affluent public schools in <LOCATION> Edina </LOCATION>, a predominantly white district in suburban <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>. Two districts do not take outsiders: <LOCATION> Sartell </LOCATION>, because it is crowded; and <LOCATION> Edina </LOCATION>, because it voted not to take part in the open enrollment program. Critics say the open enrollment program wo n't reach the poor, penalizes small towns, invites inter-school athletic recruiting, leaves some districts with inappropriate staffing levels, and provides dissident parents an extortion tool to use on school boards. Others hail the program for promoting excellence. At a White House Workshop on Choice in Education on Jan. 10, former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> referred to open enrollment as `` that marvelous program in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> that is fostering unprecedented competition among public schools to make them more attractive to parents and students.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> are not the only admirers of the plan, which encourages free market-type competition among public schools. <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, enrollment options specialist with the <ORGANIZATION> state </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, said the program will probably `` weed out'' lackluster schools. Gov. <PERSON> Rudy </PERSON> <PERSON> Perpich </PERSON> said the program makes the state `` a national leader in empowering families to make choices about their children's education. But not all state officials are convinced. `` Based on the limited experience we've had in this state, it's ridiculous,'' said state Rep. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> McEachern </PERSON>, chairman of the state <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Only 435 of <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>'s 740,000 grade school and high school students applied for the program this year and applications for next year have reached 1,300. The program applies to school districts of more than 1,000 students, and will be extended to all school districts by the 1990-91 school year. Districts now have the option of voting not to participate. `` It's a choice for the rich,'' <PERSON> McEachern </PERSON> insisted. `` That's all. In Mountain Iron and <PERSON> Buhl </PERSON>, communities still recovering from the collapse of the taconite industry a decade ago, parents have been divided over which school buildings to close in the aftermath of a merger. Open enrollment has been an escape route from conflict, <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> said. The lower enrollment wo n't cut operating expenses, but it will reduce state aid by $ 1.2 million, a third of the district's budget, he said. `` If chaos continues, more students will leave and it will be lights out,'' <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> also said some poor families wo n't have access to open enrollment because of transportation costs. In <LOCATION> Edina </LOCATION>, where the 6,000-pupil district is 96 percent white and the average price of a home in 1985 was $ 141,000, the school board voted to opt out of the program. `` We kind of anticipated that this would be viewed as a racially motivated decision,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Edina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> Superintendent <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Smyth </PERSON>, who denied `` elitism'' played a role in the decision. He said open enrollment allows students to transfer schools for athletic purposes and other reasons he considers `` trivial.'' Another drawback is the inevitable erosion of education quality for students who remain in schools of declining enrollment, he said. But <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Edina </LOCATION> wants to `` pick and choose'' its students. `` The law says you ca n't deny a student because of their race or their academic ability or whether they're a problem student. You ca n't select and choose which kids are educated and <LOCATION> Edina </LOCATION> says ` We want to pick and choose,''' she said. The <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teacher </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> has warmly endorsed open enrollment partly because `` parent and student satisfaction with their school is absolutely vital to their success,'' said <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Zohn </PERSON>, president. But <PERSON> Zohn </PERSON> noted that the <ORGANIZATION> PTA </ORGANIZATION> unsuccessfully lobbied for a declining enrollment fund that would have sent state money for one or two years to schools losing students to give them a chance to improve. <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> joked that the success of schools under open enrollment may someday be linked to their marketing ability. `` How about, ` Come here. We'll give all A's,' or ` Finish four years in three.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0110EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CharityHospitals     01-31 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Charity Hospitals,0696</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mississippi Governor Wages Emotional Fight To Close Charity Hospitals</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT NAYLOR JR.</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JACKSON, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Mabus </PERSON> has gotten himself into an emotional battle by proposing to close the three charity hospitals that the nation's poorest state operates for its poorest people. <PERSON> Mabus </PERSON> says the poor would be better served if the money that funds the hospitals went instead into Medicaid and attracted federal funds, but opponents claim to have more than 100,000 petition signatures to keep the hospitals open. <PERSON> Mabus </PERSON>, who took office a year ago after a reform-based campaign, says the hospitals are underfunded and represent the lower tier of a double standard of health care in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>. `` We have to work toward the day when where you live and how much you make are not the deciding factors in the standard of care you get,'' the 40-year-old Democrat said recently. But he has been unable to convince some people that the health care needs of the poor could be better served by closing <ORGANIZATION> Matty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hersee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Meridian </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Laurel </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Kuhn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Vicksburg </LOCATION>. The hospitals, set up in 1916, collectively maintain only 199 of the state's more than 15,800 hospital beds on a budget of $ 6.8 million. They served 77,508 patients in the 1988 fiscal year, out of a population of about 2.5 million. That includes 8,278 who required hospitalization and 69,230 outpatients. `` The buildings are older buildings, but they are well kept and they're very clean,'' said <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Sprayberry </PERSON> of the state <ORGANIZATION> Eleemosynary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, which oversees charity hospitals. The governor's plan sparked a recent rally at the state Capitol. `` I do n't have no insurance, no Medicaid and you ca n't get no doctor to wait on you if you do n't have no money,'' said <PERSON> Georgia </PERSON> <PERSON> Mae </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, one of about 300 people who traveled the 90 miles from Laurel for the rally. `` When you go to the state hospital they take good care of you. They do n't ask you if you got money. They just wait on you,'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said. `` If you go to these other hospitals, they're going to turn you out. They're going to say you got to get some money and that's something these people ai n't got. <PERSON> Mabus </PERSON> hastily called a news conference to counter the public attention drawn to the rally. `` I think that the people marching today and I have the same aims and that's quality health care for Mississippians,'' <PERSON> Mabus </PERSON> said. `` I think as governor I've got to make the decision of how we can get the most health care for the most people.'' <PERSON> Mabus </PERSON> has said that putting into Medicaid the money that now goes for the charity hospitals would attract to the state an additional $ 28 million in federal matching dollars. He also has proposed other Medicaid expansions. <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> spent $ 440,258,967 on Medicaid in the 1988 fiscal year, which ended June 30, 1988. Of that, $ 346,324,369 was in federal matching funds and $ 93,934,598 in state funds. <PERSON> Mabus </PERSON> said his plan would provide medical assistance to far more people than are served by the charity hospitals. `` By shifting these funds to Medicaid, we can cover literally tens of thousands more Mississipians statewide. We can do it in a more equitable manner,'' he said. But opponents say they have more than 100,000 signatures on petitions and most legislators from the areas where the hospitals are located have worked against the governor's plan. `` My question is, if you close the charity hospitals, how many working poor people are going to fall through the cracks?'' asked state Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON>, whose district includes <PERSON> Matty </PERSON> <PERSON> Hersee </PERSON>. But lawmakers who back the goveror's proposal agree with him that the issue is one of quality health care for the poor. `` I think the people of <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> can be served by the charity hospitals it they're properly funded, but they're not properly funded and the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> has refused to properly fund them for the last 10 years,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Buelow </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Iraq-Weapons     01-31 0172</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iraq-Weapons,0175</SECOND>
<HEAD>Twenty Major Arms Companies To Display Wares In Iraq</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BAGHDAD, Iraq (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 20 major arms companies from <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the Soviet bloc will show some of their wares at the <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> defense equipment exhibition in April, a newspaper reported. The companies include <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s Thompson-CSF, <ORGANIZATION> Matra </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Aerospaciale </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Dassault </ORGANIZATION> groups and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Fiat </ORGANIZATION>, the al-Itihad business weekly, mouthpiece of the <ORGANIZATION> Iraqi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chambers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, said Monday. <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> was <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s second biggest arms supplier after the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> during the eight-year Iran-Iraq war, which a U.N.-sponsored cease-fire halted on Aug. 20. The weekly quoted Industry Minister <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> <PERSON> Kamel </PERSON> as saying the five-day exhibition that begins April 28 will `` provide the opportunity for all concerned to become acquainted with technical developments in this field.'' <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> has claimed to build its own long-range missiles, which were used against Iranian cities during the war, and is seeking to develop its own arms industry. It is believed to be cooperating with <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> to develop a new missile.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Steinberg-Hedda     01-31 0639</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Steinberg-Hedda,0654</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nussbaum Could Become Women's Advocate</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Steinberg, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KILEY ARMSTRONG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Hedda </PERSON> <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> has become a powerful symbol of family violence and could become a powerful advocate for other battered women, says the psychiatrist who is nurturing her recovery. Tragedy put Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> into her role, portrayed by prosecutors as a brainwashed victim of brutality and by <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s defense as a fraud who killed the little girl they illegally adopted and raised until her death at age 6. The once-pretty woman bared her scarred face and psyche to television viewers during testimony that unraveled an all-too-common story of domestic violence. A state jury Monday convicted <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> of manslaughter. When Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>, a 46-year-old former children's book editor for <ORGANIZATION> Random </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, was arrested with <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> after little <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s death, she had a black eye, broken nose, nine fractured ribs, split lip, cauliflower ear, and a leg so severely ulcerated that doctors called the injury life-threatening. Charges against her were dropped when prosecutors determined she was too physically and mentally incapacitated to be responsible for the girl's death. Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> agreed to become the key prosecution witness. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, 47, was charged with beating <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> on the night of Nov. 1, 1987. The death, three days later, of a child from an affluent, well-educated household, shocked many and became a nationwide symbol of family violence as a problem that cuts across social strata. Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>'s testimony described a 12-year relationship in which she was beaten, brainwashed and subjected to other bizarre punishments for transgressions imagined by <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>. Slowly, deliberately, Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> told how she came to see <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> as a `` godlike figure'' _ asking his permission to eat, obeying his orders to sleep on the floor or sit in a tub of cold water. Jurors saw handwritten pages in which Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> vowed to care about <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s hair, clothes, work, problems, diet, future, teeth and other concerns. In another paper, she wrote 10 times that `` anger is destructive'' and that `` self-defense is regressive.'' Her psychiatrist, <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Klagsbrun </PERSON>, has said Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> wo n't be ready to leave the Four Winds hospital in <LOCATION> Katonah </LOCATION>, north of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, for at least two months But while she has n't made definite plans, <PERSON> Klagsbrun </PERSON> said he would n't be surprised to see Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> become an advocate for other battered women. `` She feels an obligation at this point to be helpful to others _ in helping people stand up and fight for themselves and regain a level of self-respect,'' said <PERSON> Klagsbrun </PERSON>. `` She's very conscious of the responsibility she now has to take a horrible part of her life and make it useful for other women as well as for herself, her own healing.'' `` She's articulate and intelligent. She has the capacity to relate and be available to other people'' _ and already has helped other patients during her hospitalization, said <PERSON> Klagsbrun </PERSON>. `` Her impact on other people who have experienced battering has been enormous,'' he said. `` She has allowed some people to reveal more than they were prepared to do ... to feel they can assert themselves in society and stand up to evil. People have said things along those lines to her.'' During seven days of testimony in December, Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> said that <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> told her in bed, after they had free-based cocaine and while <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> lay comatose on their bathroom floor, that he had `` knocked <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> down and she did n't want to get up.'' The defense charged that Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> was jealous of <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s attention toward <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> and inflicted the fatal injuries Prosecutors said Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>, who lost her job when she frequently missed work because of injuries, suffered from the battered spouse syndrome and was herself too much a victim herself to have hurt, or helped, the child.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NightStalker-List     01-31 0277</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Night Stalker-List,0287</SECOND>
<HEAD>Richard Ramirez Accused Of 13 Night Stalker Slayings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Night Stalker, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> is charged with 13 `` Night Stalker'' slayings, along with 30 other felonies, including attempted murder, rape and assault. Here is a list of the murder victims referred to Monday in prosecutors' opening arguments: _ June 1984: <PERSON> Jennie </PERSON> <PERSON> Vincow </PERSON>, 79, of Eagle Rock, killed during an apparent burglary at her home, found with her throat slashed _ March 17, 1985: <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Okazaki </PERSON>, 34, of <LOCATION> Rosemead </LOCATION>, found shot to death in her condominium A roommate, <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON>, was wounded but survived. _ March 17, 1985: Tsai-lian Yu, 30, of <LOCATION> Monterey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, apparently pulled from her car and shot repeatedly around midnight _ March 27, 1985: <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Zazzara </PERSON>, 64, and <PERSON> Maxine </PERSON> <PERSON> Zazzara </PERSON>, 44, of <LOCATION> Whittier </LOCATION>, found dead in their home _ May 14, 1985: <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Doi </PERSON>, 66, of <LOCATION> Monterey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, killed at his home _ May 29, 1985: <PERSON> Mabel </PERSON> <PERSON> Close </PERSON> <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>, 83, of <LOCATION> Monrovia </LOCATION>, fatally bludgeoned in her home Her invalid sister, <PERSON> Florence </PERSON> <PERSON> Lang </PERSON>, 80, survived the attack. _ July 1, 1985: <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Cannon </PERSON>, 75, of <LOCATION> Arcadia </LOCATION>, found in her ransacked home beaten and with her throat slit _ July 7, 1985: <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, 60, of <LOCATION> Monterey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, killed at her home _ July 20, 1985: <PERSON> Maxon </PERSON> <PERSON> Kneiding </PERSON>, 68, and his wife, <PERSON> Lela </PERSON> <PERSON> Kneiding </PERSON>, 64, of <LOCATION> Glendale </LOCATION>, killed at their home _ July 20, 1985: <PERSON> Chainarong </PERSON> <PERSON> Khovananth </PERSON>, 32, of <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, shot to death while asleep in his home during a $ 30,000 burglary His 29-year-old wife and their 8-year-old son survived beatings and sexual attacks. _ Aug 8, 1985: <PERSON> Elyas </PERSON> <PERSON> Abowath </PERSON>, 35, of <ORGANIZATION> Diamond </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION>, shot to death in his home. His 28-year-old wife was raped and assaulted.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Waistcoat     01-31 0584</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Waistcoat,0599</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Lab Probes 17th Century Mystery Of King's Blood</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GRAHAM HEATHCOTE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The waistcoat reputedly worn by <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> I </PERSON> at his beheading in 1649 is being taken back to the Museum of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> today, after a police crime lab failed to determine if its mysterious stains are royal blood. `` We have examined it but we can not tell if the stains are blood,'' said <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> <PERSON> Divall </PERSON>, a biochemist at the <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forensic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION>. `` If we had a piece of the silk we could look for some form of hemoglobin by using intensive X-rays to show the protein structure, but naturally, the museum wo n't let us cut it up,'' said <PERSON> Divall </PERSON>. To discover whether the stains could have been the king's blood, the museum sent the waistcoat to the lab, where it underwent the routine tests that would be conducted in a modern-day crime, <PERSON> Divall </PERSON> said. `` I am convinced we have the king's waistcoat,'' <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Staniland </PERSON>, the museum's keeper of costume and textiles, said on Monday, the 340th anniversary of the execution. `` The workmanship of the knitting is right for the time and when it was bought for us from a collector in 1925, it had a note attached saying it had belonged to Dr. <PERSON> Hobbs </PERSON>, the physician who attended the king on the scaffold. It then passed to his daughter, <PERSON> Susannah </PERSON>, and remained with their descendants until it was auctioned in 1898,'' Miss <PERSON> Staniland </PERSON> said. The faded blue silk waistcoat is believed to have been worn by the king next to his skin when his head was chopped off on Jan. 30, 1649, after he lost his long struggle against the Puritan leader, <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Cromwell </PERSON>. The monarch stepped out on the scaffold in <ORGANIZATION> Whitehall </ORGANIZATION>, central <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, from a window of the <ORGANIZATION> Banqueting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, which still stands. The long-sleeved garment with buttoned neck opening and small upstanding collar has armpit stains, probably from sweat, but no collar stains. Two large stains, on the upper chest and abdomen, have survived an attempt to clean them off. `` We took ultraviolet light photographs and did a very sensitive chemical test for blood which we are doing every day on clothing, weapons and at the scene of a crime. We were not surprised at the negative results because blood would have degraded in 300 years,'' he said. The king was a small man, and the waistcoat's chest measures only 28 inches. It is long enough to reach his thighs. `` We wanted to see if the legend about the stains being blood could be true. But the only way we could prove that without destroying anything was if we had some proved bloodstains of the same period and we have n't,'' said <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Keene </PERSON>, the museum's head of conservation. `` An eyewitness of the execution said the king was wearing a sky blue garment, and the waistcoat is a faded sky blue,'' Ms. <PERSON> Keene </PERSON> added. Miss <PERSON> Staniland </PERSON> said: `` Authentication is a difficult business and it would help if we had other garments of the king.'' Knitted 17th century silk garments are believed to have been made in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>. The waistcoat is displayed beside a sample of modern knitting in the same pattern as the waistcoat. Below it is a German engraving of the execution, supposedly drawn by a witness and showing the king kneeling. `` But the execution block was only 10 inches high so he must have been lying prone,'' Miss <PERSON> Staniland </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0016EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Steinberg 9thLd-Writethru a0743 01-31 1222</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Steinberg, 9th Ld - Writethru, a0743,1251</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Lawyer Convicted Of Manslaughter In Death Of 6-Year-Old</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 11th graf, `One of the ..., to UPDATE
with reax from Ms. Nussbaum, via her attorney.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserColor NY75, LaserPhotos NY74, NY67, NY68</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SAMUEL MAULL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A jury Monday convicted <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> of manslaughter in the beating death of his illegally adopted 6-year-old daughter, <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>, a death that refocused national attention on domestic violence. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> showed no emotion as each of the 12 jurors was polled on the verdict, which came at 6:38 p.m, on the eighth day of deliberations in the three-month-old trial. He was acquitted on the more serious charge of second-degree murder. The verdict culminated a case that touched the nation's conscience, with witnesses providing wrenching detail of the physical and emotional havoc wrought by spousal and child abuse _ and the failure of others to intercede <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>'s biological mother, <PERSON> Michele </PERSON> <PERSON> Launders </PERSON>, 27, said before the jury returned that `` the only verdict that would be justice for <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> is murder.'' After the verdict, she left the courtroom in tears and would not speak to reporters. She was sitting next to <PERSON> Graceann </PERSON> <PERSON> Smigiel </PERSON>, the grandmother of a young boy who was found in <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s apartment when police and <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> paramedics removed <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>'s comatose body the morning of Nov. 2, 1987. The boy, who also was illegally adopted by <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, has since been returned to his biological mother. The conviction on the charge of first-degree manslaughter carries a maximum sentence of 8 1-3 to 25 years. It was a charge that prosecutors at one time had considered dropping from the case. Sentencing was set for March 8. In acquitting <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> of murder, the jury apparently concluded that <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> meant to hurt <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> but not to kill her; a second-degree manslaughter conviction would have meant he did not mean to hurt her but showed reckless disregard for her life. District Attorney <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgenthau </PERSON>, who promised to ask for the maximum punishment, said the trial `` highlighted the dreadful problems that beset our city _ child abuse, drug abuse and family violence. All of us have a responsibility to work to ensure that similar tragedies do not re-occur.'' <LOCATION> Ira </LOCATION> <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s lawyer, said: `` We do not consider this -LRB- verdict -RRB- a win for <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> or a triumph for <PERSON> Joel </PERSON>.'' One of the jurors, <PERSON> Helena </PERSON> <PERSON> Barthell </PERSON>, 36, she argued in favor of convicting <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> of murder, said the jury had `` virtually ignored'' the testimony of <PERSON> Hedda </PERSON> <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>, <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s battered live-in companion of 12 years. Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>'s lawyer, <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Scheck </PERSON>, said she is `` relieved it's all over. He said she watched the verdict on television at the psychiatric facility in <LOCATION> Westchester </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, where she has lived since March 1988. `` The possibility of a hung jury was a very frightening prospect for her. She would have to go through this all again,'' he said. Public attention was riveted on the trial during Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>'s seven days of testimony last month Her story of abuse and psychological manipulation was broadcast live on <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s three television network affiliates and in part nationally on the Cable News Network. Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>, testifying under immunity from prosecution, said she was so dominated by <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> that she was unable to defend herself from virtually systematic beatings, or to protect the child, <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>. She also said she was unable to bring herself to summon medics promptly on Nov. 1, 1987, after <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> told her <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> was unconscious on the bathroom floor. The girl lay there nearly 12 hours by the time Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> called an ambulance; she died of brain damage in a hospital three days later. Defense lawyers claimed it was Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>, <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s live-in girlfriend, who fatally beat <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> out of jealousy over the attention <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> paid the child. Prosecutors _ pointing to Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>'s own severe injuries and deteriorated mental state _ said she was incapable of such an act `` She was a 45-year-old woman who appeared much older than her age,'' the emergency room doctor who examined Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> after her arrest testified at trial. `` She was chronically debilitated, malnourished, wasted.'' Nonetheless, state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothwax </PERSON> instructed the jury that it must consider Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> an accomplice in <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>'s death. As such, her testimony had to be supported by other evidence. It was the layers of tragedy in the <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> case that commanded public attention. One question was how Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>, a former children's book editor, could allow herself _ much less the child _ to sustain such damage. Another was how bruises on <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> could have been noticed by a student teacher at her elementary school and by neighbors, but failed to come to the attention of child welfare officials. Yet another issue was the ease with which <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> illegally gained custody of <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> and another child, 16-month old <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, from their unwed teen-age mothers. And at the center of the case were the unknown motivations of <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, a lawyer who was disbarred last fall for having falsely claimed a military exemption from the bar exam. He did not testify at the trial. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s lawyers denied that he ever beat <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>. Prosecutors and Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> told another story. Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> testified that on Nov. 1, 1987, he ordered her and the girl to eat hot peppers, then drink large amounts of water _ typical of the irrational behavior common in the household. Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> said that she was in the bathroom when <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> went into the bedroom to ask <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> if she could go out to dinner with him. About 6 or 6:30 p.m., he walked into the bathroom, holding <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>'s limp body. `` And I said, ` What happened?''' Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> testified. `` He said, ` What's the difference what happened? This is your child. Has n't this gone far enough?''' They put the unconscious child on the bathroom floor. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> then left for dinner, saying `` Do n't worry, just let her sleep,'' she testified. When <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> returned from dinner about 10 p.m., she said they smoked cocaine. It was then that he admitted hitting the girl, she testified. About 6 a.m., <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> said <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> had stopped breathing and tried to revive her, she said. They finally called 911 at 6:30 a.m., she said. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s lack of concern for the girl exhibited `` more than depraved indifference to human life,'' Assistant District Attorney <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Casolaro </PERSON> said at the trial. `` It was monumental indifference to human life.'' Staffers from <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vincent </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, many of them clearly hostile to <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, testified that he appeared unconcerned about <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>'s welfare and made distasteful comments when he was told she had brain damage. `` ` What you're saying is she's not going to be an Olympic swimmer,''' Dr. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Kilhenny </PERSON> quoted <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> as replying. <PERSON> Casolaro </PERSON> also said <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> gave differing versions of details of the events of the night of Nov. 1, including how <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> was bruised. The defense said the prosecution's case, built largely on circumstantial evidence, did not disprove every possibility except <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s guilt, as the law requires. <LOCATION> Ira </LOCATION> <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Adrian </PERSON> <PERSON> DiLuzio </PERSON>, <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s lawyers, sought at various times to explain <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>'s injuries by suggesting she had choked on her dinner, had fallen, had been struck by a classmate, had contracted <PERSON> Reye </PERSON>'s syndrome and had been killed by doctors who put a monitoring needle into her brain.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0121EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Romania     01-31 0215</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Romania,0220</SECOND>
<HEAD>London Protests ``Manhandling'' of Its Ambassador To Romania</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Romanian police `` manhandled'' <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s ambassador to that country as they prevented him from visiting a government critic who was under house arrest, the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> said. The Foreign Office on Monday summoned <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s ambassador, <PERSON> Stan </PERSON> <PERSON> Soare </PERSON>, to demand an apology for the incident in <LOCATION> Cluj </LOCATION> on Friday, when Ambassador <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Arbuthnott </PERSON> tried to deliver a letter to historian <PERSON> Doina </PERSON> <PERSON> Cornea </PERSON>. The ambassador, accompanied by his wife <PERSON> Vanessa </PERSON>, was physically stopped by police at the garden gate of Mrs. <PERSON> Cornea </PERSON>'s home and the letter was snatched from his grasp, the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> said. `` The ambassador was prevented from meeting, and was manhandled by the militiamen,'' a <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said. He spoke on condition of not being identified. Mrs. <PERSON> Cornea </PERSON> has been under house arrest since last fall, when she wrote a letter to the Western press protesting that Communist <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, under a policy of President <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>, was deliberately destroying villages and farming communities. Later Friday, British diplomat <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> was summoned to the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bucharest </LOCATION>, which protested that <PERSON> Arbuthnott </PERSON> `` tried to go down a one-way street,'' and had `` mistreated and insulted'' the police. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> rejected the Romanian version and `` a somewhat heated exchange ensued,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     01-31 0488</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0508</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Rain Man' Continues Dominance at Nation's Theaters</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HORN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Rain Man'' was moviegoers' favorite for the fifth-straight weekend, but another brotherly tale, `` Twins,'' dropped to fourth after being runnerup for four-consecutive weeks. `` Rain Man,'' starring <PERSON> Dustin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> as an autistic savant on the road with his manipulative brother <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruise </PERSON>, grossed $ 6.8 million at the nation's box offices last weekend, <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> said Monday. It was the second dose of good news this weekend for `` Rain Man,'' which collected two top Golden Globes: for best dramatic movie and best dramatic actor for <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>. `` Rain Man'' was followed by `` Three Fugitives,'' a new comedy starring <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Nolte </PERSON> and <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Short </PERSON> as outlaws trying a raise a young girl. The movie brought in $ 6.4 million. In third was `` Beaches,'' a poignant drama featuring <PERSON> Bette </PERSON> <PERSON> Midler </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Hershey </PERSON> as best friends, with $ 4.9 million. `` Twins,'' with <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> DeVito </PERSON> and <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwarzenegger </PERSON> playing brothers separated at birth, was next with $ 4.8 million. The movie had been finished second for the past four weeks and first the previous two weeks. Next was by the civil rights chronicle `` Mississippi Burning,'' which grossed $ 3.5 million. In sixth place was `` Working Girl,'' the Wall Street rags-to-riches tale, with sales of $ 3 million. `` Working Girl,'' starring <PERSON> Melanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON>, received four trophies at the Golden Globes, including best comic motion picture and best comic actress for <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON>. The detective spoof `` The Naked Gun: From the Files of Police Squad!'' finished in seventh with $ 2.9 million. `` The Accidental Tourist,'' a film adaptation of the celebrated <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyler </PERSON> novel, claimed eighth place with $ 2.6 million. In ninth was the new <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> drama `` Physical Evidence,'' with receipts of $ 1.8 million. The comedy `` Dirty Rotten Scoundrels'' finished 10th with $ 1.6 million. Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by Exhibitor Relations, with distributor, weekend gross, number of theater screens, average per screen, total gross and number of weeks in release. 1. `` Rain Man,'' <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Artists </ORGANIZATION>, $ 6.8 million, 1,563 screens, $ 4,370 per screen, $ 88.8 million, seven weeks. 2. `` Three Fugitives,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 6.4 million, 1,153 screens, $ 5,581 per screen, $ 6.4 million, one week. 3. `` Beaches,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 4.9 million, 1,097 screens, $ 4,503 per screen, $ 20.1 million, six weeks. 4. `` Twins,'' Universal, $ 4.8 million, 1,659 screens, $ 2,895 per screen, $ 86.5 million, eight weeks. 5. `` Mississippi Burning,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION>, $ 3.5 million, 1,058 screens, $ 3,350 per screen, $ 14.7 million, eight weeks. 6. `` Working Girl,'' 20th <ORGANIZATION> Century </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION>, $ 3 million, 1,149 screens, $ 2,615 per screen, $ 38.2 million, six weeks. 7. `` The Naked Gun,'' Paramount, $ 2.9 million, 1,501 screens, $ 1,910 per screen, $ 68.4 million, nine weeks. 8. `` The Accidental Tourist,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.6 million, 926 screens, $ 2,766 per screen, $ 21.8 million, six weeks. 9. `` Physical Evidence,'' <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.8 million, 691 screens, $ 2,572 per screen, $ 1.8 million, one week. 10. `` Dirty Rotten Scoundrels,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.6 million, 1,313 screens, $ 1,247 per screen, $ 36.4 million, seven weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Barenboim     01-31 0418</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Barenboim,0430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Head of Paris Orchestra Named Chicago Symphony Music Director</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SHERI PRASSO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sir <PERSON> Georg </PERSON> <PERSON> Solti </PERSON> is passing the baton as <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Symphony music director to <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Barenboim </PERSON>, who an orchestra member characterized as a first-string quarterback who `` can lead us to the Super Bowl.'' The 46-year-old Argentine-born Israeli conductor and pianist was named Monday to succeed <PERSON> Solti </PERSON>, who is retiring at the end of next season after two decades as the orchestra's conductor. <PERSON> Barenboim </PERSON>, fired recently from the newly formed Opera-Bastille in a power struggle, will continue as director of the <ORGANIZATION> Paris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION>, a position he has held for 15 years, said <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphony </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Dewey </PERSON>. He and <PERSON> Solti </PERSON> will work together until <PERSON> Solti </PERSON>'s retirement. `` Now we have two first-string quarterbacks, and either one can lead us to the Super Bowl,'' said timpanist <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Koss </PERSON>, chairman of the Orchestra Members' Committee. `` We've played for maestro <PERSON> Barenboim </PERSON> many times and know he is truly a world-class conductor, absolutely first-rate.'' `` In choosing <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Barenboim </PERSON>, I'm completely confident that we have made the best possible choice for our orchestra,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orchestral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said. `` With his infectious enthusiasm, his commitment to excellence and his exceptional credentials, I have no doubt that he will build on his previous accomplishments as well as those of the orchestra.'' The 76-year-old Hungarian-born <PERSON> Solti </PERSON>, who has won a record-high 26 <ORGANIZATION> Grammys </ORGANIZATION> and has been <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> music director since 1969, said he had the `` health and energy'' to continue here, but felt it was important to hand the baton over to someone younger. `` It is with the greatest pleasure that I welcome the appointment of <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Barenboim </PERSON> as my successor,'' said <PERSON> Solti </PERSON>, who also was <PERSON> Barenboim </PERSON>'s predecessor at the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> Orchestra. `` I have known him and have been closely involved in his development as a conductor for many years and he is my first choice.'' <PERSON> Barenboim </PERSON> will be the ninth music director of the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphony </ORGANIZATION>, which was founded in 1891. He will begin his tenure Sept. 1, 1991. `` The past 20 years of music making with the orchestra as a guest conductor have taught me to admire not only its unique qualities but also its members' devotion to music,'' <PERSON> Barenboim </PERSON> said from <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. Terms of the three-year contract call for <PERSON> Barenboim </PERSON> to conduct at least 12 weeks of concerts in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> each season. He also will lead all major tours for three to four weeks each year, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said. The salary was not announced.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BusDrivers-Manners     01-31 0409</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bus Drivers-Manners,0421</SECOND>
<HEAD>Urban Bus Company Sends Drivers To Charm School</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DINA KYRIAKIDOU</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> ATHENS </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> _ In a bid to control hot Mediterranean tempers and teach them a smattering of English for the benefit of tourists, <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> bus drivers are being sent to charm school. The $ 4.3 million program is aimed at improving the image of the capital's public transportation system, which faces stiff competition from taxis whose cost is among the cheapest in the world. Classes such as `` Driver and Communication with the Public'' and `` English for Drivers'' are part of the 15-day courses for the staff of the semi-private <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>. `` The classes will help the driver control his Mediterranean temperament ... but passengers must also understand that it's not the driver's fault when the bus is late,'' said <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON> <PERSON> Kolas </PERSON>, a spokesman for the Union of Bus Drivers. Quarrels often break out between bus drivers and passengers irked by waiting for buses or when riders insist on getting off where there is no bus stop. Because of the chaotic state of public transportation _ bus routes and timetables are rarely available _ tourists often take taxis, which cost about $ 2 for a three-mile ride. The bus fare is 20 cents. <PERSON> Kolas </PERSON> said drivers' manners are n't helped by the aggravation of navigating the capital's notoriously congested streets. According to the transit company's chairman, <PERSON> Vassilis </PERSON> <PERSON> Xeomeritis </PERSON>, about 3,500 of the 5,000 bus drivers are very experienced but `` older people with almost no education. `` Our drivers could use some retraining ... they must understand that passengers are our customers and that it's the driver's duty to serve the public,'' <PERSON> Xenomeritis </PERSON> said. The corporation's 1,200 buses cover the whole of <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> _ a 120-square-mile area. With only one subway line crossing the city, more than 70 percent of Athenians commute by bus daily. A bus driver who would n't let his name be used said the public should also `` learn how to behave'' and use the transportation system properly. `` Passengers sometimes ask us unbelievable things,'' he said. `` We try to explain something to them and they are already so upset that they turn around and swear at us.'' About 1,500 drivers are scheduled for the course in 1989. The rest will take it in the next couple of years, said <PERSON> Christos </PERSON> <PERSON> Halazias </PERSON>, a transportation company spokesman. The corporation received almost half its financial backing for the training program from the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HaitianRefugees     01-31 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Haitian Refugees,0187</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nearly 150 Haitians Interdicted Off Miami Beach</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 150 Haitian refugees crammed aboard a sailboat were detained Monday after they were intercepted eight miles off the entrance to the Port of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, the first such boatload this year, authorities said. The group reportedly included two pregnant women and a child, said <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Starks </PERSON>. A tugboat spotted the wood-hulled vessel around 2:30 p.m. and the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> immediately dispatched a patrol boat to the scene, just east of Government Cut on the southern end of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>. The 40-foot sailboat apparently was not in jeopardy of capsizing, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said, and two Haitian males suffering from severe dehydration were airlifted late Monday to <ORGANIZATION> Jackson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> for treatment. Late Monday, 149 Haitian refugees and one from the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> wer transferred to two <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> cutters and were being interviewed by immigration officials. The interviews to determine whether they would be brought ashore or returned to their homeland would be made once all the interviews were completed, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0741 01-31 0868</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0741,0896</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: ADDS Fitzgerald; Separates moved for AMs as a0621 on Da Costa,
a0595 on Virally, as a0732 on de Bourbon and as a0416 on Fitzgerald.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Morton Da Costa</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DANBURY, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Da </PERSON> <PERSON> Costa </PERSON>, 74, who directed some of Broadway's biggest hits in the 1950s including `` The Music Man,'' `` Auntie Mame,'' `` No Time for Sergeants'' and `` Plain and Fancy,'' died Sunday of a heart attack. <PERSON> Da </PERSON> <PERSON> Costa </PERSON> began his Broadway career as an actor. He had a small role in the original 1942 production of <PERSON> Thornton </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>'s `` The Skin of Our Teeth'' and understudied <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> <PERSON> Clift </PERSON> in the comedy. <PERSON> Da </PERSON> <PERSON> Costa </PERSON> also played Osric in <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>' 1945 production of `` Hamlet.'' He directed revivals of such plays as `` The Alchemist,'' `` She Stoops to Conquer'' and `` Dream Girl.'' After directing the national tour of the comedy hit `` Sabrina Fair'' in the early 1950s, <PERSON> Da </PERSON> <PERSON> Costa </PERSON> had four big successes in a row on Broadway, starting with `` Plain and Fancy.'' In 1955, he directed `` No Time for Sergeants'' and `` Auntie Mame'' in 1956. The following year, <PERSON> Da </PERSON> <PERSON> Costa </PERSON> had his biggest Broadway success with `` The Music Man.'' It ran for more than four years and won a Tony award as best musical. Among <PERSON> Da </PERSON> <PERSON> Costa </PERSON>'s other musicals were `` Saratoga,'' `` <LOCATION> Saratoga </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Trunk </LOCATION>,'' `` To Broadway With Love'' and `` <PERSON> Maggie </PERSON> <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Alfonso de Bourbon</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEAVER CREEK, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prince <PERSON> Alfonso </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Bourbon </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, a cousin of King <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON>, was killed Monday in a ski accident on the men's downhill course as it was being prepared for the World Alpine Ski Championships. He was 52. <PERSON> Alfonso </PERSON>, <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Cadiz </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Anjou </LOCATION>, was not in the line of succession to the <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> throne. He served as his country as ambassador to <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> from 1970 to 1973 and as a lieutenant in the Spanish air force. <PERSON> Alfonso </PERSON> was a member of the Council of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ski </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> and former president of the Spanish <ORGANIZATION> Ski </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION>. He formerly was married to <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> <PERSON> Franco </PERSON>, granddaughter of the late Spanish dictator <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Franco </PERSON>, but they were divorced several years ago. His father was the elder brother of the father of King <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON>, and they both were sons of King <PERSON> Alfonso </PERSON> <PERSON> XIII </PERSON>, who abdicated the Spanish throne in 1931.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Michel Virally</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>THE HAGUE, Netherlands (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Virally </PERSON>, an arbitrator at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-Iran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Claims </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribunal </ORGANIZATION> and a world renowned authority on international law, died Saturday at age 67. Virally had been one of the three third-nation arbitrators at the tribunal, which was established by the 1981 Algiers Accords. There were three American and three Iranian arbitrators on the nine-man Hague panel, which is charged with settling billions of dollars of financial disputes between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> arising out of the 1979 Iranian revolution. Virally, who took up his tribunal post July 1, 1985, was a professor at the <ORGANIZATION> Graduate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. He also had served as professor of international law and head of the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organizations </ORGANIZATION> at the university.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Richmond Crinkley</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RICHMOND, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Crinkley </PERSON>, who co-produced `` The Elephant Man'' on Broadway and later was executive director of <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Vivian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beaumont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Theater </ORGANIZATION>, died Sunday of bone marrow cancer at the age of 49. <PERSON> Crinkley </PERSON> began his theater career in 1969 in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, as director of programs at the <ORGANIZATION> Folger </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shakespeare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION> and producer at the <ORGANIZATION> Folger </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Theater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, presenting such plays as `` Total Eclipse,'' `` Happy Days'' and `` Subject to Fits.'' <PERSON> Crinkley </PERSON> later became executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Theater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> and producer of its theater program at <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peter </LOCATION>'s Church in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. He first presented `` The Elephant Man'' in 1978. It moved to Broadway in April 1979 and won <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Critics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circle </ORGANIZATION> awards as best play. Among the other shows <PERSON> Crinkley </PERSON> produced on Broadway were `` Tintypes'' in 1980 and `` Passion'' in 1983.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Pegeen Fitzgerald</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Pegeen </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>, part of the first husband-wife radio team whose broadcasts for half a century turned her life into a public soap opera and entertained generations, died of cancer Monday. Mrs. <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>'s sister, <PERSON> Cristine </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharkey </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, would not reveal her correct age. <PERSON> Mrs </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> career began in 1937 with a radio station owned by a <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, department store where she worked. Later that year, a WOR-AM executive offered to put a microphone in her office at the store and she soon was doing a half-hour show during her lunch hour. When <PERSON> Mrs </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> caught pneumonia, management asked if she could go on air from her hospital bed and later from her home while she was convalescing. Because she did not want her announcer, <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, to see her in a bathrobe, she asked if her husband, <PERSON> Edward </PERSON>, could take his place. The husband-wife combination became a radio first. <PERSON> Eleanor </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> once went to their apartment to watch the show. The couple argued on the air about such things as bills and child-rearing, with <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> becoming so angry during one breakfast show that he went back to bed, leaving his wife to finish. He died in 1982.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0230EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-North     01-31 1179</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North,1180</SECOND>
<HEAD>North's Images: Decorated Marine, Rogue Operator</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Iran-Contra Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE BYRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 He is a man of conflicting images. A patriot, seven rows of ribbons on his uniform, charged with crimes against the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Barring new delay, <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Laurence </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>, 45, goes on trial Tuesday, facing a dozen cover-up and tax counts stemming from his role in the secret sale of arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and the diversion of some of that money to the Nicaraguan rebels. The jury will decide, in the end, whether this former lieutenant colonel and junior staff member of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> was true to his government and his mission, or whether his deceits, principally to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, were the designs of a rogue operating outside of law and <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> order. Along the way, the nation may learn more about the worst foreign policy debacle of <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s presidency. And about how <PERSON> North </PERSON> came to run some of the administration's riskiest ventures from a cluttered room, No. 392, in the Old Executive Office Building next door to the White House. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> tried for months to unravel those mysteries. But, like the 1987 commission headed by incoming <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON>, congressional panels left many questions unanswered. Meanwhile, in nationally televised hearings, a defiant <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> emerged from his shadowy world, one of pseudonyms and codes and furtive border crossings, to confront his legislative tormentors. `` <PERSON> Ollie </PERSON> stood up there, took the heat, and the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people in every bar in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and every bowling alley in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and every little home said, ` Hey, this guy believes in something, and I can identify with it,''' said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> last December. North's bravura performance, and his subsequent whirlwind of $ 25,000 speeches to cheering conservative groups around the country, revealed just one of his many sides. He has always been `` Ollie'' to his White House co-workers and the American right. But to his brothers and sisters, his high-school chums back in his hometown of <LOCATION> Philmont </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, he remains <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>. To surviving members of his combat platoon in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, he is `` Blue,'' leader of `` Blue's Bastards.'' In other travels, he has been `` <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>,'' or `` Mr. <PERSON> Goode </PERSON>,'' or `` Mr. <PERSON> Johns </PERSON>,'' or `` <PERSON> Steelhammer </PERSON>.'' Another code name may be most telling: `` Blank Check.'' That was the term assigned to the private, inter-office computer communications network between <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> and his superior, former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> Adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>. The Tower commission found that the creation of `` Blank Check'' coincided with the initial shipment of anti-tank missiles to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, 14 months before the scheme blew up in the administration's face in late 1986. According to <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s first national security adviser, <PERSON> North </PERSON> was brought to the <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION> in 1981 `` to handle easels and carry the charts.'' Yet he became, in a matter of months, the <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION>'s chief troubleshooter, responsible for Central American and terrorism issues, and played a vital role in some of the administration's most daring foreign exploits They included the invasion of <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION> in 1983; initial arms shipments by the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> to the Nicaraguan rebels, also in 1983; the mining of three harbors in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> in early 1984; a crackdown on the death squads in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and the organization of free elections there; the interception of an Egyptian airliner carrying the hijackers of the Italian cruise ship <PERSON> Achille </PERSON> <PERSON> Lauro </PERSON>, and the bombing raid upon <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> in 1986. Part of <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s ascendancy, no doubt, can be attributed to his own drive and fervor. `` If there was a loose ball,'' said retired Maj. Gen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Singlaub </PERSON>, a key player in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>'s efforts to aid the Contras, `` <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> would grab it and run with it.'' As a youth, he was kept on a tight leash. His father, <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> colonel who won a Silver Star in World War II, worked long hours at a family wool mill before it fell victim to polyester and he switched to teaching history. His mother, <PERSON> Ann </PERSON>, would whistle for the kids to come in every evening at 5 p.m. for dinner. Family ritual included a discussion of world events before the table was cleared. In school, he ran track and was in the chorus, chess, drama and science clubs as well as the student council. The girls voted him best-looking. North intended to follow his father, who died three years ago, into teaching, and enrolled at the state college at <LOCATION> Brockport </LOCATION> as an English major _ not pre-med at <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION> as he later claimed _ and joined the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserves </ORGANIZATION> as an officer trainee. After spending the summer at <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lejeune </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> he was a convert to the Corps. His appointment to the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> came after his sophomore year at <LOCATION> Brockport </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> North </PERSON> had to start over as a plebe. Then, before he'd really settled in, he was in a car wreck, suffering severe knee and back injuries. He boxed as a southpaw, and in the intramural ranks he made it into the finals against a highly favored <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>, later to become a decorated combat veteran and a best-selling novelist. North won again, on points. After his graduation, a review board threatened to dismiss him because of his auto injuries. North made the board look at the film of his fight against <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>. He got his commission. Soon after <PERSON> North </PERSON> and <PERSON> Betsy </PERSON> <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> were married in a formal military service, he was shipped out, in December 1968, to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. He was `` all guns, guts and glory,'' according to <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrod </PERSON>, a fellow ex-Marine officer whom <PERSON> North </PERSON> credits with saving his life on the battlefield. Once, <PERSON> North </PERSON> was knocked off a tank rocked by enemy fire, and, despite broken ribs and a punctured lung, rose up to kill the enemy gunner with a grenade. That got him a Bronze Star. Other awards followed. But <PERSON> North </PERSON>, in recounting his <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> experiences, has sometimes seemed to exaggerate his record. He has testified that his decorations included `` several'' purple hearts; military records show two. He headed a platoon of 40 men, but said in court that he was a company commander `` in the Special Operations Force.'' Again, no record of it. He has said in court that he was in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> from 1968 through early 1970 `` and then again in 1971,'' but the corps says it has no record of an extended first tour or second tour. North did return to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, on his own time when word arrived that <PERSON> Herrod </PERSON> had been charged with war crimes in the killing of women and children. <PERSON> Herrod </PERSON> eventually was acquitted. While the case dragged, <PERSON> North </PERSON> was going off voluntarily to fight in the bush. After tours at <LOCATION> Quantico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, and on <LOCATION> Okinawa </LOCATION>, he wound up with a desk at <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> headquarters. He worked 18 hours a day. Meanwhile, <PERSON> North </PERSON> and wife <PERSON> Betsy </PERSON> were going about the business of raising their four children. Something finally snapped. North wound up in <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Naval </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> for 22 days, diagnosed as suffering `` delayed battle stress.'' Once again, he overcame his medical difficulties, and was cleared for duty.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0159EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HealthCare Bjt   01-31 0691</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Health Care, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Commission Recommends Tax to Insure Those Without Coverage</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Employers and all but the poorest <LOCATION> Americans </LOCATION> would be taxed to finance a national health care system extending medical insurance to the estimated 37 million who lack coverage, under a plan proposed by a commission including three former presidents. The proposal encourages continued reliance on private health insurance provided through the workplace, but calls for a new program to provide universal access to basic medical services. Costs would be spread among employers and all Americans above 150 percent of poverty level. The plan offered Monday is designed to extend medical coverage to all Americans, stem the growth of medical expenses which now stand at $ 550 billion annually, and improve the quality of medical care nationwide, said the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION>, which worked 2 -LCB- years preparing its proposal. `` If we continue the present trend, the $ 550 billion will double in six years and triple in 12 years,'' said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> congressman from <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> who co-chaired the commission with former <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>, a Republican. The commission also is headed by three former presidents _ <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> _ who served as honorary co-chairmen. The commission was financed by 38 corporations, unions and foundations. The commission called its plan `` eminently fair,'' and estimated it would add about $ 15 billion to the $ 550 billion already being spent on health care annually. `` It is not something that will blow us over as a nation,'' said <PERSON> Uwe </PERSON> <PERSON> Reinhardt </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> professor of economics and member of the commission. Members of the commission are to meet soon with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration officials and members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to go over the recommendations. Under the proposed system, all Americans would be covered by a basic package of medical services, which would be the minimum coverage for all private health insurance plans and for a publicly funded benefits pool. Many workers would continue to get privately financed coverage as an employment benefit, with the employer paying most or all of the premium, and they could add to that coverage if they wanted. The federal Medicare insurance program for older and disabled Americans also would continue. Everyone else would be covered by the pool called the Universal Access program. Recipients of Medicaid, the federal health insurance program for the poor, would be covered by the new program. The Universal Access pool would be financed by all employers and by all individuals not covered by Medicare who have incomes above 150 percent of the poverty level. The schedule of fees would be designed to encourage employers to offer coverage to employees and improve coverage under some existing plans. `` There is strong incentive to keep the pool of people falling into the public system as small as it can be,'' <PERSON> Reinhardt </PERSON> said. Under the current system, the millions who are uninsured, though they can not pay for their health care, still do receive medical services, he noted. Their cost, however, is borne largely by hospitals and doctors that provide the care, and it inflates insurance premiums paid by companies for their workers, he said. `` There would be some shifting of costs from large firms who do offer generous health insurance packages to those who in some sense freeload and do not offer their employees any health insurance and thereby benefit. Their employees are implicitly covered anyhow and big business picks up the tab,'' <PERSON> Reinhardt </PERSON> said. Under the proposed system, employers who do n't provide a minimum level of health insurance coverage to their full-time workers would have to pay a fee for each worker not covered. In addition, all employers and employees would have to pay a fee based on employees' income The rates would be determined once a national package of basic services was developed. The commission also proposed a $ 500 million-a-year research program funded with the health care fees to study the effectiveness of current medical procedures. Such research could reduce inappropriate care and waste while saving at least $ 1.5 billion a year by 1993, the commission said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890131-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-31-89 0158EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     01-31 0966</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1003</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MYRTLE BEACH, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Artist <PERSON> Jasper </PERSON> <PERSON> Johns </PERSON>, whose works command millions at auction, has been inducted into his native state's hall of fame. <PERSON> Johns </PERSON>, an Allendale native considered a father of pop art, is the first artist among 39 people enshrined in the <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fame </ORGANIZATION> at the <LOCATION> Myrtle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> Convention Center. Also inducted Monday was <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> <PERSON> Poinsett </PERSON>, best known for bringing the Christmas plant that bears his name to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Johns </PERSON> was overseas, but his mother, <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Riley </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, attended Monday's ceremonies. She said his paintings' high prices are `` wonderful for him,'' adding: `` But, what I'm so glad about is he's alive to know about it himself So many artists did n't know they ever became famous.'' <PERSON> Johns </PERSON>, 58, is best known for his paintings of familiar objects such as flags and numbers. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Vogt </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Archives </ORGANIZATION> and History, described <PERSON> Poinsett </PERSON>, who lived from 1779 to 1851, as `` a renaissance man'' _ a congressman, state lawmaker, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Works </ORGANIZATION> and ambassador to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. It was during his service in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> that <PERSON> Poinsett </PERSON> brought back the poinsettia.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>RADNOR, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Miss America <PERSON> Vanessa </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said she was surprised by all the publicity the <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION> movie `` The Sex Tapes'' received during filming. The film in which she plays a prostitute surrounded by sadomasochism is really just a detective movie with a kinky background, she says in this week's TV Guide. `` Well I guess it's a combination of the subject matter and the cast,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, who lost her Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> crown in 1984 after nude photos of her were published in Penthouse magazine. She said she had no qualms about her role. `` You know, it's amazing how many people have asked me whether I have a problem playing a hooker,'' she said. `` No, I do n't. My character's motivation is good. She's a girl on the run for her life.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, who portrays the hard-nosed but flashily dressed `` Miami Vice'' undercover cop, has apprehended a suspect in real life. He nabbed an intruder in a hotel room as the man rifled through the purse of his fiancee, actress <PERSON> Melanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON>, police said Monday. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, 39, discovered the intruder when he and Miss <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> opened the door to their room at the Hotel Bel-Air on Sunday night, said police Capt. <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Mayes </PERSON>. The purse contained expensive jewelry, but the couple surprised the man before anything was taken, <PERSON> Mayes </PERSON> said. `` <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> took the suspect into custody and held him until hotel security officers could detain him until police arrived,'' <PERSON> Mayes </PERSON> said. Arrested and booked for investigation of attempted burglary was <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, 34, no relation to the actor, <PERSON> Mayes </PERSON> said. Miss <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON>, 31, received a Golden Globe award Saturday night for best comic actress for her performance in the movie `` Working Girl.'' She and <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> were married previously and have decided to remarry.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SALT LAKE CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kim </PERSON>, the mentally handicapped savant whose life provided the initial inspiration for the film `` Rain Man,'' is urging the <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> to generously finance programs for the handicapped. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON>, 37, whose real name remains confidential, spoke to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Monday and demonstrated remarkable mental skills that allow him to recite long passages from books and films he has seen, or compute the correct day of the week for virtually any date on the calendar. `` The work of love is really important. We need lots more money to carry our work on together. We want you to support us in our workshops,'' <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> said. The occasion for <PERSON> Kim </PERSON>'s remarks was the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s passage of a resolution honoring him for `` being a role model for other handicapped persons, and for helping to educate the public regarding the handicapped and their rightful place in society.'' The filmmakers also used as their model <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> savant with skills similar to <PERSON> Kim </PERSON>'s. In researching his role as a handicapped savant, actor <PERSON> Dustin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> met with <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> and studied his movements and mannerisms.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
