<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 2339EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-DrugShooting     10-23 0250</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Drug Shooting,0255</SECOND>
<HEAD>DEA Agent Shoots and Kills Suspect in Midtown New York</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY39, 40</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOSEPH NEFF</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A suspect in a drug investigation was shot to death in Rockefeller Center by federal agents Monday after a drug buy went sour and the man drove off, dragging an agent down the street, authorities said. The <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> agent, who rolled off the car before it crashed into the back of a bus, suffered minor injuries, officials said. No one else was hurt. The violence occurred around 7 p.m. on 50th Street in Rockefeller Center, an area popular with tourists. More than 100 people watched as the suspect was handcuffed, then treated for a chest wound on the ground next to the car. The suspect was dead when taken to <LOCATION> Bellevue </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, said hospital administrator <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Schectman </PERSON>. The man was not immediately identified. According to <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, another undercover agent had arranged to buy 4 pounds of pure cocaine from the suspect. Once the agent saw the cocaine, a signal was given and other officers approached the car to arrest the man, <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> said. As they identified themselves, the suspect drove off, she said. An agent got caught in the car and was dragged along for about 100 feet. The agent fired two shots and rolled off the car into the street as another agent fired at least one shot, <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> said. The suspect was not armed, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Novello-AIDS     10-23 0307</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Novello-AIDS,0315</SECOND>
<HEAD>Doctor Recommended for Surgeon General Warns AIDS Is Family Disease</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KELLEY SHANNON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN ANTONIO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A physician recommended for the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Surgeon General's post says the nation must begin thinking about AIDS as a disease that strikes whole families, not just adults. `` We have to think of the children who will be sick,'' Dr. <PERSON> Antonia </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Novello </PERSON> said Monday. `` ... we also have to think of the children who will be orphaned when the parents die. It's a family context. If we think of AIDS in a family context, I think we will be much more forceful.'' <PERSON> Novello </PERSON>, 45, has been recommended by Dr. <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, secretary of <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, to succeed Dr. <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> as surgeon general. She is deputy director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Child </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Novello </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, has yet to be nominated by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. She spoke to about 500 people from 15 states attending a symposium on health career opportunities for Hispanics. The fact that she has been recommended for the job, <PERSON> Novello </PERSON> said, sends a message that the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is interested in recruiting minorities for powerful positions. `` It's an honor for me, and for being Hispanic and for being a woman,'' she said at a news conference. <PERSON> Novello </PERSON>, who chairs the <ORGANIZATION> Pediatric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Task </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> for AIDS, said health officials must obtain the `` true number'' of children infected with the HIV virus. The HIV virus causes acquired immune deficiency syndrome. The task force estimates that by 1991, 10,000 to 20,000 children will be infected with the virus, and 3,000 youngsters will have the disease. `` However, it is feasible to believe that there are many more children infected,'' she said, adding that not all infected children have been tested.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BackYardBody     10-23 0311</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Back Yard Body,0319</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Buries Friend's Body in Parents' Back Yard</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAT MILTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAYVILLE, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A young man panicked and buried a friend in his parents' back yard after the friend died in his car, then agonized for a week before telling his mother, police said Monday. An autopsy was conducted on the body of <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Istvan </PERSON>, 28, of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fairfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, said <LOCATION> Suffolk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> police Lt. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Gierasch </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gierasch </PERSON> said there would be no decision on whether to charge <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Montheard </PERSON>, a 24-year-old house painter from <LOCATION> Danbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, until <PERSON> Montheard </PERSON> had been interviewed and autopsy results were in. `` So far everything he has told us seems to be holding up,'' <PERSON> Gierasch </PERSON> said. The death and burial came to light Sunday night, when <PERSON> Montheard </PERSON> telephoned his mother, <PERSON> Virginia </PERSON> <PERSON> Eckstein </PERSON>, said the family attorney, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrnes </PERSON>. <PERSON> Montheard </PERSON> told her he had buried <PERSON> Istvan </PERSON> in her back yard in this <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> city of about 15,000 people 65 miles east of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. The police were notified and they found <PERSON> Istvan </PERSON>'s body in a 3-foot-deep grave covered with leaves behind the <PERSON> Eckstein </PERSON> home. According to <PERSON> Byrnes </PERSON>, <PERSON> Istvan </PERSON> fell asleep in <LOCATION> Montheard </LOCATION>'s car when they went out with another friend after work Oct. 13. <PERSON> Montheard </PERSON> and the other friend left <PERSON> Istvan </PERSON> alone in the car for a little while, <PERSON> Byrnes </PERSON> said. When they returned, they found him dead. `` He apparently had vomited and became asphyxiated on his own vomit,'' <PERSON> Byrnes </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Montheard </PERSON> and the friend, who has not been identified by <PERSON> Byrnes </PERSON> or police, threw a blanket over <PERSON> Istvan </PERSON>'s body, drove to <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> early the next morning, and buried it in his mother and stepfather's yard. If <PERSON> Montheard </PERSON>'s story holds up, the only charge he could possibly face would be unlawful disposal of a body, a misdemeanor violation of state health law, <PERSON> Gierasch </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Colombia-Media     10-23 0935</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Colombia-Media,0965</SECOND>
<HEAD>Colombian Journalists in Constant Peril from Drug Barons</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM WELLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOGOTA, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Every time I kiss my wife and little boy goodbye, I hold them a little longer and little tighter,'' a reporter says. In the last eight years, 45 employees of <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s news media have been murdered, eight since the government war on cocaine cartels began nine weeks ago. Drug gangs have blown up two newspapers and tried to bomb two radio stations. Every day, in print and on the air, the traffickers are faced with tough editorials and reports of police or army raids on their ranches, arrests, destruction of cocaine labs and, by their side, assassinations and bombings. In the forefront of the battle has been the 102-year-old <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> daily <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Espectador </ORGANIZATION>, whose publisher, <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cano </PERSON>, was killed by the drug lords two years ago. The paper called <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s congress a pack of cowards this month because some members favored negotiations with the traffickers and opposed extraditing Colombians to face narcotics charges in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. A car bomb exploded outside the paper's office Sept. 2, causing $ 2.5 million in damage and nearly causing it to close. <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Cano </PERSON>, brother of the slain publisher, said last week newspapers in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and other countries had offered $ 1 million in aid. He said <PERSON> El </PERSON> <PERSON> Espectador </PERSON> would not take gifts, but would accept the money as a 15-year loan free of interest. Drug traffickers realize murder and bombing wo n't silence <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Espectador </LOCATION>, and they have begun threatening advertisers, <PERSON> Cano </PERSON> said, causing a decline in advertising volume of 25-30 percent. `` The threats keep coming by telephone,'' he said, and many of <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Espectador </ORGANIZATION>'s 1,200 workers say they have been threatened with death. Gunmen on a motorcycle killed two employes Oct. 10 in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, base of the most notorious cartel. The paper closed its <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> offices and <PERSON> Cano </PERSON> said distribution there became impossible because of threats to delivery boys, drivers of delivery trucks and even newsstands. `` It unnerves me every time I hear a motorcycle come up behind me,'' an <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Espectador </ORGANIZATION> columnist said. Assassins riding double on motorcycles are a favorite weapon of the traffickers, but one <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Espectador </ORGANIZATION> reporter was killed by gunmen who burst into his home, and a radio reporter was shot down by killers waiting in shadows outside his house. <ORGANIZATION> Vanguardia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION>, a newspaper in the northwestern city of <LOCATION> Bucaramanga </LOCATION>, also has been a target. A car bomb exploded outside its plant Oct. 16, destroying 80 percent of the facilities and killing four people. It published a slim edition the next day, including news of the drug war. Executive editor <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> daily <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tiempo </ORGANIZATION>, the main competitor of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Espectador </LOCATION>, said: `` I'm afraid there will be dark days for another two years. Never in the history of <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> has there been such a dangerous and grave threat as the press is suffering through now.'' <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> worked for <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tiempo </ORGANIZATION> when its plant and <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Espectador </LOCATION>'s were burned in 1948, at the beginning of a civil war that lasted seven years and took 250,000 lives A military dictator seized both papers in 1955 when they refused to submit material to military censors or stop publishing stories about demonstrations agaist the regime. Of the threat from drug traffickers, <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> said: `` It is awful, not knowing where the enemy is. No one knows when, how or where they might strike.'' <PERSON> El </PERSON> <PERSON> Tiempo </PERSON>, yet to be attacked, carries front-page stories daily about the anti-drug war and has published editorials encouraging the government. At least eight leading journalists have left the country because of threats from the traffickers. Among them are two <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> graduates associated with <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tiempo </ORGANIZATION> _ part-owner <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Samper </PERSON> <PERSON> Pizano </PERSON>, who led the investigative reporting team, and managing editor <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON>, son of publisher <PERSON> Hernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON>. Others who have left are <PERSON> Fabio </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Caballero </PERSON> of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Espectador </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Alberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Aguire </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> daily <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mundo </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Ligia </PERSON> <PERSON> Riveros </PERSON> of the weekly news magazine <ORGANIZATION> Cromos </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Mauricio </PERSON> <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON>, director of the TV news program `` 24 Hours,'' and <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>, director of the program `` 7 o'clock News.'' Many who remain tell of looking over their shoulders constantly while walking on the street, keeping an eye on the rear view mirror while driving, in case a motorcycle approaches, and wondering whether someone is waiting when they arrive home. Some threats are telephoned to wives. A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> reporter's wife said she and her 10-year-old son have been threatened several times and she worries every day _ especially if the school bus bringing him home is a bit late, because three schools have been bombed. She does not let her son play outside, movies are out because a bomb went off in a theater, and there have been no trips to shopping centers since a car bomb was found and defused outside the city's largest one. The family stocks up on groceries to reduce the number of trips to supermarkets, several of which have been bombed. They gave up eating out because a bomb wrecked a restaurant, and fear of the darkened streets in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, a city of 6 million people, has nearly ended their social life. `` I hear a motorcycle or a car slowing down as it goes by the house and I wonder if this is it,'' the reporter's wife said. Since the crackdown began, 164 bombs have killed 16 people and wounded 195. `` I think about how easy it would be to throw one through our windows,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-AbortionPolitics     10-23 0667</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion Politics,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Abortion Bill Veto Keeps Issue Alive</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s veto of a bill expanding federally financed abortions promises to keep alive an emotional issue Republican candidates suddenly wish would fade away before this fall's off-year elections. In races for governor of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and for mayor of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, Republican candidates are doing their best to keep the debate away from abortion, an issue that now appears to be helping their Democratic opponents. `` There's no question this is going to hurt the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>,'' Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON>, R-Ore., said after <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s veto Saturday `` The issue is very much alive in the country. This is an issue that threatens to divide the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> coalition,'' added <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> consultant <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON>. Lawmakers and lobbyists who back abortion rights see little hope of overriding the veto, but they say they will mount an effort in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> anyway. `` Clearly we'll try to override. Clearly, that's probably not going to happen, so he wins,'' a disheartened Rep. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, D-Colo., said after Saturday's veto The abortion funding expansion was attached to a $ 157 billion spending bill. <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON> said on <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <ORGANIZATION> Evans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Novak </PERSON>'' show that if the override fails, lawmakers should pass the spending bill again and send it back to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The bill <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> vetoed Saturday had passed the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> by a decisive 67-31 margin, but it squeaked through the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> 216-206, far short of the two-thirds vote necessary for an override. The measure, which <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> sent to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> last week despite his pledge to veto it, would permit poor women who are victims of rape and incest to obtain abortions paid by Medicaid. That covers a relatively small group, by most estimates. Yet its passage, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s public anguish before announcing his veto plans, have given it broader symbolic importance while compounding difficulty for right-to-life candidates who find polls shifting against them. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, Republican <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Courter </PERSON> has been accused of waffling on abortion and trails Democrat <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Florio </PERSON>. <PERSON> Courter </PERSON> has tried to push the campaign onto the issues of crime, drugs, taxes and automobile insurance. `` We would prefer the race to be fought on other, traditional issues,'' says <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON>, <PERSON> Courter </PERSON>'s campaign manager. In <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> won the Republican primary with a tough anti-abortion position but has been pounded for that position by Democrat <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, who reversed a deficit in published polls while his abortion-rights ads were running. <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> responded by attacking <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>'s character and past record on crime. `` It's our responsibility to get another issue out there, and that's what you'll see from <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Michele </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governors </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` We have to demonstrate very clearly that abortion is an issue but it is not the only issue,'' adds <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Hildebrand </PERSON>, <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>'s press secretary National Republican strategists acknowledge privately, however, that the abortion issue is proving a problem for some of their candidates who have staked out firm anti-abortion stands. While that once seemed a safe political position, polls show <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> candidates are losing some voters because of the abortion issue _ primarily younger voters and women. The equation changed with the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s decision last summer giving states more room to regulate abortions. That gave the issue increased relevance and raised the prospect in voters' minds that abortion rights could be restricted. `` In order to retrieve the Republican female vote, which we are losing, we have to focus on other issues that voters care about _ like child care, the environment,'' said one Republican strategist, who spoke only on condition of anonymity. These Republicans hope that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s veto on the Medicaid abortion bill wo n't be seen by most voters in state and congressional races as directly relevant to the question of maintaining abortion rights. But they acknowledge that to the extent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s veto keeps public attention focused on abortion, it can impede their candidates' efforts to move the public debate to other issues
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CivilWarShipwreck Bjt   10-23 0775</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Civil War Shipwreck, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>Civil War Ship `Monitor' at Center of Divers' Safety Dispute</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Monitor, the ironclad Civil War ship that sank in a gale after a celebrated battle with the <ORGANIZATION> Confederate </ORGANIZATION> ship Merrimack 127 years ago, still finds itself surrounded by turbulence. The government's refusal for safety reasons to allow anyone to dive to the ironclad Monitor's watery grave for the last 10 years has angered divers, who believe the ship is on the verge of collapsing. If that happens, it will be the end of part of our `` national heritage,'' a divers' lobbying group said last week. `` Underlying this controversy is how far the government should go to protect the individual from undertaking a somewhat dangerous activity,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scuba </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Photographing the Monitor has become an obsession for marine explorer <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Gentile </PERSON>, 43, of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, who has enlisted the aid of his congressman and fellow scuba enthusiasts to help him get permission for the dive. In the last five years, <PERSON> Gentile </PERSON> said he has filed 11 permit applications and written 51 letters to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, which oversees the wreck 16 miles off the <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hatteras </LOCATION> coast in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gentile </PERSON>, who said his quest has cost him thousands of dollars, has begun filing federal Freedom of Information Act requests to try to obtain information from <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> that he believes will not be forthcoming any other way. Last week he sat through a daylong hearing before a <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> administrative law judge who considered previous denials of three of his requests _ each varying slightly _ to make the 220-foot dive using scuba gear. The judge will study the case further before making a recommendation to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ocean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, a branch of <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION>. `` The problem is bureaucratic territoriality,'' <PERSON> Gentile </PERSON> said in an interview after the hearing. `` <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> wants to preserve the wreck for themselves.'' The currents and weather can change quickly in the area where the Monitor went down. `` They do n't call that ` The Graveyard of the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>' for nothing,'' said <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Dane </PERSON> <PERSON> Konop </PERSON>, who has been to the site. `` It's a very tricky situation out there, the most dangerous conditions imaginable.'' <PERSON> Gentile </PERSON>'s attorney, fellow diver <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Hess </PERSON>, noted at the hearing that <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> allowed <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> explorer <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Cousteau </PERSON>'s party to dive to the Monitor in 1979. <ORGANIZATION> Cousteau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Brazeau </PERSON> said last week that the weather and the visibility on the trip was poor, and that little or no usable footage was produced. `` No one has dove on that site since,'' <PERSON> Konop </PERSON> said. `` You can say <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> learned its lesson from the <PERSON> Cousteau </PERSON> dive. They were happy to make it back aboard safely.'' <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> now considers the dive too deep and dangerous to be made using the compressed air that <PERSON> Cousteau </PERSON>'s group used and that <PERSON> Gentile </PERSON> proposes, <PERSON> Konop </PERSON> said. At certain depths, nitrogen in the air can cause divers to lose concentration or impede motor skills. But <PERSON> Gentile </PERSON> said he has made many deeper dives on scuba, including 24 expeditions to the 33-year-old wreck of the <PERSON> Andrea </PERSON> <PERSON> Doria </PERSON>, off <LOCATION> Nantucket </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gentile </PERSON> has now applied to make the dive using a mixture of oxygen and helium, a combination that is more expensive than compressed air but which he hopes <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> will find more acceptable. That request is still pending. `` Anyone who has put this much blood and sweat into it, it would be terrific if he could meet <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION>'s conditions,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> DeCoursey </PERSON>, spokesman for Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Borski </PERSON>, D-Pa., who has been trying to speed up the administration's consideration of <PERSON> Gentile </PERSON>'s A Union ship, the 172-foot Monitor was built with iron. Both the Monitor and the <LOCATION> Merrimack </LOCATION> survived their famous battle in 1862, but neither stayed around long. The Monitor sank in bad weather, and the <LOCATION> Merrimack </LOCATION>, renamed the <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, was destroyed by its crew to keep it from being captured by the Union. In 1987, <PERSON> Konop </PERSON> and other <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> officials journeyed to the Monitor site and returned with photographs and measurements obtained from a remote device they sent into the water. Based partly on <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION>'s own statements, <PERSON> Gentile </PERSON> and his attorney said they fear the ship is collapsing. <PERSON> Konop </PERSON> conceded the ship's situation is `` dynamic,'' but said, `` I've never seen anything from us that says it's in imminent danger of collapsing on itself.'' <PERSON> Gentile </PERSON> said he wants to capture the ship on film from an artist's perspective. `` <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> got a fantastic amount of information, but there's no human interest in it. I want something people can relate to. It should be photographed before it collapses,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     10-23 0744</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Consumer Food Prices May Moderate in 1990</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 No flat predictions yet, but one of the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s chief grocery-watchers thinks consumer food prices in 1990 wo n't go up as fast as they did this year. Food prices did rise sharply in 1989, an average of `` around 6 percent'' over the calendar year, economist <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> says, adding that not much is in the works over the next couple of months that will alter that preliminary reading. According to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> records based on official <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> statistics, this year's 6 percent all-food increase _ which includes meals eaten out as well as at home _ is the biggest gain since a 7.8 percent jump in 1981. Retail food prices averaged 4.1 percent higher in each of the last two years and had hovered at or below that level since the hefty 1981 increase. Parlett, interviewed by telephone last Friday, said he was in the midst of preparing the 1990 forecast for release at the department's annual outlook conference in late November. `` I do n't think there'll be the increase we've seen this year,'' Parlett ventured. `` It's not going to be near the 6 percent level ... I do n't think.'' Although <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said the 1990 food outlook is still a bit cloudy, there are some points that can be made about this year's situation and how those might bear on the immediate future `` Some of our price increase this year was caused early on by bad weather, with vegetables, particularly,'' he said. `` We do n't forecast bad weather for 1990, so maybe that's one thing that wo n't happen, hopefully <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> added: `` But we still have the carryover from the -LRB- 1988 -RRB- drought that left a lot of pipelines empty, in terms of the processed vegetable market. Prices will be high, and supplies are still going to be tight.'' Despite `` a respectable harvest'' of vegetables this year, supplies for processing will be tight as inventories continue to be replenished, he said. But this will gradually be corrected. `` Come next year there's no reason to see those vegetable prices _ processed or fresh _ to be screaming higher,'' <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said. Meat, poultry, fish and eggs account for more than 30 percent of the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s food-at-home price index, based on December 1988 computations. By comparison, cereals and bakery products are about 14 percent of the index; dairy products, 12 percent; fresh fruits and vegetables, 11 percent; and processed fruits and vegetables, 7 percent. `` The big story really is in poultry,'' <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said. `` Demand for poultry is n't going to change considerably, but -LRB- producers -RRB- have continued to increase production. So, I would expect some decrease in poultry prices. We've already seen them start coming down from June.'' Red meat supplies, mostly beef and pork, probably will decrease slightly in 1990, he said. But there is uncertainty about what will happen to prices, partly because poultry has an impact on beef and pork, and vice versa. Last week <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON>'s agency, the <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said that the farm price of milk has risen sharply this year, meaning that consumers will also see `` brisk'' increases, including cheese and non-fat dry milk. `` For the first time in many years, rises in retail dairy prices will surpass those of all-food or all -LRB- consumer -RRB- items,'' the report said. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Milk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Producers </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> said that from 1975 until 1982, consumer prices for dairy products climbed at about the same rate as milk prices. Since 1982, federal milk supports have dropped more than 23 percent and `` farm milk prices also declined over the same period of time,'' the federation said in a recent newsletter. `` Consumers pay when farm milk prices go up, but they have not reaped the expected benefits when farm prices decline,'' it said. The <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s report last week noted that consumer food prices overall rose a moderate 0.2 percent in September after rising sharply earlier in the year. Food and beverage prices shot up at a 9.3 percent annual rate through May, but from June to September climbed at only a 1.7 percent rate. But the price index for dairy products rose faster than the general tide, jumping 1.4 percent in September, the largest monthly increase since May 1980. <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> has been forecasting retail dairy prices rising around 6 percent this year, compared with a 2.4 percent increase in 1988 _ when overall food prices rose 4.1 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 0010EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Grenada Bjt a0729 10-23 0792</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Grenada, Bjt, a0729,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Grenada Six Years Later: Officer Says Mission Endangered U.S. Students</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 5-6 pvs, `He lauds ..., to CORRRECT date of invasion
to Oct. 25 sted Oct. 23; picks up 7th graf pvs, `If anything</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYNA BRENNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The American soldiers who invaded <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION> six years ago are rightly hailed as heroes but the official <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> rationale for the mission was bogus, says a British officer involved in the attack. Retired Maj. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Adkin </PERSON> says the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military action was not necessary to save the lives of American medical students on the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> island, as claimed by the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, and in fact endangered them. He also says <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers succeeded despite weak advance planning and haphazard coordination by leaders of the different military services involved. <PERSON> Adkin </PERSON>, who took part in the invasion as <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> operations staff officer for the <ORGANIZATION> Barbados </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, recounts the mission in a new book titled `` Urgent Fury: The Battle for <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION>.'' He lauds the outcome of the invasion, which occurred six years ago this week, and says it prevented <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION> from becoming a `` communist bastion'' in the region. But he dismisses <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> claims at the time that the 700 American medical students on the island were in danger of being taken hostage. Then-President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> repeatedly said the 6,000 combat troops staged a `` rescue mission'' on Oct. 25, 1983, to prevent the students from being taken hostage by a radical Marxist government. If anything, <PERSON> Adkin </PERSON> says, the invasion increased the chances that the students would be taken hostage. `` <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens were in no danger until the operation was launched,'' he writes. `` The assault on the island could easily have precipitated the taking of hostages by desperate men driven to desperate means to save their own lives.'' The administration decided to intervene in <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION> `` on the basis of seizing a fleeting strategic-political advantage, which had the added merit that inevitable military success would raise <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> flagging morale,'' he says. The predawn attack by combined elite units of all the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> armed forces came days after leftists on the island executed Marxist Prime Minister <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> and imposed a 24-hour curfew. The invasion forces ousted the leftists and flew the students home. A former <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration official, <PERSON> Langhorne </PERSON> <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Motley </PERSON>, disputes <PERSON> Adkin </PERSON>'s claims about the students, saying: `` He's totally incorrect. <PERSON> Motley </PERSON>, a former assistant secretary of state for inter-American affairs, said a <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> officer spoke with the students before the troops arrived and `` they were concerned'' about being taken hostage. Regardless of the reason for the mission, <PERSON> Adkin </PERSON> says, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops deserved the heroes' welcome they received from both the islanders and the American public upon their return. `` The people who had been invaded welcomed the invaders, regarded them as liberators, even going so far as to want <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops to remain far longer than they did. The island was to be a communist bastion, an ever more menacing reminder to the rest of the region that their way of live was threatened,'' he says. `` This is what it would have become. That it did not was because President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> acted, albeit primarily for reasons of national self-interest.'' Nineteen American soldiers died in the initial assault and several days of skirmishes. <PERSON> Adkin </PERSON> says two <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rangers </ORGANIZATION> also died when their parachutes failed to open. He argues that the American soldiers had to overcome a lack of intelligence information on the island and poor preparation for the joint operation. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military has done its own assessments on <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION>, finding fault with the lack of coordination and intelligence. Many details of those assessments remain classified, however. A retired <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military officer, who served in the planning and execution of the <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION> invasion, acknowledged some problems but said <PERSON> Adkin </PERSON> `` does n't tell the whole story.'' The officer, who spoke only on condition he not be further identified, agreed that the troops operated without maps and up-to-date intelligence information but said <PERSON> Adkin </PERSON> should have noted that `` a lot of decisions were made on the ground by ground commanders. They were able to adapt.'' However, he agreed that the various armed forces were ill-prepared to work together and said the decision to use a combined force at that time was wrong. The <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION> operation later was cited by Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, as the main reason for a 1986 bill mandating a joint special operations command. `` That it succeeded as it did, without costly setbacks, was due primarily to incredibly good fortune,'' <PERSON> Adkin </PERSON> says. Still, he concludes that `` for all the errors, for all the confusion, for all the suffering, <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION> and its people remain grateful to those bold enough to launch the operation and those bold enough to undertake it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Mapplethorpe-Hartford     10-23 0448</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mapplethorpe-Hartford,0462</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mapplethorpe Exhibit Draws Overflow Crowd</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER VILES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HARTFORD, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An exhibit of sexually explicit photographs that ignited a debate over government funding of the arts got mixed reviews from an overflow crowd, as it was denounced by a small band of protesters. The exhibit of photos by the late <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mapplethorpe </PERSON> opened Saturday at the <LOCATION> Wadsworth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Atheneum </LOCATION>. The collection includes photos of homosexual acts as well as more conventional nudes, celebrity portraits and still lifes of flowers. About 15 religious activists picketed, denouncing the exhibit as `` gay pornography,'' but the line of patrons extended out the door. Officials said 2,000 people paid to see the show, more than four times the usual Saturday attendance. `` The overall quality was superb,'' <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Cemino </PERSON> said as she left the museum. `` There was really nothing obscene about it. The flowers are really beautiful.'' Conservatives in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, led by Sen. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>, were angered to learn that the <PERSON> Mapplethorpe </PERSON> exhibit at <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s Corcoran Gallery of Art originally was funded in part by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endowment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last month defeated a <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> proposal to ban federal funding of art considered `` obscene'' or `` indecent.'' Instead, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> voted to bar government financing of works that `` may be obscene'' and lack `` serious literary, artistic, political or scientific value'' _ the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s 1973 guideline on obscenity. The exhibit had opened to large crowds and critical acclaim in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> before its stormy stop in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Atheneum Director <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> McCaughey </PERSON> said he was happy to show the photos because an art museum `` must n't just lie back and sit like a tabby cat.'' He said the turnout challenged `` the outsider's view of <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> _ that it's the insurance capital, that it's staid The <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> museum charged a special $ 3 admission fee to offset the cost of showing it and required that minors be accompanied by an adult. Demonstrators carried signs that read, `` Promote True Art, Not Obscenity,'' and `` Federally Funded Gay Pornography.'' <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Pressamarita </PERSON>, who has helped defeat gay rights bills in the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> and fought topless bars, said the exhibit contained `` a lot of beautiful pictures'' along with `` absolute pornography.'' The protest drew a counter-demonstration from two men, who embraced and kissed on the lips for several minutes in front of the protesters. `` Oh my God!'' screamed one demonstrator. `` Are they crazy?'' Inside, during a panel discussion, art critic <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON> defended the artist, telling an audience of about 300 that the photos contain nothing new. `` Those of you who have squinted hard at the dirty Greek vases in the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> know what I'm talking about,'' he said. `` What is the big deal?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SFQuake 5thLd-Writethru a0820 10-23 1291</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-SF Quake, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0820,1280</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 4 grafs to UPDATE with rescue work suspended; PICKS
UP 3rd graf pvs, `The evacuation ...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos FXPX1,OAS1,OAS2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SCOTT McCARTNEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rescuers euphoric over finding a survivor in a collapsed freeway had to suspend their search late Sunday because the rubble became so unstable, and earthquake-shaken Northern Californians mapped strategy for Monday's commute through `` gridlock.'' Authorities sent crews home for the night because so much further damage had been done by aftershocks and heavy construction equipment that they had no idea how to safely shore up Interstate 880. Large sections of concrete have crumbled. And there was no estimate of when work could resume. `` It's kind of minute by minute,'' said <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Kyle </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said. More than 100 people were evacuated Sunday afternoon from an <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> housing project located within 10 feet of a four-block stretch of I-880 abutting the portion that gave way in the quake. The evacuation came after a cement column fell from the structure and new cracks were discovered in the section of double-deck freeway that had previously been thought to be stable. Longshoreman Buck Helm, who spent four days in a tomb of I-880 concrete and steel, was in critical-stable condition at <LOCATION> Highland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> General </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> with some slight improvement, hospital officials said. Engineer <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Whipple </PERSON>, hailed as a hero of the rescue, said he was checking the fallen double-deck freeway for stability on Saturday when he spotted the back of <PERSON> Helm </PERSON>'s head with his flashlight, and then saw a hand wave at him. `` It stopped my heart. I thought maybe the wind was blowing and that's what caused it. I thought I might be losing it,'' said <PERSON> Whipple </PERSON>, 29. The number of dead pulled from the I-880 disaster rose to 38, including a 4-year-old boy, bringing the earthquake's toll to 59, with thousands injured and homeless and dozens still missing. `` We know there are more victims, more cars. But we do n't know how many,'' said <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Highway Patrol Capt. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Garver </PERSON>. Damage estimates topped $ 7 billion, making the quake the costliest natural disaster in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agents </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. Baseball commissioner <PERSON> Fay </PERSON> <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> announced Sunday that the World Series would not resume until Friday night, three days later than originally hoped. The championship between the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> A </ORGANIZATION>'s and the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION> was suspended the night of the quake. Sunday was a day for both mourning the dead and giving thanks for the living at churches across the <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area. Special services were set because some damaged churches remain too dangerous, and congregants praying for peace with the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> were encouraged to share their quake experiences. `` By the uncertainties of this hour, we pray to be spared from further suffering,'' Archbishop <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON> told 700 people at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mary </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cathedral </ORGANIZATION> here. `` We pray that we may be spared further earthquakes,'' <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON> said. `` We pray for all those who have suffered heavy losses. I weep for the parents, for the elderly, for the children. I pray for the relief of suffering and anxiety. I can not forget to pray for the dead and the bereaved.'' In <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>, parishioners of the <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Salles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cathedral </ORGANIZATION> had to move services to a Baptist church because the cathedral's tower was filled with cracks and leaning precariously `` Sometimes in life, God shakes us and says, ` Pay attention, there is something more important than the ordinary things in your life,''' Father <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Powers </PERSON> said. `` It was n't just the ground that shook Tuesday, the earthquake shook a lot of things that we do _ the ordinary things on our agenda,'' <PERSON> Powers </PERSON> said. Phone calls, telegrams and bouquets of flowers for Helm, the burly longshoreman, deluged Highland General Hospital Sunday. Helm regained some function in his kidneys, damaged by severe dehydration, and his lung condition improved slightly, Dr. <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Fry </PERSON> said. He was still in the intensive care unit being fed through a tube, and still was having difficulty moving his left leg. `` He is not out of the woods yet,'' Fry said. A non-smoker, Helm had high blood pressure and mild diabetes that did not require insulin before the earthquake. `` I think it's more amazing that he has been able to come through as well as he has despite those medical problems,'' Fry said. `` He's proven that he has a strong will to live.'' Crews sawed the fallen five-lane section of the upper deck of the <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION> in half and lifted one section down to a barge for repairs Sunday. A barge floating on chopping <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> is supporting a towering white crane capable of lifting the 100-ton separate sections of roadway that collapsed in the earthquake, killing a woman who drove her car into the gap. The vital link between <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> is expected to be closed for four weeks. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday reported major cracks in three dams within 5 miles of the epicenter _ <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Newell </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Lake </PERSON> <PERSON> Elsman </PERSON> _ but said they posed `` no public threat at this time'' because water is low behind them. At the I-880 rescue site in industrial downtown <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION>, six sweeps of the area where Helm was found with sniffing dogs and electronic gear turned up no signs of other survivors. Digging to remove cars and bodies was delayed because the double-deck freeway, which collapsed on top of itself, shifted under the strains of aftershocks, wind and even the rescue work itself. Workers placed giant airbags, hydraulic jacks and wood timbers under concrete sections, and used truckloads of dirt to build a sturdier foundation, according to <PERSON> Kyle </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>. They also installed seismic monitors on the structure. `` The problem is we still have to proceed cautiously and deliberately even though people are encouraged,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Drago </PERSON>, another <ORGANIZATION> CalTrans </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. Despite the slow pace, rescue workers still had a renewed vigor Sunday. `` We need to use every trick in the rescue books to make sure no one's still up here alive,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bromely </PERSON>, a construction worker moving debris. `` We know now that it's possible. We're going as fast as we can.'' A half-dozen impromptu tent cities have sprouted up around <LOCATION> Watsonville </LOCATION>, the battered, largely Hispanic city south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> and closer to the epicenter. Hundreds of residents there are so traumatized by the quake, its aftershocks, which have been both strong and numerous, and the memory of the <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> earthquake that they refuse to go indoors. `` This place is a disaster,'' <PERSON> Pamela </PERSON> <PERSON> Cote </PERSON>, of the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> human resources agency, said as she tried to coax 50 survivors living in <LOCATION> Calaghan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> to move to 22 <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> tents erected several blocks away by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>. `` People are everywhere on the streets in this town.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> opened a permanent tent shelter with large olive-colored military tents in a <LOCATION> Watsonville </LOCATION> park Sunday. Throughout the quake area, the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> said, the population at its 19 shelters dropped to 2,000 Saturday night. It had been above 10,000. In the <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area, officials were doing everything they could to scare commuters off the streets Monday, the first work day for tens of thousands since Tuesday's quake. Numerous freeways remain closed in addition to the <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION>. An armada of ferries has formed, and transit authorities touted subways and buses as well. Employers were offering flexible work schedules, but with many routes into the Bay area and <LOCATION> Silicon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> blocked, the Monday morning forecast called for `` gridlock.'' Driving to work alone amounts to `` an anti-social act,'' said <PERSON> Rod </PERSON> <PERSON> Diridon </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 0057EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Storms     10-23 0181</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Storms,0184</SECOND>
<UNK>Storms in Britain Kill 13</UNK>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two days and nights of storms in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> left 13 people dead in extreme weather conditions on the roads and at sea, all in southern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, the police and <ORGANIZATION> coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> guard </ORGANIZATION> reported today. In the worst incident, an empty bus skidding on a wet road at <LOCATION> Honiton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Devon </LOCATION>, hit a railroad bridge and landed upside down on a car, killing the bus driver and the car's four occupants, who were going home from a wedding. Five other people died in road accidents caused by vehicles skidding or crashing into trees brought down by the winds. Two men died in separate yacht capsizings off the south coast and a youth was swept away while fishing off rocks near <LOCATION> Perranporth </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Cornwall </LOCATION>. Thousands of homes in southern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> were left without power on Saturday when power lines were brought down. Meteorologists said the bad weather that began Friday night was the worst since a hurricane swept southern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> in October 1987, leaving 17 people dead and felling an estimated 15 million trees.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--GasPrices     10-23 0159</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Gas Prices,0163</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prices Dip Half-Cent Per Gallon at Pump</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: RETRANSMITTING to correct category code.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The average price of gasoline nationwide dipped about a half-cent a gallon at the pumps in the past two weeks, a survey found. The Lundberg Survey of 12,000 gas stations showed the average retail price of all grades of gasoline, including taxes, at 109.12 cents a gallon on Friday, down .53 cent from Oct. 6, analyst <PERSON> Trilby </PERSON> <PERSON> Lundberg </PERSON> said Sunday. `` The movement is not untypical for this type of year. It's partially a response to seasonally lowered demand, but also to ample supplies,'' she said Wholesale prices fell, allowing retailers to pass their savings on to customers, she said. According to the survey, self-service prices per gallon were: regular unleaded, 97.74 cents; premium unleaded, 114.87 cents; regular leaded, 96.62 cents. At full-service pumps, prices per gallon were: regular unleaded, 127.26; premium unleaded, 139.92 cents; regular leaded, 126.01 cents.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 0107EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SFQuake-Fryes 1stLd-Writethru a0412 10-23 0597</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-Fryes, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0412,0609</SECOND>
<HEAD>Homeless in the Suburbs _ Two Days on a ``Numb High''</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 13th graf, `The contents ...' to CORRECT spelling of `cupboard'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS GATOS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Leta </PERSON> <PERSON> Frye </PERSON> recently joined the ranks of the nation's homeless. She's not a disheveled bag lady with possessions stashed in a supermarket shopping cart. Mrs. <PERSON> Frye </PERSON>'s belongings are strewn on a slope in the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>, mixed up with the debris of her earthquake-ravaged $ 450,000 house. The split-level, four-bedroom home is now a splintered pile of rubble, rocked off its foundation and tossed 15 feet by the 6.9 magnitude <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area earthquake. Only three huge pine trees prevent the wreckage from sliding down the mountain. `` I realize I'm in a different subset of the population now. Suddenly, I'm a homeless person,'' the 54-year-old dietitian said Sunday, as she and her husband, <PERSON> William </PERSON>, picked through the debris. `` I slept in my car for two nights. I have a different frame of mind now.'' `` It's kind of like a death in the family,'' <ORGANIZATION> Aetna </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Casualty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Greaney </PERSON> said of the loss. <ORGANIZATION> Aetna </ORGANIZATION> adjuster <PERSON> Toni </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> Frye </LOCATION> home was the worst she had seen so far, adding that it would take weeks to determine how many homes in the Bay area were destroyed in the quake. `` There are just too many to count,'' she said. The Fryes were paid $ 20,000 on Friday as an advance to their earthquake insurance claim. The couple had argued a year ago over whether to buy insurance and reluctantly paid the $ 440-a-year premium. `` We really debated about it before we signed up. Thank God we did,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Frye </PERSON>. The couple bought the 22-year-old house five years ago. It's one of 112 houses in the <LOCATION> Villa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monte </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Estates </LOCATION> area about 50 miles south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> and just southwest of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>. `` Many people have come by here and said we have the dubious distinction of having the most destroyed house in the Villa,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Frye </PERSON> said. `` We've become very popular,'' added <PERSON> Frye </PERSON>. The contents of dressers, cupboards, drawers and desks where strewn about inside the demolished home, and the <ORGANIZATION> Fryes </ORGANIZATION> used a garden rake to fish out mementos and personal items in reach. `` I think everybody around here for two days was on this numb high _ sort of in shock,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Frye </PERSON> said. When the earthquake struck, Mrs. <PERSON> Frye </PERSON> was driving home in her car and thought the tires had gone flat. Her husband, 57, an executive at <ORGANIZATION> Lockheed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ordnance </ORGANIZATION>, was in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> on a business trip. `` His first comment was, ` Well, <PERSON> Leta </PERSON>, you wanted to remodel,' `` Mrs. <PERSON> Frye </PERSON> said. `` We had one room we called the T.U.R. _ the torn-up room, which I was going to remodel. Now I call it the T.U.H. _ torn-up house.'' The Fryes, who now are staying in a hotel, say they are uncertain whether they will rebuild on the one-acre site. The 27,750 people living in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gatos </LOCATION> were still coping Sunday with effects of the quake. Traffic lights were still out, plywood covered many storefront windows, roadblocks remained in the heart of town, and state Highway 17 leading south through the mountains to <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION> was still closed. A steady procession of trucks carried water into the mountains. The heavily wooded area features a phenomenon unusual in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> _ noticeable seasons. Fall leaves have turned orange and have filled the four-inch cracks on the mountain roads throught the region.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 0109EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AbortionPolitics Advisory   10-23 0018</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion Politics, Advisory,020</SECOND>
<HEAD>EDITORS:    PM-Abortion Politics, a0426, should have moved with
a Bjt designation.
</HEAD>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 0121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-JamaicaTrip     10-23 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jamaica Trip,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lawmakers Taking Taxpayer-Funded Trip to Jamaica</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Crockett </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Mich </LOCATION>., is inviting more than 100 colleagues on a taxpayer-financed trip to <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Montego </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> next month, and he's apparently getting quite a response The trip, scheduled for Nov. 2-6 and intended to explore <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> development issues, has attracted so much interest that aides said they may not be able to accommodate everyone. By the time the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> jet leaves, however, aides expect no more than 20 <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members plus some spouses and staffers to be on board. By Friday, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, which handles travel arrangements for congressional delegations going overseas, said it only had the names of six people who were going. <PERSON> Crockett </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on Western Hemisphere Affairs, did not respond to calls about the trip Friday. His office refused to release a copy of the invitation he sent to as many as 150 <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members, or a list of people who planned to attend the long weekend event at <LOCATION> Montego </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Half </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Moon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, the staff director, said a final list of participants probably would not be available until takeoff. The purpose of the trip is to try to get lawmakers in touch with a wide variety of people, including academics, union heads and farmers' and labor organizations, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Hellinger </PERSON>, co-director of the <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alternative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a non-profit group that is sponsoring the event, said the seminars and meetings are hard work. The conference should not be considered play even though it is held at a resort, he said. <PERSON> Atherton </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, who works with <PERSON> Hellinger </PERSON>, said a number of members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had expressed interest in the trip, but his group had `` been asked not to release names, given the whole things with junkets and ethics.'' The group provided an agenda for the five-day program. After arriving Nov. 2, participants are invited to a reception. A series of speeches and conferences are scheduled for the next two days, generally running from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. Sunday is a free day for recreation. On the final day, lawmakers will receive a briefing from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy staff before flying back to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The lawmakers will hear from <PERSON> Crockett </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Manley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>'s prime minister, before the seminars start. Topics include: `` Narcotics: Toward a new Understanding,'' a panel discussion on `` Structural Adjustment and Debt,'' an open discussion on `` Internal Constraints,'' and a presentation on `` Options and Strategies: Regional Development, Food Security and the Role of Regional Institutions.'' The <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> conference is an outgrowth of two earlier conferences on <LOCATION> Barbados </LOCATION> attended by members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Rep. <PERSON> Dante </PERSON> <PERSON> Fascell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> with responsibility for approving members' trips, attended the <LOCATION> Barbados </LOCATION> conference in February 1988 But <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Burris </PERSON>, <PERSON> Fascell </PERSON>'s spokeswoman, said her boss would not travel to <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> this year. Rep. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, who also traveled to <LOCATION> Barbados </LOCATION>, declined the trip because of the upcoming <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> mayoral race, according to his assistant, <PERSON> Miles </PERSON> <PERSON> Lackey </PERSON>. Among those who intend on taking the trip are Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Frenzel </PERSON>, R-Minn., and <PERSON> Jaime </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuster </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>'s delegate in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, their aides said <PERSON> Frenzel </PERSON> is a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION>' subcommittee on trade, which had jurisdiction over the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Basin </LOCATION> Initiative, a stalled <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> development plan for the region. He is also a co-chairman of Friends of the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>, a loosely knit task force on the region. Both groups, as well as the subcommittee on the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION>, are expected to send members to <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said the results of the <LOCATION> Barbados </LOCATION> conference have already borne fruit: <PERSON> Crockett </PERSON> introduced a $ 93 million <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> aid package which has passed the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and is pending in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. Although the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government picks up the cost of travel and pays a per diem for members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the Development GAP raised money for the conference, <PERSON> Hellinger </PERSON> said. Sources include foundations, like the <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, and private contributions from grassroots groups, such as churches, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 0124EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-All_TerrainVehicles Advisory   10-23 0018</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-All_Terrain Vehicles, Advisory,020</SECOND>
<HEAD>EDITORS:    PM-All_Terrain Vehicles, a0453, should not have carried
a Bjt designation.
</HEAD>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 0129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     10-23 0941</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0975</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLLEGEVILLE, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Author <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Michener </PERSON> helped open a new art museum with advice for politicans: Let private individuals buy public art. <PERSON> Michener </PERSON> said Sunday at the new <ORGANIZATION> Berman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Ursinus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> that elected officials `` do n't know what they're doing. They are terribly vulnerable to public opinion and it is unfair to saddle them with decisions which it takes even a brilliant connoisseur years to develop.'' `` The collection of great art must be left to private individuals, and then, structure society so that later on they will give it to the public,'' said <PERSON> Michener </PERSON>, the author of such best-selling novels as `` Tales of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>,'' `` <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>,'' `` Space'' and `` Centennial.'' The author has a home in <LOCATION> Bucks </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. The Berman Museum was named for <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Muriel </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Berman </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Allentown </LOCATION>, who contributed 1,500 art works from their collection. <PERSON> Berman </PERSON> is the former owner of the <ORGANIZATION> Hess </ORGANIZATION>' department store chain. The opening exhibit features art by <PERSON> Edgar </PERSON> <PERSON> Degas </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rembrandt </PERSON> <PERSON> Peale </PERSON>, <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Chagall </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Singer </PERSON> <PERSON> Sargeant </PERSON> and <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopper </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer <PERSON> Carly </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> says she is writing a novel based on her life after coming out with a children's book that stems from hundreds of nights of storytelling. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> recalled making up bedtime stories for her son and daughter, now ages 12 and 15, when they were very young. `` Eventually it became that the kids would want to bypass the books and they'd say, ` Oh Mom, tell that story again about <PERSON> Amy </PERSON>, the bear that danced.' Or the story about <PERSON> Wiwac </PERSON>, the little girl who had a speech impediment and could n't say her real name, which is <PERSON> Lilac </PERSON>,'' she said. `` And these stories came out of my head with no effort, because, after all, my audience was so loving and so receptive. So anything could emerge,'' she said in Sunday's <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magazine </ORGANIZATION>. The stories were turned into a children's book, `` Amy the Dancing Bear,'' published recently by <PERSON> Doubleday </PERSON>. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> has a contract to write more children's books in the future. She's also turning her attention to a longer work after <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON>, her editor at Doubleday, made the suggestion. `` That's how I originally got with <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>. `` She said, ` I've got the feeling you could write a book.'''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LAKE BUENA VISTA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A golfing foursome featuring Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Today'' show host <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> <PERSON> Gumbel </PERSON> wo n't be bragging about their game, but their shots did help a fund-raiser. The three appeared Sunday in a charity pro-am tournament that helped raise $ 200,000 for the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Negro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION>. Rounding out the Quayle-Martinez-Gumbel foursome was the vice president's former college roommate and golfing buddy, <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION> sports commentator <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Rolfing </PERSON>. They combined to shoot 249, far behind the winning 216, under a scoring system in which only three players' scores were counted on each hole. The winners in the inaugural <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> Gumbel-Walt Disney World Pro-Am Golf Tournament were the foursome of young pro <PERSON> Ronnie </PERSON> <PERSON> McCann </PERSON>; <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Norman </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION>'s executive vice president; <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunis </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Walt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Attractions </ORGANIZATION>; and golf course architect <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Trent </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MONTEVIDEO, Uruguay (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sara </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>, the Duchess of <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, flew to this South American capital to preside over an around-the-world race by sea. The duchess arrived Sunday night and left immediately for <LOCATION> Punta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Este </LOCATION>, about 85 miles east. The 23 yachts of the Whitbread Round the World Race depart Saturday for <PERSON> Freemantle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. She is scheduled to present awards Tuesday to the crews of the 23 yachts that left <LOCATION> Southampton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, last Sept. 2 on the first leg of the race. Her husband, <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, is director of the race.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON>'s infamous <ORGANIZATION> Rolls-Royce </ORGANIZATION> is n't as infamous as she hoped. The Hungarian actress offered the white 1980 Corniche convertible up for sale over the weekend at an auction. Her minimum asking price was $ 125,000, but the high bid came in at $ 105,000. To that, Miss <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON> said no, and drove off. The actress was driving the vehicle when she was pulled over by <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> police Officer <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON> last June. She is to be sentenced Tuesday on her misdemeanor convictions of slapping <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON>, driving without a valid license and carrying an open container of liquor in her car. Miss <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON> said she had not intended to sell the Rolls, but was talked into it Saturday when she and her husband visited the auction at a hotel in <LOCATION> Woodland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> where another <ORGANIZATION> Rolls-Royce </ORGANIZATION> they owned went for $ 80,000. Sold at the auction for $ 75,000 was a heavily customized, metallic red <ORGANIZATION> Jaguar </ORGANIZATION> XJS that had earned its owner, outfielder <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Canseco </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletics </ORGANIZATION> baseball team, a string of speeding tickets.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rock band The Clash's `` <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> Calling'' and rock star <PERSON> Prince </PERSON>'s `` Purple Rain'' topped a list of the 100 greatest albums of the 1980s picked by the editors of <ORGANIZATION> Rolling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stone </ORGANIZATION>. The Clash, a now defunct band whose lyrics featured aggressive working-class politics that became the staple of the punk movement, recorded `` <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> Calling'' in 1980. The rest of the top 10, in descending order, are: `` Purple Rain,'' by <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> and the Revolution; `` The <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON> <PERSON> Tree </PERSON>,'' by the Irish rock group U2; `` Remain in Light,'' by the Talking Heads; `` Graceland,'' by <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>; `` Born in the <LOCATION> U.S.A. </LOCATION>'' by <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON>; `` Thriller,'' by <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>; `` Murmur,'' by R.E.M.; `` Shoot Out the Lights,'' by <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> and <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, and `` <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>,'' by folk singer <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>. The picks by 10 editors of the magazine appear in the Nov. 16 issue.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 0129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BakkerSentencing     10-23 0454</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bakker Sentencing,0467</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bakker Faces Sentencing From `Maximum Bob'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Retransmits a0452 to fix cycle designator</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL NOWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLOTTE, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> says <PERSON> God </PERSON> has forgiven him for his sins, but his lawyer is afraid the TV evangelist will have a tougher time setting things straight with a no-nonsense federal judge they call `` Maximum Bob.'' <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> could be sent to prison for 120 years and fined more than $ 5.2 million when he goes before <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Potter </PERSON> on Tuesday for sentencing for fraud and conspiracy. `` Maximum <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> will probably knock a year off the maximum,'' defense attorney <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> joked ruefully. The judge lived up to his moniker last month when he sentenced former <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> aide <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON> to 18 years and five months in prison for tax evasion. `` One can only speculate <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> will get a heavier sentence than <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON> _ it's a foregone conclusion,'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said in an interview. <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON> also was fined $ 500,000. Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said prosecutors will ask for a prison sentence, but he refused to elaborate. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> also declined to say if the government will ask that <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> be taken into custody immediately after sentencing; prosecutors unsuccessfully tried to jail him after his conviction. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>, 49, was convicted Oct. 5 on 24 counts of fraud and conspiracy for overselling $ 158 million in lifetime vacations, or `` partnerships,'' at <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>'s resort hotels. The jury found that <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> used more than $ 3.7 million to buy luxurious homes, fancy cars, jewelry and expensive vacations. The six-week trial was briefly interrupted by <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s commitment to a mental hospital after a breakdown `` God has forgiven me for my sins,'' he told followers from the pulpit last week at his <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Covenant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> `` I'm not guilty. <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON> and his brother, <PERSON> James </PERSON>, were convicted of diverting more than $ 1.1 milion in <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> money for their own use and cheating the government out of $ 525,000 in taxes. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON> drew the maximum prison term _ 17 years and nine months _ and was fined $ 500,000. Both Taggarts testified against <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>. <PERSON> Potter </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> appointee on the bench for eight years, `` can be harsh when it's called for, compassionate when it's justified,'' <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> lawyer <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Laughrun </PERSON> said last month. If a defendant admits his guilt, <PERSON> Potter </PERSON> is likely to weigh that in his favor, <PERSON> Laughrun </PERSON> said. If <PERSON> Potter </PERSON> thinks a defendant is lying, he's likely to hold that against him, the lawyer said. Before sentencing the Taggarts, <PERSON> Potter </PERSON> said he thought they had lied on the stand. But <PERSON> Potter </PERSON> gave former <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> executive <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Dortch </PERSON> eight years out of a possible 10 after <PERSON> Dortch </PERSON> pleaded guilty, apologized and agreed to testify for the government.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 0131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Heroin Bjt   10-23 0820</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Heroin, Bjt,0856</SECOND>
<HEAD>Turmoil Makes Pakistan, Afghanistan Major Exporters of Heroin</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN WILDER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A centuries-old tradition of opium poppy cultivation in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> has blossomed into a major heroin industry during a decade of political turmoil in <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. It has spawned what many anxious Pakistanis call a `` heroin and Kalashnikov culture'' of crime, referring to the preferred automatic weapon of the region's drug lords. Most of the brightly colored poppies are grown in neighboring <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, where 11 years of civil war have precluded any attempt to control their cultivation. Officials say the flowers' sticky yield of opium is refined into heroin powder in makeshift laboratories along the rugged Pakistan-Afghan frontier. It is then spirited through <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> to markets in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Western narcotics agents estimate that up to 80 percent of the heroin sold in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and 25 percent sold in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> comes from the so-called `` Golden Crescent'' region of <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. The remainder comes from <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>'s `` Golden Triangle,'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sources say. Pakistani officials say it's hard to estimate how much of the drug passes through their country. <PERSON> Khalim </PERSON> <PERSON> Dilkhan </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Pakistan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Narcotics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, said that in 1988 alone local agents seized 13,670 pounds of heroin, compared with 950 pounds seized in 1980. He said heroin addiction was virtually unknown in this Moslem country of 109 million people 10 years ago but now more than one million mostly poor, urban Pakistanis are hooked. Their preferred method of using the drug is to smoke it, whereas most addicts in the West inject heroin. `` In 10 years, the problem has multiplied a thousand times,'' <PERSON> Dilkhan </PERSON> said. There are no statistics on addicts in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. Poppy cultivation has declined steadily in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, but it has risen sharply in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, where fighting between the Marxist government and Moslem rebels has turned tribal areas along the mountainous Afghan-Pakistan frontier into a haven for drug lords, <PERSON> Dilkhan </PERSON> said. He said opium production in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> was about 140 tons in 1988, down from nearly 990 tons in 1980. In <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, this year's yield will be anywhere from 935 to 2,200 tons, Pakistani and Western narcotics experts estimate Opium production, and to some extent export, have existed for centuries in both countries but experts say three major events in 1979 combined to help build the multimillion-dollar heroin industry: _ The <LOCATION> Turkish </LOCATION> government's crackdown on heroin labs in eastern <LOCATION> Anatolia </LOCATION>, forcing production into western <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. _ <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s Islamic revolution, which ousted the <PERSON> Shah </PERSON>'s government and purged corrupt officials who secretly participated in the opium trade. _ The war in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, which began after a Soviet-supported communist coup in 1978 and has hindered efforts to control poppy cultivation. Opium production declined in the first years following the 1979 Soviet military intervention but increased steadily in the mid-1980s, experts say. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which together with <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> backs <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s anti-communist rebels, has only recently started working with guerrilla leaders to discourage poppy cultivation. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> is mounting a $ 10 million program that over the next three years hopes to promote drug awareness among <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s mujahedeen rebels and offer incentives to substitute the opium poppy with other crops, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials say American and Pakistani experts deny reports that the insurgents systematically sell heroin to buy weapons. `` There is no evidence of organized -LRB- heroin -RRB- activity but as individuals, yes, some of them are doing it,'' <PERSON> Dilkhan </PERSON> said of the guerrillas. Experts say that Pak-Afghan heroin follows three routes from the frontier westward: _ Across northern <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, then south to <LOCATION> Bombay </LOCATION> for shipping through the Arabian Sea. _ Due south through <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s desert province of <LOCATION> Baluchistan </LOCATION>, often by camel or jeep caravan, to the Arabian Sea. _ South to <LOCATION> Baluchistan </LOCATION>, then west through <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>. The new Pakistani government of Prime Minister <PERSON> Benazir </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>, who took office after November elections, declared war on heroin traffic. The government has received more than $ 60 million in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid for the effort. <PERSON> Dilkhan </PERSON> says the government campaign focuses on poppy crop substitution, destruction of plantations through aerial spraying, interdiction of overland shipments and drug awareness among the population. Narcotics agents are reluctant to discuss official corruption, which many describe as a main obstacle to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s war on drugs. `` Lets face it, we're talking about huge amounts of money. That attracts corruption,'' said a Pakistani narcotics official, speaking on condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Dilkhan </PERSON> said police arrested a number of `` mid-level drug barons'' this year but that it was difficult to collect enough evidence to bring them to trial. `` The money factor is tremendous. It's highly profitable,'' he said. Agents say one kilogram -LRB- 2.2 pounds -RRB- of 97 percent pure heroin fetches $ 1,000 at the Pakistan-Afghanistan border. `` Multiply that about 100 times for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Dilkhan </PERSON> said. Crop substitution is unattractive to most poppy growers because they are accustomed to handsome profits, he says.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 0132EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CongressRdp     10-23 0745</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress Rdp,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congressional Democrats Regaining Upper Hand Over Bush</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Congressional Democrats _ reeling in disarray just three weeks ago _ are using shrewd legislative maneuvering and a couple of political windfalls to regain the upper hand with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, according to lawmakers in both parties. The new <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leadership came in for criticism last month, even from their own party operatives, for seeming to be too accommodating with the president. The griping intensified after House Speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> and his team made a high-profile stand against <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s capital gains tax cut, and lost. But in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> such conditions are transitory. The past week has seen <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> defeat <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on his constitutional amendment to ban flag desecration; overwhelming <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approval of an aid package for <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> that is nearly twice what <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wants; and a showdown over federal funding for welfare abortions in rape and incest cases. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Saturday vetoed a spending bill that included the abortion funds, and while members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> concede an override attempt probably would not succeed, they are talking of sending the same measure to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> again. `` I think we're back,'' said Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, D-Mich., a senior member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leadership `` Timing, strategy and some luck have added up to our being able to score some points.'' Asked about the Democratic resurgence, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> shrugged. `` It's like a ball game. Some innings you hit well and score runs,'' he said, recalling the `` wave of high popularity'' his party enjoyed a few weeks ago. But the winds have shifted, he acknowledged. `` If they're feeling good about some of the developments in the last day or two, so be it.'' Democrats also seem increasingly emboldened to take <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on directly, particularly for his response to the radical changes taking place in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. In a speech last week, Majority Leader <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Mo </LOCATION>., concluded: `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> appears to be determined to go down in history as the hesitation president At least his first year in office could be titled, ` The Year of Living Timidly.''' The spending bill vetoed by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> included money to pay for abortions for poor women who are victims of rape and incest. The bill would have reversed a decade-old federal policy, a move propelled by resurgent pro-choice forces. But many Republicans are uncomfortable with a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> veto, fearing it will put them on the losing side of another hot political issue. `` This is just the wrong front on which to fight that battle,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION> `` There's no question this is going to hurt the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>,'' Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON>, R-Ore., an abortion rights backer, said on <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <ORGANIZATION> Evans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Novak'' show And on the flag issue, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s early endorsement of a constitutional amendment at the Iwo Jima Memorial has proved less than the brilliant stroke it seemed at the time. Democrats' strategy to wait the issue out and evoke the sanctity of the Bill of Rights has been vindicated In fact, it was two last-minute <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> converts _ Sens. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> _ who helped take the amendment down to defeat in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiators this week will wrestle with the issue which represented <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s biggest policy victory to date, the cut in the tax rate on capital gains from the sale of holdings like stocks and real estate. While <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s position prevailed in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> three weeks ago, he later lost in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> when it was dropped from an anti-deficit bill. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, has said he does n't think the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will pass a capital gains cut this year, and said it was `` irresponsible'' to be pushing the initiative when what <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> needs to do is cut the deficit. `` I would like to see the president devote as much time to historic events in Western and <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> ... I'd like to see him devote a fraction of the time to that, that he is to this capital gains debacle,'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> also faces a deadline this week to pass a new stopgap spending bill to fund most government programs until the regular money bills can be enacted. The new spending measure will include up to $ 2.5 billion in aid for victims of the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> earthquake, as well as money for ongoing cleanup following Hurricane Hugo.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891023-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-23-89 0141EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Anthony-Gingrich     10-23 0355</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Anthony-Gingrich,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrat Fires Business Tabloid Article at GOP Nemesis</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
