<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EvilSpirits-Scam     11-25 0308</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Evil Spirits-Scam,0316</SECOND>
<HEAD>Women Promise to Lift Curse From Family; Instead Make Off With $10,000</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two women who told a man they were removing an evil curse placed upon him and his family made off with his $ 9,500 life savings plus $ 500 he borrowed from his daughter, authorities said. The women took the $ 10,000 from <PERSON> Guadenecio </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruiz </PERSON> <PERSON> Soliven </PERSON> and promised to bless it, but disappeared sometime late Wednesday, police Detective Lt. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaida </PERSON> said Thursday. <PERSON> Soliven </PERSON> told authorities the scam began Monday when a middle-aged woman stopped him on the street and told him he was troubled by evil spirits but that she could help him. `` She told me a relative wanted to do something to make me get sick and die,'' said <PERSON> Soliven </PERSON> who moved to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> from the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> last March. `` She told me I could have a spiritual healing to drive off the evil spirts. It would cure me and all my family.'' He said he followed the woman to a house where she and a second woman chanted and rubbed raw eggs on him. The women asked for $ 10,000 to combat the spirits, <PERSON> Soliven </PERSON> said. He said he took the $ 9,500 he had in the bank out in three separate withdrawals over two days and borrowed another $ 500 from his daughter. `` It was my whole life savings,'' he said. `` But they told me if I did n't have full trust in them, the power of the ritual would be lost.'' The women put the money in a handkerchief to bless it, <PERSON> Soliven </PERSON> said. When he returned to the house late Wednesday, the women were gone. In the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Soliven </PERSON> said, black magic is powerful. `` People cast spells on others,'' he said. `` I've seen people with my own eyes who suffer without any cause, and I was afraid of this.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0033EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-RouletteShooting     11-25 0154</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Roulette Shooting,150</SECOND>
<HEAD>10-Year-Old Dies Playing Russian Roulette</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 10-year-old boy playing Russian roulette with his father's gun died Friday after putting the revolver to his head and pulling the trigger as four friends urged him to put the weapon away, authorities said. The boy, identified as <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, loaded the .38 - caliber revolver while his mother was at the grocery store, officials The other youngsters at the <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> home told authorities that nothing happened the first time <PERSON> John </PERSON> pulled the trigger, but that it went off the second time. The friends urged <PERSON> John </PERSON> to put the gun away, police said. `` All of them seemed to recognize the danger, except him,'' said police Lt. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>. `` They said it was dangerous, it was stupid and the gun could possibly go off.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> was pronounced dead at <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. He was the son of <PERSON> John </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     11-25 0356</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0369</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MACON, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Justice goofed, but a near-frantic woman found a judge who was sensitive to her holiday plight, despite his tough reputation. State Judge <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> said he found the woman in tears as she was going from courthouse door to courthouse door trying to find one open. The <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> woman, who had driven from <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, had been ordered to be in <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>' court `` without fail'' Friday morning or risk being held in contempt, he said. But the person who wrote the summons was in error. The courthouse was closed Friday for the Thanksgiving holiday. By chance, <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> had come in to his office to catch up on some work. The judge said the woman, whom he did not identify, told him she was arrested in <LOCATION> Macon </LOCATION> a few weeks earlier on a minor marijuana possession charge. <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, who has a reputation as being a tough judge in drug cases, said he would fine her the usual $ 250. `` Well, you've got to accommodate folks,'' the judge said. `` Life's not meant to just stomp folks down. The longer I live, the more convinced I am of that.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic Gov. Rose Mofford is n't concerned that Soviet President <PERSON> Mikahail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> outranks her in a new poll of Phoenix-area residents _ as long as he does n't run next year. `` The Governor said it does n't make any difference as long as he's not in the primary or the general election in 1990,'' press secretary <PERSON> Vada </PERSON> <PERSON> Manager </PERSON> said Friday after a poll showed <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ahead of Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON> and every other state official in the survey. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> got approval ratings from 62 percent of survey respondents, while <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> got a favorable appraisal from 56 percent. The telephone survey of <LOCATION> Maricopa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> residents conducted this month by the <ORGANIZATION> Behavior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> showed 44 percent of the respondents believed Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON> was doing a good or excellent job. The survey was based on 609 interviews with adult heads of household. Pollsters said it had a margin of error of plus or minus 4 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0040EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     11-25 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0805</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON> and singer <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> encouraged holiday shoppers to remember the less fortunate as they lit a Christmas tree adorned with cards from needy youngster at a luxury mall. `` Part of life is giving and it's that time of year,'' <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON> said Friday at the plush Fashion Show Mall on the <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. The cards on the tree listed the gifts the youngsters wanted. Shoppers were encouraged to take a card, shop for the gifts, then return them to the sponsoring <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> by mid-December. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> called the ceremony `` a great way to get into the spirit of Christmas.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Archbishop <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahony </PERSON> plans to fly to war-torn <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> this weekend to deliver 20 tons of medical supplies, food and a $ 100,000 check to the Archdiocese of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mahony </PERSON>, whose archdiocese has been swollen with Central American refugees, said Friday at a warehouse where the supplies were stockpiled that the relief effort showed the bond his diocese has with the people of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. The archbishop was joined by actors <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON>, singer <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> <PERSON> Browne </PERSON> and officials of the Operation California-USA relief organization. <PERSON> Mahony </PERSON> was to deliver the $ 500,000 worth of goods and the $ 100,000 check to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> Archbishop <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> <PERSON> Damas </PERSON> at <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>'s international airport today and then return to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mahony </PERSON>, who has called for suspension of military aid to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, also criticized human rights abuses in the nation where six Jesuit priests were slain last week, allegedly by men wearing army uniforms. `` I have to ask myself how 80,000 people have been killed, human rights are totally disregarded and no one is ever responsible,'' he said. `` What the church is doing is supporting the people. They're feeding them, giving them medical aid and giving them hope.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>KENNEBUNKPORT, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the first lady are being lampooned again in a comic book, but this time Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> will play a more prominent role in response to popular demand, the authors said. The first <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> comic book by <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> cartoonists <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Pert </PERSON> and <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> featured the Bushes traveling through Vacationland, as <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> calls itself, and becoming hopelessly lost. The latest spoof, `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>'s Christmas Crisis,'' to be released Dec. 5, features <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> searching for the biggest Christmas tree in <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> and finding themselves in competition with a heartless timber company. `` We listened to what people told us,'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. `` We put <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> in heavier.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>INGLEWOOD, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rock fans gave special thanks and some paid more than $ 600 for tickets to watch former Beatle <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> perform at a Thanksgiving concert. `` A man like this, you have to think of him as an old master,'' said fan <PERSON> Teddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON>, 37. `` He's like <PERSON> Rembrandt </PERSON>, <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON>. That's what <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> is to modern music. The concert before 15,000 people Thursday was part of a five-night gig that marked the first time <PERSON> McCarney </PERSON> has played in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> in 13 years. `` I'm 42 years old and I have been waiting 25 years for this moment,'' said fan <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON>. `` This is the epitome of my life. Unfortunately, everything is downhill from here.'' <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> opened the concert with `` Figure of Eight'' from his newest album. He followed that with `` Flowers in the Dirt,'' `` Jet'' and `` Band on the Run.'' After that, Beatle songs took center stage.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sardi </PERSON>'s, the legenday Broadway theater district restaurant, may once again be owned by <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Sardi </PERSON>. The new owner, <ORGANIZATION> Sardi </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, and its president, <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>, failed to make the monthly purchase payments to <PERSON> Sardi </PERSON>, and Judge <PERSON> Burton </PERSON> <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON> ruled Friday that <PERSON> Sardi </PERSON> can foreclose on the note he holds. <PERSON> Sardi </PERSON> sold the restaurant to <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> and his group in 1986 for $ 6.2 million with $ 1 million cash down. After one default in April, the debt was restructured. In July, <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>'s group failed to make a required monthly payment of $ 136,262.38 and <PERSON> Sardi </PERSON> sued. The judge said <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> had accused <PERSON> Sardi </PERSON> of trying to grab the restaurant back because this theater season has the potential to be Broadway's best in years. But <PERSON> Sardi </PERSON> is `` not under any legal obligation to renegotiate the terms of the note with the defendant,'' <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>'s lawyer, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON>, said he had not discussed the ruling with his client. Open since 1922, <PERSON> Sardi </PERSON>'s is a favorite hangout for Broadway stars and star-gazers. Located in the heart of the theater district, the restaurant's walls are adorned with caricatures of stage greats.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Hyland     11-25 0370</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Hyland,0380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Longtime Hughes Executive Hyland Dead at 92</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LANCASTER, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lawrence A. `` Pat'' <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON>, the former head of <ORGANIZATION> Hughes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> whose inventions helped pioneer radar technology and aircraft communications, died Friday. He was 92. <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON> died at <LOCATION> Antelope </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, where he had been admitted Tuesday following a heart attack, <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrman </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON> served as vice president and chief executive officer at <ORGANIZATION> Hughes </ORGANIZATION> from 1954 to 1976. He was named the aerospace firm's president and chairman of the board after founder <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> died in 1976 Throughout, however, <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON> ran the company. He retired in 1984, assuming the title of chairman emeritus, and continued to work out of his office several times a week. Under <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON>'s tenure, <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> grew from a modest producer of airborne fire control systems to the nation's largest defense electronics company and a leading builder of communications satellites. <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON> held an early patent that contributed to the development of radio detection and imaging, or radar, which bounces radio signals off distant objects to determine their location. <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON> was born in the <LOCATION> Canadian </LOCATION> province of <LOCATION> Nova </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Scotia </LOCATION> on Aug. 26, 1897, and came with his family to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> at the age of 2. He served as a sergeant in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Army Field Artillery during World War I, receiving five battle stars for his service with the Second Division in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> He joined the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, where he worked as a chief radioman between 1920 and 1926 and helped demonstrate a blind landing system for aircraft. In 1926 he joined the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> as a radio engineer and, in 1932, demonstrated the reflection of radio waves from aircraft. <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON> held other patents that enabled aircraft to communicate with each other and with the ground via radio and to determine their altitude during blind landings. Many of his developments were adopted in standard aircraft electronics systems. <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON> founded <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> in 1932, heading the firm until it merged into <ORGANIZATION> Bendix </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> five years later. During a 17-year tenure with <PERSON> Bendix </PERSON> he became vice president in charge of engineering before leaving to join <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON> is survived by his wife, <PERSON> Muriel </PERSON>, and a daughter.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0042EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DrunksAgainstDrunks     11-25 0559</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drunks Against Drunks,0572</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Drunken Drivers Launch Their Own Campaign for Sobriety</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-CDC--Drinking, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHELLE LOCKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SPRINGFIELD, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Members of Drunk Drivers Against Driving Drunk say they hope their painful experiences will encourage others not to flirt with the dangerous pastime of drinking and driving. `` We're like blood brothers,'' said member <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlisle </PERSON>. `` We've been to the pits and now we've been able to get our lives back together again and we want to be able to go out into the community and tell them and explain to them why -LRB- drunken drivers -RRB- have to be controlled. I think somebody who's been through it three times has got a pretty good insight into it.'' <LOCATION> DDADD </LOCATION>, made up of about a dozen people, including advisers, was formed three years ago by people who had been sent to the Western <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Correctional Center for multiple drunken driving offenses, group coordinator <PERSON> Roz </PERSON> <PERSON> Canter </PERSON> said. However, the group is not affiliated with the center, which was created to house the increased number of people sent to jail when <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> toughened its drunken driving laws. DDADD members speak at programs for drunken driving offenders about `` how we got there and the things that brought us to our knees,'' <PERSON> Carlisle </PERSON> said. He said the group does not include anyone who was involved in a fatal crash. `` My story was that I had a 32-year history of abuse of drugs and alcohol and I reached a point where I was convicted of three DUI's in the course of 18 months,'' he said. The loss of his home, friends and possessions coupled with a barrage of counseling helped him admit to having a problem, <PERSON> Carlisle </PERSON> said. `` I was lucky,'' he said. `` I drove many many times under the influence of alcohol but fortunately I never hurt any one. I cracked up cars.'' The 51-year-old tool-and-die maker said he got away with driving drunk for more than two decades, but tougher driving laws promoted by Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> sent him to the correctional center. `` It's the best thing that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> did,'' he said. Despite its masculine sounding acronym, there are women in DDADD and <PERSON> Carlisle </PERSON> said the name was n't meant as a challenge to the well-known <ORGANIZATION> MADD </ORGANIZATION>, Mothers Against Drunk Driving. DDADD was formally incorporated in August under the name <ORGANIZATION> Former </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drunk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drivers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Against </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Driving </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drunk </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Canter </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, assistant director of public affairs at the national headquarters of <ORGANIZATION> MADD </ORGANIZATION>, in <LOCATION> Hurst </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, said the concept of former drunken drivers voluntarily engaging in educational efforts appeared to be new. <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Nepomuceno </PERSON> of the local chapter of <ORGANIZATION> MADD </ORGANIZATION> said she thought the appearance of DDADD was a good thing. `` They are taking responsibility now for their choices,'' she said. `` The hardest part for the victim is that -LRB- drunken drivers -RRB- never really say that they're sorry. But I think to hear a group of people that has been driving drunk and are now really saying that they're sorry for what they've done. ... I think it's a big step.'' <PERSON> Canter </PERSON> said the group has kept a low profile. `` Basically what they do, they do n't point the finger at people, they just share their own personal experiences of what happened to them to try to encourage other people to not have to go through the things they went through,'' <PERSON> Canter </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SFQuake-Shacks     11-25 0476</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-Shacks,0492</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quake of '89 Shakes Preservationist of '06 `Big One'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES O. CLIFFORD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The quake of'89 rattled the director of an organization dedicated to preserving the little shacks that housed refugees from the earthquake and fire of'06. <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Cryan </PERSON>, who founded the <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Preservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appreciation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refugee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shacks </ORGANIZATION>, has decided to pull up stakes and leave quake-prone <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. `` This little society, born of the quake, has died of another,'' said <PERSON> Cryan </PERSON>, who founded the organization after she unknowingly bought a refugee shack in the early 1980s. <PERSON> Cryan </PERSON>, 47, said the Oct. 17 earthquake that hit <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> `` threw me for a loop.'' `` I have decided to begin life anew in my home state of <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> and am returning to my ancestral town of <LOCATION> Oshkosh </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Cryan </PERSON>, who also lost her job as an administrative assistant shortly after the quake. `` <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> will undoubtedly undergo seismic upgrades that will obliterate the shacks,'' she said. `` I could n't bear to be around to see it.'' More than 60 of the 5,610 redwood cottages known to exist are still standing, said <PERSON> Cryan </PERSON>. The cottages, some as small as 10 by 14 feet, were designed by <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> engineers and built with federal funds and donations in public parks and squares. There were 11 shack camps around the city. The families were given the cottages when they moved the structures to private land. There was no <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale when the quake hit on April 18, 1906, but the magnitude was later figured to be 8.3. The quake and the fire that followed killed somewhere from 700 to 2,000 people. Last month's temblor measured 7.1 and killed 67 people, more than half of them on a freeway that collapsed in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>. The shacks were put into service after the 1906 quake and fire while 25,000 people were still living in canvas Army tents in parks around <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. After living in the shack cities, more than 5,000 families resettled and took their shacks with them, dragging them away with horses. The structures ended up scattered all over the city. <PERSON> Cryan </PERSON> was living in one of the old cottages and did n't even know it. `` Someone told me the house was a refugee cottage and I checked it out,'' she said. `` That was about three months after I moved in. It was three of them joined together. I got it recognized as a landmark.'' <PERSON> Cryan </PERSON> has accumulated shack doors, windows and other memorabilia through the years. She's `` passing the society's torch'' to her friend <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Falcon </PERSON>, who is storing the items that include an architectural model of a shack town of 22 cottages. <PERSON> Cryan </PERSON> says the shacks were `` the original modular housing.'' `` They feel like homes, they make you feel safe and cozy, even though they're small.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iran-Contra Bjt   11-25 0472</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra, Bjt,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prosecutors Appeal Dismissal of Iran-Contra Case Against CIA Official</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST ^Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prosecutors are asking a federal appeals court to revive the criminal case against a former <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> station chief in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> who was caught up in the Iran-Contra affair. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Court Judge <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Hilton </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, dismissed criminal charges against <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> on Friday, ruling <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> could not get a fair trial because the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> barred use of classified materials considered important to the defense. Independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s office quickly filed a notice of appeal with the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>. Prosecutors said the ruling places <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> outside the law. `` We believe that all citizens _ including high-ranking government officials involved in covert operations _ should be accountable to the law,'' said associate independent counsel <PERSON> Laurence </PERSON> <PERSON> Shtasel </PERSON>, who is prosecuting the <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> case. Prosecutors are appealing both the judge's ruling Friday and his July decision to reject proposed substitutions for the secrets. <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> assisted former White House aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s secret Contra resupply effort during a congressional ban on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid to the Contras. The effort in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> was financed partly by diverted profits from secret arms sales to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> was charged with two counts of obstruction of justice and two counts of making false statements. Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> on Wednesday barred courtroom use of classified materials <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> said would prove his case. The secrets _ said by the judge to be `` essential to this defendant'' _ concern <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> stations and programs in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> has claimed some activities to help <PERSON> North </PERSON> were intertwined with U.S.-assisted plans by <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> against possible invasion by <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> says, for example, that he did not lie when he told the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> inspector general an airstrip built by the North network was initiated by the Costa Rican government. <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> said after <ORGANIZATION> Hilton </ORGANIZATION>'s ruling Friday that he feared <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> operatives performing `` legitimate duties'' could be subjected to a `` politically motivated prosecution.'' `` That is a chilling message to people who put their lives on the line every day,'' he said. Iran-Contra prosecutors have said much of the classified information the government is protecting constitutes `` fictional secrets'' which have been revealed publicly before. But <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> said the secrets would compromise national security and added that its disclosure would have compromised intelligence sources. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> suggested an agreement could be reached with <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> to allow a trial for <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>. `` I continue to believe that this case can be tried without compromising the defendant's right to a fair trial or the national security of this country,'' he said in a statement Friday. `` The independent counsel and I agree that the district court's earlier rejection of substitutions and alternatives to the release of classified material constituted reversible error.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush Bjt   11-25 0556</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush, Thatcher Discuss Upcoming US-Soviet Summit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is assuring <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> that <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s stability will be foremost in his mind when he meets next week with Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> met for 4 -LCB- hours Friday at the presidential retreat in <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> David </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, to discuss a range of topics, in particular the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>'s relations with <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> European nations that are moving towards democracy and independence from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. `` The two leaders agreed on the need for European stability as <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> faces the changes in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>,'' White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said in a statement. The meeting came the week before <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> flies to the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> for a two-day summit meeting with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, although officials say Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s visit was scheduled before that summit was arranged. The prime minister told a press conference she does not expect `` great or unusual pronouncements from this -LRB- Bush-Gorbachev -RRB- meeting.'' `` I do n't think there will be a great deal of difficulty or sudden surprises about this meeting,'' she said. As to nervousness from some quarters that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s support for East block reform efforts might foreshadow a diminished role for <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION> forces, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said, `` <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> is absolutely vital'' to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s continued defense. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> described <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> as `` in very close accord in their examination of all the issues discussed today,'' which included the possible topics for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s Dec. 2-3 shipboard meeting with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> off the coast of <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>. That included support for glasnost and perestroika, the new Soviet openness and economic restructuring that have led to changes within the borders of Soviet allies, he said. `` They both emphasized the pursuit of democracy as the first step in the reform process,'' said <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. As he greeted Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> at Camp David, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he wanted to get her views `` on the rapid changes in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the strength of the alliance and everything else.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> in her news conference later described their talks as `` very relaxed, very valuable.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has sought to assure Western allies the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would not act unilaterally on matters of concern to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, such as the role of <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>, promising them `` no surprises'' in his talks with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in an interview with foreign journalists released Friday that he is `` prepared to think anew'' about reducing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troop levels abroad in light of East-bloc rapid changes but wo n't act unilaterally <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will meet with President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> on Dec. 16 in the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> to discuss the summit and other issues. French officials said the meeting would be held on the island of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Martin </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> told reporters she and the president did not differ on the <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> question. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> met as <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s entire hardline <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leadership resigned in the wake of massive pro-democracy protests, and <PERSON> Karel </PERSON> <PERSON> Urbanek </PERSON>, a former party leader of the <LOCATION> Czech </LOCATION> <LOCATION> republic </LOCATION>, was elected to replace the party leader. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> told reporters she hoped to see <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> become a democracy. `` But the wish is not the deed and it does take quite a long time to get all the democratic structures into place. And they must be genuine structures not just a facade,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0016EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-HolidayTraffic     11-25 0008</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Holiday Traffic,0008</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 Midnight EST: 152
</TEXT>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     11-25 0066</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0068</SECOND>
<BYLINE>Thurdays numbers were not available. ^By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 10; 11; 14; 18; 25; 31.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 03; 05; 06; 09; 10; 11.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday 54 Lotto Game: 01; 08; 23; 39; 44; 48. Supplementary 34.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 1-2-0; 6-2-6-2; 6-1-6-9-8; 2-0-1-0-1-6.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DangerousToys Bjt   11-25 0494</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dangerous Toys, Bjt,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Group Unwraps Hazards in Holiday Gift Toys</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENISE CABRERA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A consumer group is warning that stores nationwide this holiday season are offering toys that violate federal safety standards and pose a choking hazard for young children. `` On this, the biggest shopping day of the year, parents should not assume that the toys they find on the shelves are safe,'' said <PERSON> Lucinda </PERSON> <PERSON> Sikes </PERSON>, consumer director for <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, on Friday, the start of the holiday shopping season. Inadequate funding and staffing for state and federal enforcement agencies to monitor dangerous toys are one reason the group founded by <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Nader </PERSON> blamed for the availability of the items. <PERSON> Sikes </PERSON> said there are particular dangers `` for children who still tend to put things in their mouths.'' `` Shoppers should carefully examine toys for small parts that break off or are detachable,'' <PERSON> Sikes </PERSON> cautioned. The warnings came as <ORGANIZATION> PIRG </ORGANIZATION> released its first national survey of unsafe toys. Efforts to reach several toy manufacturers whose products are named in the survey were unsuccessful. A spokesman for the federal <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Product </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> said the agency would collect and test samples of the toys and `` take appropriate action'' if needed. The survey, titled `` Small Parts, Big Hazards: Unsafe Toys in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' was conducted in October and November in 105 stores in the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. The report focused on small parts that are regulated by the <ORGANIZATION> CPSC </ORGANIZATION> and which `` continue to be the leading cause of toy-related deaths to young children,'' the group said. Thirty-four children died in toy-related incidents between January 1988 and September 1989, according to <ORGANIZATION> CPSC </ORGANIZATION> figures cited in the report. The report called for `` mandatory, descriptive age labeling legislation,'' saying many toys are inappropriately labeled. Currently toy makers voluntarily include age labeling on toys. However, toys intended for children under age three must meet federal standards for small parts. A toy or a toy part that fits into a truncated cylinder with a diameter of 1.25 inches and a depth ranging from 1 to 2.25 inches fails the <ORGANIZATION> CPSC </ORGANIZATION> small parts test. The cylinder is designed to replicate a child's windpipe, said <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Giles </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> CPSC </ORGANIZATION>. The toys cited were recommended for children ages 9 months to six years or included no age label. Those recommended for children under age three that do not meet the small parts requirements violate government standards, <PERSON> Giles </PERSON> said. He said the Oregon <ORGANIZATION> PIRG </ORGANIZATION> had notified the <ORGANIZATION> CPSC </ORGANIZATION> about 12 toys it found in stores in the state that may pose a small parts hazard. The national survey is modeled after one conducted annually by the <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> group since 1986. <PERSON> Giles </PERSON> said the agency would collect and test samples of the 12 toys and `` take appropriate action.'' `` We will do the same for the larger list as soon as we get it,'' he added.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BudgetBattle Bjt   11-25 0648</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget Battle, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Darman Plan Puts Agencies on the Spot for Spending</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 White House budget director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> wants to use a novel budget review process to help the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration meet its deficit reduction goals. <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>, has told administration officials that <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> will use a two-track approach to reviewing their budgets this year that will force them to compete with other high-priority programs for a limited pool of extra money. <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>'s strategy, revealed this week in a letter to agency heads, leaves federal budget officers scrambling for ways to convince the White House to overturn proposed <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> cuts in their spending requests for the 1991 fiscal year. Many budget officers planned to be at their desks through this weekend to meet a Monday deadline for submitting their appeals of <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> decisions on their budgets. The administration is racing to meet a Jan. 8 deadline for submitting its new budget to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the first full budget submission President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will get to make. Last February, he submitted various revisions to the budget left by former President <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. Federal agencies submitted their initial requests to <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> on Sept. 1. Last Monday, they got the news on what reduced funding levels <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> will be recommending. The <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> proposals were accompanied by a letter from <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> explaining a new appeal process the agencies must follow in trying to overturn budget office decisions. Previously, `` an agency would recommend a very big increase,'' <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> said in an interview taped Friday on the `` <ORGANIZATION> Evans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Novak'' for broadcast on the <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> `` would say, no, no, that's too much, and then the fight would be within that range. And there was a tendency for presidents to come along and split the difference, so you would always be leveling up. `` What this is saying is, if anybody has ideas for meritorious investment, as they see it, fine. Let's have them compete against all other such good ideas, and in the end we'll take the best ideas,'' said <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>. Part of the process is similar to previous years. Agencies will be able to negotiate with <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> over the proposed spending reductions. But if an agency decides to carry its appeal to the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> has added a new twist. The appeal will automatically toss the program onto a second budget track in which the increased spending will be competing with other programs that are bidding for higher spending. In his letter, first revealed in Friday's <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> said the agencies seeking increases `` will have to compete with each other ... for resources that are in a limited pool.'' <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> assured <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> secretaries that `` you will have an opportunity to present your views directly to the president prior to his decision.'' But agency budget officials said <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>'s strategy puts the budget office in a strong negotiating position to defend its recommended cuts. For one thing, the amount of time <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will have to devote to budget appeal hearings will be limited by other issues the president must address, such as the upcoming Soviet summit. Given the Jan. 8 deadline for submitting a budget to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, all spending decisions will have to be made by mid-December. `` There will be limited opportunities for even making presentations to the president, given his travel schedule,'' said one budget officer, who spoke on condition his name not be used. In a meeting with reporters earlier in the week, <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> stressed the administration is facing a big challenge in meeting a goal to reduced the deficit to $ 64 billion. That deficit target is for the 1991 fiscal year, which begins next Oct. 1. The administration reached agreement with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> this week on $ 14.6 billion in deficit cuts aimed at meeting this year's overall Gramm-Rudman deficit target of $ 100 billion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Cheney-NATO     11-25 0207</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cheney-NATO,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cheney to Attend NATO Defense Meeting in Brussels Nov. 28</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> is beginning a trip to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> today that will include discussions of fast-moving events in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> with <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> defense ministers at a meeting in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION> is traveling first to the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>, where he will meet with the <LOCATION> Dutch </LOCATION> prime minister and visit an American military unit before proceeding to <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION> for the annual <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Planning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> meeting Nov. 28-29. A senior administration official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> agenda includes discussion of issues such as cost-sharing, arms control and defense planning and the ongoing negotiations to reduce conventional forces in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. But, the official added, `` Overwhelming the agenda is what's going on in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> ... Our European friends feel the same excitement we do.'' Despite the rapid moves <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bloc </LOCATION> countries are making towards democracy, the official said <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>'s overall message is to `` reaffirm the need for <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>.'' He added the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has pledged to maintain its financial commitment to <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> through 1990. This comes as the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> is drawing up plans that would slash planned increases in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> defense spending by $ 180 billion in the 1992-1994 budget years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0103EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AgentOrange     11-25 0405</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Agent Orange,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Secretary Derwinski Delays Agent Orange Decision</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Veterans' Affairs Secretary <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> says he wo n't decide before March whether to grant disability payments to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans exposed to Agent Orange. <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> said Friday he wo n't make his decision until the <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> releases the results of a study begun in 1985. The study is expected in March. After a Nov. 3 advisory committee meeting, <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> had promised a decision in a few weeks. <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> epidemiologists in 1985 launched a major study of the health records of thousands of veterans to see if they were at increased risk of five types of cancer: lymphoma, soft-tissue sarcoma, and nasal, nasopharyngeal and liver cancer. The advisory committee said after reviewing more than 30 studies that it could not find a statistically significant relationship between a rare cancer, non-Hodgkin's lymphoma, and exposure to the chemicals used in the defoliant Agent Orange. In May, a federal judge in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> ruled that the department had been too strict in denying disability benefits on the grounds there was no proof that those chemicals caused the illnesses cited by some 34,000 veterans. Instead, the judge said the department need only find statistically significant associations between exposure and illness. <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> decided not to appeal the decision. <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> said in a statement Friday that several committee members had said the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> study could weigh heavily in their recommendations. `` I am as determined now to resolve this issue as I was when I decided not to appeal the court decision, but it is logical to wait for a few extra months for the results of the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> cancer study,'' he said. Agent Orange, used in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> to strip vegetation cover used by guerrillas, has been blamed by veterans' groups for many disorders, particularly cancer, because it was contaminated with dioxins, a byproduct of its manufacture. Some of the 75 dioxin compounds are among the most powerful causes of cancer ever tested in laboratory animals, but it has never been proven they can cause cancer in humans. Exposure to dioxin in high concentrations is known to cause chloracne, a skin disorder, and recent work has led some scientists to suspect dioxin may also cause birth defects. In 1986, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> required the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> to give hospital care to any veteran exposed to Agent Orange in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> unless the VA found some other cause for his disability.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CompulsiveGambling Bjt   11-25 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Compulsive Gambling, Bjt,0724</SECOND>
<HEAD>Casino Owner Betting on Program to Help Compulsive Gamblers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURA MYERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RENO, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Like the addict who admits he has a problem, a casino operator has conceded that compulsive gambling is a disease and some of its patrons and employees are infected. So far, <ORGANIZATION> Harrah </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> stands alone in <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> in its public confession that the state's No. 1 industry and its biggest taxpayer is more than recreational fun for up to six million Americans. `` We did n't know if it existed,'' said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Harrah </PERSON>'s general counsel and chairman of an employee task force that studied compulsive gambling for more than a year before recommending the company help addicts Last month, <PERSON> Harrah </PERSON>'s posted signs in its five <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> casinos telling people how to get help for gambling problems. The company also agreed to pay one year's costs to operate a hotline to take those calls. `` Our role in the problem gambling issue is not to change anyone's behavior, but simply to provide help for people who might have a gambling problem,'' said <PERSON> Harrah </PERSON>'s President <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Satre </PERSON>. As many as 12 percent of <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> casino employees are compulsive gamblers, according to some estimates. Seven percent to 9 percent of Nevadans share the problem, compared to 2 percent to 5 percent of the general <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> population. To those who find it dicey for a casino owner to be helping people overcome a disease that seems to boost business, <PERSON> Satre </PERSON> responds that treatment could diminish employee absenteeism, petty theft and misconduct. Casinos would be better off without addicted gamblers who are trouble because they can run up huge debts and sometimes become angry or abusive when on a losing streak, he said. `` Helping employees and guests with this problem is both the right thing to do and also a very good businesses decision, not only for <PERSON> Harrah </PERSON>'s but for the entire gaming industry,'' <PERSON> Satre </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, casinos have had such hotlines in place since gaming began in 1978, and spend $ 300,000 a year to help compulsive gamblers. In <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, casinos have all but ignored gambling addicts since betting was legalized 58 years ago. For the state, which receives more than half its annual revenues from casino taxes, declaring gambling a problem would be akin to admitting some of the golden eggs laid by the gaming goose are really fool's gold, said <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Gaming </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` For now, I think most of the casinos are watching the <PERSON> Harrah </PERSON>'s program to see what kind of effect it has,'' he said Casinos paid $ 73.6 million into the state treasury on earnings of $ 1.21 billion in the July-September quarter, according to the state <ORGANIZATION> Gaming </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Dian </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, volunteer executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Nevada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> on Compulsive Gambling, which runs the Las Vegas-based hotline, said most <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> casino operators are like the addicted gambler who denies he has a problem. `` We just need to do a lot more education because there's still this Wild West mentality out there that gambling's just fun,'' she said. Ms. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said the month-old hotline gets three to five calls daily. Most calls come from friends and family of addicted gamblers, she said. The ones from bettors do n't last long. `` There's a real problem of denial involved in this just like for alcohol and drug addicts,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, a mental health therapist. Only one certified hospital exists in <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> to help compulsive gamblers, she said, and insurance companies do n't recognize the problem as a disease like alcoholism or drug addiction. `` We're just in the beginning stages of addressing this problem,'' she said. Ms. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said publicity about <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reds </ORGANIZATION> manager suspended for life from baseball for betting on the game, has helped gained legitimacy for people treating compulsive gambling. According to various studies, the typical gambler is male betwen the ages of 20 and 40, lives with his spouse and has at least a high school education. `` I can walk through a casino and tell you who the compulsive gamblers are,'' she added. `` They're mesmerized by the machines. They're in love with them. They ca n't take their eyes off them. It's frightening.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0105EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MIAMeetings     11-25 0108</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-MIA Meetings,110</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Meetings in Hanoi</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Vietnamese technical specialists will meet in <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> next week to discuss cooperation in the effort to account for Americans still missing from the Vietnam War. Lt. Col. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>, commander of the Joint Casualty Resolution Center in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, will lead the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> delegation to the meeting Monday through Wednesday, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said Friday. It will be the first technical meeting since President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s special emissary, retired Army Gen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vessey </PERSON>, agreed with Vietnamese Foreign Minister <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> <PERSON> Co </PERSON> <PERSON> Thach </PERSON> in October on expanded cooperation About 2,300 Americans still are listed as missing in <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FosterAttack     11-25 0225</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Foster Attack,0231</SECOND>
<HEAD>Foster Mother of 10 Killed in Drug-Related Battle</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CANTON, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A foster mother of 10 children was killed in a gun battle between her son and four men that erupted over a soured drug deal, police said. The foster children in the care of <PERSON> Elsie </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 59, were herded into a basement by relatives during the fight early Friday and were not hurt. Mrs. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s son, <PERSON> Darryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON>, and another man were injured, witnesses and police said. According to witnesses, the men broke into Mrs. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s home and confronted <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> during a family Thanksgiving party in the city in northeastern <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ross </PERSON>, 25, and <PERSON> Moses </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, 36, apparently shot each other, the Stark County Sheriff's <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> will be charged with murder, said chief sheriff's deputy <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Umpleby </PERSON> Three other men will be charged with complicity to aggravated burglary, he said. Mrs. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was shot in the chest when she tried to persuade <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> to leave the house, deputies said. Mrs. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s daughter, <PERSON> Veronica </PERSON> <PERSON> Early </PERSON>, said the foster children, ages 9 months to 16 years, were sleeping upstairs when the shooting began. They awoke and came downstairs but were rushed by relatives to safety in the basement, Ms. Early said. The children were placed in other foster homes by the county <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, the agency said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Obit-Lenihan     11-25 0173</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Lenihan,160</SECOND>
<HEAD>Early Director of Navy's WAVES Dies.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Retired <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Capt. <PERSON> Rita </PERSON> <PERSON> Lenihan </PERSON>, who served as director of the women's part of the service from 1966 to 1971, has died of cancer at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>, Md. <PERSON> Lenihan </PERSON> died Thursday at the age of 75. She joined the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> in 1943, when WAVES, which stood for Women Appointed for Voluntary Service, was still new. While serving as a newly commissioned ensign, <PERSON> Lenihan </PERSON>, who had majored in Latin at the College of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Elizabeth </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Morristown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, wrote the motto for the coat of arms for WAVES officers: `` <ORGANIZATION> Honoris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Est </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nobis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navales </ORGANIZATION>,'' which means `` It is an honor for us to serve the fleet.'' <PERSON> Lenihan </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Monroe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, spent most of her career in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, although she also was stationed in <LOCATION> Newport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>, and in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. Her military decorations include the Legion of Merit. Survivors include a brother, <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lenihan </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Verona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, and a sister, <PERSON> Priscilla </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawler </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Woodbridge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     11-25 0067</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0071</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: Retransmitting to fix slug</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 10; 11; 14; 18; 25; 31.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 03; 05; 06; 09; 10; 11.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday 54 Lotto Game: 01; 08; 23; 39; 44; 48. Supplementary 34.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 1-2-0; 6-2-6-2; 6-1-6-9-8; 2-0-1-0-1-6.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpaceShuttle     11-25 0314</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Shuttle,0321</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shuttle Flight Continues in Secret, Astronauts Prepare for Sunday
Landing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURA TOLLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SPACE CENTER, Houston (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The five Discovery astronauts worked under a shroud of secrecy today while testing the shuttle's control systems in preparation for a Sunday landing in the <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Desert </LOCATION> A news blackout ordered by the military has prevented <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> from talking about its classified mission, but sources said the crew's main goal was to deploy a spy satellite Discovery is scheduled to land Sunday at 7:02 p.m. PST at <ORGANIZATION> Edwards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. It will be the third after-dark landing in 32 shuttle flights. While the <ORGANIZATION> Johnson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> has been mum about all aspects of the mission since Thursday, it is assumed that the commander and pilot Friday tested the shuttle's flight control systems and steered thrusters to make sure they are ready for the trip back home _ a fiery, hourlong dive through the Earth's atmosphere. Besides deploying a spy satellite, the Discovery astronauts reportedly have been conducting experiments for the Strategic Defense Initiative missile defense system. Neither <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> nor the Pentagon would discuss the release of the satellite or other mission objectives. The last official status report _ issued Thursday night by <ORGANIZATION> Mission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> _ stated that the `` crew is doing well and the orbiter continues to perform satisfactorily.'' Sources close to the project said the astronauts had accomplished their main goal of deploying a 2 -LCB- - ton, $ 300 million satellite capable of monitoring military and diplomatic communications in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> The Discovery mission is the fifth shuttle flight dedicated solely to military research. Discovery is commanded by <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Col. <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON>. The crew includes <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Col. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Blaha </PERSON>, the pilot, and three mission specialists: <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Capt. <PERSON> Manley </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Story </PERSON> <PERSON> Musgrave </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kathryn </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornton </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Czech-Urbanek 1stLd-Writethru a0695 11-25 0548</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Czech-Urbanek, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0695,0564</SECOND>
<HEAD>Urbanek: Bland Party Man Who May Restore Faith</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS four grafs after 9th pvs `The official...' to ADD Urbanek
article in March; picks up graf 10 pvs `Born March 22...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>With Czechoslovakia, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PRAGUE, Czechoslovakia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Karel </PERSON> <PERSON> Urbanek </PERSON>, an obscure, unknown bureaucrat picked Friday as the new <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief, represents the party's best hope of restoring the authority it has lost in two decades of hard-line policy. News that his predecessor, <PERSON> Milos </PERSON> <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON>, had resigned brought a throng of people into the streets of <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> in a spontaneous explosion of joy. Reaction to the choice of <PERSON> Urbanek </PERSON>, however, was reserved. <PERSON> Urbanek </PERSON>, 48, joined the old 13-man Politburo 13 months ago. Since then, according to a senior Western diplomat, <PERSON> Urbanek </PERSON> has spent much of his time traveling in the provinces and apparently has gained support from regional party chiefs. His most recent responsibilities as head of a new council for the party in the <LOCATION> Czech </LOCATION> <LOCATION> republic </LOCATION> should have given him clear insight into the state of the economy and the party's standing in <LOCATION> Bohemia </LOCATION> and his native <LOCATION> Moravia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Urbanek </PERSON>'s greatest asset is his relative obscurity. Under Communist Party custom, the general secretary must come from Politburo ranks. Of the 13 men available, <PERSON> Urbanek </PERSON> was one of the few not directly associated with the unpopular hard-line policies in place since 1968, and thus has a chance to restore the party's flagging standing. The official <ORGANIZATION> CTK </ORGANIZATION> news agency said <PERSON> Urbanek </PERSON> was elected general secretary in a secret ballot of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, with 136 votes for and seven against. It was not known if there were any abstentions. What little is known of <PERSON> Urbanek </PERSON> suggests that in the past he has been an orthodox Communist. In an article in the party weekly Tribuna in March, <PERSON> Urbanek </PERSON> took the standard line of acknowledging shortcomings in the present system but excluding independent groups from dialogue. He wrote that prominent dissidents `` are not concerned with democracy, freedom and the environment, with dialogue in the realm of Socialism, but with a return to capitalism with all the consequences this would have for our country. `` It is therefore impossible to give in to them,'' he wrote. Born March 22, 1941, at <LOCATION> Bojkovice </LOCATION> in south <LOCATION> Moravia </LOCATION> to a peasant family, <PERSON> Urbanek </PERSON> joined the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in 1963, studied at an industrial school and joined Czechoslovak railways as a station master in his hometown in 1970. In 1973, he became part of the regional <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> committee in south <LOCATION> Moravia </LOCATION> while studying part-time at the party's institute in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> By 1982, he had risen to head the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Brno </LOCATION>, the capital of <LOCATION> Moravia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s third-largest city. In March 1988, he made it onto the influential <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> apparatus. Seven months later, he vaulted on to the ruling party Politburo in a reshuffle that saw four other men named to the ruling body. At the same time, he was made head of the newly created <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Work </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> Czech </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, which until then had not had its own <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> organization _ something that existed in <LOCATION> Slovakia </LOCATION> since 1969. He also was named head of a <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> commission for the political system in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>. Other details of his personal life were not known.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HazelwoodHearing     11-25 0409</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hazelwood Hearing,0418</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hazelwood Hearing to Begin Monday</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSAN GALLAGHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANCHORAGE, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The skipper of the <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valdez </ORGANIZATION> will try to get his case dismissed by claiming immunity from prosecution and seeking to have the results of a sobriety test thrown out of court. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> is expected to return to <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> for a hearing on the motions in the <ORGANIZATION> Anchorage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> that begins Monday and could last up to two weeks. His trial is set for Jan. 22. The 43-year-old mariner from <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, was fired by <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> soon after the tanker Exxon Valdez struck a Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> reef March 24 and spilled nearly 11 million gallons of oil. The worst oil spill in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history blackened pristine shores, killed tens of thousands of birds and marine mammals and disrupted lucrative fishing seasons. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> said it spent more than $ 1 billion on oil spill claims and cleanup work, and state officials say the cleanup still is not finished. <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> faces misdemeanor charges of reckless endangerment, operating a vessel while intoxicated and negligent discharge of oil, and three felony counts of criminal mischief. If convicted of the three felonies, he faces a possible maximum penalty of 10 years in prison and $ 100,000 in fines. The case was moved from <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION> because of concerns publicity about the spill would make it too hard to find an impartial jury in <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION>. The southcentral <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> port town relies heavily on the oil industry for jobs and also has commercial fishing interests. Defense motions include claims that <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> received immunity from prosecution when he reported his ship's grounding and oil spill the morning it happened. A law designed to encourage self-reporting of environmental calamities such as oil spills provides protection against self-incrimination, laywers contend. They say virtually every piece of evidence in the case against <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> grew from his report to the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> that the Exxon Valdez was aground and leaking oil. State lawyers have pointed out that it would have been hard for the massive oil spill to go undiscovered. Another defense motion asserts that the sobriety test <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> failed about 10 hours after the ship struck <PERSON> Bligh </PERSON> <PERSON> Reef </PERSON> was administered improperly, and that the results can not be used as evidence. Defense lawyers say the sample was obtained so long after the grounding that it did not provide a sound measure of <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>'s condition at the time of the wreck
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador-Church Bjt   11-25 0910</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador-Church, Bjt,0938</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Puts Heat on Church After Rebel Offensive</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CANDICE HUGHES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two commandos from the elite <ORGANIZATION> Bracamonte </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Battalion </ORGANIZATION> materialize out of the shadows near a Jesuit parish house. They stop a departing visitor. `` Who are you looking for?'' one demands coldly. `` What do you want? Show me your identification.'' The church is suspect in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, denounced by the right and persecuted as subversive because it has become a force for social change, a voice that denounces rights abuses. It threatens the status quo in a country where a handful are wealthy and the majority live in ignorance, poverty and disease and those who try to change things risk torture and death. It is also a country torn by a civil war pitting a leftist guerrilla force against a succession of U.S.-backed governments _ a war that has taken more than 71,000 lives. After the massacre of six Jesuit priests last week, Attorney General <PERSON> Mauricio </PERSON> <PERSON> Colorado </PERSON> accused Archbishop <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> <PERSON> Damas </PERSON> and auxiliary Bishop <PERSON> Gregorio </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> of fomenting leftist violence. He wrote to <PERSON> Pope </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> that the prelates should be pulled out of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> for their own good. The clerics, he said, have `` persisted in keeping alive the questionable ideology of the ` church of the poor''' and are blamed for `` much of the violence that has devastated <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> for many years and culminated in the rebel actions of this week ...'' More than 1,000 people were killed in the 11-day offensive. A dozen years ago, a Jesuit activist, the Rev. <PERSON> Rutilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Grande </PERSON>, asked what would happen if <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> came to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. `` They'd accuse him of being a rebel, a foreign Jew, of getting mixed up in exotic and strange ideas ... they'd crucify him,'' <PERSON> Grande </PERSON> said in a homily in the rural parish where he worked among the poor. He was dead less than a month later, gunned down by a death squad on his way to say Mass. <PERSON> Grande </PERSON> was one of the first priests to fall in the bloody attempt to suppress church activism in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. Dozens of priests, nuns and lay workers have been murdered since, including the six Jesuit academics. Teachers, nurses, doctors, social workers, academics _ all are suspect. <PERSON> Grande </PERSON>'s life and death symbolized the new role for the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. For hundreds of years, the church had worked with the Spanish conquerors and colonial rulers and with the oligarchs that followed. Ignore the misery of life on earth, it taught, and await your celestial reward. There were few dissenting voices. In 1968, a Latin American bishop's conference in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, decided the church should tend the material needs of the poor as well as their spiritual needs, calling it a `` preferential option for the poor.'' Instead of counseling forbearance from the sidelines, many clerics now felt their duties included standing at the side of parishioners trying to do things such as organize peasant cooperatives that might ease their crushing poverty. As war devastated <PERSON> El </PERSON> <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON>, the importance of churches and church workers, both <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> and Protestant, grew. Churches are virtually the only humanitarian institutions that have continued to function throughout a decade of bitter civil war between leftist guerrillas and a series of U.S.-backed governments. In a nation where political violence has fragmented families and displaced hundreds of thousands, the only place to turn is often a church. In some rural areas churches and church workers are the only source of social services, health care and education as well as spiritual nourishment. The church is also at the heart of the intellectual life of this Massachusetts-sized nation of 5 million. The university where the priests were massacred is one of the most respected institutions of higher learning in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>'s right _ wealthy landowners and businessmen and their military allies _ have raged at the sight of the church's inherent power and influence standing shoulder-to-shoulder with ideas they consider subversive While the many in the churches blame the war on social and economic factors, the right blames the conflict on those who try to change them. `` The general feeling of the government is that all humanitarian service groups in the country have sympathy for the rebels,'' the Rev. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Potter </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>'s partnership officer for <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>, said in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> this week after 19 layworkers at the <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> refugee center in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> were arrested. The country's only <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> pastor, the Rev. <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Berrano </PERSON> <PERSON> Laurente </PERSON>, was arrested the next day, Monday. The human rights monitoring group <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Watch </PERSON> said Friday he was still in custody. As the Salvadoran Roman Catholic church has supported its poor parishioners, foreign priests, nuns, ministers, missionaries, doctors, nurses, social worker and teachers have joined them. Episcopal, Lutheran, Baptist and Mennonite churches were on the rosters of the dozens of churches, church schools, refuges and social offices raided by authorities during the rebel offensive. Americans, West Germans, Canadians, Spaniards and Guatemalans were among those detained or deported. Many _ both Salvadorans and foreigners _ have fled, many have gone into hiding in the past two weeks. But even so, they say the work of the churches is not over. `` They feel needed here. And the more they are persecuted, the more needed they feel,'' said an American academic with extensive experience in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DangerousToys-List     11-25 0348</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dangerous Toys-List,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>PIRG Lists 25 Dangerous Toys.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With Dangerous Toys, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Following is a list of 25 toys rated as dangerous in the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>'s toy safety survey released Friday. 1. Jaunty Jalopy Tot-A-Bout, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Empire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Tarboro </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> 2. Sesame Street Musical TV Wind Up, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Illco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Toy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> 3. Sesame Street Big Bird's Motor Boat, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Illco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Toy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> 4. Spring N' Bounce cars, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> YDC </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> 5. Disney <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON>'s Safari Adventure Playset, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Arco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Toys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Westbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> 6. Disney <PERSON> Donald </PERSON>'s Speed Boat Playset, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Arco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Toys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Westbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> 7. Disney Dinosaur <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Playset </PERSON>, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Arco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Toys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Westbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> 8. Disney Airplane Playset, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Arco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Toys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Westbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> 9. My First Buddy Copter, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Buddy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> L. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corporation </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> 10. Toddle Totmobile, manufactured by <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tikes </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION>, Oh. 11. Snoopy Die Cast Vehicle, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trading </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Sherman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oaks </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> 12. Disney Carry Around Telephone, manufactured by unknown. 13. Wooden Train Set, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Marks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Itasca </LOCATION>, Ill. 14. Pull String Swimming Frog, <PERSON> Hippo </PERSON>, and fish, manufactured by unknown. 15. Dress Up Clown Plush Toy, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> JSNY </ORGANIZATION>, made in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. 16. Stuffed Dog Plush Toy, manufactured by unknown. 17. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Duck </PERSON> <PERSON> Plush </PERSON> <PERSON> Toy </PERSON>, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Applause </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Woodland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> 18. The Touchables Plush Toys, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Commonwealth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Toy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Novelty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> 19. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Teddy </PERSON> Bear Plush Toy, manufactured by The Bearons of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jolla </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jolla </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> 20. <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> VanderBear Plush Toy, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> 21. Push Toy, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Steven </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Hermann </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>. 22. Die Cast Micro Racers, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> W. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Woolworth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, made in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. 23. Eggscavators truck set, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Henry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gordy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Plainfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> 24. Car Transport car and truck set, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Manufatura </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> De </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brinquedos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estrela </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> S.A. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Sao </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paulo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>. 25. Carry Along Peg Chest and Blackboard, manufactured by <PERSON> Pressman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, N.Y.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0155EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u n BC-HolidayTraffic     11-25 0008</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Holiday Traffic,0004</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 2 a.m. EST: 153.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CDC--Drinking Bjt   11-25 0420</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CDC--Drinking, Bjt,0433</SECOND>
<HEAD>Heavy Liquor Drinking Losing its Cachet, CDC Reports</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BYRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s taste for the hard stuff has plummeted to its lowest level in three decades. The national <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> reported Friday that per-capita consumption of distilled spirits in 1986 was 0.85 gallons, the lowest since 1959, when it was 0.84 gallons. `` The decline in spirits consumption may represent changes in the drinking patterns and preferences in the drinking-aged population,'' the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> said in its weekly report. `` These changes were reflected by greater interest in beverages with reduced alcohol content -LRB- light beers and wine coolers -RRB-, as well as increased public awareness regarding physical fitness, nutrition and alcohol abuse.'' Complete statistics were available through 1986. Preliminary statistics indicate the decline continued in 1987, to 0.83 gallons, said researcher <PERSON> Darryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Bertolucci </PERSON> of the Alcohol, <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> said the drop in consumption of distilled spirits between 1985 and 1986 was the sharpest since 1956, as measured in both actual cases sold and the percentage of the decrease. But the exact statistics behind those conclusions were unavailable Friday. In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> said, per-capita consumption of ethanol _ the actual alcohol in alcoholic beverages _ was 2.58 gallons from all beverages in 1986, the lowest since 2.64 gallons in 1977. Two of three American adults drink, but a relatively small number of them account for most of the consumption of alcoholic beverages. The <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> said 10 percent of drinkers, or just 6.5 percent of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> adult population, account for half of all the alcohol consumed in the nation. Public health officials defined heavy drinking as an average of one ounce or more of ethanol each day _ about two beers, cocktails or glasses of wine. Such drinkers, the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> said, run a seven-times greater risk of liver cirrhosis than occasional alcohol drinkers. The <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> said at least 46 percent of the cirrhosis deaths among <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> men and at least 15 percent of cirrhosis deaths among women are attributable to heavy drinking. The agency reported Friday that 26,151 Americans died of chronic liver disease and cirrhosis in 1986; 42 percent of those deaths were associated with alcohol. High rates of death from chronic liver disease were scattered across the country, topped by 31 such deaths per 100,000 residents in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lowest </LOCATION> was <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, with six deaths per 100,000 people. In another 13,475 deaths, the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> said, chronic liver disease was a `` contributing cause.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0217EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RiotTrial     11-25 0454</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Riot Trial,0466</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officer's Partner Defends Shooting</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD COLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A policeman on trial for two deaths that sparked a race riot shot a motorcyclist in self-defense as he twisted to avoid being hit by the vehicle, the officer's partner testified. Officer <PERSON> Dawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Campell </PERSON> said she was only a few feet behind <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON> the night of the Jan. 16 shooting. <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>, 31, is Hispanic and the two victims on the motorcycle were black. Prosecution witnesses had testified Ms. <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> was on the sidewalk and ducked down behind their patrol car at the moment of the shooting. But on Friday she insisted she was in the middle of the street when she heard sirens, then spotted the motorcycle speeding toward <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON> at about 70 mph with another police car in pursuit. `` I saw the motorcycle come into the southbound lane, heading straight for officer <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>,'' she testified. `` As the motorcycle got right up on him, I heard a ` pop,' and saw officer <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON> give a twisting movement.'' She said the motorcycle passed within about a foot of <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>, who twisted to escape being hit. Prosecutors claim the motorcyclist did not threaten <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>. The driver, <PERSON> Clement </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON>, 23, died instantly with a bullet in his head. His passenger, <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON>, 24, was critically injured when the out-of-control motorcycle crashed. <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> died the next day. Assistant State Attorney <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Horn </PERSON> asked if, despite departmental rules, Ms. <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> had talked to <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON> immediately after the incident. She denied discussing the case and said she did n't recall a conversation at the scene among her, <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>, and a friend, officer <PERSON> Manny </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>. <PERSON> Horn </PERSON> then showed photographs of the three officers apparently talking and making gestures just after the shooting. In one, <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON> appeared to be standing in the position the defense says he occupied at the time of the shooting, but Ms. <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> denied they were reenacting the scene. She and <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON> were together, she said, because they had been ordered to find the spent shell casing. Prior to Ms. <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>'s testimony, defense attorney <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON> called the trial a political ploy. `` There is more effort made to prosecute a police officer than any 10 murder cases I've ever seen in this court,'' he said. But lead prosecutor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> responded he would make no apology for the resources spent on the case. `` There is a large proportion of the people who live in <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> who feel that they could be killed, perhaps for absolutely no reason because ... of the color of their skin,'' said <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON>. `` -LRB- And -RRB- because of the occupation of their killer, that no justice will be done, that the justice system works only for the chosen few.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891125-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-25-89 0240EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FurProtests     11-25 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fur Protests,0711</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chic Shops Targeted in Nationwide Protests Against Fur</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
