<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 2336EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CoalStrike 1stLd-Writethru a0799 07-14 0863</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Coal Strike, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0799,0891</SECOND>
<HEAD>Coal Union Leader Calls For an End To Wildcat Strikes</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 7 grafs to UPDATE with workers in Alabama and Illinois
also returning; picks up 6th graf, `Trumka asked ....'; ADDS 4 grafs after
last graf, ` ``We have ...' with background. no pick up.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KELLY P. KISSEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GILBERT, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Trumka </PERSON> on Friday issued a plea to striking miners to end their unauthorized walkouts and workers in at least three states planned to return to the coal mines. <PERSON> Trumka </PERSON> also declared an end to the union's weeklong authorized work stoppage that idled 60,000 union miners east of the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. `` I am personally asking our members to suspend their protest actions,'' <PERSON> Trumka </PERSON> said in a news release. At least 37,000 miners in eight states in <LOCATION> Appalachia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> were on unauthorized wildcat strikes before this week. The wildcat walkouts began June 12 in support of 1,900 union members on strike against the <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> in a contract dispute. In southern <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, a wildcat strike by 1,750 <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION> members was suspended Friday. <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>'s 5,000 union miners also would return to work Sunday night, said a union official there. And <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> union representatives said striking miners were planning to return to work. But in western <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, more than 1,000 wildcat strikers in <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> said they would not return to work. `` We told our people to go back to work, but they told us ` No,''' <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Watson </PERSON>, vice president of <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION> Local 1071, said late Friday. In the past, the <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION> has maintained it has not asked the workers to stay away from the coal mines; and many UMW rank-and-file have ignored back-to-work orders from judges. <PERSON> Trumka </PERSON> asked the wildcat strikers to return to work until July 26, when the union's international executive board meets. `` As the regular work schedule resumes on Monday and our members return to work, we assume that the industry will cooperate with our efforts to help restore stability in the coal fields,'' <PERSON> Trumka </PERSON> said. `` I think by and large things should go back to normalcy on Monday,'' union spokesman <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Corcoran </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Trumka </PERSON> said miners would continue the `` memorial'' or cooling off periods in <LOCATION> UMW </LOCATION> <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> 31 </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> north </LOCATION> <LOCATION> central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> from next Monday through Thursday and in <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> 6 in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s Northern Panhandle from next Wednesday through Friday. The announcement came during another day of unrest in the coal fields. Two mine employees were wounded by gunfire in <LOCATION> Mingo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, and a car bomb exploded at <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>'s headquarters in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. A federal judge Friday also called on the <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, parent of <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coal </ORGANIZATION>, to meet with him to find out what has stalled contract negotiations between the two sides <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> workers in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> went on strike April 5 after working 18 months without a contract. The <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION> on Monday began a three-day cooling-off period, which was extended Wednesday. The days off without pay _ 10 of which are allowed the the <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION>'s contract with the <ORGANIZATION> Bituminous </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operators </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> _ were aimed at easing coal field tensions, but unrest and violence has continued. A bomb went off in a car parked at <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>'s headquarters, said <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> Police Sgt <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>. There were no injuries, and no arrests were made, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said. The bomb destroyed a vehicle that <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> said was owned by a replacement worker hired during the strike against the company. `` We're very concerned about incidents such as this,'' <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Copeland </PERSON> said. She said security would be increased at the headquarters. <PERSON> Corcoran </PERSON> said he and other union officials were unaware of the explosion. He said it would be wrong to blame the union when no arrest has been made. At least one other car bombing and two failed attempts at car bombings have been reported by police during the strikes in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. Two employees of non-union <ORGANIZATION> Hampden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> were hit by buck shot Friday morning as they were replacing paint-splattered windows that had protected a camera surveillance system, said company President <PERSON> Sid </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>. No arrests were made, officials said. In <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, the wildcat strike was scheduled to be suspended at midnight Friday, a union official said. `` Members will be returning to work,'' said <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>, international executive board member for the <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION>'s District 11. `` We have suspended the protest for right now,'' <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> said in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> added that the order to ask <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> workers to return came at the same time <PERSON> Trumka </PERSON> made his plea. `` They're going back because I asked them to,'' <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> said. `` I felt there were some positive things happening down in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and recommended we go back to work. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> 12 in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, said 8,500 striking <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> miners would be returning to work in shifts throughout the weekend. In <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, the miners would be notified Saturday to `` return to work at the next available shift,'' said <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, secretary-treasurer for <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> 20.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TimberCompromise     07-14 0492</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Timber Compromise,0504</SECOND>
<HEAD>Environmental Groups Offer Plan Allowing Some Logging</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB BAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PORTLAND, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Environmentalists offered a plan Friday aimed at preserving ancient forests in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> while allowing timber companies to cut down more trees. The federal government has been prevented from selling many older forest stands to timber companies because of court injunctions won by environmental groups, who argued the stands may be the last remaining habitat for the Northern spotted owl. The injunctions have drastically reduced the supply of logs for lumber mills in the Northwest. The plan offered Friday would release 490 million board feet of timber currently barred from logging under court injunctions. A compromise plan worked out at a meeting of environmentalists, timber industry officials and politicians last month went up in smoke when some environmental groups said it allowed for too much logging. Reaction to the latest proposal was mixed. `` I'm encouraged,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> DeFazio </PERSON>, D-Ore. `` I think it's a thoughtful albeit somewhat complicated response. But <PERSON> Rachel </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorlin </PERSON>, press secretary to Rep. <PERSON> Less </PERSON> <PERSON> AuCoin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ore </LOCATION>, said: `` It raises as many questions as it seems to answer.'' And <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Geisinger </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forestry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said the plan strayed too far from the original framework for the summit compromise. `` They want to be in charge of managing the national forests,'' said <PERSON> Geisinger </PERSON>, who represented the timber industry at the summit. `` I do n't think we are prepared to turn that responsibility over to them.'' Overall, the environmentalists offer would allow 9.6 billion board feet of federal timber to be harvested in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> over the next 15 months. <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON>, conservation dirrector of the <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resouces </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, emphasized at a news conference Friday that the offer covered only the 1989 and 1990 fiscal years. The harvest level is 400 million board feet less than was proposed in the plan developed at the June 24 summit. Although the environmentalists called their proposal `` a minor reduction,'' congressional aides who asked not to be identified said the 400 million amounted to enough timber to supply four medium-sized mills with logs for a year. Under the plan, 3.7 billion board feet would be available for harvest in national forests the remainder of this fiscal year, 3.9 billion could be harvested on national forests in the 1990 fiscal year and a billion could be harvested on <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> land in each of the two fiscal years. `` A lot of this was difficult because we are bleeding,'' <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON> said. `` This plan is not sustainable for timber production and not sustainable for spotted owl production.'' Any long-term plan, he said, would have to provide more severe limits on federal logging, with a greater emphasis on improving production on private timberland. The plan would allow harvesting of small, fragmented stands; spotted owl habitat selected by environmentalists and areas that are not spotted owl habitat but have been protected by the injunctions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0001EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Honduras-Bomb 3rdLd-Writethru a0804 07-14 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Honduras-Bomb, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0804,0669</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bomb Injures Seven American Soldiers</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS lead and 7th graf, `The three...' to UPDATE with four soldiers
in serious condition flown to U.S.; DELETES reference to Fort Kelly.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserGraphic NY31</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FREDDY CUEVAS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A homemade bomb exploded outside a discotheque in northern <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> early Thursday and wounded seven <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> soldiers, four of them seriously, officials reported. Two other Americans in the group escaped injury. No one claimed responsibility for the fourth attack on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> since Feb. 1. `` Witnesses say the bomb was apparently thrown from a car, but the scenario is still confused,'' said <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Sigmund </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. `` They do n't say if the bomb was thrown from a moving car or a parked car. We're still investigating.'' The soldiers had gone into <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceiba </PERSON>, a coastal town 200 miles north of <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION>, in civilian dress and without proper leave, embassy spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Barclay </PERSON> said. `` They were not authorized to go into town,'' he said in a telephone interview. `` The group was part of a convoy carrying equipment and machinery from <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Castilla </LOCATION> to <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Soto </PERSON> <PERSON> Cano </PERSON> air base. I have no further details for the moment.'' Officials said the convoy of about 150 Americans was returning Wednesday from a road-building exercise with Honduran troops and stopped at <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ceiba </LOCATION> for the night. <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Castilla </LOCATION> is 250 miles north of <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION>. The four most seriously injured soldiers were flown to a military hospital in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, and the other three were being treated at <LOCATION> Soto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cano </LOCATION> 50 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION>, the embassy said. The names were withheld pending notification of relatives. Col. <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON>, the Honduran military commander at <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ceiba </LOCATION>, said by telephone the explosion occurred at the <LOCATION> Lido </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Discotheque </LOCATION>, and four Honduran suspects were being questioned. He would say nothing further about the suspects. <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON> said the two uninjured soldiers were turned over to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officers from the <LOCATION> Soto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cano </LOCATION> base because `` they refused to talk and demanded a lawyer.'' The soldiers had been working in the <LOCATION> Valle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aguan </LOCATION>, 125 miles east of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ceiba </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Barclay </PERSON> said. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has had facilities at the <ORGANIZATION> Soto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cano </ORGANIZATION> base in central <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> for years, and about 1,200 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel are assigned there on six-month rotating tours. <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> has been the scene of frequent <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military exercises since 1982, in part as a political signal to the leftist <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> government in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, which borders <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> to the south. Many Hondurans resent the increased <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military role in the Central American nation, as well as the use of Honduran territory by U.S.-supported Contra rebels battling <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s government. On April 11, assailants attacked a jeep convoy carrying <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers outside <LOCATION> Olanchita </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ceiba </LOCATION>. One jeep was disabled, but nobody was injured. On Feb. 1, assailants fired at an American military convoy in northern <PERSON> Yoro </PERSON> province. No one was injured. On Feb. 18, three <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> soldiers and two Honduran passers-by were wounded when a bomb was detonated under a passing bus in <LOCATION> Comayagua </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> Soto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cano </LOCATION>. A shadowy leftist group calling itself the <ORGANIZATION> Morazanista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> claimed responsibility for all three attacks this year and for attacks in 1983 and 1987. The group, formed in 1979 and named after <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Morazan </PERSON>, who ruled <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> from 1829 to 1832. It is believed to be part of the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. In addition to the attacks on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel, other violent incidents in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> have raised fears of increased activity by left-wing guerrillas and right-wing death squads. Six people have been assassinated in the last three weeks, including a university professor shot to death Wednesday, a union leader and a student leader. On Jan. 25, former military chief Gen. <PERSON> Gustavo </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> was assassinated. He helped found the Nicaraguan rebel movement in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> while head of the military from 1982 to 1984.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CommodoreTrial     07-14 0344</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Commodore Trial,0353</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thrift Executives Sentenced in Illegal Political Contributions Case</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two former thrift executives were sentenced Thursday to six months in prison for their role in a scheme to use money from the thrift for illegal political contributions. The executives of <ORGANIZATION> Commodore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morten </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrell </PERSON> were given five-year sentences by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Fish </PERSON>, who suspended all but six months of the sentences. <PERSON> Commodore </PERSON>'s former owner, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, was sentenced Wednesday to 15 years in prison for creating the donation scheme, which began in 1982. A jury in May convicted the Hopkins brothers on 47 counts including conspiracy, making false entries into the records of a bank, misappropriation of funds and making false statements to a federal agency. <PERSON> Harrell </PERSON>, former Commodore chief executive, was convicted on two counts of making false entries into the records of a bank, but acquitted on the other charges. Fish also ordered all three men to pay restitution to the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> for money diverted from the thrift. The <ORGANIZATION> FSLIC </ORGANIZATION> will recover $ 104,062 from the judgment, with <PERSON> Harrell </PERSON> to pay about $ 4,000 and the <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> brothers to pay the balance. Federal law prohibits corporate contributions to political campaigns. During the trial, thrift employees testified they gave money to political action committees and were reimbursed through pay increases or checks for fictional travel. Prosecutors alleged the defendants tried to hide contributions to members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, including Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, who was then embroiled in an ethics investigation that led to his resignation. Prosecutors said there was no evidence that recipients of the contributions knew of the scheme. Attorney <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Vance </PERSON>, who represented the defendants, did not return a phone call from The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. Prosecutor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarvis </PERSON> said the case was the first involving illegal political contributions to be tried at the felony level. The charge is a misdemeanor, but was upgraded because the defendants were accused of making false statements to a federal agency and entering false information in bank records.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0226EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ArgentineYouth 1stLd-Writethru b0234 07-14 0796</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Argentine Youth, 1st Ld - Writethru, b0234,0808</SECOND>
<HEAD>Argentina's Economic Crisis Driving Off Its Young</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: In PM-Argentine Youth, b0234, sent July 7 as an advance for
Friday, July 14, SUB one graf for graf nine, ``With the ...'', to account
for change in austral's value; pickup graf 10 prvs, ``A lot ...''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By AVIVA SHLENSKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Young descendants of immigrants who crossed the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> in years past to work in the fields and factories of <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> are taking the journey in reverse nowadays as the nation sinks deep into recession. `` This is my home and I hope to return to it and live and die here, but not if it means starving to death because I do n't have any work,'' <PERSON> Aldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Bignone </PERSON>, a 23-year-old auto mechanic, said as he stood outside the Spanish Consulate to apply for a visa. <PERSON> Rodrigo </PERSON> <PERSON> Imas </PERSON>, a 30-year-old print shop employee, said his grandfather told him many times about the four-week trip he made from <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> in the hold of a freighter to start a new life in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>. `` Now I'm hoping to find enough money to buy a one-way ticket on <ORGANIZATION> Aerolineas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Argentinas </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Imas </PERSON> said. `` The transportation has changed and the direction is reversed, but the idea is the same.'' As inflation and interest rates have soared out of control and the austral currency falls to a tiny fraction of its worth just five months ago, businesses have closed by the score and thousands of workers have been laid off. Argentines who consider themselves lucky just to have jobs have watched in dismay as food, gasoline, cigarettes, movie tickets and virtually everything else have shot up in price, while wages in real terms have shrunk. Argentines have left for years for a variety of reasons. A decade ago, it was to escape the violence of left-wing subversion followed by a brutal crackdown that began with a military coup in March, 1976. For the past several years, Argentines have left in search of economic opportunity, however, and visa applications have accelerated as the economy has deteriorated in recent months. With the austral trading at about 590 to the dollar, a teacher who earned $ 100 a month at the end of 1988 would have been earning a little as $ 40 at the end of June; a newspaper reporter who earned $ 300 now earns $ 90; a bilingual marketing administrator could well have seen his pay fall from $ 300 to $ 135 and a bank economist from $ 700 to $ 300. Some of those employers have taken their own measures to offset inflation. `` A lot of people are thinking that their children have limited futures,'' said the Canadian consul, <PERSON> Andree </PERSON> <PERSON> Bazinet </PERSON>. `` They get all these skills at the university and ca n't use them in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>. We get some of our highest quality acceptances from <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>.'' In 1986, the <ORGANIZATION> Canadian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> received 188 applications for immigrant visas and in the first five months of this year, applications stood at 1,292. Only 275 were issued. The Argentine government issues no figures on the number or job skills of emigrants, but officials at variousd consulates said visa applications are way up, and usually it's the best educated and best trained who are taken. The longest lines are outside the consulates of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, the countries to which a majority of Argentines trace their roots. <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> generally offers visas to grandchildren of its emigrants and <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> to children of people born in those countries who never renounced their citizenship. Those visas are coveted because they will allow Argentines to work thoughout <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> beginning in 1992, when the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> is unified into a single market. <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> granted about 480 immigrant visas in 1986 and 1987, the Consulate said, and inquiries for the nine-month period that ended in March skyrocketed to 16,330. It gave no figures on the number of visas to be granted. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Fainstein </PERSON>, dean of the Latin American Rabbinic Seminary, estimated that 2,000 Jews left <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> last year for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. `` There has been an increase ... because of the permanent instability and insecurity here,'' he said. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> issued 1,450 to 1,500 immigrant visas to Argentines in the past few years, a consular officer said. The number of applications is not kept, but it clearly exceeds the number of acceptances and probably has increased in recent months, the official added. Standing in line at the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Consulate, <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Ponti </PERSON> said he hopes to move to <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, to work in his uncle's clothing store. `` My family split in two after World War II,'' said <PERSON> Ponti </PERSON>, 27, who works on the <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION> subway. `` One part went to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>, another part came here to <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>. The American side of the family is doing very well.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0703EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Dalton     07-14 0777</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Dalton,0793</SECOND>
<HEAD>The New, Improved, Modern 007</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report. The opening is today, July 14.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB THOMAS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON> was faced with two of the toughest acts to follow, but he has managed by talent and sheer perseverance to bring <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> to life in a new, modernized style that could carry 007 into the 21st century. The 44-year-old Briton was here for the opening of `` Licence to Kill,'' 16th of the adventures -LRB- not counting two unofficial films -RRB- that have generated more dollars than any film series in movie history. Most critics have found <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON> at ease in his second go-round as <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>; his first, `` The Living Daylights,'' was not written for him. He also seemed relaxed in an interview, as if he had come to grips with a classic role that might have overwhelmed him. He admitted having `` enormous pause'' when he first considered it. `` My concern was not about creating the character, which after all is my job,'' said <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON>. `` If I do it well, then that's terrific If I fail, then that's also part of being an actor. `` The pause was over how to deal with it, how to bring an audience with you, away from its history and into its new present. Very clearly, before I took it on, I knew that everyone has an opinion about <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>; it's part of the cinema-going consciousness. `` Everyone has an opinion about the actors who have played Bond before. Half the world loved <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Connery </PERSON>; half the world loved <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>. Their films existed in two very different styles. You know when you take it on you run the risk of having the whole world hate what you do. If that had happened, it would have been a major catastrophe. Fortunately it did n't,'' he said. `` What one must face today is that we've got something new, something different. ... This is a new style of Bond. It is n't a light-hearted, comedic, spoofing <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>. It's not a technological extravaganza. I think it's back down to its origins, its basics, trying to capture the spirit of <PERSON> Ian </PERSON> <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON>, and of the early movies. `` I loved ` Dr. No' and ` From <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION> With Love'; they were very exciting adventure-thrillers. I watched the train sequence of <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Connery </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> the other day. It's still tremendously exciting.'' Previewers noted that <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON> seemed to be performing much of his own action, but he discounted any threat to his safety. `` I think the strenuous side of a Bond movie is the sheer amount of time to make one _ six months, which is a very, very long schedule,'' he said. `` You're on location so you work long hours. The crew works 15 hours a day; we go back, watch rushes, talk about tomorrow's work, so it's 18 hours a day.'' <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON> had a thriving career before producer <PERSON> Cubby </PERSON> <PERSON> Broccoli </PERSON> chose him as the fourth <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Lazenby </PERSON> had a single shot in `` On Her Majesty's <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>,'' 1969 -RRB-. He grew up in <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION> with non-professional parents. `` My grandfather and grandmother were in vaudeville-music halls,'' <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON> said, `` but my parents were not involved in the theater. It skipped a generation. `` I suppose I first became interested, just like most kids of my generation, by going to the Saturday morning pictures. You find yourself in a very exciting, rare, different world. An extraordinary coincidence: The first full-length feature film I saw was ` The Red Beret,' starring <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ladd </PERSON>. I discovered recently that it was produced by <PERSON> Cubby </PERSON> <PERSON> Broccoli </PERSON>. The very first picture that I saw at five or six years old was produced by the man I'm now working for.'' <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON> studied at the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dramatic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> and appeared in classics from repertory to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> End </LOCATION>. His film debut was auspicious: as the young king of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> in `` The Lion in Winter'' with <PERSON> Katharine </PERSON> <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> and <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON>. Other films have included `` Cromwell,'' `` Wuthering Heights'' -LRB- as <PERSON> Heathcliff </PERSON> -RRB-, `` Agatha'' and a curiosity, `` Sextette'' with <PERSON> Mae </PERSON> <PERSON> West </PERSON>. Although `` Sextette'' was seen by few, <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON> found working with the film legend a rare experience. `` She claimed to be 84 but some oldtimers said she was 90,'' he recalled. `` It was amazing to be working at her old studio, Paramount, and see her come to life every day as she did the thing she loved.'' How long will <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON> remain with <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>? He laughed heartily before replying: `` ` Licence to Kill' started to do extremely well in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. If it does well here, I'm sure there will be another one. ... But for how long I'll continue, I do n't know.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0229EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BolshoiAmerican     07-14 0728</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bolshoi American,0749</SECOND>
<HEAD>Young American on the Road _ From Baseball to the Bolshoi</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE GOULD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON>, a determined teen-ager who says he `` left home at 14 forever'' in hopes of becoming a world-class dancer, is coming home to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> _ with <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Bolshoi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ballet </ORGANIZATION> Five years after he said good-bye to his mother in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, he is back for a five-week, cross-country tour as the only <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> dancer with the <ORGANIZATION> Bolshoi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ballet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>, the official school for what many consider the world's most prestigious ballet company. In the intervening years, always without family and usually without money, young <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> worked and danced his way halfway around the world, being supported variously by the governments of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. He's also found himself in <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION> and along the way learned to speak Russian, Hungarian and Italian. It's been, in a literal sense, a long leap. `` It's kind of strange,'' <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> said in a backstage interview at suburban <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s Wolf Trap theater. `` I left home at 14 forever. Now I feel like a foreigner, coming back home.'' `` When I left, my mother said I'll miss you and love you, but I want you to have a better life than I have,'' <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> said. `` I have no other family, we come from what you would call the lower end of the middle class, and she had to borrow money for my plane ticket.'' The first stop was <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> as he traded his <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> love of surfing, swimming and baseball for a chance to dance. `` I still did n't know if I'd make it,'' he says now. It was n't easy, even years later when he was discovered by <PERSON> Madame </PERSON> <PERSON> Sophia </PERSON> <PERSON> Golovkina </PERSON>, director of classical dance at the <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Choreographic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> and a stern but loved master of the ballet. Now in her 70s, `` Madame Golovkina'' discovered <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> at a ballet competition in <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, on one of his brief stopovers in this country since moving away. `` She's been like a mother to me ever since, and worked to get me accepted to the <ORGANIZATION> Bolshoi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>,'' the rigorous training school for <ORGANIZATION> Bolshoi </ORGANIZATION> dancers, <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> said. Already the recipient of an award from the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> and the first American graduate of the <ORGANIZATION> Hungarian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ballet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> scraped together some money, packed his bags and ent to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. `` There was no cultural exchange at that time,'' <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> said. `` I was an exchange student without an exchange program and I spent every day going from one government ministry to another looking for support.'' `` I lived in a hotel, and on the last day when I ran out of money they called and said, `` You can stay,''' <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> recalled, relief still clear in his voice. `` They do n't have any foreigners'' <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> said of the academy, which was founded in 1773 and annually draws thousands of young Soviets hoping to be admitted as students. Although he has n't been formally admitted to the actual <ORGANIZATION> Bolshoi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ballet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> hopes to win that honor during or shortly after the current <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tour, the academy's first <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> visit in 20 years. `` I'd be the very first American. They've given me so much. I'd like to stay for years and bring what I've learned over there back here.'' The tour will take <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> and company to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, where he will be able to see, and perform for, his mother. Other stops include <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Vail </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Binghamton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> will dance with a troupe of other young, promising ballet stars, including 21-year-old <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Malakhov </PERSON> and <PERSON> Galina </PERSON> <PERSON> Stepanyenko </PERSON>, 23, both winners of gold medals at the recent 6th <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> International Ballet competition. Both young stars have high hopes for continuing improvement in U.S.-Soviet relations, noting changes Miss <PERSON> Stepanyenko </PERSON> says `` are being felt all over the world.'' `` It is a difficult process, but we have much hope,'' added <PERSON> Malakhov </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> also has hopes, `` and dreams.'' `` With glasnost, we've started something really important and I want to keep it going where I can. I've even danced for President <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, he was sitting only a few feet from me,'' he said. `` I have n't danced for my own president,'' he added. `` Yet.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0231EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-France-Notebook     07-14 0909</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-France-Notebook,0948</SECOND>
<HEAD>Paris Mood Blends Gay Paree With City Under Occupation</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-France-Bicentennial</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MORT ROSENBLUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Visitors this week found the fabled city partly good old <LOCATION> Gay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paree </LOCATION> primping for a binge and partly a capital under arms, stunned by sudden occupation. Below the surface, frenzied officials faced last-minute crises. Organizers of the giant Friday night parade hired sharpshooters with tranquilizer guns in case the elephants decided to moonwalk down the Champs-Elysees with the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> A </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; M Marching Band. It was not immediately clear how fast a tranquilizer dart worked. Or what one did with an inert elephant in the middle of a parade. Authorities had planned a temporary ban of alcohol along the Champs Elysees, fearing rowdiness from crowds milling around with liquid components of their moveable feast. Faced with violent objection, however, they backed down. One columnist observed: `` Do they think anyone would have stormed the Bastille without wine?''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Most Frenchmen left in town seemed to be wearing uniforms and sidearms, herding polyglot legions behind endless metal barriers that lent an ominous tone to bright blue, white and red bunting. There was plenty to see, and eat, while waiting for the world's biggest party to materialize as promised But getting there was decidedly not half the fun. Following signs to Tuileries 89, featuring a computer-art replica of a 1789 <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> street and an android variety show, two visitors were stopped by guards. `` You ca n't go in there,'' said one, `` It's closed for July 14 celebrations.'' But, the visitors said, that was why everyone was in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. `` Look,'' the guard said, `` We got missiles, anti-missile missiles, fireworks. How do you expect us to let the public in here?'' The visitors eventually found the right way in.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 In the gardens outside, an aging, elegant lady followed her poodle in aimless circles. Each had a bewildered expression. `` Can you help me out of here?'' she asked a stranger, seeking guidance in a neighborhood she had inhabited for 40 years. `` This is insanity, a disgrace,'' she said, identifying herself only as <PERSON> Odette </PERSON>. `` You ca n't go anywhere. I have friends who got a pass that allows them to leave their house, but they have no pass to come home at night.'' She referred to draconian parking and driving regulations that have sealed the center of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. Later, a taxi driver named <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> was asked if he would be working the long weekend. `` Are you crazy?'' he replied, smacking his left forearm in a French gesture depicting a rapid escape. `` I'm getting out of here.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 For a privileged few, <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> has never been easier. The trick is a series of passes, invitations and credentials, the issuing of which would have thrown King <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> XVI </PERSON>'s protocol staff into cold sweat. Cars move swiftly down freshly swept boulevards, ablaze in the color of hyacinths and roses and giant tricolors tied in bows, unless any of 33 visiting presidents or prime ministers happens by. Near the Grand Palais, police waved on two tourists who ambled peaceably across the broad road. Suddenly, an officer yelled: `` Move!'' The tourists leaped sideways just as roaring motorcycles and a stretch Peugeot flying a <LOCATION> Cameroon </LOCATION> flag careered around the corner at breakneck speed, missing them by inches. On the Rue du <LOCATION> Faubourg </LOCATION> <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Honore </LOCATION>, the elegant street on which the Elysee Palace is situated, police shoved Parisians back into their shops when several visitors' motorcades flashed past. `` I thought this was our city,'' one muttered. If conspicuous, the security was not necessarily effective. One journalist, testing it out, walked through a sealed-off area with a hunting rifle in a scabbard.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 All over town, people caught up on their rest wherever they could. At the Tuileries, a disheveled couple lay sprawled under a statue, an upended champagne bottle by their bare feet. They were in stark contrast to the dapper stone figure towering over them, <PERSON> Jules </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferry </PERSON>, the 19th century premier who set <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> on a `` civilizing mission'' to bring couth to a savage world. Souvenir shops did a brisk trade in revolutionary lingerie, funny hats and condoms imprinted with a guillotine. Overall, officials said, the festivities were expected to attract $ 160 million to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, but merchants were n't convinced. `` This is a T-shirt crowd,'' sniffed <PERSON> Patrice </PERSON>, a salesman in a downtown gallery where Italian jackets start at $ 600. `` These are not spenders, believe me.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The newspapers held fascinating tidbits. One noted that security teams for visiting leaders had to negotiate the firearms they were allowed, based on a strict quid pro quo. The Japanese were not permitted any. When President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> attended Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s funeral, his security guard was stripped of weapons, as were all others. The <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> reprinted an item from 100 years ago: `` The present week is being filled up to overflowing with official and social events.'' There was a state dinner for officers of the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> garrison and a commemorative fete for <PERSON> Camille </PERSON> <PERSON> Desmoulins </PERSON> `` of Revolutionary fame'' during which participants would wear horse chestnut leaves and tricolor cockades. July 14th `` will be celebrated in a way that it is hoped will surpass all past events of a similar kind that this gay capital has ever witnessed,'' it concluded. This year's organizers said the same thing, and they may be right. But 1879 festivities included a world's fair that left <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> with the Eiffel Tower, a tough act to follow.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0229EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BlueberryThieves     07-14 0419</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Blueberry Thieves,0429</SECOND>
<HEAD>Maine Cracks Down on Blueberry Rustlers</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GLENN ADAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AUGUSTA, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rustlers are having a field day in <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>'s blueberry patches, raking up $ 1 million in purloined berries a year But the state is fighting back _ a new law gives police the ability to catch thieves blue-handed. Teams of blueberry thieves who scatter from pickup trucks can pick dozens of 24-pound boxes in a night, according to <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Jasper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wyman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Son of Milbridge, which harvests wild blueberries on 7,000 acres. The industry, fearing continued thievery during this summer's harvest, turned to the Legislature this spring for help Lawmakers passed a berry bill that was signed into law by Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> McKernan </PERSON>. It is designed to give authorities the tools to track down the illegal pickers and end the black market _ make that blue market _ in berries. The law requires pickers to get written permission of landowners, and requires anyone who transports 25 pounds or more to get a numbered permit from the <ORGANIZATION> Maine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Blueberry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. Packers and shippers must also keep account of the blueberries they receive in lots of 25 pounds or more. Finally, the law authorizes police, sheriffs, forest rangers and game wardens to make inspections and arrests and investigate blueberry thefts. <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> is one of the nation's leading producers of blueberries, and they are one of its largest cash crops. Blueberries are a $ 70 million a year industry in the state, according to <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> of the blueberry commission. <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> said thefts are worst in seasons when the price is highest. He estimated the loss during the 1988 season at $ 1 million. Suspected thieves confronted by <PERSON> Wyman </PERSON> employees typically claim they took the berries from someone else's fields, said <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>. Others spotted in the act make easy getaways on the dirt roads that wind through the hilly barrens. `` These people are doing it for money,'' said <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, who added that organized thieves tend to go where the berries grow the best. `` It's a big business.'' While people in the industry say the law was a long time coming, some casual roadside pickers believe the state has gone too far. `` For heaven's sake, the most I would ever take is three or four quarts,'' said a woman who asked that her name not be used. `` They've roped off all of the good blueberry patches. I'm miffed. I'll just have to sneak in after dark.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0230EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TropicalWeather 1stLd-Writethru a0782 07-14 0203</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tropical Weather, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0782,0204</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tropical Storm Barry Downgraded To Depression</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 4 grafs to UPDATE storm's position, expected course;
picks up penultimate graf, `The depression ...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tropical storm <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> was downgraded to a tropical depression Thursday as it moved across the open <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> with top winds of 35 mph, forecasters said. At 10:30 p.m. EDT, the depression's center was near 23 degrees north latitude and 58 degrees west longitude, or 485 miles northeast of the northern <LOCATION> Leeward </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Lesser </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antilles </LOCATION>. The system was moving south-southwest at about 6 mph and was expected to continue in that direction through the night, turning to the west on Friday, said <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> forecaster <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerrish </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gerrish </PERSON> added that it was rare for a system to regain strength once it's been downgraded, but that if this one does, it would not threaten any land for at least two to three days. The depression formed earlier this week off the west coast of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. It became the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> hurricane season's second named storm when its maximum sustained winds hit 39 mph Wednesday. The season's first named storm, <PERSON> Allison </PERSON>, caused widespread flooding in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> last month.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0033EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-HUDProbe 2ndLd-Writethru   07-14 1006</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-HUD Probe, 2nd Ld-Writethru,a0742,970</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former HUD Official Seeks Immunity for Testimony Against Samuel Pierce</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERT grafs 11-13 bgng: ``The Washington,'' to report lawyer
convicted of cheating HUD being rehired; SUBS 26th graf: ``The New, ''
to remove now-redundant first name of Demery.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A top aide to former Housing Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> wants immunity from prosecution in exchange for testimony implicating <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> in the influence-peddling scandal at the agency, sources said Thursday. The sources, who asked not to be identified by name, said <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> has told congressional investigators she can testify that <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> ordered funding for specific projects under the Section 8 Moderate Rehabilitation program. The program was briefly suspended after <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> auditors criticized the selection process and said a number of prominent Republicans had been able to steer millions of dollars to their clients. The sources said Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> demanded immunity from prosecution in exchange for answering questions from the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee investigating abuses at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> during <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s eight-year tenure as secretary. One source said she told the committee that she could testify that <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> personally ordered funding for `` numerous'' projects. The source declined to be more specific. A congressional source said Rep. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>., chairman of the subcommittee, was considering such a deal `` with an open mind'' but had not made a decision Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> earlier refused to testify, citing her Fifth Amendment rights against self-incrimination. She spent three years as <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s executive assistant, and has been described by former colleagues as wielding great influence <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> told the subcommittee last month he had no direct role in funding decisions in the Section 8 or any other program. Since then, however, the <ORGANIZATION> Wall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> has reported that <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> intervened on behalf of several associates, including a former law partner. Subcommittee members have told <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, who moved back to <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> to resume his law and business dealings, that they want to question him again. Word on the negotiations between congressional investigators and Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> came as <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> officials more than doubled _ to $ 1.1 billion _ their estimate of the losses in one program suspended because of scandals plaguing the agency. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said in Friday's editions that <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> hired attorney <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Novick </PERSON> to head a program that three years earlier had losses estimated at nearly $ 240,000 because <PERSON> Novick </PERSON> made false statements working as a settlement attorney in real estate transactions. <PERSON> Novick </PERSON>, 47, pleaded guilty May 25 in U.S. District Court to one count of making a false statement, and has been ordered to report in mid-August to a halfway house to serve a one-year sentence. However, a memorandum filed earlier this year in court by federal prosecutors said <PERSON> Novick </PERSON> made false statements in 18 separate real estate transactions from 1982 to 1984, the newspaper said. <PERSON> Novick </PERSON> was rehired by <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> in February 1987 after talking with <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Demery </PERSON>, the assistant secretary for housing during the later part of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> also voted to launch its own investigation into <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> operations during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, joining the two House panels already scrutinizing allegations of mismanagement, fraud and influence-peddling at the multibillion-dollar agency. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committee said one of its priorities would be a review of a co-insurance program under <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, the subject of a new audit that estimates losses at more than double the earlier $ 452 million figure. The $ 1.1 billion estimate was based on the audit and information compiled by <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION> officials, according to a ranking <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> official who spoke on condition of anonymity. <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> was aware of the estimate Tuesday when he gave <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> a $ 2 billion `` ballpark'' figure as the cost of <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> mismanagement during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> years, the official said. Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>'s testimony would mark a dramatic turn in the investigation, which so far far has centered on influence-peddling on the Section 8 program, suspected abuses of the $ 5 billion co-insurance program and lax agency management that allowed private closing agents hired by <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> to withhold millions of dollars owed the government. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, who has suspended or canceled three programs and ordered internal reviews of virtually all the agency's housing programs, has vowed to clean up the department that he took over last winter. In other developments: _ Black, <LOCATION> Manafort </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Stone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>, a leading <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> consulting company linked to influence-peddling at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>, disclosed far broader dealings on HUD-related work than had been described by one of its principal members in recent testimony to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Manafort </PERSON> testified before the employment and housing subcommittee last month that his company had lobbied <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> for two clients. However, <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON> released a memo from <LOCATION> Manafort </LOCATION> saying that further review found the company had lobbied <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> for several other clients. _ Rep <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Traxler </PERSON>, D-Mich., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> appropriations subcommitee, said its decision not to provide new funding for the Section 8 program was n't irreversible, but that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> needed assurances influence-peddling has been eliminated _ The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> approved and sent to the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> the nomination of <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> II as <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s general counsel, a post that will have a key role in agency dealings with investigations by law enforcement agencies The co-insurance program under investigation was among those <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> suspended. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> is investigating the largest private lender under the program, <ORGANIZATION> DRG </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Funding </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported Thursday that the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> probe has expanded to include a review of company ties with <PERSON> Demery </PERSON>, the former assistant secretary for housing. <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> oversaw the co-insurance program. <PERSON> Demery </PERSON>, in an interview Thursday with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, said he believed documents seized by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> from <ORGANIZATION> DRG </ORGANIZATION>'s offices likely included official correspondence with his office at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>. `` There's nothing that would look suspect,'' <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> said. `` There would be routine correspondence from time to time between my office and DRG.'' <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> said he had n't been contacted by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>. An agency spokeswoman said she could neither confirm not deny that <PERSON> Demery </PERSON>'s actions were a part of the DRG investigation
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0058EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     07-14 0942</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0993</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Trumpeter <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Hirt </PERSON> has Grammies and gold records, but he says an award from the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Saints </ORGANIZATION> football Hall of Fame means more. <PERSON> Hirt </PERSON>, who played during halftimes in the <ORGANIZATION> Saints </ORGANIZATION>' early years, was honored Thursday with the museum's Fleur De Lis Award. `` I love this team,'' he said. He said he was the team's biggest cheerleader during the team's beginnings in the late 1960s `` We used to play right behind the bench and I'd lead the fans in cheering ` Go Saints Go.' Sometimes I'd forget to shut the microphone off and lead them in something I was n't supposed to,'' <PERSON> Hirt </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hirt </PERSON>, 66, no longer plays at games, but he still goes. `` This is the greatest team ever,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> George </PERSON>, a former Miss America who went on to become a television personality, will co-host this year's Miss America Pageant with <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, the pageant's director said Ms. <PERSON> George </PERSON>'s selection is part of the pageant's push to promote `` today's modern, educated woman,'' <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Horn </PERSON> said Thursday. `` The Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> competition helped open doors for her, and with her talents, she has achieved a great deal,'' he said. After being crowned Miss America 1971, Ms. <PERSON> George </PERSON> went on to become a television sportscaster and newscaster, an author and lecturer. For eight seasons, she was anchorwoman of <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sports </ORGANIZATION>' `` NFL Today. Today, Ms. <PERSON> George </PERSON>, 40, operates her own line of food products called `` Chicken By <PERSON> George </PERSON>.'' Unlike last year's co-host, <LOCATION> Miss </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> 1959 <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Mobley </PERSON>, Ms. <PERSON> George </PERSON> will not sing and dance. `` That's not <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Horn </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>RENO, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Heather </PERSON> <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> McLeod </PERSON>, the winner of the <ORGANIZATION> Miss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nevada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teen </ORGANIZATION> title, has filed a lawsuit to let her compete in the <LOCATION> Miss </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Teen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> pageant under way in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. The 18-year-old <PERSON> Reno </PERSON> resident was disqualified from the contest because she competed in both <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Miss Teen pageants during the same year, a violation of the national pageant rules. Ms. <PERSON> McLeod </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeh </PERSON>, said in the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> suit filed Thursday that if she is n't let into the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernadino </LOCATION> contest in time for the July 25 final, she wants $ 200,000 in damages instead. The preliminary competition began Friday. The <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nevada-Reno </ORGANIZATION> psychology student, who attended <ORGANIZATION> Poway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, was disqualifed from the national contest after winning the <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> title June 22. <PERSON> Zeh </PERSON> said Ms. <PERSON> McLeod </PERSON> was n't told she could be disqualified for competing in both states' Miss Teen contests and was n't given a copy of the pageant rules. Pageant spokeswoman <PERSON> Alyson </PERSON> <PERSON> Dutch </PERSON> said the first runner-up of the <ORGANIZATION> Miss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nevada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teen </ORGANIZATION> contest, <PERSON> Stacey </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentley </PERSON>, 18, of <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> has taken Ms. <PERSON> McLeod </PERSON>'s place in the competition. `` We've got our <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> contestant,'' she said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> settled his lawsuit against <ORGANIZATION> Sperry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which dropped him as spokesman two years ago when it merged with <ORGANIZATION> Burroughs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> to form <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. The settlement, for an undisclosed amount, occurred Thursday just as jury selection was to begin in federal court in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>. `` I've never been in a courtroom before except in a movie _ and then I always knew my lines,'' <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> said after the settlement. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> had filed a breach of contract suit two years ago against <PERSON> Sperry </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION>, claiming termination of the contract wrecked his chances of getting a `` similarly prestigious and rewarding contract with any other major <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. corporation.'' <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, star of `` Spartacus,'' `` Lust for Life'' and more than 70 other films, said he was happy the matter was closed. `` I am grateful to go back to the world of make-believe,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SYRACUSE, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Rolling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stones </ORGANIZATION> fans will be disappointed that a concert by their rock' n' roll idols was scrapped in favor of a <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> football scrimmage. Athletic Director <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> <PERSON> Crouthamel </PERSON> refused to allow the <ORGANIZATION> Rolling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stones </ORGANIZATION> to open their new tour Sept. 1 at the dome because preparations for the concert would have conflicted with an intrasquad football scrimmage and dinner for the team's booster club scheduled for the previous day. `` I could n't believe my ears when I heard he said no,'' said <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the concert promoter. The rock band will instead open its first tour in eight years at Rich Stadium near <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION> on Sept. 1. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, assistant director of the 50,000-seat dome, said the dinner and scrimmage `` means a lot _ more than any concert _ as far as the university is concerned.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Version of the following moved on sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 His lampooning talents have focused on Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON>, but now country and western songwriter <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Terr </PERSON> is poking fun at <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reds </ORGANIZATION> manager <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>. Called `` The Gambler-Pete Rose,'' the song will make it's national debut this week on the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> radio network The song lilts along to the tune of <PERSON> Kenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>' hit, `` The Gambler.'' For <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, who is under investigation by baseball for allegedly gambling on baseball games, the lyrics wo n't be a hit: `` You got to know who's been hittin' `` Know who's been missin' `` Know who's been strikin' out `` And who's got the runs. `` But do n't advertise your point spread `` Or you'll have to face the eggheads. `` There'll be time to count the money `` When the game is done.'' The song then concludes: `` He said, ` <LOCATION> Howdy </LOCATION>, son, my name's <PERSON> Pete </PERSON>. And do you see all these receipts? `` Well you might think you're a baseball fan, but I bet I know the score.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MexicanDebt     07-14 0240</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mexican Debt,0246</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush to Give Mexico $1 Billion Bridge Loan, Reports Say</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is preparing to grant <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> a temporary loan of $ 1 billion to $ 2 billion to help bring an agreement with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> banks on debt restructuring to a close, according to published reports. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported in Friday editions that the loan is contingent on an agreement between <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and its creditors to reduce and rearrange $ 54 billion in existing loans. Other countries and perhaps commercial sources may also contribute to the temporary loan, the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said. In its Friday editions, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said that <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and the banks had reached a tentative deal. A senior government official in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that he could not confirm the reports because the officials involved were with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> for the seven-nation economic summit conference. He said, however, that he did not believe <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> had reached a deal. On Saturday, the negotiators for the two parties said that they were near an agreement. `` There would have been great pleasure'' if <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and the banks could have agreed on a deal before the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> summit, but when it became clear the negotiations would span the summit `` we were n't particularly uptight about it,'' said the official, who spoke on condition of anonymity The Mexican government has said it wants to reach an agreement before accepting new loans.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-CruiseMissiles     07-14 0189</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cruise Missiles,180</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet General Advances New Cruise Missile Idea</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Soviet military would be willing to give up sea-launched nuclear cruise missiles if the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would too, a senior Soviet general is quoted as saying. In a report of an interview in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> in Friday editions quotes Col. Gen. <PERSON> Nikolai </PERSON> <PERSON> Chervov </PERSON>, chief of the arms control section of the Soviet General Staff, as saying, `` If I were determining policy, then I'd accept it.'' The general said it was a `` progressive suggestion'' to eliminate nuclear cruise missiles. The Soviets, he said, would prefer to give up all cruise missiles at sea, but faced with the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s strong desire to keep conventionally armed missiles `` we are coming to this,'' <PERSON> Chervov </PERSON> said. `` How the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> decides, we'll see.'' <PERSON> Chervov </PERSON> was reported as telling his interviewers Soviet military spending in 1987 and 1988 was 10 billion rubles, $ 16 billion at official exchange rates, below original plans, and would fall by a similar amount in each of the next two three-year periods. This would mean a 25 percent cut by 1995, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0708EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-KickingtheHabit     07-14 0516</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Kicking the Habit,0531</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Official: Smokers Need More Help Fighting Nicotine Than Just
Saying No</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ARLENE LEVINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Giving up cigarettes is more than just a matter of willpower and smokers need more help just saying no to nicotine once they try to quit, a federal health official said. Noting that `` nicotine is an addictive drug,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, chief of epidemiology in the federal Office of Smoking and Health in <LOCATION> Rockville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, said former smokers tend to relapse. `` It is no longer an issue of getting people to quit, but how to help people stay off cigarettes,'' he said. Although 17 million smokers attempt to quit each year, only 1.3 million succeed, <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said. And though 60 percent of smokers never light up after quitting, the rest do, he said. The first through fifth years after quitting is the period that needs most attention, he said Thursday. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, an Australian epidemiologist who was involved in his homeland's anti-smoking program, spoke at the start of a two-day conference of 130 health educators and practitioners who create, provide and finance services that help smokers quit. The sponsor of the national Conference on Smoking Cessation was the Institute for the Study of Smoking Behavior and Policy at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> F. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION>. About 50 million Americans smoke. Despite a decline in the popularity of smoking, it is estimated 40 million people still will be puffing away in the year 2000. `` Are there ways to get more people to use these programs? This issue needs to be treated more like a business,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinney </PERSON>, executive director of the smoking institute, said in an interview. `` It's a mass marketing problem. We're trying to help people examine this issue in a way it has n't been examined before,'' said <PERSON> Pinney </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Smoking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> in the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> administration. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> insurance commissioner and another conference speaker, said insurance companies need to be compelled to offer discounts for non-smokers and reimbursements for the cost of programs smokers use to give up tobacco. A national leader in pushing for such insurance coverage, <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON> charged that the industry resists such efforts. `` The bottom line is that health insurance companies do n't want to have healthy citizens, because then they would make less money -LRB- from medical claims -RRB- ... What businessman in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is going to be in favor of that?'' <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON> said. He called on government regulators of health insurance to compel insurers to offer such coverage more widely. Later, in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, a spokesman for the health insurance industry dismissed <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON>'s charges. `` The insurance industry stands second to no one in its efforts to reduce smoking,'' said <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> B </PERSON>. White, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> White </PERSON> said health insurers have helped establish programs to promote health through the workplace and large health insurers offer discounts for individual policy holders who do n't smoke. `` It is to everyone's financial interest to reduce smoking as much as possible,'' said <PERSON> White </PERSON>, whose lobbying group represents 350 insurers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0708EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--DogVsMailman     07-14 0152</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Dog Vs Mailman,0155</SECOND>
<DATELINE>LIDO DI CAMAIORE, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It was a case of dog bites mailman, mail route bites the dust. Many residents in this coastal town north of <LOCATION> Pisa </LOCATION> have been forced to collect their mail from the post office since postman <PERSON> Carlo </PERSON> <PERSON> Lari </PERSON> lost a war of nerves with a local dog, the Italian news agency <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION> reported Thursday. According to <PERSON> Lari </PERSON>, the German shepherd barked furiously every time he appeared at a certain house and chased him if the gate was open, the news report said. But <PERSON> Lari </PERSON> found out the dog's bite was even worse than his bark. After he was bitten, the post office decided to eliminate part of his route, including the house of the dog owner. Local police had warned the dog's owner to keep the canine tied up and muzzled, the report said. It did not say when <PERSON> Lari </PERSON> was bitten.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0707EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-TinyTim     07-14 0171</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Tiny Tim,0175</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tiny Tim Gets Request for Tiptoe Tune, Dashes Out of Store</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FARGO, N.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When <PERSON> Tiny </PERSON> <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> got a request to sing his old hit `` Tiptoe Through the Tulips'' at a department store, he threw his hands in the air and ran out of the store. `` This came at a very untimely moment,'' <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> said Thursday at a news conference with other <LOCATION> Red </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fair </LOCATION> entertainers. <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> said he was trying to decide what skin-care products to buy earlier this week at <PERSON> Delendrecie </PERSON>'s in the West Acres shopping mall when a sales clerk asked him to sing the song. `` I said, ` Listen, I do n't get any products free here, and I'm certainly not going to do a number here,''' <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> said The singer said he only had about $ 200 to spend and was trying to choose from about $ 1,000 worth of products at the time. <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> apologized for the incident Thursday, and a store spokesman said <PERSON> Delendrecie </PERSON>'s hopes there is no hard feelings as well.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0243EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     07-14 0544</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0572</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JACKSON, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>'s entry in the Rose Bowl parade will have to float without <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON>. The estate of the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> native who went on to become the king of rock' n' roll has sunk a plan to include a giant spinning likeness of his head on the float. `` The float will go on, but it will be without <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Frascogna </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Mississippi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tournament </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roses </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Frascogna </PERSON> and his group have collected almost $ 100,000 in private donations to build a <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> float for the Jan. 1 parade in <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>'s float was to feature the likeness of natives who made it big in music rotating on record platters Planners singled out <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON>, as well as bluesman B.B. King, and country singers <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wynette </PERSON> and <PERSON> Conway </PERSON> <PERSON> Twitty </PERSON>. <PERSON> Frascogna </PERSON> said plans for the last three <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> natives are still on, and they may even ride the float personally. But about a month ago, <PERSON> Frascogna </PERSON> said, <LOCATION> Presley </LOCATION> estate's denied permission to use <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON>' likeness. `` A giant <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> was a risk,'' said <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Soden </PERSON>, executive director of <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON>' Graceland in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ST. AUGUSTINE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tourists from <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION> have been showing up on some north <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> beaches this year in birthday suits instead of swimsuits. In the past month, four of five groups of tourists who have taken it all off have been asked to put it back on, said Sgt. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Suddeth </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Johns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>. Besides being unaware of local laws and customs, the tourists generally do n't speak English, making it difficult for deputies to explain that they have to wear something in public. `` Once we show them the handcuffs, they generally get the message,'' he said. Public nudity is punishable by a maximum fine of $ 1,000 and a year in jail. Local citizens, both men and women, have reported the nude beachgoers to authorities, the sergeant said. `` One guy said, ` I do n't want to do this but my wife says I have to,''' <PERSON> Suddeth </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WAYLAND, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's a stand that would bring cheers from anyone with a pile of parking tickets. Police Chief <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Loughlin </PERSON> is running out of the tickets, and selectmen in this wealthy <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> suburb wo n't authorize the expenditure of $ 1,500 to buy 5,000 more. `` There's going to be some problems,'' <PERSON> O'Loughlin </PERSON> said Thursday. He has 50 tickets left, enough to last about 10 days. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, the selectmen's chairman, said if the ticket purchase is `` that important, he will buy -LRB- the tickets -RRB-. Something else in his budget will have to be reduced instead.'' Town officials planned to meet today to further discuss the issue. The police chief does n't think voters would mind paying the $ 1,500 for the new tickets. He said as much as they hate getting ticketed, they hate being blocked by illegally parked cars more. The return on the investment also is attractive, he said. Parking fines are $ 5 to $ 10, and the new tickets would generate about $ 37,500, he said. Once the tickets run out, <PERSON> O'Loughlin </PERSON> said he'll tell officers to tow vehicles parked in tow zones. But car owners who do n't feed parking meters will get a free ride.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Barry-Election     07-14 0249</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Barry-Election,241</SECOND>
<HEAD>Barry Reportedly Will Seek New Term</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mayor <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> said through a spokeswoman he will seek a fourth term in 1990 and expects <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ who has considered running for the job himself _ to campaign for him, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reports. <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonds </PERSON>, speaking for <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>, told the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, `` He's decided to run ... he is running.'' She said <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> will formally announce his candidacy in the fall, possibly in September. However, she said <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>, a Democrat whose administration has been dogged by scandal in recent months, wanted to let the public know his intentions. Some administration officials have said privately that <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>'s move is an attempt to keep <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> out of the race <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who is moving his family and national political organization from <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> this month, has said he is considering running for mayor here in the next election. However, he has said he would do so only if <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> did not run. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> for a speech to the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> Thursday night, told the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, `` I have no comment. I do n't know the context in which -LRB- the Barry statement -RRB- was made.'' `` We expect <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> to actively campaign for the mayor's reelection,'' <PERSON> Bonds </PERSON> said Thursday, pointing out <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>'s early support for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s 1984 campaign for president and the mayor's subsequent strong backing of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s political Bonds, a longtime aide, managed <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>'s 1986 re-election campaign and has been a key campaign aide since the 1970s.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0718EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BadChecks     07-14 0236</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bad Checks,0243</SECOND>
<HEAD>Merchant Sheds Light on Bad Check Writers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLUMBIA, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Corder </PERSON> says people who write bad checks for items at his convenience store now will pay: He's displaying their names on a large sign out front `` If you saw the stack of bad checks I got in here, you'd know why I was doing this,'' said <PERSON> Corder </PERSON>, whose convenience store is about four miles south of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Congaree </LOCATION>, a small town west of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. `` The sheriff's deputies can only do so much, and it's time I did something. The names of those who write checks that bounce are on a large yellow marquee with flashing lights in front of <PERSON> Corder </PERSON>'s Open Air Market. `` I had three bad checks from the same guy on three consecutive days. Now that made me mad,'' <PERSON> Corder </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Corder </PERSON> said he has about 30 bad checks totaling about $ 1,000, but there's only room on the sign for four names. So he's putting up another sign. He said he telephones and sends a registered letter requesting payment from people who write bad checks. If they do n't respond, he puts their name up 18 days after the bad check arrives back from the bank. People can get their names off the sign by paying him the money owed, <PERSON> Corder </PERSON> said. `` It's armed robbery, that's what it is,'' he said. `` They rob with a pen, not a pistol.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0246EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ApolloAnniversary     07-14 0232</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Apollo Anniversary,0237</SECOND>
<HEAD>Amrstrong, Aldrin Help NASA Celebrate 20th Anniversary of Apollo
11</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> and <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> `` Buzz'' <PERSON> Aldrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> thanked <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s rocket fuel researchers Thursday night during a celebration marking this month's 20th anniversary of the first manned landing on the moon. `` We were participants and witness to the birth of a new human era,'' <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> said in brief remarks to several hundred people at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Lewis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, which helped develop rocket fuel for the Apollo 11 flight. <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>, commander of the three-man Apollo 11 crew, and <PERSON> Aldrin </PERSON> said present and past researchers at the center had been instrumental in helping them accomplish the first manned lunar landing on July 20, 1969. `` Their contributions were of critical importance to our success,'' <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Aldrin </PERSON>, who followed <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> out of the Eagle landing craft onto the moon's surface, said he has expected for more than a year that the 20th anniversary of the Apollo 11 landing would have special meaning. `` I sense that the 20th anniversary is going to mean a lot for this nation,'' said <PERSON> Aldrin </PERSON>, who said it was unfortunate that the nation has n't sent a manned craft to the moon since Apollo 17 in 1972. <PERSON> Aldrin </PERSON> called for development of a space port which would serve as a stopover point in space using different types of transportation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0256EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SpaceGoals Bjt   07-14 0476</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Goals, Bjt,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Space Council Wants Permanent Base on Moon, Mars Landing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The National Space Council, working on `` a major new space initiative,'' is focusing on an American return to the <LOCATION> moon </LOCATION>, establishing a permanent base and proceeding from there to <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION>. But it will be expensive, warns Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, R-Pa., who was among a group of congressmen briefed Thursday on several options being considered by the council Any of the options, <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> said, will require `` a substantial increase in resources available to <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> _ it will require doubling the size of <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> budget.'' The council, headed by Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, favors the moon-Mars scenario over other courses being considered, <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> said, but no final decision has been made. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Truly </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Albrecht </PERSON>, executive secretary of the space council, conducted the briefing. `` They basically outlined three options,'' <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, the ranking Republican member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> space science subcommittee, said in an interview. `` One, for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to move ahead with a robotic program and gradually phase men out of the space program; another, to go back to the moon with the idea of establishing a permanent moon base and then going from there to <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION>; and third, to take us directly to <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION> after the turn of the century.'' The council is not expected to make a recommendation about <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s space future to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in time for inclusion in his speech next Thursday on the 20th anniversary of the first landing on the moon. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> said <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is `` basically consulting with the people on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> who have something to say about authorizing space funds as an advance of <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> consideration of a major new space initiative.'' Attending the meeting in the White House complex were the chairmen and ranking members of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittees and committees that handle the space program. The space agency has asked for $ 13 billion in the next fiscal year, but is likely to get far less than that from a budget-minded <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` I made the point that they basically were asking for us to find about 2 percent of the federal budget for <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> in the 1990s and into the next century,'' <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> said. `` We were almost double that level in the 1960s _ this nation has shown it is capable of spending 3.6 percent of the budget for space activity if the program is truly visionary.'' The National Space Council was established by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as a presidential advisory body. It includes the secretaries of <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION>, the director of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>, the White House chief of staff, the national security adviser, the president's science adviser, the director of the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> administrator.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890714-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-14-89 0308EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Audi     07-14 0479</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Audi,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Closes Books on Audi `Sudden Acceleration' Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
