<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 2329EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-PayRaise 2ndLd-Writethru a0737 02-01 1069</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pay Raise, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0737,900</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wright Under Increasing Pressure to Schedule Pay Raise Vote</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Top 5 grafs new with Wright proposing scaled-back pay raise,
picks up into 2nd graf previous ``Survey results''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> is planning to ask the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to scale back the congressional pay raise scheduled to take effect next week, even as <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members were lining up overwhelmingly against the increase, a congressional source said Wednesday. The $ 45,500 pay raise _ a 51 percent hike _ will take effect next Wednesday unless both the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote to block it. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, plans to propose that the increase be scaled back to 30 percent, said the source, speaking on condition of anonymity. A 30 percent raise would hike the current congressional salary from $ 89,500 by $ 26,850, to a total of $ 116,350. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> plans to seek a vote on approving the lower raise on Feb. 9, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Thursday editions. Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members indicated in an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> survey that they want a vote on the sensitive issue. Survey results put additional pressure on <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> to abandon a carefully orchestrated strategy of taking no vote until after the raise automatically takes effect next Wednesday. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said Tuesday he would hold a vote if that was what lawmakers wanted. The speaker announced he was circulating a questionnaire privately to determine whether <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members really wanted a recorded vote. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s tally was not made available Wednesday. However, an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> informal survey of nearly a third of the 435 House members showed about 88 percent of those responding wanted a vote on the pay raise. Meanwhile, a survey of the entire <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> released Wednesday by opponents of the pay raise showed 62 percent saying they would vote `` no'' if the issue came to a vote. Under the law, members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and other top federal officials will get pay raises of about 50 percent on Feb. 8 unless both chambers reject it. Rank-and-file congressional salaries would go from $ 89,500 to $ 135,000, under the recommendation submitted by former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and supported by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, has promised a vote in his chamber this week. Surveys show the pay raise would be handily rejected there. House Democratic leaders, with <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> consent, had adopted a strategy of avoiding a vote until after the deadline and then softening the political blow of the substantial pay raise by passing new ethics rules including a ban on lawmakers accepting speaking fees. The strategy was based on the opinion that <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members supported the raise but would find it politically impossible to vote for it. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, who had been taking most of the political heat on the issue, changed that strategy on Tuesday. His survey was designed, in part, to demonstrate that it was not <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> alone who favored the pay increase. `` Over the past several weeks, I have heard from many members on both sides of the aisle. I have a pretty good idea of how they feel,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said. `` They support ` regular procedure''' _ which would mean committee hearings and a legislative schedule that would make a vote impossible before the Feb. 8 deadline. But when asked if he would permit a vote should members surprise him and demand one, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said, `` If the members want it, yes, of course'' The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> contacted 143 congressional offices and found 92 members publicly supporting a recorded vote on the pay raise. Only six said they were against it and seven were undecided. There was no response from 38 offices. It should be noted that advocates of the pay raise have been reluctant to publicly indicate their support, for fear of the political fallout. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s spokesman, said it would be wrong to use any informal surveys to predict the results of the speaker's private survey. However, another top leadership aide, speaking on the condition of anonymity, pointed out that the speaker's survey could compound the political problem if the results are at odds with those from media surveys. Several lawmakers who were following the leadership strategy of keeping silent on the issue privately expressed aggravation at the speaker's new tactic. `` This is like a war in which the general says to take the hill, you turn around, and find the general's gone,'' said a Republican member who spoke on the condition of anonymity. If a vote were scheduled, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members overwhelmingly would reject the pay increase, according to a survey released Wednesday by several groups opposed to the increase. The survey said 270 House members, or about 62 percent, said they would oppose the raise if it came to a vote. Forty-seven, or about 11 percent, said they would support the raise; 75 members, about 17 percent, declined to state a position, and 41 members, about 9 percent, declined to respond. The survey was conducted by <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citizen </ORGANIZATION>, a consumer advocacy group founded by <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Nader </PERSON>; the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taxpayers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, a non-partisan organization of fiscal conservatives; and <ORGANIZATION> Coalitions </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, a conservative organization headed by activist <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Weyrich </PERSON>. After the survey was released, Rep. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Carper </PERSON>, R-Del., said he too was against the raise, even though the survey had listed him as undecided Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Roe </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, was also listed as undecided, but has been publicly opposed to the raise for more than a week. `` A failure to vote on this issue would be a fundamental breakdown of democracy,'' said <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Claybrook </PERSON>, president of Public Citizen. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> opponents of the pay increase, at a hearing of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said the current system of allowing pay increases to take effect without a vote was hurting <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' public image `` What must they think of us, when we run from accountability, as cockroaches run from bright light?'' said Sen. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, R-N.H. Sen. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION> told the committee that, `` People all over the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are saying, ` They're a bunch of crooks'.'' But committee member <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, said the raise was needed, especially for judges and federal officials. `` What does it cost government to have incompetent people at the top?'' <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> asked. With the future of the pay raise uncertain, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiators were moving ahead Wednesday with their separate but similar efforts to draft ethics legislation to bar honoraria and restrict other outside income.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PresidentialDucks     02-01 0505</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Presidential Ducks,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Duck Talk Sweeps the White House</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> may be getting his ducks in a row on the federal budget, but he certainly does n't want any of his budget lines to turn up as ducks. That's because a duck by any other name in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> these days is a tax increase. And <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration officials insist there'll be no ducks _ new taxes _ in the budget plan <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sends <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Feb. 9. This duck business started when budget director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> wrote a letter to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> reaffirming <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s intention to resist new taxes. On whether the administration might hide a tax under another name, <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> suggested that would n't wash. Most Americans, he suggested, know that `` if it walks like a duck and quacks like a duck, it must be a duck.'' That's an old line, but <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> gave it new currency. Now it has joined the lexicon of other budget cliches, mentioned almost as frequently these days as that mythical budget `` table'' that items are always described as being off or on. As in, nothing's `` off the table.'' Or everything's `` on the table.'' `` Not to mix metaphors, but ducks are off the table,'' <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> himself has picked up on the duck talk. At his first news conference, he was asked whether a <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> proposal for a depositor fee to assist troubled savings-and-loans might violate his anti-tax stand. `` I would refer you to <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>,'' the president responded. `` He's the guy that defined that very well up there with the duck test on the Hill.'' <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> repeatedly used the duck analogy during his confirmation hearings. He was presented at one point with a mock trophy by committee Chairman Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>. It consisted of three bright yellow toy ducks and the label, `` if it quacks, it's a tax.'' White House Chief of Staff <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> threw yet another ingredient into the duck soup _ a rose. Asked at a news conference whether he thought the savings and loan fee was a tax, <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> responded obliquely: `` Yesterday's rose is tomorrow's rose.'' When he did not elaborate further, he was asked: `` A rose is a rose?'' and `` It passes the rose test?'' `` Let's put it this way,'' <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> said. `` Yesterday's duck is tomorrow's duck.'' Actually today's duck is not yesterday's duck, so far as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is concerned. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s duck of yesteryear was not a tax increase but a Sandinista. When running for re-election in 1984, then-Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> caused something of a stir in a campaign speech at <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> A & amp; M <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> as he portrayed the Sandinista government in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> as Marxist. `` If you walk like a duck and you quack like a duck and you say you're a duck, you're a duck,'' he said. But so far, the new <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration has n't reported any conversations with tax ducks.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0237EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FAAOrder Bjt   02-01 0697</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-FAA Order, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mixed-up Wiring, Plumbing in 17 Airliners Prompts Blanket Order</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 700 <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> jetliners operated by every major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airline must undergo a comprehensive inspection for cross-wiring and cross-plumbing in their safety systems, after problems were discovered in 17 aircraft. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administraton </ORGANIZATION>, in issuing the `` airworthiness directive'' late Tuesday, also noted that <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> is studying its design, production procedures and testing of airliner emergency systems to see if changes are needed. The newly ordered tests are not expected to disrupt airline schedules and can be completed anytime over the next 3 -LCB- weeks while the airliners are undergoing routine maintenance. The order affects 741 newer jetliners flown by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> carriers. It applies to all <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737s, 747s, 757s and 767s built after Dec. 31, 1980. Most foreign airliners using the planes also are expected to comply, although the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> has no jurisdiction over them. `` The comprehensive -LRB- directive -RRB- will require functional testing of the engine and cargo compartment fire detection, warning and extinguishing systems, both electrical and plumbing to insure that crossed wiring or plumbing does not exist,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> announcement. No accident or emergency has resulted from faulty wiring or plumbing found in airliners in recent weeks after the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> issued limited directives applying to only specific systems in certain types of aircraft. But the foulups, including cross-wiring, cross-plumbing, incomplete wiring and other problems, could have caused shutdown of the wrong engine in the event of fire, activation of the wrong sprinkling system in a cargo hold or lack of any response in emergency systems. The concern arose with speculation that the pilot in a Jan. 8 British <ORGANIZATION> Midland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> 737 crash that killed 44 people in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> may have been deceived by faulty wiring into shutting down his only good engine. Cause of the crash is still under investigation. The crash led to similar inspection orders in <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. Airbus 320s also were included in the British order, although problems have been found only in <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> aircraft. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Gamble </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said Tuesday night that the directive is based on service bulletins <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> has been putting out in recent months and years. Service bulletins are sent out each time a problem of some sort is found with a model of a plane to all carriers using that model and to the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>. Checks of planes are voluntary after a service bulletin is issued. But if the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> sees a pattern in the bulletins, it is likely to issue a directive, making checks of the airliners mandatory. `` It's a preventive and precautionary check,'' he said. <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrar </PERSON> said the latest order, which gives airlines 25 days to comply, would not disrupt regularly scheduled flights. He said planes whose systems were already tested under previous orders need not retest under the new order. <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Gamble </PERSON> said `` a lot of the'57 and'37 stuff already has been done.'' The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> estimated the inspections would cost airlines a total of $ 222,000. Airline analysts say, however, that actual cost of FAA-ordered inspections is generally two or three times higher than the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> estimates. It said the order is a `` precautionary measure'' triggered by newly discovered problems with three 757s and a 737. <PERSON> Farrar </PERSON> said he did not know which airlines reported the latest cases of faulty wiring. On one plane, an overheat indicator would have shown a problem in the wrong engine. In two others, fire extinguishers would have been triggered in the wrong engines. In the fourth, an incomplete circuit would have prevented a fire extinguisher from firing. The first cross-wiring directive applying only to two 737 models found no problems. A second triggered by reports of cross-wiring in two 757s, resulted in discovery of five more miswired aircraft. Earlier directives followed discovery of improperly installed plumbing in two 767s. The inspections exposed four other aircraft with similar problems that, in the event of a fire in one of two holds, would have routed extinguishing fluids to the hold that was not burning. The inspections would cover 472 <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737s, 33 Jumbo 747s, 123 757s and 113 767s, the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-StAlbansBodies 1stLd-Writethru a0446 02-01 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-St Albans Bodies, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0446,0426</SECOND>
<HEAD>Six Found Dead at West Virginia Trailer Compound</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: DELETES 4th graf, `It was,' and INSERTS one graf after 6th graf
pvs, `On Monday,' to CORRECT that sheriff was referring to Price, sted
Schillings slaying.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto CN1</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ST. ALBANS, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities have discovered the bodies of six people who were shot in the head with a shotgun near a trailer compound, and one of the residents has been charged with two of the deaths. The body of a man found Tuesday in the rusted hull of a car in a junkyard near the three-trailer compound appeared to have been shot twice in the back of the head at close range, said Assistant State Medical Examiner Dr. <PERSON> Vasudeo </PERSON> <PERSON> Kshirsagar </PERSON>. The condition of the body indicated that the victim had been dead several months, <PERSON> Kshirsagar </PERSON> said, adding that the five others appeared to have been killed in a similar manner. Police believe the body is that of 20-year-old <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Schillings </PERSON> of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, who came to the compound to live last spring and was reported missing last summer. On Monday, the body of 22-year-old <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON> was found on the site about 30 feet from the car, authorities said. The junkyard is about 200 yards east of the compound, where the first two bodies were discovered Jan. 8. `` We have a consistent pattern. It was a shotgun. It was consistent with the other cases,'' said <LOCATION> Kanawha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Ashley </PERSON>. If all six bodies are linked to the same killer, it would be the worst series of deaths in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> attributed to the same person. Authorities said 19-year-old <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Southern </PERSON> <PERSON> McCallister </PERSON> is being held without bond on charges of murdering brothers <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Otis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanson </PERSON>, who lived with <PERSON> McCallister </PERSON> at the compound in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Albans </LOCATION>, a town of 15,000 people 15 miles west of <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>. Prosecutors said <PERSON> McCallister </PERSON> has confessed to the brothers' murders Police found the body of the Sansons' sister, <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Pauley </PERSON>, at an abandoned motel across the street from the compound on Jan. 21. Another victim, <PERSON> McCallister </PERSON>'s grandmother, <PERSON> Charlotte </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrell </PERSON>, 69, was found in her nearby home. `` We hope this ight wrap up the investigation from the standpoint of looking for people,'' <PERSON> Ashley </PERSON> said. The sheriff's department declined to say whether <PERSON> McCallister </PERSON> would be charged in the other deaths or to speculate on a motive. However, authorities said all the victims lived at the compound, which is now abandoned, and Price and Schillings had dated <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Pauley </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0243EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RobotVision     02-01 0369</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Robot Vision,0379</SECOND>
<HEAD>Researchers Show Fast Method for Robot Depth Perception</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Want to see how some robots of the future may find their way around? Hold a finger in front of you and stare at it. Now shake your head, still focusing on that finger. Objects behind your finger appear to move in the same direction as your head, while those in front of it move in the opposite direction. Using that principle, researchers have demonstrated a fast method for depth perception in visually guided robots, which should help them navigate around objects more quickly, a scientist says. A robot at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rochester </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> state trains a pair of cameras on an object to gauge the distance to it, said <PERSON> Dana </PERSON> <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON>, a computer science professor at the university. The distance measurement is updated 30 times a second, <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON> said, so `` it potentially allows you to move at high speed.'' Current robots guided by visual feedback can move only slowly because of the time it takes them to judge the location of objects in their path, he said Tuesday. <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Thorpe </PERSON>, research scientist at the <ORGANIZATION> Robotics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie-Mellon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, said the <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION> robot is the first to combine several previously known concepts into such a high-speed system. The cameras are mounted on a motor-driven platform that allows them to move up and down or side to side. The platform is mounted on the end of a large industrial robot arm, allowing the platform to move over a range about 12 feet in diameter at speeds up to about one yard per second. Currently, a human directs the cameras to a reference point, but eventually that will occur automatically, <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. The work shows it is easier for computers to calculate distance to objects if the images come from moving cameras than if the cameras are stationary, he said. The research also demonstrated a way for the pair of cameras to remain locked on an object while it moves toward the robot, an ability called vergence, he said. The work was led by <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON> and colleague <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0256EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Mandela     02-01 0402</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mandela,0418</SECOND>
<HEAD>ANC Urges Winnie Mandela to Disband Youth Group</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GREG MYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has asked anti-apartheid activist <PERSON> Winnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> to disband her group of teen-age bodyguards, which has been accused of kidnapping and engaging in gang feuds. Anglican Archbishop <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> and community leaders in the black township of <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION> support disbanding the group, known as the <ORGANIZATION> Mandela </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> soccer club, saying it hurts the campaign to end white minority rule. Several newspapers have reported that continuing allegations that the youth group has engaged in unlawful behavior have become a source of friction between Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> and her husband <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s best-known black leader. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> has been imprisoned since 1962 for his <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> activities. `` Winnie ca n't afford to have the <LOCATION> Mandela </LOCATION> name dragged through the mud by associating with these people,'' <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> newspaper Business Day reported Tuesday. At the <LOCATION> Lusaka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Zambia </LOCATION> headquarters of the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION>, spokesman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sebina </PERSON> said Tuesday that the message about <ORGANIZATION> Mandela </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> was sent to Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> after discussions among the organization's leaders The youths, who generally wear track suits, often accompany Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> to public gatherings. Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> last week said she had disbanded the group because of `` state harassment.'' But several of the youths were present Saturday when she attended the funeral of a slain activist. While guarding Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>, the youths occasionally have threatened journalists and others. In July, the <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> family home in <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION> was destroyed in a fire set by a gang of black high school students who had been feuding with <ORGANIZATION> Mandela </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> members. <ORGANIZATION> Mandela </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> also has been accused of abducting four youths from a <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION> church. One of the four still is missing. Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> and others have alleged the kidnapped youths may have been sexually abused by a church clergyman. About 150 <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION> community leaders met last week to investigate the abductions, and later urged that <ORGANIZATION> Mandela </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> be disbanded. Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>, widely viewed abroad as a hero of the fight against the white minority government's policy of racial separation, has become entangled in several controversies in recent years. She has endorsed `` necklace'' killings, whereby black activists set alight gasoline-soaked tires placed around the necks of so-called government collaborators. She also has been criticized for building the mansion in <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION>, although she has never moved into it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0257EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtoninBrief     02-01 0601</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington in Brief,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Many People Missing out on SSI Benefits</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Almost half of the nation's senior citizens who may be eligible for Supplemental Security Income benefits are not enrolled in the program, according to the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retired </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Persons </ORGANIZATION>. SSI provides monthly cash payments to eligible low-income people who are 65 years and older, blind or disabled. The maximum federal SSI benefit this year is $ 368 a month for an individual and $ 553 a month for a couple. Some states supplement the payments with their own funds. The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> estimates that 36 percent of SSI recipients receive state supplements. The study, conducted for <ORGANIZATION> AARP </ORGANIZATION> by <ORGANIZATION> ICF </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a research and consulting firm, said its finding was consistent with other surveys that have put the <ORGANIZATION> SSI </ORGANIZATION> participation rate at about 50 percent. Another study conducted for <ORGANIZATION> AARP </ORGANIZATION> by <ORGANIZATION> Louis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Harris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> found that one-third of the eligible older people who are not receiving <ORGANIZATION> SSI </ORGANIZATION> benefits have never heard of the program, and many others are misinformed about eligibility requirements. SSI paid about $ 12.3 billion in federal benefits last fiscal year and is budgeted to pay out $ 12.5 billion this year.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>Tutu Praises Baker</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Archbishop <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> says he is impressed that Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> appears open-minded to ideas on pressing <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> to abolish its system of apartheid. `` I do n't want to be euphoric, but we certainly have been impressed,'' said the Nobel Peace Prize winner, who attended a meeting Tuesday between <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> and a delegation sponsored by the World Council of Churches. <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> said <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> made no promises, but indicated the new administration is reviewing its policy toward <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. Asked to compare his meeting with <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> and past sessions with former Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> said, `` I was very impressed by the fact that he was not dogmatic, he actually was discussing with the group and was interested in any initiative that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> might actively take to pressure the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> African </LOCATION> government to the negotiating table.'' `` They are ... involved in a review process. He did not dismiss us, he listened to us with very considerable interest,'' <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> said after the half-hour session at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> joined a delegation that has been on a three-week tour of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, several West European capitals and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to convince government officials to take a stronger stand against <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s apartheid policy.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>FDA Panel Develops Guidelines on Dental X-rays</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> panel has set new guidelines on how often people need dental X-rays, saying its goal is to eliminate any unneeded radiation exposure. Children with healthy teeth may need dental X-rays no more than once every year or two, and dentally healthy adults once every two or three years, the panel said. The guidelines, reported in the current issue of the Journal of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, were prompted by concern among some experts about the frequency of dental X-rays, both overuse and underuse. `` Although the radiation risk from a dental X-ray is extremely low, our goal is to eliminate any unneeded radiation exposure,'' <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said in statement Tuesday. `` Until these guidelines were developed, there were few concrete criteria a dentist could use in deciding when X-rays were needed,'' he said. Young also stressed the flexibility of the guidelines, saying, `` These are not hard and fast rules. In deciding whether an X-ray is needed, the dentist must use clinical judgment in evaluating the patient's needs.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0316EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GrandMarshal Bjt   02-01 0485</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Grand Marshal, Bjt,0502</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman To Lead St. Patrick's Day Parade</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY9</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE NEUMEISTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The `` First Lady of <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION>'' has been chosen as the first female grand marshal of the St. Patrick's Day parade in its 226-year history. And <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> <PERSON> Cudahy </PERSON> _ who accepted the honor with smilin' Irish eyes, not tearful ones _ says it's about time Mrs. <PERSON> Cudahy </PERSON>, 66, had been passed over in favor of a man in three previous years before she was elected Tuesday night to lead the 200,000 marchers in the nation's largest and oldest St. Patrick's Day celebration Afterward, she said <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> women have too often been left standing in the wings while men took center stage. `` Like everything else, men run it but women do all the work,'' she said of past parades. `` When I march up there, ladies and gentleman, girls and boys will remember my mother and your mother and all the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> women who came over here and did so much,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Cudahy </PERSON> said. Mrs. <PERSON> Cudahy </PERSON> and the other nominee, 61-year-old <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Holt </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, were on stage in front of 600 people in a <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> ballroom when the vote was announced. Mrs. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, a school teacher, hugged and kissed the winner. Mrs. <PERSON> Cudahy </PERSON> is known as the `` First Lady of Irish Radio'' for her `` Irish Memories'' program, which moved last August to WNWK-FM after more than 40 years on <ORGANIZATION> WEVD </ORGANIZATION>. `` This achievement was really your achievement,'' she told the delegates. The vote was narrow, 256 to 233, but the crowd seemed unanimous in its delight at seeing a woman chosen to lead the March 17 parade up Fifth Avenue. `` I guess we are a chauvinistic race,'' said delegate <PERSON> Noah </PERSON> <PERSON> Kingston </PERSON>. `` I suppose the European races in general are. We've always just went along with the status quo But the times have changed and it's long overdue really.'' `` It's about time,'' said <PERSON> Irene </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonnell </PERSON>, a member of the Ancient Order of Hibernians. `` The women in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> used to hold a high place before the English invaded.'' The delegates who picked the grand marshal were chosen from about 200 affiliated organizations that march in the more than 40-block-long parade, which usually attracts more than a million spectators. The organizations include the Ancient Order of Hibernians, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Counties </ORGANIZATION> and schools and fraternal organizations. Mrs. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said her name would not be on the ballot again. `` They kept saying, ` Next year,' and I said, ` No way,' `` she said. Although Mrs. <PERSON> Cudahy </PERSON> was widely expected to win this year, she said she `` just could n't believe it'' when the votes were tallied. But she accepted the honor with dry eyes and said she will be `` representing all the women of <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> who came over as immigrants.'' `` I'm not the crying type,'' she said. `` I guess I'm not reacting like a woman, but I'm so happy.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0338EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SriLanka-Premadasa     02-01 0531</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sri Lanka-Premadasa,0548</SECOND>
<HEAD>New President Tries To Bring Peace, But Violence Continues</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEXTER CRUEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLOMBO, Sri Lanka (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Ranasinghe </PERSON> <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON>, who completes a turbulent first month in office today, is trying hard to vanquish a legacy of ethnic violence and chart a more peaceful course for his island nation. Since taking over Jan. 2, he has freed more than 1,400 political prisoners and lifted tough emergency laws that were imposed 5 -LCB- years ago in an effort to control an insurgency by minority Tamil extremists. Political rivals credit <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> with shrewd moves. `` He had to do something startling with the looming general elections,'' scheduled for Feb. 15, said <PERSON> Kumar </PERSON> <PERSON> Ponnabalam </PERSON>, leader of the opposition All <ORGANIZATION> Ceylon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tamil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Despite <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON>'s efforts, an extremist group whose members are of the Sinhalese ethnic majority has stepped up attacks aimed at thwarting the vote. Police say The <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> killed 600 people in January alone. A Western diplomat, speaking on condition of anonymity, termed the figure `` a bit far-fetched'', but declined to say how many people he thought had been killed. For <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON>, who served as prime minister under former president <PERSON> Junius </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jayewardene </PERSON>, the parliamentary elections will be vital since his plans could be stalled if his <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> does not gain a parliamentary majority. `` The period to come is -LRB- <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON>'s -RRB- greatest challenge,'' said <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Bultjens </PERSON>, a veteran Sri Lanka-watcher and a political science professor at the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. `` Feb. 15 is his most urgent hour.'' In the year leading up to the Dec. 19 presidential election, Sinhalese extremists killed more than 800 people, mostly government officials, supporters and police, authorities said. Most of the victims were Sinhalese, who comprise 75 percent of the <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> island's 16 million people and dominate the government, which the front says has made too many concessions to the Tamils. During his election campaign, <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> took pains not to blame the Sinhalese guerrillas for the violence. Instead, he made fervent appeals to the front to lay down arms and join mainstream politics. But <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON>'s `` gamble failed,'' said another Western diplomat, who spoke on condition of anonymity. `` The Sinhalese extremists are bent upon violence and will not heed appeals.'' Despite the violence, <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> will fulfill campaign promises to help the poor, said <PERSON> Ranjan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wijeratna </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> plans to give $ 75 monthly to 1.4 million families that live in extreme poverty. The annual per capita income of nearly half the country's population is well below the national average of $ 360. Some of <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> campaign promises that have already materialized: 3,500 Indian soldiers were withdrawn and <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> agreed to consider <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON>'s promise to change the Indian-Sri Lankan peace accord into a friendship treaty. The July 1987 accord, an attempt to end the Tamil insurgency, allowed Indian troops onto the island to disarm Tamil guerrillas. But <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s attempt to play peacemaker for its southern neighbor met with resistance from Tamil militants and at least 600 Indian soldiers have been killed. About 44,000 Indian soldiers remain in the country. The Tamil separatist war has claimed about 8,500 lives, most of them Sinhalese civilians.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0341EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Korea-Adultery     02-01 0290</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Korea-Adultery,0298</SECOND>
<HEAD>Majority Of Koreans Oppose Abolishing Adultery As Crime: Survey</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A slim majority of South Koreans oppose abolishing a law under which people convicted of adultery can be sentenced up to a year in jail, according to a survey released today. These South Koreans feel that if penalties for adultery are revoked, illicit sex will increase and public morals will decline, the <ORGANIZATION> Korea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Applied </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> said its survey indicates. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> has said it will ask the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> to abolish the law, but the institute said 51 percent of those polled oppose the move to drop adultery from the criminal codes. The private research institute said 60 percent of the 752 women surveyed and 42 percent of the 756 male respondents wanted to keep the law. The survey was conducted Jan. 18-20 in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>. Pollsters said 53 percent of the respondents in their 20s also felt adultery should remain a crime. When those in favor of abolishing the law were asked their reasons, 66 percent said adultery was an individual concern, not a matter for the government. Twelve percent said the law does n't keep spouses faithful. Seventy percent who wanted to keep the law said promiscuity and immoral sexual behavior would increase without it. Sixteen percent said wives would be hurt by losing a legal handle to check indiscretions committed by husbands. Forty percent said men would benefit more than women if the law were changed and only 11 percent said women had more to gain. Nearly half of those polled, 46 percent, thought adultery was on the rise and 25 percent said it was increasing at an `` alarming rate.'' No margin of error was given for the survey.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0320EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Japan-Markets     02-01 0300</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Markets,0310</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dollar Rises, Stocks Fall On Tokyo Exchange</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The dollar resumed its strong gains against the Japanese yen today, while share prices plunged on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> as the dollar's rise discouraged investors, dealers said. The Nikkei Stock Average of 225 selected issues, a 13.80-point gainer Tuesday, lost 220.62 points, or 0.70 percent, closing at 31,360.68. The index started downward in early trading after the dollar's higher opening in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Kiyoshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Iwasaki </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Nomura </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s largest brokerage `` Since the majority of investors have been concerned over the index's rapid rise recently, they began concertedly selling as prices went down,'' he added. A major influence on the Nikkei, he said, was a decline in financial issues. Today's trading, dominated by sell orders, was active, with volume on the first section estimated at 1 billion shares. On the foreign exchange market, the dollar closed at 130.40, up 1.27 yen from Tuesday's close of 129.13 yen. The dollar opened at 130.58 and ranged between 130.20 yen and 130.67 yen. The dollar had gained a total of 2.21 yen last Friday and Monday, but fell 0.60 yen on Tuesday before climbing again. Today's early <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> trading was dominated by dollar-buying, but then speculative investors started selling to take profits, said a dealer with the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION>, speaking on condition of anonymity. The dollar's strong opening in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> followed a surge in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> prompted by comments by <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> that current exchange rates were tolerable, dealers said. Testifying before a joint economic committee of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> industry is competitive enough at the present dollar rate. He added that the current rate of inflation was too high and that he expected a substantial cut in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade deficit.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0340EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HerpesDrug Bjt   02-01 0686</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Herpes Drug, Bjt,0702</SECOND>
<HEAD>Herpes Virus Becomes Resistant to Common Antiviral Drug</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL Q. HANEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The appearance of viruses that can escape the herpes drug may be an early sign that a new class of medicines designed to wipe out viruses will be outwitted by its foes, just as bacteria-killing drugs have been, researchers say. Disease-causing herpes viruses that are resistant to the widely used drug acyclovir have been seen in AIDS patients, who have little natural ability to ward off microbes. Resistant viruses have not been found in otherwise healthy people who take the drug for ordinary outbreaks of genital herpes sores. Researchers disagree over whether the resistant viruses will spread into the general population. `` We see no lack of efficacy of acyclovir in normal patients. I do n't think it should be a concern at all,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON>, a senior scientist at <ORGANIZATION> Burroughs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wellcome </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which produces the drug. However, Dr. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hirsch </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> said the current situation may parallel the development of penicillin in the 1940s. `` For the last 40 years, it's been a battle between the organism and the drug to see which can outwit the other, and it's been a series of new drugs to try to overcome bacterial resistance,'' <PERSON> Hirsch </PERSON> said in an interview. `` Viruses have never presented that problem up until now, but it would n't surprise me that during the next 40 years we see the same kind of phenomenon developing in virology.'' Two reports on drug-resistant viruses are being published in Thursday's New England Journal of Medicine. In one of the studies, doctors described the cases of 12 AIDS patients who developed severe herpes infections that did not respond to acyclovir. One co-author, Dr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mills </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, estimates that one in 1,000 AIDS patients has acyclovir-resistant herpes. In the other study, doctors reported two AIDS victims and one leukemia patient who had overwhelming cytomegalovirus, or CMV, infection that could not be treated with ganciclovir, a still-experimental antiviral drug. Researchers believe that resistance occurs through natural genetic mutation. A strain of the virus emerges that has genes making it impervious to a drug. Then the resistant strain multiplies and spreads through the victim's body while all the other forms of the virus are killed off by the medicine. An estimated 30 million Americans are infected with the genital herpes virus, known as herpes simplex virus type 2. Most of them never develop any symptoms. But for the minority with recurring genital sores, acyclovir is the only treatment, although others are being tested. Cytomegalovirus infects an estimated 60 percent to 90 percent of Americans and rarely causes illness in otherwise healthy people. However, in those whose disease defenses are weak, the virus can attack organs through the body, resulting in blindness or death. Ever since acyclovir's introduction seven years ago as the first widely available antiviral drug, some virus researchers have worried that the herpes virus would evolve into forms that could elude the medicine and still cause disease. `` What we had feared for many years would happen now appears to be happening, at least in the AIDS population,'' said <PERSON> Hirsch </PERSON>. Dr. <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION>, a co-author of one of the studies, said he expects drug-resistant viruses to complicate treatment of organ transplant patients. They must take immunity-lowering drugs to keep their bodies from rejecting their new organs. Since the drug-resistant viruses have not been seen in healthy people, doctors can not be sure whether the viruses will become a problem for the general population. `` One concern is that someone with AIDS could give one of these resistant viruses to someone else, and then it could become established in the normal population,'' said <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>. Dr. <PERSON> Clyde </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Crumpacker </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Beth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, another co-author of the research, said he doubts this will happen. `` I have been aware of most of the cases of resistance that have occurred, and it is an unlikely event,'' he said. `` It is not occurring in the normal population that we have been watching.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0346EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AirTanker-Facts     02-01 0149</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Air Tanker-Facts,0161</SECOND>
<HEAD>Facts About the KC-135A</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Air Tanker Crash, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> KC-135A, a modified version of a <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 707 that refuels planes in the air, crashed near <LOCATION> Abilene </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, killing all 19 aboard. Here are some facts about the KC-135A. _ First model flown in 1956. _ Powered by four <ORGANIZATION> Pratt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> jet engines. _ Wingspan, 130 feet, 10 inches. _ Length, 136 feet, 3 inches. _ Height, 41 feet, 8 inches. _ Weight, 98,466 pounds. _ Maximum takeoff weight, 297,000 pounds. _ Maximum speed, 600 mph. _ Range, 1,150 miles while carrying 120,000 pounds of transfer fuel. Can fly up to 9,200 miles on a ferry mission. _ Normally flies at or below 50,000 feet. _ Normal crew pilot, co-pilot, navigator, boom operator; able to carry many more passengers. _ Cost, $ 20.1 million. _ <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> nickname, Stratotanker.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0412EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Philippines     02-01 0551</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Philippines,0566</SECOND>
<HEAD>Marcos Supporter Acquitted In 1987 Takeover Attempt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By YASMIN ARQUIZA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge today acquitted a prominent supporter of <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> of rebellion, saying his takeover of a provincial government during a 1987 coup attempt was not violent enough to merit conviction. But Judge <PERSON> Maximiano </PERSON> <PERSON> Asuncion </PERSON> sentenced <PERSON> Orlando </PERSON> <PERSON> Dulay </PERSON> to 10 months in prison and fined him the equivalent of $ 50 for trying to strangle the governor and holding other officials and employees of <PERSON> Quirino </PERSON> province during the Aug. 28, 1987 coup attempt, in which 53 people were killed in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. It was the most serious of about a half-dozen coup attempts since President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> rose to power in a February 1986 revolt that sent <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> into exile in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. Records of the case show that <PERSON> Dulay </PERSON> and about 50 rebel soldiers and police barged into the capitol building in the Qurino provincial capital of <LOCATION> Cabarroguis </LOCATION> and announced a takeover of the local government. But in acquitting <PERSON> Dulay </PERSON> and four other defendants, <LOCATION> Asuncion </LOCATION> said that announcing a takeover and appointing new officials `` are not sufficient to hold them liable for the crime of rebellion.'' `` To constitute rebellion, there must be some sort of public uprising which is absent in the instant case,'' said the judge. `` And when we say public uprising, there must be men engaging in war against the forces of government.'' `` In order to commit the crime rebellion, there must be public uprising and taking of arms against the government,'' the judge added. <PERSON> Dulay </PERSON> has been in jail since March 1987 _ longer than his sentence. But <LOCATION> Asuncion </LOCATION> did not order Dulay's release because he faces charges of murdering two supporters of Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> during the February 1986 presidential election. <PERSON> Dulay </PERSON> was in jail in <LOCATION> Quirino </LOCATION>, 100 miles north of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, pending trial on the murder charges when the coup attempt began. Some of the soldiers and policemen who preceded him to the capitol building during the brief takeover were his prison guards. During the trial, prosecutors presented witnesses who described how <PERSON> Dulay </PERSON> wrung the neck of Gov. <PERSON> Renicolas </PERSON> <PERSON> Delizo </PERSON> and yelled: `` Goddamn, you will die, I will kill you.'' <PERSON> Dulay </PERSON>, who was dressed in military combat fatigues, then put a gun to <PERSON> Delizo </PERSON>'s head, the witnesses said. <PERSON> Dulay </PERSON> and his armed followers next herded <PERSON> Delizo </PERSON> and others into the governor's office and held them there until midnight, when it became clear in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> that the coup attempt had failed. <PERSON> Dulay </PERSON> acknowledged that he grabbed <PERSON> Delizo </PERSON> by the neck but claimed that was merely for `` psychological effect.'' He also said it was not he was who tried to takeover <PERSON> Quirino </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dulay </PERSON> headed the provincial chapter of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Quirino </LOCATION>. He and his followers were accused of murdering two civilians campaigning for Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Quirino </LOCATION> during the 1986 election which both Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> and <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> claimed they won. <PERSON> Dulay </PERSON> was arrested shortly after <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> left, but escaped from a suburban <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> military prison. He resurfaced in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> but was expelled back to <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> on March 18, 1987. Last June, armed men attacked the stockade at <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>'s Camp Crame, where <PERSON> Dulay </PERSON> was held, in what the military said was a bid to free him. The group failed to free <PERSON> Dulay </PERSON> but looted the garrison's armory
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Fog-Pileups     02-01 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Fog-Pileups,0085</SECOND>
<HEAD>Five People Killed, 35 Injured In Road Fog Crashes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NAMUR, Belgium (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Five people were killed and 35 injured in four traffic accidents as thick fog blanketed central and northern <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>, authorities said. In the worst of Tuesday's accidents, four people were killed and 30 injured when 90 cars and trucks slammed into each other on an expressway near <LOCATION> Namur </LOCATION>, about 30 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>. Among the injured were four firefighters burned when one of the cars exploded.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     02-01 0887</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0925</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PALO ALTO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> spent his first day at the <ORGANIZATION> Hoover </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION> learning to `` just say no'' to requests for speeches and interviews. `` The invitations are overwhelming,'' said <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Whiting </PERSON>, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s assistant at the think tank on <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s campus `` They want to give him honorary degrees and awards, they want him to give talks or interviews. There's an incredible array and variety. It's impressive, to say the least.'' She said he `` now is a member of <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s ` Just Say No' club'' in responding to such requests While serving as secretary of state, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> was on leave as a professor at <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Graduate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION>. He and his wife, <PERSON> Helena </PERSON>, maintain a home in <LOCATION> Palo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alto </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> has returned to the institute, where he was an honorary fellow, to work on a series of documentaries on policy making at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and teach public policy.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress Cybill Shepherd and her husband have separated after two years of marriage. Miss Shepherd, who plays the witty detective <PERSON> Maddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON> on TV's `` Moonlighting,'' and <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Oppenheim </PERSON>, a chiropractor, were married March 1, 1987 They have year-old twins, <PERSON> Ariel </PERSON> and <PERSON> Zachariah </PERSON>. The separation was announced Tuesday by Miss Shepherd's publicist, <PERSON> Cheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Kagen </PERSON> No reason for the separation was given. Ms. <PERSON> Kagen </PERSON> said the custody of the children was n't being disclosed. Miss Shepherd, 39, lives in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and has custody of her 9-year-old daughter, <PERSON> Clementine </PERSON>, from a previous marriage. The model-turned-actress appears with <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neal </PERSON> in the movie `` Chances Are,'' due for release March 10.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Clint </PERSON> <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON>, who won a <ORGANIZATION> Golden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> for best director, is n't among the nominees announced for the prestigious Directors Guild of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> achievement award. Their nominations mark the five directors as favorites for Academy Awards in March. Only three times in motion picture history has the <ORGANIZATION> DGA </ORGANIZATION> award winner failed to go on to win the Oscar for best director. The nominees are: <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, for the civil rights saga `` Mississippi Burning''; <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Crichton </PERSON> for the crime-caper comedy `` A Fish Called Wanda''; <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON> for the brotherly love story `` Rain Man''; <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Zemeckis </PERSON> for the semi-animated detective spoof `` Who Framed Roger Rabbit''; and <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>, for the corporate comedy `` Working Girl.'' `` I was hoping <PERSON> Clint </PERSON> <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON> would be nominated this year, but -LRB- his film ` Bird' -RRB- was n't,'' said <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON>, who announced the nominations Tuesday. `` I thought ` Bird' was an outstanding directorial accomplishment.'' The winner will be announced March 11. All 9,000 guild members were eligible to vote on the nominations, and all are eligible to vote for the winner. The guild includes film and television directors and their assistants.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Edd cq.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Andrea </PERSON> <PERSON> McArdle </PERSON> says some fans can not let go of her image as the red-haired moppet who exploded on Broadway at age 12 as the Tony-nominated star of `` Annie.'' The little girl who sang `` Tomorrow'' in the show from 1977 to 1978 is now 25 years old and appearing in `` Singin' In The Rain,'' at the Claridge Casino Hotel. `` I do n't think anybody would be lying if they said they were tired of the vehicle that started their recognition,'' she said. `` I do n't know anybody who's bitter about the thing that made them a hit.'' She said it's nice to know she's old enough that she'll never again be asked to play `` <PERSON> Annie </PERSON>.'' `` I do n't feel any different really,'' she said. `` I'd like to say I'm more mature, but I guess I'm not.'' She is married to record producer <PERSON> Edd </PERSON> <PERSON> Kalehoff </PERSON>, and they have a 5 -LCB- - month-old daughter, <PERSON> Alexis </PERSON> <PERSON> Paige </PERSON> <PERSON> Kalehoff </PERSON>
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Television producer <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Schlatter </PERSON>, creator of `` Laugh-In'' and `` Real People,'' was honored with a sidewalk star on the Hollywood Walk of Fame. <PERSON> Dudley </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Purcell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dinah </PERSON> <PERSON> Shore </PERSON> were among 250 people standing in front of the <ORGANIZATION> Hollywood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roosevelt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotel </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday to witness the unveiling of the walk's 1,885 th star `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> has eluded his keepers for years,'' quipped <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Shore </PERSON>, whose `` Dinah Shore Chevy Show'' was produced by <PERSON> Schlatter </PERSON>. Throughout his career as a producer, director and writer, <PERSON> Schlatter </PERSON> has been responsible for more than 1,000 hours of television. A special selection committee chooses sidewalk star recipients and sponsors pay a $ 3,500 fee.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A scary moment on horseback during the filming of `` Lassie Comes Home'' led to <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>'s big breakthrough in `` National Velvet,'' her mother says. <PERSON> Sara </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, an actress herself, recalled the first day of shooting in memoirs published in March's Good Housekeeping magazine. Nine-year-old <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> was riding a horse down a road when it shied at a light reflector and reared. `` The cameras went on grinding and everyone stared in amazement as that tiny little girl gently reined the frightened animal, calmed him down, and brought him to the exact spot where she was supposed to be; then she dismounted, opened the gate, and went on with the scene as if nothing had happened,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> wrote. `` The rest of us were shaking.'' According to Mrs. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>: `` When the studio saw the rushes and how she controlled and calmed that high-spirited horse, they immediately said, ` Here's the girl we have been searching for.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-AlanLaddJr     02-01 0247</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Alan Ladd Jr,0251</SECOND>
<HEAD>Alan Ladd Jr. to Head New Movie Company</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Movie producer <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ladd </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, who last year quit his job as top moviemaker at <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, has formed a new movie company backed by Italian financier and <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> buff <PERSON> Giancarlo </PERSON> <PERSON> Parretti </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ladd </PERSON>, who made his name guiding `` Star Wars'' through 20th Century <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> when he was president there, will be chairman of the new <ORGANIZATION> Pathe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>. The company will produce 14 to 16 movies during the next four years, he predicted Monday. The company apparently takes its name from <ORGANIZATION> Pathe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> France </ORGANIZATION>, a big French movie company that <PERSON> Parretti </PERSON> and associated companies bought last year. <PERSON> Parretti </PERSON>, who heads a partnership that controls 40 percent of struggling moviemaker <ORGANIZATION> Cannon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, is rumored to be interested in buying <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>. Investor <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerkorian </PERSON>, who controls <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, has the company up for sale, and has said he prefers to split the firm and sell an interest in <ORGANIZATION> MGM </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Ladd </PERSON>, son of the late actor and <PERSON> Marjorie </PERSON> <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Ladd </PERSON>, resigned in September as chairman of the MGM portion of <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION> amid the turmoil brought on by <PERSON> Kerkorian </PERSON>'s attempts to sell parts of the company. During his <ORGANIZATION> MGM </ORGANIZATION> tenure, he was credited with overseeing such movies as `` A Fish Called <PERSON> Wanda </PERSON>,'' `` Willow,'' and `` Moonstruck.'' Previously, his <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ladd </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> made two critically favored but commercially unsuccessful movies, `` The Right Stuff'' and `` Blade Runner,'' as well as such moneymakers as the `` Police Academy'' series.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     02-01 0310</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0320</SECOND>
<HEAD>NBC Scores Another Smashing Victory in TV Ratings</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY BUCK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> extended its domination of the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> ratings to 32 weeks, and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> dropped from first to third in the news category. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s victory for the week that ended Sunday was accomplished almost entirely with regular series programming. The week before <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won big with its coverage of the Super Bowl. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> placed six prime-time shows in the top 10 last week. The network did not have a single show in the bottom 25. Its only non-regular show high in the ratings was the second half of the miniseries `` Brotherhood of the Rose.'' The first part, which followed the Super Bowl, was ninth the previous week. `` The Cosby Show'' on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> was first, followed by <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne''; <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` A Different World''; CBS' `` 60 Minutes''; <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Who's the Boss''; <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Cheers''; <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` Murder, She Wrote''; and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Golden Girls''; `` ALF''; and `` Unsolved Mysteries.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s average prime-time rating for last week was 17.1; CBS' was 13.1 and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s was 12.0. For the season to date, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> leads with an average of 15.7 to <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s 12.9 and CBS's 12.4. Each ratings point represents 904,000 homes with television. The ratings for the networks' nightly news shows were close again, but <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> moved ahead of <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, last week's winner, which fell to third place. The ratings: CBS 11.7, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 11.6, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 11.5. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Studio 5B'' on Sunday was the lowest-rated show among the three networks. The five lowest network shows were <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Incredible Sunday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` A Fine Romance,'' CBS' `` TV 101'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Studio 5B. <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted'' was in 62 place, placing higher than 10 shows from the networks. <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>'s `` 21 Jump Street'' was 71st, which put it just ahead of <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` A Fine Romance.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0128EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     02-01 0685</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0765</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's Top-Rated TV Shows</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week Jan. 23-29. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 27.0 rating, 24.4 million homes. 2. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.8, 22.4 million homes. 3. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.5, 22.2 million homes. 4. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 23.4, 22.1 million homes. 5. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.9, 20.7 million homes. 6. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.1, 20.0 million homes. 7. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 21.8, 19.7 million homes. 8. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.7, 19.6 million homes. 9. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.4, 18.4 million homes. 10. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.8, 17.9 million homes. 11. -LRB- 20 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.6, 17.7 million homes. 12. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` Brotherhood of the Rose, Part 2'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 19.2, 17.4 million homes. 13. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.9, 17.1 million homes. 14. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.7, 16.9 million homes. 15. -LRB- 25 -RRB- `` Hallmark Hall of Fame: Home Fires Burning'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 18.6, 16.8 million homes. 15. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.6, 16.8 million homes. 17. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.0, 16.3 million homes. 18. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.9, 16.2 million homes. 19. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.8, 16.1 million homes. 20. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` She Knows Too Much'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 17.4, 15.7 million homes. 21. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.3. 22. -LRB- 25 -RRB- `` Knots Landing,'' CBS, 16.5. 23. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 16.4. 23. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 16.4. 25. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS, 16.2. 26. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.1. 27. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4. 27. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` In the Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4. 29. -LRB- 12 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3. 30. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` Nightingales,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1. 31. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.0. 32. -LRB- 44 -RRB- `` Ghostbusters'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.7. 33. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.6. 34. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` The Father Dowling Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.3. 34. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Eat! Eat! Eat! _ Candid Camera,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 14.3. 36. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.0. 36. -LRB- 32 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.0. 38. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.6. 39. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.3. 39. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Studio 5B Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.3. 41. -LRB- 42 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2. 42. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` Day By Day,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.1. 43. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' CBS, 13.0. 44. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` The Day After'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movie,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8. 45. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` Man Against the Mob'' _ `` Friday Movie of the Week,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.6. 45. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 12.6. 47. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.2. 48. -LRB- 50 -RRB- `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 12.0. 49. -LRB- 54 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Red </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, White Earth'' _ `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' CBS, 11.9. 50. -LRB- 68 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: Critical Condition,'' CBS, 11.4. 51. -LRB- 39 -RRB- `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 52. -LRB- 62 -RRB- `` The Equalizer,'' CBS, 11.0. 52. -LRB- 52 -RRB- `` A Man Called Hawk,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.0. 54. -LRB- 65 -RRB- `` Magical World of Disney,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.6. 55. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` Paradise,'' CBS, 10.6. 56. -LRB- 47 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.5. 57. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 10.4. 57. -LRB- 60 -RRB- `` Dynasty,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.4. 59. -LRB- X -RRB- `` People Magazine on TV,'' CBS, 10.2. 59. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 10.2. 59. -LRB- 47 -RRB- `` Hooperman,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.2. 62. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 10.1. 63. -LRB- 58 -RRB- `` Almost Grown,'' CBS, 9.7. 64. -LRB- 69 -RRB- `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.2. 65. -LRB- 79 -RRB- `` West 57th,'' CBS, 8.7. 66. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` Dolphin Cove,'' CBS, 8.6. 67. -LRB- 81 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Smothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Variety </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 7.3. 68. -LRB- 72 -RRB- `` Incredible Sunday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.2. 68. -LRB- 82 -RRB- `` HeartBeat,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.2. 70. -LRB- 83 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.7. 71. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.6. 71. -LRB- 71 -RRB- `` A Fine Romance,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.6. 73. -LRB- 87 -RRB- `` TV 101,'' CBS, 6.5. 74. -LRB- 74 -RRB- `` Studio 5B,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.8. 75. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` It's <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON>'s Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.0. 76. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Television Hall of Fame,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.4. 77. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.0. 77. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` The Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.0. 79. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Duet,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.2. 80. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.7.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0101EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-GrandMarshal 1stLd-Writethru a0829 02-01 0193</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Grand Marshal, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0829,0191</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman To Lead St. Patrick's Day Parade</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Recasts 3rd graf to CORRECT by deleting reference to WEVD, which
no long carries program, now on WNWK-FM.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Broadcaster <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> <PERSON> Cudahy </PERSON> was selected Tuesday night as grand marshal of the St. Patrick's Day parade, the first woman chosen to lead the annual march in its 226-year history. Mrs. <PERSON> Cudahy </PERSON> was picked by about 600 delegates from the approximately 200 affiliated organizations that march in the parade, including the Ancient Order of Hibernians, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Counties </ORGANIZATION> and schools and fraternal organizations. `` It will be in honor of your mother and my mother and all the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> women who did so much,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Cudahy </PERSON>, who is known as the First Lady of Irish radio for her `` Irish Memories'' program, which has been broadcast on <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> area radio stations for more than 40 years. `` This achievement was really your achievement,'' she told the delegates who crowded into a hotel ballroom in <LOCATION> mid-Manhattan </LOCATION>. A <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ireland </ORGANIZATION> executive was elected grand marshal last year, the third straight year Mrs. <PERSON> Cudahy </PERSON> had lost.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0105EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-TribalTrekkers Bjt   02-01 0603</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tribal Trekkers, Bjt,0618</SECOND>
<HEAD>Foreign Trekkers Destroying Tribal Way of Life</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Material in 3rd graf may be offensive to some readers</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENIS D. GRAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHIANG MAI, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Armed with cash and cameras, foreign trekkers by the thousands are scouring the hills of northern <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> for unspoiled tribal people, turning the region into `` a human zoo,'' critics say. Thai officials, <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> missionaries and others interviewed say these increasingly popular treks by Western Europeans, Americans and Australians are hastening the erosion of traditional culture among 500,000 tribal people already reeling under rapid modernization. Villagers are selling their colorful costumes, jewelry and other heirlooms or exchanging them for jeans and other Western goods offered by trekkers. And intruding brusquely into village life are some Westerners who, as former tour operator <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> recalls, `` run around with their breasts hanging out.'' `` Nothing is free now. Their traditional hospitality has been corrupted,'' says American missionary <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Morse </PERSON>. `` Before they would offer food and lodging to strangers. Now they no longer accept people for who they are. They have become hardened, less open.'' According to the government's tourist authority, tribal trekking has grown from a handful of hikers in the 1970s to more than 100,000 last year. Most sign up with tour companies in this major northern Thai city, then make their way by jeep, bamboo raft, elephant, motorcyle or foot to the hill villages of the Akha, <PERSON> Karen </PERSON>, Hmong, <LOCATION> Lisu </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Lahu </PERSON> and other tribes. The trekking companies capitalize on the region's natural beauty and the lure of the exotic and notorious _ the area is part of the so-called Golden Triangle of opium fields and warlord armies. `` Padaung hill tribes now available,'' reads one typical advertisement, which has prompted critics to charge that the tribal people are being marketed like animals on a safari or in a zoo. Young, a longtime <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> resident of northern <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, says trekking agencies vary greatly. Some, he says, educate clients about local cultures while others may offer an `` opium experience'' and provide opportunities for `` authentic'' photographs by getting tribesmen to smoke their opium pipes or engage in courtship rituals. Some trekkers have died of drug overdoses. Violence and robbery against tourists _ once unheard of _ are on the rise as cultures clash and cash is haphazardly injected into primitive economies. <PERSON> Suppakit </PERSON> <PERSON> Apasil </PERSON>, director of the government's tourism office in <PERSON> Chiang </PERSON> <PERSON> Mai </PERSON>, says part of the trouble stems from lack of controls over the mushrooming agencies and the trekking industry, which brings $ 5 million annually to the city. <PERSON> Chiang </PERSON> <PERSON> Mai </PERSON> has 110 agencies, some no more than a table in a restaurant catering to backpackers, offering tours that range from $ 6 to $ 100 and guides whose knowledge of tribal languages and lore varies as widely. The government has no regulatory powers but provides would-be trekkers with a list of warnings and recommendations and helped organize a <ORGANIZATION> Jungle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tour </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, an association of about 50 trekking outfits that attempts to raise standards. <PERSON> Wanat </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruksasri </PERSON>, who heads the <ORGANIZATION> Hill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, lists tourism among factors changing hill tribe life. Other factors are greater road access, population growth, an influx of lowlanders and the impact of foreign and Thai development agencies. `` See real primitive hill tribes in the Thai jungle, if you're looking for an intensive and unforgettable experience,'' announces one trekking company But some who sign up are in for a disappointment. After a long walk through deforested hills, trekkers may well come upon a village where the natives watch television, drive Japanese pick-up trucks and wear jeans purchased from previous trekkers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Brady-LBOs     02-01 0622</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Brady-LBOs,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Reluctantly Supports Cutting Deduction on Debt</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX9</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is giving qualified support to cutting the tax deduction for interest on debt incurred in leveraged buyouts, saying it prefers fairer tax treatment of traditional forms of raising capital. `` If you're going to make a change _ and clearly we're not suggesting one _ we would suggest that you look in the area of perhaps limiting interest deductions and using that money to give a break to corporate owners of stock,'' Treasury Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> told the tax-writing <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> said the `` driving force'' behind the LBO phenomenon is that companies can avoid a 34 percent corporate income tax rate by raising capital through debt rather than stock. He said the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> also has been attempting to find a way through <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> regulations or a legislative proposal to make the tax treatment of stock-equity and bond-debt financing more equal. `` The LBO problem would disappear with a level playing field,'' he said. `` But so far we have n't been able to come up with a way to do it.'' <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> also suggested that the best action might be inaction. `` We have a habit of correcting things just as they are about to correct themselves,'' <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> said. `` If we wait a little longer, this thing is not going to gobble us up.'' But <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> conceded the administration is concerned about the rapid rate with which companies are going into debt to launch takeovers or defend against them through stock buybacks _ both often financed by high-interest junk bonds. Rep. <PERSON> J.J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pickle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, likened <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>'s qualified endorsement of taxing interest on takeover-related debt to `` a kiss through a veil'' and criticized him for not coming up with specific suggestions or data on the impact of the buyouts on the federal treasury. With a `` that depends'' answer, <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> evaded a question on whether President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s desire to reduce the capital gains tax would only encourage more buyouts since shareholders would have to pay less tax on the 35 percent to 45 percent above-market prices they often get in the transactions. Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, D-Ill., said it is ironic the outcry for congressional action to curb takeovers `` has become deafening'' in the past 16 months In 1987 the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> had approved similar legislation to limit the tax deductibility of interest on junk bonds and other borrowing used in financing takeovers. But it suffered a quick death in negotiations with the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> after then-Treasury Secretary and now Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> tried to blame the bill as the cause of the October 1987 stock market crash. Since then, the size of companies being taken over through junk bonds has increased several times. And instead of just plants closing and workers losing jobs, owners of more traditional long-term, investment-grade bonds in the companies being acquired have seen the value of their holdings diminished in some takeovers. For example, holders of some $ 5 billion in long-term bonds in <ORGANIZATION> RJR-Nabisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, lost $ 1 billion overnight when credit agencies downgraded their rating upon the announcement of the company's takeover by <ORGANIZATION> LBO </ORGANIZATION> specialist <ORGANIZATION> Kohlberg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kravis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roberts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Co.. <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON> and other lawmakers also have questioned whether many of the newly restructured companies will be able to make the interest payments on their much higher debt and avoid bankruptcy if and when a recession `` I have a feeling that we're looking at a <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale that's showing zero and then we have an eruption of 7 or 8 on the scale and it's too late,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Downey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, using a major earthquake as a metaphor
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PretrialPublicity Bjt   02-01 0607</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pretrial Publicity, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Watergate Jury Selection a Model for North's Trial</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Watergate cases of the mid-1970s could provide a road map for selection of a jury in <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s trial that will not be biased by pretrial publicity, legal experts say. `` I would say Watergate is your best guide. From what I can understand the Iran-Contra hearings wo n't exceed publicity of that,'' says Professor <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenhalgh </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. There are important parallels between the prosecution of the leading Watergate defendants and <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s case, <PERSON> Greenhalgh </PERSON> said Tuesday. Most notably, he said, the trials in both instances were preceded by congressional hearings that attracted vast television audiences. A federal appeals court upheld the Watergate convictions, saying the defendants' rights were protected by the careful questioning of prospective jurors to guard against prejudice from pretrial publicity. `` That's what -LRB- <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> is doing now,'' <PERSON> Greenhalgh </PERSON> said. `` He has a road map. And if he's following it I think he'll be all right.'' Professor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> agreed. `` We have an imperfect system that stumbles through,'' he said. `` It's not an impossibility to get a jury'' in the North trial that will be unbiased. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> also said it is easier to guard against prejudiced jurors in federal cases because the judges generally do the questioning in empaneling jurors. In the state courts, he said, the quizzing is done by the lawyers on each side. As <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s trial began Tuesday, <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said there may be problems finding an impartial jury as required by the Constitution because so many people have seen or read of North's testimony in congressional hearings. Only 16 of the first 54 prospective jurors indicated on questionnaires that they were n't exposed to <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s congressional appearances, the judge said. North, a former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide, testified to <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> investigating committees in 1987 under a grant of limited immunity. The immunity grant meant the congressional testimony itself could not be used to prosecute <PERSON> North </PERSON>, although independent counsel <PERSON> Laurence </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> was free to develop the same information independently. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> noted that <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s trial on charges of lying to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, shredding evidence and conspiring to commit tax fraud comes after intense publicity, and the judge said the spotlight will remain on throughout the trial. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said he will rule Wednesday on how much exposure to such publicity ought to be allowed before a possible juror is disqualified. North himself has contributed to the attention his trial is receiving. In recent months, he has been giving speeches for $ 20,000 fees. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has made it clear that pretrial publicity is not necessarily fatal to a fair trial. The justices' most recent ruling on the issue was in 1984 when, by a 6-2 vote, they reinstated the murder conviction of a <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> high school teacher for raping and strangling a student. The court stressed in that case that the conviction came years after the offense occurred, allowing ample time for the community's sense of outrage to cool Justice <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, writing for the court, said the trial judge has broad discretion to decide whether prospective jurors are biased. `` Under our system it is that judge who is best situated to determine competency to serve impartially,'' <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said. The high court in 1961 provided some guidelines for permissible pretrial publicity. Justice <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, writing for the court then, said it is not necessary for jurors to `` be totally ignorant of the facts and issues involved.'' He said requiring them to know nothing would amount to an `` impossible'' standard.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NorthCharges     02-01 0141</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North Charges,140</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-North Trial Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a list of the 12 felony charges against former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>. All carry five-year prison terms and fines up to $ 250,000 except as noted. Obstruction of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in Sept. and Oct. 1985. False statements to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Sept. 5, 1985. False statements to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Sept. 12, 1985. False statements to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Oct. 7, 1985 Obstruction of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in Aug. 1986. Obstruction of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in Nov. 1986. Obstruction of a presidential inquiry in Nov. 1986. False statements on Nov. 23, 1986. Destroying or falsifying government documents, three-year imprisonment and $ 250,000 fine. Receipt of an illegal gratuity, two-year imprisonment and $ 250,000 fine. Conversion of traveler's checks to personal use, 10-year imprisonment, $ 250,000 fine. Conspiracy to defraud the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890201-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-01-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Philippines-Drunks     02-01 0130</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Philippines-Drunks,0133</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mayor Nips Noon Time Nipping In The Bud</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
