<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 2336EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Poland-Israel     08-22 0289</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Poland-Israel,0299</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israeli Minister Meets Cardinal On Convent Dispute</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s religious affairs minister, <PERSON> Zevulun </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammer </PERSON>, met with Cardinal <PERSON> Franciszek </PERSON> <PERSON> Macharski </PERSON> on Tuesday in an effort to resolve the dispute over a Roman Catholic convent at the former death camp at <LOCATION> Auschwitz </LOCATION>. Hammer was the first high-ranking <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> official to visit <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> since diplomatic relations were severed more than 20 years ago. Any conclusions reached by Hammer and the <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION> cardinal during their 1 -LCB- - hour meeting of <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION> were not released. Members of Hammer's family died at <LOCATION> Auschwitz </LOCATION> and he visited the site before meeting the cardinal, said a spokesman for the Israeli interest section in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Macharski </PERSON> announced this month that the convent would not be moved from the camp's perimeter as promised in an international accord signed by <PERSON> Jewish </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> leaders in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> leaders initially agreed to transfer the Carmelite nuns by Feb. 22 to an interfaith prayer center to be built farther from the camp. But <PERSON> Macharski </PERSON> said the agreement would not be honored in an `` atmosphere of aggressive demands.'' Protests by Jewish groups increased after the deadline passed. In one highly publicized incident on July 14, an American rabbi and six students demonstrating at the convent were roughly evicted by workmen at the site. Jewish groups and others have viewed the convent as an offensive intrusion of Christian symbols at the camp, where an estimated 2.5 million Jews died. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, with the rest of the Soviet bloc except <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, cut diplomatic ties with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in 1967 after the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> war. But contact has been steadily increasing. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> now has an independent interest section in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>. Hammer will also meet Polish political leaders during his five-day visit that began Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 2349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Newspage-Ryan's5000 1stLd-Writethru a0734 08-22 0312</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Newspage-Ryan's 5000, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0734,0314</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nolan Ryan Strikes Out His 5000th Batter</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf to UPDATE with Oakland beating Texas; INSERTS
1 graf after 4th graf, `Ryan tipped ...,' to UPDATE with Ryan totals for
game; picks up 5th graf, `He finished ...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ARLINGTON, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rangers </ORGANIZATION> pitcher <PERSON> Nolan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> struck out his 5,000 th batter Tuesday night, becoming the first to reach that milestone when he fanned <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Rickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Henderson </PERSON> in the fifth inning But the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletics </ORGANIZATION> took away some of the thrill by beating the <ORGANIZATION> Rangers </ORGANIZATION> 2-0. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> went into the game needing six strikeouts. He struck out the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletics </ORGANIZATION>' <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Canseco </PERSON> in the first inning, <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Henderson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> in the second, <PERSON> Rickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Henderson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Hassey </PERSON> in the third. He finally got <PERSON> Rickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Henderson </PERSON> swinging on a 3-2 fastball leading off the fifth. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> tipped his hat to a thundering standing ovation while rookie catcher <PERSON> Chad </PERSON> <PERSON> Kreuter </PERSON> ran the historic ball out to the mound. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>'s teammates on the field surged to congratulate him and the scoreboard flashed `` 5,000'' as hundreds of flash bulbs popped in the stands He finished the game with 13 strikeouts, walking two and allowing only five hits. That gave <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> 5,007 strikeouts. A sellout crowd of 43,000, including Commissioner <PERSON> Bart </PERSON> <PERSON> Giamatti </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Rangers </ORGANIZATION> owner <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, son of the president, gave <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> three standing ovations before the game even started. The fans cheered loudly every time he got two strikes on a batter, and <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> rarely disappointed them. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> struck out the first batter of his career, <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> pitcher <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarvis </PERSON>, as a 19-year-old with the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> on Sept. 11, 1966. He reached 1,000 on July 3, 1973, with <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, got to 2,000 on Aug. 31, 1976, hit 3,000 on July 4, 1980, with <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> and got to 4,000 on July 11, 1985.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0007EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BRF--Koch-Ghost     08-22 0139</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Koch-Ghost,0144</SECOND>
<HEAD>N.Y. Mayor Calls on Ghost For Endorsement</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Chalk it up to campaign stress: ghosts are talking to Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, and he's talking back. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Moses </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s planning czar who died in 1981, recently stopped by to chat with <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, the mayor said Monday. <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, in the middle of a tough primary contest for his fourth term, said <PERSON> Moses </PERSON> relayed two requests. `` First, he wants me to be mayor,'' <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said. The second request was that <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> bring the World's Fair to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> sometime in the mid-1990s, he said. <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> was speaking to a black tie crowd attending a 50th anniversary celebration of the 1939 <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION>'s Fair. <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> reported that he told <PERSON> Moses </PERSON>, `` If I did n't see him in person between now and then, I'll do it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0013EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     08-22 0576</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0595</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Uncle Buck' Tops Box Office; `Nightmare' Fades</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Candy </PERSON> vehicle `` Uncle Buck'' took first place in the weekend box office revue, beating the highly touted `` Parenthood,'' `` The Abyss'' and `` Casualties of War.'' Director <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>' comedy grossed $ 8.8 million, according to figures released Monday by <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. The movie stars Candy as a peculiar relative struggling to babysit his nephew and two nieces. Meanwhile, attendance at `` A Nightmare on Elm Street 5: The Dream Child'' dropped by nearly 50 percent and the film finished eighth in its second week of release, indicating <PERSON> Freddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Krueger </PERSON>'s final demise may arrive sooner rather than later. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>'s `` Parenthood'' finished second after two weeks in first place. A bittersweet commentary on the American family, `` Parenthood'' stars <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Robards </PERSON> and had ticket sales of $ 7.6 million. The underwater spectacular `` The Abyss'' continued to generate steady business in third with a box-office take of $ 7.2 million. The movie features <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Mastrantonio </PERSON> trapped on the ocean floor in a special-effects laden epic. `` Casualties of War,'' the new <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> movie starring <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Penn </PERSON>, opened with an unimpressive $ 5.2 million in wide release to claim fourth place. Directed by <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON>, `` Casualties of War'' tells the story of the rape and murder of a Vietnamese girl by a group of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers. `` When <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Met </PERSON> <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> ...,'' the romantic comedy pitting <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Crystal </PERSON> and <PERSON> Meg </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> as best friends who become lovers, finished in fifth by collecting $ 4.9 million. It was followed in sixth by `` Lethal Weapon 2,'' the action-adventure sequel with <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Glover </PERSON>, which grossed $ 4.5 million. In seventh was the police comedy `` Turner and <PERSON> Hooch </PERSON>,'' featuring <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanks </PERSON>, on receipts of $ 4.3 million. In eighth was `` A Nightmare on Elm Street 5: The Dream Child.'' The film's take, $ 8.1 million in its opening week, fell to $ 4.1 million. Rounding out the Top 10 were `` Batman'' in ninth with $ 3.4 million and the new family film `` Cheetah'' in 10th with $ 2.6 million. `` Let it Ride'' opened weakly in 12th place with sales of $ 1.9 million. Both `` Young <PERSON> Einstein </PERSON>'' with Australian import <ORGANIZATION> Yahoo </ORGANIZATION> Serious and `` Lock Up'' with <PERSON> Sylvester </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> dropped out of the Top 10. Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by Exhibitor Relations, with distributor, weekend gross, number of theater screens, average per screen, total gross and number of weeks in release. 1. `` Uncle Buck,'' Universal, $ 8.8 million, 1,804 screens, $ 4,875 per screen, $ 11.9 million, one week. 2. `` Parenthood,'' Universal, $ 7.6 million, 1,316 screens, $ 5,780 per screen, $ 43.3 million, three weeks. 3. `` The Abyss,'' 20th Century <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, $ 7.2 million, 1,538 screens, $ 4,690 per screen, $ 24.7 million, two weeks. 4. `` Casualties of War,'' <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, $ 5.2 million, 1,487 screens, $ 3,498 per screen, $ 5.2 million, one week. 5. `` When <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Met </PERSON> <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> ...,'' <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, $ 4.9 million, 1,144 screens, $ 4,281 per screen, $ 54 million, six weeks. 6. `` Lethal Weapon 2,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 4.5 million, 1,584 screens, $ 2,851 per screen, $ 119.6 million, seven weeks. 7. `` Turner and <PERSON> Hooch </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 4.3 million, 1,594 screens, $ 2,682 per screen, $ 46.6 million, four weeks. 8. `` A Nightmare on Elm Street 5: The Dream Child,'' New Line, $ 4.1 million, 1,846 screens, $ 2,213 per screen, $ 15.2 million, two weeks. 9. `` Batman,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 3.4 million, 1,400 screens, $ 2,457 per screen, $ 229 million, nine weeks. 10. `` Cheetah,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.6 million, 1,310 screens, $ 2,012 per screen, $ 2.6 million, one week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-JapaneseWomen     08-22 1172</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japanese Women,1202</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stifled at Home, Japanese Women Seek Room of Their Own Overseas</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL HIRSH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A quarter-century ago, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedan </PERSON> called the oppression of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women `` the problem that has no name.'' But <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> today has a name for <PERSON> Meiri </PERSON> <PERSON> Marimo </PERSON>'s problem: She's `` leftover Christmas cake.'' Miss <PERSON> Marimo </PERSON>, in other words, has grown a bit stale as a marriageable commodity _ at least that's what her mother complains. In <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, where many marriages are still arranged, a woman is considered to have a shelf life of about 25 years. When <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Marimo </PERSON> was 28, she left for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> _ alone. <PERSON> Sumiko </PERSON> <PERSON> Morikawa </PERSON> sits next to the `` No Smoking'' sign in her <LOCATION> Waldorf-Astoria </LOCATION> office and lights a cigarette. At 39, she says she's looking for a new man She is n't particular about his background _ as long as he is n't Japanese. `` Japanese men and women, they can not understand how to love,'' says <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Morikawa </PERSON>, the owner of a translating service. Three years ago, she ended a 16-year marriage undertaken to please her tradition-minded brother in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. No passion, she says. `` Japanese businessmen are very nice, but they are so totally quality-controlled. They see themselves as company men. And their wives also, they say, ` I'm a <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> wife.' It kills the individuality of people.'' It is 11:30 a.m. <PERSON> Renko </PERSON> <PERSON> Isowa </PERSON>, 42, pauses over a dish of vanilla ice cream as she cheerily recalls the strict training of her youth in the traditional female skills. `` I learned flower arrangement, tea ceremony and cooking for two years. I was totally dead,'' says <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Isowa </PERSON>, vice president of a television production company here. `` I wanted to start working. I wanted to be a member of real society.'' Twenty-six years after `` The Feminine Mystique,'' <PERSON> Friedan </PERSON>'s manifesto of women's rights, helped kindle feminism in the West, only a trickle of women in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> are able or willing to live out its creed But many of those few come to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to try. The three expatriates above may seem refreshingly liberated, but in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> many would consider them wild-eyed radicals. They insist on standing out in a society where wa, or group harmony, dictates `` the nail that stands out is hammered down.'' `` Japanese women have n't been raised to have aspirations,'' says <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Condon </PERSON>, author of `` A Half-Step Behind: Japanese Women of the'80s.'' `` They're still facing boundaries we broke through 20 years ago.'' `` To be good American, you have to be an individual. To be a good Japanese, you'd better damn sight not be,'' says <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Fochios </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> psychiatrist who counsels many <LOCATION> Japanese </LOCATION> women. `` The women who ... come to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>, then get into the machinery of the country, are able to enjoy the kinds of freedoms they had never dreamed of,'' he says. `` And these women are tough. They are tough.'' Miss <PERSON> Marimo </PERSON>'s family frets, to no avail. To her friends, she is an `` incredible oyahuko,'' a bad daughter. A few years ago, she moved into her own apartment in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, watching defiantly as the social pressures that mold a Japanese woman's life _ a cycle of temporary employment, marriage and child-raising _ claimed her schoolmates one by one. Her old friends `` spoke to me as if they were accusing me, criticizing me very severely,'' recalls the lithe, long-haired Miss Marimo, a free-lance writer. `` I did n't care at all. I do n't want to be involved in housekeeping. I smiled a Japanese smile'' _ and left. In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, disaffected minorities organize, as <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women did in the 1970s. In <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, it has always been easier to jump ship than to rock the boat. Until recently. Today, the glacial rigidity of Japanese society _ `` otoko no shakai,'' the man's world _ shows signs of thawing after more than a century of uneasy integration with the West. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s giant corporations, facing chronic worker shortages as the economy surges, are beginning to open management jobs to women. Traditionally they are hired as tea-pouring `` office ladies'' while pursuing their real vocation: marriage. Japanese women are even making an impact on politics. A record 22 women won seats in the July 23 elections for Parliament's upper house. Female voters had been angered by allegations that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s just-departed prime minister, <PERSON> Sousuke </PERSON> <PERSON> Uno </PERSON>, kept paid mistresses The election also showed, however, that much has not changed. Many of the victorious female parliamentary candidates had portrayed themselves not as feminists but as simple housewives immune from corruption. Indeed, apart from the odd individualist who ventures abroad to live, few <LOCATION> Japanese </LOCATION> women want change. `` If you go to a party here and introduce yourself as a housewife, people will think you're strange. But in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> it's OK. Being a housewife does n't bother <LOCATION> Japanese </LOCATION> women, because they have a social position,'' says <PERSON> Kako </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakagawa </PERSON>, the executive editor of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yomiuri </ORGANIZATION>, a newspaper published for Japanese in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. `` I think in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> you have no secure place for women,'' she says. `` Here there are opportunities for women, so if you do n't try anthing hard, then you feel guilty. ... But in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> there are no opportunities so there's no such struggle. It's easy.'' `` When I go to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Japanese </LOCATION> women I see are very content-looking, very happy,'' says <PERSON> Naoko </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, a researcher for <ORGANIZATION> Sunstar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a Japanese company with offices in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. When I come back to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, I notice the women look very unhappy, frustrated.'' While women in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> are largely blocked from positions of power, they provide a vital temporary worker base that absorbs economic downturns, allowing large Japanese companies to maintain their much-vaunted `` lifetime employment system'' for permanent workers. In addition, they are the linchpin of an economic system that allows men to spend long hours working and, as is expected, socializing afterward. With the men otherwise occupied, women often control family purse strings, and so completely control their children's destinies that surveys have shown the central relationship in a Japanese man's life is not between him and his wife but between him and his mother. So strong is such patterning of Japanese women, in fact, that leaving it behind sometimes causes deep emotional problems for expatriates, who must spurn what they have been taught since childhood and embrace alien values. `` Some of them say they feel guilty about being free as an American,'' says <PERSON> Fochios </PERSON>, the psychiatrist. `` They feel inferior to a Japanese woman because they do n't have the capacity to be a good Japanese wife.'' Some expatriate women, however, simply decide to ignore <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> values. `` Japanese women are better off. I do n't think I would like to marry an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> man,'' says <PERSON> Kiyomi </PERSON> <PERSON> Koizumi </PERSON>, a 65-year-old neurophysiologist who came to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1949 and married a Japanese. `` I always say my husband is like air _ you would miss it if it's not there, I ca n't live without it, but you do n't feel it An <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> man might be around me too much.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Chile-Military     08-22 0698</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chile-Military,0718</SECOND>
<HEAD>Civilian Politicians Seek To Get Along with Chile's Military</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EDUARDO GALLARDO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTIAGO, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The political opposition is pursuing an unprecedented dialogue with the armed forces, seeking a formula for peaceful co-existence when <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> returns to civilian government in March. The military, which has ruled since 1973, has indicated a willingness to negotiate, but only under certain conditions. Both sides agree that the lack of communication in the past had led to a mutual animosity and distrust that both sides agree must be eliminated if the future government is to enjoy stability. <PERSON> Patricio </PERSON> <PERSON> Aylwin </PERSON>, the presidential candidate of a united center-left opposition and heavily favored to win the presidential election Dec. 14, recently remarked: `` We want an approach, an exchange of views.'' `` The isolation that has existed for years among civilians and military is not good for the country and must end,'' <PERSON> Aylwin </PERSON> added. `` The time has come for a dialogue.'' Gen. <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, the right-wing army commander who has been president since seizing power in September, 1973, was obliged to call December's general elections after losing a referendum in October on extending his rule to 1997. <PERSON> Aylwin </PERSON> and other opposition leaders want the dialogue to take place before the new government takes office March 11. Experts expect several highly conflictive items will be on the agenda. <PERSON> Ignacio </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, a leading adviser to <PERSON> Aylwin </PERSON> on military matters, said the talks would include the role of the armed forces under the civilian government, the continuation of the present commanders-in-chief in their posts, the defense budget and, probably the most sensitive problem, how the new government will deal with the human rights violations during <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>'s rule. After the 1973 coup, which toppled the elected government of <PERSON> Marxist </PERSON> <PERSON> Salvadoe </PERSON> <PERSON> Allende </PERSON>, the military launched a campaign of political repression. Thousands of leftists were arrested, many were tortured, killed or sent into exile. Human rights groups have documented more than 700 cases of dissidents who disappeared after being arrested by seurity agents. The opposition has said that it will investigate all pending cases of rights abuse and try those responsible. Its leaders have also said they will seek to repeal an amnesty law, issued by <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, that pardoned violations occurred from 1973 to 1978. That announcement by the opposition prompted a stern warning from the military ranks. Gen. <PERSON> Fernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Matthei </PERSON>, the air force commander who is considered politically moderate and has expressed support for a dialogue, said repealing the amnesty law could unleash `` an unpredictible reaction'' by the armed forces. `` Those wanting to repeal the law do not realize how serious that could be,'' <PERSON> Matthei </PERSON> added. He noted that <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> himself has warned that an attempt to try military officials could lead to an interruption of the democratic transition. Opposition leaders have insisted they seek `` truth and justice,'' not vengeance against the military. They are under heavy political pressure from human rights groups representing victims of repression or their relatives. Another highly controversial subject is the constitutional clause that allows the military chiefs, including <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, to retain their military commands under the civilian government. <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> has said he will remain the army's leader for as long as the constitution allows _ until 1998. Even some pro-government politicians contend the new leadership must be empowered to make changes in the military command. But the armed forces have vowed to make no concessions on the point. A statement issued by the army warned the armed forces are prepared to `` use legitimate force'' to uphold constitution, which was drafted by the military and approved in a referendum. And military commanders insist that their mission includes ensuring internal stability as well as defending the country against foreign attack. That is considered another potential area of controversy, but opposition leaders say they are prepared to talk about it, too, in spite of the risks and difficulties. `` The peaceful end of military dictatorships has never been easy, and <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> can not be an exception,'' wrote <PERSON> Rene </PERSON> <PERSON> Abeliuk </PERSON>, a Social Democratic leader, in a newspaper column. The <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> also has urged civilians and military to talk about their differences `` to help the transition to democracy.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Beirut-Past     08-22 1014</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Beirut-Past,1051</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Ravaged City Once Was a Playground</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 An old guidebook says: `` One thing a foreigner in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> need never worry about is making friends.'' That was long ago, before a civil war devastated the city and nation, before the hostage-taking. Here is a report on what it was like, by an AP correspondent who lived in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> in those days.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By NICK LUDINGTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 I remember when <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> was the playground of the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, a vibrant crossroad between the Orient and the West. The bright <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> sun glinted from its high-rise buildings and its vaults were full of oil money. <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> was a stimulating intellectual center then, and a vital contact point for businessmen. Now, it is a shambles strewn with garbage, a city brought low by 14 years of vicious civil war. Those of us who lived there remember <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> before the war as a place where 100,000 foreigners mingled with <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> princes, high-rollers, emigres, adventurers and 17 Christian and Moslem sects. A veneer of Western culture was superimposed on the fragile sectarian structure created by the French when they granted <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> independence in 1943. A dormant volcano of hatreds seethed beneath the exuberance and sophistication. Luxury hotels, apartments and office blocks gleamed between the blue <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> and pine-covered mountains. Non-Lebanese Arabs, constrained at home by puritanical Moslem rules or dictators, could kick up their heels with liquor, women or $ 300 roulette chips and voice their political opinions freely in the Arab world's only working democracy. Westerners came to tap the oil money that poured into <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, buying into several dozen <LOCATION> Lebanese </LOCATION> banks or opening their own offices. <ORGANIZATION> Citibank </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> decorated a full floor of its office annex at the Holiday Inn with imported carpets and furniture. A few months later, we watched from the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> office nearby as it was looted and destroyed by rival militias battling for strategic high-rise buildings along what became the line dividing Christian and Moslem sectors of the city. Westerners found <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> intriguing for its combination of modern amenities with the oriental flavor of the old gold market, its cosmopolitan society, the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> food at such restaurants such as <PERSON> Ajami </PERSON>'s. I still have a dusty, English-language guidebook, the last published before the war. `` Everywhere you will feel the warm eastern hospitality,'' it says. `` One thing a foreigner in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> need never worry about is making friends.'' Fourteen years later, scores of foreigners have been kidnapped, most of them by virulently anti-Western Moslem groups. Sixteen still are held, including <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, an AP colleague. More than 150,000 Lebanese, most of them civilians, have been killed in the war and 1 million have been displaced. Burned-out hulks of the <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Georges </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Phoenicia </LOCATION> and Holiday Inn hotels cluster in what once was <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s tourist center and now is a wasteland inhabited only by snipers. I recall sitting in the <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Georges </LOCATION> restaurant in the good old days, watching water skiers skim behind needle-nosed Italian speedboats. There also was the less-costly, though fastidious, <ORGANIZATION> Myrtoum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> restaurant and pension run by <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Matschek </PERSON>, an Austrian expatriate. Regulars said it was the only place in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s sunny climate to risk eating steak tartare. An attraction at night was the great Casino <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Liban </PERSON>, north of the city in what is now <LOCATION> Christian </LOCATION> territory, where one could gamble or watch two imported floor shows. Those with the right connections might attend functions dominated by the doyenne of high society, <PERSON> Isabelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Soursock </PERSON>. She was from an old-money Lebanese Christian family and became <PERSON> Lady </PERSON> <PERSON> Isabelle </PERSON> when she married Sir <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>. A vivid memory is of a visit to the home of <PERSON> Henri </PERSON> <PERSON> Pharaon </PERSON>, a bachelor shipping millionaire who lived among priceless Islamic art treasures and pictures of horses he raced against those of <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> princes. The racetrack on the city's dividing line is a ruin now, a nightmare scene of bullet-splintered trees and shell holes. An unusual establishment, even for <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, was the Surprise. It was the size of a packing crate and had a bartender, four stools, one hefty prostitute and a remarkable number of customers bidding for her favors. The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION> and large numbers of <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> intellectuals who fled persecution in their own countries gave the city a more serious side. `` The Arab emigres contributed to the city more than the Lebanese socialites,'' said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Snow </PERSON>, an oil economist who spent many years in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> and moved to <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> in 1976. The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and medical school once had 5,000 students and produced a great share of the professional, academic and political leaders in the Arab world. Among the graduates was Dr. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Habash </PERSON>, whose <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> carried out airline hijackings in the 1970s. A 5-month-old artillery war between <LOCATION> Syrian </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> soldiers has forced the university to close temporarily. Several of its officials have been kidnapped. Adjoining the park-like university campus was the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, where children of expatriate families studied and played Little League baseball. Some tried the pinball machines at <PERSON> Anwar </PERSON>'s, where many British and American boys, including my two sons, learned Arabic insults from local youngsters. Beirutis could ski at <LOCATION> Faraya </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, play tennis or squash and race in motor rallies. An <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> journalist who played at the <ORGANIZATION> Golf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, next to the now-closed airport, as late as 1983 wrote that the safest places on the course were the sand traps. The luxurious <ORGANIZATION> Delamiyeh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Country </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, with a gorgeous sea view from a ridge south of the city, was abandoned after <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> guerrillas took it over early in the war. Will the old <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> ever return? No one knows, but I remember <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON> <PERSON> Saab </PERSON>, owner of Summerland, a functioning hotel built during the war. A television reporter asked why he made the investment, and <ORGANIZATION> Saab </ORGANIZATION> replied: `` Did you, as a child, ever kick over an anthill? Did you see how quickly the ants rebuilt? That's <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0022EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Thames     08-22 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Thames,0703</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Tides of Change: Working River Becomes Party River</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Britain-Boat</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LESLIE SHEPHERD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For centuries, the Thames has been a working river, a winding highway where barges, tall ships, then steamers brought the wealth of the world to one of its major commercial centers. Now it's also a popular excurison river, and Sunday's fatal collision of the pleasure cruise boat Marchioness and a dredger many times its size raises questions about whether there is room for both. Transport Minister <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Portillo </PERSON> said Monday the government `` will obviously be looking very carefully'' at whether to ban pleasure cruisers from the river. The opposition <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> called for an immediate conference involving the <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION>, the police and river users to discuss what can be done to improve safety. The Port of <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> says the <LOCATION> Thames </LOCATION> is like `` an eight-lane motorway,'' traveled by 37,000 vessels annually, but insists it is still one of the safest rivers in the world. `` There are very few incidents indeed on the <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Thames </LOCATION>,'' a spokesman said. `` It's one of the safest in the world.'' The port says 25 companies are licensed to operate 40 river cruise boats, like the Marchioness, on the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> stretch of the Thames between <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION> and Hampton Court Palace. `` They have certainly increased, the popularity has increased,'' said port spokesman <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatton </PERSON>, although river cruise operators disagreed. A ferry service was also launched last year, taking passengers from central <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s business and financial districts to the booming Docklands residential and commercial development. An ocean liner dropped anchor in the Thames for the first time in a decade last year, the first of 25 booked up to 1991. The river cruisers carry about 2 million passengers annually. By day, they're full of tourists viewing <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> from a different angle, sailing past the Houses of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, the Tower of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, or the <LOCATION> Kew </LOCATION> botanical gardens. By night, they become floating restaurants, cocktail lounges or discos, chartered for private parties. `` In recent years the growth of tourist boats on sightseeing trips has been accentuated by the popularity of business entertaining by firms hiring crafts to take customers up and down the river,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> lawmaker <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> McCrindle </PERSON>. `` Add in the evening party types and the commercial traffic still using the river, and the feeling that the river may be catering for too many small ships leads me to call for reassurances about safety.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeffery </PERSON>, chief executive of the Port of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, said Sunday's accident involving the 90-ton Marchioness and the 1,475-ton dredger <PERSON> Bowbelle </PERSON> was `` clearly a navigational matter,'' and that the rules governing the passage of boats on the river may have to be reviewed. <PERSON> Jeffery </PERSON> said taped VHF radio messages from the Bowbelle to the <ORGANIZATION> Thames </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navigation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> were being examined. Commercial vessels must report their positions and progress along the river, particularly near bridges, but pleasure craft do not. `` If we required every small craft to report its every movement, the airwaves would be so cluttered it would be difficult to get out of that a picture of the really important pieces where things could possibly go wrong,'' <PERSON> Jeffery </PERSON> said. Commercial ships have plied the Thames for 2,000 years, berthing originally at natural indentations in the river. Vessels later docked in the center of the river and loaded their cargoes onto barges to be taken ashore. River traffic surged in the 1890s when locks were built to control the strong tidal flow, and trade peaked in 1964 when 64 million tons were handled. When container shipping was introduced in the mid-1960s, cargo ships moved to deeper ports like Tilbury at the river's mouth. <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s docks were n't big enough to handl the new, larger container ships. Pilots on the river have to undergo a five - or seven-year apprenticeship to become Freemen of the Watermen and <PERSON> Lightermen </PERSON>'s Company of the City of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, which dates from Members are also designated Queen's Watermen, responsible for rowing Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> on the rare occasions she travels the Thames.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Allies     08-22 0735</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Allies,0759</SECOND>
<HEAD>Today's Poland, Prague Anniversary Show Times Have Changed</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARK J. PORUBCANSKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Twenty-one years after it sent tanks to crush the `` Prague Spring'' reforms in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is watching quietly as <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> takes its political changes even further, breaking the communist monopoly on power. The Soviet reaction to events in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, including the nomination of Solidarity journalist <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> as prime minister, indicated how <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has shaken up the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>'s relations with its Eastern European allies since Soviet-led <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION> forces halted <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s reforms on Aug. 21, 1968 In contrast with <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is willing to allow his allies to find their own way as he experiments with reform at home and grapples with nationalist movements on his own side of the border. Even in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, where reforms have proceeded the furthest, they apparently have not gone beyond what is now acceptable to the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>. It is no longer certain where that limit is. `` The formation of a government in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> is an internal affair of the Polish people,'' <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gremitskykh </PERSON> told a news briefing Monday. `` At the same time, we are not indifferent to it. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> is a neighbor and an ally,'' he said. `` We hope the political forces in the country will act constructively to find a way out of the crisis.'' <PERSON> Gremitskykh </PERSON> was reiterating the cautious Soviet reaction to events in the past several months as <LOCATION> Soldiarity </LOCATION> has been legalized and carried out a successful election campaign. In the meantime, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> has not been able to form a government and President <PERSON> Wojciech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> was forced to turn to Solidarity for a prime minister. Soviet officials last week expressed satisfaction at Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>'s statement that even a Solidarity-led government had responsibilities to the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact. In 1981, <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> crushed Solidarity after it grew into a national movement, ending speculation that <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON> would again use Soviet soldiers to bring a wayward ally back in line. Official Soviet TV and radio are reporting the events in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> but generally refraining from making judgments about the political situation. The <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> newspaper Pravda on Monday painted a grim picture of shortages of meat and other goods. It said <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> was on the brink of `` hyperinflation.'' Prospects of a coalition of Solidarity and two minor, non-communist parties were `` becoming all the more realistic,'' Pravda said. In contrast, it said the Polish <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> was `` living through one of the most difficult periods of its history.'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has said several times in trips to <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> believes its allies should be free to find their own road to developing socialism, depending on local conditions. Twenty-one years ago, on Aug. 21, 1968, <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON> and the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact sent soldiers to <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> to end a reform spearheaded not by an organized opposition, but by <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Czechoslovak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is reported to be frustrated with the conservative leadership in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> that has been in power since 1968 and continues to block reform. But the Soviet reaction to the anniversary of the invasion indicates a continuing sensitivity. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has never said that it made a mistake in sending soldiers into <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>. In response to a question Monday about how the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> now views the invasion, <PERSON> Gremitskykh </PERSON> said only that it had to be understood in the context of the times. <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION>, the Soviet government newspaper, on Saturday printed remembrances of soldiers and Soviet officials who took part in the invasion. <PERSON> Kiril </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazurov </PERSON>, then a member of <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>'s Politburo, said Soviet leaders had learned of plans `` to provoke a nuclear attack on the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.'' `` The Central Committee of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Czechoslovakia </ORGANIZATION> had lost control of the media. In the difficult international environment, we had just one wish _ to unite even more, to prevent a war, to survive together,'' he said. `` It was hard to imagine that a bourgeois parliamentary republic, swarming with West Germans and afterward Americans, might appear next to our borders,'' he said. V.V. <PERSON> Nefyodov </PERSON>, a 19-year-old paratrooper when he was sent to <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> in 1968, told <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> he could not understand why he was sent to a country where the people did n't want him. `` I was ashamed,'' he said. `` Forgive us, <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0004EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-OfficialFired     08-22 0274</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Official Fired,000</SECOND>
<HEAD>Acting Deputy Assistant Secretary of Interior Dismissed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has fired an acting deputy assistant secretary who failed to pass a security check, officials said Monday night. The official, <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> <PERSON> Dress </PERSON>, had agreed to resign in June, efffective July 31, but changed her mind last week and decided not to submit a resignation, said <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON>, press spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Manual </PERSON> <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON>. `` She was terminated,'' <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON> said. He said she was `` a fine employee'' and would not elaborate on why she was fired. The spokesman said <PERSON> Dress </PERSON> told her staff she was dismissed because she failed to pass her security investigation, something confirmed by other officials who spoke on condition they not be identified. Dress had been acting deputy assistant secretary for territorial and international affairs since early May. She had had no access to classified information pending completion of her security check, when she would have stepped up out of the `` acting'' category, <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON> said. The department's Office of Territorial and International Affairs is in charge of the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> and relations with the trust territories and other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dependencies in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>. Just what classified information is involved was not immediately clear, but the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> areas contain <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military bases. The deputy assistant's job does not require <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation. Dress previously served in the <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. After her appointment was announced, she attended a Rose Garden Ceremony where President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> praised her as one of the highest-ranking Asian-Americans in his administration. A woman who answered the telephone at the Dress home Monday night said she was `` not available.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0035EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-NorthKorea     08-22 0881</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North Korea,0904</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese, North Koreans Get By With a Little Help From Friends</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> have pursued different paths in recent years, but they still have a lot in common. Here is a report by one of several Beijing-based reporters recently invited to <LOCATION> Pyongyang </LOCATION> as the government there shows signs of seeking to end its long isolation.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PYONGYANG, North Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 How does a North Korean buy a fancy watch, leather shoes and Japanese cigarettes in a country where such things theoretically require foreign currency? `` I have a lot of friends,'' said a North Korean with all three. As in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, one cultivates friends not just for company, but to skirt regulations and get access to scarce goods. Friendless North Koreans are worse than lonely: they are condemned to walk in flimsy plastic or cloth shoes and wait on long lines for the few public buses or trolleys that ply the broad avenues of this sprawling capital city. There are no private vehicles and no bicycles are allowed in downtown. `` I have friends who are -LRB- official -RRB- drivers,'' said the well-shod North Korean. `` If I want to take my family somewhere, I ask them, and they say, ` Sure.''' That could mean a trip in a <ORGANIZATION> Mercedes-Benz </ORGANIZATION> or at worst in a <ORGANIZATION> Toyota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nissan </ORGANIZATION> or <ORGANIZATION> Volvo </ORGANIZATION>, the only cars in North Korean official fleets. There is much in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> to remind of life in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, its socialist big brother across the <LOCATION> Yalu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>: slow service, careful checks of travelers' identification and lots of uniformed soldiers around, although most are simply walking or standing along the road. As in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, interviews with officials often begin with a `` brief introduction'' that turns into an hour-long recitation of statistics and the official line. Officials give interviews in pairs: one who is introduced and who answers questions, and one who is never introduced but silently supervises. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s separate currencies for locals and foreigners confuse and annoy many visitors, but <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> has three currencies. Ordinary pink-and-green won can buy the bare necessities: the cabbages, eggplant and hard-looking apples and pears on display at a <LOCATION> Pyongyang </LOCATION> green-grocer's one recent morning. Foreigners who convert Soviet rubles get red bills and have a few more choices. But only holders of blue money, changed from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dollars, can buy <ORGANIZATION> Coca-Cola </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Kirin </ORGANIZATION> beer, Japanese televisions and British cigarettes. `` Friends who are diplomats and traders give -LRB- blue money -RRB- to me,'' said the well-connected North Korean, puffing on a Japanese Mild Seven cigarette. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> does n't have <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s hordes of youths openly trading the various currencies for illegal profit on the sidewalks, or the dozens of other symptoms in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> of crumbling official control. Chinese officials trying to reinstall past ideological unity after spring pro-democracy protests might well look to <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> for reminders on how it is done. Political slogans have faded from most walls in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in the past decade, as senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> stressed economic development over ideology. But signs every few hundred meters in rural <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> still exhort, `` Long live the Great Leader <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Il </PERSON> <PERSON> Sung </PERSON>. Long live the glorious Workers' Party of <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>.'' <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> never let its political education mechanisms rust, as <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> did. Professor <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wonsok </PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> said that in workplaces, `` political work is as important as production work.'' Perhaps most important, citizens in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> have not been allowed the sense of independence that comes from being one's own boss. Private businessmen were key supporters of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s protests, but private farm plots in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> are kept tiny and there is virtually no other private economic activity. How far <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has strayed from such basics of old-time socialist rule was illustrated by the comments of two ethnic <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> women who live just inside the Chinese border. They spoke of visits to <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> much as overseas Chinese used to talk of visiting <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>: `` You and I can sit here and say what we like about <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>,'' said one, `` but they ca n't do that about <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Il </PERSON> <PERSON> Sung </PERSON>.'' <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> is helped in its task of control by a smaller population _ 20 million people to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s 1.2 billion _ and strong non-ideological unifying forces: a sense of outside threat, from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, and the common goal of national reunification. Ordinary Koreans and officials spoke of these much more often than of juche, the official philosophy of Marxism and self-reliance. In the 1950s and 1960s, post-war reconstruction and the fear of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> or Soviet attack helped unify <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, but the 1970s and 1980s have seen increasing concern with individual goals. But the North Koreans have not given up all personal happiness for the glory of the nation. Even in a brief visit it was clear they still remember how to have a good time. Accordion music could be heard coming from several homes. A youth with a guitar serenaded friends on the sidewalk one night in <LOCATION> Kaesong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, near the border with the south. And on a sunny afternoon, several dozen young men in dirty blue work clothes went carousing at the nearby Pagyon Waterfalls. Red-faced and a bit wobbly, they sang and danced down the road home.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TechnologyConspiracy     08-22 0294</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Technology Conspiracy,0302</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Arrested on Technology Conspiracy Charges</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> arrested a West German and an Afghan here Monday for allegedly conspiring to export a sophisticated military computer to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The arrests of German national <PERSON> Egbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Partesuis </PERSON>, 46, and <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Aziz </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON>, 40, capped an eight-month investigation into what <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> McDermott </PERSON>, special agent in charge, said was a `` significant case.'' `` The technology is such that it's being sought by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bloc </LOCATION> and there are people attempting to obtain it in this country for them,'' <PERSON> McDermott </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Partesius </PERSON> was in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on a visitor's visa; <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> was a resident alien living in <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. Customs spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Conroy </PERSON> said agents believe that <PERSON> Partesuis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hady </PERSON> <PERSON> Azimi </PERSON>, who remained in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, conspired to purchase and export a digital equipment VAX 8820 mainframe computer, which requires a validated export license from the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> The VAX 8820 has military capabilities and is not eligible for licensed export to Soviet bloc countries, <PERSON> Conroy </PERSON> said. <PERSON> McDermott </PERSON> said the men intially paid $ 28,000 to agents working undercover for an <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> computer with military applications and shipped it to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. `` At that purchase they came forward with the deposit to purchase the VAX 882 and gave a initial deposit. Then last Thursday they came forward with the balance of the $ 596,000,'' <PERSON> McDermott </PERSON> said. Parthesuis and <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> were charged in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> with violating a 4-year-old federal arms export control law and with conspiracy and money laundering. If convicted on all counts, each defendant could receive up to 35 years in prison and a $ 2.5 million fine. The two are being held as federal prisoners at the <LOCATION> Maricopa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jail </LOCATION> without bond, <PERSON> McDermott </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Battleship-Crew 3rdLd-Writethru a0422 08-22 0667</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Battleship-Crew, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0422,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Blast Investigation Finds Many Problems, No Cause of Iowa Blast</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 6th graf: ``In a,'' with three grafs to CORRECT name of
newspaper to Daily Press sted Daily News and add detail from sailor reports</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> investigation of the USS Iowa explosion which killed 47 sailors has found `` various things wrong'' with procedures aboard the battleship but none of them can be determined to be the specific cause of the blast, a defense official Monday. `` It does not point to the cause of the problem,'' the official said, `` The report cites a probability.'' The official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, was asked about reports that crew members of the No. 2 gun turret that blew up April 19 were not properly certified for their jobs or failed to follow maintenance procedures designed to prevent breakdown in the turret. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Tuesday editions that the naval investigation has found the crew faled to perform certain unspecified preventive maintenance procedures, but the newspaper added it was not known whether the faulty maintenance caused the explosion. The Post reported the No. 2 turret's guns passed pre-firing checks before the explosion. In a separate story, the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, reported the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> failed to properly qualify the sailors who worked with the explosives in the turret. The report said the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> requires that all who work at such posts be certified by a qualified board in order to handle the weapons. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Drowns </PERSON>, one of 11 sailors who escaped turret No. 2 after the April 19 explosion, told the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> a qualification board was never convened on the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> during his three years on the ship. Gunner's Mate 2nd Class <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mullahy </PERSON> and a third <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> survivor, Gunner's Mate 3rd Class <PERSON> Kendall </PERSON> <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON>, said one of the sailors who lacked a qualification book showing facts about the guns was Gunner's Mate 3rd Class <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Backherms </PERSON>, the rammerman of the center gun where the explosion occurred. <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> said <PERSON> Backherms </PERSON> joined the ship shortly after Christmas, was inexperienced and may have caused the blasts by ramming the bags of explosives into the gun too fast. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials would not confirm the details in the two newspaper reports. They said the results of the investigation are still in the chain of command and the review process is not completed. `` Until then, we are not in a position to comment,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman Cmdr. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said the investigaive process is not finished while the report remains in the chain of command and the chief of <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION>, Adm. <PERSON> Carlisle </PERSON> <PERSON> Trost </PERSON>, has not made it public. `` As far as we're concerned, it's all still under investigation,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is expected to make the report public in early September. The report was prepared under the guidance of Rear Adm. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Milligan </PERSON> and was sent last weel to top officials at the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, where it is being reviewed by `` a very tightly controlled group of people,'' another <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> source said. `` Only a few people currently are working on it. As far as I know there are no civilians in the group and it's next stop will be on the desk of the chief of <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION>,'' the source said. However, the defense official said he was told the report will show a number of `` lapses in procedures,'' but he said he could not identify them. `` The investigation found various things wrong about procedures. But none of them has been found to be the cause,'' the official said. The official said the investigation has gone deeply into details of the ship's operations, which means multiple problems could be found in such a complex operation as a battleship firing its guns. `` There were lapses in procedures, but to cite just maintenance problems would be nitpicking. It does not point to the cause of the problem,'' the official said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Colombia-Glance     08-22 0391</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Colombia-Glance,0406</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING to fix paragraphs</HEAD>
<HEAD>Colombia-at-a-Glance</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Colombia, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are some facts and figures about <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 THE LAND _ <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> is bordered on the northwest by <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, on the north by the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>, on the east by <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, on the southwest by <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ecuador </LOCATION>, and on the west by the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>. With 456,500 square miles of territory, it is about three times larger than <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. It is mostly tropical on the coast and eastern plains and cooler in the highlands. The capital, <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, is the largest city with over 4 million residents. The other main cities are <LOCATION> Cali </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Barranquilla </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 THE PEOPLE _ With more than 29 million inhabitants, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> is 95 percent Roman Catholic. The main ethnic groups are mestizo, 58 percent; <LOCATION> Caucasian </LOCATION>, 20 percent; mulatto, 14 percent; African descent, 4 percent; mixed African - Indian, 3 percent; Indian, 1 percent The predominant language is Spanish.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 THE ECONOMY _ The chief crops are coffee, accounting for about half the country's $ 6 billion in annual exports, which also include bananas, flowers, sugar, oil, clothing, textiles, cotton and tobacco. Illegal cocaine earnings bring home an estimated $ 500 milllion to $ 1.2 billion annually. <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> has crude oil reserves of about 3.2 billion barrels. Mineral resources include gold, copper, lead, coal, iron and nickel. <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s gross national product grew 3.7 percent last year. Annual inflation is 28 percent.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 POLITICS _ In 1957, the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> formed the `` <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>'' under which they jointly governed, alternating the presidency every four years and alloting parity in all elective and appointed offices. That arrangement ended `` la violencia,'' a period of warfare between the parties that killed an estimated 200,000 people from 1948-58. The power - sharing arrangement was phased out during the 1970s The current <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> president, <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> <PERSON> Vargas </PERSON>, was elected in May 1986 and took office three months later. <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> is battling urban leftist guerrilla groups, of which the April 19th Movement, also known as M-19, is the most aggressive and best-organized.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 HISTORY _ Established as the <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> colony of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Granada </LOCATION> in 1549, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> proclaimed its independence and formed the Republic of <ORGANIZATION> Greater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colombia </ORGANIZATION> in 1819. The nation has been one of the few functioning democracies in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> for nearly all of its post-independence history.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-UndergroundExplosions Bjt   08-22 0620</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Underground Explosions, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Texas Town Says No to Pentagon Plan for Massive Underground Blasts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A south <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> city is fighting to protect the springs that make it a desert oasis from a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> proposal to rock a nearby ranch with a series of massive underground explosions. The proposed explosions on the Buck King Ranch near <LOCATION> Del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, are an important element in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> strategic deterrent capabilities, says the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. The non-nuclear explosions are designed to simulate the impact of nuclear blasts on subterranean missile silos and military command centers. But 12,000 of the 40,000 <LOCATION> Del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> residents have signed petitions asking the agency to take its explosives elsewhere. They say they do n't want to take any chances with the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> border city's only source of water, the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Felipe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>. `` We depend on <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Felipe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> for survival,'' says City Manager <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Pomeranz </PERSON>. `` The city of <LOCATION> Del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> is not willing to play a what-if game with our water and the future of our city. `` No one in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> has offered us any guarantees, nor can they, that if our water supply was adversely affected, the federal government would step in and correct the situation,'' he said. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> also has expressed concern to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials about the potential impact of the explosions near the border, said <PERSON> Leonardo </PERSON> <PERSON> French </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Mexican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. Defense Nuclear Agency officials, however, say a final decision to conduct the tests hinges on geological and environmental assessments of the area that are not yet completed. The agency spent two years choosing the site 25 miles north of <LOCATION> Del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> for the graduated series of explosions. The explosions would start with a 1,000-pound charge in 1990, increasing to 470 tons _ equivalent to 300 tons of <ORGANIZATION> TNT </ORGANIZATION> _ in November 1992. Defense spokeswoman <PERSON> Cheri </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdelnour </PERSON> said the tests would be performed with the same conventional explosives used by the mining industry, and do not involve nuclear or radioactive devices. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bachkosky </PERSON>, director of plans, programs and requirements for the defense agency, said the tests are `` important to the continued credibility and viability of our strategic deterrent.'' `` As an agency, our primary responsibility to the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> is to ensure the survivability of our strategic assets and the effectiveness of those same assets when used against anyone who might threaten our security,'' he said. <PERSON> Del </PERSON> <PERSON> Rio </PERSON> officials were told the purpose of the tests was to `` determine the survivability of underground missile silos and foreign missile silos and other underground military facilities,'' <PERSON> Pomeranz </PERSON> said. But <PERSON> Del </PERSON> <PERSON> Rio </PERSON> residents say water in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> is more important. Last week they became even more skittish when an underground cave-in contaminated their water with an unknown substance, forcing them to drink boiled or bottled water for two days. Just as the springs are tied to the city's future, they are part of its past, with the first <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> explorers writing about the springs in their chronicles. Long before it was settled, <PERSON> Del </PERSON> <PERSON> Rio </PERSON> was an oasis on the long, dry trail between <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Pomeranz </PERSON> said. `` Del Rio's entire growth and development is centered around the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Felipe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Pomeranz </PERSON> said. On Friday, <PERSON> Pomeranz </PERSON> and Mayor <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Gutierrez </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> met with <PERSON> Bachkosky </PERSON> and Vice Adm. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> director, to ask that the drilling for the core samples be abandoned. `` What we're saying is, we've got 12,000 signatures of <PERSON> Del </PERSON> <PERSON> Rioans </PERSON> who want the project stopped and the city of <LOCATION> Del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> is going to do everything possible to protect our citizens,'' <PERSON> Pomeranz </PERSON> said. `` Therefore, let's stop the test drilling now, and look for another site.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Fed-InterestRates Bjt   08-22 0690</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fed-Interest Rates, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fed Policymakers Meeting Today</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal Reserve policymakers, meeting privately today, likely will decide against lowering interest rates soon despite pressure from the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, analysts say. The Federal Open Market Committee, which controls the benchmark federal funds rate that banks charge each other for overnight loans, is devising the central bank's monetary strategy for the next six weeks. But, as usual under the committee's procedure, the results wo n't be publicly disclosed until Oct. 6, three days after the next meeting Most analysts expected the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> to hold interest rates steady unless it sees unexpected signs that economic growth is fizzling. `` I do n't think they're going to do much of anything right now,'' said economist <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Markets </ORGANIZATION>. `` They can say their policies are working pretty much as desired. The economy is still moving up and the inflation numbers have been fairly good.'' The central bank, which tries to regulate the nation's economy by manipulating interest rates, has been engaged in a delicate balancing act over the past 18 months. It is trying to hold inflation in check by moderating economic growth but at the same time keep the country from toppling into what would be the first recession since 1982. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> tried last week to tip the balance in favor of lower rates, which would stimulate economic growth and revenue to the government. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> endorsed comments by his budget director, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>, who said it would be the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>'s fault if the economy falls into a recession. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, however, warned that such lobbying of the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>, a fiercely independent agency, may backfire. `` If anything, it causes them to dig in their heels,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> believes economic growth of only a little more than 2 percent a year is sustainable without fueling inflation, but the administration is looking for growth closer to 3 percent this year to help it reduce the federal budget deficit. `` In a $ 5 trillion economy, that's not peanuts,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Aubrey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> G. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lanston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a government securities dealer in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. `` In fact, for every 1 percent increase in growth, Mr. <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> gets an extra $ 25 billion in revenue to help ease the budget deficit.'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said there is a split in the 12-member <ORGANIZATION> FOMC </ORGANIZATION>, which consists of seven <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> governors _ although there is one vacancy _ and five presidents of regional <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banks </ORGANIZATION>. Board members have tended to favor easier money, while regional bank presidents have leaned toward tighter policy, he said. Board member <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Angell </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Livestock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> on Friday that he believed the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> has succeeded in curbing inflation, which he predicted would decline from about 5 percent a year to about 3 percent. Earlier last week however, <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoskins </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Stern </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, told bankers at a <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin </ORGANIZATION> forum that they believed economic growth was accelerating, a sign that inflation wo n't subside. At least for now, it's hard to say for sure which faction is right, economists say. The Fed only recently began easing its tight money policy. From March 1988 to March 1989, the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> pushed short-term interest rates up by 3 percentage points in an effort to curb the economy and bring inflationary pressures under control. It paused for several months and then in early June, as signs of sluggish growth emerged, reversed course and began to push rates lower. Now, as economic reports come in for July, it appears the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> has exactly what it wants. The most recent data suggests the economy has recovered a bit from sluggishness in the April-June quarter. The <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>'s index of industrial production rose in July after falling the two previous months. And new home construction rebounded in June and July from four consecutive monthly declines. Consumer price inflation, which from January through May soared at the worst rate in seven years, averaging 0.5 percent to 0.6 percent each month, fell to 0.2 percent in both June and July.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0135EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     08-22 0805</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Horticulture Industry Blooming</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When a new home is offered for sale, even in the heart of big-city suburbia, it very often adds to farm income with an eye-catching display of freshly planted shrubs and green sod almost ready to mow. Add cut flowers and floral arrangements for weddings, funerals, lovers, <PERSON> Aunt </PERSON> <PERSON> Sophie </PERSON> and sick friends and you have horticulture _ one of the fastest developing sectors in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agriculture. Since 1982, says an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> economist, the horticulture industry has grown an average of 10 percent a year. Preliminary figures for 1988 show that producers of horticultural products had cash receipts totaling $ 6.9 billion, which was more than 9 percent of the $ 72.4 billion received by farmers last year for all crops. For example, according to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> statistics, the $ 6.9 billion for flowers, shrubs, sod and other greenery exceed 1988 cash receipts for cotton, $ 4.7 billion, and tobacco, $ 2.04 billion, and was creeping up on feed crops _ including corn _ $ 7.68 billion. <PERSON> Doyle </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said the industry was in two sectors. Floriculture includes cut flowers, potted flowering plants, bedding plants and cut cultivated greens such as ferns used in arrangements. The other is environmental horticulture, which includes all other nursery and greenhouse products. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s analysis of the rapid growth of the horticulture industry is in the September issue of <LOCATION> Farmline </LOCATION> magazine. `` One of the reasons for the increase in horticultural sales is that the housing industry is spending more for sod and other landscape ornamentals,'' the report said. `` Also, cities are doing more landscaping in the inner cities as well as in parks and along highways.'' <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> accounts for about 23 percent of total horticultural sales, followed by <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, nearly 15 percent, and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, 7 percent. Of 2 million farms in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, there are fewer than 38,000 horticultural operations. But in 1987, the most recent statistics available, those had sales averaging $ 154,818 each, compared with $ 65,165 for all farms. There are an estimated 57,000 retail floral outlets in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the report said. Mass-market outlets, mostly grocery stores, account for 21,000, but the majority, an estimated 36,000, are independent retail floral shops. According to 1986 figures, grocery store sales of flowers and plants amounted to $ 1.49 billion, averaging $ 28 per square feet of store space, compared with $ 8 to $ 12 for other produce, the report said. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is the world's largest producer of flowers and plants, and American growers control about 95 percent of the domestic market, the report said. But imports are important, totaling $ 451 million last year. <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> is the largest source of the imports, the report said. Others include the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 British wine drinkers offer a potential growth market for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> producers, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Fondahn </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural trade officer in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, says per capita wine consumption in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION> grew from 2 liters in 1967 to 12 liters in 1987. `` It currently is the only growth market in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> for wine,'' he said. `` With 41 supplying countries, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION> has become the most sought after wine market in the world.'' <PERSON> Fondahn </PERSON> said in the September issue of AgExporter magazine that the <LOCATION> U.K. </LOCATION> imports 57.4 million cases of wine annually, compared with domestic production of 9.4 million cases. Although the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> market share is less than 1 percent, last year's sales of American wine to the <LOCATION> U.K. </LOCATION> rose 20 percent to 550,000 cases, he said. Consumers prefer white wines over red, although there has been substantial increases in red and rose wines lately. `` The most dramatic development in wine sales in recent years has been the establishment of wine bars,'' <PERSON> Fondahn </PERSON> said. `` These establishments have introduced a large segment of the population to a variety of wines. Many of the wine bars offer their wines by the case for home consumption.'' <PERSON> Fondahn </PERSON> said that as a member of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> U.K. </LOCATION> must comply with <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> requirements for the importation of wine. These requirements can be stringent and, in some cases, can hinder the sale of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wine in the <LOCATION> U.K. </LOCATION>, he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Catfish production continues to increase, but the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says producers are getting lower prices than they did a year ago. Production in July totaled 27.8 million pounds of live weight delivered to processing plants, the department said Monday in its monthly report. That was up 17 percent from July 1988. But prices paid to growers averaged 71 cents per pound, down 9 cents a pound from a year earlier, the report said. Production through the first seven months of 1989 totaled 196.6 million pounds, up 16 percent from the same period last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Budget     08-22 0598</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Budget Director Warns of Possible Program Cuts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's battles against drugs, AIDS, tax cheats and dangerous airways could be undermined unless <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> implements an agreement to cut the budget deficit, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration says. Such spending programs may have to be arbitrarily cut _ and $ 8.1 billion taken from the military budget _ unless the 1990 deficit is reduced to the level allowed by law, says <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>. However, in a report to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Monday, <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> said across-the-board spending cuts are avoidable. `` It remains my hope, and my cautiously optimistic expectation, that necessary legislation'' cutting selected programs and raising revenues can be enacted when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> returns Sept. 5, <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> said. The government can avoid the across-the-board reductions if <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will implement a budget-cutting agreement reached with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in April, <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> said. He noted that almost none of that agreement has been enacted into law. The deficit is on a path that, in the absence of further congressional action, would lead to $ 116.2 billion of red ink during the 1990 budget year, which begins Oct. 1. That's down from about $ 170 billion this year. The law limits the 1990 deficit to $ 100 billion. As a result of the estimate, <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> told reporters, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will issue an order Friday to cut _ `` sequester'' in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> jargon _ $ 16.2 billion worth of spending, half from the military budget and half from most non-military programs. But that order will be only a warning; the real cuts would not be ordered until Oct. 15. In his report, <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> listed specific cuts that would be required in specific programs, ranging from a $ 1 billion slash in salaries and benefits for the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> to a $ 7 million reduction in health benefits for retired federal workers. Among the effects that could occur, <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> said, are:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ A cut below this year's level in funds for the <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, which `` could undermine its ability to wage an aggressive war on drugs. The Coast Guard might have to ground aircraft needed for critical interdiction activities. _ Reductions `` would severely hamper the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>'s efforts to prevent HIV -LRB- the AIDS virus -RRB- transmission and conduct research into therapies and vaccines _ The effect on the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> `` could include a furlough of up to three days per month of all <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> staff, including air traffic control and maintenance personnel. _ <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> funding would be reduced; the agency could lose 4,700 workers, meaning 10 million fewer taxpayer-assistance calls could be answered and fewer returns could be audited _ About 1 million needy college students would lose federal education grants _ The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> might be forced to cut 160,000 personnel Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Frenzel </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, senior Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, predicted that once the smoke clears, `` <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is going to lurch across the finish line'' and avoid the arbitrary cuts. Rep. <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, D-Calif., chairman of the committee, cautioned that `` <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> should not be lulled to sleep by <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION>'s artificially low deficit projections Even with these dubious economic and spending assumptions, we face the possibility of harsh across-the-board spending cuts this fall ... and ... we still need $ 30 billion to $ 60 billion in additional deficit reduction for 1991.'' <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> also noted a greater effort will be required a year from now to cut the deficit further. But <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s opposition to a tax increase is unchanged, he said. `` We still say revenues -LRB- tax increases -RRB- do n't have to be on the -LRB- negotiating -RRB- table for 1991.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0137EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BoyorGirl     08-22 0547</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Boy or Girl,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boy or Girl: Parents of One Want the Other</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For American parents, the old-time preference for boys seems to be giving way to a desire for a child of each sex. Parents with two boys or two girls are quicker to have a third child than those with one of each gender, report researchers <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schollaert </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Teachman </PERSON>. And, contrary to their expectations, parents who have a son first try again slightly sooner than those who start with a daughter, they report in the August edition of Demography, the journal of the <ORGANIZATION> Population </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. `` The American norm really is a boy-girl family,'' Schollaert, of <ORGANIZATION> Old </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dominion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said in a telephone interview. That finding, he added, could ease fears that the ability to select the gender of children could lead to an excess of boys. `` Our results are straightforward. The gender of children affects birth timing. Yet it is not whether a child is a boy or a girl that is important,'' reported <PERSON> Teachman </PERSON> and Schollaert. `` Women with two boys or two girls are more likely to time a third birth rapidly than are women with a boy and a girl,'' they said. Their conclusions were based on an analysis of births to more than 2,000 women, reported in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Survey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Growth </ORGANIZATION> in 1973, 1976 and 1982. By recording births every six months they were able to compare whether women in one group had births before those in other groups. They did not report the actual length of time between births, however. Were they surprised that parents who had sons first were quicker to have a second child than those who had a daughter first? `` Oh, we were,'' responded Schollaert. In many societies there is a strong preference for boys, leading to the killing of female babies in some countries, <PERSON> Schollaert </PERSON> said. Past studies in this country have indicated a slight preference for boys. `` So, logic is that if you tried once and had a daughter you'd be more likely to go try again quickly,'' he said. `` What, we found, to the contrary, was that those who had sons were more likely to have a rapid -LRB- second -RRB- birth,'' he said. However, he explained that the slight preference for boys still might be the reason. <PERSON> Schollaert </PERSON> said he and <PERSON> Teachman </PERSON> found that `` couples that have sons are slightly more likely to stay married, and, of course, the most powerful determinant of whether you have another child in short order is ` are you married.''' Tradition has it that people prefer boys, and that slight preference in <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> society has a bearing, he said. Fathers are `` more likely to be involved with their sons than their daughters. This involvement leads to greater familial ties and interdependencies that work against marital dissolution,'' said <PERSON> Teachman </PERSON> and Schollaert. Studies have found that parents who have a daughter first are somewhat more likely to divorce than those who have a son. Thus, women with sons were more likely to remain married and to have a second child. Women with daughters, being more likely to be divorced or separated, had a reduced likelihood of having second children, they concluded.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890822-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-89 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Fed-JapanSecurities     08-22 0529</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fed-Japan Securities,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fed Won't Penalize Japanese-Owned Securities Companies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
