<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0003EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>b a AM-USAirCrash 1stAdd   09-21 0072</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-USAir Crash, 1st Add,0073</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>NEW YORK: officials said.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The plane, <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> Flight 5050, a <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737-400, went down on takeoff from <LOCATION> LaGuardia </LOCATION>, bound for <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> spokewoman in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. `` On takeoff it went off the end of the runway and it is now partially submerged in the water,'' she said. Young had no information about the number of people aboard or possible injuries.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     09-21 0574</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0600</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAFAYETTE, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 What's a hot tub doing at the Farm Science Review? `` The farmer likes hot tubs just as much as anyone does. We have a tendency to think the farmer is not a normal person. But of course he is,'' said <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Fendrick </PERSON>, manager of the farm equipment exposition at the <ORGANIZATION> Molly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caren </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, 20 miles west of <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>. Organizers of the three-day event say the 600-plus demonstrations and displays have changed over the years. `` We sat back and thought, ` How come we can attract the farmer but not his wife, his family, his neighbors?''' <PERSON> Fendrick </PERSON> said Wednesday. So along with tractor demonstrations and free samples of pesticide, the review offered tips on how to remove chocolate stains from linen, manage personal finances, update a wardrobe with inexpensive accessories and eat at Pizza Hut without gaining much weight. Information also was available on owning a bed-and-breakfast inn and breeding a pet llama. Ten or 15 years ago, the typical visitor at the review was white, male, between 50 and 60 years old, wore overalls and attended the event by himself. `` Today he's wearing designer jeans, his wife is with him, and she's usually pushing the stroller,'' <PERSON> Fendrick </PERSON> said. `` A lot of them out there are in their 30s.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHEYENNE, Wyo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Glasnost notwithstanding, there are still some unknown details about Soviet leaders. Such as, how big is Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>'s head? <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> officials wanted to know that before <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>'s scheduled arrival in <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hole </LOCATION> today for two days of talks with Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> Officials from the <ORGANIZATION> Cowboy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> did n't want to cause an international embarrassment by presenting the minister with an ill-fitting <PERSON> Stetson </PERSON>. `` We tried calling the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Embassy </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. They said it's just kind of average. We did n't really know what that meant,'' said <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Curran </PERSON>, spokesman for Gov. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>. So they rang up the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, counting on the resourcefulness of the American intelligence network. It took two days of research to find an answer: 60 centimeters. `` We were n't quite sure what that meant,'' <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> said, adding that officials think it corresponds to a size 7 -LCB-. The cowboy hat is intended to help <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> fit in at a western barbecue to be thrown by <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> on Saturday night at the end of the two-day talks.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LANSING, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members returned from summer break to temporary quarters in a former print shop and went to work on folding chairs and cafeteria-style tables instead of their usual stately chairs and desks. The House is being housed in an office building so its Capitol chamber can be restored during the next few months. Low ceilings made the noise level louder than usual Wednesday, and legislators practically had to step over each other in crowded aisles. One lawmaker said he could n't find a bathroom. `` This would n't pass the inspection for a dairy barn,'' Rep. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Gnodtke </PERSON> said, `` but I guess it's good enough for legislators.'' Despite the tight space and the noise, most lawmakers gave good reviews to their temporary chamber. `` I was all set to come here and gripe, but I want to make sure the right people get complimented,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>. House Speaker <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodak </PERSON> said he hoped members would start using their phones to call each other on the floor to cut down on traffic and noise.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0142EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Cambodia-War     09-21 0730</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cambodia-War,0752</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cambodians Fear More War After Vietnamese Withdrawal</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report. Vietnamese pullout set to be completed
by Sept. 26.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER ENG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHNOM PENH, Cambodia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At 6 a.m. one recent Thursday, Soun Sundary, gentle and serene at 21, gave birth to her first child and held her up to a <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> that has known only war for two decades. `` I do n't know about the future, whether there will be peace or not,'' she said as the sun shone into her hospital room after days of monsoon rains. She and her husband, <PERSON> Soun </PERSON> <PERSON> Rithy </PERSON>, 25, have spent most of their lives with their tragic nation in turmoil and mass deaths _ the civil war of 1970-75, the fanatical communist <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> rule of 1975-78 and the fighting since <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> invaded in late 1978. Seven members of their two families died in the murderous scourge of the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> who defeated a pro-West government in 1975. The couple and their daughter are likely to see more killing in the years ahead, even though the Vietnamese are pulling out. Rithy had come to <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> for the birth of his child but is returning to southern <LOCATION> Koh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> province, where he has fought as a government soldier for seven years against the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> and other guerrillas. Peace talks in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> have collapsed. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s pullout, due to be completed Sept. 26, will leave the Vietnamese-installed <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> government in <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> facing the guerrillas alone in what could be the war's most chaotic and violent phase. `` We would like to have peace, really,'' Vice Premier <PERSON> Kong </PERSON> <PERSON> Sam-Ol </PERSON> said in n interview. `` For almost 20 years, our people have known more about killing and war than peace.'' Most feared is the possibility that <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s pullout will allow the return of the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, the black pajama-clad fighters who killed hundreds of thousands of people in torture chambers and slave labor camps after they took over in 1975. The government claims the army will have no problems handling the guerrillas. Many others do not feel as confident. Some <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> residents have been stocking rice in case supplies are cut off by escalating fighting, said <PERSON> Khieu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kanharith </PERSON>, editor of the government-sponsored weekly Kampuchea. Some senior government officials have told Western aid workers they are saving money in case they have to flee. `` They do n't know what is going to happen after September if there are problems with the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>,'' one aid worker said. `` They believe if there are problems, the first problems would be for them.'' At <LOCATION> Kompong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chhnang </LOCATION>, just north of <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION>, Maj. <PERSON> Chhour </PERSON> <PERSON> Chandoeun </PERSON>, the provincial military commander, said his nine battalions are hard pressed in their fight against the 300 <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas in the area. `` They do n't stay in one place and we do n't know all their hiding places,'' he said. An aid official said the government's military draft appears to be widening. A few months ago, some parents forbade their sons to leave the house as overzealous recruiters yanked men off the streets. Some youths flee to the border with <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, only to be rounded up by the guerrillas for service. A 10 p.m.-5 a.m. curfew was lifted in April, but the climate of war still pervades this riverside capital. In July, authorities closed dance halls that had been packed nightly since they were permitted to open last year. Mayor <PERSON> Thong </PERSON> <PERSON> Khong </PERSON> blamed drunken quarrels and said only the rich could visit them anyway. `` At that time, there was increased fighting at the border and it was difficult to justify the sacrifice at the border and the good life in <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION>,'' one foreign-aid official said. For many years, popular support for the Vietnamese-backed government had stemmed mostly from its being the only alternative to the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>. With <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s pullout, <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> extended economic reforms to include a freeing up of private trade in an effort to raise primitive living conditions. Ironically, it created a new security problem by worsening corruption among officials, and corruption was a factor that helped the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> topple <PERSON> Lon </PERSON> <PERSON> Nol </PERSON>'s pro-West government in 1975. The reforms reduced somewhat the gulf between the people and their leaders But in addition to the fear of more war remains the widespread fear of the authorities and `` the police,'' who are thought to be everywhere.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0143EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BunkerBandits     09-21 0816</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bunker Bandits,0848</SECOND>
<HEAD>Robbers in The Ruins: Bandits Plague Shell-Shocked Citizens</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 As though the constant shelling is n't enough, residents of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> now face marauding bands of gunmen who loot abandoned apartments or rob those huddling in bomb shelters. Here is another in a series of periodic reports on life in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By DONNA ABU-NASR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Long-suffering residents of this beleaguered capital have braved six months of shelling and shortages only to face a new terror _ bunker bandits. Bands of gunmen prowl the streets of Moslem west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> at night, cleaning out apartments hit in the artillery battles between the Syrians and Christian forces. They grab anything salvageable: Persian carpets, television sets, video recorders, silverware. It's not unusual to hear the crackle of automatic weaponsfire at night, as the marauders fire in the air to keep people away from the scenes of their depredations. They also prey on civilians huddling in basement shelters during the shelling because many people take their savings and jewelry with them when they go underground. One gang of masked gunmen robbed six families in a bunker beneath their apartment block in west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Aishe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bakkar </LOCATION> neighborhood. `` I do n't know how they managed to get in during the shelling,'' said one of the victims, <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu-Samir </PERSON>, a middle-aged Sunni Moslem taxi driver. `` They just ordered us to hand over our jewelry, money and watches and we had to do as they said,'' he said. `` I do n't know which is the worst: getting robbed in our own shelter, or the shelling.'' The number of reported robberies has gone down in recent weeks because about 1.3 million of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s 1.5 million people have fled to safer areas to escape the nightly barrages that have killed more than 900 people and wounded nearly 2,800 since March 8. But the thousands of abandoned apartments make easy pickings. Some residents now take pistols to their shelters to protect themselves against the looters. Other indirect victims of the violence are hundreds of Sri Lankan maids stranded in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> by fleeing employers who order them to guard apartments and houses. `` I risk my life here during the shelling, looking after their carpets and silverware while they're safe somewhere and having fun in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>,'' said a bitter <PERSON> Kumari </PERSON> <PERSON> Hami </PERSON>, left to fend for herself in an eighth floor apartment in Moslem west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. `` I'd rather starve in my own country than be here,'' she said. Her countrywomen, along with Filipinas and women from other poor <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> countries, came to <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> hoping to make a decent living. Most are paid $ 50 a month. She said most employers make sure the maids do not flee by taking their passports. Unable to leave <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, they're left alone and frightened amid the daily artillery battles. Some are among the casualties, but police said they have no specific figures. <PERSON> Fadi </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinno </PERSON>, who runs an office that hires Sri Lankans to work in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, said about 2,000 women share <PERSON> Kumari </PERSON>'s plight. `` Their employers leave them in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> because thieves usually rob empty apartments,'' he said. `` The maids come to me crying, but there's nothing we can do about it because they're bound by their contracts.'' The <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> government has evacuated more than 200 Filipinas who were stranded in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, some complaining they had been forced into prostitution. Many have been made destitute by the 14-year-old civil war that has destroyed <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s economy, but the latest round of fighting has brought a boom for scrap metal merchants. In the <LOCATION> Chatilla </LOCATION> district of west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, junkyard owners like <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Wehbi </PERSON> are out in the rubble-strewn streets every day in their trucks as soon as there's a lull in the shelling. They scavenge among wrecked cars, shrapnel and bombed-out apartments for battered metal household items. `` We only care about copper pieces of shrapnel,'' <PERSON> Wehbi </PERSON> said during a recent sweep through west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. `` Iron ones are n't worth the trouble of collecting because they do n't bring in much money.'' He said when he sees a smoldering car, he usually looks for the owner to buy it. `` The most I'll pay for such a car is 15,000 -LRB- Lebanese -RRB- pounds -LRB- $ 30 -RRB-,'' he said. But people in some neighborhoods said dealers usually just tow the blackened, shrapnel-holed hulks away without bothering to ask about ownership. <PERSON> Wehbi </PERSON> said that after the metal is compressed it is shipped to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and some Arab countries through the southern ports of <LOCATION> Sidon </LOCATION> and Tyre to be melted down and used to make household appliances and ammunition. `` <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> takes copper for ammunition. <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> take brass for electrical appliances,'' he said. Pointing to a large shipping container, <PERSON> Wehbi </PERSON> said: `` That's more than half full of empty beer cans. People are drinking more because they're nervous and because there's no water. It's all good for business.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--YoungFund-raiser     09-21 0185</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Young Fund-raiser,0192</SECOND>
<HEAD>12-Year-Old Raises $587 for Bullet-Proof Vests for Police</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BRISTOL, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police thanked a 12-year-old boy for raising $ 587 to buy them two bulletproof vests. Seventh-grader <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> said he learned of the dangers facing police officers when he read a magazine article describing how a bulletproof vest saved an officer's life. He visited the police department, where he learned that the department had only enough of the $ 300 vests for about a third of its officers. So, he placed jars for contributions in stores, raising about $ 300. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, whose father is a doctor, then got more than $ 200 from doctors at <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> voted Monday to let the police department buy two vests with the $ 587 he raised. `` He did it on his own,'' Lt. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Killiany </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` We're very appreciative of the efforts of this youth.'' It was n't <PERSON> Flores </PERSON>' first contribution to the city. He has volunteered to help senior citizens and with clients of the <ORGANIZATION> Bristol </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> for the Retarded _ and now he's looking for more volunteer work. `` I'll find something,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0611EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Rescue911     09-21 0121</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Rescue 911,0124</SECOND>
<HEAD>TV Crime Show's Film Crew Gets Taste of Real Thing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT WORTH, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A crew from <ORGANIZATION> CBS-TV </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Rescue 911'' that came to <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> to film a burglary re-enactment got a first-hand look at real crime. A $ 30,000 camera disappeared Monday night as the crew was unloading equipment to shoot a segment about real-life emergencies. `` It's a sad fact for <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>,'' said police Lt. <PERSON> Alvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Allcon </PERSON>. `` Here someone is filming a property crime and then they become a victim of a property crime.'' Investigators believe a passer-by simply walked away with the camera that was left unattended on a sidewalk. They have no leads. Filming resumed Monday night after the crew got another camera.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Typhoon     09-21 0173</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Typhoon,0178</SECOND>
<HEAD>Death Toll From Typhoon Rises to 162</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The death toll from a powerful typhoon that hit <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s east coast over the weekend has risen to 162, with 354 people still missing, an official newspaper reported today. The <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> Daily, quoting flood control officials in <LOCATION> Zhejiang </LOCATION> province, said 692 people were injured and property losses from Typhoon Vera were estimated at $ 350 million. The typhoon, the most powerful to hit the province in 27 years, flooded 857,000 acres of farmland and washed out 40,000 acres of crops. Earlier television newscasts showed toppled buildings, flattened fields and workers rebuilding the shoreline with stones and sandbags. <LOCATION> Zhejiang </LOCATION>, located just south of <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>, was also hit by torrential storms this July that killed 122 people and caused economic losses of $ 405 million. `` These natural calamities have brought appalling losses to the province's people and property as well as to its industrial and agricultural base,'' the flood control headquarters said. Last year, summer storms in the disaster-prone province killed an estimated 400.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-TeddyBear     09-21 0498</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Teddy Bear,0516</SECOND>
<HEAD>World's Most Expensive Teddy Bear Bought As Anniversary Gift</HEAD>
<HEAD>By JESSICA BALDWIN</HEAD>
<UNK>Associated Press Writer</UNK>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s was surprised when a well-preserved, 67-year-old teddy bear sold for a record $ 86,000. So was the buyer. `` His first words were, ` You're kidding','' <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, who was an intermediary in the deal, said Wednesday. However, <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said, his <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> friend was prepared to pay even more and was delighted to bag the bear as a 42nd anniversary present for his wife. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> refused to identify the buyer. The actual bidding was done by stockbroker <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, 26, of <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION>, who was given a blank check and sent to <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> on Tuesday. `` I could tell from his voice he was ashen,'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said, `` and he said ... the auction's just over and I've got the bear.' `` And I said ` well done, <PERSON> James </PERSON>' and then he said ` you'd better sit down because I paid 50,000 -LRB- pounds -RRB-.' `` And I said ` You've done what?!''' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said he waited a few hours before phoning his American friend. `` I guess he might have figured on a third'' of that record price, said <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, who is chairman of the House of Nisbet teddy bear manufacturers in <LOCATION> Weston-super-Mare </LOCATION> in southwest <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. `` He's is very pleased. He was determined to have it.'' The buyer and his wife are avid teddy-bear collectors, <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said, and both happen to be as old as the record-breaking bear. The price is nearly five times the previous highest price for a teddy bear and 61 times its catalogue estimate, said <PERSON> Bunny </PERSON> <PERSON> Campione </PERSON>, a valuer for <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said his firm would like to do a replica of the bear. `` It's up to my friend, although it seems like we have the inside track,'' he said. The previous highest auction price for a teddy bear was $ 19,000 paid at a Christie's auction in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> on May 18 for a Steiff bear made between 1906 and 1909 for Princess <LOCATION> Xenia </LOCATION>, a cousin of Czar <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>. Several bidders stayed in the race until the price reached $ 38,000, <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. `` The other bidder after 24,000 pounds -LRB- $ 38,000 -RRB- was a telephone bidder and the general impression was that the caller was from <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. `` Bears are an art form like paintings,'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. `` People are used to hearing about crazy figures like $ 400 million for paintings and this is the same kind of price inflation. It is a very rare bear.'' The German-made teddy, <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> is thought to date from 1927. The bear is 24 inches long, has dual-plush fur in blond and brown, amber and black glass eyes measuring about 1 inch in diameter, swivel joints, a humped back and widely spaced pricked ears. It is believed that it was part of a batch of a few thousand, but Mrs. <PERSON> Campione </PERSON> said the bear was in unusually good condition. Before going to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, the bear will on display at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teddy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Stratford-upon-Avon </LOCATION> this weekend.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0150EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-MissSaigon     09-21 0483</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Miss Saigon,0495</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mixed Reviews Follow ``Miss Saigon'' Ovation</HEAD>
<HEAD>By MATT WOLF</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The new show `` Miss Saigon'' received a rapturous ovation at the Theater Royal, <PERSON> Drury </PERSON> <PERSON> Lane </PERSON>, followed by decidedly mixed early reviews for the first major musical set mostly in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. `` For all its frenzied breast-beating, this is a show with about as much heart as the Tin Man in ` The Wizard of Oz,''' <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Osborne </PERSON> in The <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> wrote of the musical, which updates the tragic tale of <PERSON> Puccini </PERSON>'s `` Madame Butterfly'' opera to the Vietnam War. <PERSON> Lea </PERSON> <PERSON> Salonga </PERSON>, an 18-year-old Filipino making her acting debut in the West, and Welsh actor <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryce </PERSON> star as a young Vietnamese girl, <PERSON> Kim </PERSON>, and her cynical pimp, The Engineer. Both yearn for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> _ she to escape her war-torn country, he to exploit what he refers to sardonically in a second-act showstopper as `` the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> dream.'' <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowman </PERSON> plays the American GI who weds <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> in 1975 prior to the fall of <LOCATION> Saigon </LOCATION> only to leave her for a new life, and a new <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> bride. The story reaches its fatal climax in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> in 1978, with the implication that innocence, as embodied by <PERSON> Kim </PERSON>, can not be reclaimed. <PERSON> Salonga </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pryce </PERSON> both received cheers from the black-tie audience Wednesday night that gave `` Miss Saigon'' an eight-minute standing ovation. But alongside the applause came concerns about the hype, with some wondering whether this was n't another in a series of effects-heavy, overhyped British productions that substitute impressive mechanics for meaningful emotion. Said The <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Osborne </PERSON>: `` It gives the impression of having been cynically concocted _ with lavish high-tech decor as the most important ingredient _ merely to fill theater seats.'' <PERSON> Lester </PERSON> <PERSON> Middlehurst </PERSON> in Today newspaper wrote: `` There's more to a musical than the -LRB- money -RRB- it cost <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON> <PERSON> Mackintosh </PERSON> to create such stunts as landing helicopters on stage and building giant statues of Ho Chi Minh ... `` Both these staging coups received extensive advance publicity in the British press and elicited more applause than most of the musical numbers. Problems installing the 22-foot statue of <PERSON> Ho </PERSON> <PERSON> Chi </PERSON> <PERSON> Minh </PERSON>, reported to weigh almost two tons, had led to the cancellation of the first two previews Sept. 4 and 5. But the opening night proceeded without technical difficulty. Budgeted at $ 4.65 million, `` Miss Saigon'' will most likely withstand any critical slights. Its advance sale to date is almost $ 8 million, and a Broadway opening is tentatively scheduled for late autumn, 1990, with director <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hytner </PERSON> repeating his <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> assignment. `` Miss Saigon'' marks another commercial hit for millionaire producer <PERSON> Mackintosh </PERSON>, whose shows, besides `` <LOCATION> Les </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Miserables </LOCATION>,'' include `` Cats'' and `` The Phantom of the Opera,'' two internationally successful <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Webber </PERSON> musicals. But the producer said in a pre-opening interview that he is forsaking mega-musicals for a while to turn his attention to <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>'s upcoming film version of `` Les Miserables.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0119EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AircraftExplosion     09-21 0151</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Aircraft Explosion,0155</SECOND>
<HEAD>Aircraft Explodes at Eielson AFB</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FAIRBANKS, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> tanker aircraft exploded and burned Wednesday at <ORGANIZATION> Eielson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, killing two people, <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> officials said. Five people aboard the KC-135 tanker were treated for minor injuries, along with two base firefighters, said Sgt. <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> LaDoucer </PERSON>. The aircraft was destroyed. The plane apparently was taxiing to park when the explosion occurred at about 3 p.m. <PERSON> LaDoucer </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Eielson </ORGANIZATION> public affairs office was notified at 5 p.m. that the fire was out. Five of the seven people aboard were crew members, and the other two were military passengers, he said. Names were withheld until relatives could be notified. <PERSON> LaDoucer </PERSON> said an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> board will investigate the cause of the crash and probably will release findings in several months. The aircraft was part of the 168th <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refueling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Squadron </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Eielson </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0210EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TheAgeof?     09-21 0604</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-The Age of ?,0619</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gathering of Intellectuals Searches for `Metaphor for Our Times'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN GALVIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It was billed as a gathering of world-renowned intellectuals tackling the loftiest of subjects and perhaps coming up with a metaphor for our times. But while participants in the modestly named <PERSON> Conversazioni </PERSON> on Culture and Society considered changes in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bloc </LOCATION>, the influence of religion in world events and cultural illiteracy, the larger assignment proved elusive. `` Everybody was satisfied but no final metaphor, alas, emerged,'' said <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, chief columnist for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION>. In an introduction to the conference, <PERSON> Claudio </PERSON> <PERSON> Veliz </PERSON>, a conference host, noted such past `` eloquent and economical'' tags as `` Roaring 20s,'' `` Neo-Gothic,'' and even `` Cold War,'' but lamented that `` today we are encumbered with ` post-industrial' and ` post-modern,' usages as illuminating as ` post-life' is for death or ` post-oats' for porridge. <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, one of many academics, historians and others who joined a debate of world issues, did not seem defeated by the group's failure to write a tag line for the closing years of the 20th century. `` The whole idea is that we thrash out these things,'' he said. The third annual conference, held this year at <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, brought together such thinkers as former presidential advisor <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Schlesinger </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Cambridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> professor <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Gellner </PERSON> and noted French historian <PERSON> Emmanuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Ladurie </PERSON> to work on `` A Metaphor for Our Times.'' The conference invited about 60 top thinkers. Several papers were presented Sunday and positions taken on the best name for the present era. During dinner discussion groups and public presentations, the participants defended and attacked each others reasoning. The papers were revised and a final session was held Tuesday night. `` I do n't think the idea of the metaphor was ... built into the idea. It was just a way of saying, ` What do we think of our condition?''' <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> pointed in his presentation to the drug epidemic, the collapse of form in the arts and `` the old certainties vanishing and nothing being put in their place'' to coin `` The Age of Disorder.'' The points he raised provoked considerable discussion and, he said, a degree of accord, particularly his position that cultural literacy would someday return. ` I had said that our time is the only one that would in fact try to define itself,'' he added. `` Obviously any era, the ` Dark Ages,' the ` Age of Enlightenment,' is not called that when it happens. We're the first age to try and define itself right now, rather than waiting for history.'' American economist <PERSON> Walt </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostow </PERSON> talked of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>'s plans for dropping border restrictions in 1992 and offered `` The Age of Regionalism. <PERSON> Schlesinger </PERSON> gave an overview of how the world became what it is, while <PERSON> Ladurie </PERSON>'s presentation was non-political and more abstract, dealing with the `` nature of the world,'' <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Veliz </PERSON>, a professor at <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trobe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Melbourne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, focused on the domination of the English language and English culture throughout the wolrd. He noted how soccer, or English football, is played throughout the world. He also displayed a group photograph in which <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s late leader <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeni </PERSON> and his fellow ayotollahs wore jogging shoes. <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Botsford </PERSON>, <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> correspondent for the Independent in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, said one series of discussions focused on the fact that 15 years ago no one would have predicted that religion would affect politics in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, or that Islam and fundamentalism would dominate headlines. `` Religion came in a startling second to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and really was talked about a great deal,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-USAirCrash-737Glance     09-21 0119</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-USAir Crash-737 Glance,0127</SECOND>
<HEAD>With AM-USAir Crash</HEAD>
<HEAD>A Thumbnail Sketch of the Boeing 737-400</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 LENGTH: 119 feet, 7 inches. WINGSPAN: 94 feet, 9 inches. ENGINES: Two turbofan jets built by <ORGANIZATION> CFM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, a joint venture of <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and the French industrial consortium <ORGANIZATION> SNECMA </ORGANIZATION>. CAPACITY: Pilot, co-pilot and up to 146 passengers and flight attendants in typical mixed-class configuration, or up to 168 in charter configuration. RANGE: Up to 2,879 miles. HISTORY: Part of the 737 family of jets, the smallest jets made by the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. The first of the twin-engine, short-to-medium-range 737s flew on April 9, 1967. <ORGANIZATION> Piedmont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, which merged with <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION>, was the first customer to get the 737-400.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0246EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CleanAir Bjt   09-21 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Clean Air, Bjt,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Panel Defeats Emission Averaging Proposal</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A `` very upset'' auto industry predicts many more recalls will result from the swift collapse of a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration plan to let carmakers meet pollution targets by averaging vehicle emissions. A <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee removed the averaging plan from the president's clean air bill Wednesday, in a unanimous voice vote that shocked a standing-room crowd that expected a closely divided tally. The vote means the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> bill would require each car sold in this country to pass anti-pollution requirements for hydrocarbons, carbon monoxide and nitrogen oxide. Current law has the car-by-car requirement, but the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plan would make the standards tougher to meet. <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> MacCarthy </PERSON>, of the auto industry's <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vehicle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said the new standards would be too tough for each car to meet after they're driven for several years. The industry _ and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ wanted to allow some engine classes to flunk the requirements, while other classes would meet them with room to spare, resulting in an overall pollution reduction after the emissions were averaged. <PERSON> MacCarthy </PERSON> predicted that once an engine class began regularly failing emissions tests, the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> would order massive recalls for repairs. Subcommittee Chairman <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, D-Calif., the chief proponent of eliminating averaging, said the concept would simply allow more dirty cars on the road `` Averaging provisions would cause more pollution,'' he said, because emissions from cars failing to meet the standards would not offset the gains from autos bettering the requirements. The subcommittee vote had a bizarre quality, because the two chief sponsors of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> measure _ Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Mich </LOCATION>. and <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lent </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION> _ vigorously defended averaging at the outset of debate But as one subcommittee member after another argued averaging was a bad idea misunderstood by the public, the defense stopped. The voice vote was taken with only `` ayes'' heard, and nobody sought a roll call to record individual members. Rep. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON>, D-Ill., sponsor of the anti-averaging amendment, said it may be possible to work out a modified averaging proposal later But <PERSON> MacCarthy </PERSON> said the averaging idea `` suffered a mortal wound.'' `` We are very upset by the removal of the averaging provision,'' <PERSON> MacCarthy </PERSON> said. `` It takes away our flexibility to deal with some very severe requirements in the bill.'' After the vote, <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, the powerful chairman of the full <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> who moments earlier defended averaging, told reporters that it `` appears existing law is working satisfactorily'' without averaging, and that if the administration wanted the concept it could impose it without legislation. Asked why averaging was needed, he said, `` I did not advocate that particular point of view.'' <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenberg </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s assistant administrator for air programs, said the averaging idea was devised in the White House and not by <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>. But <PERSON> Rosenberg </PERSON> said he had no indication that <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON> had any reservations. `` We did n't give any signals'' that the administration was willing to drop averaging, he added. `` I was surprised. I did not expect this would happen.'' Current law requires auto and light truck exhausts to meet a standard of 0.41 gram per mile for hydrocarbons such as unburned fuel, 1 gram per mile for nitrogen oxides and 3.4 grams for carbon monoxide. Cars sold in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> must meet even tougher standards. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> legislation would make the 49-state standards 0.25 gram per mile for hydrocarbons, 0.7 gram for nitrogen oxides and leave carbon monoxide unchanged at 3.4 grams. Today's exhaust limits represent reductions of 96 percent in hydrocarbons and carbon monoxide and 75 percent in nitrogen oxides from the uncontrolled cars of the 1960s and earlier. But environmentalists note that cars are still the main contributor to urban smog and argue that they account for 50 percent of cancer deaths due to toxic emissions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0208EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Frank     09-21 0559</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Frank,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Frank Won't Resign Pending Ethics Investigation</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> says it would be `` a great mistake'' and `` cowardly'' to resign in the midst of a scandal over his involvement with a male prostitute. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Democrat broke two days of public silence on his case Wednesday to declare his resolve to ride out the scandal, at least until the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee completes its inquiry into the case. He disputed reports that <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and congressional leaders were urging him to step aside in order to save them further embarrassment and risk partisan damage. `` I have n't been asked by anybody to resign,'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said. `` No one has been urging me to resign.'' A leading ally of <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, meanwhile, backed off plans to draft and circulate for the signature of <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> colleagues a statement supporting <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s desire to stay in office through the ethics probe. Rep. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Moakley </PERSON>, D-Mass., dean of <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s home-state <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> delegation, had planned such a statement But his press secretary, <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Moakley </PERSON> decided press attention has been so negative for <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> that it was `` better to do nothing.'' `` He's not running away from <LOCATION> Barney </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, a five-term <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> member and leading liberal in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, is an acknowledged homosexual who has come under scrutiny since admitting last month that he had an 18-month relationship with male prostitute <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON>. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> admitted paying <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> for sex, then hiring him as a driver and personal assistant. <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON>, who went public with his allegations last month, contended that he operated a prostitution ring out of <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> apartment with <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s knowledge. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> denied knowing of such activity and said he threw <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> out when he learned of it. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> asked for the ethics committee review, heading off a certain request by opponents. `` I think that resignation would be a great mistake,'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said. `` It would cut off the ethics committee process, and I think that would be a cowardly and inappropriate way to proceed. `` There are things that I did that I should not have done, that I've apologized for, and I will submit to the judgment of the ethics committee,'' he said. `` There are other things that I've been accused of that I have n't done that I want to be able to rebut, and the ethics committee is the place to do that.'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> also responded to a partisan attack leveled by House Republican Leader Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> of </PERSON> <PERSON> Illinois </PERSON>, who suggested that <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> was benefiting from a double standard that judged him less harshly, either because he was a liberal or because the allegations involved activity with another man rather than a woman. `` I do n't think it's fair to suggest the ethics committee of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> would be imposing a double standard. They've been very tough in the past. So I think that's just an inaccurate accusation,'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said. Over the weekend <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION>, long an editorial supporter of <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, called on him to resign. Democratic National Chairman <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> on Tuesday acknowledged that `` pressure is building'' for <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s resignation but said the ethics investigation should go forward. Asked if he was hurting the party, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> responded: `` At this point I think it's important to have the ethics process go forward. Then, people can make judgments after that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Cambodia 1stLd-Writethru a0701 09-21 0692</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cambodia, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0701,0712</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Precede KOMPONG SPEU</HEAD>
<HEAD>Vietnam Begins Pullout From 11-Year Cambodian War</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES thruout with final withdrawal beginning. No pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER ENG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SIEM REAP, Cambodia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With a commander waving flowers in the lead, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> on Thursday began a pledged final withdrawal from an 11-year war against guerrillas it could n't eradicate despite superior firepower. Vehicles carrying thousands of soldiers bearing rifles rumbled out of this northwestern province after a band played pop music and thousands of Cambodians threw the troops flowers and flags in a government-organized ceremony. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> says it is conducting a six-day withdrawal of its last 26,000 troops from Siem Reap and several otehr areas of the country. But guerrillas charged that <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> was faking the troop movement and actually hiding and disguising its troops. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> invaded <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> on Christmas Day 1978 and within two weeks toppled the fanatical <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> regime, a former <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> comrade that had launched bloody attacks on the Vietnamese border. During its four-year rule, the Pol Pot-led <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> killed hundreds of thousands of Cambodians as it tried to turn <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> into an agrarian commune. At the height of its conflict with <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> guerrillas, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> had 200,000 men in the country, according to Vietnamese officers. They say it began annual partial pullouts in 1982 and that 55,300 Vietnamese died fighting the Cambodians, including 25,000 in 1977-78. The invasion also brought economic blockades by non-Communist countries that kept <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> one of the world's poorest counties. With the collapse of peace talks in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> last month, the pullout would leave the Vietnamese-installed <ORGANIZATION> Phnom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Penh </ORGANIZATION> government fighting three guerrilla groups backed by <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> and other countries. Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Huol </PERSON> <PERSON> Savorn </PERSON>, commander of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>'s 4th <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Region </ORGANIZATION>, said he expected a major guerrilla offensive after the pullout of the some 10,000 soldiers of `` Front 479'' from Siem Reap, <LOCATION> Battambang </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Oddar </PERSON> <PERSON> Meanchey </PERSON> provinces. These are among Thai border provinces the guerrillas have been strongly contesting for years. `` They are going to fight a lot'' to try to occupy border areas before striking inland, he told reporters. `` But they will not be able to achieve this,'' he said `` With the equipment that they have, they can only carry out hit-and-run attacks.'' The <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> talks failed to agree on international monitoring of the troop movement, and the only official foreign observers seen in Siem Reap were from <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and its close allies <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the main source of arms for the war. Of the absence of Western observers, Soviet delegate and <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> official <PERSON> Genrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Kinreed </PERSON> said `` it was astonishing why they insisted -LRB- on international monitoring -RRB- but did n't come.'' His four-member team was led by <PERSON> Suleimenov </PERSON> <PERSON> Oljas </PERSON>, member of the Supreme Soviet, or parliament. About 50 journalists from non-Communist countries watched the troop movement. The Cambodians bade the soldiers farewell in a two-hour ceremony on the rain-soaked gravel road outside a kindergarten built by Vietnamese soldiers. Banners expressing sadness at the troops' departure and hopes for continued Vietnamese-Cambodian `` solidarity'' were raised by groups of students, soldiers, and schoolchildren wearing red kerchiefs _ the `` young pioneers'' of the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Cambodian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. They sweated under a hot sun that charged in just after a morning mist lifted. On a wooden stage with the military officers, four <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monks in flowing saffron robes chanted prayers for peace. Cambodian and Vietnamese officials took turns with speeches that denounced the `` Pol Pot genocide'' and defiantly claimed the guerrillas can not take any territory. Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Khieu </PERSON> <PERSON> Anh </PERSON> <PERSON> Lon </PERSON>, commander of Front 479, hugged a <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> commander in front of a blue banner displaying the national emblems of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s yellow star and <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>'s Angkor Wat temple. A young pioneer gave him her kerchief while three women in traditional costumes presented a bouquet of flowers. The general walked down the muddied road, picked up a young boy, and climbed into his weather-beaten U.S.-made jeep to begin the withdrawal. The Vietnamese troops, whose intervention triggered fighting that killed tens of thousands of people and split almost all <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> into two hostile camps, waved yellow and purple flowers as they disappeared down the road.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0249EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Alzheimer'sDisease Bjt   09-21 0594</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Alzheimer's Disease, Bjt,0612</SECOND>
<HEAD>Unusual Protein in Skin May Help in Alzheimer's Diagnosis and Treatment</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A protein found in the brain of Alzheimer's patients has been located elsewhere in their bodies, and that may lead to better diagnosis and treatment of the disease that afflicts 2 -LCB- million Americans The protein deposits appear in several tissues, including the skin and intestines, indicating they may come from an unknown substance that circulates in the blood, said <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Selkoe </PERSON>, co-director of the Center for <ORGANIZATION> Neurologic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diseases </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Brigham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. If so, finding ways to block delivery to the brain may help in fighting Alzheimer's disease, he reported today. But he said it is too early to know if such an approach would be useful. And another scientist said the research provides only suggestive evidence for the idea that the protein deposits come from a blood-borne source. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Drachman </PERSON>, chairman of the medical and scientific advisory board of the <ORGANIZATION> Alzheimer </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, also said it is unproven that the protein's appearance in the brain plays any role in causing Alzheimer's. Nonetheless, he called the study `` a very important advance'' in knowledge about the protein, which is called amyloid. <PERSON> Selkoe </PERSON>, who is also associate professor of neurology at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, reported the findings in the British journal Nature with colleagues <PERSON> Catharine </PERSON> <PERSON> Joachim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hiroshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Mori </PERSON>. Even if no circulating substance is involved in the protein deposits, the work suggests that doctors may one day be able to confirm an Alzheimer's disease diagnosis by taking skin samples, <PERSON> Selkoe </PERSON> said in an interview. <PERSON> Drachman </PERSON> said data from the study suggest such a test would be unreliable, but that perhaps the accuracy can be improved. Alzheimer's disease attacks the brain and produces progressive impairment in memory, thinking and behavior. It kills more than 100,000 Americans a year. No cause or cure is known. Doctors now have no standard biological test to confirm the diagnosis in a living patient. They can only rule out other possible causes, including treatable ones, for suggestive symptoms. A standard feature in the brain of Alzheimer's victims is a large number of spherical neuritic plaques, composed partly of the amyloid protein. Scientists do not know whether the plaques cause the disease or simply result from it. Brains of Alzheimer patients also contain deposits of amyloid alone, which is what the new study found in other tissues, <PERSON> Selkoe </PERSON> said. Eight of 11 Alzheimer patients showed patchy amyloid deposits in the skin, subcutaneous tissue or intestines, with suggestive evidence of such deposits in two others. Three of 26 people without Alzheimer's showed the deposits, with two showing equivocal evidence. The three with deposits were at least 77 years old. <PERSON> Selkoe </PERSON> noted that elderly people without Alzheimer's also can have plaques in the brain, although they have fewer plaques than Alzheimer patients. The findings imply that the amyloid deposits either are created independently at multiple sites in the body or derived from some substance that circulates in the blood, he said. <PERSON> Selkoe </PERSON> said he favors the latter idea. Other kinds of amyloid come from such a circulating precursor, and some newly found deposits were in or near blood vessel walls, much as they can appear in the brain, he said. Nobody has yet identified a circulating substance that can be demonstrated to give rise to the form of amyloid linked to Alzheimer's, <PERSON> Selkoe </PERSON> said. He also said further study is planned to see if skin sampling might be useful to confirm a diagnosis of the disease.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0206EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CatastrophicCare     09-21 0357</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Catastrophic Care,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Administration Asks Congress to Keep Catastrophic Care</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is supporting efforts to retain catastrophic medical insurance for retirees amid growing indications that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> may bow to pressure to repeal the program. `` Catastrophic meets a very real need in protecting senior citizens against financial ruin'' as a result of an illness, Secretary of <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. Although some adjustments may be needed, he added, `` repeal would be a big mistake.'' But leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> acknowledged Wednesday the number of lawmakers who will vote to repeal the program outright is growing. Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, an author of the program and chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> probably will vote for repeal. Democratic leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> agreed to allow a repeal vote next week when the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> considers a <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> plan for keeping catastrophic care but scaling the program back. The program, the largest expansion ever of Medicare, is under attack from two groups of retirees: those who already are covered by a catastrophic plan, including federal retirees; and higher-income older Americans who object to paying for coverage for those at the bottom of the economic ladder. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said that although the administration prefers no changes in the program, it would support a modification backed by <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders of both parties. That proposal would eliminate coverage for most prescription drugs; scale back coverage of physicians' fees, and reduce the surtax on higher-income retirees that pays for most of the program. `` We want to do everything we can to preserve the core benefits'' in the program, <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> told the committee. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON>, R-Mo., said <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> should repeal the program and consider a replacement as part of an overall national health strategy Sen. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, said any discussion of repeal should include recognition that `` people's lives are at stake.'' Repeal, he said, would amount to `` denying somebody the right to get an operation in a hospital and allow them to live ... without going bankrupt.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0253EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TightenedSecurity     09-21 0468</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tightened Security,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Security Measures Are Legacy of Pan Am Bombing</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Pan Am Fine Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Transportation officials believe new security rules brought on by the explosion that destroyed a Pan American airliner over <LOCATION> Lockerbie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, make flying <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> carriers in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> as safe as possible. `` Nothing is 100 percent, but we try,'' said <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrar </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, which ordered security procedures tightened after the Dec. 21, 1988 bomb blast that killed 270. `` The airlines are doing a lot,'' said <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Neale </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, an industry group. `` We spend a half billion dollars a year on security.'' The new rules imposed by the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> since the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> 103 explosion include a requirement that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airlines operating in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> X-ray or physically search all checked luggage. A certain percentage of the luggage is searched by hand. The new <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> regulations apply only to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> carriers. Air carriers operating in and out of 40 high-risk airports are required to make `` a positive passenger-baggage match,'' designed to ensure that no piece of luggage gets on an airplane unless the passenger who checked it is also aboard. And the installation of automatic devices for detecting explosives in checked luggage has begun, with the first installed at <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> John </LOCATION> <LOCATION> F. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. The Thermal Neutron Analysis Machine costs $ 750,000 to $ 1 million. `` We have issued a rule requiring airlines to provide devices like this and have them installed in 40 airports here and abroad within 1 -LCB- years,'' <PERSON> Farrar </PERSON> said. Asked whether the explosive-sniffer could have detected the bomb hidden in a radio-cassette player which blew the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 airliner apart, <PERSON> Farrar </PERSON> said: `` We are confident it could have caught it.'' <ORGANIZATION> ATA </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Neale </PERSON> was not so sure. `` It's hard to say,'' he said. `` We still do n't know for sure exactly what happened there. It's like a moving target, you are constantly readjusting.'' Airline security originally was designed to counter hijackings of planes, mainly to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. `` Now, it's an entirely different threat, it's more sabotage than hijacking,'' said <PERSON> Neale </PERSON>. `` Defenses have to be changed and the new requirements are intended to do that.'' There is no single answer to terrorism, he said. `` The idea is to set up a new series of roadblocks.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airlines are frustrated, he said, because there is a perception among the traveling public that flying a foreign carrier is safer. But, he said, `` the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> carriers are the only ones physically inspecting and X-raying all checked luggage now.'' Overseas airlines, he said, use the `` profile'' system in which added attention is paid to a passenger who has behavior patterns or matches statistical data characteristic of hijackers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NightStalker Bjt   09-21 0709</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Night Stalker, Bjt,0740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ramirez Convicted of 13 Night Stalker Slayings</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto LA9 of Sept. 20</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Note language in next-to-last graf.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDA DEUTSCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> cooly flashed a sign of the devil and muttered the word `` evil'' after jurors convicted him of all 13 murders and 30 other felonies in the 1985 satanism-tinged `` Night Stalker'' rampage. The glum, shaggy-haired drifter refused to stay in the courtroom when jurors returned their verdicts Wednesday after 22 days of deliberations. The jury found that <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> was the devil-worshiping `` Night Stalker'' who left satanic symbols at some murder scenes and forced terrified victims to `` swear to Satan'' as they suffered unspeakable assaults. Husbands were murdered in their beds and wives were raped beside the dead bodies. One victim's eyes were gouged out. The verdicts came four years after the killings terrified many Californians and more than a year after the trial began. When <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> was caught, it was by angry residents who ran him down and beat him. <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, listened to the verdicts on a speaker in a nearby cell. As he was taken from the courthouse while wearing sunglasses, <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> flashed photographers a `` devil sign,'' extending his index and little finger. Asked what he thought about the verdicts, the 29-year-old <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> said only: `` Evil.'' The trial's finale came despite a juror's slaying, which had threatened to halt the case during deliberations. In a silent courtroom, <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Tynan </PERSON> and clerk <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> spent more than a half hour reading the jury's thick book of verdicts. The word `` guilty'' echoed again and again. <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> was convicted of all charges, including rape, sodomy, oral copulation, burglary and attempted murder. In addition, the jurors found 18 special circumstances existed, making it possible to impose the death penalty. In one of the murders, the panel reduced a charge of first-degree murder to second degree, a decision the prosecutor praised as `` sophisticated.'' The victim in that murder, <PERSON> Tsai-Lian </PERSON> <PERSON> Yu </PERSON>, was dragged from her car on a street and shot to death, indicating a lack of premeditation. <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> still faces an attempted murder charge in <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> and a murder charge in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. His status in those cases will be decided after sentencing in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> case. <PERSON> Tynan </PERSON> scheduled the penalty phase of the trial to begin Sept. 27. The same jury will decide the sentence. The judge forbade the jurors from talking about the case. `` We're going to try to save his life,'' defense attorney <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said of the penalty proceeding. `` We will try to convince the jury that he should not be executed.'' The defense had argued <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> was a victim of mistaken identity, that the victims were too traumatized to remember their assailant's face <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> characterized <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>' reaction to the verdicts as `` kind of stoic.'' <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said he would appeal, citing the juror's slaying as one reason for overturning the conviction. On Aug. 14, juror <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Singletary </PERSON> was found beaten and shot to death. Her live-in boyfriend confessed to the killing in a note written before he committed suicide. The slaying was not related to the case, but defense lawyers unsuccessfully asked for a mistrial, arguing that the killing had made the other jurors prejudiced against <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>. Relatives of three `` Night Stalker'' victims were in the packed courtroom and listened somberly to the verdicts. Outside court, Deputy District Attorney <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Halpin </PERSON> said, `` I'm satisfied that certainly the jury considered the evidence very carefully and rendered appropriate verdicts.'' But he added, `` I'm not going to be relieved until its over, and it's not over yet.'' He said he would urge jurors to impose the death penalty. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> conceded that the most powerful evidence against <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> came from attack survivors who wept and sometimes shouted at the defendant as they recalled their ghastly ordeals from the witness stand. `` You son of a bitch, why did you kill him?'' cried one woman who witnessed her husband's slaughter. `` I gave you everything you wanted. ... What's wrong with you? ... He was such a nice man.'' Through it all, <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> sat slumped in a chair, occasionally smirking and once laughing as a foreign-born witness struggled to describe her rape.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0253EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     09-21 0048</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0052</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Wednesday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 01; 03; 05; 13; 18; 30.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto Game: 02; 03; 22; 33; 40; 50. Supplementary 20.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 3-8-3; 6-8-8-5; 2-3-1-7-2; 2-6-3-1-1-2.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0257EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CropInsurance     09-21 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crop Insurance,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Crop Insurance Most Equitable Way to Aid Farmers, Report
Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The federal crop insurance program needs improvements, but it is a better way to provide disaster aid to farmers than emergency loans and direct payments, a congressional report says. And a government commission says some changes could be made immediately in the crop insurance program to boost farmer participation beyond the current 25 percent. The program needs to be simplified and made more responsive, and the administration could be improved, <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Classen </PERSON>, co-chairmen of the Commission for the Improvement of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crop </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Program </ORGANIZATION>, told a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on Wednesday. A <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> report said the federal government spent $ 17.6 billion between 1980 and 1988 assisting farmers who lost crops because of drought or other natural causes. About $ 6.9 billion of that was direct assistance, $ 6.4 billion came through emergency loan programs and $ 4.3 billion was spent to subsidize crop insurance. However, the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said the crop insurance program is a more equitable and efficient way to provide aid to farmers. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said its investigation showed that most farmers do n't buy crop insurance because they are used to having <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> come to the rescue with special assistance whenever there is a major crisis. For example, $ 4 billion in direct payments were made in 1988 by emergency act of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> because of the severe drought, said the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION>. Rep. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> English, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., who chairs the subcommittee on conservation, credit and rural development, said 65 percent to 70 percent participation in the crop insurance program is needed to make it work `` We can not continue to do this,'' English said, referring to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' ad hoc approach to agricultural disasters. `` The costs are too high.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Harman </PERSON>, of the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION>, said that in examining disaster assistance programs, his agency found that direct payments or emergency loans can result in different treatment for similarly affected disaster victims. `` In contrast, the terms of compensation under crop insurance are determined before a disaster occurs and therefore, crop insurance provides farmers equitable assistance more consistently,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> also found that crop insurance, because it is consistently available, allows farmers more flexibility in long-range planning. `` We recognize that the crop insurance program has had a history of management problems that, in the short term, makes it difficult to justify the current crop insurance program as the sole source of disaster assistance to farmers,'' said <PERSON> Harman </PERSON>. He said <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> should provide a transition period if it decides to rely exclusively on crop insurance for disaster assistance. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Classen </PERSON> testified before the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on conservation, credit and rural development. `` The commission believes that many changes to effect immediate administrative improvements in the program can be made under existing law by the secretary of agriculture and the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crop </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Classen </PERSON>. `` These changes would foster increased participation by farmers.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0309EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-IceCurtain     09-21 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ice Curtain,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Seeks Soviet Reforms on Ethnic Groups</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-US-Soviet, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American ethnic groups view the U.S.-Soviet meeting that starts today as a means of seizing on Kremlin reforms to lobby for such causes as Baltic independence, Jewish emigration, easy travel for Eskimos and Armenian rights. Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> and Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> are to sign an agreement Saturday to shatter the so-called `` Ice Curtain'' that has divided the Yupik and Inupiat Eskimos of <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> since the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> forbade travel across the <LOCATION> Bering </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION> in 1948, administration and congressional sources said. `` The Arctic winds that pass through are becoming warmer, beckoning others to join in chipping away at the ice curtain,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Murkowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, hailing the promised agreement. The well-being of other ethnic groups in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is far less certain. Jewish, Armenian and Baltic organizations were pressuring the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration to use the <LOCATION> Baker-Shevardnadze </LOCATION> session to discuss many of the same issues dealt with at a stormy <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> meeting that ended Wednesday in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> passed a resolution urging Soviet nationalities, including the Lithuanians, Estonians and Latvians of the Baltic republics, and the Armenian majority of the troubled <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION> enclave, to curb their demands for political independence in return for greater economic autonomy. Six senators led by Sen. <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, have introduced a measure urging <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to transfer authority over <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, from which it is separated by a narrow band of <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION>. Armenian-American groups took out newspaper advertisements this week urging <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> to raise the issue with <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> when they meet in <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hole </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, this Friday through Sunday. Baltic-American groups were planning similar steps. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> never has recognized the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> annexation of the Baltic republics at the close of World War II, and on Tuesday Baker advanced that policy a step further by urging independence for those people. `` It's been the position of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for some time that we do not recognize the incorporation of the Baltic states into the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. `` We do not seek to foster, nor would we profit from, instability in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. So we'd like to see a peaceful move toward independence for the <LOCATION> Baltic </LOCATION> states.'' Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> signaled a more outspoken White House stance on the Baltic in a <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> interview on Sept. 9. `` Clearly, every event triggers a response. And if there's a negative event toward the <LOCATION> Baltic </LOCATION> states, I would imagine there would be a negative response,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. Neither he nor other administration officials have specified what steps they would take if the Kremlin cracks down. <PERSON> Viktor </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakas </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Lithuanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, a Washington-based emigre group, said, `` I see this as a step. I think that circumstances have forced the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration to take a stand.'' A bipartisan group of 24 senators, headed by <PERSON> Sens </PERSON>. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>, D-Mich., sent a public letter to <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> on Wednesday saying that `` the vice president's recent statements to the press in support of the Baltic peoples' struggle for independence must be reemphasized in face-to-face meetings with Soviet officials'' The administration also came under some pressure, and some applause, this week from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> on Soviet Jewry, which pointedly met in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Tuesday, two days before <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>'s arrival. `` It looks as if most Jews who want to leave the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> may now leave,'' Deputy Secretary of State <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> told the conference. `` That does not mean we are dropping the refusenik cases that are still unresolved. We will continue to work on them until every single case in which an emigrant permit is unjustly denied has been satisfactorily resolved,'' he said, stressing that the issue would be raised at the meeting this week. The Jewish group, in response, endorsed a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration plan to shift to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> consulate in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> the job of screening of Soviets seeking to emigrate to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The change is needed to cope with the rapid rise in emigration, which promises to top the record level set in 1979.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ArlingtonAshes     09-21 0326</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Arlington Ashes,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Panel OKs Burial of Ashes at Arlington</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT GREENE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Legislation advancing in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> would give more veterans the opportunity to choose <ORGANIZATION> Arlington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cemetery </ORGANIZATION> as their final resting place. The national military cemetery, on a hillside directly across the <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, is expected to run out of casket space in 2020. The columbarium, where urns are stored, is expected to be full in 2029. But a bill approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Wednesday would allow veterans who qualify for burial at <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION> to choose an unmarked burial for their ashes. Although the legislation does n't specify the site, one proposal would have ashes buried in one area with the names of all the deceased carved on a large memorial stone. The problem of dwindling space at <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION> has been growing as the average age of the veterans population has grown older. The number of veterans over 65 years old total nearly 6 million now and should be nearly 9 million by the turn of the century. Until restrictions were enacted in 1967, any honorably discharged veteran could be buried at <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>. Roughly 190,000 people are buried in the 612-acre cemetery. The disposal of ashes in a common area would be strictly optional and would not use any space that could be used for caskets, the bill says. The ashes, which would not be placed in urns, would be buried under sod or in small hole. An aide to Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., the bill's chief sponsor, said the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> would insist on a fitting ceremony and interment to address concerns `` that it may seem like a mass grave. In another action, the committee approved legislation to create a World War II memorial in or near the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, paid for by donations and taxes. No decisions have been made on size, location and design of the memorial.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0317EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Powell     09-21 0490</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Powell,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nominee Says Defense Cuts Would Undercut Treaty Talks</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cuts <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is considering in the fiscal 1990 budget for various weapons programs could derail a U.S.-Soviet agreement on reducing strategic arms, says President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s nominee to be chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION>. Gen. <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, whose career has spanned two combat tours in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> to a stint as former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s national security adviser, won unanimous approval Wednesday from the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> to be the nation's top military commander. If confirmed by the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> would succeed Adm. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Crowe </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, who is retiring Sept. 30. During the nearly three-hour confirmation hearing earlier Wednesday, <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> told members of the committee that political changes in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> should not lead to wholesale cuts in the Star Wars program, land-based nuclear missiles or the B-2 stealth bomber. House legislation would cut $ 502 million from the $ 1.1 billion request for the multiple-warhead, rail-based MX missile and eliminate all $ 100 million earmarked for the single-warhead, truck-mobile Midgetman. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> plan `` would completely unhinge our START -LRB- Strategic Arms Reduction Treaty -RRB- negotiating position.'' House and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> conferees met behind closed doors Wednesday to craft a final version of the defense bill. According to congressional sources who requested anonymity, senators rejected a revised <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> proposal calling for full funding of the MX missile and elimination of the Midgetman. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>'s remarks came one day after Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> announced the administration will no longer insist on elimination of land-based mobile missiles, conceding the issue had complicated negotiations. The Soviets have two mobile missiles while the administration is asking <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to fund the MX and Midgetman. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> also told senators that scaling back the program to build 130 of the bat-winged B-2 bombers, considered the most expensive plane in history at $ 530 million a copy, would force the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to change its stance in arms talks with the Soviets. `` Without the B-2, we no longer have the same START position that we did for the last several years and I believe it most unlikely that there will be a treaty up here to ratify,'' he said. `` We would have to go back quite a ways and renegotiate a different type of treaty,'' he said. On other issues, <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said: _ He supported using the armed forces in the war on drugs and in response to terrorist attacks _ The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> should not unilaterally cut troops in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and other overseas posts to convince allies to share more of the defense burden <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said he was `` very hesitant'' to do it to satisfy current budget demands. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> is commander of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> MacPherson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga </LOCATION>. He was hailed by Democrat <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and Republican <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> as likely the best appointment <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has made.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0223EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Soviet-PowerPlay Bjt   09-21 0685</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Power Play, Bjt,0709</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gorbachev Shows Renewed Strength in Politburo Shake-up'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL PUTZEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s swift elimination of a quarter of the ruling Politburo, including two leading conservatives, demonstrates his political strength just as doubts about his staying power were gaining currency in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The dramatic power play, executed on the eve of Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>'s meeting with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> at the White House, served to counter suggestions that the Soviet president had been weakened by increasing public frustration with worsening economic conditions and heightened ethnic tensions. The shake-up could be seen as strengthening <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>'s hand as he seeks to revitalize the arms control process during talks with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. With successive moves during the last year to consolidate his power, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> may now have broken high-level resistance and opened the way for sweeping changes that reformers say are needed if <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s program of economic restructuring is to shake the country out of the doldrums. The party's <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> meeting that shuffled the makeup of the party's Politburo also handed <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> an early opportunity next year to use a party congress to reach further down into the party apparatus to shake out bureaucrats blamed for smothering reform. The president and <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief successfully instituted glasnost, which has brought more open criticism and debate. He overhauled the political system to encourage competitive elections and representative oversight of government operations. And his `` new thinking'' in foreign policy has done much to dispel what he called his country's `` enemy image'' abroad. But <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms so far have failed to relieve the grinding economic hardship that has left consumers frustrated by barren cupboards and empty store shelves at a time when their own media show them the practical pleasures of living in the comparatively wealthy West. Outspoken reformists in and out of the recently elected <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> Deputies have said the transition from the old system of central planning and control to a new market economy requires radical stripping away of bureaucratic control over supplies and prices. But <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> so far has talked about such steps without actually taking them. With the retirement of veteran Ukrainian party boss <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON>, 71, the 58-year-old <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is now the only member of the Politburo elevated to the ruling body during the regime of the late <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>. <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> has long been regarded as one of the most conservative forces in the leadership but too entrenched in his home republic for <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to unseat him. Former <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Viktor </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chebrikov </PERSON>, 66, another of those retired Wednesday, also was regarded as a conservative anchor who opposed many <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> reforms. The departures left one prominent conservative, <PERSON> Yegor </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>, in place. But both <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON> have taken pains to express their support for each other while often disagreeing on policy. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> installed two of his own men, Gen. <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kryuchkov </PERSON>, the new <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> chief, and <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Maslyukov </PERSON>, who heads economic planning, as full members of the Politburo, which now numbers 11 men. The retirements also included non-voting member <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Solovyev </PERSON>, who thus became the first member of the party's top leadership to fall after being defeated at the polls. <PERSON> Solovyev </PERSON>, who was rejected by the voters of <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> when he ran unopposed for a seat in the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, already had been removed as <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> party chief. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> opened the way for graceful retirement from the top echelons of <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> power when he paid public tribute to <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON> as he relieved him of the presidency a year ago. He continued that practice Wednesday. When it was announced that <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON>, <PERSON> Chebrikov </PERSON> and <PERSON> Viktor </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nikonov </PERSON> were going out on pension, <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> thanked the three Politburo members warmly for their `` many years of fruitful activity'' in the party. Departures from the party leadership were once accomplished only by death or abrupt ouster into instant obscurity or public disgrace.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Putzel </PERSON> is chief of the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> bureau.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890921-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-21-89 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bloch     09-21 0373</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bloch,370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Suspected Spy's Wife Resigns Foundation Job</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
