<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0034EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Opera     01-28 0349</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Opera,0363</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: No PMs Planned</HEAD>
<HEAD>Met Performs Season's First `Don Carlo'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Grand opera as grand as it gets filled the Metropolitan Opera stage in the first performance this season of <PERSON> Verdi </PERSON>'s `` <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlo </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON> conducted on Friday night, bringing out the opera's orchestral glories and at times threatening to drown out the singers But the soloists had powerful lungs and the large chorus soared vocally over the orchestra. Tenor <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Shicoff </PERSON> was <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlo </PERSON>, betrothed to <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON>, daughter of the French king. After they meet and fall in love they discover that a treaty has given her to <PERSON> Carlo </PERSON>'s father, <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>. The fallout from that, plus the Spanish Inquisition, is plenty for an opera, even one as long as `` <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlo </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Shicoff </PERSON> began too loud but quickly settled into a well-sung, feeling portrayl. <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON> sang <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON>. Her voice is beautiful, smooth and large. At the end of the third long scene, singing to a banished countess, Miss Price sounded tired. But she recovered before Act 2. Both <PERSON> Shicoff </PERSON> and Miss Price were singing their parts for the first time at the Met. Baritone <PERSON> Bernd </PERSON> <PERSON> Weikl </PERSON> as <PERSON> Rodrigo </PERSON> was more brusque than subtle. He sounded as though he were pushing for volume. <PERSON> Ruggero </PERSON> <PERSON> Raimondi </PERSON>, his voice very focused, was impressive as King <PERSON> Philip </PERSON>. <PERSON> Tatiana </PERSON> <PERSON> Troyanos </PERSON>, always a favorite of the Met audience, was fine as Princess <PERSON> Eboli </PERSON>. She did n't wear the eye patch that was part of the costume when this production was new 10 years ago. The real <ORGANIZATION> Eboli </ORGANIZATION> wore one but since `` Don Carlo'' is more drama than history and the stage eye patch was distracting, Miss <PERSON> Troyanos </PERSON> was better off without it. The auto-da-fe scene was lavish with clerics, onlookers and flag wavers. The royals and Grand Inquisitor -LRB- Jan-Hendrik Rootering -RRB- wore black trimmed in gold. <PERSON> Hei-Kyung </PERSON> <PERSON> Hong </PERSON> sounded celestial as the celestial voice. However, in this staging, she welcomed those burned into heaven before anybody lighted the fire. `` <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlo </PERSON>'' was last sung at the Met during the 1985-86 season.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0034EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AlaskaCold     01-28 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Alaska Cold,0275</SECOND>
<DATELINE>ANCHORAGE, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With record temperatures dipping to 75 degrees below zero and <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s cold snap showing no sign of breaking, the governor activated the state's emergency services agency Friday. `` We're not declaring an emergency, yet,'' Gov. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowper </PERSON> said in a brief radio address, but added that the weather forecast offers little hope for a break. `` There's no end in sight, apparently,'' he said. <PERSON> Cowper </PERSON> said Alaskans in need of help should first call local authorities, and then to the state agency, which will be open 24 hours a day. He also announced a toll-free number for the agency. The community of <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON> posted the state's low of 75 below zero overnight and <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> diesel-powered trucks were among the few vehicles still operating. The temperature warmed to minus 59 by 11 a.m. Friday. <LOCATION> Sitka </LOCATION>, with the high of 43, was tropical by comparison. <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s largest city, <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION>, shivered through a high of minus 15 Even light winds pushed wind chill factors to minus 100 degrees or colder. Schools were closed in some towns, including <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Nenana </LOCATION>, and some <LOCATION> Kodiak </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> communities used exchange agreements to replenish household heating fuel by obtaining supplies from well-stocked schools. Maj. Gen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaeffer </PERSON>, adjutant general of the <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, said rural Alaskans who have been in the state for awhile likely stocked up on essentials before the winter. The Brim Frost military exercises involving some 20,000 troops from <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and elsewhere continued, despite the cold, but temperatures below 80 degrees could force the war games to shut down, said <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Canterbury </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CowboyPoets     01-28 0561</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cowboy Poets,0582</SECOND>
<HEAD>Smile When You Recite That, Partner</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM CRANDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ELKO, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 300 cowboys in town this week ai n't here to rope steers or whoop it up at a saloon. No sirree, mister, these folks are the biggest bunch of prose-packin', simile-slingin', versifying-est cowboys you ever saw, and they're here for the annual Cowboy Poetry Gathering. It ai n't all dogie doggerel, and you better smile when you quote'em, pardner. Upwards of 7,000 visitors have jammed this northeastern <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> town of 13,000 for the five day-event, which began Wednesday and wraps up Sunday. The area's 40 motels have been booked for weeks. Ten-gallon hats dot Railroad Avenue and Commercial Street, and more spill out of the Branding Iron Bar. The crowds have come to hear the cowboys recite their bunkhouse ballads, sing soulful songs and tell of hard and high times on the range. The activities have filled every available meeting place in town, from the <ORGANIZATION> Elko </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> to the bar at the <PERSON> Stockman </PERSON>'s Hotel. The buckaroos don fancy duds for the gathering _ broad-brimmed Stetsons, silver buckles and handmade pointy-toed boots _ but their sunburned faces, calloused hands and faraway gaze tell their own tales of hard and solitary lives. One such poet is <PERSON> Waddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, who runs 2,000 head of cattle on a ranch near <LOCATION> Jiggs </LOCATION>. Before he came to the gathering, he had to make sure there was enough hay put out and find a baby sitter for his five children. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> began writing verse during long winters on the range. Like most cowboy poets, he did n't show his work to many people because poetry did n't quite fit the cowboy image. But the first cowboy poetry gathering five years ago brought a lot of sagebrush scribes off the prairie. One of <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>'s poems tells the plight of <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Dell </PERSON>, found behind a bar with his throat cut. When `` they got him to the hospital he would n't sign a complaint against the fella who done it because he was a friend of his.'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Baxter </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, who will sing and tell stories at the Saturday night finale, are big guns in the cowboy entertainment world. They have ben on `` The Tonight Show,'' and Black's records are available anywhere Western music is sold. Black, a veterinarian from <LOCATION> Brighton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, earns a six-figure income from his performances. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> McMahan </PERSON>, a singer, songwriter and poet from <LOCATION> Bellvue </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, who claims to have the only yodeling dog, recited this verse at one gathering: `` Two things in life that I really love, That's women and horses, of that I'm sure of. So when I die please tan my hide, And tool me into a saddle so fine, And give me to a cowgirl that likes to ride, So in the hereafter I may rest, Between the two things that I love the best.'' Besides stage performances, there are informal sessions for greenhorn poets, singers and storytellers. Exhibitions display handmade saddles, bits, spurs and other cowboy regalia. <PERSON> Tara </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarty </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Folklife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, which coordinates the gathering, said one of the center's biggest challenges is keeping the cowboy poetry pure. That's why they've come up with an ironclad rule: Every participant has to make a living on the range. No `` drugstore cowboys'' allowed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     01-28 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0026</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 17; 18; 22; 23; 24; 38.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     01-28 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0087</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 17; 18; 22; 23; 24; 38.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 4-1-6-0.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 03; 04; 09; 17; 22; 34.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 10; 14; 17; 25; 34; 45. Bonus: 22672.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 01; 13; 18; 33; 41; 46. Supplementary 12.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 3-5-4-5.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 9-3-2; 0-3-5-8; 4-4-3-2-3; 2-6-3-9-2-4.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Baghead     01-28 0211</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Baghead,0216</SECOND>
<HEAD>He Forgot to Cut Eyeholes in Mask, Prosecutor Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DERIDDER, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A robber who forgot to cut eyeholes in the plastic garbage bag he wore in a botched motel holdup was sentenced Friday to 25 years in prison. <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Creswell </PERSON>, 51, was sentenced to concurrent terms for that holdup and two other armed robberies which he admitted, according to <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Milam </PERSON>, assistant district attorney for Beauregard Parish. <PERSON> Milam </PERSON> said <PERSON> Creswell </PERSON> previously was convicted of four other armed robberies in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Creswell </PERSON>'s undoing <PERSON> Milam </PERSON> said, occurred in May, a week after he held up a clothing store twice last May. <PERSON> Milam </PERSON> said <PERSON> Creswell </PERSON>, knife in hand, was pulling a garbage bag over his head as he entered the lobby of the Park Motel, according to a statement by motel clerk <PERSON> Monica </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroud </PERSON>. <PERSON> Creswell </PERSON> suddenly realized he forgot to make eyeholes in the bag, the clerk told police. `` So he started pulling on the bag to try to put some holes in it,'' <PERSON> Milam </PERSON> said. `` And then he asked for the money. `` Well, she said she was n't going to give him any money and he left,'' <PERSON> Milam </PERSON> said. The clerk called police and <PERSON> Creswell </PERSON> admitted to the botched holdup when he was arrested minutes later, <PERSON> Milam </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PresidentialPorkRinds     01-28 0337</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Presidential Pork Rinds,0344</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chicago Pork Rind Processor Going for Capitol Gains</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRENDA C. COLEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One of the largest processors of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s favorite snack food is hoping to catapult the product to national popularity with a new brand: Presidential Pork Rinds `` I'll be on the street with them next week,'' <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Connor </PERSON>, sales manager for <ORGANIZATION> Evans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, said Friday. The brand is a take-off on the president's well-known predilection for the porcine product. A gift jar of pork rinds replaced <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s crystal container of jellybeans on the table at <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s first Cabinet meeting this week. `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has done wonders for pork rinds here this year,'' said <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Rickard </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Snack </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> `` My view is, ` Skins are in. Pork rinds in'89,''' said <PERSON> Connor </PERSON>, who sent 3,000 pounds of the crunchy, puffed snack to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for the presidential inaugural ball and in return got an invitation to the event. Pork rinds are fried pieces of hog skin, cooked in hog fat, stored in pellets for 30 days and fried again for 60 seconds in oil heated to 400 degrees, `` at which time they explode like popcorn,'' <PERSON> Connor </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Evans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION>, with a plant on <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s south side, supplies pork rind pellets to Dallas-based <ORGANIZATION> Frito-Lay </ORGANIZATION>, the largest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> marketer of pork rinds, and other companies, <PERSON> Connor </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> handles about 50 million pounds of pork skin annually. He said pork rinds compare favorably to peanuts in fat content and contain a high percentage of protein. Nutrition experts, however, say the salted snack has enough calories, fat and sodium to make it a poor food for all but the most physically active people with the lowest cholesterol levels. The <ORGANIZATION> Snack </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said pork rind sales totaled $ 195 million in 1987, a figure dwarfed by sales of potato chips, which enjoyed $ 3.8 billion in sales in the $ 8 billion salty snack food market.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--StanfordCats     01-28 0158</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Stanford Cats,0161</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stanford University to Go After Stray Cats</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STANFORD, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 8,100-acre <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> campus has apparently became a popular place for cat owners to abandon their pets, officials say. An estimated 1,500 cats live in storm drains, steam tunnels and just about everywhere at the school, says <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Fong </PERSON>, the manager of grounds and custodial services. <PERSON> Fong </PERSON> said the university will place traps that wo n't hurt the animals, beginning Feb. 22. Cats with identification tags will be released, but those that appear to be untamed will be taken to the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clara </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> animal shelter. <PERSON> Fong </PERSON> said animal lovers often feed the cats. `` They're not tame enough to just take home,'' he said. `` There are some areas that employees do n't want to go into because of the feral cats that are in there. You get a wild cat trapped in a corner, they'll be biting and scratching their way out of there.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-StudentsKilled     01-28 0286</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Students Killed,0296</SECOND>
<HEAD>Saddened Students File By Smashed Car</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OKAY, Okla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The collision of two vehicles that killed three students and a man just 100 yards from the school has brought many in the town together to mourn. Many students stopped by a salvage yard to see the smashed remains of a classmate's car on Friday, a day after three people were killed in the vehicle. School officials in the town 40 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION> called off classes Thursday and Friday. The Rev. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Knox </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Okay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> said there was no easy way to ease the sorrow felt by friends and families of the victims. `` You just touch them. That's all I know, you just touch them. Be available and try to be sensitive and touch them however you can,'' he said. The Rev. <ORGANIZATION> Opal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Large </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Okay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fellowship </ORGANIZATION> said some of the children had attended services at her church in the town of 600. `` It does n't make any difference if they were in our church or not. We feel close to everybody in Okay and we love them and want them to know that,'' she said. The <ORGANIZATION> Oklahoma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> identified the dead as <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Branchcomb </PERSON>, 17, of <PERSON> Wagoner </PERSON>; <PERSON> Stephanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamby </PERSON>, 17, of Okay; her brother, <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamby </PERSON>, 14, of Okay and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Risinger </PERSON>, 56, of <PERSON> Wagoner </PERSON>. <PERSON> Branchcomb </PERSON>'s brother, <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON>, 11, was in stable condition at <ORGANIZATION> Muskogee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. Troopers said the car driven by <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Branchcomb </PERSON> went out of control and collided with the pick-up truck driven by <PERSON> Risinger </PERSON>. Most of the 600 students in the school learned of the accident from the wail of ambulance sirens. A school assembly was planned for Monday morning.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-India-Gandhi     01-28 0664</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-India-Gandhi,0679</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poll Defeat Ominous For Gandhi In Election Year</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RAJU GOPALAKRISHNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The debacle for <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in a major state election this past week was the latest in a series of reverses for the prime minister, who will face his own voter test by the end of the year. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>, 44, had a dream start as prime minister _ his party won four-fifths of the 542 seats in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> in 1984 _ but allegations of corruption, a belligerent opposition headed by a former <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> colleague and successive defeats in state elections raise doubts about his return for a second term. The <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> has lost 11 of its last 18 state elections. The latest defeat was Jan. 21 in populous <LOCATION> Tamil </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nadu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> state </LOCATION>, where it won only 26 of the 234 state assembly seats. `` Gandhi's problem is a failure at the political level,'' said <PERSON> Bhabani </PERSON> <PERSON> Sengupta </PERSON>, one of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s foremost political analysts. `` It's a pity because he came in with a tremendous amount of goodwill and a tremendous amount of promise. In January 1985, the former airline pilot was sworn in as prime minister after his <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> swept the highest number of parliamentary seats ever won by a single party since <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> became independent in 1947. The victory was ascribed mainly to the wave of sympathy for <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> after his mother, Prime Minister <PERSON> Indira </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>, was assassinated three months earlier. But it was helped also by <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s `` Mr. Clean'' image, which sprang from his age and inexperience in what many people saw as the dirty world of politics. His stewardship gave the government an unprecedented honeymoon with the press. Even normally anti-establishment newspapers were enthusiastic. `` The parliamenary election <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> won four years ago ... has created an illusory world for him,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Hindustan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, a usually pro-government newspaper, said in an editorial this week. `` This kind of mandate breeds dangerous smugness.'' The cracks did not appear for almost a year. The first murmurs against <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> began with his inability to solve the lingering problem of a murderous Sikh insurgency in the northern state of <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>. The low point came in 1987, when newspapers claimed the Swedish arms company <ORGANIZATION> AB </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION> paid $ 50 million in bribes to secure a government contract for artillery guns. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> denied involvement. A parliamentary committee cleared the government of complicity, but the allegations persist and are still under investigation. In the midst of the allegations, V.P. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, who had held the defense and finance portfolios in <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s Cabinet, quit the party after building a reputation as a crusader against corruption. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> went on to win a parliamentary by-election as an independent running on a clean-government platform. In the past six months, he has been largely successful in persuading national opposition parties and regional parties to form a national coalition opposed to <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 41-year history, no single opposition party has ever posed a serious threat to the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Instead, the opposition has been splintered among powerful local parties and a vast array of national parties. The only time <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> ever lost a national election was in 1977 when the opposition united after Mrs. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> imposed an emergency and banned political activity. `` If the opposition is united and can present itself as a creditable alternative, then the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Party -RRB- will be in very serious trouble,'' said <PERSON> Sengupta </PERSON>, the political analyst. At least seven parties have joined the anti-Gandhi front, and together they control seven of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 25 states. Last week's polls in <LOCATION> Tamil </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nadu </LOCATION> voted the front's <ORGANIZATION> Dravida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Munnetra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kazhagam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> into power, and the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> trailed a poor third behind another regional party. `` It will be dangerous for the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to believe that what happened in <LOCATION> Tamil </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nadu </LOCATION> was only a regional phenomenon,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Hindustan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said. `` No state is out of the national mainstream. What -LRB- happens -RRB- at the polling booth in <LOCATION> Tamil </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nadu </LOCATION> has also an impact on the rest of the country.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0121EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ConfirmationRdp Bjt   01-28 0562</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Confirmation Rdp, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Panel Gives Approval to Trade Representative Nominee</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> must be ready to use the `` crowbar'' of retaliation to open world markets, says President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s nominee for top <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade negotiator, while <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s choice as housing secretary called the `` appalling problem'' of homelessness his top priority. `` Retaliation can not be the goal of our policy _ in fact, it signals the failure to open foreign markets,'' <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Carla </PERSON> <PERSON> Hills </PERSON> said Friday before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> approved her nomination as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade representative. `` But the credible threat of retaliation provides essential leverage in our market-opening efforts,'' said the former secretary of housing and urban development in the Ford administration. `` Thus, actual retaliation will be used, albeit reluctantly, to preserve the credibility of this threat.'' Pledging to fight to open global markets `` with a crowbar if necessary,'' she said: `` We have to have our agreements enforced,'' she said. `` And where our partners are violating our agreements we must take action.'' The panel was unanimous in recommending <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation of the 54-year-old <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> native to succeed <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>, who has been tapped by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for secretary of agriculture. A confirmation hearing has yet to be scheduled for <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>. Appearing before another <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> panel, former Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, said about homelessness: `` I acknowledge that it is a very severe problem _ it is an appalling problem. It is an emergency problem, and I'm willing to treat it as the highest priority, immediately, of my new leadership at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>.'' The 1988 candidate for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> presidential nomination avoided committing himself on most specific spending questions but did pledge to be an advocate for increased federal efforts to house the poor. He promised to seek full funding of legislation passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to provide emergency shelter for the homeless, called the McKinney Act, and said he favored expanding it in some areas. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said he visited privately with leaders of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>'s riot-torn <LOCATION> Overtown </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Liberty </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> areas last weekend when in that city for the Super Bowl. He said that if confirmed he planned to visit blighted inner cities and places where the homeless cluster. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> banking committee took no vote on <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s nomination, but the hearing was filled with bipartisan praise for the nominee, who is expected to win confirmation easily. A committee vote may come next week, after <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> answers additional written questions. Mrs. <PERSON> Hills </PERSON> sought to dampen concern that she could become vulnerable to conflict-of-interest charges because she and her attorney husband, <PERSON> Roderick </PERSON> <PERSON> Hills </PERSON>, have represented foreign law clients. `` Let me address the question of potential conflicts of interest right away,'' she said. `` There are none.'' Lawmakers seemed satisfied when she promised that she and her husband would divest themselves of any business interests that could present such a conflict. She also pledged to keep hands off cases involving her former clients. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s appearance was interrupted briefly by six demonstrators from the <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Creative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Non-Violence </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> advocacy group for the homeless. Two stood up holding a large sign saying `` Housing Now,'' while they and others shouted and turned on a noisemaking machine. The four women and two men were charged with disrupting a committee of the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and demonstrating within a Capitol building, charges that carry a maximum $ 500 fine and six-month jail term.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DefenseProbe Bjt   01-28 0571</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Probe, Bjt,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Consultant Admits Illegal Political Contributions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three congressmen with defense-related committee assignments say they were unaware of receiving illegal corporate contributions through a consultant who pleaded guilty in the government's investigation of <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> corruption. `` The circumstances of this contribution were totally unknown to me ... and I am returning it immediately,'' Sen. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>, D-Tenn., said in a statement after learning Friday that his campaign had received $ 1,000 illegally Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>, D-Ga., said he was `` extremely upset'' by the news that <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, 76, of <LOCATION> Mineola </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, had given money to his campaign He said he too would send the money back. Between 1982 and 1988 <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> contributed over $ 25,000 to political campaigns at the direction of his consulting client, <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a giant computer company that does work for the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, prosecutors said. Federal election law says individuals may give $ 1,000 in general and primary campaigns, but corporations are prohibited from donating money. <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION> executive, entered guilty pleas to a variety of charges in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Court in the latest development in the Pentagon investigation. Also pleading guilty before <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hilton </PERSON> was <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON>, a civilian purchasing official with the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON>, 52, admitted he accepted bribes in exchange for providing confidential information on pending contracts to consultants and companies. He could face up to 20 years in prison and a fine of as much as $ 500,000. <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> pleaded guilty to four misdemeanor counts of making political contributions in the name of another, namely his client. He could face up to four years in prison and a fine of $ 400,000. Prosecutors said <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> was paid by <PERSON> Sperry </PERSON>, which later merged into <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION>, and was `` asked by representatives of Sperry-Unisys to make numerous contributions in his name.'' Besides the campaigns of <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> also contributed in 1987 and 1988 to the campaigns of Reps. <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>, D-Md., and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ala </LOCATION>., prosecutors `` It angers me that someone would give my campaign illegal money,'' <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> said they knew nothing about the source of the money when it was given. <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON>'s spokesman, <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, said his boss was also in the dark about the contribution <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON>, 55, pleaded guilty Friday to conspiracy to defraud the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and to aiding and abetting in making false statements to the government. He could face up to 10 years in prison and a $ 500,000 fine. <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON>, who first worked for <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION>' predecessor, <ORGANIZATION> Sperry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> suburbs, was involved in a complicated scheme in which $ 2,000 was funneled to the election campaign of former Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., prosecutors said <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON> chaired the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> defense appropriations subcommittee until his defeat last November. Prosecutors said the contractor paid consultants with the understanding that they would contribute an unspecified portion of the funds to political campaigns. In December 1986, <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> collected two undated checks of $ 1,000 each from two men and steered them to the `` <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON> Campaign Committee.'' <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON> repeatedly denied any wrongdoing while he was in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Friday's pleas are part of the federal government's two-year-old investigation into the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s $ 150-billion-a-year procurement practices. The case includes allegations that private consultants, hired by defense contractors, bribed <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials to obtain inside information that gave companies an edge in securing contracts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;Ls     01-28 0579</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;Ls,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Swift Action Needed on Insurance Fund, Congressmen Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are urging President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to reassure savings and loan depositors by swiftly developing a plan to pump more money into the ailing government insurance fund for S & amp; Ls. `` Public confidence is so precarious today that it is imperative that a comprehensive approach be presented soon,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, the second-ranking <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` The exact nature is not as important as the fact that a serious package be presented,'' he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sought Friday to stem nervousness following scattered reports that some S & amp; L depositors withdrew their money after learning that the administration is considering a 25-cent fee on every $ 100 in federally insured accounts. `` The savings and loan deposits are backed by the full faith and credit of the government and they are sound, they are good,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told reporters at the White House. `` I want to assure the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people of that and that's not going to change.'' However, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he has made no decisions on a plan for the <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L problem and would not rule out the deposit insurance fee. `` There seems to be some controversy around it, but that does n't mean that any thinking along those lines should cease,'' the president said Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said in a statement that the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's disarray on the <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L crisis is contributing to a growing nervousness among depositors `` Savings and loans are receiving a heavy run of calls from depositors who are confused and concerned about the reports of a new tax on their deposits,'' <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> said. `` In some areas there have been higher than expected withdrawals of funds.'' <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Wall </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, disputed <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>' assertion, saying it was based on `` an inartful distillation of calls made by somebody on the -LRB- committee -RRB- staff.'' However, in an interview a day before, <PERSON> Wall </PERSON> said: `` There have been cases where they -LRB- depositors -RRB- say, ` I do n't like what I heard on TV, I'm taking my money out.''' <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> board spokesman <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyle </PERSON> said a survey of thrift institutions Thursday night showed `` no outflows of any significance that we can attribute to anything that's been said.'' <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> accused the administration of being `` extremely careless'' in floating the deposit fee trial balloon and called on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to `` take a personal hand in clarifying the administration's proposal. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has been studying the S & amp; L problem since the fall and is expected to present <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> with its recommendations next week. Department officials have been briefing members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on some of the options under consideration, in addition to a deposit fee. Rep. <PERSON> Stan </PERSON> <PERSON> Parris </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>., a senior member of the banking committee, said <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> is talking about borrowing about $ 45 billion, roughly the amount needed over and above the $ 38 billion committed last year, and is examining the full range of options of how to pay it off The laundry list includes using interest on <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> funds that is now paid into the general fund, or tapping the retained earnings of the industry-owned regional <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banks </ORGANIZATION>. Options in the reform package that will accompany any new money include an administrative merger of the fund that insures commercial banks with the <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L fund, as well as additional control by federal regulators over risky activities undertaken by state-chartered S & amp; Ls, <PERSON> Parris </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AirlineCompetition     01-28 0591</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Airline Competition,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study: Above Average Air Fare Increases at Hub Airports</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY MASSEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Air fares since 1985 generally have increased much faster than average at airports largely controlled by single airlines, according to a new government study of those hub operations. `` The present situation at hub airports is intolerable,'' Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON>, R-Mo., said Friday in releasing the study prepared by the <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> He blamed the increases on a lack of competition at some airports in the wake of deregulation of the airline industry in the 1970s. Under deregulation, most airlines have adopted `` hub and spoke'' operations to help lower their costs. The concept involves having flights from smaller airports feed into a central airport, or hub, where passengers make connections for their ultimate destinations. The study found that air fares rose substantially above national averages from 1985 to 1988 at more than a half-dozen hub airports dominated by single airlines: <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Raleigh </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>; and <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. The increases, in most instances, were twice or nearly three times greater than the air fare portion of the Consumer Price Index during the same period. The study looked at average round-trip ticket prices for passengers beginning or ending their flights at the hubs. Fares rose an average of 11.1 percent across the nation from 1985 to 1988, the study said. It said fares for the biggest carriers at two major airports either rose less than the national average or dropped over the three-year period. From 1985 to 1988, according to the study: _ <ORGANIZATION> Piedmont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> fares rose 34 percent over three years at <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, where the airline had 89 percent of the market last year _ <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> fares rose 25 percent at <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>, where the company had 81 percent of the market _ <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> fares rose 27 percent at <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, where the airline had 62 percent of the market _ Northwest fares rose 21 percent at <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, where the airline had 77 percent of the market _ <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> fares rose 35 percent at <LOCATION> Raleigh </LOCATION>, where the airline had 67 percent of the market _ Delta fares rose 26 percent at <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> The airline had 77 percent of the market. _ Delta fares rose 5 percent at <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, where the airline controls 62 percent of the market _ <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> fares dropped 6 percent at <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, where the airline had 80 percent of the market The study focused, however, on Lambert-St. Louis International Airport and the effects of a 1986 merger that made <ORGANIZATION> Trans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> the dominant carrier of passengers in and out of the city <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, disagreed with <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON>'s reading of the report. He said the study did not link the increases to the airline's control of the market at its <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> hub. The <ORGANIZATION> DOT </ORGANIZATION> study found that <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> fares at <LOCATION> Lambert </LOCATION> for non-stop roundtrip travel increased 22.7 percent from the first half of 1985 to the first half of 1988. The airline component of the CPI rose 11.1 percent during the same period. `` I do n't there is any correlation between the fare increases and the hub operation,'' said <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>. He attributed the increases to `` market forces.'' The report did not examine in detail the other airports. It cited the fares at other concentrated hubs only to show that <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION>'s air fares had not increased faster than comparable airports across the nation. However, the study cautioned, `` Hub concentration alone does not explain why fares change or how much they change.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-BushText 13Takes   01-28 0300</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 13 Takes,300-7500</SECOND>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a transcript of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s news conference Friday. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: Harmony and peace in here. -LRB- Laughter. -RRB- First, I sound worse than I feel. But let me _ Q. What's wrong with you? A. A slight cold. But it's been a full week since inauguration. I just wanted to stop by, under our new policy, give you an update. I've been talking this week about ethics, and the emphasis is not, believe me, a fad or some passing fancy. We're going to be hearing more about it, I think a lot more. In broader terms, I'm trying to set high standards for government service _ duty, honor, personal sacrifice for the common good. And I want to assemble a government that the people of this nation can be proud of, that's our goal, that's our mission. We did appoint this week, as you know, a new commission on ethics. We've got two able chairman, vice chairman _ Judge -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Malcolm </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- <PERSON> Wilkey </PERSON> and General <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>. We appointed that commission, started a fresh, constructive dialogue with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on both sides of the aisle. I'm pleased with the way those initial meetings have gone, and so we're ready to roll. I think it's been officially announced that we're going to _ certainly to <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, then on to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, which I'm looking forward to very much. And then also we'll be stopping for a relatively brief stop in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> on the way back from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. We've had other invitations. That's about all we can do. And on a nostalgic basis, needless to say, we're _ <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> and I are looking forward in a very personal way to going back to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. Now with no further ado, I'll be glad to take your questions. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON>?
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-BushText 1stadd   01-28 0328</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 1st add,310</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: questions. Terry?</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Q. Mr. President, you said, before you became president, that you supported <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s decision on a 50 percent pay raise for members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and that you might have something more to say about it once you got to the Oval Office. Most of the polls show that the vast majority of Americans oppose that pay raise. Now you're president. What's your view on that pay increase? A. Well, I did say I supportd it, and I do support it. A raise is overdue; there's no question about that. There are some good things in this. The reform of the honorarium, payments for these speeches, I think is very, very good. I think it's good government. It's a complicated formulation. There are some elements that bother people, including me. But the president did consider all this carefully. He went forward with the commission's recommendation. And that, because of the way it works in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and the ball is clearly in their court, it leaves us with either the commission recommendation or nothing. And so seeing the problems as I do, I still feel that I should not go about undoing the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> decision. Yeah, <PERSON> Helen </PERSON>? Q. Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, your trial balloon on the S & amp; Ls taxing savings and checking accounts has fallen like a lead balloon. Are you dropping that plan? Do you have any other plans in the works? A. In the first place, I think it ` sa little absurd to be commenting on a facet, a possible facet, of solving a problem, when it has n't even come to You're talking about speculating on something that has n't even reached the desk of the president, even as an option, to say nothing of its being a proposal. And so _ Q. _ come from your people. A. Well, as an option, not as a proposal. And I think you're right, there seems to be some controversy around it.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-BushText 2ndadd   01-28 0481</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 2nd add,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: around it.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 But that does n't mean that any thinking along those lines should cease. But, I'm going to reserve comment until I actually have it presented to me. And I expect this is the first of many such things that's going to happen of this nature. I will say this, that the savings and loans' deposits are backed by the full faith and credit of the government. And they are sound. They are good _ dollar good. And I just want to assure the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people of that. And nothing is going to change in that regard. But, in terms of this one idea, let them float it around. It does n't bother me for a lot of ideas to be considered and debated. Q. The reaction is very negative; the public reaction and congressional reaction. Will that enter into your decision? A. Anything I do on savings and loans or when we get into this budget deficit reduction program _ look, I do n't expect it's all going to be sweetness and harmony and light. The minute we get those proposals up there on Feb. 9, I expect we're going to have other firestorms swirling around. But, I have not made decisions on this one. I'll wait till I get all the facts, call them as I see them, and hope that we can convince the American people that that's the way to go. Yes, <PERSON> Brit </PERSON>? Q. Mr. President, you've set a tone of high-mindedness and propriety this week with your emphasis on ethics, also bipartisanship in your discussions with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Beyond those matters of process and tone, sir, what would you like the country and the world to say is the message of your first week in office as to what your administration is about? A. Reaching out to the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. I really am serious about this trying to get more of a bipartisan foreign policy, for example. And though we have n't addressed that specifically in terms of issues, I have addressed it in broad terms to the members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> with whom I've met here and with whom I've met over in the residence. And, so, I'd like to signal an era of real openness with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Look, I know we're going to have conflicts, Brit, and I know we're going to run up against each other. But, I want to start with that approach, and we're going to _ we're in a broad review, as you've heard from my various nominees as they appear before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, on specific areas of foreign policy. But a message would be taking steps to make clear to the congressional leadership that that's what I want to do. The other one, as I mentioned, is trying to set a tone in terms of conflict of interest that I hope will serve us in good stead.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-BushText 4thadd   01-28 0625</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 4th add,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: Yes, Lesley?</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Q. Mr. President, there seems to be some question about just how long your `` no tax'' pledge applies. Is that a one-year pledge, a two-year pledge, a four-year pledge? A. I'd like it to be a four-year pledge. And _ Q. Is it a four-year pledge? A. I'd like it to be a four-year pledge, yeah. Q. Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s been over in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> meeting with the foreign ministers of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> has said, and so has <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON>, that it's too early for <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> to meet with <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>. On what level would it be appropriate for <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> to meet with an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> official? An assistant secretary of state, for example? A. We changed the policy on the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, on dealing with the _ I mean, as change came about in the policy on communicating with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, it was based on their acceptance of three principles. As long as they stay hooked and stay committed to those three principles, we will have, when appropriate, meetings with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. I have n't given any thought at all to what _ what _ when a meeting with the _ Chairman <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> with an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> official, is appropriate. And I would wait to see how we go forward. The point in talking to them is to try to facilitate peace in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. And it seems to me that if there's some logical step that requires high-level sign-off by various participants over there, then, and then only, would it be proper to elevate the meetings to that level. We're just starting. You crawl before you walk. We're just starting to talk to them, because they have _ dramatically, I'd say _ agreed to the _ to the principles that are part of our policy. Q. Let me ask you again in that regard. You said in a wire service interview the other day that you needed to have some foreign policy initiative early in your administration. It seems the Soviet relationship is going on the back burner while you discuss the nuclear force structure, for example. In what area are you going to try to move forward? Central America? The <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION>? Where? A. All of them. But we've got to have a little time. We're not going to let this Soviet thing put us in a mood of _ mode of foot-draggers. We're going to be out front. There's no reason to suggest that all we have to do is react to a speech by the general secretary. I want to take the offense in moving this relationship forward and doing _ taking steps that are in the interest of the free _ freedom around the world, whether it's in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, or in strengthening our alliance. But there's plenty of trouble spots. One of them, as you mentioned, I think _ <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> _ but we need to complete the reviews. But I ca n't tell you, <PERSON> John </PERSON>, which one will become _ where you will see the first major initiative, whether it's going to be the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, whether it's going to be <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. We've got problems, of course, that afflict the whole continent and other continents in this Third World debt problem; and then, of course, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. But, no, I do n't want to play defense, and I do n't want to look like we're foot-dragging, just waiting around to _ to, you know, let others set the agenda. But, prudence is the order of the day. And when you're gunning for something as important as a bilaterally supported policy in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, it does take a little time. I've only been here less than a week. Yes?
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-BushText 5thadd   01-28 0530</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 5th add,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: week. Yes?</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Q. As you know, the minimum wage has been frozen for even longer than congressional pay raises. Since you support a large increase in pay for the most affluent 1 percent of the country, will you favor pushing for an increase in the minimum wage, which would benefit the lowest income groups in the country, as part of your promise in your inaugural address to reach out to all the people? A. I would _ I've always said that my position on minimum wage is that I would want it linked to a training wage, to a differential of sorts, so that you do n't throw people out of work by raising the minimum wage. And I'm not one who has felt that the minimum wage is the key to economic prosperity for the lowest _ people on the lowest end of the economic spectrum. But, as I indicated _ a certain flexibility on that question. And again, I'll wait for <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, who takes office in the next couple of days, to come in with her recommendations. <PERSON> Saul </PERSON>? Q. If I could just follow. Do you _ are you _ A. How are we going to _ wait, let me ask you to stop the proceedings _ do n't take it out of their time. How are _ what would be the fair and noble way to handle follow-up questions as we do these things? Would it be good to have them or not have them? Q. There should be two follow-ups. Q. Yes. One follow-up. Q. There should be one follow-up. Q. There should be two follow-ups. A. But then you've cut out _ but then if we do it, everybody else does n't get a chance to ask their question, becuase I'm about to pull a rip cord on this thing. -LRB- Laughter. -RRB- No seriously, how do we _ I want some advice _ Q. Come back every day! -LRB- Laughter. -RRB- Q. _ if you make a statement and not have anyone follow it up _ it just hangs out there. Q. Suppose you do n't answer _ A. You mean my first answer is less than precise _ -LRB- Laughter -RRB-. Q. On occasion. A. On occasion _ -LRB- laughs -RRB-. No, but I'm asking, we've got to get _ I'd like to get _ because here we are, all of these _ Q. _ to follow up _ A. _ women and men who have to let that the <PERSON> Leubsdorf </PERSON> area untested on the question. Q. One follow-up. Q. The standees. Q. We'll just have to be more precise. A. And the standees have gotten no time at all. Q. _ a true follow-up. A. Instead of yet another question, you mean. Q. You decide. When you think somebody's playing games with you, say, `` I'm sorry.'' A. I'll just say I've already answered that. Then what happens? -LRB- Laughter. -RRB- <PERSON> Saul </PERSON>? Q. Wait a minute _ where's my follow-up? A. -LRB- Laughs. -RRB- You did n't have a follow-up. Q. _ gets a follow-up then. A. All right. I've already answered that one. Yes, <PERSON> Saul </PERSON>? -LRB- Laughter. -RRB- No. Go ahead _ -LRB- laughter -RRB- _ go ahead. Q. I yield to <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> first.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-BushText 6thadd   01-28 0645</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 6th add,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: Owen first.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 A. OK. Q Are you concerned, from the standpoint of perception, that you're supporting a pay raise for a high-income group and not pushing on an equal basis for a lower-income group will give the public's perception that you're lobbying for a wealthy sector of the country? A. No, I'm not concerned about that perception because _ but I am troubled by certain aspects of the proposal, as I think I've indicated _ the pay raise proposal But, we're down to the crunch here. The recommendation's up there on the hill _ it's either yea or nay. I mean, it's one way or another. But, I do n't think that would be fair at all. I think the main thing in terms of the question you raised _ jobs. How do we continue to create jobs, keep it going? And I've given you one ingredient that I think has to be a part of the _ of any consideration of the minimum wage, but as I've indicated, I'm flexible on how that should be accomplished But, I'm not sure that one could make a connection between the minimum wage and more employment. I think you can _ if you raise the minimum wage without this difference, so I think you will reduce employment. So, I think the main thing in the area you're talking about is, how do we increase economic opportunity? And maybe there is a way to do it, but I do n't think it would be fair to say, when you take a pay raise that affects a tiny fraction _ judges and congressmen _ that that has a broad economic impact on the country. I've expressed some concern about it, but for other reasons. Yes? Q. Do you agree with Senator Tower's testimony, in which he does n't seem to believe that the SDI program as envisioned by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is likely? And if you do agree with it, can you expand on that, please? A. No. I think I should wait and see a little more what <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> means. My position has not chaned on SDI. Q. Which is? <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> said that he does n't believe that a large-scale SDI would protect the population as envisioned by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> _ A. I better _ yes? Q. Do you disagree with that? <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Saul </PERSON>, before I comment on Tower's testimony, I better read it. If he's talking about a shield so impenetrable that you have no _ that that eliminates the need for any kind of other defense, I probably would agree with that, certainly short-run. But I better cover by waiting until I see what he said. The standees _ two standees alone. Q. Thank you. The first action taken by your secretary of state was to order the boarding up of embassy in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. Does that indicate that this administration and this country then has no influence with the rebels, and you are now fearful of chaos and massacres there? And to what extent did you discuss this with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> the other day? A. I did not discuss it with him the other day. And what it indicates is a prudent policy to protect a handful of American life. And it's a step that other countries have taken in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. There is _ certainly I think we'd all agree _ there is uncertainty about what follows. I'm convinced the Soviets will continue their withdrawal, and well they should. But it is simply a prudent way in which to protect life. I think we've had meeting after meeting with Afghan rebels, and there's no question in their mind how we feel about, say, a Soviet presence in that country. But I think there's a lot of uncertainty, and there's enough uncertainty that a secretary of state was taking prudent action in this regard.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-BushText 7thadd   01-28 0736</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 7th add,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: this regard.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Q. What role do you see for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> after the Soviets withdraw, in that country? A. Catalytic role for helping bring about stability, hopefully in a government where the people have a lot of say, and it wo n't be easy. Yes, <PERSON> Tom </PERSON>? Q. Mr. President, I'd like to try the pay raise one last time. As you just said, it's not just for members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and it's not just for federal judges. It's for a lot of senior officials in the government, political appointees. You also have told some reporters in recent days that you're concerned about the long-term pension implications of all these larger salaries. Would n't you be happier with a pay raise that's a little bit less rich than 50 percent? A. I do n't have that option to get into that now. I have, I think, expressed myself in the past on separating out some of these categories. But we're not _ regrettably, you're never dealing with just the way I would like it to be. And so I'll just leave it that what _ my earlier statement. Q. Sir, this is a thematic question. You've had a week on the job. Has it been easier or tougher than you expected? Any surprises? And did you find the note in your underwear? A. No note in the underwear. And it's been a good, easy week, and I expect it will change dramatically in the days ahead. But my view is to _ if it were n't for the cold _ `` Smile and enjoy it while you can,'' because I can already sense, you know, looking forward to a little more _ a little more confrontation out there. Q. Have there been any surprises, sir? A. None particularly, no. It _ it _ and I think one of the reasons is that I've been around here in a different role for eight years, and then in and out on other jobs. So it's _ but there's the, still the wonder of it all. I mean, it still feels different, but not surprises. Q. A follow-up, sir! A. You've already a follow-up! Nice try. <PERSON> Rita </PERSON>? -LRB- Laughter -RRB-. Q. Mr. President, there seems to be some brouhaha about the fact that <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>'s not an actual member of the Cabinet, as are the U.S.T.R. and the <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> directors. In light of the fact that you emphasized drugs as an overriding consideration in your campaign, and also that public opinion polls show consistently this is among the top priorities of the public, why is n't he in the Cabinet? And do you foresee that you might change your mind on that? A. No. The reason he is n't in the Cabinet is that I've tried to reduce down the numbers of full Cabinet members. And I think that <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>'s time is best spent not worrying about agricultural subsidies, but _ when we have a meeting on agriculture _ but concentrating on drugs. To the degree there's symbolism that this means I think it's less important, I'd like to knock that down hard. And I have to do that in substantive ways, sitting at his side as we meet with his peers at Cabinet level, making clear to them that I will be insisting on cooperation as he asks for the support of the <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> secretary for military assets on interdiction; as he asks for the support of the education secretary on certain educational initiatives. But the Cabinet rank is there, giving him the standing that I think the job not only requires, but demands, and I think his _ I think the idea of not sitting through Cabinet meetings that have nothing to do with that subject should be the reason that _ a rationale for having Cabinet-level but not being in all those meetings. I've seen _ I'm glad he mentioned this, because I think there's been some feeling, `` Well, that means I'm less interested in drugs. That's not right. I'm not _ I'm very interested in the economic statistics, but our chief of economic advisers is not a Cabinet member, as he has been designated by previous presidents. Our chief of staff, in whom I have full confidence, is not a <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> member, but I think we have a very strong chief of staff set-up. Over here, way up in the window _ an innovative stance.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-BushText 8thadd   01-28 0757</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 8th add,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: innovative stance.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Q. I wonder if I could just touch on the issue of Third World debt. There are many experts who are saying that, if there is any danger for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy, it's in how greatly leveraged it is opposed to terms of corporate indebtedness and Third World debt. And they say that the S & amp; L crisis, for example, is simply a subsumed feature of this. Do you see this as a real problem that you're going to address aggressively? And what kind of steps would you take to overcome the high proportionality of debt to equity that exists in the economy now? A. The question of corporate debt _ the role _ on that one, the role of th White House and the role of the federal government ought to be to do its level best to keep a strong economy. And I do n't believe that it's the government role to assign levels beyond which a corporation ca n't borrow. In terms of Third World debt, we do have a responsibility, and a lot of that's going to be working with the private banks and others, and, again, that's going to be _ we'll have some recommendations. We have to have them pretty soon on that question. That _ I'm not sure I got to the substance of your question there. But I do n't _ separating out those two things. Q. _ in the reported differences that you have with <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON>'s testimony in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> earlier this week with regard to interest rates and monetary policy? A. I'll be honest with you. I do n't think I'm far apart from Chairman <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> at all _ far apart. There may be some differences. He is, because of the plant capacity utilization, he is more concerned about inflationary pressures than I am right now. Seems to me there's an area of difference. But basically and generally speaking, I think we're in _ we're fairly close together Yes? Q. Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, by spending your first week dwelling as you have on ethics, are n't you voicing an implicit criticism of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's record _ ethical record? A. No. Q. Then why else was it necessary to declare `` national ethics week,'' so to speak? A. Because I feel strongly about it. Q. On that _ also on that line, sir? A. No, she's first and then you. Need to cool off on that one. -LRB- Laughter. -RRB- Q. Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, during _ given your strong anti-tax stand in the campaign, why are you allowing Mr. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> to consider as an option for the <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls a tax increase? A. I'm not _ he has thrown out a lot of different possibilities in discussions we've had. We have people that are experts on what a tax is. I would refer you to <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>, who is the head of the <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION>. And he's the guy that defined that very well up there, with the `` duck test'' on the hill. And _ Q. So you do n't think it's a tax? A. Well, I'm just saying I'm not prepared to say what I think on it right now till I hear from it, because the more I discuss it, the more you all go out and say this is something that I'm considering, when I'm not. It has n't come to me yet. But I've been around for a long time, and I do n't remember hearing people talk about the fee that went into covering the <ORGANIZATION> FDIC </ORGANIZATION> or <ORGANIZATION> FSLIC </ORGANIZATION> as a tax. I do n't remember people writing that before. But, I'm not trying to get into the fight anymore right now. I'll be back _ yes, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>? Q. You've mentioned ethics in a number of ways, and you've talked about the value of service. The last few days, we picked up the headlines in the papers, and they've read, `` The president has _ President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> _ has a $ 5 million book deal. He's got a $ 50,000-a-speech deal.'' With all respect for the office and the former president, do you think it's appropriate to cash in on the presidency? A. I do n't know whether I'd call it `` cashing in.'' I expect every president has written his memoirs and received money for it. Indeed, I read that a former president _ was it <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>? <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> got half a million bucks _ that's when half a million really meant something. I mean, you know _ so I think there's plenty of tradition that goes with presidents writing memoirs and being paid for it.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w BC-BushText 9thadd   01-28 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 9th add,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: for it.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Q. But, you've also talked about perceptions. Is there a perception problem here? A. No, because I think there's been a long history of that. And, I do n't think it's ever been challenged as inappropriate. Yes? Q. Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, would you try to clear up the continuing controversy over the reports of disagreements on abortion between your nominee for health and human services and yourself that _ are you in sync? Is he in sync _ A. Yes. Q. _ with you? Does it matter? Do you have to be absolutely in sync as long as, once in office, he would support your position? A. Well, I think that last point is the important point. But, also, we are in sync. And, so, I have a person who has stood in front of you all when I nominated him and said that. And I have no reason to think anything different. Yes? Q. Mr. President, a few moments ago, you talked about, on your no-new-taxes pledge, the idea that you'd like it to be a four-year pledge. And that does appear to be a softening of language from the campaign. I wonder, has anything that Mr. <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> or any of your advisers told you changed your mind about the duration of that pledge _ revenues needed and so on? A. No. That has n't changed my mind _ anything in the last few days of talking like that. Yes? Q. Mr. President, we've been hearing a lot about your position on abortion this week because of Mr. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>. Are you planning any initiatives from the White House related to abortion? Or are you going to wait and see what the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> does, number one? And, number two, as a person who's always, from what we know, had the financial and emotional resources to know that you could raise your children comfortably, do you feel any awkwardness about telling other people, whose situations you do n't know, how they should run their lives? A. Not when it comes to the question of life. I do feel an awkwardness in terms of having been able to take care of my kids when they were sick or raise them properly or something like that; I feel a certain privilege. I feel a certain _ very fortunate in that regard. And I know a lot of people are n't. But, in some _ on this issue, I think we're talking here of principle and I sure would like to put the emphasis on adoption. And that means a broader acceptance of that principle. Q. Are you going to have any White House initiatives or are you going to wait for the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>? A. Oh, wait for _ I think probably wait, but I have been pledged, as you know, to an amendment. But, I'd like to see the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision as soon as possible. Q. Mr. President _ A. One, two, three _ Q. Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> radio report this morning seems to indicate that they are rejecting your statement of a week ago today that good will would beget good will. While you did n't specifically mention <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> by name in your speech, what would your message to them be on relations, and what would your message be to them about helping get the hostages out? A. Well, I would make a broad appeal, transcending <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, to anybody that can be helpful to get the hostages out. Perhaps _ I have n't seen the wire copy, but perhaps they are _ if there is such a story by them, maybe they're saying, `` Look, we're not holding your hostages. And I'd have to say, `` Well, from our intelligence, our information, that's probably correct _ probably correct.'' In terms of the future, there was a period of time when we had excellent relations with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. And I do n't want to _ want to think that the status quo has to go on forever. But I do think that the renunciation of terror in any form, and a facilitating to the degree they can the release of the hostages, would be a couple of good steps they could take.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-BushText 10thadd   01-28 0676</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 10th add,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: could take.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Q. May I follow up, Mr. President? Follow up on that? Q. Mr. President _ A. No, you do n't get to follow his question! -LRB- Laughter. -RRB- <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> _ and then here. Q. Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, reaching out _ Q. You've _ you've spoken frequently about reaching out to blacks, that you want that to be an important goal of your administration. This week, the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> issued a decision that may kill many of the minority set-aside programs that have been so helpful to blacks across this country. Does that concern you? Are you worried about these programs? A. I _ it did n't kill all set-asides, and it did n't kill off affirmative action. I have been committed to affirmative action. I want to see a reinvigorated Office of Minority Business and Commerce. I want to see our SBA program go forward vigorously. And so, I would say that that decision spoke to one set of facts, in <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION> I believe it was. And _ but do n't read in _ I will not read into that a mandate, to me, to stop trying on _ on equal _ equal employment, and on affirmative action generally. Yes? Q. You said during the campaign, Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, that you would roll back taxes on capital gains if elected. Now, as you begin to look at the budget numbers, is that going to be a promise you can keep when you make your submission to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, or is that no longer affordable? A. I hope it _ affordable! It gains you revenue. And we've got a big argument with some people about that, they do n't want to go back and look at what happened in 1978 _ it gains revenue. Now I know we've got all kinds of bureaucracies around here that do n't agree with that. But that was discussed in the campaign. I'm convinced it will bring in additional revenue and, in the process, create additional jobs for men and women. So I would like to see it a fundamental part of whatever we do. Now, if your question is: can I get it done? _ that's something else again. But I want to see it done. We _ there was an issue in that campaign where there was a clear difference; that was one where there was a clear difference. The opposition was saying: My opponent is proposing something that will cost the taxpayer $ 30 billion. And I'm saying it will create jobs. And, indeed, I've seen estimates by intelligent people thinking it will bring in revenues in excess of $ 4 billion. And so I'm going to keep pushing that because I know it's right, and I ran on it. Yeah, <PERSON> Robby </PERSON>? Q. Mr. President, once more on the pay raise. You've portrayed yourself as a late-comer on the issue who has no real power to affect it. But, a point of fact, I believe that you do have the power, if you want to, to limit the pay raises that would otherwise automatically go to your own staff. Will you do that, number one; and number two, do you think both houses of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> ought to vote on it? A. Well, I think in a _ I think in the best of all worlds _ Wait till I get _ wait till I _ Q. It's a trick question, sir. -LRB- Laughter -RRB- A. -LRB- Laughs -RRB- He's a fair-minded guy! -LRB- Laughter. -RRB- No, I _ I think our _ our _ our chief of staff has tried to hold the line on increases in hiring people. And I think you're all aware of that. And I think he's done a very good job on it. I do n't know how the law affects the staff in terms of automatic _ automatic increases. But there's a nice little problem that if you do go forward with automatic increases, is there any money? That has to be appropriated in some way. So we'll have to talk about what we'll do. What was the other part of it?
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-BushText 11thadd   01-28 0601</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 11th add,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: of it?</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Q. Do you think both houses of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> ought to vote on this issue? A. In a _ in a _ in a perfect world, in a world where you were starting over, yes, I'd have to say I do. But that is n't the proposal that's up there. And it's all or nothing. And in my view, I've told you where I come down on that. We've got time for a couple more because it's 38:57.89, 58.80 _ this thing is buzzing away up here. -LRB- Laughter. -RRB- Yes? Q. Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, a few minutes ago, on the answer concerning the hostages, you indicated that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> was probably not holding the hostages. Did you mean to say that we believe that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> exercises no control over the people who are holding the hostages? A. No. I mean to say, they are not holding the hostages. Do they have any control? We can get varying degrees of intelligence on that, various assessments as to how much control they have over <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> or these families or whoever it is. And also, you've got different _ different groups involved in the holding of these hostages. But, what I _ no, I'm glad to get a chance to clarify it, because unless the information I have is wrong, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> itself, the government, is not actually holding these _ holding these people. And if they were, you know, I would just reiterate my view that the way to improve relations is to let them go, give these people their freedom _ they did n't do anything wrong. Q. And a follow-up, Mr. President. Do we believe that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> can exercise influence to gain the hostages' release? A. I think they can have influence. Yes, <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON>? Q. You inherited a budget from President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> that calls for something like a 2 percent real increase in defense spending. In the campaign, you seemed to think that maybe zero real growth in defense spending would be adequate. Given the deficit pressures, do you think there is some room for reduction in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> defense budget to fund some of the other programs, like the <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L problem that you've got to worry about A. We are wrestling with that problem right now. I'm committed to a strong defense. I did say certain things in the campaign that fit into our flexible freeze concept. And so, we will _ I will have to address that with some detail on Feb. 9, and I will. We have time for just a couple of more. Q. Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, in the back _ A. This is 36 minutes here. Q. Mr. President, you said the other day that _ Q. Just say `` no.'' Q. _ education was the main way for dealing with drugs. A. Yes. Q. Is n't that a backing away from your commitment on drugs? Certainly, there are other things than education to deal with the problem. A. Absolutely. And I was surprised when I read that some interpreted what I said as _ for suggesting that interdiction is not important, or cooperation with foreign governments in terms of eradication at the source is not important. They are very important! My point is, we are not going to solve the problem of drug use in this country through interdiction alone, through cutting off the supply alone. And a larger component of the solution lies in education and on _ and in that whole demand side of the equation, law enforcement at home, these things. Last one, here. Q. -LRB- Inaudible -RRB-. A. Look, this is a follow-up.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-BushText 12thadd   01-28 0592</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 12th add,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: a follow-up.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Q. Mr. President, how much money are you going to spend on drugs? If it's the major problem that you say it is, certainly education just one very small part of it? A. It's not a small part, it's a tremendous part. And the federal government can spend some on it and the private sector has got to spend enormous amounts. The media has done a good job in terms of pro bono advertising. And that's got to be enormously stepped up. So it _ look, it has got to be a tremendous increase, not only on the money, but the emphasis on the educational side. I do want to see _ find a way to step up the total funding on anti-narcotics, and I want to get _ I'll go back to what I said on <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, because this question of Cabinet rank and whether that shows less of an interest in narcotics troubles me. You will see me side by side with <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> on _ in putting the proper emphasis from the Oval Office on my determination to do everything in the government's power, federal government's power, to eliminate this scourge. Last one! <PERSON> Carl </PERSON>? Q. Is there any _ Q. Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, you and your aides have talked about the need for a fast start, and you've talked all week about ethics and about bipartisanship. And yet, the week has been marked by unexpected controversies over Dr. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>'s views on abortion and then the <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L issue, which is sort of a self-inflicted wound. Are you finding it harder to control an agenda here than you thought you might? A. No, no. I'm just getting a preview of coming attractions and it's been lovely. -LRB- Laughter. -RRB- And it's going to change and I know it. But, no, I think it's been a wonderfully harmonious week, and these are just little ripples on the surface of an otherwise calm pond. Q. You're not concerned that if you just talk about things that _ I mean, everyone approves of ethics, just about everyone approves of bipartisanship, is n't there a danger of people saying that, you know, there's not much meat behind the words? A. There's a danger of that, yeah, but people are _ realize that you've been here four days of this week, or five, this is the fifth day, in office after the weekend, and they understand that in things like the foreign policy area, that it's prudent to have a review; they understand that we've got to get our people in place. And so I _ there's some danger, I guess, <PERSON> Carl </PERSON>, but I would n't say an overwhelming danger. I mean, we just go for it. If we just sat around and did nothing except be pleasant to people on the hill or something, why, I could expect that would grow a little old for you all. But, we're going to _ we're going to _ I think we did _ we've set a certain tone and a certain outreach, and then go forward when _ as soon as these specific proposals start up there, whether it's on education or anti-narcotics or on foreign policy or on some bilateral foreign visitor coming in, there will be plenty of _ plenty of time for controversy and plenty of time for lively debate on substance. But I would simply say that will follow and follow pretty soon. Thank you all very much. The press: Thank you.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>End Bush Text _ 13 Takes</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-Bush-Glance     01-28 0577</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush-Glance,570</SECOND>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here at a glance are highlights from President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s first formal news conference Friday:
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>S&amp;L PROBLEMS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he was not disturbed by the flap in response to reports that he was considering a fee that would be charged to <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L depositors to raise money for government efforts to deal with failed institutions. `` It does n't bother me for a lot of ideas to be considered and debated. ... I have not made decisions on this one. I'll wait till I get all the facts, call them as I see them, and hope that we can convince the American people that that's the way to go.'' He added: `` I will say this, that the savings and loans' deposits are backed by the full faith and credit of the government And they are sound. They are good _ dollar good. And I just want to assure the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people of that. And nothing is going to change in that regard.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>CONGRESSIONAL PAY RAISE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said of the Reagan-proposed $ 45,000 pay raise for judges, members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and other high-ranking government officials: `` I do support it. A raise is overdue, there's no question about that.'' He added, `` I am troubled by certain aspects of the proposal ... but we're down to the crunch here. The recommendation's up there on the <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> _ it's either yea or nay. ... Seeing the problems as I do, I still feel I should not go about undoing the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> decision.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>TRIP TO CHINA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Asked about visiting <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> before responding to Soviet Leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s request for an early meeting, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> replied: `` I do n't know what signal it sends in that regard, but let me just remind you that I'm the one who does not believe in, quote, ` playing the Soviet card' or, quote, ` playing the <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> card.' ... It just seemed like an appropriate visit, but not to signal a playing of the card to go one up on Mr. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. There's nothing of that nature in this visit. ... The visit stands on its own and does not have any signaling that should be detrimental to anybody else's interest.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MINIMUM WAGE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> reiterated his position that any increase in the minimum wage should be `` linked to a training wage, to a differential of sorts, so that you do n't throw people out of work by raising the minimum wage. And I'm not one who has felt that the minimum wage is the key to economic prosperity for the lowest _ people on the lowest end of the economic spectrum. But, as I indicated, a certain flexibility on that question. And again, I'll wait for -LRB- Labor Secretary -RRB- <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, who takes office in the next couple of days, to come in with her recommendations.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>THE PLO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said meetings would be held with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> `` as long as they stay hooked and stay committed'' to accepting <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s right to exist, renouncing terrorism and accepting two <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> resolutions affirming the right of all Middle Eastern states to live within secure borders. `` If there's some logical step that requires high-level sign-off by various participants over there, then, and then only, would it be proper to elevate the meetings to that level. We're just starting. You crawl before you walk. We're just starting to talk to them, because they have _ dramatically, I'd say _ agreed to the, to the principles that are part of our policy.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890128-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-28-89 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Vietnam     01-28 0542</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Vietnam,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vietnam Might Open Cam Ranh Bay, Senator Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GENE KRAMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
