<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r e BC-JamesEurope     07-15 0442</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-James Europe,0458</SECOND>
<HEAD>Carnegie Hall Recreates 1912 Concert</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: No PMs Planned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The week in music here has been busy. The Mostly Mozart Festival kicked off in <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, to run until Aug. 26. <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> inaugurated a large, new outdoor concert series on a <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> pier. And among the top musical delights was Friday night's recreation of a May 2, 1912, Clef Club Concert when <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Reese </PERSON> <PERSON> Europe </PERSON> brought 125 black singers and instrumentalists to Carnegie Hall. They performed music mostly by black composers, mostly high-quality, high-spirited light classical, no spirituals. It was a first for an American stage. High points of the evening included <PERSON> Jester </PERSON> <PERSON> Hairston </PERSON>, born in 1901, vigorously conducting `` Swing Along for Choir and Orchestra'' and `` Rain Song for Choir and Orchestra,'' both by <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>. `` Swing Along'' got so much applause in 1912 it was performed again. The same thing happened on Friday. Another high point was two numbers by the Versatile Entertainers Quartet: piano, two banjos and snare drum. Conductor <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Peress </PERSON>, who organized the program, could n't find the quartet's music from the 1912 concert. He knew they were post-ragtime and pre-jazz but did n't know what they sounded like. But he turned up a 1916 recording and the quick-tempo `` Winter Nights'' and `` Down Home Rag'' on it were recreated Friday, starting with a delightfully trembling piano by <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Morgan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Male </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Choir </ORGANIZATION> and Boys Choir of <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> sang <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s `` Clef Club March,'' `` Benedictus from the Mass in G'' by <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolin </PERSON> and <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleridge </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>'s `` By the Waters of Babylon.'' The diva engaged to sing `` <LOCATION> Swanee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>'' in 1912 substituted `` My Heart at Thy Sweet Voice'' from the opera `` <PERSON> Samson </PERSON> and Delilah'' and <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> did the same on Friday. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Warfield </PERSON> sang <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosamond </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s folk-sounding `` L'il Gal'' and he and Miss <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> had fun dueting `` Play that Barber Shop Chord.'' <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Bates </PERSON> played a piano solo with flourishes, `` Dance Heroique.'' At a pre-concert lecture, Dr. <PERSON> Reid </PERSON> <PERSON> Badger </PERSON> talked about <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, who formed the <ORGANIZATION> Clef </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> as a booking agency for black musicians. He maintained a Clef Club Orchestra, with mandolins and banjos instead of second violins, for a strumming accompaniment, really the beginning of orchestral jazz. <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and his musicians often accompanied dancers <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Irene </PERSON> <PERSON> Castle </PERSON>. The last piece on the program was a waltz he composed for them. <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> wrote for Broadway and in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> in World War I, he organized a brass band. He is n't better known, <PERSON> Badger </PERSON> said, because he died at 38, stabbed by a deranged musician during a concert in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LostFish     07-15 0437</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lost Fish,0451</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fish Escapes After Marathon Battle</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SOLDOTNA, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Ploeger </PERSON> will have a well-documented fish story to tell when he gets back home to <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. As with most fish stories, it will be about the one that got away. But this one is on the record. <PERSON> Ploeger </PERSON> attracted the attention of local news photographers and hundreds of onlookers as he battled a king salmon for nearly a day and a half before losing the fish and perhaps a world record. The length of the struggle coupled with the way the fish dragged boats up, down and across the river prompted speculation that it might have been the king of kings, the sport-caught salmon that finally would top the 100-pound mark. Kings that big have been caught commercially in <LOCATION> Cook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Inlet </LOCATION> near the mouth of the Kenai, but the biggest ever taken on a rod and reel was 97 pounds, 4 ounces. The struggle began just after noon Wednesday when the 63-year-old <PERSON> Ploeger </PERSON>, a retired jailer from <LOCATION> Sandstone </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, hooked the fish about four miles upstream from the <LOCATION> Soldotna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION> in south-central <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> about 75 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ploeger </PERSON> was fishing from a drift boat with a rookie guide, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ploeger </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> soon abandoned the drift boat, hopping aboard a passing powerboat after <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> was unable to maneuver adequately through some boulder-studded rapids. He fought the fish that quickly was dubbed the `` Boss Hog'' through the night and all day Thursday. As word of the fish spread, the crowds grew. Local restaurants and businesses offered food and drink to <PERSON> Ploeger </PERSON> and the people helping him. Other guides shuttled fuel to the boat. <PERSON> Ploeger </PERSON> said there were hours of boredom punctuated by heart-stopping runs when the fish decided to go somewhere else. At one point, they thought they had him. `` He started coming up,'' said <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, another guide recruited along the way. `` We thought he was worn out, but he must have gotten scared by the net.'' By Thursday evening, the shoreline was lined with people. Some brought lawn chairs, others fished themselves. At 8:36 p.m. they erupted in cheers when it seemed a world record had been set for the longest battle with a sport fish. According to the Guiness Book of World Records, a fisherman took 32 -LCB- hours to land a 1,600-pound marlin in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ploeger </PERSON> had that beat _ if he could land the fish. But about four hours later, in the murky twilight that passes for night during <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> summers, the fish escaped _ leaving <PERSON> Ploeger </PERSON> and everyone else wondering how big it really was.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People--KittyDukakis     07-15 0157</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People--Kitty Dukakis,0159</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kitty Dukakis Injured Slightly in Cape Cop Traffic Accident</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FALMOUTH, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was treated for a minor neck injury and released from a hospital here after the car in which she was riding was struck in the rear by a pickup truck, authorities said. Mrs. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, whose sister, <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON>, was driving at the time of the accident, was admitted to <LOCATION> Falmouth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> about 6:30 p.m. Friday and released an hour later, nursing supervisor <PERSON> Pauline </PERSON> <PERSON> Giabbai </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> also was treated and released. The driver of the pickup truck, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Haddad </PERSON>, 22, was cited for failing to use care in stopping, following too closely and failing to have his vehicle inspected Mrs. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, 52, completed a 30-day treatment for alcohol dependency in March. She has been working on a book and speaking on the lecture circuit since her husband, Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, was defeated in his 1988 presidential bid.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-GuardInjuries     07-15 0183</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Guard Injuries,0185</SECOND>
<HEAD>Guard Troops Injured When Storm Flattens Tents</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TRINIDAD, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 100 soldiers in <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> units from <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> were injured when a storm hit during war games at the Pinon Canyon Maneuvers Site, officials said Friday. Sgt. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Aguilar </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Animas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's office said the injuries ranged from scrapes, cuts and bruises to a few broken bones and concussions. The most seriously injured were flown to a hospital at nearby <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carson </LOCATION>, he said. The soldiers were injured when winds, accompanied by rain and small hail, flattened between 12 and 15 tents with troops inside, he said. A half inch of rain and winds up to 50 and 60 mph were reported, and there were unconfirmed reports of a tornado, <PERSON> Aguilar </PERSON> said. Maj. <PERSON> Joy </PERSON> <PERSON> Moser </PERSON>, a public affairs officer for the 105th Detachment, <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, said the storm hit about 3 p.m. and moved over the 562nd <ORGANIZATION> Support </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> and the 82nd Field Hospital. He said the injured were evacuated because the field hospital blew down.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0151EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Croce     07-15 0119</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Croce,0121</SECOND>
<UNK>Publisher Joseph P. Croce Dead At 57</UNK>
<DATELINE>NORRISTOWN, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Croce </PERSON>, vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> Intercounty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, which publishes 24 newspapers in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, mostly weeklies, has died at age 57. <PERSON> Croce </PERSON>, who died Wednesday, was publisher of the group's <ORGANIZATION> Breeze </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspapers </ORGANIZATION>, which Independent purchased in 1971. A cause of death was not given. Among the eight newspapers under his wing, starting with north <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Tioga </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> in 1965, were the Northeast Advisor, <LOCATION> Bensalem </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bulletin </LOCATION>, the Conschohocken Recorder and the North Penn Chat. He is survived by his wife, <PERSON> Catherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Croce </PERSON>; two sons, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON>; a daughter, <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>; a brother; a sister and two grandsons.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HUDProbe Bjt   07-15 0595</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-HUD Probe, Bjt,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Aide Claims `Silent Sam' Spoke Up on HUD Projects</HEAD>
<BYLINE>BY DENISE CABRERA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A top aide to former Housing Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> disputes <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s sworn claim that he had no direct role in deciding what projects the scandal-scarred agency funded. Former <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Assistant Secretary for Housing <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> McVay </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiseman </PERSON> also says <PERSON> Carla </PERSON> <PERSON> Hills </PERSON>, currently the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade representative, lobbied <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> to lift restrictions on a mortgage lender now under federal criminal investigation. Hills is scheduled to testify before the committee on Monday. <PERSON> Wiseman </PERSON> said in sworn testimony Friday that <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> personally called her and instructed her to approve more than $ 15 million in funding for a <LOCATION> Durham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, project sought by a former <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> law partner. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said: `` I want the project funded,'' <PERSON> Wiseman </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on employment and housing, one of three congressional panels investigating mismanagement and fraud at the housing agency. The <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> approval brought more than $ 11.3 million in rent subsidies, a $ 2.3 million grant and more than $ 3 million in tax credits to developers who were seeking to turn a hosiery mill into an apartment complex, said Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, D-Calif., chairman of the subcommittee <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> has testified he set up a three-person panel to make funding decisions for the moderate rehabilitation program, but said he maintained `` final authority'' over the decisions. `` I did not plan, however, to get into the decision-making process of the panel when there was no complaint to justify my doing so,'' he told the subcommittee in May. Efforts by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> to reach <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> for comment were unsuccessful. <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON> said he would seek to recall <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> to the subcommittee before the congressional recess Aug. 4. <PERSON> Wiseman </PERSON> said she told <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> she could not fund the project over the objections of career <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> employees who had been `` violently opposed'' to the project. The project was eventually approved by <PERSON> Wiseman </PERSON>'s successor, <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Hale </PERSON>, who said she believed she was `` acting on the approval of my boss.'' <PERSON> Wiseman </PERSON> also testified that <ORGANIZATION> DRG </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Funding </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a private lender that was suspended from participating in a $ 5 billion program in which <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> insured large portions of mortgages, was allowed to get back into the program after lobbying from <PERSON> Hills </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Secretary. DRG is now under <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> criminal investigation. <PERSON> Wiseman </PERSON> said DRG's ability to underwrite mortgages had been placed on hold during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration because of infractions of department rules. The suspension remained despite a meeting with Hills in late 1984 or early 1985 to get the restrictions lifted. `` It was not a convincing argument,'' <PERSON> Wiseman </PERSON> said. But DRG's probation was lifted despite the concerns of staff members, she said. `` It was later brought to my attention that <PERSON> Hills </PERSON> had ... taken the case to Secretary <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>. I was informed by staff that there was a meeting,'' she said. Lawmakers expressed concern about the conflicting testimony regarding <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>. `` The factual noose seems to be tightening around <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s neck,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION> `` We were very careful about asking him if he had ever tried to influence any project and we have two people making it very clear that he wanted a particular project funded,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Shays </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Conn </LOCATION> Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> filed suit in <LOCATION> Forth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, on Friday seeking to recover more than $ 2.5 million a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> woman is accused of bilking from the agency and spending on real estate, cars and guns. The woman is one of 10 closing agents nationwide the agency believes defrauded <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> of about $ 10 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     07-15 0945</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0983</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Scribner </PERSON>'s Sons has contracted former Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> to write two books, one on the art of diplomacy and the other a memoir of his 6 -LCB- years as secretary of state. Under the agreement announced Friday, <ORGANIZATION> Scribner </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>, part of <ORGANIZATION> Macmillan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, has been granted world rights to both books. The statecraft book is related to a PBS series that <ORGANIZATION> MacNeil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lehrer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Productions </ORGANIZATION> is producing. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> served as secretary of state under President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> from July 1982 until January. He currently is the <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Steel </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> professor of international economics at the <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Graduate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> and honorary fellow at the <ORGANIZATION> Hoover </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION> on War, Revolution and Peace. His publications include `` Economy Policy Beyond the Headlines,'' 1978; `` Workers and Wages in the Urban Labor Market,'' 1970, and `` Guidelines, Informal Controls and the Market Place,'' 1966.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ALBANY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>, who knows how to keep people guessing about his possible presidential ambitions, continues to talk about his lack of interest in discussing the subject. As usual, he refused even to hint at a yes or no. `` I want to talk about it because I want to dispose of it,'' <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> was quoted as saying in Friday's edition of the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>. `` If I speak on the subject at all, it becomes an occasion for speculation,'' <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> said. `` And so, for the time being, if anyone does ask me about it, I'm simply not going to discuss it.'' <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> then went on to talk about `` a thousand letters'' he's received from people urging him to run for president _ `` letters from some names that would shock you ... Republicans, people of great stature in this country. On Monday, <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> set off the latest round of speculation about him and the presidency when he told a meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasters </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> that as a public servant he was `` obligated'' to think about running for president.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HOOSICK FALLS, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Grandma </PERSON> <PERSON> Moses </PERSON>, in the guise of actress <PERSON> Cloris </PERSON> <PERSON> Leachman </PERSON>, has come home to the valley that inspired her artist's eye. The town about 45 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION> gave a warm welcome Friday to the actress who portrays <PERSON> Moses </PERSON> in the stage show `` <LOCATION> Grandma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moses </LOCATION> _ An American Primitive.'' `` I really believe we've found the heart and soul of what we're trying to do here,'' <PERSON> Leachman </PERSON>, 63, told an audience of about 150 people, including about 15 descendants of <PERSON> Moses </PERSON> <PERSON> Leachman </PERSON> sat with <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Moses </PERSON>, 90, widow of <PERSON> Grandma </PERSON> <PERSON> Moses </PERSON>' youngest son, <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON>; <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Moses </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrington </PERSON>, 65; and <PERSON> Margery </PERSON> <PERSON> Moses </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>, 60, both granddaughters of the painter <PERSON> Anna </PERSON> <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> <PERSON> Moses </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Eagle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION>, just a few miles from <LOCATION> Hoosick </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, moved to <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Shenandoah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> with her husband, and returned at the age of 45. <PERSON> Moses </PERSON> began painting in her 70s, after her hands had grown too weak for other tasks. She painted for three decades, illustrating <PERSON> Clement </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>'s ``' T was the Night Before Christmas'' at the age of 100 <PERSON> Grandma </PERSON> <PERSON> Moses </PERSON> was 101 when she died in December 1961.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PATERSON, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Eastside </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> will be leaning on someone new come September, following the city <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>'s replacement of disciplinarian <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> as school principal The school board Thursday unanimously approved <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Lighty </PERSON> for the high-profile job. In chosing <PERSON> Lighty </PERSON>, an elementary school principal, board members said it was time to emphasize academics at a school that became famous for <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>'s barking, authoritarian style. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, 52, who is on a leave of absence at his <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> home recuperating from open heart surgery, already had announced his intention not to return to Eastside in September. His no-nonsense approach to education was symbolized by a baseball bat and bullhorn he wielded during patrols of the halls at Eastside. His efforts were depicted in the movie `` Lean on Me.'' Telephone calls to <PERSON> Lighty </PERSON>'s home were not answered Friday.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>THE HAGUE, Netherlands (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Saxophonist <PERSON> Stan </PERSON> <PERSON> Getz </PERSON>, pianist <PERSON> Herbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hancock </PERSON>, an 8-year-old vocalist and a man billed as the world's first bagpipe jazz artist are among the players at this year's North Sea Jazz Festival. Also scheduled to appear in the three-day festival, which opened Friday, are the inveterate percussionist and band leader <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Blakey </PERSON>, pianist <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON> and trumpeters <PERSON> Dizzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Gillespie </PERSON> and <PERSON> Miles </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>. Organizers say they are expecting up to 50,000 visitors to watch the more than 150 bands and dozens of soloists appearing at the sprawling Congresgebouw complex here. <PERSON> Blakey </PERSON> is one of the three winners of this year's Bird Award, an international jazz prize awarded at the festival and named after the innovative alto saxophonist <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> `` Bird'' <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>. Other winners of the trophy were Dutch pianist <PERSON> Misha </PERSON> <PERSON> Mengelberg </PERSON> and British saxophonist <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Surman </PERSON>. A novelty at this year's festival will be a daylong family program dubbed `` Gigs for Kids,'' which includes bagpipe artist <PERSON> Rufus </PERSON> <PERSON> Harley </PERSON> and 8-year-old skat singer <PERSON> Emily </PERSON> <PERSON> Haddad </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, billed as a `` miniature <PERSON> Ella </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SACRAMENTO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There's a new and younger Judge <PERSON> Wapner </PERSON> on the bench. <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> Wapner </PERSON>, 39, of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, the son of the `` People's Court'' jurist, was named Friday to the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Municipal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> He was one of five people, all current or former deputy district attorneys, chosen by Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON>. <PERSON> Wapner </PERSON> is the son of <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Wapner </PERSON>, the judge of the nationally syndicated television show, the governor's office said. The younger <PERSON> Wapner </PERSON>, a deputy district attorney since 1975, replaces <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON>, who was promoted to the <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. The salary for a <ORGANIZATION> Municipal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> judge is $ 82,052.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-GuamFraud     07-15 0473</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Guam Fraud,0485</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bond Firm Executive Pleads Guilty to Fraud Involving Guam</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LOUINN LOTA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> executive accused of pumping money into the campaign of a former governor of <LOCATION> Guam </LOCATION> in exchange for a political favor pleaded guilty Friday to three counts of mail fraud. <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Abba </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> entered the plea before <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON>, said <LOCATION> Guam </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney, <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>. In exchange for his guilty plea, 46 counts alleging bribery, conspiracy, wire and mail fraud, and violation of interstate racketeering statutes were dismissed. `` In dismissing the counts, the Guam issues were dissolved,'' <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> said. `` Other issues are on the table if another jurisdiction sees fit to follow through.'' Twelve of the counts were related directly to <LOCATION> Guam </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> territory since August, 1950, said <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>. The balance of the counts related to fraud involving use of the <ORGANIZATION> Commercial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Americas </ORGANIZATION> in transactions that did not involve <LOCATION> Guam </LOCATION>, <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> said. Although <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, executive vice president of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> bond underwriting firm of <ORGANIZATION> Matthews </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, only pleaded to three of the dozen counts, <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> was satisfied with the outcome. `` Mr. <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>'s plea gave the same latitude of sentencing than if he went to trial,'' <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> said. `` We, of course, will recommend jail time and a heavy fine.'' <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> faces a possible 15 years imprisonment, a $ 750,000 fine and restitution payments, <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> said in a telephone interview from his <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ana </LOCATION> office. Sentencing was scheduled in <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON>' court Sept. 11. One of <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>'s attorneys, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Weitzman </PERSON>, said he had no immediate comment. A receptionist who answered a call made after business hours to another defense attorney, <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Hochman </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Hochman </PERSON> had gone for the day. The three mail fraud counts concerned $ 57,500 bilked from the Guam Program Development Fund and a letter assuring fund authorities that transactions were above board, while fraud was taking place. <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> prepared phony invoices that were sent to the bank entrusted with fund money. `` The bank paid the money <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> exerted for his purposes and ... he attempted to cover up later with false papers in the files,'' <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> said. <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> said $ 25,000 was `` used to buy campaign paraphernalia _ parasols, hats, shirts, junk like that'' for Guam Gov. <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bordallo </PERSON>'s unsuccessful 1986 re-election bid. The funds were funneled to <PERSON> Bordallo </PERSON> after he was promised the money in exchange for his support on a bond issue, $ 300 million of which was sold by <ORGANIZATION> Matthews </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. The bond was approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Guam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> in 1985. <ORGANIZATION> Matthews </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> deny any wrongdoing. <PERSON> Bordallo </PERSON> was acquitted in February, 1986, of accepting bribes from <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> but convicted on 10 counts of government corruption. The case is among about 25 municipal bond deals nationwide involving <ORGANIZATION> Matthews </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> under investigation by the <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0226EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BlackCatholics     07-15 0491</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Black Catholics,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Archbishop Calls for Blacks to Lead Church ``From Within''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANNE RUMSEY</BYLINE>
<UNK>Associated Press Writer</UNK>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The leader of the nation's 300 Roman Catholic bishops admits there are persistent `` elements of racism'' in the church, but is calling for a black priest's breakaway congregation to return for the sake of unity. Archbishop <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> May </PERSON> of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bishops </ORGANIZATION>, promised the Rev. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> the nation's two million black Catholics would be given `` full voice'' in the church. `` It is possible to ... be a voice of conscience for the family and lead that family from within,'' May said in a statement Friday. <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON>, 41, has been suspended for holding services the past two weeks at his <ORGANIZATION> Imani </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> in defiance of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Cardinal <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Hickey </PERSON>. A spokesman for <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON> said he would have no comment on May's statement or another call for unity from the nation's 13 black bishops earlier this week <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON> has said he formed the new congregation because the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> has not addressed black concerns and he has charged the church with racism. May's statement conceded, `` Surely, as all the bishops in this country have acknowledged in the past, there have been elements of racism in the church and there continue to be. `` We need to recognize more black leadership; our liturgies need more of the vibrancy, and our policies more of the insight, of African Americans,'' May said. He said the nation's 52 million Roman Catholics `` share the sadness'' reflected in the black bishops' call Wednesday for reconciliation. The black bishops' statement said in part, `` We sincerely hope -LRB- <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON>' followers -RRB- are not commingling personal disappointment, individually felt frustrations, and personal anger under the banner of racism. Racism is a sin which the church must address. It is too serious an issue to be used as a cover for selfish concerns.'' Several priests have supported <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON>, however, including 15 who met with him in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Thursday. They called for <PERSON> Hickey </PERSON> to lift <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON>' suspension, imposed after the first service of the renegade church at <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> on July 2. Appearing Friday on The <PERSON> Oprah </PERSON> <PERSON> Winfrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Show </PERSON>, <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON> denied he is forming the church for personal gain. `` I know exactly the picture they're trying to paint ... but <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> X </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, people say they all have inflated egos,'' <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON> said on the national television program. He affirmed his plans to continue services despite the suspension, and said he `` can not be excommunicated from <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hickey </PERSON> should `` eat crow,'' and `` admit he's wrong. `` Since the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> can not make inroads into the black community, all we are saying is, let us show you how. What's wrong with that? he asked. Suspension means <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON> is not sanctioned to say Mass or perform other sacraments. It is the strongest step <PERSON> Hickey </PERSON> can take without moving to excommunicate <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0230EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WanderingPlane-Probes     07-15 0669</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wandering Plane-Probes,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dramatic Rescue Prompts More Investigations of Pilot</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Wandering Plane Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Officials are investigating the pilot who survived an 800-mile flight, bullet wound and crash-landing in the ocean, expanding probes that began when three dozen guns and a can of ether were found in <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Root </PERSON>'s private plane. The reports that the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> communications lawyer is under investigation by several agencies added a peculiar twist to the tale of Root's rescue from the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> after apparently crashing unconscious into the water. Officials at agencies said Root is being investigated by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> over the weapons and ether, the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> Secretary of <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>'s Office concerning possible securities violations, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, which investigates crimes aboard aircraft. Widespread publicity over Root's unlikely survival prompted Customs to expand its investigation Friday into <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. `` This is weird to say the least,'' said a Customs official, who spoke on condition of anonymity. In addition, a review of documents at the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> showed Root repeatedly failed to comply with deadlines and other requirements in cases before the commission. Root also represented numerous clients of a Georgia-based company that another broadcast firm labeled a `` notorious application mill'' for FM broadcast licenses that allegedly has bilked hundreds of individuals of their investments. The 35 guns, many loaded, were found during a search April 24 by federal and local officials of Root's <ORGANIZATION> Cessna </ORGANIZATION> 210 at the <LOCATION> Manassas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, airport, said the Customs official. All the guns were legal under federal law, and all but one _ a machine gun Root had registered with the <ORGANIZATION> federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alcohol </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tobacco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Firearms </ORGANIZATION> but not with <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> authorities _ were legal under state law. The state has filed a misdemeanor charge against him over the machine gun, the official said. Among the guns, including assault-style weapons and three .357 - caliber Magnums, the officials found silencers, ammunition clips, handcuffs, an electrical stun gun and a five-gallon can of ether _ which is used in cocaine production _ in the plane, the Customs official During a May 31 interview with Root by Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> County </PERSON> <PERSON> Polie </PERSON> and a Customs agent, `` by and large he was able to account for legal possession of those weapons.'' `` Basically, he indicated that he was a gun collector,'' the official said. But Root did not explain why he kept the weapons on his plane _ registered to a Washington-based company he owns _ nor why they were loaded. Root told officials the ether `` was used to clean his aircraft. But of course that's not what you use to clean an aircraft with unless you're going to blow it up,'' the official said. Customs kept the case open `` because when you come across this many weapons ... we always continue to take a look to make sure no Customs laws have been violated,'' he said. The search had been prompted by an unidentified source who said `` there was a suspicious aircraft at <ORGANIZATION> Manassas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airfield </ORGANIZATION>,'' the Customs official said. <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, Police Chief <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Witt </PERSON> revealed Friday that Root had been shot. The bullet traveled through his left rib cage and his colon, left his body, and then pierced his arm. A powder burn indicated Root was shot at close range, the chief said. In <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, Secretary of State <PERSON> Rufus </PERSON> <PERSON> Edmisten </PERSON> said his office had spoken with Root about a securities investigation involving Georgia-based <ORGANIZATION> Sonrise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> and that the lawyer `` knew he was under investigation.'' Sonrise said in a statement that the only connection between the company and Root `` is that he represents certain entities which also number among our clientele.'' <PERSON> Edmisten </PERSON> said <PERSON> Root </PERSON> was the attorney for investment partnerships formed by Sonrise to obtain <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> licenses. Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Rachel </PERSON> <PERSON> Halterman </PERSON> said investigators `` have not come to any conclusions and have not ruled out anything at all'' about what caused the events on the plane Thursday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0231EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DomesticSpying     07-15 0569</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Domestic Spying,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Protest Group Says Report Criticizing FBI Should Go Farther</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An organization investigated by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> during its protests of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policies in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> says a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> report criticizing the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> probe did n't go far enough. <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>, political director of the <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in Solidarity with the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Salvador </ORGANIZATION>, praised the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> for calling the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> surveillance of his organization unjustified and telling the agency to purge its files of the case. But `` we take strong issue with its conclusion that the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> investigation was an aberration and that it was n't politically motivated,'' <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> said Friday after the <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> issued a report criticizing the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s investigation of <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> between 1983 and 1985. The report sharply criticized <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> management for letting the investigation continue and said the probe was based on `` allegations that should not have been considered credible.'' `` The <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> files contain information about domestic political activities that the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> should never have gathered,'' said Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> chairman, and Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Maine </LOCATION>, vice chairman `` That information must be removed from <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> records so it can not be used to damage the reputation of innocent persons,'' they said. But the report called the investigation an `` aberration'' and said it did not reflect `` significant <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> political or ideological bias,'' a point noted by both <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>. `` We do n't believe that an investigation that involved 59 field officers and 178 spinoff investigations that resulted in retrievable information being held in <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> files about approximately 2,375 individuals and 1,330 groups can be called an aberration,'' said <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>. `` We believe the investigation was politically motivated from the start,'' said <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> said Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sessions </PERSON> is still reviewing the report but issued a statement saying it was `` significant'' that the report found `` the <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> investigation was not politically motivated to harass or influence legitimate First Amendment activities.'' An <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said the files would not be immediately purged because there is continuing litigation over the investigation. The Committee in Solidarity with the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Salvador </ORGANIZATION> was formed in 1980 because of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration aid to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, which has totaled $ 3 billion since 1981. A 1983 <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> memorandum is quoted in the report as attacking <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> for its protests and its practice of hosting Salvadoran refugees who said their lives had been threatened by death squads in their homelands. `` It is imperative at this time to formulate some plan of attack against <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> and specifically against individuals ... who defiantly display their contempt for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government by making speeches and propagandizing their cause while asking for political asylum,'' the memo said. The report said, `` There may not have been tangible harm intended or done to any groups or individuals involved in constitutionally protected activity, but unjustified investigations of political expression and dissent can have a debilitating effect upon our political system.'' Despite such comments, the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constitutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION>, which filed a lawsuit on behalf of <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION>, said `` critical and unresolved issues relating to the monitoring of First Amendment-protected activities of domestic groups that oppose <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy'' remain. The probe was done while <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON>, now director of the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>, was head of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>. Sessions has taken several internal measures over the probe, including disciplining six employees at the supervisor, unit chief and section chief levels.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0238EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-OilSpills-Cleanup     07-15 0420</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Oil Spills-Cleanup,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Oil Spill Rules Could Mean Exxon Pays More</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal court ruling could make oil companies pay more to clean up oil spills, including the massive spill from an Exxon tanker that polluted the coastline of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, says a congressman involved in the fight over liability for environmental accidents. A three-judge panel of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> for the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> unanimously ruled Friday the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> should rewrite its rules on paying for oil spills to include the costs of more than just the monetary value of animals killed. The decision raises chances `` that companies will have to pay the whole cost of restoring an environment,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Torricelli </PERSON>, D-N.J. <PERSON> Torricelli </PERSON> said the case could have a major impact on damage payments by oil companies involved in spills, such as the March 24 accident that occurred when the tanker <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valdez </ORGANIZATION> dumped 11 million gallons of crude oil into <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s pristine Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>. `` This will make <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s exposure much greater,'' said <PERSON> Torricelli </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Levitt </PERSON> said the agency had n't studied the ruling and would n't have any comment He said no decision had been made on whether to appeal the case. The regulations were issued three years ago to implement the 1977 Clean Water Act and the 1980 Superfund law, which required the government to write regulations determining the monetary costs of oil spills. Several environmental groups and states sued over the regulations. Under the 1986 regulations, the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> created a computer model putting a dollar value for `` lost use'' of various types of wildlife. For example, the cost of a fur seal was set at $ 15, based on the expected value of a seal pelt. The cost of geese ranged up to $ 35, based on their popularity among hunters. But the appeals court said <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, in writing the laws, had intended that repayment should be more broadly drawn to consider not simply the value of lost wildlife, but the larger cost of restoring the damaged environment. `` Because in some _ probably a majority _ of cases, lost-use value will be lower than the cost of restoration, <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION>'s rule will result in damages awards too small to pay for the costs or restoration,'' the ruling said. The <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has not yet decided on a damage assessment for either the Alaskan spill or three smaller spills which occurred last month off the coasts of <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0238EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     07-15 0449</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0464</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AUGUSTA, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Stanley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steamers </ORGANIZATION> chugged and puffed from lobster bakes to parades and museums as owners from all over the continent headed <LOCATION> Down </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> to pay tribute to the <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> twins who invented the automobiles. The gathering was to wind up Friday evening with a Blow-Down Banquet following a showing at a coastal transportation museum. After operating their cars, drivers `` blow down'' the boilers, venting steam. A day earlier, more than 30 drivers made the trip to <LOCATION> Squirrel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, where F.E. and F.O. <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON>, inventors of the celebrated steam-powered cars, used to spend summers. In their first <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> `` hub tour,'' owners of <ORGANIZATION> Stanley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steamers </ORGANIZATION> and the less-common White steamers came from all over the continent. Three vehicles made it on their own steam, while others made most of the trip on trailer beds. `` A lot of these people came 700 or 800 miles,'' said <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Bourdon </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Woodstock </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vt. </LOCATION>, who made the 250-mile trip in his 1913 <ORGANIZATION> Stanley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mountain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wagon </ORGANIZATION>. `` I would say this is the largest number of Stanleys that have been running -LRB- together -RRB-'' said <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Orillia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION>. Drivers must adjust valves to control water, fuel, throttle and steam pressure. For the car to be ready to go, a pilot light must be lit. It takes about 20 minutes before a cold steamer will move. Of the roughly 400 <ORGANIZATION> Stanley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steamers </ORGANIZATION> nationwide, about 150 are still roadworthy, said <PERSON> Bourdon </PERSON>. Stanley Steamers were built between 1899 and 1924 in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. It was a family-owned business until 1917, when F.E. <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> was killed in one of the steamers and the business was sold.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BAKERSFIELD, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some people will go a long way to defend their hometowns. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Friese </PERSON>, a soldier stationed at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, did n't try to dodge his civic duty when he was summoned for jury duty. Instead he took some vacation, hopped a plane and traveled 6,000 miles to meet the obligation. `` We get <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. He is continually cutting down this town. I felt it was my duty to come back and do this and maybe show the people that someone -LRB- living -RRB- out of <LOCATION> Bakersfield </LOCATION> does care for this place,'' <PERSON> Friese </PERSON> said. He reported to <ORGANIZATION> Kern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Monday and still had n't been seated on a jury Friday. It may have been well worth the trip, had <PERSON> Friese </PERSON> been paid the usual 15 cents for every mile traveled from home to the court. But he was only paid mileage for the distance traveled to court from his address in this city 100 miles north of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, plus $ 5 for every day he reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0242EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CoalStrike Bjt   07-15 0627</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Coal Strike, Bjt,0650</SECOND>
<HEAD>UMW Seeks End to Wildcat Strikes as Memorial Period Expires</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KELLY P. KISSEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GILBERT, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Coal miners in at least three states agreed to return to work this weekend, complying with the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> union in its bid to end a monthlong wildcat strike. About 15,250 miners in <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> decided to return to work beginning with shifts at midnight Friday and continuing through the weekend, <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION> officials said. `` There may be a light at the end of the tunnel,'' said <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> 11 international executive board member <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>. `` We're just pleased that the miners have chosen to return to their jobs,'' said <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Feeney </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> AMAX </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. But miners in <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> said Friday they would stay off their jobs. The situation of miners in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> was unclear. Wildcat strikes in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> ended last month. <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Trumka </PERSON> on Friday ended a five-day `` memorial period,'' a contract-sanctioned work stoppage that had affected 60,000 union miners east of the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. He also asked 37,000 wildcat strikers _ included among those participating in the memorial period _ to go back to work on their next scheduled shifts. The <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION> international executive board meets July 26, and <PERSON> Trumka </PERSON> asked the miners involved in the wildcat strikes to return to work at least until then. The wildcat walkouts began June 12 in support of the <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION>'s strike against <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>. That strike, idling 1,900 <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION> members in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, began April 5 and showed no signs of ending Also Friday, a federal judge in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> said he wanted to talk with <PERSON> Trumka </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, head of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, parent company of <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coal </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Trumka </PERSON> accepted; <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> gave no word. Only a small group of miners were scheduled to work today, and under the union's contract, no work is permitted at underground mines on Sundays. `` I anticipate a major return starting Sunday night and Monday,'' said <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Corcoran </PERSON>. <PERSON> Trumka </PERSON> called the memorial period last week in an attempt to calm the coal fields, where non-union coal shipments have been met by shootings, rocks and `` jack rocks,'' nails specially welded to flatten tires. As <PERSON> Trumka </PERSON> called on the strikers to return to work, violence erupted again in the coal fields. Two company guards were shot and wounded at <ORGANIZATION> Hampden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> near <LOCATION> Gilbert </LOCATION>, and a bomb damaged a replacement miner's car at <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coal </ORGANIZATION>'s headquarters in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. Coal company officials this week blasted <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> Gov <PERSON> Gaston </PERSON> <PERSON> Caperton </PERSON> and state police for letting the strikers get out of hand. <PERSON> Caperton </PERSON> and state police have defended their actions, saying the coal fields are under control. However, no arrests had been made in any of the incidents of violence that have marked the wildcat strikes, and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney's office in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> said Friday it will begin investigating such incidents. Tension was evident after the Hampden shootings. Hampden Coal President <PERSON> Sid </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> _ speaking with two handguns strapped to his body, and flanked by two men toting semi-automatic weapons _ decried the violence. But he said his employees will not be intimidated by the 150 miners camped out in front of his mine beside <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> 52. `` I'd hate to be in the first 50 guys who try to stop'' shipments out of the mine, he said. On the <LOCATION> Hampden </LOCATION> picket line, most union members refused to talk to reporters. An <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reporter was escorted from the site by a miner who held an ax handle pressed against the reporter's head. `` If ya'll know what's good for you, you'll stay away,'' the miner said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0242EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Cooke-Cable     07-15 0193</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cooke-Cable,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cooke Sells Cable TV Systems for $1.6 Billion</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON>, the owner of the <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Redskins </ORGANIZATION>, sold his cable television systems to six companies for about $ 1.6 billion, according to a report published today. The business deal, believed to involve one of the three largest purchase prices in cable history, is expected to net <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON> more than $ 500 million in profit in two years, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported. The properties have 675,000 subscribers in 17 states and will be sold to a consortium of companies that includes <ORGANIZATION> Tele-Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the Denver-based operator of the nation's largest group of cable-television systems, and <ORGANIZATION> Inter-media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Partners </ORGANIZATION>, a privately held <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> company partly owned by <ORGANIZATION> Tele-Communications </ORGANIZATION>, said the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON> paid a total of $ 1.05 billion for the systems in two deals in 1987, investing about $ 200 million of his own money and borrowing the rest, according to the newspaper. Other buyers include <ORGANIZATION> TCA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> TV </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Tyler </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Chambers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Falcon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> TV of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>; and a group including members of the <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rigas </PERSON> family, which controls <ORGANIZATION> Adelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0245EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-StarWars-Experiment     07-15 0313</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Star Wars-Experiment,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Star Wars' Particle Beam Fired Into Space</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Pentagon is studying results of a `` Star Wars'' test that is considered a key step in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> research to deploy futuristic weapons that could shoot powerful beams at enemy missiles. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials on Friday confirmed completion of the test, which involved firing a beam of electrically neutral atomic particles into space for the first time. The BEAR test _ which stands for the Beam Experiment Aboard Rocket _ is designed to test how an accelerator of neutral particles would work in space. The experiment, which has been planned for more than a year, was completed early Thursday morning at the White Sands Missile Range in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, said Army Maj. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connell </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Initiative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. Program scientists need to test whether neutral particle beams _ in this case, hydrogen atoms _ can be used to discriminate between real and mock Soviet warheads. The spokesman said it was `` presumptive'' to announce whether the test had been a success, since officials and scientists still need to study the results of the experiment over the weekend before releasing more information Monday. The experiment involved lifting into space _ just for a few minutes _ a neutral particle beam accelerator atop a small Aires rocket. Before the rocket returned to earth, the accelerator was to be turned on for collection of data on how it worked and how the beam moved. In June, a similar test was aborted when the rocket failed to ignite on command. The Star Wars program is a research effort aimed at developing lasers, beam accelerators and other futuristic weapons that could be used to automatically shoot down nuclear missiles fired at the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> or its allies. The Pentagon and <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> are spending $ 4 billion on such research this year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0252EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtoninBrief     07-15 0788</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington in Brief,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>USDA Official Sees Dangers in Global Warming</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A senior <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> scientist says the possibility that the so-called `` greenhouse effect'' will cause global warming `` is too much of a risk to ignore.'' Assistant Secretary <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hess </PERSON>, who oversees science and education programs, said Friday he has named <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> as his special assistant for global change issues. `` There are climate experts who claim the 1988 drought was evidence that global warming has already begun,'' <PERSON> Hess </PERSON> said. `` A conclusive link has not been proven, but the threat of global warming from heat trapped by so-called greenhouse gases is too much of a risk to ignore.'' Those gases include carbon dioxide, chlorofluorocarbons, methane, nitrogen oxides and halons, <PERSON> Hess </PERSON> said in a statement. Some of the gases also seem to be causing a thinning of the high-level ozone layer, which filters out a large part of the ultraviolet rays which can limite the growth of sensitive crops. <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, who has been deputy administrator of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, will coordinate activities among seven <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> agencies and the land-grant universities as part of the department's efforts to protect crops and forests, <PERSON> Hess </PERSON> said
</TEXT>
<NOTE>FBI Examines Contract Allegations At Fernald</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> is investigating allegations of contract fraud at an <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> plant that makes material for nuclear weapons, says a top <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official. The Fernald plant, where production was suspended earlier this week, also is the target of a special investigation by a DOE team assessing health and safety measures and other aspects of the plant's operation. `` Fernald's been at the top of our list for some time,'' said Deputy Energy Secretary <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> on Friday. `` We're going in there to see what's wrong and what might need to be done to get into compliance.'' <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Boldt </PERSON> said from <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> that the investigation was triggered by an allegation of criminal wrongdoing in contracting. He provided no details. The Fernald complex, located about 18 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>, is a key contributor to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nuclear weapons production. It processes uranium compounds, produces uranium billets for nuclear weapons production and makes uranium target elements for defense nuclear reactors. It's also one of the government's most seriously contaminated facilities. The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> this week proposed adding <PERSON> Fernald </PERSON> to the Superfund list of high-priority cleanup sites.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Rules Proposed for Security Ban on Foreign Takeovers</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has published for public comment proposed rules that would allow President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to plead national security and block takeover of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> firm by foreigners. Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Exon </PERSON>, D-Neb., and Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Florio </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, who were responsible for parts of the law, praised the proposed regulations published Friday in the Federal Register The comment period runs through Sept. 12, although the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said later comments will be considered if possible. The Trade Act, signed by former President <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> last August, provides authority for the rules that would allow the president to block a merger if he has credible evidence that the foreign interest taking control might act to hurt <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> security. If a president decides on an investigation, he gets 30 days to begin it, 45 days to complete it and another 15 days to announce it. <PERSON> Florio </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> has interpreted the law broadly to make sure that it covers a variety of ways that a foreign firm could take over an American one.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>US Making Progress on Compensation Concerning Iran Air Crash</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration will announce a compensation offer early next week for families of the non-Iranian victims on the <ORGANIZATION> Iran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> flight shot down by a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warship a year ago, officials say. All but 40 of the 290 people who died were Iranian. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has said it would pay compensation to all families, but the Iranian government has refused to provide details about its citizens who died. The 40 non-Iranians were Indians, Pakistanis, Koreans, Japanese and citizens of several Arab countries. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government has said it will not pay the Iranian government directly, and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has called that position `` not acceptable.'' In civil lawsuits arising from crash deaths in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, courts generally award compensation based on the lost earnings of a family member. Thus families of people who die early in lucrative careers usually win larger awards than families of retired people. It is not known whether such an approach would be followed in the government's compensation offer. The officials, who asked not to be identified, on Friday were unable to provide figures on the compensation package they expect but said a formal announcement was expected early next week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0329EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WanderingPlane Bjt   07-15 0688</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wandering Plane, Bjt,0712</SECOND>
<HEAD>Investigators Await Interviews With Flight Survivor As Probe Widens</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRIAN MURPHY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A gunshot wound suffered by <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Root </PERSON> is only one of the mysteries surrounding the attorney after he flew apparently unconscious 800 miles down the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>. Officials from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> hope to interview Root today about the flight and crash landing in Bahamian waters. But they also are curious about two probes involving his gun collection and conduct as an attorney. Root was in stable condition today at Memorial Hospital in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, north of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. He was under heavy sedation Friday. `` It's an odd story all right,'' said <PERSON> Root </PERSON>'s brother-in-law, <PERSON> Brett </PERSON> <PERSON> Geer </PERSON>, after visiting Root at the hospital. `` With this wound and him not being able to recollect how he got it, I'm sure there is reason for an investigation.'' Root had a .32 - caliber handgun with him in the cockpit, <PERSON> Geer </PERSON> Investigators from the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> need permission from Root's physicians to conduct the interview. `` There are many questions I'll be asking,'' said <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> investigator <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Alston </PERSON>. Developments Friday included: _ In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Customs official said authorities found 35 guns, many of them loaded, and a can of ether in a search of Root's plane last April at the <LOCATION> Manassas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> in All of the guns were legal under federal law, and all but one under state law, which led to a state misdemeanor charge. The arsenal included assault-style rifles and three .357 - caliber Magnum Root had told Customs officials that the ether, which can be used in cocaine production, was used to clean his aircraft. _ In <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, Secretary of State <PERSON> Rufus </PERSON> <PERSON> Edmisten </PERSON> said his office has been investigating security fraud allegations against a company with which Root acted as an attorney <PERSON> Edmisten </PERSON> said there are allegations that the company, <ORGANIZATION> Sonrise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, was set up in a way that allowed it to avoid securities laws. <PERSON> Edmisten </PERSON> said the lawyer knew he was under investigation. Root, 36, apparently became unconscious in his cockpit Friday with his plane on autopilot and military pilots shadowing his aircraft for nearly four hours. His plane ran out of gas and crashed in mile-deep waters 14 miles west of the <LOCATION> Bahamian </LOCATION> island of <LOCATION> Eleuthera </LOCATION>. Root swam to a raft, where rescuers pulled him to safety. <PERSON> Geer </PERSON> said <PERSON> Root </PERSON> told him the bullet wound was not self-inflicted and could have occurred when the impact of the crash triggered a .32 - caliber pistol carried on board the single-engine <ORGANIZATION> Hollywood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Witt </PERSON> noted that a powder burn on Root's skin indicated the shot was fired at close range. Investigators said there was no evidence that anybody else was in the plane. <PERSON> Witt </PERSON> said surgeons had found a wound to Root's abdomen, and determined that a bullet passed through his colon, exited, struck him in the left arm and exited again. Authorities have received `` multiple phone calls'' from people in several states making `` various allegations that have not been confirmed,'' said <PERSON> Alston </PERSON>. He declined to give details, but said they came from private citizens and government agencies on topics that included <PERSON> Root </PERSON>'s finances and his piloting ability Root's wife, <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON>, 35, was in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> but has refused to comment on the episode. <PERSON> Alston </PERSON> said he hoped to interview Root's relatives. Authorities earlier had speculated that the <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, communications lawyer may have had a heart attack or inhaled carbon monoxide, causing him to black out about two hours after leaving <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> National Airport. <PERSON> Alston </PERSON> said Root reported in radio transmissions that he was having difficulty breathing, and then radio contact ceased. Capt. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Rahman </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> surgeon who first treated Root in <LOCATION> Nassau </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>, said he was shocked to learn a gunshot wound had been discovered by doctors at Memorial Hospital. <PERSON> Rahman </PERSON> said <PERSON> Root </PERSON> hestitated when asked to explain why he passed out. `` Looking back, now I see that he answered everything else promptly. I had to ask that question twice and he paused before answering, but I did n't think about it at the time,'' the doctor said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0313EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel-Prison     07-15 0636</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Prison,0656</SECOND>
<HEAD>Inside Jneid Prison, Palestinians Run Their Own State</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SERGEI SHARGORODSKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Behind the cement walls, barbed-wire fences and guard towers of Jneid prison, 850 tough Palestinian prisoners are running their own state. The prison, built on the barren hills near the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION>, is the largest for `` serious'' <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> guerrillas, those serving 20 years or more for attacks on Israeli targets. Among the inmates, dozens are serving life sentences, <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> said. The report Friday by the state television, the first time TV had been allowed to film inside the prison walls, showed something that looked more like a miniature state than a jail. The 850 inmates are kept in small, often crowded cells, each occupied by an average of 14 people. Jneid prison costs <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> more than $ 7.5 million a year. Unlike other prisons, there are reportedly no sexual assaults and no drugs in this one, practically run by a committee of six elected leaders. `` We have a committee of six prisoners who belong to different <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> factions. Each group has its own internal laws of selecting its representatives,'' said the prisoners' spokesman, <PERSON> Abdel </PERSON> <PERSON> Khader </PERSON> <PERSON> Fares </PERSON>. The committee was shown discussing prisoners' demands with warden <PERSON> Muffid </PERSON> <PERSON> Abbas </PERSON>, a Druse officer, and writing down a protocol of the talks. `` The prisoners are trying to expand all the time what they see as mini-autonomy. They demand improvements in all the fields: new teeth, union rights ... free passage from one prison section to another and a private doctor,'' the television said. <PERSON> Abbas </PERSON> said he usually responds positively to prisoners requests `` if it does not harm the security of the prison and if it is a human matter the prisoners need. They know it and they appreciate it.'' But Fares, serving a 15-year sentence for planting a bomb and a firearm attack on an Israeli bus, had a different opinion. He said inmates can pressure the authorities because of their influence on the <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> revolt that has raged for 19 months outside Jneid walls. `` They feel we are a honorable part of the Palestinian people in the -LRB- occupied -RRB- territories and we can influence the situation,'' he said. The prisoners refuse to work for the benefit of their Israeli enemies. But the discipline imposed by their leadership is tight and they clean their rooms, run the kitchen and have a tailor and a barber. The prison library has 4,000 books and the prisoners use it to conduct lessons in Hebrew, English, French, philosophy and Marxism, the television said. The prisoners also are allowed to spend 2 -LCB- hours in the prison courtyards. During one such break, prisoners were shown purposefully playing table tennis, basketball and chess or jogging around the courtyard. `` The terrorists view the prison as an academy for revolutionary education and for the creation of commanders,'' the television said. `` Every minute is reserved for useful conversations, studies, for strengthening the body and the spirit.'' <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Shoshan </PERSON>, an officer of the prison administration, said the prisoners `` have their own doctrine. They have a specific way of life: sport activities, reading, education. They want to leave the prison more educated.'' Fares said the prisoners view their miniature Jneid state as a step bringing the Palestinians closer to their goal of independence. `` We are inside prisons, but everybody knows we are part of the Palestinian people, part of the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. During family visits, held in a large hall separated by wire mesh, the prisoners' conversations are not monitored and it showed the inmates passing written notes described as `` instructions and reports,'' the television said. `` This is the heart of the prison, a link to the territories,'' the television said. `` And if you ask the prisoners, the uprising started here, in security prisons.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0346EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Romania-Rights     07-15 0198</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Romania-Rights,0202</SECOND>
<HEAD>Romania Bars U.N. Human Rights Investigator</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BERN, Switzerland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A U.N.-appointed special investigator on human rights in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> said that <LOCATION> Bucharest </LOCATION> has refused his request for an entry visa. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Voyame </PERSON>, a Swiss jurist named investigator for <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> last March by the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, said <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s communist authorities told him Friday that they consider the probe `` worthless.'' <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> has come under international fire for the treatment of its Hungarian minority and plans by President <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> _ apparently shelved now _ to raze thousands of villages in a `` rural consolidation'' program. <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, the first communist country subjected to special scrutiny by the <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, is not alone in barring its envoys. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> refuses them entry, as did <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> for years. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has denied U.N.-mandated human rights investigators access to the occupied Arab territories. <PERSON> Voyame </PERSON> told reporters he plans to travel to <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> to interview Romanian refugees there and expects to submit his report by December as scheduled. The <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> is due to debate the report at its annual meeting next February. <PERSON> Voyame </PERSON> said he has gathered information so far from private human rights groups and Romanian refugees in <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0406EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MilitaryHistorian Bjt   07-15 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Military Historian, Bjt,0721</SECOND>
<HEAD>Grandson of Military Historian S.L.A. Marshall Rebuts Damaging Article</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARRIE FIGDOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The question of whether Brig. Gen. S.L.A. <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> fabricated data in his book about <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers under fire is central to a debate raging between his critics and his grandson. In the renowned historian's 1947 `` Men Against Fire,'' <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> stated that as few as 15 percent of American infantry soldiers in World War II fired their weapons, for a variety of factors including paralyzing fear. The `` firing ratio'' finding led historians to change their emphasis in studying combat from the perspective of the commander to that of the common soldier, and helped prompt the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military to modify infantry training for the Korean and <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> wars. `` We think in a new way about combat because of <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Fredric </PERSON> <PERSON> Smoler </PERSON>, a historian at <ORGANIZATION> Sarah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lawrence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bronxville </LOCATION>, N.Y. But <PERSON> Smoler </PERSON> wrote in the March issue of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> magazine that <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>'s findings were merely a theory he had derived from anecdotal evidence, and not based on the authoritative study that <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> claimed. <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>'s thesis may have been based on evidence he `` made up,'' <PERSON> Smoler </PERSON> wrote. <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>'s grandson, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>, entered the fray late in May with a three-part series in the <ORGANIZATION> Seattle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post-Intelligencer </ORGANIZATION> that defended his ancestor's thesis and questioned the research of his detractors. <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>, a reporter for the newspaper, spent four weeks interviewing his grandfather's colleagues and searching archives. The younger <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> fell out with his grandfather during the Vietnam War when he was given an honorable discharge from the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> as a conscientious objector. In an interview last week, he said he conducted the investigation of his grandfather's work `` as a reporter, not a defender.'' `` American Heritage raised questions of methodology but they have n't refuted his basic thesis. The bigger issue is, was he right or was he wrong?'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> said. S.L.A. <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>, who died in 1977, wrote 30 books over his career as a reporter for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> and as military historian. Among his works are `` <LOCATION> Pork </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chop </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>,'' about the Korean war battle, and the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> history of World War I. But his most important contribution was the `` firing ratio,'' which he said was based on 400 to 600 post-battle interviews with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in World War II. <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Leinbaugh </PERSON>, a World War II infantry company commander and author, felt S.L.A. <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>'s work maligned American soldiers and conducted the research that initially questioned the basis of <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>'s hypothesis. The research by <PERSON> Leinbaugh </PERSON> and <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Spiller </PERSON>, a historian at the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s Command and <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Leavenworth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, showed no statistical evidence existed to back up <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>'s claim that most soldiers did n't fire in battle, <PERSON> Smoler </PERSON> wrote. `` It all pivoted on the fact that -LRB- <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> -RRB- said he had the statistical evidence to back it up. ... We're saying he did n't have the numbers to back himself up,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Snow </PERSON>, managing editor of American Heritage. <PERSON> Spiller </PERSON> said he was doing research at the S.L.A. Marshall Military History Collection at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION> for a possible biography of <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> and found no evidence of the studies <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> said he conducted. `` I would have been satisfied with tickmarks on a page of rough notes ... but I did not find some indication that he had done what he said he had done,'' <PERSON> Spiller </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. <PERSON> Spiller </PERSON> also interviewed <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Westover </PERSON>, a retired <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> professor of history and <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>'s assistant during his World War II research, who said he did n't recall conversations with <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> on the subject. <PERSON> Westover </PERSON> said <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> `` did not have the statistical evidence'' a social scientist would require to back the thesis. `` The statistics are made up out of the whole cloth, but the truth is there,'' he said in a telephone interview. <PERSON> Spiller </PERSON> said he disagreed with <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> and <PERSON> Westover </PERSON> in accepting `` impressionistic evidence'' as the basis for the theory. `` That's like saying it may not be the truth but it ought to be,'' he said, adding, `` I use his books in class and will continue to do so, but in a different way.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0411EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BastilleDayRdp     07-15 0583</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bastille Day Rdp,0604</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bastille Celebrations: Champagne Race, Frenchmen Honored, French
Bread Gifts</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-France-Bicentennial, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DONNELLY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 In <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, two French visitors became instant celebrities. <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> waiters raced with champagne. And passengers at a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> airport received loaves of French bread. Thousands of Americans on Friday celebrated the French's bicentennial of Bastille Day It marked the July 14, 1789, storming of the Bastille prison in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, the start of the French Revolution. But the celebration in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, beginning Friday and lasting through the weekend, opened with a problem _ no <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> representatives. <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Paris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> said she could n't lure <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> officials to the northeast <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> town of 27,000 for the celebration, which includes a bike race called the Tour de <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> So when French residents <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Claud </PERSON> <PERSON> Savouret </PERSON>, 57, and <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Perraut </PERSON>, 38, arrived at the festivities, they became honored guests. `` They'll be our special ambassadors,'' <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> said after meeting the two, who were visiting friends in the area. Said Perraut: `` I feel glad for us as Frenchmen to celebrate in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>.'' In <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, 115 waiters and waitresses carrying full bottles of champagne ran 11 blocks, opened the bubbly and served it with style to a panel of judges. They were after a free trip to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. Competitors, who also carried a glass of water and a <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> flag, had to finish with the water glass at least half-full and the champagne bottle intact. <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Niknam </PERSON>, 37, won. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Rojas </PERSON>, 23, a Colombian native, was second. `` I ran for the <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> people in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Rojas </PERSON> said. Passengers at a <LOCATION> LaGuardia </LOCATION> Airport terminal got loaves of French bread and the <ORGANIZATION> Parks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> presented `` Les Inconsolables,'' an accordian-and-torch song group, in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s celebration. Cast members from the Broadway musicals `` Les Miserables'' and `` Phantom of the Opera'' attended a Bastille Day luncheon to benefit a soup kitchen. There was one Bastille Day controversy in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, though: An <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> artist harboring a 13-year grudge burned a <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> flag in front of the French Consulate. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> <PERSON> Corey </PERSON> said he was protesting treatment of artists at an exhibit in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> held in December 1975 and January 1976. And in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Surrealist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> passed out leaflets denouncing the anniversary events as `` a trivialization of an important landmark of human freedom.'' One French-owned hotel in a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> suburb featured a giant guillotine made of cream puffs and a sugar model of the Bastille at its bicentennial celebration. In <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, three French climbers on Friday ascended the <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Teton </LOCATION>, the three peaks that cap the <LOCATION> Teton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Range </LOCATION>. Mountain guide <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> said the Bastille Day climb was a joint project with three Americans climbing in <LOCATION> Chamonix </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Blanc </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> said the Tetons were first discovered by French fur trappers in the early 1800s who named them `` Les Troix Tetons,'' meaning the three breasts. Farther west, at <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> racetrack in <LOCATION> Inglewood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, organizers of a bicentennial celebration on Sunday continued to build a 50-foot-high layer cake. The cake, which was to be attached to a frame today, was to include two models of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>' Arc de Triomphe stacked atop one another, with a version of the Eiffel Tower across the arcs. `` I think it's the largest cake you can build without a foundation system,'' said architect <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, one of its designers. Originally, the cake was planned for 100 feet, but that would have required a building permit.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890715-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-89 0454EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-Parties     07-15 0521</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Parties,0535</SECOND>
<HEAD>UFO Watchers, Other Fringe Politicians Take to The Airwaves</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JANICE FUHRMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
