<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 2330EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-BRF--InfantAbducted     10-24 0240</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Infant Abducted,240</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baby Abducted From Hospital Returned</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An infant abducted from a hospital pediatric ward was returned safely on Tuesday, about 24 hours after he was reported missing, and a woman who recently lost her own baby was arrested, authorities said. The infant, now 19 days old, appeared to have been well cared for and was in excellent condition, according to <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Chisholm </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> D.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON>, 23, of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, was charged with kidnapping, police said. She was scheduled for a <ORGANIZATION> D.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> appearance on Wednesday. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> recently lost a baby of her own and desperately wanted another, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Police Chief Deputy <PERSON> Alfonso </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> said. `` She did have a child that she had lost,'' <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> said. `` Apparently, she had a cradle and all of the necessities that's needed to care for an infant. The baby, who was up for adoption, was taken by a woman posing as hospital volunteer, police said. Police spokesman <PERSON> Quintin </PERSON> <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON> said detectives were led to Ms. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> after receiving tips from neighbors. Someone saw Ms. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> with a baby Tuesday, and knowing that she did n't have a child, called the police. She was arrested at her home, authorities said. Hospital officials said Tuesday new security measures were being considered. `` We are certainly going to take a look at some changes with regard to the check-in procedures and the identification of volunteers,'' Ms. <PERSON> Chisholm </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BakkerSentencing 6thLd-Writethru a0801 10-24 0937</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bakker Sentencing, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0801,0961</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bakker Sentenced to 45 Years, $500,000 Fine</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 10th graf, `Bakker was...,' with two grafs to UPDATE with
Bakker's arrival at prison. Picks up 11th graf, `Bakker's attorney...'.
INSERTS one graf after 20th graf, `Prosecutors didn't...'. to ADD that
judge didn't order restitution. Picks up 21st graf, `Bender, asked...'.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto CH2, LaserColor CH2C</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL NOWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLOTTE, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>, the television evangelist who lost his <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> empire in a sex scandal, was sentenced to 45 years in prison and fined $ 500,000 Tuesday for defrauding his followers for his own enrichment. `` I'm deeply sorry for those I have hurt,'' <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>, 49, said before he was sentenced by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Potter </PERSON>. `` I have sinned. But never in my life did I intend to defraud.'' <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> shook his head in disbelief while a federal prosecutor presented arguments, as did his daughter, <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Faye </PERSON>, did not attend the court session. <PERSON> Potter </PERSON> is nicknamed `` Maximum Bob'' after his reputation for harsh sentences, particularly in drug sentences. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> had faced a maximum sentence of 120 years, but the judge consolidated the 24 fraud and conspiracy counts to nine and sentenced <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> to five years on each. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> could be eligible for parole in 10 years. His lawyers said they would appeal, and despite defense pleas, <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> was immediately taken into custody and driven to the medium-security <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Talladega </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, about 60 miles east of <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION>. In handing down the sentence, <PERSON> Potter </PERSON> said, `` I'm concerned about the hundreds of letters I have here from people who say they'd do anything for him and that could include preventing Mr. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> from going to prison. I believe them.'' Because of that, he said, `` I think we're going to have to put him into custody.'' At that point, <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s daughter broke into sobs. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> was put in a holding cell, then taken away in a government sedan to <LOCATION> Talladega </LOCATION>. He arrived at the prison about 9:30 p.m. CDT and was led in handcuffs and shackles to the prison entrance. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> kept his eyes on the ground and did not comment as he was hustled inside surrounded by six guards. A prison official said <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> would probably be transferred to another prison in one or two weeks. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Bender </PERSON>, said his client was `` in as good spirits as he can be under the circumstances. Of course, he's concerned about the lengthy sentence but he has strong faith, and will come through. <PERSON> Bender </PERSON> said he had filed notice of appeal with the 4th <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, and would ask the court to free <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> on bond. Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s sentence `` sends a message that you ca n't use TV and the mails to make fraudulent statements to get people to send money to you. This is a simple fraud case.'' <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON>, the former church secretary whose sexual tryst with <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> led to the hush money scandal that caused him to lose control of <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> in 1987, said she was n't satisfied with the sentence. `` It can not repay those millions of dollars, and the years of work people did to make it, but at least it's a start,'' <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON> said in a telephone interview with The Associated Press from her <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hollwood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, home. `` At least people can feel like they wo n't be taken for fools `` How must they feel?'' she asked. `` The ones who gave millions, the people who took out loans? `` <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> supporter <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> said the sentence was not fair. `` <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s no crook. The news media made him look like one,'' she said. There was no sign of Mrs. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> or at the couple's home in <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, where the couple established a new church and television ministry Former defense attorney <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said the sentence was `` pretty heavy ... for a white-collar criminal. That's pretty startling.'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, who was interviewed by telephone in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> while awaiting a flight to his home in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, said he asked <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> to release him from the case before sentencing. Prosecutors did n't recommend a specific sentence, but asked <PERSON> Potter </PERSON> for a long sentence and a heavy fine, arguing that <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> has n't assumed responsibility for his crimes. The government also asked that <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> be ordered to repay up to $ 100 million in money donated by followers. <PERSON> Potter </PERSON> did not order <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> to make restitution, saying that issue needed to be resolved in bankruptcy court. <PERSON> Bender </PERSON>, asked <PERSON> Potter </PERSON> to consider alternatives to prison `` and allow this defendant the benefit of the court's compassion and mercy.'' <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> was convicted Oct. 5 on 23 counts of fraud and one count of conspiracy for selling lodging guarantees at his Christian retreat when he knew there were n't enough rooms available. The jury, which began hearing the case Aug. 28, found that <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> used more than $ 3.7 million of his followers' money to buy luxurious homes, fancy cars, jewelry and expensive vacations. Those who bought the lodging guarantees, called lifetime partners, sent him more than $ 158 million. The partners then were supposed to be entitled to three nights' lodging each year at the <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> retreat at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> resigned from the <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> on March 19, 1987, amid a sex and money scandal involving Ms. <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON>. During the trial, which lasted nearly six weeks, defense attorneys called 75 witnesses, including more than 50 who were loyal <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> supporters. Prosecutors called more than 100 witnesses, including many lifetime partners who had sent money _ usually $ 1,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 2352EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-SF-Quake-5:04 Bjt   10-24 0659</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF-Quake-5:04, Bjt,900</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Minute of Reflection on A Minute of Fear</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER SULLIVAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Beneath a cracked steeple, people prayed and embraced. By a flattened freeway, children played in the setting sun. As bells tolled, a man stared at the shards of his old piano. It was 5:04 p.m., and <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> took a minute for reflection on a minute of fear. Exactly one week after the Oct. 17 earthquake, the sound of church bells filled <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Eimers </PERSON> returned to the ruins of his <LOCATION> Marina </LOCATION> district apartment building, the focus of the <ORGANIZATION> Goodyear </ORGANIZATION> blimp's network camera as the structure blazed that night. `` I came back just to see. I wanted to get in and see what I could see, to put some kind of closure on the whole experience,'' <PERSON> Eimers </PERSON> said. His 1914 Steinway piano was barely discernible in the debris. Burned were 15 years of genealogical research on his family. Missing were his cats, <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON>. `` I'm still pretty numb,'' he said. The bells' tolling surprised <PERSON> Nicole </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinton </PERSON>, who was talking with a friend on steps next door to the city's 200-year-old Mission Dolores church. At 5:04, they happened to be discussing the quake. `` I'm refeeling the fear and terror of not knowing if my brother and sister-in-law are safe,'' she said. `` The feeling the world's not safe to walk on. Down the coast in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Holy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> is closed, a red tag marking a portal and the steeple cracked by the quake. `` We're not going to be saddened. We're going to rebuild, not out of fear but out of hope,'' Pastor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> said at an outdoor service at 5:04. Some of the 150 people present embraced, listening to readings from the Book of Genesis. All was quiet in <LOCATION> Candlestick </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, where light stands had shook and concrete had fallen in chunks a week before. At 5:04 Tuesday, construction workers were patching cracks, getting ready for Friday's restart of the World Series. They did n't seem to notice the time of day. It was sunset, and light winds wisped through the blue-collar neighborhood on the west side of sagging Interstate 880 in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>. Children played and giggled, regardless of the road's looming wreckage. Stopping his bike, an 8-year-old boy who gave his name only as <PERSON> Nate </PERSON> told how he'd watched as two men jumped and a truck fell from the buckling roadway a week earlier. At the <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> terminal of the <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>, where Buck Helm worked before I-880 fell on him, the yellow panel truck that was his home during the week remained parked where it always was. The rundown alarm clocks inside were n't ticking at 5:04. `` It's about that time, is n't it?'' said <PERSON> Basil </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, a ship's clerk like <PERSON> Helm </PERSON> who spent the moment thinking of him and of how they'd left work around the same time that night `` A train was crossing a set of tracks and he had to stop. That's when I passed him going up to the freeway,'' said <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, who saw the cloud of dust rise behind him from the collapse that would trap Helm for four days. `` I'm going home to celebrate. It's been one week. <PERSON> Momma </PERSON> has some of that apple juice with bubbles in it like champagne _ yeah, sparkling cider. I'll have a glass of sparkling cider.'' At 5:04 on Oct. 17, <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrice </PERSON> <PERSON> Cupples </PERSON> was 1 minute old. The quake shook the operating room where <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Cupples </PERSON> had just given birth by Caesarean section. Nurses struggled to keep their balance and protect mother and baby. Precisely a week later, Mrs. <PERSON> Cupples </PERSON> wondered if an aftershock would mark the moment. As for <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON>, she nestled in her mother's arms, nursing.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Contributing to this story were AP reporters <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Dvorchak </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Maclay </PERSON>, <PERSON> Catalina </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnard </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-SFQuake-Magnitude     10-24 0276</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-Magnitude,280</SECOND>
<HEAD>Magnitude Raised to 7.1 After Additional Readings Studied</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MENLO PARK, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The magnitude of the deadly earthquake that pelted <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> last week was increased from 6.9 to a 7.1 after seismologists studied additional monitoring charts, geophysicists said. The quake was recorded at 5:04 p.m. PDT on Oct. 17 and was blamed for the deaths of dozens of people, injuries to thousands and damage in excess of $ 7 billion. Besides altering the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale reading, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Geological Survey altered the epicenter and focal depth. `` The revised magnitude was based on more clearly defined data that was recorded at 18 selected seismic stations all over the world,'' Waverly Person, director of the <ORGANIZATION> USGS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Earthquake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Golden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, said in a statement Tuesday. `` The original magnitude of 6.9 was based on more localized seismic readings,'' the statement sid. The temblor was the largest quake to occur along the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Andreas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fault </LOCATION> since the 1906 <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> quake, <PERSON> Waverly </PERSON> said. That quake has been estimated at 8.3 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale of ground motion, although monitoring equipment had not been invented at that time. Thousands of aftershocks have rattled the <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Area </LOCATION> region in the week since the main quake. The epicenter of the quake was moved one mile northeast but was still in the <LOCATION> Loma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prieta </LOCATION> area, said <ORGANIZATION> USGS </ORGANIZATION> Geophysicist <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Pitt </PERSON>. Geologically, the most significant change in readings was the focal depth, originally measured at 12 kilometers but now believed to have been 18 kilometers, <PERSON> Pitt </PERSON> said. `` You measure from the surface down. It started at a depth of 18 kilometers and broke upward horizontally,'' he explained.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 0005EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-SFQuake-Volunteers     10-24 0589</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-Volunteers,Bjt</SECOND>
<HEAD>For Volunteers, It's A Job Well Done And Well Worth It</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANTHONY MARQUEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rather than just write out a check, volunteers toil every day at the <ORGANIZATION> Harrison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> warehouse, unloading emergency supplies, from toiletries to toys, donated from across the country. For many reasons, they drive to this two-story warehouse in the city's <LOCATION> South-of-Market </LOCATION> district to give their sweat and time, helping people they do not know at a time of great need. `` I did it for the feeling that I get,'' says <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Kay </PERSON>, 20, who came from <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mateo </LOCATION> on his day off from a <ORGANIZATION> Safeway </ORGANIZATION> store to help. <PERSON> Rodger </PERSON> <PERSON> Christopherson </PERSON>, 60, drove from his home in <LOCATION> Bevelry </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, 300 miles south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, to do his part. He worked 12 hours on Sunday, including a supply trip to quake-ravaged <LOCATION> Watsonville </LOCATION>. Still, the self-employed screenwriter and novelist shrugs off the long hours. `` I think it's much better to have a first-hand experience,'' he says. A dozen volunteers shuttled about the 10,000-square-foot warehouse on Monday, sorting boxes and bags filled with sleeping bags, blankets, clothes, canned food and drinks. Stacked along one wall of the damp warehouse are boxes with some 6,800 loaves of bread delivered overnight by the owner of a <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, bakery. Other walls are piled high with 10 - to 12-foot stacks of cereal, water, sodas and paper supplies Almost lost amid the supplies that litter the concrete floor is a single yellow toy truck. The toy is missing some parts, but it symbolizes the thousands of heartfelt gifts pouring in from all points. The public's generosity is not lost on the volunteers, such as <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Potrok </PERSON>, a 26-year-old sailor who came here with several other crew members of the San Diego-based U.S.S. <LOCATION> Schenectady </LOCATION>. `` With all the problems and stuff, you'd think people would be pretty tight. But people have been pretty good,'' says <PERSON> Potrok </PERSON>, as he sorts through a bag of clothes. Stories of good deeds are told and retold by volunteers. One found a hand-drawn, colored postcard inside a box of donated goods. Written in crayon, it said in child's printing: `` I hope you get your house back soon. <PERSON> Angie </PERSON>.'' And there's the story about the elderly woman who saved her money for a year to buy a nice down jacket, only to give it to a volunteer following the quake. `` She just said that she had open-heart surgery recently and it had taken her a year to buy it, and she felt that other people needed it more,'' recalls Major <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, divisional secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> oversees the volunteer organization at the warehouse. People have been good, he says. One gentleman stopped his car in front of the building, jumped out, and dropped off a television set. <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> accepted a gift of 90,000 pounds of potatoes from <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>. A woman in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> told him Monday she was sending a shipment of five boxes of toiletries by airplane. `` People are just very generous,'' says <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, wearing a red sweater over his white <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> uniform. `` They're very concerned about the needs of other people.'' He said 1,400 volunteers have pitched in to help at the <LOCATION> Harrison </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION> warehouse over the past four days. `` They've just been fantastic,'' says <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>. <PERSON> Christopherson </PERSON>, the screenwriter-volunteer, was asked if he had any advice f or anyone thinking of volunteers. `` I think just to be aware of other people's suffering,'' he said, `` and do what their conscience tells them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-FEMAReserves Bjt   10-24 0700</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-FEMA Reserves, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Retired People Help Disaster Agency Stretch</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARNARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OAKLAND, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> likes to be where the action is when disaster strikes. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Lytle </PERSON>'s wife wanted him out of her kitchen. Both retired, they are reservists for the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> who help the agency stretch when the pressure is on. Last month they were helping victims of Hurricane Hugo. Now they're pulling 12-hours shifts at the Veterans Memorial Building in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>, where <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> set up its disaster assistance center to handle applications for grants and low-interest loans. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 61, retired in June from the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> office in <LOCATION> Redding </LOCATION>, but has been a <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> reservist for three years. Before she retired, she saved up vacation time to work disasters. `` It's an organization that's there quickly and we like to be part of the action,'' said <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, who is assistant manager of the disaster assistance center here. <PERSON> Lytle </PERSON>, 78, of <LOCATION> Tempe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, a retired associated professor of agricultural engineering, has been a reservist 12 years. `` My wife said she married for better or worse, but not for lunch,'' said <PERSON> Lytle </PERSON>. `` She wanted to know, ` What are you going to do to stay out of my kitchen?''' Until recently, neither one had been sent to a disaster in more than a year and a half. On Sept. 1, <PERSON> Lytle </PERSON> was sent to <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, to a flood. Three weeks later, he was sent to <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, for Hurricane Hugo. A day at home and he was in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> to help open an earthquake disaster assistance center. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> was packed and ready to go to the Grand Canyon on vacation with her husband, <PERSON> Larry </PERSON>, another <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> reservist now working in <LOCATION> Monterey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, when the call came Sept. 24 for <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON>. `` We split our clothes into two suitcases and off we went to <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>,'' she said. Three weeks later, they both were sent to help out with the quake. `` We had a beautiful spring and summer at home,'' she said. `` I have n't been home at all this fall.'' Both find getting their laundry done one of the biggest challenges. `` If you go to a Laundromat, that's an hour you could be sleeping,'' <PERSON> Lytle </PERSON> said. Coast-to-coast diasters have stretched <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION>, but it has n't snapped yet, said spokesman <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> McAda </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> `` I sure do n't want to see it strained much more, though,'' <PERSON> McAda </PERSON> said. `` Right now I have laying on my desk a request for a disaster declaration from the state of <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>,'' where flood damages are estimated at $ 12 million, <PERSON> McAda </PERSON> said. `` We're about to find out whether we can -LRB- meet more demands -RRB- or not.'' The agency has 3,000 people assigned to Hurricane Hugo and the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> earthquake, he said. Of them, only 200 are full-time <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> employees. Six hundred are regular reservists who have been trained in advance and are called up in time of need. The remaining 2,200 are hired locally and get one day of training before being thrown in the breach. Hurricane damage has accounted for 350,000 disaster aid applications from <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, 8,000 from the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, 51,000 from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and 2,800 from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <PERSON> McAda </PERSON> said. A week after the earthquake struck <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area, 10,000 applications have come in from the 12 disaster centers in seven counties, said <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Rhoda </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>. More than 400 people of various specialties from the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> have been dispatched from around the country to verify disaster claims before <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> signs checks. The total number of applications from <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> and the earthquake alone amount to more than three years' worth under normal ccircumstances, <PERSON> McAda </PERSON> said. `` I do n't think our people would ever admit they have reached their limit. Somewhere down the line you will run out of manpower, but I do n't know where that is,'' he said. `` Do you put together an agency that is big enough to handle the current situation, then sit around and do nothing for a year? That's not very effecive.'' Instead, <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> lets people like <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lytle </PERSON> do the sitting around. `` I just sit at home and rock slowly'til they call me,'' <PERSON> Lytle </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 0052EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     10-24 0818</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0856</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Busfield </PERSON>, who has gained fame as an actor in <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION>'s `` thirtysomething,'' says a little applause is needed for the most important people in theater _ producers. `` The producer is the least egotistical person,'' <PERSON> Busfield </PERSON> said during a weekend appearance at the <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> Governor's Conference on the Arts. `` And if he is effective, he gets artistic performances out of everybody. You need to find good producers to spread good producers across the state.'' Next in line are writers, directors and designers, said <PERSON> Busfield </PERSON>, who holds a theater degree from <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and conducts summer workshops for young people at the school. `` The actor is the lowest one on the totem pole, and the most recognized, sometimes unrightfully so,'' <PERSON> Busfield </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Busfield </PERSON>, 32, has worked as a producer, writer and director for the Fantasy Theater, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s 4-year-old state theater for children. On `` thirtysomething,'' he plays <PERSON> Elliot </PERSON> <PERSON> Weston </PERSON>, a yuppie that <PERSON> Busfield </PERSON> has said `` does n't want to grow up.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: `Rumer' is cq.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> says he's not nostalgic for his wild and crazy bachelor days. `` I like what -LRB- mythologist -RRB- <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> says about marriage,'' the actor said in an interview in Fame magazine's November issue `` He says that it's nothing more than a symbol for the sacrifice of the ego and of the individual towards something larger, which is the union that is made from two individual egos.'' The 34-year-old <PERSON> Willis </PERSON>, who is married to actress <PERSON> Demi </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> and the father of their young daughter, <PERSON> Rumer </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, said he has n't lost anything `` And I've gained a hundredfold,'' he said. `` My little child is the light of my life, is the best thing that I've ever done and the most spiritual thing that I've ever done.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Author <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Vonnegut </PERSON> made a surprise visit to the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION>, where he was a cub reporter more than 40 years ago. `` It was delightful talking to him,'' said managing editor <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Zimbrakos </PERSON>, who started working at the bureau in 1958, after <PERSON> Vonnegut </PERSON>'s time. City News is wire service owned by <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s major daily newspapers and serves as a training ground for young journalists. He said <PERSON> Vonnegut </PERSON> was impressed with the bureau's new look since the days when he worked there as a reporter in 1947. `` His first question was, ` Where are the tubes?''' <PERSON> Zimbrakos </PERSON> said, referring to the pneumatic tubes that City News once used to transmit stories to clients. <PERSON> Vonnegut </PERSON> stopped at the bureau's office Monday while on a business trip. The 66-year-old author's novels include `` Slaughterhouse Five'' and `` Cats Cradle.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MONTREAL (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Opera star <PERSON> Luciano </PERSON> <PERSON> Pavarotti </PERSON> kept singing and singing and singing _ for a half-hour worth of encores at a sold-out fund-raising concert for the <ORGANIZATION> Montreal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION>. Among Sunday's appreciative audience was former prime minister <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Trudeau </PERSON>, who received birthday greetings at an after-concert dinner and dance. <PERSON> Trudeau </PERSON>, who turned 70 last week, said the concert was `` beautiful.'' `` It was very generous of <PERSON> Pavarotti </PERSON> to give as many encores as he did,'' <PERSON> Trudeau </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Serge </PERSON> <PERSON> Savard </PERSON>, general manager of the <ORGANIZATION> Montreal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canadiens </ORGANIZATION> hockey team, said he enjoyed the concert even though he never goes to the opera. He compared the 54-year-old <PERSON> Pavarotti </PERSON> to hockey's Great One. `` I guess you could say that <PERSON> Pavarotti </PERSON> is the <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Gretzky </PERSON> of opera,'' <PERSON> Savard </PERSON> said. The recital was expected to raise about $ 700,000 for the orchestra. Fans paid up to $ 1,500 for tickets.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DELRAY BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Chevy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chase </PERSON> has been released from a hospital where he was kept under observation after complaining of chest pains during a benefit tennis tournament in nearby <LOCATION> Boca </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Raton </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Chase </PERSON>, 46, was taken by ambulance to <ORGANIZATION> Delray </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday afternoon after playing a practice round with tennis star <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Evert </PERSON>, sponsor of the tournament to raise funds for a non-profit drug abuse foundation. The former `` Saturday Night Live'' star, suffering from dehydration and fatigue, underwent tests before his release Monday, said hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Koller </PERSON>. `` When he left the hospital he looked just like he does on TV,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Koller </PERSON>. `` He was in good spirits.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A kinder, gentler <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>? So says <ORGANIZATION> CNBC </ORGANIZATION> officials who are starting a half-hour weeknight series featuring <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> called `` Showdown.'' The 55-year-old <PERSON> Downey </PERSON>, whose syndicated talk show was canceled last summer after losing sponsors and declining ratings, will regularly debate social and consumer issues with <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> columnist <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> before a studio audience. Other guests also will join the debates. <ORGANIZATION> CNBC </ORGANIZATION> said Monday, however, that the show wo n't resemble the loud, boisterous, often insult-filled series that gained <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> national attention. <ORGANIZATION> CNBC </ORGANIZATION> president <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Eskridge </PERSON> said the new series `` will not be ` The <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>. Show' revisited. <ORGANIZATION> CNBC </ORGANIZATION> is an NBC-owned cable service. `` Showdown'' premieres Dec. 4.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-SFQuake-Graves     10-24 0433</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-Graves,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Earthquake Rocks Santa Cruz-Area Cemeteries</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WATSONVILLE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Coffins were jostled and tombstones were toppled by the hundreds in graveyards when the earth groaned during last week's 7.1-magnitude earthquake. The <PERSON> Virgin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> and other religious icons, sentinals over a century-old graveyard near midtown here, tumbled to the ground and cemetery managers called off all burials until repairs can be made. `` Some of the marble monuments are shattered and they will be very difficult to repair. The granite ones we can stand up again, though,'' said <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> Dias </PERSON>, manager for the five <PERSON> Santa </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruz </PERSON> County-operated cemeteries. The five cemeteries _ <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, Pioneer, <ORGANIZATION> Watsonville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> and Day Valley _ hold 20,000 bodies dating to 1860. Hardest hit was <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cemetery </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boulevard </ORGANIZATION>. A huge pepper tree is the centerpiece of the two-acre garden of marble and granite where most graves bear the inscription: `` Rest in Peace.'' `` We suffered extensive damage to the upright stones in four cemeteries,'' said Dias. Valley Cemetery was spared damage because only flat markers are allowed. <PERSON> Dias </PERSON> said the cemeteries had received dozens of telephone calls from concerned relatives. Graveyard officials assured them repairs would be swift. <PERSON> Dias </PERSON> said cemetery workers were trying to clear away debris and repair damage. On a cold and rainy Tuesday one week after the disaster, there were no visitors in the cemetery. `` At this time we are holding off on burials to the end of the week,'' he said. `` We have holding vaults for them now.'' He estimated up to 500 markers were toppled in the quake that killed dozens, injured thousands and caused more than $ 7 billion in damage to <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. The aged <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cemetery </ORGANIZATION> was littered with fractured madonnas and <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> statues. The face of a 3-foot-tall marble <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Magdalen </PERSON> was buried in the grass. Ornate marble crosses were shattered to bits. Many concrete-covered gravesites were cracked. In some cases, there had been cave-ins. Well-manicured lawns surrounded family plots where concrete and plastic flowers were bleached by the sun and upended by the quake. The four-space <PERSON> Stolieh </PERSON> family crypt is only half full. The two empty crypts have shattered granite doors. An ornate, 10-foot-tall marble marker honoring <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dail </PERSON>, who died Jan. 31, 1888, toppled. The tombstone of <PERSON> Cary </PERSON> <PERSON> Freirmuth </PERSON>, who died in 1929, was upside down and in the mud. The marble cross over <ORGANIZATION> Thereza </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gonzalves </ORGANIZATION>' grave was shattered. It had withstood the 1906 <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> quake. She died Oct. 13, 1885. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahoney </PERSON> died April 19, 1874. His marble marker was also destroyed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hungary-Neighbors Bjt   10-24 0657</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hungary-Neighbors, Bjt,0675</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hard-Line Communists In Czechoslovakia and Romania Unnerved By Hungary's
Path</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY5</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALISON SMALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In 1956, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> sent tanks and soldiers into <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> to crush an anti-communist revolt. Now, with <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> declaring itself a democracy and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> coping with its own internal turmoil, the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> is deafeningly quiet. With <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> also absorbed in their own turbulent politics, it has been left to <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s orthodox neighbors, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, to sound the communist alarm about the historic events in <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION>. Their concern is compounded by worries about the reaction of their own large ethnic Hungarian minorities, who were able to follow commemorations of the 1956 Hungarian uprising on live Hungarian television broadcasts Monday. A `` political coup d'etat,'' thundered the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> daily Pravda in <LOCATION> Slovakia </LOCATION> on Monday, commenting on a historic parliamentary session in <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> that rewrote the Hungarian constitution to embrace democracy and pave the way for free elections next year. <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> so far has been silent about that session and Monday's rallies, in which more than 100,000 Hungarians cheered the proclamation of a democratic republic on the 33rd anniversary of their popular uprising But President <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, perhaps the staunchest communist ideologue in the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc, last week denounced <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s path. He pledged <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> would never follow the same course toward a free market. At odds with <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> for years over charges that <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> is harassing its 1.7 million ethnic Hungarians, <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> is bound to be further unsettled by the strident demands for democracy voiced in <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> on Monday. A unique race in central <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, with no linguistic bonds to neighboring Slavs and Germans, Hungarians have a tradition of maneuvering for the maximum freedom despite dominance by stronger neighbors. This history has also made them fiercely nationalistic, a pride that has not died in the extensive former Hungarian territories now incorporated in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>'s tough rule has so far kept ethnic Hungarian yearnings for more freedom from combining with widespread discontent at food and fuel shortages to ignite major outbreaks of unrest such as that which occurred in the <LOCATION> Transylvanian </LOCATION> city of <LOCATION> Brasov </LOCATION> in November 1987, when 10,000 angry workers took to the streets in protest. While <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> bristle, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> turns the other cheek. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s reticence toward the dramatic changes in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> confirm that President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, plagued by strikes and ethnic unrest at home, is sticking to his policy of non-interference in eastern <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Referring to <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s ruling <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s decision to disband and form a <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> that espouses democratic ideals, Soviet East European expert <PERSON> Oleg </PERSON> <PERSON> Bogomolov </PERSON> wrote in the Oct. 15 edition of the weekly <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, `` Obviously, difficulties lie ahead. As it appears, the new party will be sailing in stormy and hazardous waters.'' <PERSON> Bogomolov </PERSON> is credited with helping forge the new Soviet attitude toward its allies. In his commentary, he insisted on only one point: that Hungarians `` must n't question the existence of the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact and their contacts'' within the Soviet trading bloc. Similar assurances from Solidarity labor leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> helped lead to the August nomination of non-communist Prime Minister <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s reform-minded leaders hope to stave off the resounding defeat suffered by the Polish Communists in June elections, adopting a program of radical economic and political change in an effort to win popular support. However, the pace of change in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> is so swift that opinion polls indicate its current leaders will at best be only partners in a coalition government after elections. The Soviets, and the rest of eastern <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, will then have to deal with the implications of another ouster of communism through the ballot box.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Alison </PERSON> <PERSON> Smale </PERSON>, chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Vienna </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has reported on Soviet bloc affairs from <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> since 1980.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 0104EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Baker-Soviets Bjt   10-24 0488</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Baker-Soviets, Bjt,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baker Calls for Sharp Reductions in First-Strike Nuclear Weapons</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Reducing first-strike nuclear weapons is the top goal set by Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet negotiators trying to complete a new arms reduction treaty. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> singled out the deadliest missiles in superpower arsenals, capable of devastating an enemy in a surprise attack, during a speech Monday in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. He also urged the Soviets to join in a strategy shift to defense. `` We want to see Soviet defensive military operations made habitual,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said in his first in-depth description of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's goals for negotiations under way in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> to cut strategic weapons _ bombers, missiles and nuclear submarines _ on both sides. He said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would explore `` a cooperative and stable transition to a greater reliance on stability-enhancing, cost-effective strategic defense.'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s emphasis on reducing first-strike weapons, such as Soviet SS-18 intercontinental ballistic missiles, signals a subtle shift from the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's stress on across-the-board strategic cuts. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> made no reference to the 30 percent to 50 percent cutback <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> negotiators have been aiming for in the Strategic Arms Reduction Talks. Some analysts, such as former Secretary of State <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>, have urged greater emphasis on slashing first-strike weapons such as the Soviet SS-18s. Designed to destroy an adversary's ballistic missiles in their silos, first-strike nuclear weapons have a potential of wreaking havoc on the other side's nuclear forces. Former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> responded to a perceived Soviet threat by beginning a defensive program, known popularly as Star Wars, designed to destroy Soviet ballistic missiles in space before they could destroy their targets. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, in his speech, encouraged the Soviets to concentrate their efforts on defense as well, while the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration pursues the Strategic Defense Initiative. He said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> goal in the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> talks was `` a new relationship in which the capabilities and incentives to attack first are minimized and the possibilities of strategic defense are pursued.'' He said the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration had tailored its proposals in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> to emphasize the relative merits of slow-flying weapons, such as cruise missiles and bombers that are not suitable for a first strike. At the same time, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> urged a skeptical <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to approve a <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> request for $ 100 million to produce mobile Midgetman missiles. Otherwise, he said, the Soviets could exploit differences between <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> and the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> eliminated the request from the $ 305 billion defense authorization bill, but the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> gave its approval for the funds. A congressional conference committee is trying to reconcile this and other differences. `` <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> needs now to support START, not undercut it, by funding this program,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> had planned to speak to the private <ORGANIZATION> Commonwealth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> on arms control last Thursday, but the speech was postponed because of the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area earthquake.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 0118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WeaponsPlants Bjt   10-24 0563</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Weapons Plants, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Embargoed for release 10 a.m. EDT; time set by source</HEAD>
<HEAD>Report Says DOE Downplayed Key Problems at Rocky Flats Arms Plant</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Energy Department underestimated or ignored health and safety problems at the Rocky Flats nuclear arms plant as it gave the operator millions of dollars in bonus fees, federal auditors said today. A report by the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, the investigative arm of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, said in the fiscal years 1986-88, <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> won $ 26.8 million in award fees for running the plant, which has been under <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> investigation for alleged criminal violation of environmental laws since June. `` We believe that the seriousness of the -LRB- environmental, safety and health -RRB- problems ... were never conveyed in the evaluations'' of the plant's performance, the report concluded. <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> announced last month that it was withdrawing from the plant, and the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Oct. 11 that <ORGANIZATION> EG </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> G </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> had agreed to take over Jan. 1. The plant makes plutonium triggers for nuclear warheads and is owned by the government. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> report was being released today during a House Government Operations subcommittee hearing on <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> problems with the private companies that run major nuclear weapons facilities in 12 states under government contracts. Many of the contracts, including that at <ORGANIZATION> Rocky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Flats </ORGANIZATION>, reimburse the company for all operating costs and allow bonus fees based on performance in key areas, including production of arms materials and compliance with health and safety rules. The fees are set during semiannual performance evaluations. Rep. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Synar </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., chairman of the subcommittee, said Monday that the terms of the <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> contract made it difficult for the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to effectively manage the plant about 16 miles from downtown <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> <PERSON> Synar </PERSON> said the Rocky Flats problem was typical of management weaknesses throughout the nuclear weapons manufacturing complex, which includes 17 major plants. `` The department effectively has left itself no way to control the performance of its contractors or to hold them fully accountable for their actions,'' <PERSON> Synar </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said the $ 26.8 million in bonus fees for <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> during the 1986-88 period represented 84 percent of the total awards possible under its contract. In this period, the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s operations office in <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, rated <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION>'s health and safety performance as `` moderately good'' to `` excellent.'' The report said that while <PERSON> Rockwell </PERSON> rightly was applauded for holding down the number of work days lost due to injury, fire loss and property losses, some of its shortcomings in the health and safety area were underestimated or ignored. Among the problems downplayed by the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, according to the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> report, were an inadequate health physics program, repeated violations of environmental regulations and the `` questionable quality'' of the monitoring data used to comply with environmental laws. Under the Energy Department award fee system, <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> was encouraged to increase production at Building 771, the main plutonium processing center, despite safety problems there. About two months before Building 771 was shut down due to safety problems in October 1988, the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> awarded <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> $ 310,000 for increased plutonium production, the report said. The building resumed production in January. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> noted that <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> has substantially changed the terms of management contracts at some weapons facilities since he took office in March, and that further adjustments were planned.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Kemp-Fed     10-24 0444</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Kemp-Fed,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kemp Advocates More Influence Over Fed</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Housing Secretary <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> says elected administration officials should have more influence over interest rate policies set by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, a longtime critic of the nation's independent central bank, told the annual convention of the <ORGANIZATION> Mortgage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bankers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> that he favors putting the treasury secretary on the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> board and forcing it to announce its monetary policy decisions immediately. `` I believe sunlight on the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>'s operations is called for. I also believe the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> could use some input from the democratically elected executive branch,'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said Monday. He endorsed legislation sponsored by Reps. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, D-Ind., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorgan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.D. </LOCATION>, that would require the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> to release the decisions of its policymaking <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Open </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Market </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> immediately rather than waiting for six weeks, the current practice Originally, <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dorgan </PERSON> wanted to place the treasury secretary on the open market committee, which meets eight times a year to set interest rate and monetary policy. However, <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> has said he will modify the bill to instead require two meetings a year between the open market committee and senior administration officials. The <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>, an independent body whose members are appointed by the president but ca n't be removed by him during their 14-year terms, has long been the target of critics who allege it favors high interest rates to fight inflation at the expense of jobs and economic growth. `` Interest rates are too high either by long - or short-term historical perspectives,'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said `` I believe the best thing the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> can do for the economy is to allow it to grow at a healthy rate by keeping interest rates down.'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s comments follow statements in recent months from President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his budget director, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>, both of whom have pushed for lower interest rates. A housing secretary usually would not comment on monetary policy, leaving that to either the treasury secretary or the president's chief economic adviser. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, however, is a former <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and candidate for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> presidential nomination who has a longstanding interest in the subject and has frequently criticized the central bank. The Hamilton-Dorgan bill is one of two measures that will receive a hearing Wednesday before the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Banking subcommittee on domestic monetary policy. The other, sponsored by Rep. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Neal </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.C. </LOCATION>, is a resolution exhorting the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> to set a target of reaching non-inflationary economic growth within five years. <PERSON> Neal </PERSON>'s resolution is supported by <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON>, who is scheduled to testify at the hearing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HUD-Demery     10-24 0527</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-HUD-Demery,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former HUD Official Says He Did Nothing Wrong in Advising Bush Campaign</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former top housing official says he did nothing improper in providing campaign debate advice to <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> last year while administering a program now at the center of the <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> scandal. Former assistant housing secretary <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> provided debating points on housing, using documents from computer files in his office at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, according to <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> and documents released by the department Monday under the Freedom of Information Act. <PERSON> Demery </PERSON>'s contact with the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign was Republican consultant <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Manafort </PERSON>, who has admitted to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that he practiced `` influence-peddling'' at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Manafort </PERSON> is a partner in a disputed <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> housing development that received more than $ 31 million in federal subsidies. He has acknowledged to congressional investigators that he lobbied <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> on more than 20 other projects. <PERSON> Demery </PERSON>, in an interview, said he did not believe <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> used the debate material. In other documents, <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> said he delivered campaign speeches for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, sometimes while traveling on <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> business. <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> administered the department's Section 8 Moderate Rehabilitation program, which provided lucrative subsidy grants sought by developers, including <PERSON> Manafort </PERSON> and <PERSON> Manafort </PERSON>'s clients. Alleged abuses of the moderate rehabilitation program, including the steering of lucrative subsidy grants to politically favored developers, triggered further investigations of <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> programs by congressional committees, and the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says it is investigating <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> activities across the nation. In the interview, <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> acknowledged providing tips for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s debates with Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> He contended there was nothing improper about providing political advice while working at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> because he was a presidential appointee, named by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. In one document, he said that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the governor of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, `` has presided over de facto segregation'' in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> public housing and said the city `` still contains some of the last vestiges of segregation in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> today.'' <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> was sharply criticized in a <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> audit report issued by inspector general <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> last May. The audit charged favoritism in the awarding of moderate rehabilitation grants and questioned his efforts to raise money from developers and others dealing with <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> for a favored charity, FOOD for <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> contends others made the subsidy decisions and that his activities for the charity were proper. <PERSON> Demery </PERSON>'s files contained letters he wrote to <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> last year defending his actions and questioning the investigation. He wrote one letter to <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sessions </PERSON> complaining about the inspector general's investigation, but he said Monday he never mailed it. <PERSON> Demery </PERSON>'s letter charged that his mail had been intercepted and the documents involving his personal finances eventually were obtained by the inspector general. Other documents show that <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> complained to then-Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> about the activities of <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cushing </PERSON>, then deputy assistant secretary for multi-family housing, and reprimanded <PERSON> Cushing </PERSON> directly for poor work. <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> contends that although <PERSON> Cushing </PERSON> reported to him, <PERSON> Cushing </PERSON> was engaged in political work and worked with <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s former top aide. Dean, <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cushing </PERSON> have all refused to testify before congressional investigators, citing their constitutional rights against self-incrimination.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 0131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     10-24 0398</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0413</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sheriff <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Leis </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> started an internal television system to inform prisoners on such things as the rules of the <ORGANIZATION> Hamilton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. But the system has given rise to jailhouse entertainers who have messages for fellow prisoners _ and the sheriff. The close-circuit channel, which has operated for about three weeks, was made available for in-house videos after officials found out prisoners wanted to sing, dance and recite poetry, said sheriff's spokesman <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Weikel </PERSON>. Five women inmates, in a performance they call `` Stay Out of Jail,'' sing, `` We ca n't keep losing time by doing all kinds of crime. So make up your mind right now to do it right. Do n't you wan na stay out of jail?'' <PERSON> Delores </PERSON> <PERSON> Madden </PERSON>, 29, who is charged with receiving stolen property, said the performers were trying to give a message to young people. `` This is no place to be,'' she said. The five singers apparently also hope the sheriff was paying attention. They ended their song with a plea: `` <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Leis </PERSON>, please hear me. Please release me real soon. We need to stay out of jail. It's hard to make bail.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>EAU CLAIRE, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ericka </PERSON> and <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> say their only regret about their wedding day is they failed to catch the names of two strangers who returned a few thousand dollars in missing wedding gifts. The Howards, who were married Saturday, were about to leave the reception about 1 a.m. Sunday when an unknown man and woman drove up to the reception hall. The man asked if a bride named <PERSON> Ericka </PERSON> was in the group and then handed over all the cards with money the Howards had received as gifts earlier in the day. `` I could n't believe it,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said Monday. `` I just about died.'' The basket containing the cards apparently was left on a car roof. When the car drove off, the cards blew onto a highway. A man collected the cards, which were in a ditch off <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> 37, and brought them back to their rightful owners. Mrs. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>, who along with her husband is 19, said she did n't get the men's names because she was so rattled `` They just kept saying ` it's a miracle and praise be to God' and that we should n't let it bother us and just be happy,'' she said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 0121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SFQuake-FEMA     10-24 0660</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-FEMA,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quake Aid Offered for Everything From Home-Rebuilding to Mental Counseling</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: May be updated with House action on aid bill</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The billions of dollars that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> wants to give <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s earthquake victims will be used for a range of relief and recovery programs, from home-rebuilding loans to mental health counseling. Families whose homes are uninhabitable can seek money to pay for temporary housing, while special loans are available to small businesses that need quick capital and local governments can get aid in repairing public buildings and parks. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is rushing to approve a $ 2.85 billion aid package for the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area, and members say more money could come later. Shortly after the earthquake struck <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> a week ago, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> signed a disaster declaration that freed up $ 273 million for emergency programs, but members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> immediately said a major aid package would be needed. Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, D-Calif., estimated the damage at $ 7 billion, but said Monday that he did n't expect the federal government to pay that much Under some federal programs, the state of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> will kick in 25 percent of the cost. Others are fully funded by the federal government. <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION>, which coordinates recovery programs, provided the following information about available programs. The amount of money spent on each program depends on how many applications are received. The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> gives money for the repair or reconstruction of highways.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>The president's disaster relief fund, administered by FEMA,</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 includes: _ Temporary housing assistance: Reasonable payments for families whose homes are uninhabitable Aid is available for 18 months, with payments based on prevailing rental rates. _ Home repairs: Payments to make minor repairs to make housing usable _ Individual and family grants: Up to $ 10,400 per individual or family to meet serious disaster needs and expenses not covered by other federal assistance programs The federal government pays 75 percent; the state the rest. _ Disaster unemployment assistance: Benefit payments for up to 26 weeks, based on state benefit rates, for workers who lost their jobs because of the disaster or others who are not covered by state compensation _ Crisis counseling: <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> provides short-term counseling for mental health problems _ Public property: <ORGANIZATION> Reimbursable </ORGANIZATION> payments to local governments of at least 75 percent of the eligible costs for the repair and replacement of damaged public facilities such as roads, bridges, utilities, buildings and parks _ Community disaster loans: The loans are not to exceed 25 percent of the annual operating budget of any local government which has suffered a substantial loss of tax or other revenue as a result of a major disaster
</TEXT>
<NOTE>The Small Business Administration has two programs:</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 _ Disaster loans: Low-interest loans of 4 percent to 8 percent to cover uninsured private and business property losses Ceilings are $ 100,000 for primary residence; $ 20,000 for personal property, and $ 500,000 for businesses. Length of repayment can be extended 30 years. _ Economic injury disaster loans: Up to $ 500,000 for small businesses that suffered disaster-related cash flow problems and need loans for working capital This loan, in combination with a physical property loan, can not exceed $ 500,000.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>The Department of Agriculture offers three programs:</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 _ Emergency loans: <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> gives loans to cover physical property and production losses Limits are 80 percent of the sum of the calculated production loss, and-or 100 percent of the actual physical property loss, or $ 500,000, whichever is less. Interest rates vary between 5 percent and 8 percent. _ Emergency conservation: Payments of up to $ 200,000 for repair of items such as permanent fencing, debris removal or irrigation systems _ Emergency watershed protection: Financial aid to eliminate the imminent threat to life due to damage to a watershed Money is available to governments.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>The Department of Education has two programs:</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 _ Grants to public schools damaged by a disaster _ Grants for maintenance and operation expenses, such as replacement of equipment, debris removal and minor building repairs
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 0122EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NuclearDeals     10-24 0677</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuclear Deals,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Utilities Report Deals With Nuclear Workers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At least three electric utilities admit making deals with nuclear plant workers that could be seen as rewarding them for not reporting potential safety problems, government records show. All three companies insisted in letters to the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> that the labor settlements were legal and proper, but they acknowledged some provisions might be viewed as `` silence-for-money'' deals. <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> GPU </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Parsippany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>; and <ORGANIZATION> Omaha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Omaha </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, disclosed the agreements in response to an <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> inquiry last spring aimed at determining if such deals are common in the industry. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has criticized the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> for failing to explicitly outlaw such settlements. The controversy stemmed from a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> investigation last spring of two labor settlements between builders of the Comanche Peak nuclear power plant in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and workers who received payments in return for keeping quiet about potential safety hazards. The <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> later ruled that such settlement provisions were unacceptable, but the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> commissioners have been unable to agree how and whether to outlaw them. In April, the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> sent letters to all nuclear utilities and their contractors asking to be told of any labor settlements that restricted an employee's ability to report safety information to the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>. A review Monday of the written responses from the utilities and contractors showed all denied having any such restrictions. However, the three companies said they had settlements with provisions that might be construed by others as limiting a worker's ability to raise safety concerns <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> <PERSON> Power </PERSON> was the only utility to provide specific information about a settlement. It said it felt compelled to report the case to the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> `` in light of the sensitivity of the issue,'' even though it believes the settlement was proper. The case involves an April 21, 1988, settlement with former employee <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, who filed a civil suit against <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> after he was dismissed in October 1983. In a passage similar to a provision of the Comanche Peak settlement, the <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> settlement stipulated that <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> `` will not voluntarily appear as a witness'' in any legal or administrative proceeding involving <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>. It also said he would not `` seek to induce any government agency'' to take any action against <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>. <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> these passages were designed to settle the <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> suit. The deal `` clearly left Mr. <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> free ... to bring any concerns to the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> ... if he so desired,'' <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> wrote to the commission. <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> said it wrote to <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> in July saying he is free to bring any safety matter to the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> operates three plants in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> GPU </ORGANIZATION> Nuclear and <ORGANIZATION> Omaha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION>, in separate letters to the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>, said that while they found no restrictive clauses in their labor settlements, the language in four settlement agreements might be viewed as restricting the individual's ability to raise potential safety issues with the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>. The utilities provided no details, but said they advised the people involved to disregard any settlement language that they thought limited their ability to raise safety issues. <ORGANIZATION> GPU </ORGANIZATION> Nuclear owns the <LOCATION> Three </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mile </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> nuclear station in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Oyster </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> plant in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Omaha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> owns the <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Calhoun </LOCATION> nuclear plant in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Newlin </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said Monday the commission wrote letters to people involved in questionable settlements. A few of them wrote back to the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> about safety issues, but <PERSON> Newlin </PERSON> said he could not provide details. Five other companies said that while they saw no problems with any of their labor settlement deals, they wrote to people involved in 11 cases to emphasize that they were under no limits in contacting the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> about safety issues. The five are <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lighting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Light </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Raleigh </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 0122EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;LWithdrawals     10-24 0436</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;L Withdrawals,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>$5.1 Billion Drained from Savings Accounts in August</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's thrift institutions allowed $ 5.1 billion to drain from savings accounts in August, a move an analyst says is a positive sign. `` Shrinkage is the order of the day,'' said <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Ely </PERSON>, a private thrift analyst in <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> `` It's the only effective way that marginal S & amp; Ls can meet the higher capital requirements.'' Thrift legislation, signed Aug. 9 by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, requires institutions to hold more capital for every loan or other investment they make. If an institution can not earn enough profits to add to capital or raise it from outside investors, its only alternative is to scale back operations before the new standards go into effect Dec. 7. Deposit outflows, which do n't include interest credited to savers' accounts, totaled $ 5.1 billion, compared with an inflow of $ 54 million in July. It was the highest level of withdrawals since $ 5.3 billion left thrift accounts in April, the Office of Thrift Supervision reported. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Barth </PERSON>, chief economist of the thrift office, said the deposit outflow, as well as a record $ 13.4 billion reduction in assets, largely reflected a deliberate strategy by the industry. `` This was the third consecutive month in which thrifts ... shed assets to adjust to the new regulatory environment,'' <PERSON> Barth </PERSON> said. Thrift holdings of mortgages and mortgage-backed securities fell by $ 7.8 billion in August, while cash and investment securities dropped $ 3 billion. The data shows that mortgages originated by thrifts rose to $ 16.4 billion in August, up from a six-year low of $ 13.2 billion in July. However, the institutions are selling an increasing proportion of the mortgages to investors and retaining fewer in their portfolios. Savers withdrew a record $ 10.8 billion from thrifts in January and net withdrawals have exceeded $ 1 billion in every month except July. In the first eight months of the year, $ 44.5 billion drained from thrifts. August marked the 15th month of withdrawals in the 16 months beginning in May 1988. The earlier outflows were attributed to interest rates, which were rising through the spring, and to depositor uncertainty about the S & amp; L bailout. With the August report, the thrift office for the first time began reporting separate statistics for insolvent S & amp; Ls under government control and the rest of the industry. The 264 thrifts taken over by the government by the end of August, for instance, had net withdrawals of $ 1.2 billion in August, compared with an inflow of $ 187 million in July. The 2,657 other thrifts had withdrawals of $ 3.9 billion, up from $ 133 million a month earlier.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 0145EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DietRecommendations     10-24 0617</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Diet Recommendations,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Adults Should Eat Less Salt, Research Council Says</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Health and Diet, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The average American adult can get along on as little as 500 milligrams of salt a day, far less than the usual diet contains, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> says. `` Although no optimal range of salt intake has been established, there is no known advantage in consuming large amounts of sodium and clear disadvantages for those susceptible to hypertension,'' the council said in an update of its nutritional recommendations. The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s 10th edition of its Recommended Dietary Allowances, published today, also says cigarette smokers need at least 100 milligrams of vitamin C per day _ as opposed to 60 milligrams for adult non-smokers. `` Smoking seems to increase metabolic turnover of the vitamin, leading to lower concentrations in the blood,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>. The new guidelines also say pregnant women should increase vitamin C to 70 milligrams a day. The new guidelines are the first update of the nutrient recommendations in nearly 10 years. The RDAs are a major guide for developing nutrition programs and policies. `` There are a lot of little changes, up and down, but not earthshaking,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobson </PERSON>, executive director for the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interest </ORGANIZATION>, a health advocacy group. One of the noteworthy changes, he said, is the one on sodium. `` This marks the first time this committee or any other official committee suggested so low a number,'' <PERSON> Jacobson </PERSON> said. `` They are telling Americans what is optimal, not what's convenient.'' About 75 percent of the sodium consumed by Americans comes from processed food. `` A typical serving of canned soup has almost 1,000 milligrams of sodium as flavoring,'' <PERSON> Jacobson </PERSON> said. `` A fast-food cheeseburger has 1,400 milligrams.'' He said previous recommendations specified 1,100 to 3,300 milligrams of sodium a day for adults. The new recommendations are not daily objectives, but rather goals to be met over time. `` In planning meals or food supplies,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>, `` it is technically difficult and biologically unnecessary to design a single day's diet that contains all the RDAs for all the nutrients.'' RDAs are defined as levels of essential nutrients that are `` adequate to meet the known nutrient needs of practically all healthy persons.'' People with special nutritional needs are not covered by the RDAs. The recommended allowances are intended to be consumed as part of a normal diet. The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> said they `` are neither minimal requirements nor necessarily optimal levels of intake.'' RDAs are used in a number of ways by different groups. The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION>, for instance, uses them to evaluate the adequacy of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> food supply, for setting standards for food assistance programs and determining the nutritional status of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> population. Most average Americans come in contact most often with the nutrition information listed on the sides of breakfast cereal boxes. They are derived from the RDAs. The new volume leaves most previous recommendations unchanged or modified only slightly, but it includes some important changes. Instead of basing <ORGANIZATION> RDAS </ORGANIZATION> for adults on arbitrary heights and weights, allowances now are based on actual heights and weights in the population. The <ORGANIZATION> RDA </ORGANIZATION> for vitamin B12, an essential nutrient for maintaining normal metabolism and function of the blood-forming organs, was reduced from 3 micrograms for men and women to 2 micrograms. The new edition lists recommended allowances for protein, 11 vitamins and 7 minerals. It points out that besides known nutrients, food contains thousands of other naturally occurring substances of nutritional value. `` A varied diet meeting RDAs,'' said the subcommittee of the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nutrition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> of the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>, `` will probably be adequate in all other nutrients.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Frank     10-24 0483</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Frank,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Frank Hires Lawyer for Sex Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DIAMOND</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The lawyer who will represent Rep. <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> before the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee says the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Democrat will defend himself against false allegations. `` He's chastened by the events that are true, but he's damned if he's going to run from allegations that are garbage,'' <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sachs </PERSON> said in an interview Monday. `` Barney's been forthcoming about this publicly. He is equally certain that there has been a substantial amount of untruth peddled, or attempted to be peddled, in the public press.'' <PERSON> Sachs </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> and former <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> attorney general, said he would be ready by early next week to present a detailed case that will debunk some of the sex-related charges leveled against the five-term lawmaker. <PERSON> Sachs </PERSON>' hiring was the latest move by <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> indicating a renewed feistiness after several weeks in which friends said he was emotionally down about his prospects. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> took to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor last week for the first time since the allegations about his relations with a male prostitute became public in August. He has maintained a full schedule in his home district and has begun a legal defense fund set up by political aides. <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Cahn </PERSON>, a spokesman for <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s congressional office, declined to disclose how much had been contributed to the fund, saying the first public report on the account is due at year's end. A leading liberal in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> has admitted paying <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> $ 80 for sex in 1985 and subsequently hiring him with personal funds to serve as a housekeeper and driver from July 1985 through August 1987. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> had acknowledged he is homosexual well before the recent publicity. <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> has leveled various charges against <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> that the congressman has denied. Among those are that <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> knew <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> was running a prostitution ring from <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> apartment and that <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> engaged in sexual activity at the House gymnasium. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee investigating the Frank case plans to conclude its deliberations by the end of the year, <PERSON> Sachs </PERSON> said, basing his statement on two meetings with the committee's legal counsel and one with the minority counsel. `` They want very much to act promptly and want to conclude the matter this year,'' <PERSON> Sachs </PERSON> said. Members of <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s staff said they expect the case to come up at least in a preliminary form at a committee meeting later this week. A spokesman for the ethics committee said the panel's schedule for this week had not been set by Monday and that committee proceedings and the agenda are kept confidential. <PERSON> Sachs </PERSON> has prosecuted several members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and recently gained attention for his defense of Dr. <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, who spent two years in jail after being cited for contempt of court for refusing to allow her daughter to visit the child's father.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891024-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-24-89 0135EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     10-24 0697</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farmers Still Waiting for Disaster Relief Checks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Most farmers who planted a second crop after freezing weather and drought destroyed their winter wheat or cotton are still waiting for disaster relief checks from the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, says Sen. <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>. `` For people who are waiting for their checks, this is getting to be a problem and I'm eager to do something,'' said <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON> and other <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> lawmakers contend <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s regulations implementing an $ 895 million drought relief bill unfairly cut payments to farmers who planted a second crop <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> officials said Monday that farmers who rotated their traditional spring crop to land where winter wheat was destroyed by drought or freezing weather are entitled to disaster payments. `` It does n't solve the problem most people have with their second crop,'' <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON> said. Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, called the decision by the <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stabilization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> good news, but agreed it does n't go far enough in reversing <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> regulations that would cut disaster assistance to many other farmers who had also planted a second crop. A <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> aide said the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s decision Monday apparently applies only to winter wheat farmers who would traditionally plant a second crop, such as milo, on non-wheat acres in the spring. Those farmers who planted their second crop on the wheat acres instead, to take advantage of fertilizer already on the land, wo n't see their disaster checks cut, the aide said The decision does n't cover hundreds of cotton farmers who also planted a second crop, or farmers who planted non-traditional second crops on their wheat acreage or in addition to their wheat acreage, officials said. Legislators and <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> have been wrangling over the regulations on `` ghost acres'' for two months, and one <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> aide said the decision came because `` we had to force their hand on this.'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said farmers from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> and elsewhere on the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> planted milo or cotton on their failed wheat acres this year, but were told by <ORGANIZATION> ASCS </ORGANIZATION> that their disaster checks would be reduced if they instead planted their spring cotton or milo crops on the winter wheat land. `` Had they planted the spring crop normally, without rotating it to the failed wheat acres, there would be no reduction in the disaster checks,'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said. `` It is obviously unfair to penalize farmers when they are following normal farming practices by simply rotating their crops on the farm.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
