<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 2337EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Judge-Homosexuals     02-27 0202</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Judge-Homosexuals,0208</SECOND>
<HEAD>Commission Institutes Proceedings Against Judge In Gay Killer Sentencing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AUSTIN, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judicial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conduct </ORGANIZATION> said Monday it has instituted formal proceedings against a <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> judge who said he gave a murderer a lighter sentence partly because the two victims were `` queers.'' The commission said a master appointed by the <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> would hold a hearing on complaints against Judge <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> <PERSON> Hampton </PERSON>, then report to the commission. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said in December that he sentenced 18-year-old <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bednarski </PERSON> to 30 years in prison instead of a maximum life sentence because the two men he killed were homosexuals. <PERSON> Bednarski </PERSON> was convicted of the execution-style slayings of <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> Trimble </PERSON>, 34, and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, 27, who were found shot to death in a <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> park. `` I do n't care much for queers cruising the streets picking up teen-age boys. I've got a teen-age boy,'' <PERSON> Hampton </PERSON> said at the time. His remarks triggered protests from homosexual and civil liberties groups, who staged a series of demonstrations and news conferences in December to call for his removal from the bench. The commission said in a brief statement Monday that it had had a `` large number of complaints in this matter.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 2350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Romania-Destruction     02-27 0281</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Romania-Destruction,0289</SECOND>
<HEAD>Journalist Smuggles Out Film Of Village Eradication</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A British journalist says she and a colleague were arrested four times for clandestinely filming rural areas of <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> wrecked by President <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>'s agricultural modernization scheme. Sue <PERSON> Lloyd-Roberts </PERSON> said she managed to save her videocassettes from confiscation by hiding them in her underwear whenever she was arrested and handing authorities footage of home movies the two had brought along. She and colleague <PERSON> Vivian </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> overcame stringent restrictions on foreign news coverage by entering the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc country posing as tourists, she said. Her footage, broadcast on <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, showed empty, brick-strewn fields where three villages had stood until last fall, and a signpost with its place name replaced. These villages appeared on older maps which were already unobtainable in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, Ms. <PERSON> Lloyd-Roberts </PERSON> said. An unidentified peasant woman was shown describing what had happened: `` We worked all our lives. They destroyed everyone's home. My house was knocked to the ground. They've made us live in new blocks. Everything is wretched and miserable. What can be done?'' The report said people spoke of villagers being killed resisting militiamen who evicted them from their homes on 24 hours notice. The demolitions are part of <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>'s plan to raze up to 7,000 of <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s 13,000 villages and resettle the population in so-called agro-industrial centers. `` <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> wants to create his ` Communist Man,' and he has to destroy the Romanian village because that's where the opposition to communism is total,'' <PERSON> Ion </PERSON> <PERSON> Rativ </PERSON>, a Romanian emigre leader in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, told <ORGANIZATION> ITN </ORGANIZATION>. In <LOCATION> Bucharest </LOCATION>, the capital, Ms. <PERSON> Lloyd-Roberts </PERSON> also filmed areas demolished to make way for a vast palace <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> is building for himself.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 2352EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AP-BureauChief     02-27 0139</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP-Bureau Chief,0143</SECOND>
<HEAD>AP Names Bureau Chief In Washington</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolman </PERSON>, assistant bureau chief of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>' <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> bureau for the past five years, has been promoted to bureau chief, <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boccardi </PERSON> has announced. <PERSON> Wolman </PERSON> will direct the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s news operations in the capital. He succeeds <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, who is joining <ORGANIZATION> Hearst </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspapers </ORGANIZATION> as <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> bureau chief. <PERSON> Boccardi </PERSON> made the announcement Monday. <PERSON> Wolman </PERSON>, 38, joined the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> in 1973. He became news editor for <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> in 1975, then moved to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in 1976 as a member of a team specializing in coverage of urban problems. In 1981, he became a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> news editor. He was promoted to assistant bureau chief in September 1984. He is a graduate of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin </ORGANIZATION> and a native of Madison.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 2354EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-EndangeredGorillas     02-27 0830</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Endangered Gorillas,0852</SECOND>
<HEAD>Primeval Forest Is Last Refuge For Lowland Gorilla</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL GOLDSMITH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BAYANGA, Central African Republic (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This is as remote a place as you can get in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The large-scale map of the <LOCATION> Bayanga </LOCATION> region shows only primeval forest crossed by rivers with not a single paved road. In this heart of darkness, hundreds of miles from the nearest village, man's closest relative in the animal kingdom, the lowland gorilla, has found his last refuge, a sanctuary of sorts from Pygmy tribes and others who hunt him for his flesh and his hide. The gorilla is an endangered species and theoretically under tough protection in the Central African Republic. But the government has neither the money nor the personnel to enforce the protective laws. There are two main groups of gorillas in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>: the mountain gorilla in <LOCATION> Rwanda </LOCATION> and eastern <LOCATION> Zaire </LOCATION> _ whose habitat and life style have been fully explored _ and the lowland gorilla who remains largely a mystery. The mountain gorilla can be seen from peak to peak and gradually allows himself to be approached as he becomes familiar with human beings. The lowland gorilla is supremely shy and elusive, explains <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forestry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Haven </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>, who has made the gorilla his life's work, rarely gets close enough to strike up an acquaintance In more than five years' work almost exclusively concentrated on the lowland gorilla, <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> has yet to get one accustomed to the human presence in the forest He estimates that a desolate area of 40,000 square miles of forest where the <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> African </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cameroon </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Congo </LOCATION> meet may still have at least 90,000 gorillas permanently settled there. With the exception of rare logging camps along the rivers, there is no human activity in this area, and the gorillas have until recently remained undisturbed. In recent years, the logging camps have developed, and there has been `` heavy illegal poaching'' for meat and the ivory of elephants who are the other main inhabitants of the region. In the central market in <LOCATION> Bangui </LOCATION>, the Central African capital 220 miles to the east, stands are piled high smoked monkey meat, a local delicacy. `` Gorillas taste like monkeys, only better,'' said <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Somse </PERSON>, who is <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>'s Pygmy guide. `` And there is more of them.'' <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>, who lives in <LOCATION> Bayembe </LOCATION> with his wife and 3-year-old daughter, has been trying to teach the Pygmies why the gorillas are best left alone. It's an almost hopeless task. The Pygmies go after the gorillas with bows and arrows. But larger Africans, those brought in to work the logging camps, use rifles and even machine guns, <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> said. `` They bribe the Pygmies to help them by giving them clothes and liquor. In some areas, we find snares made of cables stolen from the logging companies every few yards along trails used by the gorrillas.'' The gorillas eat the fleshy leaves of the ever-present ginger-like Aframomum shrub, the fruit of tropical trees and the eggs of termites. `` It's quite common to see a 400-pound silverback gorilla climb more than 100 feet up into the trees to get at the fruit,'' <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> said. `` They love that more than anything. `` They will even build a nest up in the trees and sleep there.'' In some areas on the ground, gorilla nests are visible every five or six yards. But the gorillas scamper away when they sense a human being approach. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> has been trying to persuade the Central African government to set up a wildlife reserve in the remote southwestern tip of the country. But in reality, the effort is useless unless the other two governments in the area, the <LOCATION> Congo </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cameroon </LOCATION>, cooperate. Meanwhile, the poaching goes on. Even poorly paid wildlife guards sometimes find it more worth their while to hunt gorillas and elephants. And the dense forest paradoxically helps to protect the poachers from the guards. `` It would help to be able to get a radio tag on the animals,'' <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> said. `` We have to crawl on our hands and feet to get close to them, and even then we do n't see them'til we are a foot or two away. With a radio, we could find a place ahead of them and watch them coming.'' He said the gorillas share 90 percent of human genetic materials, and, as such, are by far the closest animals to man. But he deplored the ineffectiveness of the present system of control and the inability of local governments and European and American organizations to stop the poaching. `` Recently we were in a camp on the <LOCATION> Sangha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, where it forms the border with the <LOCATION> Congo </LOCATION>. A Congolese gunboat came up the river and ordered us to get out of there. We were clearly in the C.A.R. -LRB- Central African Republic -RRB-. But quite obviously, we were interfering with their poaching.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 2358EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ArtTheftProbe     02-27 0392</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Art Theft Probe,0407</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Police Chief's Son Charged in Art Case</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The son of a former city police chief has been charged in a federal investigation of an alleged $ 3 million art-theft ring centered in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>, federal authorities said Monday. <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schott </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 48, of the <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> was arraigned Monday before <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Magistrate <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> on a charge of interstate transportation of stolen property. <PERSON> Schott </PERSON>, the third person to be charged in the case, filed notice he would plead guilty to the charge in a plea bargain with federal prosecutors. <PERSON> Schott </PERSON> agreed to cooperate with federal authorities and testify against <PERSON> Teddy </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudder </PERSON>, an alleged member of the art-theft ring already charged in the case, said Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> DiPuccio </PERSON>. In exchange, federal authorities agreed not to file additional charges against <PERSON> Schott </PERSON>, who was released on his own recognizance, <PERSON> DiPuccio </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Schott </PERSON> is the son of the late <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schott </PERSON>, who was <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> police chief from 1967 to 1970. He is accused of transporting an $ 80,000 painting stolen from a <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> house in February 1988 to <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>, where is it was sold to an art dealer, <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Boldt </PERSON> said. The oil painting by <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Potthast </PERSON>, `` Women on Beach-Women in Water,'' was later sold to a <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, art dealer. The <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> Fe dealer saw the work listed in a bulletin on stolen art, and reported it to the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Boldt </PERSON> said. The charge against <PERSON> Schott </PERSON> carries a maximum sentence of 10 years in prisona and $ 250,00 fine on conviction. The ring is accused of stealing items with an estimated worth of $ 3 million from <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> area homes, <PERSON> DiPuccio </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> estimates it has recovered more than $ 500,000 worth of items, most of them art objects. Rudder, 42, of <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, was arrested Feb. 7 and is jailed without bond while his case is pending before a federal grand jury, <PERSON> DiPuccio </PERSON> said. Rudder is charged with conspiracy to transport stolen property interstate, and is charged with interstate travel to commit an arson in an unrelated case, <PERSON> DiPuccio </PERSON> said. Federal authorities also have arrested <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulholland </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> in the art-theft case. <PERSON> Mulholland </PERSON>, who is out on bond, is charged with an unrelated count of possession with intent to distribute cocaine, <PERSON> DiPuccio </PERSON> said. Federal authorities said they anticipate more arrests.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 0030EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--ChineseOut     02-27 0183</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Chinese Out,0186</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Businessmen Ordered To Leave South Korea</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> has refused to extend the visas of eight Chinese businessmen who have been trying to gain a foothold for their operations in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, press reports say. The eight include <PERSON> Hong </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheong </PERSON> <PERSON> Tak </PERSON>, vice chairman of <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liaoning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, a Hong Kong-based trade arm of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Liaoning </LOCATION> province, the South Korean news agency <ORGANIZATION> Yonhap </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. The agency said the ministry ordered the businessmen, who arrived in December seeking to open company branches in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, to leave by March 2. <ORGANIZATION> Yonhap </ORGANIZATION> said the move indicates <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> does not want Chinese companies to open branches in the country on a long-term basis, given that <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> have no formal diplomatic relations. South Korean businessmen are not allowed to stay in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> more than three months, and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> prevents <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> firms from opening branches there. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has promoted economic exchanges with <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> in recent years but has been reluctant to upgrade such relations, apparently due to its ties with communist <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0790 02-27 0664</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0790,0685</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: AMs separates moved as a0764 on Dreyer and on sports and business
wires; as a0401 on Eldridge, a0806 on Gorman.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Roy Eldridge</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Eldridge </PERSON>, one of the great innovators of the jazz trumpet, died Sunday at age 78, just three weeks after the death of his wife of 53 years. A native of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Eldridge </PERSON> came to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> in 1930 and gained national attention as featured trumpeter and singer with <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Krupa </PERSON>'s band from 1941 to 1943. When he left the <PERSON> Artie </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> band in 1945, <PERSON> Eldridge </PERSON> complained angrily about the many racial incidents he endured while playing with the band. He vowed he would never play with a white band again, although he did later. He gained star status in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, when in 1950 he toured with the <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON> sextet. He returned to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1951 and often appeared with jazz luminaries such as <PERSON> Ella </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>, <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodges </PERSON> and <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Dr. Harry Gorman</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FORT COLLINS, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Dr. <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorman </PERSON>, the veterinarian who helped develop the artificial hip joint for animals and humans and also trained animals the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> sent into space, died Friday at the age of 72. <PERSON> Gorman </PERSON>, who retired in 1982 from the faculty of the <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterinary </ORGANIZATION> medicine, designed the first artificial hip joint for dogs and later adapted it for human use. A past president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterinary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, he spent 22 years in the military, starting with the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and in 1946 heading the newly created <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>'s Veterinary Corps. He retired in 1960 as a colonel. During World War II, he led veterinarians who rescued more than a million cattle from drowning in the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> when dikes destroyed by bombs let farmland flood. He received the Bronze Star, Legion of Merit and nine other military decorations. In 1956, he joined the <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerospace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Brooks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> as chief of the veterinary division. There he raised and trained the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' first animals in space. A native of Colorado who earned his doctorate at <ORGANIZATION> CSU </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Gorman </PERSON> returned to the university in 1964, and did research there for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Floyd Dreyer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Floyd </PERSON> `` Pop'' <PERSON> Dreyer </PERSON>, who developed the first magnesium wheels for race cars and built miniature race cars for children, died Saturday at age 90. <PERSON> Dreyer </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Chillicothe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, came to <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> in the 1920s to work for carmaker <PERSON> August </PERSON> <PERSON> Duesenberg </PERSON> as a welder, after racing motorcycles for the former <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motorcycle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. A lifelong motorcyclist, in the early 1920s he developed a sidecar linkage that allowed the car lean with the motorcycle in turns. Later that decade, he helped build a car that set a land speed record at <LOCATION> Daytona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dreyer </PERSON>'s miniature race cars for children, one of which was owned by child movie star <ORGANIZATION> Shirley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION>, raced at the <ORGANIZATION> Indianapolis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Speedway </ORGANIZATION> and on sprint and midget tracks around the country <PERSON> Dreyer </PERSON> was a member of <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> `` 500'' <ORGANIZATION> Oldtimers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, which honored him in 1983 for his contributions to racing. Also in 1983, he was inducted into the Oldtimers Automobile Racing Hall of Fame in <LOCATION> Flemington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Charles West</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> `` </PERSON> <PERSON> Dick </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> West </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, former editorial page editor of The Dallas Morning News and a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> journalist for 50 years, died Saturday following a long illness. He was 76. Before joining The Morning News in 1944, he worked at the <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> and The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> as a desk editor and sportswriter. In 1946, 1949 and 1952, <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> won first place in a state contest sponsored by <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> Managing Editors Association. West was a passionate conservative and anti-communist, and The Morning News said his editorials and commentaries helped define the image of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> during the turbulent 1950s and 1960s.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-India-Sikhs     02-27 0219</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-India-Sikhs,0226</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sikh Gunmen Kill Family of Three, Two Policemen Slain</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AMRITSAR, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Militant Sikh separatists shot and killed a Sikh farmer and his two sons and two policemen in separate attacks in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> state, police and news reports said today. Five gunmen raided the home of <PERSON> Banta </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Gagubhua </LOCATION> village in <LOCATION> Amritsar </LOCATION> district late Sunday and fatally shot <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> and his sons at point-blank range after separating them from the women in the family, said area police chief <PERSON> Sanjeev </PERSON> <PERSON> Gupta </PERSON>. Sikhs militants who are campaigning for an independent homeland in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s north often pick moderate Sikhs as their targets. Moderate Sikhs want greater political autonomny for their rich farming state but refuse to endorse the radicals' demand for secession. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> said two policemen were shot and killed late Sunday night by <ORGANIZATION> Sikh </ORGANIZATION> militants in the village of <LOCATION> Deffarwal </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Hoshiarpur </LOCATION> district. The latest slayings brought the total number of deaths blamed on <ORGANIZATION> Sikh </ORGANIZATION> militants in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> to at least 325 this year. Last year, at least 2,440 deaths were blamed on the extremists. Sikhs, who make up about two percent of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 880 million people, say they are discriminated by Hindus, the country's religious majority accounting for about 82 percent of its people Sikhs comprise a slight majority in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> state.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 0023EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-RailroadExplosion 2ndLd-Writethru a0810 02-27 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Railroad Explosion, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0810,0506</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tanker Cars Explode; Thousands Evacuated</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto Staffing</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES throughout with quotes from fire chief, CSX spokesman,
more specific numbers of cars involved and later information on their contents;
DELETES outdated material; ADDS byline.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHUCK MELVIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AKRON, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A train derailment caused an explosion and fire involving four tanker cars, forcing the evacuation of thousands of people from a residential and industrial area near downtown Sunday night, authorities said. No injuries were immediately reported. The burning cars were among 17 that derailed from a <ORGANIZATION> CSX </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> train at the <ORGANIZATION> B.F. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Goodrich </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> plant, said <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION> Fire Chief <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Romanoski </PERSON>. Nine of the cars carried highly flammable butane, <ORGANIZATION> CSX </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said by telephone from <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>. The eight other cars carried non-hazardous materials including vegetable oil, clay and sand, he said. <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> Franks </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said one of the cars contained butadiene, which may produce hazardous smoke when burned, but <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said the petroleum derivative was not in any of the derailed cars. <PERSON> Romanoski </PERSON> said fires in three of the cars and been put out and one car was still burning late Sunday night. Firefighters had planned to allow the fourth car to burn itself out. The accident occurred about 7:30 p.m., authorities said. Firefighters ran hoses up to the train to spread water on adjoining cars to cool them and diminish the possibility they would explode, he said. `` The area was evacuated because of the danger of explosion in the surrounding tank cars,'' <PERSON> Romanoski </PERSON> said. At least 1,500 homes in an area within one-half mile of the plant were evacuated, but the number of evacuees was not immediately available, Mayor <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Plusquilic </PERSON> said. The evacuees were taken by bus to a high school and to the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Akron </ORGANIZATION>'s Memorial Hall, said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Swearengin </PERSON>, the county emergency management coordinator. <PERSON> Romanoski </PERSON> said people would not be allowed to return to their homes until the fire was extinguished. He said he did not know when that would be, `` but just as a yardstick, we're saying ` plan on being there overnight at least,''' he said. The train was not making a stop at the Goodrich plant, but was using its tracks to pass through the area, said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Fletcher </PERSON>, plant manager. The train, which had a total of 45 cars, was en route from <LOCATION> Willard </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, to <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION> and back to <PERSON> Willard </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said. He did not know where the train's next stop was scheduled. He said the train carried a crew of three or four, and that no crew members were injured. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said investigators from <ORGANIZATION> CSX </ORGANIZATION> would arrive in <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION> early Monday morning. No cause for the accident had been determined Sunday night, he said. Witnesses said flames from the burning tankers could be seen for miles. Akron-area hospitals reported no injuries four hours after the explosion, but some area residents reported feeling nauseated.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugNumbersGame Bjt   02-27 0973</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Numbers Game, Bjt,940</SECOND>
<HEAD>Publicized Drug Seizures Having Little Effect on Supply, Officials
Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The large drug seizures announced with fanfare by law enforcement authorities are having little effect on supplies on the street, with dealers simply absorbing them as a cost of doing business, federal officials say. `` Historically, a manager of drug couriers gives up one courier who is body carrying -LRB- drugs -RRB- to take your attention away from four more,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Norsworthy </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> agent at the <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paso </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. `` People walk away from a brand new aircraft after one load and consider that an expense of the trip,'' he said. `` The same goes for boats, automobiles, campers. They expect to pay a price.'' A better way to assess how the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is doing in the war on drugs is to ignore the ballyhoo about drug busts and concentrate on the price and purity level of drugs on the street, says Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, D-Del. `` For too long, when we've asked whether or not our drug strategy is working, the administration has cited record arrest and seizure data,'' said <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, who chairs the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. A check of price and purity of drugs on the streets, <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> said, reveals that `` cocaine and heroin on the streets are much cheaper and more potent than they were five years ago.'' In 1982, cocaine sold at the retail level at a nationwide range of $ 2,000 to $ 3,000 per ounce and was 50 percent to 60 percent pure, said <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Cornelius </PERSON> <PERSON> Dougherty </PERSON>. In 1988, the street price of cocaine had dropped to $ 500 to $ 2,000 per ounce and it was 80 percent pure, said <PERSON> Dougherty </PERSON>, who said the information came from drug seizures, undercover drug buys, intelligence gathered and records seized. The amount of drugs seized `` is not a dent'' in comparison with what is coming into the country and being produced domestically, said <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>. Given the uncertainty over exactly how large the nation's illegal drug market is, there are very few solid numbers about anything, which gives drug busts and amounts seized a certain cachet. There is not even a clear total of the amount of seizures around the country, the one number in the maze of drug statistics that could be expected to be solid. One problem is that many different agencies may take credit for the same bust. `` It's a quagmire,'' says <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>. `` If you add them up, you'll find the government -LRB- claiming it -RRB- got 10 times what it actually seized. ... Everyone's trying to make themselves look good.'' <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> outlined a hypothetical case in which the <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> provides the intelligence on an incoming shipment, <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> radar locates the ship, a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> jet spots the ship, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> tracks it and the final seizure is conducted by a local sheriff in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. `` Even if everyone was trying to do the right thing and no one was trying to cheat, it would still be a nightmare'' to sort out the various claims for responsibility, even though the agencies attempt to note when they have assisted and when they have made a seizure alone, he said. This problem was noted in 1983 by the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, the investigative branch of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and some efforts have been made to correct it. `` We've tried to get all the federal agencies to call into the <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paso </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> where they give each seizure an identification number in case other police agencies claim it as well,'' said <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, who still acknowledged `` there's no real way'' to tell how much the federal government seized last year. <PERSON> Norsworthy </PERSON>, who is special assistant to the special agent in charge of EPIC, said that this program of giving each seizure a Federal Drug Identification Number `` does avoid duplication.'' However, <PERSON> Norsworthy </PERSON> said EPIC has not been providing annual totals for federal drug seizures and the information it started collecting only recently is limited because seizures must meet a threshold _ such as a minimum of 1 pound of cocaine _ before they are given identification numbers. In addition, `` absolutely no one'' is compiling figures of local police seizures unless they choose to call in, he said. `` I do n't believe that you will find a good, true figure -LRB- of the total amount of drugs seized -RRB-,'' said <PERSON> Norsworthy </PERSON>. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Narcotics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>, said he's not concerned about some duplication of seizure numbers, even if it's being done so agencies will look better and possibly get more government money for their efforts. `` Those guys need all the help they can get,'' <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON> said. Committee Chairman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Rangel </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, `` does n't think you can overplay the danger and hard work the front lines in law enforcement have.'' Disregarding the likelihood of duplication, the federal agencies do n't make it easy even to add up what they each claim to have seized by maintaining different methods of calculation. Some compile figures by calendar years, others by fiscal years that start Oct. 1; some report on the number of pounds of drugs seized, others on kilograms. Law enforcement agencies also repeatedly seize millions of dollars in drug profits that go unclaimed, because anyone claiming the money would have to prove it was his and say where it came from, <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> said. `` I recall a little old lady way back in the early 70s who handed me a shoe box full of $ 20 bills and said she was being paid to carry it to a woman in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Norsworthy </PERSON> said. The woman, who disclaimed any knowledge of the contents or the rightful owner, was allowed to continue her trip and the government got the money since no one claimed it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Tower-Senate Bjt   02-27 0878</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tower-Senate, Bjt,870</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Win or Lose, Tower Nomination Changes Assumptions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When a conservative activist told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> he had seen former Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> drunk in public, he set off a chain of events shattering the assumption that the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will protect its own no matter what. Ill-founded or not, the assumption was that the nomination of the feisty <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> had relatively clear sailing in his quest to be confirmed as President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s secretary of defense and that only minimal attention would be paid to decades of rumors that he had a serious drinking problem and a fondness for women to whom he was not married. The testimony of conservative <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Weyrich </PERSON>, who opposes some Tower positions on defense issues, inspired a rush of similar allegations. An ongoing <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> investigation was broadened. The result: Senators were forced to take the concerns about Tower seriously. The nomination of the man who until three years ago was chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> was suddenly in deep trouble in that committee and in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> itself. The dispute over Tower threatens the spirit of bipartisanship which the president sought to build in his inaugural address little more than a month ago. All 11 <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> members of the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> voted `` no'' on Tower. All nine Republicans voted `` yes.'' A similarly partisan split is possible when the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> votes. In an attempt to prevent that and salvage his nomination, Tower made an extraordinary promise on Sunday, vowing not to take a single drink if he is confirmed. But the struggle over Tower and his alleged problems already has brought a large degree of unaccustomed pain in a legislative institution where progress is marked by the free flow of flattery, in which all senators are invariably addressed as `` distinguished'' and `` honorable.'' `` I can recall few equivalent instances on major issues in my <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> career where my colleagues were so genuinely torn by the evidence and undecided in their position until the time came to vote,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., the current <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> voted `` no'' on Tower. Seventy-one members of the 101st <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> served when Tower was a member. None has come forward with a personal account of ever seeing him intoxicated or obviously out of control. Several senators, all Republicans, have insisted the opposite is true, that they have observed Tower in periods of stress, during late-night sessions of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, during extensive overseas travel and on numerous social occasions and never saw him intoxicated or exercising poor judgment. But others, mostly Democrats, say they are deeply troubled by the allegations assembled during the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> investigation. These include <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, who, when he marked Tower's retirement from the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1984, suggested the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> senator might one day be deservedly selected as secretary of defense and praised him for `` the background and knowledge that are indispensable in the defense arena.'' Senators voicing concern over Tower's alleged drinking problem insist that his status as a former senator and as a principal arms control negotiator in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> can not outweigh concerns that a secretary of defense must be alert and ready to respond to crisis 24 hours a day. `` We must not overlook a nominee's problems and subject him to less rigid standards just because he once served in this body,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s president pro In an interview, <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> asserted that nothing has changed in the way the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> judges Cabinet-level nominees but added that `` a new set of circumstances has come to center stage.'' `` If the same nominee had come to center stage 100 years ago he would have been rejected by his colleagues,'' <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> contended. But others saw two centuries of <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> traditions under assault. `` It seems to me we are on the verge ... of tearing this place apart,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republican Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, who said unfounded allegations are `` coming out of the woodwork, over the transom, under the door.'' `` We have to have some fairness,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said. `` There could be some hypocrisy around here.'' Some senators say Tower's conduct in the past is being unfairly judged by the changed standards of the present. `` This is a different era,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, who says he never saw Tower take a drink during working hours and never saw him `` where he was not in complete control of his brain.'' `` The whole country is drinking less, and that includes members of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> _ everybody is more health-conscious,'' <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> says. `` We did drink more in the 60's and 70's,'' he said. `` We had more private time then. ... And if there is any place that will bring up a drinking problem it is right here in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> predicts that the Tower controversy will lead to a closer examination of the private habits of all politicians. `` Yes, this has opened a can of worms,'' he said. `` But there will be even more of a can of worms before this is over. `` People will ask all politicians, ` Do you have a drinking problem?'''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Knutson </PERSON> covers <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 0103EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     02-27 0685</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farmers Face Higher Seed Prices</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Seed prices are higher as farmers head into the spring planting season, largely because of last year's drought but also because of huge additions to the government's conservation program, according to <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> analysts. A survey of companies by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> last August indicated that 45 percent of the planned seed corn production was wiped out by the drought, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. To make up the losses, many of the companies planned off-season seed corn production in southern areas of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. `` According to industry sources, the off-season production and carryover stock should provide adequate seed corn supplies for domestic use in 1989, if planted acreage does n't exceed 78 million acres,'' the agency said in a report. `` However, some popular hybrids may be in short supply, requiring farmers to choose other varieties.'' Results of a survey among farmers to determine planting intentions this spring will be issued by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> on March 31. Corn plantings totaled 67.6 million acres last year, 65.7 million in 1987 and 76.7 million in 1986. Two factors add up to planting costs: acreage and prices. And in most cases, farmers are planting more acres this year, and prices are higher. Overall, the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s `` prices paid'' index for all seeds is expected to rise 10 percent to 15 percent from year-earlier levels. `` Several seed corn firms have announced average increases of 10 percent to 15 percent in the spring price,'' the report said. `` Soybean, wheat, oat and barley seed prices tend to follow commercial crop prices, which have climbed substantially since the beginning of 1988. Cotton prices, however, have fallen over the last year.'' The Conservation Reserve Program, which has a goal of taking 40 million to 45 million acres of highly erodible land from crop production by the end of 1990, has helped boost grass seed prices. Under CRP contracts, farmers agree to plant the idled land with grass or trees as protective cover. As of now, more than 28 million acres have been signed into the <ORGANIZATION> CRP </ORGANIZATION>, with 90 percent of it to be planted to grass. The report said that if yields of grass seed are normal this season, the supply of new seed should increase. But if <ORGANIZATION> CRP </ORGANIZATION> and foreign demand for grass seed do n't ease, higher prices can be expected in 1989. `` Between 1985 and 1988, grass seed prices for timothy and annual ryegrass increased 124 percent and 28 percent, respectively,'' the report said. Meanwhile the reduced seed output because of last year's drought has affected exports, mainly corn and soybeans. `` Exports are likely to be down in 1989, while imports are expected to rise,'' the report said. `` However, neither exports nor imports of corn and soybean seed typically constitute a large share of total <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> seed consumption.'' However, seed exports are valuable, totaling a record of $ 374 million in the 1987 calendar year, up 1 percent from 1986, the report said. The increase was primarily due to larger shipments of soybean and vegetable seeds. The decline in corn seed exports in 1988 is likely to mostly be felt by <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, the report said. Major soybean seed buyers are <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. `` While the full effects of the drought on seed corn exports will not be known until later in 1989, the two major seed corn export markets, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, showed declines of 18 percent and 51 percent respectively, during the first nine months of 1988,'' the report said. But those sharp declines probably were due to tighter sanitary restrictions imposed on imports by the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, the report added. Imports of corn seed, up sharply last year, have traditionally been mostly from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and lesser amounts from <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>. But in the first nine months of 1988, <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> provided 45 percent of the imported corn seed, up from only 2 percent in the same period of 1987. Increases also were reported from <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-OscarLobster     02-27 0250</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Oscar Lobster,0260</SECOND>
<HEAD>Oscar The Lobster Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TACOMA, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hot lights rather than boiling water may have killed a 1 \ - pound lobster that gained attention when the woman who bought it for a Valentine's Day feast decided to spare it from <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said the $ 14 <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> lobster she dubbed <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> died this weekend. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerontis </PERSON>, a seafood merchant who had offered to fly the lobster back to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> so that it could be tossed back into the ocean, told Mrs. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> on Friday that <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> was terminally ill. She said she gave him permission to put the lobster to sleep by placing it in the freezer Mrs. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, tearful over the whole incident, said she feared the media attention she stirred up to save Oscar might have caused its demise. She said she told her story to the news media in hopes of finding a tank for Oscar. The story of the woman who fell for the lobster became an instant hit, and <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> spent ensuing days under hot television lights, a pen shoved in one claw to sign autographs. `` Everybody thought it was a wonderful story and it did make a lot of people happy,'' she said. Mrs. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said she planned to bury the crustacean at Point Penrose State Park. Her husband, <PERSON> Dave </PERSON>, planned to help bury the lobster that was intended for his dinner plate. While he supported her efforts, he offered a final observation: `` I never did get my dinner.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 0114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Budget     02-27 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrats Trying to Avoid Being Outmaneuvered By Bush on Budget</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Congressional Democrats are split over their budget strategy, two weeks after President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> put them on the spot with a $ 1.16 trillion spending proposal that leaves many of the difficult questions unanswered. Some leading Democrats lean toward cooperation with the administration _ perhaps culminating in full-fledged, high-level negotiations _ as the best way to forge a spending plan and to cut the deficit to $ 100 billion, as required under the Gramm-Rudman balanced budget law. <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, D-Calif., and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, are among those advocating a cooperative approach `` My sense is that as long as the administration wants to discuss issues and look at options together, we're prepared to do that,'' <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON> said in an interview. Others, including <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, are less disposed to collaborate beyond the consultations already under way among White House and congressional budget writers, at least for now. Some of these lawmakers argue that Democrats can gain politically by continuing to attack <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s budget, and say there is no hurry to work out a bargain on the spending plan just yet. `` It's the administration that feels an urgency to get things going,'' says <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>, D-Tenn. Others, including many liberals, are even more militant, arguing that domestic programs would fare better if the Democratic-controlled <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> wrote its own budget An agreement with the administration risks having Democrats share blame with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for harsh cuts in popular programs, these legislators say. `` The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> budget has the rhetoric of a kinder, gentler <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, but it has the fiscal numbers of an austere, harsh <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' says Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democratic leadership and the former chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> budget panel. `` The Democrats have to come up with their own budget.'' When <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> presented his spending proposal to the Democratic-controlled <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Feb. 9, he simultaneously asked the lawmakers to negotiate with him over its final shape. Congressional Democrats complain that the president's blueprint is woefully lacking in details, especially on the cuts that would be needed to meet overall spending limits envisioned in the plan. They say that before they agree to work out a budget jointly with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, they need specific figures indicating exactly how much the administration proposes spending on the hundreds of separate programs covered by the budget. Some observers, however, believe <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has won the first round of the public relations war. `` Do you really think <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Sixpack </PERSON> thinks it's unreasonable for the president to say he wants to sit down with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and work it out?'' asked <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON>, president of the bipartisan <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> a </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Responsible </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>, which monitors budget activity. `` At the moment, we're boxed in,'' says Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Durbin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ill </LOCATION>., a budget committee member `` The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people are looking at <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to make a move.'' Says Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Frenzel </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, ranking <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> member on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> budget panel, `` It's been a pleasure to watch them writhe this week.'' Some Democrats say accusing <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> of producing a budget that leaves about $ 10 billion worth of cuts for later bargaining _ and that makes only tiny increases in priority domestic areas _ will eventually pay off with the public. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> and some other liberals say that rather than enacting <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s plan, they prefer writing a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> budget that gets half of its savings from domestic spending and half from defense That is the same formula under which the Gramm-Rudman law automatically slashes spending if the deficit target is missed, and they argue that domestic spending would fare better this way. Some Democrats fear that even if they negotiate a budget settlement with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, Republicans will campaign against them in the next elections by blaming them for the cuts anyway. If there are negotiations between the administration and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, a two-year budget _ rather than the usual one-year plan _ could well emerge. This would get messy decisions for fiscal 1991 out of the way before next year's campaigns, and free lawmakers to concentrate on policy issues instead of spending woes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NationalParks     02-27 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-National Parks,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Conservation Groups Urge Bush Administration to Buy Park Land</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Conservation groups want President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to reverse the record of his predecessor and revive a program to protect land around national preserves. `` You can defer buying a car, but a desirable piece of land is likely to turn into a shopping mall or become too expensive. Special areas bought today will pay enormous dividends for future generations,'' says <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Frampton </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Wilderness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. A coalition led by the <ORGANIZATION> Wilderness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> urged the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration Sunday to spend $ 781 million next year to buy land that might otherwise be lost to developers in and around national preserves in 46 states. `` You ca n't keep putting off these investments,'' <PERSON> Frampton </PERSON> said. The money would come from the Land and Water Conservation Fund, created by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1965 to protect natural resources. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> may appropriate $ 900 million a year from the fund, which gets 80 percent of its money from oil-drilling on the federally owned outer continental shelf. But purchases of land under the fund fell sharply under President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, from $ 509 million in 1980 to $ 206 million this year. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has recommended keeping investments at $ 206 million for the fiscal year beginning next October. As an example of land lost to development because of delays, <PERSON> Frampton </PERSON> cited a 700-acre tract in Devil's Canyon in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, which conservationists urged the government to buy for three years. The land has since been subdivided. Most of the recommended tracts lie within national parks or forests and would not expand the boundaries of federal lands, the statement said. The recommended purchases include land at <ORGANIZATION> Chincoteague </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refuge </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, Olympic National Park in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Acadia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monica </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mountains </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recreation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, and along the <ORGANIZATION> Appalachian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trail </ORGANIZATION>, which runs from <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. The only states in which purchases were not recommended were <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. In addition to spending $ 781 million from the Land and Water Conservation Fund, the coalition urged appropriation of $ 200 million in matching funds for recreation projects by state and local governments. Among the sites at which the report recommended purchases were: _ <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monica </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mountains </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recreation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION>, $ 30 million for a total of 5,000 acres in <LOCATION> Zuma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Trancas </LOCATION> and Corral Canyons and elsewhere _ <ORGANIZATION> Appalachian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trail </ORGANIZATION>, $ 23 million to buy land along the 2,100-mile corridor, which is administered by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> _ Mt <ORGANIZATION> Baker-Snoqualmie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, $ 10 million to buy 620 acres near <LOCATION> Noisy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION>. Some of that land contains trees up to 10 feet in diameter. _ Alpine Lakes Management Area, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, $ 9.6 million to buy 7,750 acres in the Teanaway, <LOCATION> Tumwater </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Icicle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Skykomish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Annette </PERSON> <PERSON> Lake </PERSON> areas _ <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gorge </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Scenic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Area </LOCATION>, $ 9.3 million to buy almost 5,200 acres on both sides of the <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> _ Olympic National Park, $ 4 million for 350 acres in the <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crescent </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Quinault </LOCATION> and coastal sections of the park _ <ORGANIZATION> Chincoteague </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refuge </ORGANIZATION>, on the eastern shore of the <LOCATION> Chesapeake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, $ 3.5 million to buy 4,350 acres, including the barrier islands <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Cedar </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Metomkin </PERSON> and Assawoman _ <ORGANIZATION> Acadia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2 million to buy 500 acres in a boundary expansion area <ORGANIZATION> Acadia </ORGANIZATION> is the nation's second most visited national park, after <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Smoky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> park in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. _ Goose Prairie, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, $ 700,000 to buy 25 acres, including the summer cabin of the late <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> In addition to the <ORGANIZATION> Wilderness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, the coalition includes the <ORGANIZATION> Izaak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Walton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION>, Friends of the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hiking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Sierra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TornadoToll     02-27 0688</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tornado Toll,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tornado Deaths Below Average in '88</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One of nature's most vicious spectacles, the tornado, is poised to renew its annual assault on <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, as changeable spring weather breeds the storms that spawn twisters. Last year was one of fewer than normal tornado deaths, but even so, more than 700 of the violent funnel clouds struck the nation. In 1988 the nation recorded 32 tornado deaths, down from the 59 killed a year earlier and well below the long-term average of 99 fatalities annually, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported on Sunday. But while that's good news, it is n't an indication that the danger has lessened. `` There is no way of knowing what this tornado season will bring, but the way to survive is through preparedness,'' said <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>, deputy director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Severe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Storms </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forecast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Meteorologists have attributed the decline in tornado deaths in recent years to increased public awareness of the storms, which are most common in May and June but can occur in any month of the year. Unusually warm and wet weather last November helped trigger a record number of tornadoes for that month, at 121 across the country. The average for November is only 23 tornadoes, and the record had been 81, set in 1973. Last year also recorded the largest tornado outbreak in 14 years. That took place on Mother's Day when 57 twisters tore through parts of <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>. That outbreak did n't cause any deaths, although 10 injuries were reported <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> recorded the most fatalities last year with six deaths apiece, followed by <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> with five. Four people were killed in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and two each in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>. States with a single fatality apiece were <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The transition from winter to spring, spurring unsettled weather and frequent thunderstorms, helps create tornadoes, violently twisting winds that reach down from thunderclouds. After a low point in the winter they begin to increase sharply in March and peak in May with a national average of 166 twisters in that month, according to records kept at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Climatic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. June ranks second, averaging 150 tornadoes, followed by April with 109 in a typical year. Other months averaging more than a twister-a-day somewhere in the nation are July, 82; August, 57; March, 50 and September, 38. Hot weather stirring the air helps form thunderstorms and their tornadoes, with 60 percent of all twisters occurring between noon and sunset, according to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION>. Tornadoes are least likely during the early morning just before sunrise. The typical tornado is only about 50 yards wide and travels about two miles on the ground _ 87 percent of the time heading toward the northeast, <ORGANIZATION> NCAR </ORGANIZATION> researchers report. But while an individual twister can cover only a small area, they often come in groups and in the affected area destruction can be total. The familiar funnel cloud is the most common sign of a tornado although adjacent winds can also cause severe damage. When twisters are in an area, common sense and knowing a few simple rules can save lives, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> says. If tornadoes threaten, turn on radio or television to keep current on the danger, the agency says. The weather service even has its own radio network which can provide continual updates. If a twister is reported, safety rules include: _ At home, seek shelter immediately in a basement or interior hallway Stay away from windows and outside walls. _ At school, move to hallways and lie flat on the floor with head covered _ In a mobile home or trailer, leave immediately Head for a secure shelter or lie flat on the ground. Be wary of areas with poor drainage, however, because of the possibility of flooding from the thunderstorm. _ At work or in public buildings, head for interior hallways on the lowest floor, or designated shelter areas _ In an automobile, leave immediately Do not try to outrun a tornado.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-StreetCrimeBlues-1stAdd     02-27 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Street Crime Blues - 1st Add,0713</SECOND>
<HEAD>UNDATED: for keeps.    In Miami, an undercover narcotics team made
14 arrests in assembly line fashion. One of the busts was a 16-year-old
selling crack outside his apartment.    Plainclothes partners buy drugs.
Ten tactical officers, known as the ``Jump Out Boys'' because they leap
out of their car whenever they see a crime, make the arrests.    Across
the city that day, about 200 of an estimated 1,000 armed robberies, auto
thefts and burglaries were believed to have been drug-related, said police
spokesman Ray Lang.    ``The burglaries and robberies are probably 50
percent related to drugs,'' said Lang. ``Whatever they steal, they pawn
it and use the money to buy drugs.''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 In <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, six men were face down on the floor of an abandoned, smoke-filled apartment as a handful of officers stood over them with guns drawn. Fragments of a copper mesh pad were found during a search, but the suspect denied knowing the pads often are used to strain crack. `` Some drug addict put that there,'' the man told police. `` This is a day-in, day-out battle,'' said Lt. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Richie </PERSON>, who heads the evening crew at <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s central division. If a crack addict has a $ 20,000 a year habit, he must steal about $ 200,000 worth of goods to support it, according to Capt. E.R. <PERSON> Walt </PERSON> of the Narcotics Division. `` Most crack addicts do n't work and could n't afford it if they did,'' <PERSON> Walt </PERSON> said. `` So there's a lot of stuff stolen.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 A 17-year-old <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> man was busted on his birthday Wednesday as police seized $ 1,500 in cash and $ 4,700 in drugs. Police saw him selling drugs the day before but could n't find his stash. `` Yeah, man, I'll be 17,'' he taunted officers. `` So they paid a visit to his house on his birthday,'' said Sgt. <PERSON> Leman </PERSON> <PERSON> Dobbins </PERSON>. `` If he's going to play in the grown folks' world, we're going to treat him like one.'' Police said six of the 14 reported crimes on Wednesday were drug-related, including auto break-ins, burglaries and robberies. `` For a brand new VCR, a guy might give you five to six capsules of heroin worth $ 50 or $ 60. For a brand new VCR, not a used one,'' <PERSON> Dobbins </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 The 52 drug arrests in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> on Wednesday included a federal fugitive wanted for allegedly helping a notorious drug kingpin arrange a multimillion-dollar heroin deal from his jail cell. Three other arrests followed a raid that netted $ 500,000 worth of cocaine and heroin. <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> <PERSON> Hines </PERSON>, 26, of <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> was arrested at 8 p.m. He was one of five people indicted by a federal grand jury in November on charges of conspiring in the sale of 5 kilograms of heroin to a Pakistani informant in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. In the cocaine-heroin raid, customers rang the bell to a third floor apartment and the occupants yelled down for orders, `` just as though you were talking to a neighbor,'' said officer <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Devine </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 In <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, 24 of 75 Wednesday arrests were drug-related, police said. Three came at a townhouse where police found dozens of bags of marijuana, cocaine, crack, $ 2,800 in cash, drug paraphernalia and a police scanner. Also in the house were a homemade apple pie on the oven and a wall papered with high school attendance awards and varsity football certificates. <PERSON> Shawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>, 18, his stepfather, <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sneed </PERSON>, 30, and his mother, <PERSON> Beverly </PERSON> <PERSON> Sneed </PERSON>, 39, were arrested and jailed on $ 35,000 bond. <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sneed </PERSON> were released the next day because of jail overcrowding.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 In <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, sheets of rain fell most of the day and city's two bicycle-mounted drug teams were off duty Wednesday. Only seven incidents involved the arrest of people in possession of drugs. Normally, an eight-hour shift in the city's downtown precinct will yield five to eight drug arrests. A targeted operation, usually held two or three times a week, might net 10 to 25 people at a time.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 If the war image were n't real enough, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> has approved a $ 300,000 project for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> to help police break up 80 flourishing drug markets in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-LeavingNicaragua Bjt   02-27 0844</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Leaving Nicaragua, Bjt,0876</SECOND>
<HEAD>Desperate Nicaraguans Undeterred By U.S. Immigration Policy</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DORALISA PILARTE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The young businesswoman looked tense and worried when the morning papers brought the news of the cordoba's fifth devaluation this year. The government's latest devaluation of the national currency meant only one thing: higher prices for food and transport; higher costs for doing business; yet another round of belt-tightening. `` If we ate meat three times a week, now we'll eat it once a week and so on until we become vegetarians,'' the woman said, toying with a pencil at her desk. `` But even vegetables are expensive _ when you can find them.'' The woman and her husband are urban professionals in their early 30s with a small business. They are expecting their third child. In private conversations, the two spoke of the hardships the middle class is enduring as a result of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s economic crisis and the thought that crosses so many people's minds: pack up and leave for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, where many have relatives and friends. The devaluation of the cordoba is part of the government's efforts to halt hyperinflation `` You keep cutting back and cutting back -LRB- on the household budget -RRB-, but now I'm wondering what else I can eliminate,'' the woman added. `` And if that's us and people like us,'' she said, leaning forward to emphasize her point, `` can you imagine what poor people are going through?'' Poor and middle-class people are leaving the country in droves, undeterred even by a get-tough <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> immigration policy that took effect last Tuesday. Despite a tripling of the price for a new passport, Nicaraguans still flock to immigration offices. A senior Western diplomat said figures compiled from various sources indicate that from 1979 _ when the leftist <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> came to power _ through 1987, <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> lost about 8,500 professionals. The diplomat, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said about 2,000 professional and business people left the country in 1988 alone _ despite the signing of a preliminary peace accord in March after seven years of war with the Contra rebels. <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s population is about 3 million `` That's people in education, business, engineering, medicine,'' the diplomat said. `` We're not talking about ideology; these are people seeking better horizons.'' With Thursday's latest currency devaluation, the official rate of exchange became 3,800 cordobas per dollar, up from 3,200. At the new rate, a typical monthly salary of 200,000 cordobas is worth $ 52. Many professionals earn up to 500,000 cordobas a month, which translates to only $ 131. A new passport costs 150,000 cordobas. With the lastest devaluation, the price of a gallon of gasoline rose to $ 2.07, up from $ 1.76 a gallon. Higher fuel costs mean higher prices for food, which is trucked into the city from the countryside. `` She's been pressuring me for us to get out of here and go to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>,'' the woman's husband confided when his wife was out of earshot. `` But I ca n't abandon my business now and lose all I've put into it.'' He said that even if he wanted to sell, he'd be hard pressed to find a buyer. To control runaway inflation that reached 20,000 in 1988 and 97 percent in January alone, the government is firing more than 30,000 workers, slashing public spending, and tightly restricting credit. President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> has summed up his government's attitude toward the exodus by saying that whoever does n't like it here can `` leave for <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> to look for democracy and ways to enrich themselves.'' The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> has summed up its new policy, aimed at Central Americans who usually come in illegally through <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, by saying that anyone who ca n't prove political persecution will be denied asylum and immediately jailed and deported. That policy led to only a small decrease last week in the number of people wanting to leave, said <PERSON> Sergio </PERSON> <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> <PERSON> Prado </PERSON>, who owns a travel agency specializing in trips to <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He said he used to organize trips to <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> buy bus but stopped because every increase in fuel costs increased the price of his bus tickets. `` People did n't understand. Now I just deal in plane tickets. They're more stable,'' he said. His customers often make their way from <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. On a recent evening, people began assembling on a sidewalk in a lower-class neighborhood of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> to wait for a bus to <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>. Sitting on the curb in front of a travel agency were small knots of travelers and their relatives. Some were silent; others cried. <PERSON> Lourdes </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Rayo </PERSON> <PERSON> Vargas </PERSON>, 23, was leaving with her 15-year-old sister and their mother. They were the last in the family to leave. Their father and three brothers had left for <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> four months ago. `` I was the only one in the family working,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Rayo </PERSON>. `` I worked in a supermarket, then I sold shoes. Now I've been out of work for seven months.'' She said she gave up trying to find a job.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     02-27 0906</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0950</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Oscar-winning actor <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON>, who sued <ORGANIZATION> MGM </ORGANIZATION> for allegedly deceiving him in 1983 about the demise of the motion picture `` Roadshow,'' has been awarded $ 9.75 million in damages from the studio. A jury found Friday that the studio committed fraud and breach of contract. <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON>, who won an Academy Award for his role in the film `` Ordinary People,'' said studio executives told him the picture, about a modern-day cattle drive, was being called off because director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON> had suffered a heart attack. Actually, <ORGANIZATION> MGM </ORGANIZATION> lost interest in the movie after a change of management, the actor said. The monthlong trial included testimony from other `` Roadshow'' actors, including <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicholson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Nicholson </PERSON> resolved matters with <ORGANIZATION> MGM </ORGANIZATION> several years ago, the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. MGM is now owned by <ORGANIZATION> Turner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION>. `` Turner is very surprised and disappointed in the verdict and will seek a further review,'' a company attorney said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Liz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Claiborne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> soon wo n't have <PERSON> Liz </PERSON> <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> as boss. Ms. <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON>, 59, said Sunday she will retire in June as chairwoman and president of the major clothing design house she founded. She is one of the few female chief executives of a major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> company. The company also announced that Ms. <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON>'s husband, <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortenberg </PERSON>, who co-founded the company, will retire from his position as vice chairman of the board of directors. Both will remain as board members, the company said. `` We are looking forward to making time to devote to personal interests and to enjoying the fruits of our labors,'' the couple said in a statement. Vice Chairman <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chazen </PERSON> will become chairman upon Ms. <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON>'s retirement, the company said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickerson </PERSON>, the first woman TV news correspondent and now a commentator for <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>, has married former Deputy Secretary of State <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitehead </PERSON>. The couple was married Saturday at <PERSON> Dickerson </PERSON>'s home in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. In 1960, she became the first woman TV correspondent, covering <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, political conventions and civil rights for <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> and then for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Whitehead </PERSON>, who until last month was the deputy secretary of state, is the chairman of <ORGANIZATION> AEA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> investment company.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ORIENT, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Paycheck </PERSON> is in prison for shooting a man in a bar. But he said that does n't mean his country music career has to stop. Paycheck, 50, began serving a seven - to 9 -LCB- - year sentence this He wo n't be eligible for parole for at least 5 -LCB- years. The singer, best remembered for his 1978 hit `` Take This Job and Shove It,'' wants to record an album with other inmate musicians and use the money to help pay medical bills for his wife, who has cancer. `` We did n't have no insurance,'' he said. `` I have attorney bills, doctor bills. When I had the money and I could have put it away, I did n't have much sense.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MEDFORD, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Shuttle astronaut <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Hauck </PERSON> returned to <ORGANIZATION> Tufts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, his alma mater, with the brown and blue college flag he took into space with him in 1984. <PERSON> Hauck </PERSON>, 48, said <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> has become a much stronger agency since the Challenger explosion. `` We had all our eggs in one basket before,'' said <PERSON> Hauck </PERSON>. `` Now both military and civilian space programs are developing unmanned missions as an alternative.'' <PERSON> Hauck </PERSON> is leaving his career in space to work at the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` I know I'll miss going into space,'' he said Friday. `` It's a wonderful thing to be in 4 -LCB- million pounds of machinery launched into the heavens.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Versions of the following two items moved on the sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>IRVING, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Landry </PERSON> said he knew the moment the <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cowboys </ORGANIZATION> were sold that he was done as the football team's coach `` No one had to tell me,'' he said in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Landry </PERSON>, who was the team's only coach in its 29-year history, was fired Saturday night after <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> oilman <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> bought the team and replaced <PERSON> Landry </PERSON> with <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricanes </ORGANIZATION>' head coach <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Landry </PERSON>, 64, said he will probably never coach again `` because it would just be hard, not being in the <ORGANIZATION> Cowboys </ORGANIZATION>' blue.'' Though being fired was an emotional experience, <PERSON> Landry </PERSON> said, `` I'm not upset over what happened. I've never been one to get that upset because I accept people as they are.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Olympic sprinter <PERSON> Florence </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> <PERSON> Joyner </PERSON> is n't slowing down, despite her retirement from track competition. On Sunday, a day after announcing her retirement, <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> <PERSON> Joyner </PERSON> said she's ready to pursue her interests in writing and acting as well as signing a series of endorsement contracts. `` I'm ... looking to more things in my life, to move on, because I know I'll be just as happy as I was in track and field,'' she said. <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> <PERSON> Joyner </PERSON>, 29, appeared at a news conference held after she received the <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> for Intercultural and Race Relations Award. <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> <PERSON> Joyner </PERSON> said she was honored to win the award, which has been given in the past to Bishop <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> and <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON>, secretary general of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. `` Just thinking about who has won the award, it gets me excited. It takes me back to <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>,'' she said. There, at the Olympics, <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> <PERSON> Joyner </PERSON> won three gold medals and a silver.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 0105EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-PalmeCase Bjt   02-27 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Palme Case, Bjt,0735</SECOND>
<HEAD>On Third Anniversary of Leader's Murder, Swedes Hope Case Solved</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ARTHUR MAX</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After three frustrating years, Swedes hope the mystery behind the assassination of Prime Minister <PERSON> Olof </PERSON> <PERSON> Palme </PERSON> is finally solved and that his accused killer will soon be tried. Prosecutors are reported to be worried, however, that their case may not hold up against the man arrested 10 weeks ago on suspicion of gunning down Palme on a <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION> street on Feb. 28, 1986. They acknowledge that crucial pieces of evidence are missing. If they have found a motive, they are n't saying. Legal experts say the case will rest on whether a chain of circumstantial evidence can be established. `` The prosecution is in bad shape if they do n't find the murder weapon or present other very strong forensic evidence,'' said <PERSON> Lena </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmqvist </PERSON>, a lecturer in criminal law at <ORGANIZATION> Uppsala </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. Since the shooting, police have dedicated nearly one million man-hours and hundreds of millions of dollars chasing international conspiracy theories centering on <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> or on Kurdish terrorists. In the end, the suspect they arrested was a Swede, a loner with a previous manslaughter conviction and a history of drug addiction, alcohol abuse and psychiatric treatment. The arrest Dec. 14 of <PERSON> Christer </PERSON> <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON>, 41, came as such an anticlimax that one legal commentator wrote in the <ORGANIZATION> Dagens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nyheter </ORGANIZATION> daily that `` the borderline between reality and fiction is being erased.'' <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON>'s lawyer says his client has denied any connection with the slaying, which occurred as Palme was walking home from a movie with his wife <PERSON> Lisbet </PERSON>, who was grazed by a second bullet and survived. Prosecutors have released virtually no information about their case, and <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON>'s name can not even be published here under Swedish press regulations. But they have made enough headway to persuade a judge five times to extend the two-week detention order against him. `` There has been progress ... but we can not make any estimate of how long the investigation will go on,'' chief prosecutor <PERSON> Jorgen </PERSON> <PERSON> Almblad </PERSON> said two weeks ago. Published reports say the prosecution's case was built on witnesses who placed the suspect at the scene. Mrs. <PERSON> Palme </PERSON> has identified <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON> as the gunman, but without absolute certainty, the reports say. If the case against <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON> falls apart, the testimony of the few eyewitnesses would be useless against anyone else, virtually destroying any chance of sending <PERSON> Palme </PERSON>'s killer to prison. <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON>, who was questioned briefly and released shortly after the murder, came under suspicion again after police received a tip that his alibi was phony. He has a long criminal record, which includes the fatal bayonet stabbing of a man in a street brawl in 1970. `` I think most people were pleased that we finally have found someone and are relieved that it's a Swede,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Holmqvist </PERSON>. `` If it's an ordinary maniac, we can leave the whole story behind us.'' Under Swedish law, the case would be heard by the <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION> district court before a panel of one judge and five laymen, each of whom have equal say on whether to convict. A 4-2 vote is enough for conviction, but a tie means acquittal. The slaying of <LOCATION> Palme </LOCATION>, a four-term prime minister who championed international disarmament, jolted Swedes from the idea that they were safe from the viciousness and terrorism that afflict other countries. But the national trauma is fading. Last year, people stopped putting fresh flowers on the improvised sidewalk monument where Palme fell. Palme's governing <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> party </ORGANIZATION> said it planned no ceremony to mark the anniversary this year. The three-year manhunt exposed some weaknesses in the Swedish criminal system. Many Swedes were astonished that a man with <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON>'s violent past was free on the street. Several parliamentary committees criticized the police for bungling the investigation. For years, police and prosecutors squabbled over who was in charge of the case since the law is not specific. Frustration over the failure to make an arrest also encouraged overzealous authorities to approve a private investigation that overstepped legal limits. The resulting scandal forced the resignation of Justice Minister <PERSON> Anna-Greta </PERSON> <PERSON> Leijon </PERSON> in June, and a parliamentiary commitee is now trying to find out how much unauthorized eavesdropping and other illegal activity was going on.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890227-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-27-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Honduras-Violence     02-27 0932</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Honduras-Violence,0961</SECOND>
<HEAD>Caught In The Middle, Honduras Fears Reaction To Violence</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD HERZFELDER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
