<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 2345EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Salvador     11-07 0646</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Salvador,0668</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Salvadoran Leftists Tortured, Slain</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCOS ALEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The tortured, shot bodies of three members of a leftist party were found Tuesday in western <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, a party spokesman said. He accused the military and demanded that those responsible be handed over for prosecution. Spokesman <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> said that because of recent attacks, `` our leaders have ordered all party installations closed. ... The authorities are threatening us, they do not let us operate.'' <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in a telephone interview that <PERSON> Cecilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON>, the movement's coordinator in western <LOCATION> Sonsonate </LOCATION> province, was kidnapped on Monday with two other party members. He said their bodies, showing signs of torture and bullet-riddled, were found on the outskirts of <LOCATION> Sonsonate </LOCATION> city, the provincial capital 40 miles west of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, on Tuesday evening. Local judicial authorities ordered the three bodies buried as unidentified cadavers, but party members were able to identify them, <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> said. He said <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON>'s age and the names and ages of the other two were not available immediately. `` Our comrades were seized by military officials dressed in civilian clothes after a meeting at the party hall -LRB- in <LOCATION> Sonsonate </LOCATION> -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> said, adding that they were killed `` in death-squad style'' and a hand-printed sign was found next to the bodies saying they had `` betrayed the fatherland.'' `` We hold those military officials dressed in civilian clothes responsible and we ask that the Sonsonate commander turn them over to judicial authorities,'' <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> said. The commander is Col. <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Armando </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>. <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Martel </PERSON>, a member of the party's national executive, told reporters: `` We do not have the least doubt the three were seized by soldiers dressed in civilian clothes.'' According to human rights organizations, most of the more than 70,000 people killed in a 10-year-old leftist guerrilla war have been civilians slain by rightist death squads that were especially active from 1979 to 1984. Death-squad activity sharply diminished in mid-1984 with the election of President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>, a centrist Christian Democrat. Repression of leftists started again when rightist President <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> succeeded <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> on June 1 for a five-year term. Leftists have often accused <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> of being linked to the death squads, made up of off-duty military and security agents. A bomb wrecked the headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> Salvadoran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> on Oct. 31, killing 10 people and wounding 29. Earlier that day, another bomb injured four people at <LOCATION> Comadres </LOCATION>, an organization of relatives of political prisoners and people who have disappeared in the civil war. Two of those injured in the blasts were Americans. Leaders of those two leftist groups accused the military of mounting the bombings in retaliation for an Oct. 30 mortar attack by the <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> on the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> compound that killed one civilian and wounded 15. The <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> was created in 1980 by dissidents who broke away from <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. The <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> home of party leader <PERSON> Ruben </PERSON> <PERSON> Zamora </PERSON> was bombed Oct. 19, but no one was hurt. <PERSON> Zamora </PERSON> is a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, a political coalition allied to the <LOCATION> Farabundo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Marti </LOCATION> guerrillas. He long lived in exile but returned to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> two years ago when the <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> government promised an end to repression. <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> said that now the union halls, offices and other installations were being closed because the party does not want to see more members killed. To protest the attacks, <PERSON> Farabundo </PERSON> <PERSON> Marti </PERSON> canceled its participation in a third meeting with <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> government representatives Nov. 20-21 in <LOCATION> Caracas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>, to negotiate a cease-fire. Earlier meetings in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, ended in deadlock but the two sides had agreed to continue meeting at 30-day intervals until they could agree on some kind of a truce.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 2348EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-ELN--DinkinsProfile     11-07 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-ELN--Dinkins Profile,0632</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Clubhouse Politician Reaches The Heights</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY SCHWARTZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> is no political meteor, streaking suddenly across the civic firmament to seek office as the first black mayor of the nation's most populous city. He is a deliberate, courtly man who entered politics more than 30 years ago, working his way up the ladder one rung at a time _ clubhouse worker, assemblyman, district leader, city clerk, borough president. When he defeated three-term incumbent <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> in September's Democratic primary, the top of the ladder was within reach. On Tuesday, he defeated Republican <PERSON> Rudolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON> to become the 106th mayor of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. `` What I do is provide hope,'' <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON>, 62, said some months ago _ hope to other blacks who want to climb up the city's power structure. He is a soft-spoken, cordial man whose diction is perfect; a man who wears well-tailored suits, made in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Chinatown </LOCATION>; an avid tennis player who is said to have a very strong forehand. Born in <LOCATION> Trenton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, the son of a barber, <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> earned a bachelor's degree in math at <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> after a tour in the Marines. He went on to <ORGANIZATION> Brooklyn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, graduating in 1956; he had already married <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Burrows </PERSON>, daughter of a <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> assemblyman. <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> joined a law firm, but also joined the <ORGANIZATION> Carver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> base of powerbroker <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, who later became <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>'s Democratic chairman, was mentor to a generation of black politicians, preaching a moderate course and encouraging compromise with the white establishment. In 1965, <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> was elected to the state Assembly. His seat was eliminated by reapportionment a year later, but in 1967 <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> was elected a district leader from the <ORGANIZATION> Carver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, a job he would retain for 20 years. In 1975, he was appointed city clerk. He ran three times for <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> borough president before winning the office in 1985. Though none of these jobs is all-powerful, <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> used each post as a platform to speak out against discrimination and to support organized labor. He seldom took the spotlight, and he rarely made enemies. His one misstep was soon forgiven, though it came back to haunt him when he ran for mayor. In 1973, <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> was named deputy mayor for planning, but when a background check disclosed that he had failed to file income taxes for four years he was forced to give up the post. He paid $ 15,000 in back taxes and ascribed his actions to negligence. The omission was especially surprising given <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON>' legendary cautious nature. Before he announced his candidacy in February _ promising `` a different direction, new ideas and a fresh perspective'' _ he formed a committee to examine whether he should run. He ran as an unabashed liberal, but his was not a campaign brimming with position papers and brash promises. Instead, he focused on the need for reconciliation of the city's diverse population. He handily defeated <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> in the primary, 51 percent to 42 percent. In the general election, <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON>' taxes were an issue, as were his transfer of stock in a cable company to his son and his acceptance of a friend's gift of a free vacation to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. So too was his friendship with <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who is distrusted by many in the Jewish community. <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> would not renounce <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, but said the former presidential candidate was not an advisor; he reminded Jewish groups that he had condemned the anti-Semitism of Muslim Minister <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> and his wife have lived in the same three-bedroom apartment in upper <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> for 26 years. They have two grown children and one grandchild.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Jordan-Campaign Bjt   11-07 0714</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jordan-Campaign, Bjt,0736</SECOND>
<HEAD>Desert-Style Electioneering In Runup To First Nationwide Vote In
22 Years</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN MARRIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MAAN, Jordan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Young men wrestled a camel to the ground, slit its throat and butchered it for a banquet thrown by parliament candidate <PERSON> Suleiman </PERSON> <PERSON> Arar </PERSON> in this desert town where bloody price riots broke out six months ago. Such rituals of rural campaigning in this sleepy town of 25,000 are partly the result of the violence that prompted King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> to call the first nationwide elections in 22 years. There were few visible reminders of April's riots, just the occasional scar on the street where tires were set alight during unrest that left 10 people dead nationwide. The talk in <LOCATION> Maan </LOCATION>, 120 miles south of <LOCATION> Amman </LOCATION>, was about Wednesday's elections and little else as local men met to chat with their friends in diwans, gatherings often held beneath goat's hair tents. Old men wearing red-and-white headdresses and younger ones in Western-style suits sat under one tent on a dusty lot beside <PERSON> Arar </PERSON>'s house sipping tea and smoking Arabic water pipes Among them was a local notable, <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Turki </PERSON> <PERSON> Sabah </PERSON> <PERSON> Krayshan </PERSON>, who called the elections for the 80-seat parliament `` a new page in our history, a new lease of life for our country.'' He said <PERSON> Arar </PERSON>, a former interior minister who most people in <LOCATION> Maan </LOCATION> call <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON>, `` will listen to the people, and he will present their requests to the parliament.'' The new parliament must approve all laws and budgets and it can even override the king's veto. It can also toss out the royally appointed Cabinet, a right spirited lawmakers exercised several times in the past. But <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> remains the center of power, and he has the power to dissolve parliament and rule without it, as he has done for most of the past 15 years. A young man who helped slice the camel into chunks for the banquet said `` it's a special treat, and we'll be killing a lot more camels after <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> wins the election.'' Twenty-eight candidates are competing for five seats in the sprawling Maan governorate. Another 13 are vying for two rural seats reserved for southern Bedouin tribes. The April violence in <LOCATION> Maan </LOCATION> was sparked by taxi drivers angry at a 25 percent increase in gasoline prices. But most of the rioters were young men frustrated by rising prices and a lack of jobs. At one diwan, a young man told a visiting reporter that `` the government must do something about unemployment and about public services here, which are not as good as in <LOCATION> Amman </LOCATION>.'' But older tribesmen quickly urged him to quiet down. <PERSON> Turki </PERSON> denied that there was a gap between older leaders known as `` the sheiks'' and a younger generation of often better-educated Jordanians trying to break away from tribal influence. `` There are differences between the old people and the young,'' he acknowledged. `` But they're very slight. All the youth are with the sheiks.'' But columnist <PERSON> Mariam </PERSON> <PERSON> Shahin </PERSON> wrote in the <ORGANIZATION> Jordan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> daily that the influence of the sheiks appears to be eroding in some districts. She quoted one younger candidate as saying: `` Tribal leaders have had their chance. Look where it got them. `` Our rural areas have been neglected as far as educational, economic, social and cultural development projects are concerned. So why should they be given another chance?'' In <LOCATION> Maan </LOCATION>, local journalist <PERSON> Mustafa </PERSON> <PERSON> Khoshman </PERSON> said tribal allegiances would be more potent in the elections than any political stands by the candidates. The Maan region has the largest area but the smallest population of <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s governorates. Its 150,000 people are overwhelmingly of Bedouin stock and form the bedrock of <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>'s support. The railroad that runs through Maan along the Islamic pilgrimage route to <LOCATION> Mecca </LOCATION> was repeatedly attacked by T.E. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> _ <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> _ during his campaign against the Turks alongside <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>'s ancestors during World War I. The southern Bedouins of the Howeitat tribe were famous for their bravery in the battles that helped put <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>'s grandfather, King <PERSON> Abdullah </PERSON>, on the throne. `` His majesty the king is very popular here,'' said <PERSON> Turki </PERSON>, who said <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> was welcomed like a hero when he visited <PERSON> Maan </PERSON> after the riots. `` He can come here any time. There will be no problems,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0005EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-ELN--TV     11-07 0162</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-ELN--TV,0168</SECOND>
<HEAD>Election Reports on Television</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two television networks are planning brief special reports tonight on today's state and local elections while a third says it will cover the results in its regular news programs. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> plans to interrupt its programming with a brief special report when results on major races become available, then give more coverage in its half-hour `` Nightline'' show at 11:30 p.m. EST, according to spokeswoman <PERSON> Elise </PERSON> <PERSON> Adde </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> will have a 15-minute special report, `` Decision'89,'' at 11:30 p.m. EST, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> McQuay </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> plans to report on the elections in its regular news broadcasts, including up to an hour of coverage on `` Nightwatch,'' airing at 1:35 a.m. EST Wednesday in some areas, 2 a.m. in others. On cable television, <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> will have election reports throughout the night, said spokesman <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Haworth </PERSON>. Major contests include races for governor in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and for mayor in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0024EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-General-Bribery     11-07 0432</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-General-Bribery,0446</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dominican Republic General Arrested in Bribery Scheme</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD COLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A general from the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> was jailed Monday for allegedly accepting bribes to release a drug plane impounded in his homeland. Gen. <PERSON> Joaquin </PERSON> <PERSON> Pou </PERSON>, 54, who <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Dexter </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehtinen </PERSON> said had identified himself at different times as either an active or retired general, was ordered held without bond during an appearance Monday before a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> magistrate. He was taken into custody when he arrived at a <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> airport, said <PERSON> Lehtinen </PERSON>. `` All I can tell you he was arrested Sunday,'' <PERSON> Lehtinen </PERSON> said. `` He came to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> in furtherance of the conspiracy.'' <PERSON> Pou </PERSON>, who had close contacts with other Dominican generals and aviation officials, allegedly received about $ 20,000 to release a confiscated plane, according to federal authorities. Also arrested for violating the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act was <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Guasch </PERSON>, 43, a Miami-based aide to the general, who was granted a $ 250,000 bond Monday. A third defendant, pilot <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Gurin </PERSON>, was expected to turn himself in Tuesday, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney's office said. <PERSON> Lehtinen </PERSON>, saying the investigation was continuing, refused to reveal many details of the case, but authorities released an affidavit by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Customs Agent <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Lang </PERSON>. <PERSON> Lang </PERSON> said in the affidavit that in February Customs and the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> began investigating `` allegations of the bribery of high-ranking military officials of the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gurin </PERSON> ... to assure the release of aircraft seized by the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> for narcotics smuggling.'' <PERSON> Gurin </PERSON> was also involved with officials in <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>, and the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>, the affidavit said. Informants told <PERSON> Lang </PERSON> that <PERSON> Gurin </PERSON>, who owns <ORGANIZATION> AEA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recovery </ORGANIZATION>, was aided by <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, manager of the international field office of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, the affidavit said. At one point, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> was taped by agents as saying `` my darkest dream is being picked up and put in a ... jail right here in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> was not indicted, and <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> said the agency had only just learned of the case. <PERSON> Lehtinen </PERSON> would say only that the investigation was continuing. Through informants and taped phone calls, Customs learned that <PERSON> Gurin </PERSON> was trying to recover a Rockwell Aerocommander 690 B seized in the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gurin </PERSON> at one point said he paid $ 50,000 to get another plane released in that country. On the tapes, <PERSON> Gurin </PERSON> also said a <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> attorney, <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Duran </PERSON>, was channeling the money to generals in the Dominican military through an escrow account. <PERSON> Duran </PERSON> has not been charged in the case, and <PERSON> Lehtinen </PERSON> refused to discuss him further.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     11-07 0910</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0954</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SYRACUSE, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON> withdrew from a production of `` A Walk in the Woods'' after experiencing chest pains, organizers said. `` It became clear he could not handle the show,'' said co-producer <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Weisler </PERSON>. `` He ... wo n't be permitted to travel until he is out of pain and the doctor gives his approval.'' <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON>'s withdrawal Saturday forced cancellation of previews scheduled for Sunday, today and Wednesday at <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stage </ORGANIZATION>. Stage officials said Monday the 74-year-old actor was under the care of his personal physician in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. They said there was no diagnosis. Director <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Storch </PERSON> said <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON> was in pain early last week. `` We were rehearsing the scene in which the Soviet diplomat has an angina attack and <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> said, ` I know what that is. I have it.' And we talked about it,'' <PERSON> Storch </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON> was to portray the diplomat in the play, which is about the friendship struck between <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms negotiators. Opening night is still set for Friday, but <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON> has been replaced by <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammer </PERSON>. The show also stars <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hormann </PERSON>. A planned tour may be scuttled, <PERSON> Storch </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HOUSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Duchess of York ended a five-day visit to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> with a visit to an inner-city school, where she took part in a day filled with anti-drug messages. The 30-year-old former <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> also was serenaded by more than 600 pupils at <ORGANIZATION> Blackshear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. The duchess, who is married to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s Prince <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, came to <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> on Thursday at the invitation of the <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opera </ORGANIZATION>, which is saluting 300 years of British opera. At the school, she participated in an anti-drug play and handed over autographed copies of her two children books about a helicopter named `` Budgie.'' The students gave her a book they had written and made her feel like royalty with a playground performance. `` Your Royal Highness, the Duchess of <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, from the boys and girls of <ORGANIZATION> Blackshear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, may I present to you these flowers and ask for your permission to sing?'' shouted 8-year-old <PERSON> Jermaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Thibodeaux </PERSON>, who gave the duchess a bouquet of yellow roses. The duchess gave her the go-ahead, and the students sang `` Deep in the Heart of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>,'' `` Yankee Doodle Dandy,'' `` We are the World,'' and an anti-drug song. Later Monday, she left on a flight to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, where she was to meet with her publisher, <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Schuster.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>JUNEAU, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southeast </ORGANIZATION> has set its sights high for a speaker at next spring's commencement: Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. `` My feeling is there can be no way to find out unless you do ask,'' said Professor <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> <PERSON> Olson </PERSON>, who suggested the invitation. Chancellor <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> <PERSON> Lind </PERSON> said Monday he discussed the invitation with <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Dubinin </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> ambassador to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, during <PERSON> Dubinin </PERSON>'s recent <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION> visit. <PERSON> Lind </PERSON> said he was told the invitation is being considered in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. A response is not expected until December. The commencement is scheduled May 4 in <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION>. `` We feel that he would be a very appropriate speaker for us in view of all the things that are taking place between <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Lind </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Olson </PERSON> said his idea was inspired by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s role in permitting visa-free travel between the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> for the region's natives. If <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is unable to speak in person, the university is hoping for the next best thing _ a speech broadcast by satellite or videotape.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Engelbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Humperdinck </PERSON> will appeal a judge's dismissal of his $ 50 million lawsuit against <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enquirer </ORGANIZATION> for its report that the mother of the singer's daughter fears he had the AIDS virus <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Rotstein </PERSON>, an attorney for the singer, said Monday the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> lawsuit was dismissed last week but <PERSON> Humperdinck </PERSON> would appeal. <PERSON> Humperdinck </PERSON> has tested negative for the virus, <PERSON> Rotstein </PERSON> said. The Enquirer stood behind the article, which it said was based on a court filing and was thereby not libelous. `` We feel vindicated by the judge's verdict,'' said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, an editor with the Florida-based tabloid. <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jetter </PERSON> filed papers in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s Family Court demanding that <PERSON> Humperdinck </PERSON>, 53, provide for the financial future of her 12-year-old daughter, ruled by a court to be his daughter. <PERSON> Humperdinck </PERSON>'s lawsuit said the woman's claims about the entertainer were false and have been dismissed by the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> court. <PERSON> Rotstein </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> court's decision was based on an overly broad reading of libel law.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Jaclyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, one of the original `` Charlie's Angels'' TV sleuths who moved on to serious roles in such dramas as `` Windmills of the Gods,'' now has a star on the Hollywood Walk of Fame. More than 200 fans and friends, including actors <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferrer </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Bellamy </PERSON>, cheered during Monday's unveiling of the sidewalk star, the 1,903 rd dedicated along <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Boulevard </LOCATION> and Vine Street <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> sponsored the star and paid the $ 3,500 cost. In 1976, she starred with <PERSON> Farrah </PERSON> <PERSON> Fawcett </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in `` Charlie's Angels.'' Four years later, she played the title role in <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON> <PERSON> Bouvier </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>.'' In recent years, she has appeared in `` Rage of Angels,'' `` <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nightingale </LOCATION>,'' `` Sentimental Journey,'' `` The Bourne Identity'' and `` Settle the Score.'' Miss <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> returns to series television this fall in the new two-hour <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> series `` <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> Cromwell </PERSON>,'' part of `` The <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Saturday Mystery'' lineup.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-USATodayTV     11-07 0237</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-USA Today TV,0242</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Producer Settles Lawsuit</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bellows </PERSON>, the former managing editor of `` USA Today on TV,'' has settled his $ 1.8 million lawsuit against the company that makes the syndicated series. He called the agreement `` an amicable settlement.'' <PERSON> Bellows </PERSON>' attorney, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Zweig </PERSON>, and M.S. `` Bud'' <PERSON> Rukeyser </PERSON>, a spokesman for the producers <ORGANIZATION> GTG </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION>, said terms of the settlement could not be revealed. The company is the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> branch of <ORGANIZATION> GTG </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION>, which is based in <LOCATION> Culver </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and is a co-venture of former <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> <PERSON> Tinker </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Gannett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bellows </PERSON> filed his lawsuit in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> here on Oct. 2 He was the second of four senior executives that have run <ORGANIZATION> GTG </ORGANIZATION>'s show since it premiered in September 1988 as `` USA Today: The Television Show. <PERSON> Bellows </PERSON> was hired under a two-year contract paying him $ 275,000 a year. He took over the series in October 1988 and left in March to help develop a new program for GTG. His lawsuit alleged he was fired without cause or warning. <PERSON> Bellows </PERSON>, 66, is a former newspaperman who also has worked at <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> and has been executive producer of the syndicated `` Entertainment Tonight'' series. He said in an interview he has n't decided what he'll do next However, he said Monday, he plans to move back to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> next summer. He has lived in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> since 1983.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0018EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Iowa-Insurance 1stLd-Writethru a0693 11-07 0546</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iowa-Insurance, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0693,0558</SECOND>
<HEAD>Truitt, Hartwig Family Agree on Insurance Settlement</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 7th graf, `Hartwig's family ...,' with 4 grafs to UPDATE
with comment from Hartwig family spokeswoman; picks up 8th graf, ```If
the insurance ...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD COLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former USS <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> sailor <PERSON> Kendall </PERSON> <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> will share a $ 100,000 insurance claim with the family of a crewmate whom the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> concluded probably caused a deadly gun turret explosion, his attorney said Monday. Gunner's mate <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> had named <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> as beneficiary for the life insurance policy taken out about a year ago. The connection initially focused <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> investigators' attention on <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> after the April 19 disaster that killed 47 sailors, including <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>. <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> was later cleared, but the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> insists that <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> was the most likely cause of the explosion, possibly as part of a suicide. Settlement of the insurance policy was initially held up by <ORGANIZATION> Amex </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rafael </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, because of a dispute between <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>'s family. The money was paid Sept. 13 to <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> after <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> filed a lawsuit, said <PERSON> Melinda </PERSON> <PERSON> McMullen </PERSON>, the insurer's spokeswoman. The dispute ended with Monday's agreement, releasing the $ 100,000, said <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON>'s attorney <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON>. <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> refused to give details of the agreement. `` Some of the money will be paid to the <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> family in recognition of the loss of their son, and we are allocating an amount to the building of a memorial or monument to all 47 sailors who died,'' <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> said. `` It's a very minimal sum, but we are not allowed to disclose how much,'' said <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Kubicina </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>'s sister and spokeswoman for the family. She said her father was `` really upset.'' She said that <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> had told her parents they would get most of the money because it was such a large amount, `` but now he seems to have forgotten'' what he said. <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>'s family and <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> have challenged the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s conclusions <PERSON> Kubicina </PERSON> said the insurance company `` did an investigation of their own and came to the conclusion there was no suicide or murder involved.'' `` If the insurance company thought he had committed suicide, they would not pay off the policy,'' said <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON>. `` It's another indication that the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> theory of suicide by <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> will not hold water.'' <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON>, now stationed at <LOCATION> Mayport </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Naval </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, is scheduled to testify Wednesday before a congressional committee investigating the explosion, <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> said, and would have no comment before then. The insurance policy named <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> as the beneficiary of <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>'s $ 50,000 life insurance coverage, which had a double-indemnity clause for accidental death. <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> filed a lawsuit Aug. 14 seeking payment from Amex. <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> died in the explosion, while, <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON>, on a lower floor of the gun turret, survived unhurt. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s official report by Rear Adm. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Milligan </PERSON> cleared <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON>, and cited <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> as the most likely person to have caused the explosion, saying he apparently placed some type of detonator between powder bags while loading a 16-inch gun. Leaks from the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> investigation suggested that <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> had a homosexual relationship that had gone sour. <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON>, who is married, strongly denied any sexual relationship with <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>, and the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> concluded there was no evidence <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> was a homosexual.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ShootingRampage 1stLd-Writethru a0401 11-07 0342</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Shooting Rampage, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0401,0350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Dead, Two Wounded in Ga. Shooting</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 2-3 to ADD locator, CORRECT spelling of Frederick's
wife's name to Gwendolyn, sted Gwyn. SUBS last 4 grafs, `Police tried ...,'
with 5 grafs to UPDATE with niece's name, quote from sheriff, CORRECT that
children were two daughters, sted daughter and son. No pickup. ADDS byline.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELLIOTT MINOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANDERSONVILLE, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man shot his mother and wife to death Monday, wounded his sister and a niece, then killed himself, a state police spokesman said. The rampage occurred at the home of <ORGANIZATION> Polly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mae </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Frederick </ORGANIZATION>, mother of <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON>, in the southwest <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> city, said <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investigation </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bankhead </PERSON>. <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON>, 28, of <LOCATION> Sumter </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> and his 20-year-old wife, <PERSON> Gwendolyn </PERSON>, had gone to the house to do laundry Monday afternoon, <PERSON> Bankhead </PERSON> said. An argument occurred around 1:30 p.m., and <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> shot the two women in the head, killing both, the spokesman said. <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON>'s 33-year-old sister, <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON>, ran outside to lead their brother, <PERSON> LeRoy </PERSON>, who is blind, to safety. But <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> followed them outside and shot his sister in the head. <PERSON> LeRoy </PERSON> <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> ran to <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> 271, and got the attention of a truck driver, who called police. <LOCATION> Sumter </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's deputies, the <ORGANIZATION> GBI </ORGANIZATION> and state police rushed to the scene. Police tried to talk <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> out, but eventually fired a tear-gas canister into the house. Officers found him dead and a niece, <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Watts </PERSON>, hiding under a bed with a gunshot wound in her side, <PERSON> Bankhead </PERSON> said. Officers found Ms. <PERSON> Watts </PERSON>' two daughters, aged 4 and 2, locked inside a car parked near the house, where they apparently fled when the shooting began, the spokesman said. <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> underwent surgery at <ORGANIZATION> Columbus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, and was in critical condition Monday night. Ms. <PERSON> Watts </PERSON> was in stable condition at <ORGANIZATION> Sumter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Americus </LOCATION>. `` I was shocked,'' said <LOCATION> Sumter </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>. `` He wiped his family out. I just do n't understand. We may never know why it happened.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-DriftNets 1stLd-Writethru a0591 11-07 0415</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Drift Nets, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0591,0425</SECOND>
<HEAD>States Urge Reduction of Drift Net Fishing</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: ADDS 6 grafs to ADD U.N. action. No pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Six Western states and the province of <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> on Monday issued a proclamation urging their federal governments to take action to reduce drift net fishing in the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>. The proclamation was announced at a news conference preceding the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fisheries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> meeting this week in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. The proclamation seeks reductions in Japanese high-seas salmon fisheries to reduce the impact of squid fleets on salmon, albacore tuna, seabirds and marine mammals. The proclamation also wants <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to establish a new convention in the ocean region aimed at protecting salmon in international waters. It would also form a research organization among the nations. The states are <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. Drift nets are small, monofilament nets that are draggd through the water and catch everything they come in contact with. About 800 fishing vessels from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> use the nets in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>. On any given day, the drift net fleet can cover 30,000 miles of ocean. The <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fisheries </ORGANIZATION> estimates that the annual damage to fisheries on the high seas by drift net boats at about $ 100 million _ including the effects on salmon, albacore tuna and other <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> fisheries. Also Monday, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> joined <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> nations at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> in denouncing driftnet fishing as `` potentially devastating technology'' that massacres marine mammals, sea birds and unwanted fish. A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> delegate, Ambassador <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, told the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Second </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which deals with the environment and other social affairs, that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is joining the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> and other nations in a resolution banning the huge drift nets. Under the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> resolution, drift-net fishing would be abolished immediately in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>, and phased out worldwide by June 30, 1992. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had no objection to developing nations using small drift nets that allow fish multiply and renew the stocks, but was opposed to the vast `` pelagic'' driftnets. The resolution is cosponsored by <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fiji </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mauritania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Papua </LOCATION> <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Guinea </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Solomon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vanuatu </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Zaire </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>. It does not single out any nation for criticism, but expresses concern of the indiscriminate nature of driftnet fishing and sets out proposals for international management and the eventual ban of driftnet use.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Braniff 2ndLd-Writethru a0431 11-07 0384</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Braniff, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0431,0393</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Braniff Ceases Flight Schedule</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: ADDS six grafs background; no pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ORLANDO, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Braniff </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> announced Monday it was ceasing all passenger service immediately because a severe cash shortage doomed its bankruptcy reorganization plan. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> McGee </PERSON>, the company's chairman, president and chief executive officer, said the action was taken to preserve assets while <ORGANIZATION> Braniff </ORGANIZATION> continues to develop alternatives, which might include selling the airline. `` We did n't come up with any other alternative financing and options like that. There just was n't any more cash,'' said <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Braniff </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman in <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION>, where the board of directors met Monday. <ORGANIZATION> Braniff </ORGANIZATION> halted all passenger service at midnight Monday, but will continue and expand its charter airline service while <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Markets </ORGANIZATION> explores strategic alternatives, <PERSON> McGee </PERSON> said in a short statement released just before midnight. The last flights were arriving around midnight, and the planes would remain at their destinations indefinitely, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. <PERSON> McGee </PERSON> said employees at the Orlando-based <ORGANIZATION> Braniff </ORGANIZATION> will be notified individually about their status. Persons holding <ORGANIZATION> Braniff </ORGANIZATION> tickets should check with other airlines, which may honor <ORGANIZATION> Braniff </ORGANIZATION> tickets in some cases, the statement said. People holding tickets bought with a credit card were told to consult with the card company, and those who purchased tickets with cash or a check after Sept. 28 were advised to call a toll-free number for a refund. <ORGANIZATION> Braniff </ORGANIZATION>, which operated 46 of its 256 pre-bankruptcy flights Friday, was the first major carrier to file for bankruptcy following airline deregulation in the early 1980s. It emerged as a smaller carrier in 1984, but claimed weekly losses of about $ 1.5 million before filing for Chapter 11 bankruptcy again on Sept. 28. It lost $ 31.8 million on revenue of $ 293 million in the first six months of the year. On Friday, <ORGANIZATION> Braniff </ORGANIZATION> laid off about 100 mostly administrative employees. It was scheduled to submit salary plans for its top executives in bankruptcy court Nov. 17. Last week, <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, editor of the Dallas-based Commercial Aviation Report, said <ORGANIZATION> Braniff </ORGANIZATION> needed $ 50 million to $ 100 million to operate on a long-term basis and could run out of cash sometime this month. `` I think executive salaries will all be a moot point very shortly,'' he said. `` Frankly, I'm surprised <ORGANIZATION> Braniff </ORGANIZATION> is still flying.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugPlaneProblems Bjt   11-07 1133</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Plane Problems, Bjt,1100</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anti-Drug Radar Plane Plagued by Electronics Problems, Documents
Say</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX15</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A costly <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> radar plane envisioned as a key weapon in the war against drugs is plagued by electronics problems and ca n't reliably guide interceptors to drug-smuggling aircraft, agency documents say. `` Next month marks one year that we have been flying'' the first P-3 airborne early warning -LRB- AEW -RRB- aircraft, a Customs memo said on May 4, adding computer errors `` still make air intercept control a difficult task.'' In September, the plane's manufacturer, <ORGANIZATION> Lockheed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, said it would commit additional resources to `` upgrade'' the plane's computerized tracker. The equipment automatically plots the course and speed of other planes, and its inaccurate readings have been largely responsible for difficulties in intercepting planes suspected of smuggling drugs, according to the documents. `` You ca n't use the system for interception, and that's what all this magic is about,'' said a Customs source, adding that the P-3's computerized altitude, course and speed readings are so inaccurate that radar specialists worry they could direct their interceptors into a collision with a drug plane The source spoke on condition of anonymity. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McGinnis </PERSON>, director of <ORGANIZATION> Lockheed </ORGANIZATION>'s airborne early warning program, said in an interview the firm is making improvements in the tracker because of `` anomalous behavior that we could not prevent. The plane is functioning but there are problems with it and we are correcting it. `` The airplane and the tracker are very capable and doing their job,'' he said, adding the firm hopes to have the difficulties fixed by `` the first of the year.'' Other difficulties mentioned in the documents relate to the computer system that locates targets, faulty on-board communications for the crew, and problems with a spinning metal radar dome atop the plane. Difficulties aside, sources speaking on condition of anonymity said reports critical of the plane's performance were ordered rewritten by an agency supervisor after one early test. The P-3 <ORGANIZATION> AEW </ORGANIZATION>'s are designed to play a major role in drug interdiction from their <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> base in <LOCATION> Corpus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The government's multi-agency <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paso </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> reports 51 percent of the 112,000 kilograms of cocaine seized during 1988 arrived by air _ 45 percent in private planes. Despite the shortcomings detailed in the documents, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Kendig </PERSON>, acting director of <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corpus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christi </ORGANIZATION> surveillance center, called the aircraft `` a cost-effective piece of equipment, giving taxpayers one of best bangs for the buck in government today. It works and it works great.'' He said the system for tracking smugglers has a `` few glitches'' that can be solved. The first P-3 <ORGANIZATION> AEW </ORGANIZATION> aircraft has experienced both electronic and mechanical difficulties since the $ 27 million plane arrived at the Customs Surveillance Support Center in <LOCATION> Corpus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christi </LOCATION> in June 1988, according to the documents. The documents show some of the problems afflicted a second P-3 that arrived in April at a cost of $ 30.6 million. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> already has approved $ 35 million for a third P-3. The P-3 Orion has been used for years as a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> anti-submarine detection plane, but the <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> plane contains specially designed electronics for the drug war. Identification of the authors of most of the documents was obscured by sources who made the material available to The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The majority of documents were written by P-3 crew members, the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> was told. The difficulties diminish one of the most important features of the four-engine turboprops: the ability to use the multi-colored computer displays, with their impressive interchangeable graphics, to direct <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> planes intercepting and pursuing the flying smugglers. <PERSON> Kendig </PERSON> said the two P-3 <ORGANIZATION> AEW </ORGANIZATION>'s were mainly responsible for detections leading to 36 arrests from Jan. 1 to Aug. 10 this year. Seizures included 37,000 pounds of marijuana, 8,300 pounds of cocaine, 17 vessels and vehicles and three aircraft, he said. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Berezonsky </PERSON>, project manager for the <ORGANIZATION> AEW </ORGANIZATION> program at <ORGANIZATION> Lockheed </ORGANIZATION>, said in an interview the plane's problems `` have n't prevented the aircraft from doing a hell of a job'' and result from `` trying to put so much information on display to the operator so quickly We can track a greater number of targets simultaneously than anyone operating an <ORGANIZATION> AEW </ORGANIZATION> aircraft now. That's the key.'' Yet the documents, and interviews with those knowledgeable with the program, said the mission has been hampered in a number of ways: _ Planes that were possibly 300 miles away appeared as nearby targets Single targets were displayed as multiple images. Targets were lost when the P-3's on-board computer system `` crashed.'' Ships appeared at altitudes of 15,000 feet. _ The spinning radar dome atop the plane, similar to that on an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> AWACS, stopped working when the plane's speed reached 270 knots _ Agency officials accepted the first plane without the test flights designed by experts to create what a memo called `` real world'' conditions The test plan, included in the documents, would have evaluated the radar equipment over every possible terrain, trying to see how well it detected other Customs aircraft playing the role of drug-smuggler planes. The evaluation was flown months after Customs accepted the aircraft. _ The P-3's experienced numerous communications problems Radar specialists in the back of the plane were unable to monitor pilots' transmissions, a handicap that would _ according to a memo _ `` hinder safety of flight, and impede crew coordination. A memo warned of the potential for a `` <ORGANIZATION> NORAD </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- no radio -RRB- situation,'' a total communications failure. _ Two crewmen at <LOCATION> Corpus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christi </LOCATION> were ordered to water down their highly critical reports of the first P-3's performance during a then-top secret mission in late July-early August 1988 to detect drug planes leaving <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> One of the initial reports of the plane's first operational test said, `` The -LRB- tracking -RRB- program is so inaccurate'' the radar specialists `` had to develop alternate procedures to detect and track targets.'' The aircraft tracker problem was an important part of the evaluation of Operation Barrier, the mission to detect Colombian drug planes completed in early August 1988. There are at least four reports: two highly critical, and more favorable versions of the originals. A <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> source speaking on condition of anonymity said both original versions were ordered rewritten by a supervisor in <LOCATION> Corpus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christi </LOCATION>. One of the originals, dated Aug. 2, 1988, said the computer `` crashed'' at `` irregular intervals'' and communications improvements were needed `` so the next three aircraft will not be ` communications cripples.''' It added that `` deficiencies in the tracking program'' required use of antiquated `` raw radar'' to `` verify the validity'' of the computer displays and to `` provide accurate intercept data.'' After the rewrite was ordered, the same author wrote on Aug. 17, 1988, the operation was `` a complete success'' in which `` systems reliability was superb.'' He concluded, `` the potential of this asset is unlimited.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SacramentoUnion 1stLd-Writethru a0420 11-07 0622</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sacramento Union, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0420,0635</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Rules for Guild on Workers, Pay</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 4th graf, `The newspaper ...,' with 3 grafs to UPDATE with
comment by one of four fired employees; picks up 5th graf, ```We believe
...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB EGELKO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal appeals court has upheld government rulings that the <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> acted improperly in cutting salaries by 15 percent in 1986 and firing four employees who criticized the newspaper in a letter to advertisers. The two 3-0 rulings by the 9th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>, which were made public Monday, were victories for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> in disputes stemming from negotiations with the newspaper in 1986. An agreement was recently announced to sell the newspaper to a group headed by <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> developers <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Benvenuti </PERSON> and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Kassis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Saucerman </PERSON>, one of the four employees fired over the letter, said he expected the decisions and felt vindicated. `` I'm very pleased. I hope the employer would now swiftly implement the court's order and give everybody their 15 percent,'' said <PERSON> Saucerman </PERSON>, who was a retail advertising salesman. But <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> Union President <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Bates </PERSON> said the newspaper will appeal both rulings to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bates </PERSON> said 170 to 180 employees were affected. `` We believe very strongly that we were at impasse'' in contract negotiations and had the right to implement the pay cut, <PERSON> Bates </PERSON> said. `` We also believe very strongly that we had the right to fire those -LRB- four -RRB- people on the basis of their actions.'' The Guild, representing editorial, circulation, business, advertising and maintenance employees, negotiated with the newspaper in 1986 on a contract to replace the one that was to expire that May. The talks continued beyond May, but in early August 1986 the newspaper declared an impasse and put its last offer into effect, including an across-the-board 15 percent pay cut and elimination of a longstanding provision requiring all employees to join the Guild. The union denied that negotiations were at an impasse, as required for an employer to implement its final contract offer. A hearing officer ruled in the newspaper's favor but was overruled by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, whose decision was upheld by the appeals court. The court said there was evidence to support the <ORGANIZATION> NLRB </ORGANIZATION>'s conclusion that no real bargaining had taken place on the key issue of union security when the talks were suspended When the security issue was raised, `` the company put the matter off to a later time and then declared an impasse before any real discussion took place,'' the court said. It rejected the newspaper's argument that the Guild had refused to discuss the issue. The court upheld the <ORGANIZATION> NLRB </ORGANIZATION>'s order requiring the newspaper to reinstate the former contract, which included the higher pay level and the union membership requirement. The unsigned ruling was issued by Judges <PERSON> Otto </PERSON> <PERSON> Skopil </PERSON>, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Fletcher </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>. The other ruling involved a letter written by four members of the <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION>'s negotiating committee to 50 of the newspaper's advertisers in October 1987 The letter described the employees' efforts to get a contract, mentioned the pay cut, and declared that the paper was `` speeding downhill,'' with circulation plummeting and good staffers leaving. The advertisers were urged to contact executives of the newspaper. The court said the four employees _ <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Saucerman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ana </PERSON> <PERSON> Sandoval </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canfield </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> _ were fired two weeks later. <PERSON> Bates </PERSON> accused them of disloyalty and said the letter contained falsehoods that disrupted the newspaper's relationship with advertisers, the court said. In an opinion by <PERSON> Fletcher </PERSON>, the court upheld the <ORGANIZATION> NLRB </ORGANIZATION>'s decision that the letter was within the employees' rights of collective bargaining and was not an improper act of disloyalty.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     11-07 0497</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0513</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> and <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> are proving that love and marriage really do go together like a horse and carriage. <PERSON> Ross </PERSON>, 58, who runs a horse-drawn carriage business in the <LOCATION> Waikiki </LOCATION> tourist area, knew Ms. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> was the woman for him the moment the 60-year-old <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> woman got into his carriage while vacationing with her father and stepmother recently. `` The first thing the driver said to me was, ` Would you like to go for a cruise, go out to dinner or get married?''' Ms. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> recalled. `` Well, it was just foolishness so I said, ` I'd rather get married.''' `` The moment I spotted her beautiful brown eyes, I knew that this is it,'' <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> said. `` I've waited 18 years for a woman like her. I've prayed to the Lord for it and he finally sent me an angel.'' It was a whirlwind romance after that first carriage ride. After a breakfast date the next day, <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> asked Ms. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON>'s father for her hand. `` My father said: ` Well, she's 60 years old, she ought to be able to make up her own mind,''' said Ms. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON>, a registered nurse. The date has n't been set, but the wedding, the second for each, will be as soon as possible.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Good drivers are getting tickets these days _ to the movies. Officers on the city's west side are handing out movie passes to courteous and careful drivers. `` There's so many citations given out to violators who abuse the law, the <ORGANIZATION> LAPD </ORGANIZATION> thought it would be nice to reward the good drivers in our city for a change,'' said Officer <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Lovold </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s West Traffic Division. The program will last through the end of the year, courtesy of a movie studio and theater chain that donated the passes.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tired of scrounging under the car seat for change to drop in the parking meter? This city is considering introducing the latest in convenience for the motorist on the go: the personal parking meter. If the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> goes along with the proposal today, drivers would be offered pocket computer-sized devices that automatically keep track of parking time in metered zones. The `` Parkulators'' would sell for $ 50, and be dumped in the trash when $ 50 worth of curb time is used up. `` It's your own personal parking meter,'' said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON>, city parking manager. `` We get complaints constantly: ` If I only had enough change on me or had some way to prepay the meter, I would n't have gotten this ticket.' Now they wo n't have that excuse.'' Motorists would be responsible for turning the units on and punching in the maximum time allowed at whatever meter they've pulled up to If they do n't, or if they fail to come back and punch in another deposit when the time's up, <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON> said, they'll get tickets just like an old-fashioned meter scofflaw.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0131EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-RayJohnson     11-07 0518</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Ray Johnson,0535</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ex-Con Who Became Prominent Anti-Crime Consultant Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN DIEGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, an ex-convict sterlized by the state of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> as a teen-ager who turned his life around and became a prominent anti-crime consultant, has died. He was 62. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> died Sunday night at a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> hospital. He had undergone serveral surgical procedures and was in ill health for the past year, said a longtime friend, <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Attorney </LOCATION>'s spokesman <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s life was the basis for a television movie. In and out of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> juvenile institutions from the age of 7, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> was sterlized at age 17 under a theory that juvenile delinquency could be eradicted by ensuring that teen-age offenders did n't have children. The <LOCATION> Syracuse </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, native moved to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> at age 1. He served time in juvenile and adult institutions for auto theft, burglary and escape, but most of his criminal career involved armed robbery. While doing time at Folsom Prison for armed robbery, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and two other inmates became the first maxiumum-security prisoners to escape from the <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> facility in 1958. The three were recaptured. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> spent the next four years in solitary confinement. <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> newspaper reporter who met <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> while covering jails and prisons, said <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> never liked small places after that. `` He once had an apartment and it drove him nuts,'' <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> recalled. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, who used to claim the late <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diego </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mafia </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Mirable </PERSON> as his godfather, turned his life around after his parole in 1968. He returned to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> and worked for the old county <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Honor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Camps </ORGANIZATION>, then as a research associate for <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Behavioral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jolla </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, who lived in <LOCATION> Del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mar </LOCATION>, also became an internationally known anti-crime lecturer who spoke frequently to business and civic groups. Among the law-enforcement organizations he addressed were the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canadian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mounted </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>. In 1978, Gov. <PERSON> Edmund </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> `` </PERSON> <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> granted <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> a full pardon. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> made about three dozen appearances as a guest on `` The Tonight Show,'' and regarded host <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> as a good friend and a major influence, <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> was honored by Mayors <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Maureen </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, who declared days in his honor in 1978 and 1988, respectively. When he died, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> was working on a robbery - and violence-prevention program for small businesses and a similar program to help the elderly `` If we need proof that it's possible for a person to change, <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> was that proof. I would n't have liked the old <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> co-wrote a 1975 autobiography, `` Too Dangerous To Be At Large,'' which was a reference to one of Superior Court Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hewicker </PERSON>'s comments to <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> when he was sentenced to prison for the last time. The book was the basis for a television movie, `` Dangerous Company,'' in which <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s role was played by <PERSON> Beau </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON>. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> also had a bit part in the network movie, playing a prison guard. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> is survived by his wife, <PERSON> Joanna </PERSON>, and his mother, <PERSON> Doris </PERSON> <PERSON> Tarry </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     11-07 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0025</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Down In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 35,270.46, down 163.54 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FallFromGrace     11-07 0726</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fall From Grace,0748</SECOND>
<HEAD>City in Shock As Drugs Cut Down Well-Loved Police Chief</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LESLIE DREYFOUS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BROCKTON, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 No one really knows what happened to <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Sproules </PERSON>. Two weeks ago he was a well-respected police chief in this tough shoemakers' town that gave the world <PERSON> Rocky </PERSON> <PERSON> Marciano </PERSON> and championship football teams. Then, on Oct. 24, <PERSON> Sproules </PERSON> was arrested for allegedly taking cocaine from the police department's evidence room to support his five-year addiction. At his arraignment, prosecutors said <PERSON> Sproules </PERSON> confessed he was a cocaine addict. The 22-year police veteran, who once headed the department's anti-drug unit, also is being investigated in connection with hundreds of thousands of dollars missing from operating funds and money from seized drug deals, court documents show. The news has taken people's breath away. Sproules, 45, was a light for this blue-collar city's 93,000 residents some 20 miles south of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. With drug-related crime a daily reality and racial tension a constant presence, they looked to him often. <PERSON> Nan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellison </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION>'s local president, met Sproules more than 10 years ago after racial graffiti was scrawled over a neighborhood church. `` He was very sensitive to people's needs _ all kinds of people's needs,'' she said. `` He made you feel like a friend and his door was always open.'' That open door, and the way <LOCATION> Sproules </LOCATION> refused to concede defeat without a battle, may have been his undoing, friends and colleagues said. Between heading a 185-member police force, setting up neighborhood crime watch patrols, acting as a liaison on various community boards, guiding high school counselors, coaching pre-teen soccer, his plate was full. When he got home to his wife and two kids at night, it was after hours of doling out advice and hearing people's problems. `` He was called upon so much _ maybe it was too much,'' <PERSON> Ellison </PERSON> said. `` He might have been under stress and we did n't know it. He never showed it.'' Everyone agrees, <PERSON> Sproules </PERSON> never let on that anything was bothering him. Since the news broke, officers down at the department have been dazed. At the bar, people drain beers while discussing <PERSON> Sproules </PERSON>' alleged secret life and speculating on his fall from grace `` The overriding thing was the intensity of their reaction,'' said <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Albert </PERSON>, a talk show host at <ORGANIZATION> WBET </ORGANIZATION> radio, who threw open his mike the evening the Sproules story broke. `` In a lot of cases we were knocking people off their chairs with this ... it was the last thing anybody expected to hear. They needed to talk and let off some steam.'' Perhaps what people find most disconcerting is the fact that <LOCATION> Sproules </LOCATION>, an authority figure, could succumb to an everyday human frailty. `` If it can happen to him it can happen to anyone,'' people said again and again. <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Franciosi </PERSON>, a junior high school principal, is still trying to figure out how the police chief, a friend and adviser to whom many students turned, could have sunk into the very hell he was trying to eradicate. `` It's been like a car accident or some other kind of tragedy,'' he said. `` It's easy to say ` That's terrible, but it's not going to happen to someone we know,' `` he said. `` Now we know that assumption's just not true.'' Cocaine, like many drugs, can be extremely addictive and <PERSON> Sproules </PERSON>' work drew him daily into temptation's way until eventually co-workers suspected him and an internal investigation was launched. <PERSON> Sproules </PERSON> was suspended with pay and subsequently resigned. He was freed on his own recognizance after pleading innocent to the drug charges. He talked only briefly following his arrest. `` I was always helping other people,'' he said. `` But I never found time for myself. Maybe that was my problem.'' Authorities have convened an investigative grand jury to examine evidence against <PERSON> Sproules </PERSON>, who last week admitted himself to a four-week drug rehabilitation program was not available for comment. His attorney, <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Edmands </PERSON>, did not return telephone messages left at his office. If convicted, <PERSON> Sproules </PERSON> could face more than 20 years in prison. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Stern </PERSON>, a local carpenter and friend who spoke recently with Sproules, said the chief in some ways has been set free. `` The man feels like there's a 3,000-pound weight off his soul _ that finally he does n't have to lie anymore,'' <PERSON> Stern </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-Consultants Bjt   11-07 0476</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Consultants, Bjt,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Gives Agencies `Open Money Sack' to Hire Consultants</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is giving federal agencies `` an open money sack'' to hire private consultants and contractors, and the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> even lets them perform sensitive work on nuclear technology, a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> report says. The Department of Energy relies on private consultants `` to perform virtually all basic governmental functions,'' according to a report released Monday by Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>., chairman of a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee The number of <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> employees has declined from 20,000 in 1980 to 16,000, the report said, adding that contractors have in effect become part of its permanent work force. `` It relies on contractors in the preparation of its most important plans and policies, the development of budgets and budget documents, and the drafting of reports to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and congressional testimony,'' the report said. `` It relies on contractors to monitor arms control negotiations, help prepare decisions on the export of nuclear technology, and conduct hearings and initial appeals in challenges to security clearance disputes,'' it said. <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON> said the department was unable to say how many contractors and consultants it has, or how much it is spending on them. But he said the department pays more for work by consultants than it would for the same work by employees. `` We spend in the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> weeks debating whether government employees should get a 2 percent or a 3.6 percent pay raise, but we provide literally an open money sack to agencies to hire private contractors,'' <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzpatrick </PERSON>, assistant energy secretary for management and administration, defended the use of consultants and contractors as necessary to provide technical expertise that the government can not obtain from its own employees. She said the department's employees `` are stretched very thin,'' and that government salaries are too low to keep employees who can be hired at higher salaries by the contractors. But she said the department uses only its own employees to make policy decisions. <PERSON> Fitzpatrick </PERSON> acknowledged the panel's finding that remarks by Energy Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> to a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel in April on nuclear facilities had been written by a private defense contractor, <ORGANIZATION> BDM </ORGANIZATION>. But she said that was an `` isolated'' incident. The report was written by the staff of <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Governmental Affairs subcommittee on federal services, post office and civil service, which has been looking into use of consultants by the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and other agencies. <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON> said many of the consultants and contractors also do business with private energy companies or foreign governments and companies. `` The potential for a conflict of interest is unchecked,'' he said. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, director of procurement and contract management for the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, defended <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s use of outside contractors in testimony before the panel. He said <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s budget for contracts tripled during the 1980s
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     11-07 0529</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0549</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Look Who's Talking' Still Nation's Favorite Movie</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HORN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Look Who's Talking,'' the comedy about love and diapers, sold more than $ 11 million in tickets for the fourth consecutive weekend, becoming only the seventh movie since 1982 to do so. `` The Bear,'' the live-action drama about two bears being pursued by hunters, jumped to second place with $ 5.1 million in its second week of release. `` Look Who's Talking,'' starring <PERSON> Kirstie </PERSON> <PERSON> Alley </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Travolta </PERSON> and the voice of <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON>, has now made nearly $ 60 million, according to figures released Monday by <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. During the past seven years, the only other movies to surpass $ 11 million each weekend for a month were `` E.T the Extra-Terrestrial,'' `` The Return of the Jedi,'' `` Ghostbusters,'' `` <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> Cop,'' `` <PERSON> Indiana </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and the Last Crusade'' and `` Batman,'' according to Entertainment Data. In third place in box offices revenues for last weekend was director <PERSON> Wes </PERSON> <PERSON> Craven </PERSON>'s `` Shocker,'' a story about a murderer who more or less appeals his death sentence. `` Shocker,'' falling 26 percent from the previous weekend, reported a gate of $ 3.4 million. <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>'s melancholy comedy `` Crimes and Misdemeanors'' sold $ 2.7 million worth of tickets during a weekend of limited release to finish in fourth place and become the director's biggest hit since 1986's `` <PERSON> Hannah </PERSON> and Her Sisters.'' In fifth was the new comedy `` Second Sight,'' with <PERSON> Bronson </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinchot </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Larroquette </PERSON> co-starring as psychics, with $ 2.2 million. In sixth was `` Phantom of the Opera,'' starring <PERSON> Freddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Krueger </PERSON> veteran <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Englund </PERSON>, which debuted with $ 2.1 million. The <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Swayze </PERSON> adventure film `` Next of Kin'' was seventh, grossing $ 2 million. `` Sea of Love,'' the romantic thriller pairing <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Pacino </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Barkin </PERSON>, was eighth with $ 1.8 million. In ninth was the medical-school comedy `` Gross Anatomy,'' which collected $ 1.7 million. In 10th with $ 1.6 million was `` The Fabulous Baker Boys,'' starring <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Pfeiffer </PERSON>. Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> and Exhibitor Relations. Figures are based on a combination of actual box-office receipts and studio projections where actual figures were not available. 1. `` Look Who's Talking,'' Tri-Star, $ 11.5 million weekend gross, 1,638 screens, $ 6,995 per screen, $ 59.6 million total gross, four weeks in release. 2. `` The Bear,'' Tri-Star, $ 5.1 million, 1,045 screens, $ 4,851 per screen, $ 9.9 million, two weeks. 3. `` Shocker,'' Universal, $ 3.4 million, 1,795 screens, $ 1,870 per screen, $ 9.3 million, two weeks. 4. `` Crimes and Misdemeanors,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.7 million, 440 screens, $ 6,010 per screen, $ 6.2 million, four weeks. 5. `` Second Sight,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.2 million, 815 screens, $ 2,646 per screen, $ 2.2 million, one week. 6. `` Phantom of the Opera,'' 21st Century, $ 2.1 million, 1,498 screens, $ 1,402 per screen, $ 2.1 million, one week. 7. `` Next of Kin,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2 million, 1,197 screens, $ 1,641 per screen, $ 11.6 million, three weeks. 8. `` Sea of Love,'' Universal, $ 1.8 million, 1,128 screens, $ 1,565 per screen, $ 51.3 million, eight weeks. 9. `` Gross Anatomy,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.7 million, 1,038 screens, $ 1,611 per screen, $ 7.5 million, three weeks. 10. `` The Fabulous Baker Boys,'' 20th <ORGANIZATION> Century </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.6 million, 742 screens, $ 2,183 per screen, $ 12 million, four weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HomeEquityLoans     11-07 0659</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Home Equity Loans,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Rules Simplify Shopping for a Home Equity Loan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The confusing task of choosing a home equity loan should be easier starting today under new federal rules requiring lenders to disclose in advance the interest rate, fees and other terms they're offering. Federal Reserve regulations, voluntary since June 7, became mandatory today. In addition to advance disclosure, the law curbs misleading advertising and other abusive practices. `` Simple, easily understood and easily comparable information will be available to consumers to intelligently shop around for a home equity loan,'' said Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.C. </LOCATION>, chief sponsor of the legislation passed late last year that directed the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> to write the rules. Lenders now must disclose basic cost information when borrowers make an initial inquiry and again when the loan application is filed. Another provision targets deeply discounted `` teaser'' rates that offer borrowers a break on their first few payments before the rates rise sharply. Lenders can still advertise teaser rates, but they must give equal prominence to the interest rate borrowers will be paying after the discount expires. The rules forbid contract clauses permitting lenders to call in the loan, accelerate payments or raise the interest rate at whim. Adjustable-rate home equity loans now must be based on an index outside the lender's control, such as the prime rate published in newspapers, not the lender's own prime rate. Consumer advocates were pleased with the law, sponsored in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> by <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., but they complained that the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> regulations do not fully live up to their spirit Consumer's Union, a national organization that publishes Consumer Reports magazine, filed suit last week in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> seeking to close what it considers several loopholes. The group opposes a provision in the law that requires lenders in the first pre-application disclosure to reveal only the index on which a floating interest rate is based, but not the margin, or difference between the rate charged and the index. `` We think the margin is an integral part of the cost that consumers need to know. We also think the legislation expressly requires lenders to disclose the margin,'' said attorney <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Meier </PERSON> of Consumers Union. Bankers are generally satisfied with the law, recognizing it was needed to curb at least isolated abuses. But, according to <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>, regulatory affairs director of the <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bankers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, the disclosures may swamp borrowers with too much detail. One provision, for instance, requires the lender to provide a chart showing how the interest rate and minimum monthly payment would have varied over the past 15 years. `` It gets confusing,'' <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> said. `` People do n't care what happened 15 years ago. They want to know what's happening today and what their payment is going to be tomorrow.'' The popularity of home equity loans has surged since the 1986 tax law began phasing out the deductibility of consumer loans. Home loans, however, are still fully deductible, including home equity loans in most instances. This year, only 20 percent of non-mortgage interest is deductible; in 1990 only 10 percent is eligible and beginning in 1991 none will be. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> said outstanding revolving home equity loans totaled $ 26.3 billion at mid-October, up from $ 21 billion a year earlier and $ 11.7 billion in June 1987, when the agency first began keeping track. According to a survey of 138 lenders by the <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bankers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the delinquency and foreclosure rates for home equity loans were lower this year than for regular first mortgages. But, consumer advocates have always been leery of home equity loans and say they have n't been tested during an economic downturn. Defaults could soar in a recession, they contend. The Better Business Bureau says home equity loans should be used only for major expenditures such as college education, home improvement or for major medical expenses, not for luxuries such as sports cars.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891107-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-89 0232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     11-07 0716</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Committee Chairman Urge Defeat of Cason</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The chairmen of two <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committees that oversee natural resources issues are urging their colleagues to reject <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Cason </PERSON> as assistant secretary of agriculture. Sen. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, D-La., who is chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, and Sen. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, are sending a letter to all senators, saying <PERSON> Cason </PERSON> `` is neither qualified nor suitable'' for the <PERSON> Cason </PERSON>, 35, has been nominated to head the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s forest and conservation programs. He has drawn fire for his record as a high-ranking official during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration at the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, where critics contend he put private development interests ahead of environmental concerns. `` A review of Mr. <PERSON> Cason </PERSON>'s education and employment history indicates that he came to the Department of the Interior with little, if any, by the way of background or qualifications for the job,'' said the letter, dated Nov. 3. `` Moreover, Mr. <PERSON> Cason </PERSON>'s record indicates a reluctance to rely on the professional expertise available to him at the Department of the Interior,'' it says. <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON> opposed <PERSON> Cason </PERSON> during committee hearings, saying he repeatedly shrugged aside public interests in decisions on how to use public lands. Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>, who is widely admired on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, has sought to assure senators that he sets environmental policy at the department and <PERSON> Cason </PERSON> would be taking orders from him. But <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> and <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON> cited testimony critical of <PERSON> Cason </PERSON> from <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON>, who retired recently as chief of the forest service after 38 years with the agency and currently holds the title chief emeritus. `` In my judgment, he -LRB- <PERSON> Cason </PERSON> -RRB- clearly is not qualified,'' the senators quote <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON> as saying. `` The opposition to Mr. <PERSON> Cason </PERSON>'s nomination is broad and deep, and ranges across political and ideological viewpoints,'' said <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>. `` It is opposition based on the recognition that we need appointees who are dedicated to protecting the public trust, whatever their party.'' The nomination was approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on a 12-7 vote, but full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> action was been put on hold because of opposition to the appointment.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal subsidies would be available to cities that start tree-planting programs if a bill passed by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> becomes law. The legislation, known as the urban and community forestry act, was approved on voice vote Monday and now goes to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. It directs the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to start a matching grants program that would provide cash, services or in-kind contributions for up to 50 percent of the cost of any tree-planting program. The legislation addresses `` an important concern in our country about what can be done to reforest our nation's cities, to cool down and green up our urban areas,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jontz </PERSON>, D-Ind., who authored the bill Rep. <PERSON> Sid </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, R-Wash., said that for every tree being planted in cities, four are being lost He advocated passage of the bill, saying it would help clean the air and battle against global warming. The measure also: _ Directs the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to start an educational and technical assistance program in cooperation with state foresters and state extension agents _ Establishes a 15-member <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forestry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> to help develop criteria for the cost share program and develop a national urban and community forestry plan
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
