<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 2330EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Nicaragua-American     03-29 0235</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua-American,0243</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Citizen And Belize Citizen Arrested After Emergency Plane Landing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen and a <LOCATION> Belize </LOCATION> citizen were being held after their small plane made an emergency landing on the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> coast, the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday. A ministry statement identified the American as <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Burton </PERSON>, 37, and the <LOCATION> Belize </LOCATION> citizen as <PERSON> Abimael </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> <PERSON> Canur </PERSON>, 38. No hometowns were given. The men were taken into custody after their Aerocommander plane suffered a gas leak when it made an emergency landing Saturday at <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cabezas </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Zelaya </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Norte </LOCATION> province, 186 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>. `` Given the irregularity and strangeness of the case, Nicaraguan authorities have decided to retain the crew members of the plane,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> statement said. The two will remain in custody `` until we clarify their identity, the ownership and nationality of the plan and the reasons they were traveling without any documents,'' the statement said. It said neither man nor the plane carried documents and that a flight plan had not been filed. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> source in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>, speaking on condition of anonymity, would only say that a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> consular official had visited <PERSON> Burton </PERSON>. The statement by the Nicaraguan government did not say where the men were being held. The <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Belize </LOCATION> governments had been notified of the case and asked for their cooperation in clearing up the affair.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 2337EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Whistleblower-Litton     03-29 0498</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Whistleblower-Litton,0516</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Joins Suit Alleging Fraud by Pentagon Contractor</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GARTIES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government has joined a `` whistleblower'' lawsuit that accuses <ORGANIZATION> Litton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of overcharging the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> $ 25 million for computer work, according to court documents unsealed Wednesday. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> decision to intervene in the suit by a former <ORGANIZATION> Litton </ORGANIZATION> employee suggests government investigators believe the allegations may have merit. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> McMenimen </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney's office in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, declined to comment on the action. The suit, filed last April by former <ORGANIZATION> Litton </ORGANIZATION> manager <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Carton </PERSON>, alleges that the company in effect charged the government for work it did for commercial customers using the same computer system. <ORGANIZATION> Litton </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Thom </PERSON> denied wrongdoing by the Beverly Hills-based company, which makes electronic navigation and control gear for a variety of military planes and missiles. The suit alleges the company programmed computers to under-record the amount of commercial work while properly recording the volume of government work at the <ORGANIZATION> Litton </ORGANIZATION> computer services division in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Woodland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>. Overcharges on dozens of computer design and engineering contracts from 1981 through 1987 amounted to at least $ 25 million, alleged Carton's attorney, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>. The action was brought under the False Claims Act, which entitles those who report fraud against the government to get up to 25 percent of any damages awarded. <PERSON> Carton </PERSON> decided to file suit only after complaints to company officials and a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> fraud hotline failed to bring action, <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> said. `` He told everybody within the division ... and they did n't do anything,'' the lawyer said. `` He talked to somebody at the hotline in general terms but he was not persuaded or convinced that they were really going to make a serious effort to do something about this.'' <PERSON> Thom </PERSON> refused to comment in detail on the allegations, but maintained that joint government-civilian use of the computer system saved the Pentagon money. That is because civilian work could be scheduled during slack times in the government contracts and help defray operating cost of the system, he said. `` We're going to fight it,'' <PERSON> Thom </PERSON> said. `` We think the charges have no merit whatsoever.'' The lawsuit does n't specify which military systems might be involved in the alleged overcharges. It does n't name company officials responsible for the alleged overcharging, but <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> said Carton believed knowledge went at least as high as top-division management. Carton, who was technical director at the division from 1984 to 1987, discovered the alleged cost-shifting while conducting a profitability study on the company's 30 commercial accounts, <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> said. Commercial customers included businesses as diverse as <ORGANIZATION> Kaiser </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Flynt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publications </ORGANIZATION>, publisher of hard-porn Hustler magazine. Carton, 46, left <ORGANIZATION> Litton </ORGANIZATION> on friendly terms during a reorganization of the division's management in early 1987 and now works for another defense contractor, <ORGANIZATION> Northrop </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, the attorney said. In addition to its electronics work, <ORGANIZATION> Litton </ORGANIZATION> builds <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> ships at its Ingalls shipyard in <LOCATION> Pascagoula </LOCATION>, Miss.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0011EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-IndianaCongress 4thLd-Writethru a0736 03-29 0570</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Indiana Congress, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0736,0583</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrat Wins Surprise Victory In Election For House Seat Once Held
By Quayle</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 4th graf, `It was ...,' with 5 grafs to CORRECT that Long
lost 1986 Senate race, sted 1984, UPDATE with quotes from Long, Heath;
picks up 5th graf, `The polls ...' Should stand for AMs.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By THOMAS P. WYMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FORT WAYNE, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat <PERSON> Jill </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON> scored a surprise victory over Republican <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Heath </PERSON> Tuesday night in a special election for the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> seat that launched the political career of Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. Long received 65,160 votes, or 51 percent, to 63,388, or 49 percent, for <PERSON> Heath </PERSON>. She will be the first Democrat to represent northeast <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>'s 4th Congressional District since <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> won the 1976 congressional election and the 26th woman in the 435-seat House of Representatives It was the third try for a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> political office by <PERSON> Long </PERSON>, who lost a bid for the seat last November by a margin of nearly 50,000 votes and lost the 1986 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> election to <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. `` I knew it was going to be a close race,'' <PERSON> Long </PERSON> said in her victory speech. `` I believed we were going to win. The surprise would have been if there had been a large margin of victory. `` I am committed to doing what I believe is right for northeast <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and my country. I have long believed that <ORGANIZATION> Hoosiers </ORGANIZATION> are independent, and when we put forth god candidates on either side, we win,'' Long added. In his concession speech, <PERSON> Heath </PERSON> said, `` It's a hard pill to swallow but I am a man and a good man and I did my best.'' <PERSON> Heath </PERSON> claimed his record and credentials as a candidate had been distorted in the campaign by negative advertising. `` I apologize to no one and to no voter,'' he said. `` Winning this race was a quest but not an obsession.'' The polls closed at 6 p.m. EST, one hour after <PERSON> Heath </PERSON> and <PERSON> Long </PERSON> ended a final day of campaigning at restaurants and plant gates Thundershowers, which had been predicted for the afternoon and which Democrats had feared would reduce turnout among blue-collar voters casting ballots after factory shift changes, failed to materialize. With voting predicted to dip as low as 30 percent among more than 200,000 registered voters, turnout efforts were more important than usual, said party workers on both sides. <PERSON> Heath </PERSON> and Long renewed their campaigns before sunrise, each opening election day with a coffee shop stop here. An independent poll taken in the week before the election showed <PERSON> Heath </PERSON> with 44 percent and <PERSON> Long </PERSON> with 36 percent, with 20 percent still undecided. The 4th District seat was vacated in January by <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> incumbent <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Coats </PERSON>, who resigned to take the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> occupied before becoming vice president. In 1976, district voters were the first to send <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> as a 28-year-old congressman. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> won re-election in 1978, then gave up the seat in a successful effort to defeat three-term <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> senator <PERSON> Birch </PERSON> <PERSON> Bayh </PERSON>. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> and First Lady <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaigned earlier for the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> candidate and former Democratic presidential hopeful Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> campaigned for the Democrat. County election administrators decided to use paper ballots rather than voting machines or computer ballots to cut costs in an election that no one had budgeted. <LOCATION> Allen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> officials estimated paper ballots would save $ 20,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Oscars-Filmography     03-29 0334</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Oscars-Filmography,0394</SECOND>
<HEAD>Best Picture Winners Through the Years</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Oscars, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a list of the Best Picture Oscar winners through the years. Dates represent the official period of competition for the film. 1927-28 _ `` Wings'' 1928-29 _ `` <LOCATION> Broadway </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Melody </LOCATION>'' 1929-30 _ `` All Quiet on the <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>'' 1930-31 _ `` Cimarron'' 1931-32 _ `` Grand Hotel'' 1932-33 _ `` Cavalcade'' 1934 _ `` It Happened One Night'' 1935 _ `` Mutiny on the Bounty'' 1936 _ `` The <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ziegfeld </LOCATION>'' 1937 _ `` The <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zola </ORGANIZATION>'' 1938 _ `` You Ca n't Take It with You'' 1939 _ `` Gone with the Wind'' 1940 _ `` <LOCATION> Rebecca </LOCATION>'' 1941 _ `` How <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Was </LOCATION> <LOCATION> My </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>'' 1942 _ `` Mrs. <PERSON> Miniver </PERSON>'' 1943 _ `` <LOCATION> Casablanca </LOCATION>'' 1944 _ `` Going My Way'' 1945 _ `` The Lost Weekend'' 1946 _ `` The Best Years of Our Lives'' 1947 _ `` Gentlemen's Agreement'' 1948 _ `` Hamlet'' 1949 _ `` All the King's Men'' 1950 _ `` All About Eve'' 1951 _ `` An <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>'' 1952 _ `` The Greatest Show on Earth'' 1953 _ `` From Here to Eternity'' 1954 _ `` On the Waterfront'' 1955 _ `` <ORGANIZATION> Marty </ORGANIZATION>'' 1956 _ `` Around the World in 80 Days'' 1957 _ `` The Bridge on the <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kwai </LOCATION>'' 1958 _ `` <PERSON> Gigi </PERSON>'' 1959 _ `` Ben-Hur'' 1960 _ `` The Apartment'' 1961 _ `` <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Side </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Story </ORGANIZATION>'' 1962 _ `` Lawrence of Arabia'' 1963 _ `` <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>'' 1964 _ `` My Fair Lady'' 1965 _ `` The Sound of Music'' 1966 _ `` A Man for All Seasons'' 1967 _ `` In the Heat of the Night'' 1968 _ `` <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON>'' 1969 _ `` <ORGANIZATION> Midnight </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cowboy </ORGANIZATION>'' 1970 _ `` <LOCATION> Patton </LOCATION>'' 1971 _ `` The French Connection'' 1972 _ `` The Godfather'' 1973 _ `` The Sting'' 1974 _ `` The Godfather Part II'' 1975 _ `` One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest'' 1976 _ `` Rocky'' 1977 _ `` <ORGANIZATION> Annie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION>'' 1978 _ `` The Deer Hunter'' 1979 _ `` <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON>'' 1980 _ `` Ordinary People'' 1981 _ `` Chariots of Fire'' 1982 _ `` Gandhi'' 1983 _ `` Terms of Endearment'' 1984 _ `` Amadeus'' 1985 _ `` Out of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'' 1986 _ `` Platoon'' 1987 _ `` The Last Emperor''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Oscars-Facts     03-29 0278</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Oscars-Facts,0298</SECOND>
<HEAD>Facts and Figures from the 61st Academy Awards</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Oscars, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a collection of facts, figures and trivia from the 61st Annual Academy Awards ceremony scheduled from 9-12 p.m. EST tonight, to be telecast live from the Shrine Auditorium on <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION>. Price for 30 seconds of network commercial time: $ 375,000. Minutes of commercial time in ceremony: 21 network, 8 local. Nominee expected to travel the longest distance: <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Olmos </PERSON>, who is shooting a film in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. Individual flowers to be used at the Oscar ceremony and the Academy's Governors' Ball: 6 million. Celebrities whom official greeter <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Archerd </ORGANIZATION> expects to welcome as they arrive at Shrine: `` as many as 100.'' Costume jewelry provided for performers, presenters and nominees: 800 pieces valued at $ 250,000. <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> engineers assigned to the show: 81. Cameras to be used by <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> in covering the ceremony: 17. Feet of cable to be used by ABC-TV: 80,000. Reporters covering the awards: 700 from 30 countries. Photographers covering the ceremony: 175. Makeup people backstage: 11. Craftspeople involved in building the show's sets: 100-plus working for more than 6,000 cumulative hours on 15 sets. Stagehands: 106. Phone calls fielded daily by Producer <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> Carr </PERSON>'s office during last two weeks: 500. Cases of Moet Champagne expected to be popped at the Governors' Ball: 25 Bottles of <PERSON> Halston </PERSON> cologne to be given as favors to guests at the ball: 1,600. Gift truffles at the ball: 9,600. Expected to be eaten at the ball: 20,000 baby vegetables, 1,800 pounds of salmon fillets from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, 1,800 pounds of free range chicken breasts, 2,000 potato baskets. Servers hired for the ball: 250.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0056EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Germany-Anti-US     03-29 0177</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Germany-Anti-US,0181</SECOND>
<HEAD>Protesters Try To Block Transport Of U.S. Tanks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BREMEN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Peace activists hauled trees onto a new rail spur used to transport <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> tanks, officials said, and police reportedly used truncheons to disperse protesters who had blocked a nearby road. A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official said Tuesday's protests did not disrupt the transport of tanks along the rail spur near <LOCATION> Bremen </LOCATION> en route to maneuvers. `` It's been pretty much business as usual here,'' said Capt. <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s 2nd Armored Division Forward unit in nearby <LOCATION> Garlstedt </LOCATION>. But activists, who asked not to be identified, said that at one point West German police used truncheons to break up a group of demonstrators blocking a road near the rail spur and that one protester was slightly injured. A police official, who also asked not to be identified, said late Tuesday that he had no information about the reported incident. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> said protesters placed small trees on the 5.2 mile rail link during the night but the debris was easily removed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SavannahRiver     03-29 0469</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Savannah River,0480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Savannah River Plant Managers Say They Recommend Putting Off Safety
Tests</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AIKEN, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Managers of the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s nuclear weapons complex near here said Tuesday they have recommended putting off a series of safety tests until after one of its three idle reactors is restarted. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savannah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> River </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which takes over as operator of the government-owned complex Saturday, said ultrasonic testing for cracks in the reactor vessel and piping would be `` just an added burden'' that would not enhance safety. `` The concept of doing the ultrasonic is really to get a good idea of the actual situation in the vessel to determine the long-term capabilities of the vessel,'' he said. `` It's not a near-term safety problem at all.'' Then-Energy Secretary <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> said last year that he would require ultrasonic testing of the plant's K reactor before it could be restarted. All three active reactors at the plant have been shut down for safety reasons since last April. They are the nation's only source of tritium, a highly perishable gas needed to manufacture <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nuclear weapons. The Pentagon has said that at least one of the reactors must be restarted by the end of this year to avert a serious shortage in tritium supplies. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in his temporary office a few miles from the reactor complex, said <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> remained committed to carrying out the ultrasonic testing. `` To put in an ultrasonic testing program ... would really be counterproductive in terms of all the other things going on,'' he said. Energy Department officials at the weapons plant are reviewing <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION>'s recommendation to put off the testing. The recommendation is part of a broad new plan that <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> presented to the department last week as a proposed blueprint for restarting the K reactor, <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> declined to reveal other details of the restart strategy, which he said he would be discussing with Energy Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> over the next few weeks. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> has instructed <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> to give top priority to getting the K reactor running again, but has stressed that operations would not resume until safety could be assured. He has not commented directly on the question of whether ultrasonic testing is needed first. The company that has managed the <ORGANIZATION> Savannah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> River </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plant </ORGANIZATION> since its construction in the 1950s, E.I. du <ORGANIZATION> Pont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nemours </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, has used conventional tests with colored dyes to search for cracking in reactor vessels and piping, and had said earlier this year that it planned to start ultrasonic testing this summer. A leak from a crack in the vessel of another reactor at <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, the the C reactor, was discovered in 1984. That led to its permanent shutdown a year later.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0110EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Corsica-Unrest     03-29 0236</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Corsica-Unrest,0243</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Disperse Demonstrators With Tear Gas</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BASTIA, Corsica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Striking government workers used slingshots to hurl fishing weights at police and were repelled with tear-gas grenades in the latest battle over union demands for a cost-of-living bonus. French Premier <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON> offered to reopen negotiations in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> on a bonus to cover high costs on the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> island, but several unions said the talks should take place in <LOCATION> Corsica </LOCATION>. The 400 to 500 demonstrators, some of them masked, hurled stones and fishing weights Tuesday at the prefecture building in the northern port of <LOCATION> Bastia </LOCATION>. They were charged by riot squads but regrouped and attacked throughout the day, witnesses said. The workers are demanding a bonus to offset the high cost of living on <LOCATION> Corsica </LOCATION>, estimated at 4.2 percent more expensive than the French mainland. At least one demonstrator and three policemen were injured in the clashes, Corsican officials said. Union leaders met with government officials on Saturday, but talks broke down after just two hours. <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON> designated the Cabinet minister in charge of the civil service, <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> Tuesday's violence was the latest in six weeks of intermittant strikes and blockades or ports and airports which cut the <LOCATION> Mediteranean </LOCATION> island off from the mainland. The blockades were lifted for four days but a cargo boat was prevented from leaving the southern port of <LOCATION> Ajaccio </LOCATION> on Tuesday, the French news agency Agence France-Presse reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SpeechFodder Bjt   03-29 0580</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Speech Fodder, Bjt,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Politicians Get 520 Pages of Speech Fodder in New Book of Quotes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Politicians stumped for memorable quotations to enliven their speeches need look no further than `` Respectfully Quoted,'' a newly published book from the <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that is crammed with 2,100 oratorical gems from the past. The book might give some comfort to Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, D-Del., whose 1988 presidential hopes were torpedoed partly by a controversy over cribbed comments If <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> recalls a famous line from President <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s inaugural address in 1961, he might be intrigued that Lebanese writer <PERSON> Kahlil </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibran </PERSON> asked much earlier, `` Are you a politician asking what your country can do for you, or a zealous one asking what you can do for your country? The book, a three-year project by <PERSON> Suzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Platt </PERSON> of the library's congressional reference division, is a compilation of quotations which members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> or their staffs over the past 75 years have asked the library to verify for their exact wording and origins For the hapless politician scrambling to extricate himself from trouble, there's this reputed quote from former Republican presidential candidate <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Romney </PERSON>: `` I did n't say that I did n't say it I said that I did n't say that I said it. I want to make that very clear.'' It was <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> who cast this verbal harpoon at President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyler </PERSON>: `` He has been called a mediocre man, but this is unwarranted flattery. He was a politician of monumental littleness.'' Exasperation prompted former Rep. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Danielson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>., to declare that trying to get answers from Attorney General <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> during <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> hearings on the Watergate scandal in 1974 was `` like trying to nail a drop of water to the wall. `` These quotations come from the real world of cut-and-thrust politics,'' says <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodrum </PERSON>, former assistant director of the library's <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, which compiled the 520-page dictionary of political quotes. `` They show the combination of spirit and humor that represents <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> political activity at its best.'' Ms. <PERSON> Platt </PERSON> amassed verified quotations which researchers began recording on 3-by-5 cards nearly 50 years ago to avoid time-consuming duplication of efforts. The CRS handles more than 1,500 requests for information from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> every day. The researchers discovered that some widely used quotes, now part of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> folklore, are impossible to trace to the person who first uttered them. Other quotes have been mistakenly attributed to a few legendary orators, such as <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>. It has never been verified, they say, that <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> _ or P.T. <PERSON> Barnum </PERSON> _ observed that `` you may fool all the people some of the time; you can even fool some of the people all the time, but you ca n't fool all of the people all the time.'' Who said, `` Winning is n't everything, it's the only thing?'' The library says it was n't the late <PERSON> Vince </PERSON> <PERSON> Lombardi </PERSON> but <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sanders </ORGANIZATION>, football coach at <ORGANIZATION> Vanderbilt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Goodrum </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> no longer produces thundering, long-winded orators of the likes of <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON>, <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> or <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Calhoun </PERSON>, and that television's insatiable hunger for 20-second `` sound bites'' is largely to blame. `` Today's politicians probably are n't as quotable as the old-time orators who spoke in the measured cadences of the Bible and <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>,'' he said. `` Even though their quotes do n't stand up so they can be chiseled on marble as clearly, their speeches reflect some very incisive thinking about the major issues of our time.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PellegriniExecution     03-29 0205</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pellegrini Execution,0210</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Court Issues Stay For Nevada Inmate</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CARSON CITY, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 22-year-old man who faced execution by lethal injection Friday for murdering a <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> store clerk during a 1986 robbery won a stay Tuesday from a federal judge. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pellegrini </PERSON> had initially not wanted a stay but changed his mind Monday. Assistant Federal Public Defender <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Flanagan </PERSON> immediately obtained the stay from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Pro </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>. Pro told <PERSON> Pellegrini </PERSON> he should return to the state courts and file any post-conviction appeals possible at that level before filing any more federal court petitions. <PERSON> Pellegrini </PERSON> was sentenced to die for the slaying of <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hancock </PERSON>, 27, who was handcuffed and shot in the head. <PERSON> Flanagan </PERSON> sought a stay on grounds a prosecutor improperly suggested during a penalty hearing that there could be more victims if <PERSON> Pellegrini </PERSON> ever got out of prison. The defender also claimed authorities conducted an illegal search of <PERSON> Pellegrini </PERSON>'s apartment, where the murder weapon, bullets and blood-spattered clothes were found. The same issues were raised in a state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> appeal, which was rejected last November when the high court held that the record provided substantial support for the verdict and the penalty.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Baker-Cuba Bjt   03-29 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Baker-Cuba, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baker Sees Hostile Relations Until Cuba Changes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> rejects speculation that U.S.-Cuban relations are about to improve, saying American policy will not change until <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> ends repression at home and `` unacceptable behavior'' abroad. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s views are outlined in a confidential memo drawn up to counter suggestions that <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s pledge in December to withdraw its troops from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> will improve the climate between <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy has not changed in the wake of the southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> accords,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said in the memo. The memo has been distributed to diplomatic posts abroad and to selected government agencies. The document is dated March 1989 and is stamped `` confidential.'' A copy was made available to The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday. The memo indicates that no changes are planned from the hard-line <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> policy of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. Under President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> tightened the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade embargo against the island and waged an international campaign against alleged human rights abuses by the regime of <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>. `` No modification of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy is contemplated in the absence of significant changes in Cuban repression at home and unacceptable behavior abroad inimical to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> interests,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> rejected the arguments of some, including <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy toward <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> over three decades has failed and should be changed. `` <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> provides the U.S.S.R. major political, strategic and intelligence benefits that it otherwise would not have,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. `` <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> continues to engage in military adventurism abroad and to support subversive movements in the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION> to the detriment of peace, stability and democratic processes. `` Further, the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> government persists in its internal repression and violation of the basic human rights of its citizens. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> has not changed its basic policies.'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> is involved in a public diplomatic effort to reinforce the impression that there will be an improvement in relations with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He said an end to the trade embargo, imposed by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1960, `` would benefit greatly the failed Cuban economy and enhance <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s image and prestige.'' It also would undercut <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> efforts to encourage other countries to maintain economic and political distance from <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, he said. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> `` has steadfastly failed to offer any concrete proposals of its own to satisfy longstanding and well-known <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. concerns.'' As described by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> has demonstrated a more accommodating attitude toward the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> over the last 18 months, and there has been an improvement in the ability of the two countries to work out differences on non-strategic issues, such as immigration. Cuban officials have disclosed that the head of the Cuban Interests Section in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON> <PERSON> Parodi </PERSON>, will be replaced shortly by <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Arbesu </PERSON>, a vice chief of <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, a party organism that oversees <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s relations with other nations in the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION> Former Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> said Monday that the Cuban shift indicates a willingness to intensify discussions with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on issues that have divided the two countries. He noted that <PERSON> Arbesu </PERSON> had been instrumental in the negotiations leading to the agreement on <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. But two current <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials, both insisting on anonymity, said they did not see <PERSON> Arbesu </PERSON>'s appointment as a political signal. <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON> <PERSON> Parodi </PERSON> has been in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> since September 1977 and is one of the longest serving heads of diplomatic missions in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> continues to support `` radical political movements and violent subversive groups'' in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. `` <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> provides a wide range of support for the <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION> insurgent armies in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and guerrilla groups in <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>,'' the secretary said. `` <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> has close relations with and provides extensive military and economic assistance to the Sandinista regime in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> which, in turn, provides material support to guerrillas throughout <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> added that <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> has exploited <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> differences with <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s government by using the dispute to promote Latin American solidarity against the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> has been supporting subversion in <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> and to a lesser extent rebel groups in <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ecuador </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Afghanistan     03-29 0538</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Afghanistan,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Say US Should End Support to Warring Afghan Factions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> says <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> refusal to stop arming rebels in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> could lead to a wider conflict in <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. Two Soviet diplomats, at a news conference Tuesday, urged Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> to reconsider a <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> proposal for a mutual arms embargo. `` So far, the American side is reluctant to accept our proposal,'' <PERSON> Oleg </PERSON> <PERSON> Derkovsky </PERSON>, a counselor at the Soviet embassy here, said. He said Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> is likely to renew the appeal when <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> goes to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in May. <PERSON> Derkovsky </PERSON> said fighting between the rebels and the Afghan government is escalating and could involve <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, as the two countries seek to protect their interests. The Soviet diplomat said the two countries were concerned that <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> might try to arrange a federation with <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> should the rebels succeed in overthrowing President <PERSON> Najibullah </PERSON>'s government `` People have to be very careful of avoiding incidents that could lead to a larger conflict,'' <PERSON> Yevgeny </PERSON> <PERSON> Kutovoy </PERSON>, minister-counselor of the embassy, said. The two diplomats accused the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> of illegally arming the rebels and said the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> should conduct an inquiry and consider posting monitors at the country's borders The diplomats also recalled predictions that <PERSON> Najibullah </PERSON> would collapse `` like a house of cards'' after the Feb. 15 departure of Soviet troops. The Soviet-backed Afghan leader and his army `` have shown most convincingly they are prepared to uphold on their own the country's sovereignty,'' <PERSON> Kutovoy </PERSON> said Soviet troops backed the government in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> against the U.S.-armed rebels for nine years. The war has continued since their departure. Kutovoy accused <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> of training and arming rebel forces in `` extensive subversive and terrorist activities'' to overthrow <PERSON> Najibullah </PERSON>'s government. He said Pakistani officers were directing attacks and that Pakistani servicemen have been captured deep inside <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s involvement calls for a special investigation by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> monitoring of the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> accords of last April which barred outside intervention in the Afghan war, <PERSON> Kutovoy </PERSON> said. At the same time, <PERSON> Kutovoy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Derkovsky </PERSON> criticized the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration for its decision to maintain <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms shipments to the rebels through <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid `` is contradictory to the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> accords, and does not help the peaceful solution of the situation in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Kutovoy </PERSON> said. `` The continuation of the shipments to the parties in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> is a source of the continuation of the fratricidal conflict in that country.'' <PERSON> Derkovsky </PERSON>, meanwhile, said the Soviets are no longer arming <PERSON> Najibullah </PERSON>'s government and that the weapons left behind with the departure of Soviet troops are not outlawed by the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> accords. But, he said, `` any supply of weapons to the opposition forces in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> through the territory of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> is a clear-cut, flagrant violation'' of the accords. `` Any weapon coming to <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> through <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> is a violation,'' <PERSON> Derkovsky </PERSON> said. `` If it comes from heaven, it's OK. If it comes through the territory of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, no way, it's a violation.'' <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman, said she had no comment on the Soviet allegations or on whether the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> should conduct an inquiry.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Czechoslovakia-Dissent Bjt   03-29 0697</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Czechoslovakia-Dissent, Bjt,0718</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ignoring The New Tolerance, Authorities Quash Dissent With Usual
Firmness</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALISON SMALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PRAGUE, Czechoslovakia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ignoring a new moderation in neighboring <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, this country's Communist government has silenced or muted voices critical of its rule. To a flurry of publicity in the West and protest even from the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc, playwright <PERSON> Vaclav </PERSON> <PERSON> Havel </PERSON> was arrested Jan. 16 and subsequently sentenced to eight months in jail. At least seven leading activists who are less known abroad but important in the emerging, younger dissident groups at home have also been jailed. Dozens of other critical voices have been muted by what dissidents term not only the most sweeping crackdown in a decade but a skillful, carefully targeted repression. Last year, it appeared to other activists that the authorities had at last loosened up on Charter 77, <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s oldest human rights movement, and were prepared to tolerate a measure of more active dissent. Leading activists such as <PERSON> Havel </PERSON> and fellow Chartist <PERSON> Jiri </PERSON> <PERSON> Dienstbier </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jiri </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruml </PERSON> began publishing Lidove Noviny -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-, an underground monthly they estimated quickly gained a readership of 4,000 and even seemed a candidate for legal registration A year later, those hopes are dashed. Underground journals, starved of equipment and money, can not reach more than a few thousand readers, making activists dependent on foreign radio stations _ widely listened to in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> _ to spread their news. `` Our great problem is the problem of information,'' said Charter 77 signatory <PERSON> Ladislav </PERSON> <PERSON> Lis </PERSON>. The situation has worsened, he noted, with the passage of new laws this month imposing stiff fines or jail terms on anyone circulating any documents deemed anti-Communist. Dissidents see various factors behind the change of tactics by the authorities. One is that the <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> conference reviewing implementation of the 1975 <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> Final Act has ended. At that forum, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> found itself under fire for repression of known dissidents. Now, the authorities assure Western diplomats they will implement the <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> accords _ they appear willing, for instance, to make it easier for millions of citizens to travel to the West _ but are not giving rein to groups they view as anti-Communist enemies. Probably the biggest factor in the changed tactics is the response to mass anti-government protests that occurred in August, October and January. <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>, a charming city of winding alleys, towers and steeples, is the only capital in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> where riot police appeared on the streets six times in five months, using tear gas, batons, dogs, water cannon and even armored personnel carriers to disperse peaceful crowds. Thousands of intellectuals signed at least three different petitions to the government protesting the police actions and the detention of <PERSON> Havel </PERSON> and other dissidents. The crackdown on known dissenters since has signaled the authorities' determination not to allow Charter 77 a voice in politics. Instead, an official committee was created in December to monitor human rights. Two officials, <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Flegel </PERSON> and <PERSON> Zbynek </PERSON> <PERSON> Vokrouhlicky </PERSON>, said in an interview they have already solved 65 cases where citizens previously were refused permission to travel abroad. But the committee has not spoken out against the police brutality in January and against toughened penalties on violating public order, an indication of authorities' desire to maintain control over political and social activity. Yet change could be in the offing. There have been few if any reprisals against the intellectuals who signed the petitions, an indication that at least some of the country's Communist leaders realize they can not isolate the brains they need to revitalize an increasingly stagnant economy. A well-informed source who asked not to be identified reported that at a meeting in mid-March, senior party leaders and economists discussed a plan to open the economy and allow some political liberalization. The plan _ the work of economist <PERSON> Valtr </PERSON> <PERSON> Komarek </PERSON>, who drew attention late last year with highly critical analyses of the Czechoslovak economy _ was rejected when first put to party leaders last December. Now, the source reported, it appears to have at least partial support from party leader <PERSON> Milos </PERSON> <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON>, who Western diplomats believe is under some pressure from the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> to open up to reform.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PhoenixTransit 5thLd-Writethru a0427 03-29 0389</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Phoenix Transit, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0427,0399</SECOND>
<HEAD>$8.4 Billion Phoenix Transit Issue Defeated In Special Election</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 4th graf to DELETE extraneous word `billion.'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Voters on Tuesday rejected a proposal to increase the sales tax half a penny to finance an $ 8.4 billion expansion of the growth-burdened <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> area's mass transit system. With ballots from 923 of 1,093 precincts counted, the tax increase had 114,618 votes, or 38.5 percent, to 182,833 votes, or 61.5 percent, against. `` Obviously this train is not leaving the station,'' said Mayor <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Goddard </PERSON>. The 30-year tax increase would have paid for a system which had been hailed by some as the metropolitan area's salvation from traffic jams and hazy skies and condemned by others as a white elephant. County Recorder <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Purcell </PERSON> had predicted a 30 percent turnout, or around 265,000 registered voters, for the vote on Proposition 300, the seed ballot for the ValTrans system. Approval would have raised the sales tax in most of the county to 7 percent by July 1. Proposition 300 asked voters to fund a 103-mile elevated railway, 23 miles of rush-hour train service along regular tracks, freeway lanes for multiple-passenger vehicles and a bus system expanded from 350 buses to 1,500. The <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> had projected a $ 44-per-year cost to the average household. But a study by the <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tax </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associations </ORGANIZATION> put the cost at $ 82 to $ 107. <ORGANIZATION> ValTrans </ORGANIZATION> was pushed as a way to reduce both air pollution and the nation's second-highest rates for auto insurance, to unclog city streets and to help families get rid of second or third cars. Opponents said <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> was too spread out for mass transit. ValTrans was the second version of Proposition 300 put before voters in 3 -LCB- years. The first, approved by more than two-thirds of the voters in October 1985, created the <ORGANIZATION> RPTA </ORGANIZATION> to plan for growth. It also instituted a 20-year, half-cent sales tax for 231 miles of freeways. So far, three miles have been completed and 22 miles are under construction. <ORGANIZATION> RPTA </ORGANIZATION> planners said ValTrans' first impact would have been more buses and routes beginning in September. The 10-year, rush-hour train service between <LOCATION> Chandler </LOCATION> and downtown <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> would have begun in 1991. The initial 24 miles of the light-rail system between <LOCATION> Glendale </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tempe </LOCATION> would have opened in 1995.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Woodshed Bjt   03-29 0723</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Woodshed, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Gray Follows Path First Trod by Stockman</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has made a few changes to the White House grounds, but the woodshed out back remains. You wo n't find it by the new horseshoe pit <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had installed, or the `` Beware of Dog'' sign he posted by the Rose Garden. The woodshed is invisible, fabricated by onetime budget director <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Stockman </PERSON> during a contrite 1981 news conference. Just as <PERSON> Stockman </PERSON> claimed he was `` taken to the woodshed'' by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for his public criticism of the president's economic policies, so was <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> counsel <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyden </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> rebuked for publicly raising questions about a day-old bipartisan agreement on <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> endorsed by the president In both cases, the dressing-down may have been more for show than for real, and parallels can be drawn between the two incidents. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, in an interview with <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, suggested the new agreement with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> diluted the constitutional powers of the president. The statement questioning a presidential decision was highly unusual coming from a White House subordinate, and the reverberations were almost immediate. White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> _ asked at his daily news briefing if <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> had yet been to the woodshed over his remarks _ said the official, in fact, had just met privately on that very matter with both <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and chief of staff <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON>. `` They had a polite discussion about how things work in the White House,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. And <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, asked for his reaction to <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>'s criticism, said pointedly: `` I shared my reaction with <PERSON> Boyden </PERSON>, which is the way I handle things.'' <PERSON> Stockman </PERSON> found himself in hot water when his skepticism about the ability of Reaganomics to make a dent in the budget deficit found its way into an article in the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> Monthly. And one of the first people <PERSON> Stockman </PERSON> sought out for advice was <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, according to no less a source than <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> himself. In his 1987 biography, `` Looking Forward,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` A forlorn figure in a dark blue suit showed up at my office seeking advice.'' It was <PERSON> Stockman </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the youthful budget director told him that he believed his comments to writer <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Greider </PERSON> had been off the record, which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said seemed a little naive because <PERSON> Stockman </PERSON> also told him <PERSON> Greider </PERSON> had a tape recorder going. `` When <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> finished telling his story, my advice was that he go down to the Oval Office as soon as possible, get an appointment with the president, and give him the same account he'd just given me. ` Admit you've made a mistake and apologize,' I advised him. `` My thought was that everyone's entitled to one mistake,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wrote. <PERSON> Stockman </PERSON>, in his 1986 book, `` The Triumph of Politics,'' claims he was n't scolded by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in the Oval Office meeting that followed. In fact, he wrote, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> asked him to stay on, saying `` I need your help.'' <PERSON> Stockman </PERSON>, who resigned his <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> job four years later, saw his book become a best seller and went on to become a Wall Street financial consultant, said he created the `` woodshed story'' to appease other White House aides. <PERSON> Stockman </PERSON> said the line about him having been called on the carpet by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was demanded by an enraged chief of staff, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, who told him it was the only way he could save his job. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, now the secretary of state, also figures prominently in the recent episode. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>'s voicing of concerns about the constitutionality of the Central American agreement marked the second time the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> counsel had challenged <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, who was the chief architect of the accord. Earlier, <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> raised conflict-of-interest questions about stocks <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> held in a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> bank because it was a Third World creditor. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> sold his holdings as a result. Any conversation between <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> at the woodshed remains unreported. Meanwhile, White House officials are taking the flap in stride, even with a measure of humor. `` First of all, I want to announce that <PERSON> Boyden </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> concurs in the constitutionality of the Easter Egg Roll,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said at the outset of his briefing on woodshed day. `` I checked with him myself.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BusInvestigation Bjt   03-29 0828</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bus Investigation, Bjt,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Accident Blamed on Drunken Driver Leads to Strong Recommendations</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal safety officials are calling for tougher drunken driving laws and want the oldest one-fifth of the nation's school buses off the road, in response to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' worst alcohol-related highway accident. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, ending its inquiry into the May 1988 head-on collision that killed 24 children and three adults aboard a <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> church bus, adopted a long list of recommendations for federal and state officials Tuesday. Flames spread through the bus after it collided with a pickup truck that was going the wrong way on Interstate 71 near <LOCATION> Carrollton </LOCATION>, Ky. Authorities said the pickup driver had a blood alcohol content of .26 in tests 90 minutes after the accident, and a board investigator said Tuesday he likely was at .29 when the collision occurred, which is nearly three times the legal level of presumed intoxication. All 27 deaths aboard the bus, which belonged to the <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> God </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Radcliff </LOCATION>, were attributed to smoke inhalation, the board said. Forty people escaped, most with injuries. The bus was returning from an amusement park near <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION>'s acting chairman, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kolstad </PERSON>, said the May 14 collision `` may be one of the most influential highway accidents the board has ever heard.'' The board said the accident clearly was caused by `` the alcohol-impaired condition'' of the pickup truck driver, <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahoney </PERSON>, 35, of <LOCATION> Worthville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, who is free on $ 540,000 bail awaiting a November trial on 27 counts of murder. But the board also said characteristics of the 11-year-old former school bus contributed to the accident's severity. The vehicle's unprotected fuel tank, flammable seat covers and a rear door partially obstructed by the last row of seats were all noted in the report which was adopted after a daylong session. The <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> bus was assembled by <ORGANIZATION> Sheller-Globe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. Last July, both <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Sheller-Globe </ORGANIZATION> reached out-of-court settlements for undisclosed amounts with families of nearly all the victims' families. Neither company admitted any liability. The board recommended that states set a date for phase-out of buses not meeting 1977 federal standards. If adopted nationwide, the rule would affect 77,000 school buses, about 22 percent of those now in use. It would also affect thousands of former school buses used by church groups and other organizations. The 1977 standards required strengthened fuel systems, stronger seats, toughened roof and body joints and more accessible exits. The five-member board also asked states to toughen their drunken-driving laws to allow police to revoke drivers' licenses, to prohibit plea-bargaining in drunken-driving cases and to end the practice of giving convicted drunken drivers reduced licensing penalties if they enroll in treatment programs. Among safety improvements suggested by the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION>, which has no enforcement powers and can only recommend actions to other federal agencies and the states, were making seatcovers out of fire retardant material, putting more exits on school buses and making their fuel tanks more resistant to puncture in severe accidents. The board noted that a three-inch tear in the fuel tank on the <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> bus led to the fire that engulfed the vehicle. But the board said it was unclear whether such strengthening measures would have prevented the fuel tank rupture, which it said was probably caused by a spring broken loose in the collision. It also noted that flame-retardant requirements did not change under the 1977 rules. The bus involved in the crash was built two weeks before the stiffened federal school bus safety requirements took effect April 1, 1977. Among specific board recommendations were: _ That the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Traffic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> require more fire-retardant material in bus seatcovers _ That school buses be made to meet the same standards for exit doors imposed on public transit buses, including the installation of either more exits or pop-out windows _ That the safety administration evaluate and revise, if necessary, its standards on the placement of school bus fuel tanks, plus adding various protective structures around the tanks, in addition to cages required under the 1977 law _ That the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> conduct a test of increasing the number of `` wrong way'' signs on divided highways to determine the signs' effectiveness in reducing wrong-way accidents, which the board said kill an average of more than 270 people a year _ That church groups and other private organizations purchase only buses that meet the post-1977 standards <PERSON> Micky </PERSON> <PERSON> Sadoff </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Mothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Against </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drunk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Driving </ORGANIZATION>, praised the recommendations but said she was saddened that the board focused more on bus safety than drunken driving. `` We would n't want to put down bus safety in any way,'' she said, but added, `` The equivalent of a fully loaded 747 crashing every week for a year equals the number of fatalities on our roads due to drunk driving.'' The board said 51 percent of the 46,000 annual fatalities are attributable to alcohol use.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush     03-29 0646</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Condemns Casual Treatment of Drugs in Entertainment Industry</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX9</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says proposals to legalize narcotics are `` 180 degrees wrong'' and the entertainment industry should stop depicting drugs as a humorous or harmless diversion. `` We have to change the way this problem has been looked at,'' the president said Tuesday during a question-and-answer session with about 100 civic class students at a high school in a <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Inching further away from his once ironclad opposition to tighter gun controls, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also said `` maybe there's a need for more laws'' to restrict the semiautomatic assault-style weapons that are used in drug-related violence. And he backed away from his earlier support of the proposal for a 51 percent pay increase for members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> _ an idea that died under a tidal wave of public opposition. `` In retrospect,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` it was too big a bite at once and the country did n't support it at all. So to accommodate the needs, the legitimate needs for a raise, it has to be done differently.'' Fielding a question on foreign policy, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is `` the only country that can be a substantial catalyst for peace' in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will hold separats at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> next week with Egyptian President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mu </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Foreign Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>. `` We will be probing as best we can and making suggestions to them as to what the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> can do in trying to bring about peace in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. The president talked with students during a surprise visit to <ORGANIZATION> James </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Madison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, about 15 miles from the White House. The school had only 90 minutes' warning he was coming To the delight of hundreds of chatting teen-agers in the school cafeteria, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had lunch with them, eating pizza and french fries and sipping milk through a straw. In the school library, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> perched on a stool and answered questions for 30 minutes. Bemoaning `` this stupid abuse of drugs,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said that `` for a while in this country, it seemed to be we condoned those things we should condemn.'' `` And we went through a period where the treatment, for example, of the use of cocaine in movies was done in a humorous vein or some kind of, well, harmless, but made the user look like some kind of silly idiot,'' he said. `` But nothing ... condemnatory. `` And so, we've got to mobilize the entertainment media and say, look, do n't put out great emotion in favor of or treat these _ in favor of cocaine or other drugs.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he recognizes that students are under pressure from their peers to experiment with drugs. He suggested that schools try to educate students `` about the damage that comes from substance abuse.'' He said that `` people used to talk about legalizing narcotics.'' Without naming names, he said, `` And that was some very serious people. And I just think it's 180 degrees wrong.'' Answering a question about international terrorism, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` It's like dealing with fog _ you ca n't get hold of it very well.'' In another development, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he was still seeking clarifications from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> on building the advanced FSX jet fighter and that efforts to nail down an agreement were `` going back and forth a little.'' Administration officials said the final go-ahead on the joint project was being delayed by haggling with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> over who will own the technology and how many planes would be U.S.-built. It is possible that a Japanese-set Friday deadline for a final decision may be missed, said the officials, speaking on condition of anonymity. However, officials also sought to dispel the idea that the project was unraveling and said a deal was still considered likely.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Thornburgh     03-29 0574</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Thornburgh,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thornburgh on TMI: Don't be Afraid to Scramble Organization Chart</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> says his thoughts were on securing his first state budget when he began the day March 28, 1979, but instead he wound up dealing with the nation's worst commercial nuclear accident. Now <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney General, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> had been <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> governor 72 days when a stuck valve at the <LOCATION> Three </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mile </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> plant allowed vital cooling water to drain from the Unit 2 reactor's radioactive core Although the plant was just 10 miles from the Capitol in <LOCATION> Harrisburg </LOCATION>, it could have been on the other side of the planet as far as <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>'s understanding of nuclear energy was concerned. Nuclear jargon `` was like a foreign language to me,'' he said Tuesday in a speech at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>. Still, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> was a quick study, and is widely credited for his calm handling of the accident. In Tuesday's speech, as in a speech he gave four years ago at <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said he learned that a manager `` should not be afraid to scramble the organization chart, as we did during Three Mile Island.'' He compared his handling of the accident to President <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> during the Cuban missile crisis, `` when his own brother's advice weighed more heavily with him than that of the secretary of State or the Joint Chiefs of Staff.'' No one was hurt during the accident, although radioactive gas was released into the atmosphere and pregnant women and preschoolers were advised by <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> to evacuate within five miles of the plant. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said he learned another lesson at TMI: `` respect but do not depend on the news media.'' While much of the reporting of the accident was reliable, he said some was `` downright outrageous.'' <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> added a postscript to Tuesday's speech, saying the 1986 accident at <LOCATION> Chernobyl </LOCATION> that killed at least 31 people `` might have been prevented if the people of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> were as free to question their authorities'' as were Americans in 1979. After <ORGANIZATION> TMI </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> served a second term as governor beginning in 1982, then headed the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Politics </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> before becoming attorney general last August. On other matters Tuesday, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>: _ Said the question of whether special investigations should be required for members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> suspected of criminal wrongdoing would be resolved `` at an early date. An order signed by <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>'s predecessor, <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, called for attorneys general to appoint an independent counsel to investigate serious allegations against congressmen and senators. `` I'm no great fan of independent counsels, period,'' <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said, adding that a review of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s order was nearing completion. _ Said he was unaware of a contingency plan for any federal takeover of the police department in the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, which has been plagued by drug-related murders _ Sidestepped a question on the appropriateness of a suit against random drug testing filed by Executive Office employees While declining to give an `` offhand'' opinion of the suit, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said he was encouraged by recent <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> rulings upholding <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> drug testing and post-accident drug testing by railroads. `` The validation of drug testing by the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> does send in my view a very positive signal _ gives a green light _ to those in the private sector who want to use sound drug testing programs to ensure a drug-free workplace,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iraq-Compensation     03-29 0607</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iraq-Compensation,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>With USS Stark Death Claims Settled, Claims for Injured Begin</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Pentagon is preparing claims on behalf of the 21 sailors injured in a missile attack on the USS Stark now that <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> has agreed to compensate the families of the 37 killed in the 1987 incident. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> also intends to ask <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> for compensation to cover the $ 82.9 million repair bill for the guided missile frigate, which was badly damaged when two French-made Exocet missiles were fired at the ship as it steamed through the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. `` We intend to move quickly to file those claims'' now that <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> has agreed to pay $ 27.3 million for the dead, a <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official said Tuesday after the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> announced the settlement with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. Among the 60 claims still to be filed against <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> are several on behalf of two seamen seriously injured in the fiery attack, and others on behalf of servicemen who suffered light burns and other injuries, officials said. The officials said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> wanted to see the outcome of the claim for the dead before submitting those for the survivors. `` The government of <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> has undertaken to make prompt payment of the full amount,'' said a defense official. `` Payments will be made to the families as quickly as possible after the receipt of the funds.'' <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s agreement to settle the claim was viewed by the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> as a `` good sign,'' said one diplomat. `` Further lack of progress in the case could have affected relations,'' he added, speaking on condition of anonymity. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> renewed its ties with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> in 1984 after a 17-year break and has sought to maintain a steady improvement despite some tensions. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> apologized for the missile attack, which occurred at the height of the <LOCATION> Iran-Iraq </LOCATION> `` tanker war,'' saying the pilot mistook the Stark for an enemy Iranian vessel. After an investigation, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> accepted the explanation. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> claim was presented 11 months ago but it took a trip to <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> last week by one of the department's top trouble shooters, legal adviser <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Sofaer </PERSON>, to nudge the Iraqis into action. Officials said the American team was called in to see <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> Foreign Minister <PERSON> Tariq </PERSON> <PERSON> Aziz </PERSON> on Monday `` and told that this was what -LRB- <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> -RRB- President -LRB- <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> had decided.'' `` There were no negotiations,'' one source continued. `` They just announced this was what they were prepared to pay.'' The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> team decided it was better to settle for slightly less than the original claim of $ 29.6 million in order to prevent further delays, the officials said. Each family will get an average of $ 740,000 according to a formula that takes into account the servicemen's remaining dependents. After the attack, the Stark spent several months undergoing temporary repairs in <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION> before returning with its surviving crew members to their home base in <LOCATION> Mayport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, in August 1987. The Stark later sailed to the shipyard in <LOCATION> Pascagoula </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, where it was built, for extensive repairs. It returned to fleet duty in <LOCATION> Mayport </LOCATION> in September 1988. Settlement of the Stark compensation brought to mind the unsettled claims of 290 victims of another <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> attack _ those killed when the <ORGANIZATION> USS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vincennes </ORGANIZATION> mistakenly shot down an Iranian airliner over the gulf last year. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> says it has not gotten specifics about those killed and therefore has been unable to determine the compensation. `` We've tried a number of channels to obtain information,'' but nothing has been accomplished over the past several months, said a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official, speaking on condition of anonymity.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     03-29 0027</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0027</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nikkei Closes 430 Points Higher</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed Wednesday at 32,737.28, up 430.92 points on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0205EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     03-29 0843</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,840</SECOND>
<HEAD>Regional Expenses of Raising Soybeans Vary Within Both US, Brazil</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A study by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says that <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> both have some cost advantages in the production of soybeans, but that the expenses vary greatly from region to region in each country. <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> is the chief competitor of American farmers in the lucrative world soybean market and is expected to harvest a record crop this year. <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> also has been expanding production. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has a big lead in global soybean output, producing 41.9 million metric tons of the world's 93.4 million tons forecast for the 1988-89 harvest. <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s harvest is currently indicated at 21 million tons, and <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>'s 8.5 million. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 36.7 bushels of soybeans. Questions have been raised about costs of production and whether <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> farmers can continue to compete with the growing output in the <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION> countries, particularly <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>. The study by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> offered no final answer to the debate but did pinpoint a number of regional cost differences in each country. For example, the study showed that American farmers generally have an edge with lower `` variable'' costs of production, which includes expenses for fertilizer, weedkillers, seeds and labor. But `` fixed'' costs are higher than in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>. Those include general farm overhead, taxes, insurance and interest payments. In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, using 1986 figures, the soybean regions with the lowest variable costs are the <ORGANIZATION> Corn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Belt </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> regions, with production costs averaging in a range $ 50 to $ 60 per ton. Those areas account for about 70 percent of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soybean area. But when the Southeast and <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> regions are included, the average variable cost jumps sharply to $ 110 per ton. `` Given the substantial portion of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soybean area outside the <LOCATION> Corn </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Belt-Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> region, use of data from this region alone may be inappropriate for making comparisons with <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>,'' the report said. Looking at <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, the analysts noted that the traditional soybean area is in the south, including the states of <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> do Sul, <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Catarina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Parana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sao </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paulo </LOCATION>. These states accounted for about 92 percent of <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s soybean area in 1977 _ but less than 64 percent in 1986. `` Therefore, it is no more correct to talk of the traditional region as typical of Brazilian production than it is to talk of the Corn Belt-Lake States region as typical of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production,'' the report said. Variable costs of production range from $ 102 per ton in <LOCATION> Sao </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paulo </LOCATION> to $ 203 in <LOCATION> Bahia </LOCATION>, one of the regions of soybean expansion. `` In absolute terms,'' the report said, `` these cost figures indicate that <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s cash expenses are high relative to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and that <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s soybean expansion has occurred despite high variable costs of production.'' The report added: `` One obvious hypothesis is that the low cost of land is driving the expansion of soybeans in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has bought 550,000 metric tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> corn for delivery in the 1988-89 marketing year that began on Sept. 1, the first in almost three months. Although <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> has been buying <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat regularly under an export subsidy program, it was the first significant corn purchase since Jan. 4, officials said Tuesday. The corn, which is not subsidized under the export program, is scheduled for delivery by Sept. 30, the end of the sixth year of a long-term grain supply agreement between the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Officials said the latest sales brought total corn sold to the Soviets for 1988-89 to more than 10.7 million tons. Additionally, sales include 4 million tons of wheat, 450,000 tons of soybeans, 1.4 million tons of soybean meal, and 507,400 tons of grain sorghum. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 39.4 bushels of corn or 36.7 bushels of wheat or soybeans. The 550,000 tons of corn would be about 21.7 million bushels. Corn prices have been averaging about $ 2.61 per bushel at the farm level, according to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> estimates, meaning that the latest sale could have a farm value of around $ 1.4 million.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Citrus and apples from the Empalme area of <LOCATION> Sonora </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, must be treated as a precaution against exotic fruit flies before entering the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, according to a new <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> rule. Peaches from the area are banned completely from entering the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> market. The restrictions took effect on March 24 but were not officially announced until Tuesday. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Slagle </PERSON>, acting administrator of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inspection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said federal inspectors `` have confirmed an infestation of Mexican fruit flies in the municipality of Empalme.'' Citrus fruit from Empalme must be fumigated before shipment to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Apples have to undergo a cold treatment to kill possible pests. But <PERSON> Slagle </PERSON> said there is `` no acceptable treatment'' for peaches.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0216EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CorporationFined     03-29 0446</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Corporation Fined,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Illegal Contributions to Glenn Campaign, Ford Group, Prompt Fines</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD L. VERNACI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Bekins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and 11 of its employees were fined $ 18,250 for making illegal contributions to Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>'s 1984 Democratic presidential campaign, federal records show. The contributions, amounting to $ 3,750, broke the law because the company paid the employees for making them, according to <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> records made available Tuesday. Corporations are not allowed to contribute to presidential or congressional campaigns. `` Most of the 15 employee-contributors were reimbursed, some through ` grossing up' of their annual incentive bonuses and some through their expense accounts,'' said a report by the commission's general counsel `` Some employees who received reimbursement did not even know they were reimbursed.'' The contributions began after <PERSON> Irwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Bekins </ORGANIZATION>' parent company, <ORGANIZATION> Minstar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, asked <PERSON> Bekins </PERSON>' president at the time, <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Labinger </PERSON>, to solicit contributions for the <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> campaign, the report said <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> also was a member of the <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> campaign's finance committee. Some of those who were asked to give money to the campaign said that they felt pressured to do so, the commission's report said. The company agreed to pay a $ 4,000 fine, and <PERSON> Labinger </PERSON> agreed to a $ 4,500 fine, and <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, who was <PERSON> Bekins </PERSON>' chief financial officer at the time, agreed to pay a $ 5,000 fine. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartman </PERSON>, the company's general counsel, was fined $ 2,000 and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Morse </PERSON>, a vice president for personnel, paid a $ 1,000 fine, the commission said. Seven other employees each agreed to pay $ 250 fines. On a separate matter, a political action committee organized to support the causes of former President <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> agreed to pay a $ 1,500 fine for accepting $ 15,000 from state organizations that could have received the money in ways that are legal at the state level but are not allowed in federal campaigns. The <ORGANIZATION> Gerald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> R. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> received $ 5,000 contributions each from the re-election campaign of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Clements </PERSON>, the 1986 <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> gubernatorial campaign of <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Leroy </PERSON> and the 1986 campaign of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> permit corporations to give money directly to political candidates and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> allows individuals to give unlimited amounts to candidates, the commission said. In addition to prohibiting corporate contributions to federal campaigns, the national law also limits individuals to giving no more than $ 1,000 per election to any one candidate. The commission found that the <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> committee broke the law by mingling that money with cash intended to support candidates for federal office. Both the <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> case and the <PERSON> Bekins </PERSON> case were settled in the past few months, but the files had remained sealed until Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890329-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-29-89 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Names 1stLd-Writethru a0434 03-29 0966</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0434,0997</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: INSERTS dropped logo in second item</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ringo </PERSON> <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> is back at work at <LOCATION> Abbey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION> studios for the first time since his treatment for alcohol abuse, and all he had to do was act naturally. `` <PERSON> Ringo </PERSON> looked terrifically healthy and well when he arrived at <LOCATION> Abbey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION>. He was bright-eyed and very entertaining all day,'' said country singer <PERSON> Buck </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>. The former Beatle recorded a new version of his 1965 hit, `` Act Naturally,'' with <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, who wrote the song. <PERSON> Starr </PERSON>, 48, and his wife, 38-year-old actress <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bach </PERSON>, spent five weeks undergoing treatment at a clinic in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> last year. The Owens-Starr duet will be the title track of an album to be released this summer. `` <PERSON> Ringo </PERSON> must be the most down-to-earth famous person I have ever met,'' <PERSON> Owens </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` I know a lot of people who have had his kind of problems. But it is not everyone who has the intestinal fortitude to stand up and tell the world: ` I've got a problem and I'm going to get some help.'''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Pointer Sisters are looking for a new record label and are talking with <ORGANIZATION> Motown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION>, said June Pointer. Their last two albums _ `` Hot Together'' and `` Serious Slammin'' _ sold poorly because they did n't get the proper attention from <ORGANIZATION> RCA </ORGANIZATION>, leading to the group's split with the label, said Ms. <PERSON> Pointer </PERSON>, who performs with her sisters, <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON>, <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON>. She recalled during an interview that her parents, the Rev. <PERSON> Elton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Pointer </PERSON>, who did n't allow pop music in their home, were troubled by their daughters' choice to embark on a show business career. But their 1973 debut album went gold, and by 1976, the sisters became the first black women to perform at the Grand Ole Opry with their first Grammy winning song `` Fairy Tale.'' They received two Grammys in 1983, for the singles `` Jump'' and `` Automatic.'' Although their father died in 1979, their parents saw the group make those first stabs at success and gave their daughters their blessing to perform, Ms. <PERSON> Pointer </PERSON> said. `` After the turnaround, when we had health insurance and money in the bank, then they could come to the shows and enjoy themselves,'' she said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A planeload of celebrities, including <ORGANIZATION> Morgan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fairchild </ORGANIZATION>, will fly to the nation's capital to join thousands of others who will march for abortion rights next month. `` I believe very strongly in a woman's right to choose. I believe very strongly in a woman's reproductive rights. It's very important to let people know that we are the majority,'' said <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Fairchild </PERSON>, a former TV star of `` Falcon Crest'' and `` <LOCATION> Flamingo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Mills </PERSON>, <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Close </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> <PERSON> McGillis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cybill </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON>, <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarandon </PERSON>, <PERSON> Marlo </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, <PERSON> Polly </PERSON> <PERSON> Bergen </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Burstyn </PERSON>, <PERSON> Teri </PERSON> <PERSON> Garr </PERSON>, <PERSON> Veronica </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamel </PERSON> and <PERSON> Valerie </PERSON> <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> are just some of the celebrity women who plan to participate in Pro-Choice Weekend in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, April 8-9. Many are members or affiliated with the <ORGANIZATION> Hollywood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Political </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, a group of activists in the entertainment industry who in the past have raised funds for liberal Democratic candidates
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ALBANY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Teen-age singing group <PERSON> Menudo </PERSON> will be featured in public service announcements warning Hispanic New Yorkers about the dangers of AIDS. The commericals, in English and Spanish, are being distributed to television stations by the state <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to encourage use of the Spanish AIDS information hot line. Menudo is from <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION>, but two of its four members are from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Doolittle </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Promotion </ORGANIZATION>, which announced the campaign Tuesday. The television spots are designed to appear like a music video, featuring computer-generated effects, she said. They were taped while the group was on tour in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> last year.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MADRID, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Spanish court has acquitted flamenco star <PERSON> Lola </PERSON> <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> of tax fraud charges, handing the government a setback in its highly publicized campaign to crack down on tax evaders. But court officials said Tuesday the <ORGANIZATION> Madrid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Provincial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> could be subject to administrative sanctions for failing to file tax returns between 1982 and 1985. The officials did not say how much she would have to pay. About $ 1.3 million had been sought in back taxes and penalties from <LOCATION> Flores </LOCATION> and up to two years in prison. During her trial this month, <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> said she did not have money to pay off the tax ministry, adding she never thought she would be prosecuted for what she called an innocent mistake. <PERSON> Flores </PERSON>, 66, starred as a Gypsy girl in numerous films in the 1940s and 1950s that popularized abroad the image of a poor but happy Spaniard dancing the flamenco.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Longer version moved on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>CHAMPAIGN, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
