<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 2355EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Germany-Terrorist 1stLd-Writethru   05-22 0436</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Germany-Terrorist, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0809,0450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Magazine Says Bomb Maker Eyed in Pan AM Flight 103 Case Is Freed</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: SUBS 4th graf, `A spokesman...' with two grafs to UPDATE with
officials quoted as confirming report. Pick up 5th pvs, ``He has...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HAMBURG, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A magazine reported Monday that a bomb maker for a Palestinian group suspected in the Pan Am Flight 103 bombing was freed 15 days after his arrest in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> because he works for the country's intelligence service. Stern magazine said <PERSON> Marwan </PERSON> <PERSON> Khreesat </PERSON>, 44, was arrested in October after raids in <LOCATION> Neuss </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>, but was allowed to go free the following month and returned to <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, where he was born. `` Five weeks later, a radio bomb of the type that <PERSON> Khreesat </PERSON> had built in <LOCATION> Neuss </LOCATION> blew up in the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> jet over <LOCATION> Lockerbie </LOCATION>,'' the Hamburg-based publication said. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, in Tuesday's editions, quoted unidentified <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> as confirming the report. But a spokesman for the intelligence agency, Bundesnachrichtendienst, or <ORGANIZATION> BND </ORGANIZATION>, denied the report, saying of <PERSON> Khreesat </PERSON>: `` He has never been an agent for <ORGANIZATION> BND </ORGANIZATION> and he is not one now.'' The spokesman declined to discuss other aspects of the report. He spoke on the condition of not being identified. A spokesman for the chief federal prosecutor's office said <PERSON> Khreesat </PERSON> was released because investigators could not find enough evidence to hold him. <PERSON> Khreesat </PERSON> is believed to be the bomb maker for the <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palestine-General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> PFLP-GC </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Stern </PERSON> said. British, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> news reports have mentioned the Syrian-based group as a prime suspect in the bombing of New York-bound Pan Flight 103 over <LOCATION> Lockerbie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, on Dec. 21. All 259 people on board and 11 on the ground were killed. <PERSON> Stern </PERSON> said its report was based on information provided by two high-ranking security officials it did not identify. It said <PERSON> Khreesat </PERSON> was among 16 suspected Palestinian terrorists arrested in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in October. Police seized large quantities of weapons and explosives in the raids, including a bomb-rigged radio cassette recorder. A similar device is believed by British investigators to have caused the Pan Am explosion. <PERSON> Stern </PERSON> said <PERSON> Khreesat </PERSON> was responsible for making `` radio bombs for attacks on planes'' for <ORGANIZATION> PFLP-GC </ORGANIZATION>. West German officials say they have no evidence linking <ORGANIZATION> PFLP-GC </ORGANIZATION> members arrested in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> to the Pan Am bombing. Only two of the 16 arrested in October remain in custody. <PERSON> Stern </PERSON> said its report is to appear in Wednesday's editions of the magazine. The publication released the report in advance to other news media on Monday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0009EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-China-USReax 1stLd-Writethru a0740 05-22 0553</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-US Reax, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0740,0564</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Students in U.S. No Longer Recognize Beijing Government</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 5th graf, `Rallies also...,' INSERTS new penultimate graf
to UPDATE with rally in Philadelphia.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-China, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JONATHAN W. OATIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of Chinese college students demonstrated around the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on Sunday in support of the pro-democracy uprising in their homeland, and <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> protesters said they no longer recognized <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s government. `` Lots of the students are crying. ... I feel like crying, too. I feel so sad and so angry,'' protest organizer <PERSON> Dong </PERSON> <PERSON> Lu </PERSON> said during a somber rally by about 300 students at the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> consulate in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. `` In the near future the Chinese -LRB- government -RRB- may win the game, but history tells us that the butchers of democracy are doomed in the end,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Hunter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> graduate student added. The demonstration came as hundreds of thousands of protesters led by students occupied <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> for a third day. A reported ultimatum by Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> passed without any sign of a military crackdown. Rallies also were held in <LOCATION> Lawrence </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Thousands turned out for protests in several cities Saturday. In <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, students have led the largest uprising in the 40-year history of the People's Republic of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is host to about 40,000 students from that nation. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on Sunday, three demonstrators met with consular officials and delivered an open telegram. `` We 10,000 Chinese students in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are on the side of the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> people,'' the telegram said. `` We no longer recognize the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> government led by <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> as a legal administration in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, and we pledge our complete disobedience to such a hostile government towards the whole Chinese nation,'' it said. The telegram called for <PERSON> Li </PERSON>'s replacement, and said the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> army should `` stand on the people's side and refuse to suppress the democratic campaign.'' A woman who answered the telephone at the Chinese consulate said officials had no comment. About 100 people marched for three hours at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION>, carrying signs with such messages as `` No Crackdown,'' `` No Violence'' and `` We want freedom of speech.'' Students, former students and faculty members from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> urged <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> leaders to voice their support for democratic reforms in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. `` It's important that we realize the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> did not achieve its independence alone,'' said <PERSON> Beth </PERSON> <PERSON> Chao </PERSON>, an American married to a former Chinese student. `` We got help from the French and other people. It's our responsibility to help others.'' In <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, about 50 students from <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> rallied in front of the Chinese consulate. A letter calling for an end to martial law in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> was handed to <PERSON> Xian </PERSON> <PERSON> Bin </PERSON> <PERSON> Li </PERSON>, who is in charge of Chinese students in the region. The demonstration followed a rally by about 800 people in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> on Saturday. In <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, about 50 Chinese students from <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION> carried banners and chanted English and Chinese in a peaceful protest on the Temple campus, officials said. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, where about 3,500 students demonstrated Saturday, four people from <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and five Americans held a rally in front of the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0012EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SpillwayDrowning 1stLd-Writethru a0713 05-22 0220</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Spillway Drowning, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0713,0222</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police: Two Dead, Three Missing in Boating Accident</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS last graf with 2 grafs to UPDATE with identities of victims;
no pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FARMERVILLE, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two small fishing boats were caught in the swift current flowing over a spillway into a bayou, leaving at least two people dead and three others presumed drowned Sunday. Police said two men had been fishing from a boat tied to a post near a dam spillway where water from <LOCATION> D'Arbonne </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> dumps into Bayou D'Arbonne. The lake is unusually high because of recent storms. The men untied the boat to return to shore but their motor would not start and the boat began drifting toward the dam, authorities said. They said the men managed to grab brush about 30 yards from the spillway and people in a second boat threw a line to them. When the men grabbed the rope, both boats were swept into the swift current. The bodies of a man and woman found Saturday were identified Sunday as <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradshaw </PERSON>, age unknown, of <LOCATION> Grambling </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Pamela </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Trammell </PERSON>, 35, of <LOCATION> Ruston </LOCATION>. Two men and a teen-ager who were missing and presumed dead Sunday were identified as <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Osborne </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Grambling </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Carey </PERSON> <PERSON> Trammell </PERSON>, 58, of <LOCATION> Ruston </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Trammell </PERSON>, 14, of <LOCATION> Ruston </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0014EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--Magellen     05-22 0144</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Magellen,0148</SECOND>
<HEAD>Magellen Corrects Orbit and Increase Speed Toward Venus</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PASADENA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Magellan spacecraft responded to a computer command and successfully corrected its trajectory Sunday, increasing the speed of its travel toward <PERSON> Venus </PERSON>, officials said. The maneuver was completed at 7 p.m. Sunday with a 5.6 second rocket burn, said officials with the Jet Propulsion Laboratory. The lab controls the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>'s unmanned planetary explorations. The correction increases the spacecraft's velocity by about 6.6 miles per hour. The spacecraft, launched from the space shuttle Atlantis on May 4, hurtles at 60,022 miles per hour as it continues its 15-month journey toward <PERSON> Venus </PERSON>. There it will map most of the surface of the planet with imaging radar. Another maneuver to correct <PERSON> Magellon </PERSON>'s path through space is set for Aug. 10, 1990 _ 17 days before the spacecraft enters orbit around <PERSON> Venus </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0018EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-Soviet     05-22 0283</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Soviet,0289</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Open Sakhalin Island to Japanese Tourists</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Seventy-seven Japanese left by ship for <LOCATION> Sakhalin </LOCATION> today, becoming the first group of Japanese tourists to visit the Soviet island since the end of World War II, local officials said. <PERSON> Tatsuo </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamamori </PERSON>, mayor of <LOCATION> Wakkanai </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s northernmost island of Hokkaido, was among the tourists who left the city for <LOCATION> Kholmsk </LOCATION>, a city on southern <LOCATION> Sakhalin </LOCATION>, aboard a Soviet ship this morning. `` I hope today's voyage will pave the way for a regular ferry service linking -LRB- <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> with the Soviet island -RRB- ... and which will contribute to promoting exchanges of people, culture and goods,'' <PERSON> Hamamori </PERSON> said in a nationally televised interview before the ship's departure A territorial dispute over a group of islands near <LOCATION> Sakhalin </LOCATION> seized by the Soviets in the closing days of the World War II has blocked efforts to conclude a Japan-Soviet peace treaty, technically leaving the two nations at war. The Soviet claim to <LOCATION> Sakhalin </LOCATION> is not now disputed by <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, but total recognition is being withheld by the government until the return of the other islands, known in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> as the `` northern territories.'' Though this is the first group of tourists allowed entry, relatives of Japanese buried on <LOCATION> Sakhalin </LOCATION> have in the past been allowed to visit the island. <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Travel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, a private Japanese tourist agency sponsoring the tour, said seven more trips from <LOCATION> Wakkanai </LOCATION> are scheduled this year. It said the tourists will tour the southern part of <LOCATION> Sakhalin </LOCATION> during their five-day stay. Last Monday, some 240 Japanese tourists left from a separate Japanese city by ship for <LOCATION> Vladivostok </LOCATION>, a major Soviet far east port, also for the first time since 1945.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0019EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--Magellan 1stLd-Writethru a0414 05-22 0157</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Magellan, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0414,0156</SECOND>
<HEAD>Magellan Corrects Orbit and Increase Speed Toward Venus</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: CORRECTS spelling of Magellan in slug, overline</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PASADENA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Magellan spacecraft responded to a computer command and successfully corrected its trajectory Sunday, increasing the speed of its travel toward <PERSON> Venus </PERSON>, officials said. The maneuver was completed at 7 p.m. Sunday with a 5.6 second rocket burn, said officials with the Jet Propulsion Laboratory. The lab controls the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>'s unmanned planetary explorations. The correction increases the spacecraft's velocity by about 6.6 miles per hour. The spacecraft, launched from the space shuttle Atlantis on May 4, hurtles at 60,022 miles per hour as it continues its 15-month journey toward <PERSON> Venus </PERSON>. There it will map most of the surface of the planet with imaging radar. Another maneuver to correct <ORGANIZATION> Magellan </ORGANIZATION>'s path through space is set for Aug. 10, 1990 _ 17 days before the spacecraft enters orbit around <PERSON> Venus </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0029EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     05-22 0457</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0474</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RIO GRANDE, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fearless fowl named <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> refused to be cooped up following a record-setting flight at the 18th annual International Chicken Flying Contest. <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> flew 542 feet, 9 inches Saturday to win the contest at the <ORGANIZATION> Bob </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Evans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> in southeast <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. Her flight shattered the 10-year-old mark of 302 feet, 8 inches and won $ 1,100 for her owner, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Salyers </PERSON>. But <PERSON> Salyers </PERSON> was unable to bring <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> to the trophy stand to share in the award ceremony. During her flight, <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> swept over the flying course, an adjacent field, and so far into the nearby woods that <PERSON> Salyers </PERSON> was unable to find her. `` I lose one or two every year that way,'' said <PERSON> Salyers </PERSON>, who has entered chickens in the meet for nine years. `` Two years ago, I had the longest flier here and I never did find that chicken.'' The rest of the 228 contestants were not as anxious to flout the law of gravity. The average chicken entered the mail-box launching chute, flapped its wings hysterically and settled on the ground a few feet away. <PERSON> Salyers </PERSON> said he had no secret for training flying chickens. `` I do n't mistreat them,'' he said. `` They're pretty wild. I just go out and say, ` Shoo!' That scares them, I guess, and they take off. But there's no training a chicken so you'll know which one will fly and which wo n't.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW STRAITSVILLE, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal revenuers have taken the moonshine out of the New Straitsville Moonshine Festival. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Straitsville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Betterment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> had a temporary permit from the federal <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alcohol </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tobacco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Firearms </ORGANIZATION> to make moonshine whiskey for the last seven festivals, but that has been lifted. `` The bureau says they ca n't legally give us a permit to make moonshine when they're trying to stop it,'' said <PERSON> Kenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Burgess </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, secretary of the association. The 19th annual festival runs Wednesday through Monday in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Straitsville </LOCATION>, a south-central <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> community which for years called itself the moonshine capital of the world. Of the 47 stills smashed by federal revenuers in the 1930s in <LOCATION> Perry </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, 32 were in or around <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Straitsville </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Burgess </PERSON> said. Festival organizer <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clair </PERSON> said she needed permission from the bureau just to make the mash, a concoction of cracked corn, sugar, yeast and water that is run through the still. `` I think it's silly. There are no free samples,'' she said of the decision to halt the moonshine. Ms. <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clair </PERSON> remembers being asked by a policeman where she was from during a trip to the 1934 World's Fair in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. `` ` New Straitsville?' he said. ` Oh, you're from down there where they make that good moonshine,''' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MovieAuction     05-22 0330</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Movie Auction,0339</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Gone With The Wind' Edition Fetches $20,000 at Movie Memorabilia
Auction</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LOUINN LOTA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A hard-bound edition of `` Gone With The Wind,'' with signatures of 23 cast and crew members from the legendary MGM film, was sold for $ 20,000 at a <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> auction at the Ebell Theater. Other remnants of <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>'s heyday auctioned Saturday included a jacket worn by <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON> and tap shoes worn by <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Astaire </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Vilkin </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Camden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auctioneers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> `` Some people buy from the heart when money's no object,'' <PERSON> Vilkin </PERSON> said. `` Maybe that's another explanation why these things sell for as much as they do.'' The 1938 edition of <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>'s Southern romance novel belonged to actor <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Crane </PERSON>, who played <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Tarlton </PERSON>, one of the twin's vying for <PERSON> Scarlett </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Hara </PERSON>'s affection in the movie's opening sequence. The book was valued at $ 25,000 to $ 30,000. <PERSON> Vilkin </PERSON> said at least 350 guests were on hand when a vest worn by <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Gable </PERSON> in `` Gone With The Wind'' sold for $ 3,800, nearly double its estimated value. A Civil War coat worn by <PERSON> Gable </PERSON> went for $ 6,000. <PERSON> Vilkin </PERSON> declined to identify the bidders. `` I think movies are a common denominator amongst all of us no matter what we do. We all have great memories,'' <PERSON> Vilkin </PERSON> said. `` In <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, where the industry started ... these things are thrown away. It's amazing the stories I've heard. `` One guy told me, ` My basement got flooded. That's where I had all the stuff stored.' I'm hoping to flush out the treasures that are out here before they get destroyed. We have so little of the vintage Hollywood of the'30s and'40s.'' A bidder paid $ 9,000 for the black patent leather tap shoes worn by <PERSON> Astaire </PERSON> in `` The Gay Divorcee,'' and someone paid $ 5,000 for a jacket worn by Presley in `` Double Trouble.'' A 126-page script from `` The Wizard of Oz,'' dated July 5, 1938, sold for $ 15,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ClassroomTV     05-22 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Classroom TV,0728</SECOND>
<HEAD>Classroom TV: It Isn't Just The Commercials</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE MITGANG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When Tennessee-based <ORGANIZATION> Whittle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> started beaming a news program with commercials into six high schools last winter, educators were outraged. This spring, when <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> and the Discovery Channel each promised schools commercial-free cable news and documentary programming, many of those same people applauded. Those reactions left the impression that the presence or absence of Snickers or blue jeans ads was the only concern school officials have about classroom TV programmming. But there are other issues. One is time, `` a school's most precious commodity,'' said <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyer </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endowment </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Teaching. Hardly a week passes that some study does n't demand that public schools raise test scores and teach more math, or science, or art, or values, or safe sex _ all of this, presumably, to be shoehorned into the same 180-day school year. The 12-minute-a-day Channel One news show that Whittle offers is the equivalent of six classroom days a year, one of which would be commercials alone. <PERSON> Manya </PERSON> <PERSON> Ungar </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> PTA </ORGANIZATION>, and others say that because classroom time is so precious, educators should be sure that TV programs support, rather than supplant, the curriculum. `` If there are ways to provide this technology when, where and how the teacher feels it best enhances instruction, discussion and comprehension, then it is to be applauded,'' <PERSON> Ungar </PERSON> said. `` If it does n't, it's a detriment.'' Few educators outright oppose classroom TV. Nearly two-thirds of all school districts now have some link to cable programming, according to a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> survey. But television has inherent shortcomings as an educational technology, many still believe, especially compared to microcomputers. `` Television is not the preferred technology in most instances,'' said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomson </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Secondary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Principals </ORGANIZATION>. `` It has a cost advantage over film. `` But microcomputers are far more powerful educationally than television because they are individualized and they are interactive. `` Unfortunately,'' he continued, `` the public thinks we are against technology when we say we're not that impressed with television. But in many ways it is outdated. Research shows it is not that effective.'' At least some of these problems can be overcome. <ORGANIZATION> Kentucky </ORGANIZATION> won praise this school year when it financed the nation's first statewide educational satellite system. Public TV station <ORGANIZATION> KET </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Star Channels'' features hardware that allows students all over the state to communicate with a televised teacher at the touch of a button. The announcement last week of `` Assignment: Discovery,'' to debut Sept. 18, followed <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>'s announcement that his <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> will begin running a 15-minute current events show called `` <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newsroom </ORGANIZATION>'' on Aug. 14. The Discovery Channel's proposed classroom TV offering is getting favorable early notices. Teachers would be free to tape Discovery programs and use them when and however they see fit. Discovery Channel's forte is documentaries, and school officials said they were excited at the prospect of supplementing lessons with clips that would bring history alive in the classroom as no textbook could. `` In a social studies class, I can imagine a teacher saying, ` I want you to watch <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> give his ` Ich Bein <PERSON> Ein </PERSON> <PERSON> Berliner </PERSON>' speech,'' said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Marx </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administrators </ORGANIZATION> The group has blasted Whittle's commercial Channel One, but has praised Discovery Channel. But the debate over classroom commercials masks another fundamental issue: the decadeslong failure of government and educational systems to harness technology to enhance student achievement. In effect, commercial broadcasters like <PERSON> Whittle </PERSON> are being blamed for stepping into that void and wanting to make a profit. And the school officials pointing accusing fingers at <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Whittle </PERSON> for his commercials are the very ones who have largely escaped blame for doing little about the technology void that private entrepreneurs now seek to fill. `` I think it's a scandal that we're so far into these technologies and yet they remain so unconnected with schools,'' said <PERSON> Boyer </PERSON>. `` Education is still standing in the wings, lamenting its abuses.''
</TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Poll-Environment Bjt   05-22 0722</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poll-Environment, Bjt,0740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poll: Americans Favor Broad Measures to Curb Pollution</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Americans would accept an array of encroachments on their lives to help clean up the environment, such as a ban on aerosol cans and mandatory household recycling, a poll has found. The Media General-Associated Press survey of 1,084 adults found broad perceptions that environmental pollution is on the rise, and that government, businesses and average Americans are not doing enough to combat it. Three-quarters of the respondents said laws against pollution in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are too weak, and majorities favored urgent government action, no matter what the cost, to protect the nation's drinking water Large majorities also supported strict pollution controls at all major oil facilities and at oil - and coal-burning power plants, even if those measures would raise the price of oil, gasoline and electricity Environmental concerns were heightened by the nearly 11 million gallons of oil spilled by the tanker <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valdez </ORGANIZATION> off <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> in March. But the poll, conducted by telephone May 5-13, found concerns went beyond the issue of oil tanker safety. The highest environmental priority was toxic waste disposal, in which 63 percent supported urgent action by the government regardless of the expense. Next was the related issue of the pollution of drinking water, with 52 percent favoring urgent action, cost aside. On the issue of household waste, 20 percent said their communities now require them to separate and recycle glass, cans and paper refuse. Of the rest, an overwhelming 87 percent said they would support such a requirement. Respondents also favored new steps against air pollution. Seventy-five percent backed a ban on household aerosol products; 60 percent supported a ban on charcoal lighter fluid; and 58 percent favored a ban on non-radial tires, which release more rubber into the air than do radials. Those proposals are among the steps suggested for <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> by a regional air quality board in March. Other measures in that plan won less support nationally: Respondents were split on parking restrictions in cities to discourage driving, and 59 percent opposed banning gasoline-fueled garden appliances. Still, 72 percent supported strict pollution controls on oil-and coal-burning power plants, even if that would raise the price of power. Smokestack controls are another feature of the <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> plan. In an issue related to the Exxon Valdez disaster, 81 percent said new safety rules and emergency cleanup teams should be in place at all major oil facilities, even if that raised the price of oil and gasoline. Responses were less certain on whether the federal government should issue new drilling permits. Forty-five percent opposed new drilling off the coasts of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, while about 35 percent favored new drilling there and 20 percent were unsure. Opposition was greater to oil drilling in the <ORGANIZATION> Arctic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refuge </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, which also is being considered. Sixty percent were opposed and only about a quarter were in favor, with the rest unsure. Overall, 72 percent said pollution appears to have increased during the past decade. And in a measure of its personal impact, nearly a quarter said they stayed away from the beach last year because of beach pollution. Concerns about the environment crossed ideological and political lines. Residents of the nation's most densely populated areas were the most apt to see anti-pollution efforts as inadequate and to favor new steps. Respondents indicated there was plenty of blame to go around for the nation's pollution problems. Forty-two percent said businesses are doing a poor job of keeping the environment clean and 36 percent said `` only fair.'' Similarly, 83 percent rated the federal government's environmental record as only fair or poor, as opposed to good or excellent; 71 percent gave a negative rating to their state and local governments' environmental records; and 79 percent said most Americans are doing only a fair or poor job of keeping the environment clean The poll, which had a margin of error of plus or minus 3 points, was conducted by the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a communications company based in <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, that publishes the Richmond Times-Dispatch, The Richmond News Leader, the <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Winston-Salem </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal, and operates TV stations <ORGANIZATION> WXFL </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, WCBD in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> WJKS </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Afghanistan-Stalemate Bjt   05-22 0786</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghanistan-Stalemate, Bjt,0808</SECOND>
<HEAD>Using A Military Stalemate To Press For Peace</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SHARON HERBAUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three months after the last Soviet soldiers left, the government is showing increasing confidence it can ultimately force Moslem guerrillas and their supporters _ especially the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> _ to talk peace. After initial anxiety following the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s withdrawal and the guerrillas' <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> offensive, President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>'s government is displaying a new optimism in its ability to stand alone against the mujahedeen guerrillas. Western countries had predicted the mujahedeen, or Islamic holy warriors, would overwhelm the Afghan armed forces within weeks or at least a few months of the Soviets' departure on Feb. 15. Although these predictions have not come true, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has rebuffed proposals by Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> for a mutual cut-off of weapons and stepped-up efforts for a cease-fire. `` They say, ` We should give the mujahedeen more time,' but they have had time and they have nothing to show. They have no power. They can only fire rockets,'' Foreign Minister <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Wakil </PERSON> said. He said President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> should accept that the guerrillas will not bring down the Soviet-backed government and that a negotiated peace is the only policy consistent with the principles espoused by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The guerrilla attack on <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION>, which <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> claims was orchestrated by neighboring <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s top military and civilian officials, was based on the assumption that <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s fifth-largest city would fall quickly, clearing the way for a push on <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> But government forces defending <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> have proved their morale was not sapped by the Soviet withdrawal. And the mujahedeen have not yet shown themselves capable of transforming from hit-and-run fighters to a cohesive force able to mount a conventional assault on a heavily defended city. The guerrillas' failure to capture <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> and other major cities appears to have strengthened feelings among government troops that the war has become a do-or-die affair. `` As long as the Russians were here, there was confusion among the people about what we were fighting for,'' a 30-year-old soldier in <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> said recently. `` Now we know. We are fighting as Afghans, and the fighting is for our future.'' After failing for nine years to win the war with 115,000 soldiers and a mighty modern arsenal, the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> now professes a desire to play peacemaker. It has called for a broad-based government in which <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>'s Soviet-style party would play a role _ but not the only role. <PERSON> Yuli </PERSON> <PERSON> Vorontsov </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> ambassador, predicted the military stalemate and increasing diplomatic pressure will oblige the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to begin talks on ending the bloodshed. More than 1.3 million Afghans _ nearly one-tenth of the country's pre-war population of 15 million _ have been killed. Another 5 million have fled across the borders to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. `` By the end of summer, I think there will be a change of mind, a change of this policy of ` give war a chance,' `` <PERSON> Vorontsov </PERSON> said. Many foreign diplomats in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, including from nations friendly to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>, also said they believe the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will feel increasing pressure for a settlement. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> already has promised <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> it will halt arms supplies to the guerrillas when current contracts expire, Chinese and Soviet diplomats said on condition of anonymity. And on Sunday, <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> offered a dozen guerrilla field commanders full autonomy in their regions if they stop fighting the government and help end the 11-year-old civil war. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, anxious to repatriate its 2 million Afghan refugees, also appears to be shifting toward a negotiated peace. That leaves only the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> _ the guerrillas' other major backers _ committed to ending the fighting A diplomat from a non-communist, pro-Western nation said: `` <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> has proven he is tough, organized and that he wo n't run. The longer the Western countries try to ignore him, the stronger they're going to allow him to become. In two or three months' time, he could well be a hero.'' A common preference for a settlement seems to rest with an ill-defined compromise: a government that is neither as ruthless as the ruling <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Afghanistan </ORGANIZATION> has been since it seized power in 1978, nor as committed to Islamic fundamentalism as some of the most powerful guerrilla groups are. Events of the last decade have provided little nourishment for middle-of-the-road politics and seem to leave the task of finding a compromise up to those on the outside, such as the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> or the superpowers.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Herbaugh </PERSON>, news editor for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>, covered the Soviet withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and has reported extensively from the country since.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     05-22 0795</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0831</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MALIBU, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> is miffed at `` certain irresponsible media personalities'' for the way they reacted to his declaration as honorary mayor of this star-studded beach community. <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> shook up some of his neighbors by designating <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION> a nuclear-free haven for the homeless and aliens. On Sunday, he had more to say. `` I regret that my concern for the poor and the environment was so dishonestly misinterpreted and misused to perpetrate a cruel hoax on 4 million Americans who are already broken beyond any measure of understanding,'' <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> said in a statement. `` I am deeply troubled and profoundly saddened by certain irresponsible media personalities who have abused their power to gain ratings by treading on misery and suffering.'' <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON>'s declaration last week was a bit ill-received. <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> poked fun at it in his monologue on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Tonight'' show, and the marquee at the <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Inn </LOCATION> and restaurant briefly read `` Dump <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gumshoes trying to crack the case of why <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Moonlighting'' was canceled have at least two suspects _ <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cybill </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON> The show's stars apparently spent much of their time arguing with each other and with the series' creator, <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Caron </PERSON>, said an <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> official quoted in this week's People magazine. `` They were working in a pressure cooker,'' said the official, who was not identified. The tongue-in-cheek detective series had its final episode earlier this month, after four seasons spiced with snappy repartee and double-entendres. It made a star of <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> and was a comeback vehicle for Shepherd. But the show's real turnaround came with <ORGANIZATION> Shepherd </ORGANIZATION>'s 1987 pregnancy, which plagued her with sickness and left her unable to work the show's long hours. And when <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> lost interest, one writer told People, the show was doomed. `` Cybill may have been erratic, but <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> had always been the motor that drove the show. Once <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> stopped caring, it became very hard on everyone,'' said the writer, who also was not identified.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WEST HOLLYWOOD, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Keith </PERSON>, who played former <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> in a TV miniseries, is facing charges of drunken driving for a collision with another car, officials said. <PERSON> Keith </PERSON>, 35, was speeding when he hit a car making a U-turn around midnight Saturday, injuring a woman riding in the other car, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's Deputy <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Ducoulombier </PERSON> said. `` He was charged with the more serious felony violation because of the speeding and the injury,'' the deputy said. <PERSON> Ducoulombier </PERSON> said <PERSON> Keith </PERSON>'s blood alcohol level was tested at more than 0.18 percent, 0.08 percent higher than the level defining drunken driving. He was freed early Sunday after posting $ 2,500 bail, the deputy said. <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> played North in the miniseries `` Guts and Glory: The Rise and Fall of <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>,'' which was broadcast last month and early this month.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prince <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> says the dream of rebuilding <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s Globe Theater began as a `` slightly crazy notion'' but will become a tribute to <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>. The effort to raise $ 33 million to recreate a replica of the theater, where the <PERSON> Bard </PERSON> made his debut as an actor, is a `` grand scheme,'' the Duke of <LOCATION> Edinburgh </LOCATION> told reporters Sunday. The prince was the guest of honor at a dinner where actor <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Wanamaker </PERSON> and representatives of the <ORGANIZATION> Shakespeare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Centre </ORGANIZATION> finished a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> fund-raising tour. <PERSON> Wanamaker </PERSON> initiated the restoration project. The prince said <PERSON> Wanamaker </PERSON> persevered over those who wanted to build houses on the site, adding that the idea was initially considered a `` slightly crazy notion.'' The Globe replica is scheduled to open in 1992 on <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>'s birthday, April 23 The original Globe was built in 1599; it was destroyed in 1613 when a cannon fired during a performance of `` <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> VIII </PERSON>'' set fire to the thatched roof. It was rebuilt in 1614 but torn down in 1644 for tenement housing. Today the site is an empty lot.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> attended Mass in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s holiest shrine and was mobbed by so many well-wishers after the service it took him 20 minutes to reach his car. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, a Roman Catholic, and family members traveling with him attended Mass at the Basilica of the Virgin of <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION> on Sunday. Afterward, hundreds of people inside and outside the church surrounded the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Democrat as security agents helped keep some people away. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> then left for the southern city of <LOCATION> Oaxaca </LOCATION>, where he toured agricultural areas and met with farmers. On Saturday, the first day of <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s four-day <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> tour, the senator met with <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s attorney general and praised Mexican efforts to fight drug trafficking. He planned to return to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0106EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Proxmire Bjt   05-22 0771</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Proxmire, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Proxmire Still Moving Fast After Senate Career</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The platform of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> subway station is crowded and former Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> is striding so rapidly through the cavernous space that he could almost be said to be running. Flashing lights and a far-away rumble signal the approach of a train. <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> is out of position. He moves from a rapid walk to a dash, darting inside a car just before the doors close with an automated whoosh. It's not an isolated event. It's a routine. `` I pace up and down carrying a heavy brief case,'' the 73-year-old <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> Democrat says. `` I do a sprint right at the very end.'' <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> was once the country's most celebrated long-distance amateur runner. For decades he ran flat out _ `` I never jogged'' _ the five miles between his home in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> park in <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> office on Capitol Hill. `` I ca n't do that anymore,'' he says. `` I've got a bum knee.'' So he exercises, rides his stationary bike, and strides the length of lengthy subway platforms. `` One great heart specialist says the secret is that you've got to keep moving, got to keep moving,'' the former senator says. On this particular day, like most days, <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> goes to work in a tiny cubicle attached to the <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> LaFollette </PERSON> Sr, <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reading </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Room </ORGANIZATION> in the Library of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The room has a special significance for him. He held <PERSON> LaFollette </PERSON>'s seat in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> for 31 years, ever since he won a special election to replace the late Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> in 1957. The cubicle is equipped with a chair, bookshelves, a telephone and typewriter. It is not equipped with a view. A computer terminal is expected soon. Not much room, not much equipment, for a man who until last December commanded a large office suite in the <ORGANIZATION> Dirksen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Office Building and a personal and committee staff of dozens. `` When you're in the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> you really get support,'' <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> says. `` I loved the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, but I do n't very much miss it.'' `` What I do miss is the clerical staff, the secretarial support, the schedulers, the researchers.'' In retirement, <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> is pretty much of a one-man band, with an occasional boost now and then from former staff members. He does his own typing. And he is gingerly returning to what he calls `` my first love, journalism.'' An early job, in 1949, was as a reporter with the <ORGANIZATION> Capitol </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis </LOCATION>. He was fired after a series of run-ins with management. But now he's back. <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> is launching a twice-a-week newspaper column under the auspices of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Features </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Syndicate </ORGANIZATION>. He says that one of the 40 or 50 subscribers signed up so far is The Capitol Times. <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> launched his column last week with a news conference at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> in which he resurrected his Golden Fleece Award, perhaps the most successful political public relations device of its era. The Fleece will be a monthly feature of the Proxmire column, carrying on a tradition that, beginning in March 1975, continued for 165 consecutive months with citations for what <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> considered examples of conspicuous government waste, and an occasional award of merit for a positive action that saved money or spent it well. `` Just because I'm out of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> does n't mean we have to abandon a device that does something to cut down spending in this time of fearful budget deficits,'' <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> says. <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> also is planning a book. Subject: debt, government debt, business debt, household debt. <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>, former chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, has been predicting a sharp recession for years: `` I think when the recession comes it's likely to be a real killer, a depression _ and that is because our debt is so enormous.'' He has been working up to the book by using debt as the theme of dozens of speeches around the country. At the press club news conference, <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> was asked if he, as a former <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> chairman, had ever considered giving himself a Golden Fleece for failing to spot and stop the pattern of abuses that grew into the multibillion-dollar savings and loan scandal. There were so many mistakes by so many people `` that you'd have to have a barrel of fleeces, including one for the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>,'' he replied. `` I'll let other people give me a fleece, rather than commit suicide,'' <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Knutson </PERSON> covers <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0105EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WrightProbe Bjt   05-22 0782</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wright Probe, Bjt,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wright Says Rules Were Changed on Him in Mid-Game</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s televised defense against ethics charges this week will be that the rules were changed in mid-stream, but even his own lawyers give him less than an even chance of winning quick dismissal of the case. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s lawyers will argue that the two most serious sets of charges brought against their client by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee should be dismissed because the panel, reacting to a new moral climate, has stretched the rules beyond their original intent. `` We are hoping for a clear interpretation that the rules have n't changed on us,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said. But <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s lawyers concede such motions are routinely denied and give the speaker less than even chance of winning a pre-emptive dismissal of the charges. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Oldaker </PERSON>, one of <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s lawyers, said last week that in a best-case scenario, the odds of succeeding with such a motion would be 50-50; in this case, he conceded that the odds could be something less than that. And a growing number of House Democrats are saying that while the ethics process is important, it may ultimately prove irrelevant to the speaker's political fortunes. `` It would be nice if he could be in a position to defend his case on the merits before he has to face the question of what the political consequences are,'' said Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Obey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Wis </LOCATION>., who has argued that the rules are on <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s side <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Susman </PERSON>, a hard-nosed trial lawyer brought in this month to bolster the defense team, is expected to argue that the committee misapplied the rules in two ways: _ In charging <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> with evading limits on outside earned income through bulk sales of his book, `` Reflections of a Public Man,'' the panel ignored a rule specifically exempting book royalties from the limit House rules place a cap on money earned from speaking fees at 30 percent of congressional salary. The ethics panel said that in seven instances, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> sold bulk quantities of books to groups he had spoken to, and that the sales were really disguised speaking fees which he otherwise would n't have been able to accept. `` No rule of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, no advisory opinion, no prior cases and not one shred of legislative history ... supports the outside special counsel's revisionist approach to the copyright royalty exemption,'' the lawyers argue in a statement. _ Charges that <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> improperly accepted $ 145,000 in improper gifts from <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mallick </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> real estate developer and business partner of the speaker, are based on a finding that <PERSON> Mallick </PERSON> had a direct interest in legislation before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> Over a period of nearly 10 years, <PERSON> Mallick </PERSON> gave <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON>, use of a car and a condominium in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, and from 1979 through 1984 paid Mrs. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> an $ 18,000-a-year salary. The committee found reason to believe those amounted to gifts, and that <PERSON> Mallick </PERSON> had a stake in legislation because of his many investments. House rules bar acceptance of more than $ 100 in gifts annually from any such person. An ethics committee advisory opinion defines the direct interest standard as `` a distinct or special interest in influencing or affecting the federal legislative process which sets the individual or organization apart from the general public.'' <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> lawyer <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>, the ethics committee's special outside counsel in the case, will defend the panel's rules interpretation at the hearing Tuesday. The dismissal motion essentially asks the ethics committee to abandon rules interpretations it earlier had decided to accept. <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Julian </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Calif., last week characterized the panel's original decision as `` very well founded. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s defense team is not challenging, at least for the moment, charges that he failed to report the <PERSON> Mallick </PERSON> benefits as gifts on his annual financial disclosure forms, a relatively minor concern. Following the hearing, expected to take about six hours, the committee will meet later in the week to rule on the dismissal motion. Any remaining charges then would become the subject of a disciplinary hearing. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and his advisers, hoping to avoid prolonging what has become a daily barrage of negative news stories and new allegations, are expected to ask that the committee begin the trial-like hearing immediately. <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> has said the hearing would probably take more than a week. The panel then would rule on whether the charges have been proved with clear and convincing evidence, and could recommend sanctions to the full House. The House is free to accept, reject or modify the recommendation, but many lawmakers say it is most likely that the chamber would simply accept whatever the ethics panel suggests.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     05-22 0860</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,860</SECOND>
<HEAD>Profits Predicted for `Foundation Herds'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> analysis shows that farmers and ranchers with cow-calf operations, the foundation herds that form the bedrock of the nation's beef business, will probably make money again this year. But the detailed figures by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> include some sour notes regarding capital improvements that could affect the long-term financial health of the cattle industry. The analysis also includes some mixed outlook figures for hog producers, who saw market prices drop sharply last year. Even sheep producers are feeling a pinch. If only cash flow is considered, the cow-calf operators are in pretty good shape, economists <PERSON> Hosein </PERSON> <PERSON> Shakpouri </PERSON> and <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON> said in their report. But when costs of capital replacement are included, the situation is much less encouraging. The report compares estimated 1988 production costs and net returns with those projected for 1989. Last year's drought `` severely affected'' all livestock producers, the report said. Spending on feed jumped 28 percent from 1987, while gross cash receipts from livestock sales increased only 3 percent. On the average, the `` gross value of production'' of one beef cow totaled $ 348.18 in 1988. That was up from $ 313.70 in 1987. The projection for 1989 is $ 346.06 per cow. The values were construed by including allowances for calves and culled cows, and converting them to a one-cow figure. Cash expenses, ranging from feed to taxes, insurance and interest, also were prorated on a one-cow basis. Those added up to $ 296.77 last year, up from $ 255.84 in 1987. The projection for 1989 is $ 306.26 per cow. Thus, after deducting cash expenses from gross values, the cow-calf operator this year may have an average cash return of $ 39.80 per cow, down from $ 50.46 in 1988 and $ 57.86 in 1987, the report showed. But if an allowance for capital replacement of buildings, equipment and other facilities is included, the tidy per-cow net `` profit'' disappears. In this case, the report said, the operator could lose an average of $ 41.79 per cow in 1989, compared with losses of $ 26.69 in 1988 and $ 17.72 in 1987. `` Cash returns, before and after a charge for the replacement capital, are key indicators of producer supply response,'' the report said. `` A positive cash return is an incentive for producers to continue or even expand their operation; a negative cash return is often regarded as a signal to discontinue production.'' However, the report added, the figures are averages, and there are producers who fare better or worse. Some individual operators may expand when most do not. Also, they can make substitutions in production items in different proportions than allowed in the analysis. The cash return, or residual, reflects the cash flow available for paying family living expenses, repaying debts and replacing machinery, equipment and buildings. `` In the short-term, producers may defer machinery and equipment purchases or repairs if the farm is producing little income or is in an unfavorable tax position,'' the report said. `` But over the long run, operators must replace and maintain the buildings and equipment typically used in the operation.'' The report said the projected decline in net returns to cow-calf operators this year is `` due primarily to higher wintering expenses.'' Higher feed costs and a small increase in the market price of fed beef `` would lower the price cattle feeders can pay for feeder cattle'' in 1989, which will help depress cow-calf returns. Looking at the hog situation, the report said farrow-to-finish operators, who account for about 80 percent of the slaughter hogs produced, saw 1988 gross value of production drop to an equivalent of $ 42.87 per 100 pounds from $ 51.30 per hundredweight in 1987. This year's value was projected at $ 41.23. Cash expenses, meanwhile, jumped to $ 41.64 per hundredweight in 1988 from $ 34.07 in 1987. This year cash expenses were projected at an equivalent of $ 44.44 per hundredweight. Consequently, last year's cash return to farrow-to-finish operators averaged $ 1.23 per hundredweight, down from $ 17.23 in 1987. This year, hog farmers are expected to lose $ 3.21 per hundredweight. After allowing for capital replacement, hog producers lost $ 5.89 per hundredweight in 1988, compared with a profit of $ 10.34 in 1987. This year's loss was shown at $ 10.64 per hundredweight. `` Sheep production has consistently been one of the most profitable livestock enterprises in the past 18 years,'' the report said. `` Nevertheless, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sheep producers experienced a sharp decline in their cash returns in 1988 as sheep production increased. Higher feed costs, as well as lower lamb prices eroded their financial positions.'' The average value of sheep production 1988 was reported at $ 65.56 per ewe in 1988, down from $ 73.05 in 1987. The value for 1989 was projected at $ 63.98 per ewe. Cash expenses were $ 46.38 in 1988, $ 44.66 in 1987 and projected at $ 47.67 in 1989. As a result, net cash returns averaged $ 19.18 per ewe in 1988, compared with $ 28.39 in 1987 and a 1989 return projected at $ 16.31. With allowances for capital replacement, sheep producers were shown at a profit of $ 11.12 per ewe in 1988 and $ 20.60 in 1987. The projection for 1989 was $ 7.90 per ewe.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TeachingGeography     05-22 0439</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Teaching Geography,0452</SECOND>
<HEAD>12-Year-Olds Map the World From Memory</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SONNI EFRON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Last September, <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> thought <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> was a blob on the eastern tip of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Last week, the 12-year-old could draw a map of the world _ from memory. For more than a decade, <ORGANIZATION> Shady </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> teacher <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> has been sending seventh-grade geography whizzes into a society where, according to a recent Gallup Poll, one in seven Americans ca n't find the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on a map of the world. `` You ca n't get anywhere underestimating the ability of a seventh-grader,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. `` They can accomplish enormous things if you set them a task they can break into manageable pieces.'' Without consulting an atlas, this spring's crop of pupils has already outlined the continents with startling accuracy. On <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON>'s map, the sinuous curve of the <LOCATION> Americas </LOCATION>, the Scandinavian hump, even the six states of <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> were correctly proportioned on a Mercator grid. Now she is filling in countries, cities, mountains, and rivers, even adding the names of Soviet republics. At 12, <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> is trying to remember facts that would stump most college pupils: whether <LOCATION> Wellington </LOCATION> is the capital of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>, and whether to put it on the island's north or south. `` The hardest part is <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION>, and all the little islands on the top of <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>,'' she said. At the beginning of the school year, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> hands his pupils a blank sheet of paper and asks them to draw everything they know about the world. Most of the sheets are returned with little more than vague circles and squiggles. The problem is n't limited to younger students. A 1988 Gallup Poll commissioned by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Geographic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> found Americans ages 18 to 24 knew less about the world than their counterparts in nine countries. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> keeps those embarrassing first efforts so pupils can proudly compare them to their memory maps at year's end. He teaches geography at the approximate rate of a continent every two weeks. At the end of the year, students spend six weeks making practice maps and three weeks creating their memory maps. Some children who rarely speak in class produce maps so beautiful that their parents frame them, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. Though Shady <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> is a private school, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> thinks his teaching method would work elsewhere if educators allot the subject enough time. `` It's important that they know about <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s place in the world,'' he said. `` But what's really important is that it's a nine-month project in an age of instant gratification. They leave here with a sense of what they're capable of.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Wright-Charges     05-22 0395</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wright-Charges,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Wright Probe Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, was charged April 17 by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee with 69 instances of violating <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> rules, and new allegations have since arisen in news reports. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> denies having committed ethical violations. Here is a rundown on the charges: BOOK SALES _ The ethics committee charged that on seven occasions, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> sold bulk quantities of his book, `` Reflections of a Public Man,'' to groups to which he had given speeches. The panel contends that <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> improperly disguised speaking fees, which are limited under the rules, as royalties, which are not. LEGISLATIVE INTEREST _ The committee charged that <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> real estate developer <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mallick </PERSON>, by virtue of his extensive financial holdings, had a direct interest in legislation before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. That would make benefits <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and his wife received from <PERSON> Mallick </PERSON> from 1979 to 1988, totaling $ 145,000, improper under the rules. GIFT REPORTING _ The committee charged that the benefits, including Mrs. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s $ 18,000-a-year salary from 1979 through 1984, and use of a 1979 Cadillac and a <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> condominium, were not reported as gifts on <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s annual financial disclosure form, as required. <LOCATION> SABINE </LOCATION> <LOCATION> LAKE </LOCATION> _ Ethics investigators are still looking into whether <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> received improper proceeds from a 1988 investment in a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> gas drilling venture. Known as the <LOCATION> Sabine </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prospect </LOCATION>, the venture yielded <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s blind trust a quick $ 170,000 profit, even though the well has so far proven dry. <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaffe </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> businessman who arranged the investment, is seeking to sell training aircraft to the Pentagon. <ORGANIZATION> JEWELL </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> ENTERPRISES </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> borrowed $ 100,000 to invest in a now-defunct business that bought and sold nursing homes. Although he ultimately lost his money, at one point he reportedly received $ 23,000 in dividends unavailable to other investors, and got help paying the interest on his loan. The ethics panel still is examining the transactions. <LOCATION> PACIFIC </LOCATION> <LOCATION> INSTITUTE </LOCATION> _ Former employees of a <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, firm that sells motivational programs say <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s wife <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> did little or no work for the $ 36,000 salary she received from 1985 to 1988. Her boss at the time insists she performed satisfactorily. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> used the Congressional Record to print a glowing endorsement of a videotape his wife had helped produce for the firm. The ethics panel is believed to be taking a look at these events, as well.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush     05-22 0751</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Says NATO Dispute Could be Settled Pre-Summit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says the dispute over short-range nuclear weapons that has split <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> could be resolved before next week's 40th-anniversary meeting of the alliance. `` I think great progress has been made'' in efforts to reconcile U.S.-West German differences over possible negotiations on the missiles, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Sunday during a joint news conference in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> with <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>. `` I think that we could well have this resolved before the summit,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. Still, the dispute remains a `` vexing question'' and `` there are strong-willed people from strong countries, and they each have an opinion,'' he said after he and <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> gave back-to-back commencement speeches at <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` One way to guarantee there will not be progress is to lock each other in, in public statements,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> added. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, after first opposing <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>'s suggestions for early U.S.-Soviet talks on reducing short-range missiles in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, has sent a counterproposal to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> agreeing to accept such talks in principle in the future, according to Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>. However, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> first wants to see the Soviets reduce their conventional-force edge, a position <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> reiterated Sunday. In his commencement address, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said that `` though hope is now running high for a more peaceful continent, the history of this century teaches Americans and Europeans to remain prepared.'' <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>, who has generally agreed with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> position, said his role was not that of a mediator between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> on the issue. `` Obviously, I'd be happy if views can be reconciled and I believe, I think, that they can be reconciled,'' he said. <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>, in response to a question, refused to agree with a statement last week by White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> that Soviet Leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was acting in a `` drugstore cowboy fashion'' in making a succession of arms-control proposals. `` I think that one must be wary of caricatures. Mr. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is worth very much more than that,'' <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> said. In his own commencement speech, delivered in French and translated in segments to an estimated audience of 31,000 in <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Nickerson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Field </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> praised <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> along with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and former President <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for their combined efforts to reduce the world's arsenal of nuclear weapons. <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> also called for all nations to join in framing `` an emergency plan to save the environment. ... The death of the environment is our death,'' he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, at the news conference, said: `` I heard his clarion call for cooperative action on the environment, and I salute him for that.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had entertained <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> at his oceanside vacation home in <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, for the weekend. After the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> appearances, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> bade the <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> leader farewell at a military departure ceremony at <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> boarded his <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> France </ORGANIZATION> supersonic Concorde for the return trip to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> then traveled to <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, where he visited his ailing 87-year-old mother, <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, for about an hour and a half. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is recovering from a mild stroke. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> returned to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Sunday evening. In <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> met with his vanquished 1988 Democratic presidential challenger, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. The two shook hands at a pre-commencement reception. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, applauded vigorously by the hometown audience when he was introduced later in the stadium, also shared the dais with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> during the commencement ceremonies. In his commencement speech, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was sharply critical of recent comments by Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> that the Soviets' `` commitment to destroy SS-23 missiles under the -LRB- 1987 treaty to eliminate medium-range nuclear weapons -RRB- may be reversible.'' `` The Soviets must surely know the results of failure to comply with this solemn agreement. Perhaps their purpose was to divide the West on other issues. Regardless, it is clear that Soviet ` new thinking' has not yet totally overcome the old,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> made the comments in response to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> proposals to upgrade and extend the range of the American-built Lance short-range missiles, which are not covered by the treaty on intermediate-range missiles. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has consulted with the government of <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> to come up with an agreement with <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> that would avoid a clash over the short-range missile flap at the May 29-30 <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> meeting. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, like the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, has strongly opposed East-West talks on cutting <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s nuclear battlefield weapons at this time.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0154EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Cardinal-AIDSClasses     05-22 0394</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cardinal-AIDS Classes,0404</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boston Cardinal Urges Students to Skip AIDS Classes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Roman Catholic cardinal said an AIDS education program in the <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> public schools will increase students' risk of getting the disease, and has urged parents not to allow their children to participate. In a letter read at weekend Masses in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> parishes, Cardinal <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Law </PERSON> said the lessons planned for students in seventh throught 12th grades over the next six weeks `` could place our children in danger, both moral and physical.'' `` The curriculum presents various issues of sexual behavior in a valueless, amoral context,'' Law wrote. `` It admits a permissiveness in sexual behavior which is not acceptable to a great many citizens of the city, is certainly unacceptable for Catholics and which increases the children's risk of gettting AIDS.'' The schools plan to offer two 45-minute lessons stressing abstinence and shunning intravenous drug use as the best way to prevent AIDS. Instructors will tell students who are sexually active to use condoms. Parents who object may exempt their children from the classes. Law warned that `` students as young as 13 will ... be given explicit instructions in the use of condoms. Sexual abstinence can not be taught if at the same time detailed directions on how to use condoms are presented as an alternative.'' He said the archdiocese will offer its own `` value-centered'' AIDS education program this summer. Some school leaders disagreed with Law's evaluation of the program. `` It is fine for him to take moral positions, but young people have not abstained from sexual activity,'' said School Superintendent <PERSON> Laval </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>. `` That's the reality we deal with in the public schools.'' `` They are not all Catholic, but Protestants, Jewish, Buddhists,'' said <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> McGuire </PERSON>, a school committee member. `` They have a right to know how to protect themselves from any sexually transmitted disease.'' A Protestant leader, the Rev. <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, pastor of the <ORGANIZATION> Columbus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Avenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> A.M.E. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> and chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ecumenical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, said that like <PERSON> Cardinal </PERSON> <PERSON> Law </PERSON>, he was concerned that `` parts of the curriculum send a mixed message to young people.'' `` But the cardinal's position fails to take into consideration the fact that the problem already exists,'' he added. Two years ago, a plan for pilot school health clinics that could have prescribed birth control devices was derailed by political and religious foes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-VineyardSkunks Bjt   05-22 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Vineyard Skunks, Bjt,0671</SECOND>
<HEAD>Martha's Vineyard Residents Don't Know What's Worse: Tourists or
Skunks.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN GALVIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TISBURY, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's springtime on <PERSON> Martha </PERSON>'s Vineyard and the locals are girding for what's become an annual influx of arrogant, offensive pests who walk the streets at night and hang out at restaurants. It's not tourists. It's skunks. Hordes of the `` black cats with white tails'' have inhabited the island, taking up residence under houses, rummaging through restaurant garbage, intimidating vacationers, terrorizing pets and, frankly, stinking up the place. `` They're really bold and brassy. You can see them on the main streets, you can see them walking around anywhere,'' said <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodale </PERSON>, animal control officer for the Vineyard Haven section of town. `` If you're fishing at night, they'll just come right up to you.'' Dead fish along the shore, ground nesting birds and plenty of woods make the island an ideal habitat for skunks. And state wildlife officials and animal control officers in the island's six towns say their telephones do n't stop ringing in the springtime when baby skunks are born and the warm weather makes the beasts more active. <PERSON> Fin </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> was the man many residents hired from 1982 until his retirement in 1987 to rid their property of the raccoons, skunks and feral cats that were giving them headaches. During that five-year period, he said, he trapped nearly 500 skunks. Another trapper was said to have caught about 300 a year during the period. `` I found they're partial to <ORGANIZATION> Devil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dogs </ORGANIZATION> and Twinkies. People used to call it junk food but I used to call it skunk food,'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. `` I could catch a skunk on any place, except the Presbyterian church steeple. They have n't gotten up there yet.'' Many islanders swear that, at least since Colonial times, no skunks were on the island before the late 1950s. How they returned to <PERSON> Martha </PERSON>'s Vineyard is a touchy matter involving old allegations that have flourished into local lore. Legend has it that the skunk population was revived when Vineyard Haven native <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Kingsbury </PERSON> brought two unscented skunks _ one male and one female _ and set them free to roam with the oxen, cattle and goats on his farm some 30 years ago. <PERSON> Kingsbury </PERSON>, 77, swears it's not true. He blames vacationers for bringing baby skunks and raccoons over as pets and abandoning them on the island when the cuddly critters got big and nasty. The old farmer said he was accused by his neighbors because a family of abandoned skunks took up residence on his property. `` The skunks moved in on my farm and I did n't bother them, kill them, or have a fit over them. I just left them alone,'' he said, and laughed at the typical city vacationer's fear of wildlife. `` Anything bigger than a field mouse puts them in a trauma.'' But the rumors persist. `` For some reason there's always a dead skunk in front of his house. If you do n't see them, you can smell them,'' <PERSON> Goodale </PERSON> said. The 100-square-mile island has few predators to control the skunk population. `` They only have one natural enemy, and that has four wheels,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Kazlauskas </PERSON>, operations manager of the island's trash disposal agency. <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> of the state's <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> said the problem is really part-skunk and part-people. She said if residents could learn to cap their garbage, close up basement windows and not bother the skunks people could coexist with the mammals. Wildlife workers occasionally are called to come to the aid of a skunk found stumbling along with a head trapped in a yogurt container or jelly jar. But more often, they get complaints. <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>' favorite comes from people who call to say their dog was sprayed while he was out running around the neighborhood. `` They violate the leash law, their dog gets sprayed, and they want me to kill the skunk,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0203EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Marcos     05-22 0323</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Marcos,0334</SECOND>
<HEAD>Marcos Remains In Very Critical Condition</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Marcos Exile</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVE ELLIOTT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Family and friends of <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> were heartened by news that the former <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> president was alert and responding to medication, an aide said. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> continued to rally on Sunday, said a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, stressing that his condition remained very critical. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, 71, was undergoing kidney dialysis, had a respirator to help him breathe and was hooked up to a monitoring system, said <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Tiwanak </PERSON>, the hospital's assistant adminstrator. <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Aruiza </PERSON>, a top aide who has been with <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> much of the time since a surgical procedure was performed Thursday to prepare him for dialysis, said <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> has shown the will to live. `` The will to fight, the determination, he has that,'' <PERSON> Aruiza </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> is able to mouth words to his doctors and family, and responds with a smile when his wife, <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON>, and children, <PERSON> Irene </PERSON> <PERSON> Araneta </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, hold his hand and speak to him, <PERSON> Aruiza </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> was alert and conscious and seemed to be responding to medication to fight a bacterial infection, <PERSON> Tiwanak </PERSON> said. But he added: `` I did n't say he improved. I said his condition is such that he appears to be rallying, but I'm cautioning always that it's very episodic and can drop _ just as I'm standing here, it can get worse.'' <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> still has a fever, but not as high as a few days ago, <PERSON> Tiwanak </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Aruiza </PERSON> said cautious optimism had replaced some of the despair that prevailed Thursday. `` Even the hospital wanted to know our arrangements for the body then,'' <PERSON> Aruiza </PERSON> said. `` They said their morgue could only keep a body for a certain number of days. It was very morbid.'' <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> and his wife have lived in exile in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> since fleeing the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> in February 1986 after a civilian revolution swept <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> to power.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0218EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stock     05-22 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stock,0025</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Up In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 34,067.86, up 65.90 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Monday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0234EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Bush-Excerpts     05-22 0587</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush-Excerpts,570</SECOND>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are excerpts from the joint news conference Sunday by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and French President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>: BUSH ON <LOCATION> CHINA </LOCATION>:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 `` We do support freedom of speech, freedom of assembly, freedom of the press, and clearly, we support democracy. I do n't want to be gratuitous in giving advice, but I would encourage restraint. I do not want to see bloodshed. We revere the model of <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> in this country for his peaceful protest, and so I might suggest a familiarization with that for the people in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, and I would urge the government to be as forthcoming as possible in order to see more democratization and to see a peaceful resolution of this matter. `` We have been in touch with our ambassador on this very key question. I think this perhaps is a time for caution, because we aspire to see the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> people have democracy, but we do not exhort in a way that is going to stir up a military confrontation. We do not want to have a situation like happened in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>, or some other place. And so, as we counsel restraint, and as we counsel peaceful means of effecting change, that is sound advice. And I think to go beyond that and encourage steps that could lead to bloodshed would be inappropriate. `` I do n't think that it would be appropriate for the President of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to say to the demonstrators and the students in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> exactly what their course of action should be. That is for them to determine. They know the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' commitment to democracy, to the commitment to freedom, to the aspiration we have that all people will live in democratic societies. But I'm not about to suggest what I think they ought to do except to spell out: peaceful, and continue to fight for what you believe in, stand up for what you believe in, but ... beyond that, I can not go. `` There's certainly an enormous expression on the part of many people -- students and others -- for change, for movement toward democracy. I lived there. I saw a society totally different than the one that exists in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> today. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has moved in some areas towards democracy. Now, the quest is, and the appeal from these kids, is to move further ... But I am not going to dictate, or try to say from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, how this matter should be resolved by these students. I'm not going to do it.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 ON RESOLVING THE <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> DISPUTE OVER SHORT-RANGE MISSILES:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>: `` I think that we have now the elements of ideas that could form a decision that will be taken just in a week's time And I think that the decision that will be taken will be found positive from the point of view of all members of the alliance ... The important thing is that the unity of the -- the general interest of the alliance should prevail, and it will.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: `` I think great progress has been made ... We are in active consultation with the Germans and others ... I think that we could well have this resolved before the summit. `` There are strong-willed people from strong countries, and they each have an opinion. But my role has been to try, behind the scenes, to be helpful for working this problem out. And I should salute the President of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> as he has tried to be extraordinarily helpful in working this problem out.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0235EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bush'sSister     05-22 0259</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush's Sister,0266</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Bush's Sister Suffers Minor Mishap on the Way Graduation
Ceremony</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Bush-China, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LESLIE DREYFOUS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s sister injured three police officers in a minor car accident en route to hear her brother speak at <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s commencement. The officers had been directing <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> to a parking area Sunday morning near the campus where 30,000 graduates and their families were gathering to hear <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and French President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> deliver the keynote addresses. Mrs. <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> stopped to talk to the officers after she encountered a roadblock. She put the car in reverse and the car suddenly lurched backward and struck the officers, police said. `` One officer was hit in the knee with the car's fender, another was hit by the door as it flung open, and a third was swept back about 10 feet by the door itself,'' said <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Orlando </PERSON>, a police spokeswoman. Mrs. <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON>' <ORGANIZATION> Audi </ORGANIZATION> sedan then bashed into a police truck stationed at the roadblock, <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION> said. Two of the officers sustained minor cuts and bruises and the one who was swept back 10 feet sustained minor head and neck injuries, <PERSON> Orlando </PERSON> said. All three men were treated at a hospital and released. Investigating officers reported there was no apparent negligence on the part of Mrs. <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> and no charges were filed, <PERSON> Orlando </PERSON> said. `` All's well that ends well, so to speak,'' she said. Mrs. <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> did not answer a message left on the telephone answering machine at her suburban <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> home.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890522-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-22-89 0251EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BushCommencement     05-22 0479</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush Commencement,0495</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush-Mitterrand A Mixed Blessing for BU Graduates</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Bush-China, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANA KENNEDY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
