<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-89 2356EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Dinkins-Stock 1stLd-Writethru a0835 12-03 0545</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dinkins-Stock, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0835,0559</SECOND>
<HEAD>Newspaper: U.S. Attorney Probes Dinkins Stock</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 9 grafs to UPDATE with Dinkins' reax. Picks up 8th
graf pvs, `Inner City...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal prosecutors are investigating a controversial transaction through which Mayor-elect <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> said he transferred stock to his son, the Daily News reported Sunday. The probe by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Maloney </PERSON>'s office is part of a larger inquiry into a cable television franchise related to <ORGANIZATION> Inner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, the News quoted unidentified law enforcement sources as saying. Investigators are trying to determine whether <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> transferred <LOCATION> Inner </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> stock to his son, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, through a genuine transaction in 1985; how much it was worth and whether taxes were fully paid, the News said. <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON>' spokesman, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Fishlow </PERSON>, said the mayor-elect had hired a criminal attorney, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Stillman </PERSON>. `` I'm confident this inquiry will reveal that there's nothing with which I need to be concerned,'' <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> told reporters Sunday. `` Those of us in public life are subject to criticism and scrutiny of all sorts over time.'' <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> said the federal investigation is a response to a suggestion by his opponent, Republican <PERSON> Rudolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON>, that the stock deal be looked into. `` My marching order from Mr. <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> is 1,000 percent cooperation,'' <PERSON> Stillman </PERSON> told the News. `` We want to put this thing to bed once and for all.'' <PERSON> Stillman </PERSON>, however, also described the investigation as `` <PERSON> Rudy </PERSON> <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON>'s last hurrah.'' <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON>, a Democrat, defeated <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON> last month following a campaign highlighted by questions about <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON>' finances. <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON> is a former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney for <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Maloney </PERSON> is <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney for <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>. Inner City owns a number of radio stations and one of its subsidiaries has a substantial interest in the Queens Innerunity Cable Systems franchise. Its chairman, former <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> Borough President President <PERSON> Percy </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutton </PERSON>, is a longtime friend of <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> first acquired stock in the privately held company in 1972. His holdings grew to 588 shares, largely, he has said, through stock splits. <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> said he transferred the stock to his son after his election as <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> borough president in 1985 to avoid a conflict between his position on the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estimate </ORGANIZATION> and the board's role in regulating cable television. It was assumed at the time that he gave the shares to his son as a gift. During the mayoral campaign, it was revealed that <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> had not paid a gift tax. <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> released a handwritten note dated Oct. 30, 1985, in which his son agreed to buy the stock, promising to pay $ 58,000 in 1991 plus 8 percent interest a year. <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON>, his son and <PERSON> Sutton </PERSON> then declined to release financial or corporate records that might further document the transaction as described. The News said the investigation includes testing the paper and the ink in the note to determine whether it was written in 1985 or during the campaign. There also are plans to analyze the handwriting. <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> once placed the stock's worth at $ 1 million on a financial disclosure form. But during the campaign he said he had done so in error, based on an inflated appraisal by <PERSON> Sutton </PERSON>. The city Department of Investigation is conducting a separate, previously disclosed investigation into whether <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> filed misleading financial disclosure forms regarding the stock.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-89 0218EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i Nicaragua-US     12-03 0176</FIRST>
<SECOND>Nicaragua-US,0183</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Congressmen Protest Nicaragua Entry Denial</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four members of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> congressional delegation criticized <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> Saturday after they were denied entry by that country's leftist government to observe its elections. Rep. G.V. <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON>, D-Miss., a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> `` stuck its foot in its mouth. Also denied entry were Rep. <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON>, D-Ga.; <PERSON> Dana </PERSON> <PERSON> Rohrabacher </PERSON>, R-Calif., and <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, The four are part of a 20-member delegation named by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to inspect preparations for the Feb. 25 elections. Nicaraguan President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> blocked their entry, saying they were not impartial observers because they had been appointed by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The group came to <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION> after they were denied Nicaraguan visas. <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s elections are part of a Central American peace plan that also calls for the disbanding of U.S.-supported Nicaraguan rebels known as Contras. The congressmen planned to spend two days in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> visiting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces based at <LOCATION> Palmerola </LOCATION>, 40 miles from <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION>, and Contra camps in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> near the border with <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-03-89 0023AET</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BoatSinks 2ndLd-Writethru a0674 12-03 0431</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Boat Sinks, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0674,0440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nineteen Rescued After Fishing Boat Sinks Near Entrance to New York
Harbor</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES throughout with two dead, quotes from captain, other
details, edits to tighten; no pickup</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A charter fishing boat with 19 people aboard sank near the entrance to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> Saturday, killing two men and injuring at least 16 other people, authorities said. All 19 people aboard were pulled from the frigid waters within two hours of the sinking, which was reported at about 3:30 p.m., <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> officials said. Captain <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Chale </PERSON> said the 110-foot <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Queen </LOCATION> was in 40 feet of water `` when we hit something, hit a submerged object. Whatever it was, I have no idea. I never saw it. `` Soon as I seen I had trouble, I called the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> immediately,'' <PERSON> Chale </PERSON> said. The boat began taking on water right away. One of those rescued, an unidentified man in his 50s, died hours later at <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION> <LOCATION> General </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> borough of <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION>, said Sgt. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Wrensen </PERSON>, a city police spokesowoman. The man's body temperature had dropped to 81 degrees and he suffered cardiac arrest, hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Perlman </PERSON> said. Another man, also unidentified and also said to be in his 50s, died at <ORGANIZATION> Monmouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Branch </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Scheideler </PERSON>, a nursing supervisor there. Fifteen other people were taken to two <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> hospitals, and a 16th was at Peninsula General in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Chale </PERSON> declined hospital treatment, said <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Petty Officer <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Henderson </PERSON>. He was taken to the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> station at <LOCATION> Sandy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hook </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, for questioning, <PERSON> Henderson </PERSON> said. The Bronx Queen went down near Ambrose Light, between <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> and about 15 miles southeast of the Verrazano Narrows Bridge spanning the entrance to the harbor, said Lt. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> operations center in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. `` The seas were very rough when we got on the scene,'' said Petty Officer <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Pechacek </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Sandy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hook </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, station. `` As we approached, we could see about 30 feet of the boat still above water and all the people were on the bow,'' <PERSON> Pechacek </PERSON> said. Petty Officer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Belloni </PERSON> said people starting jumping off the bow as the rescue vessels approached. Coast Guard boats from <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hook </PERSON> and helicopters from <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> May </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, participated in the rescue, <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON> said. `` They basically launched everything they could,'' he said. The water temperature in the harbor was 48 degrees, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-03-89 0033AET</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Comaneci 3rdLd-Writethru a0636 12-03 0812</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Comaneci, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0636,0832</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nadia's First Day of Freedom: Where Is She?</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: RECASTS lead to show Comaneci's first day in U.S. sted first
day of freedom; SUBS 19th graf, `Karolyi, who...' to UPDATE with 8 grafs
with later comment from gymnastics federation official on Comaneci's plans;
no pickup</HEAD>
<HEAD>A version moved on sports wires.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANNE MARIE CALZOLARI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Asociated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After four days of hiding out in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, Olympic gold medalist <PERSON> Nadia </PERSON> <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> spent her first full day of freedom in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on Saturday doing the same thing. The 28-year-old Romanian gymnast, who burst into prominence with her run of perfect 10s in the 1976 Olympics, slipped out of sight Friday following a brief news conference shortly after her arrival at <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> F. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airport </ORGANIZATION>. `` I wanted to have a free life,'' said <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON>, who was guaranteed political asylum here, and on Saturday that included staying out of the limelight generated by her defection. <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> reportedly spent Friday night in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, but there were varying reports about her whereabouts Saturday. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gymnastics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Patti </PERSON> <PERSON> Auer </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> told a federation official that <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> was headed to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> on Saturday afternoon on a <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> flight. But the captain of the flight <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> was scheduled to take said she had canceled her plans. `` <PERSON> Nadia </PERSON> was to be with us on our flight but ... she decided to stay in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>,'' said pilot <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> <PERSON> Gosheff </PERSON>. `` At the last minute, they said she's not coming.'' <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Timper </PERSON> said the airline _ which carried <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> _ had no reservations out of JFK under the gymnast's name. Reporters at <LOCATION> JFK </LOCATION> when the Miami-bound flight was due to board did not see her and <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Authority </LOCATION> police, who patrol the sprawling airport, said they were n't aware of her plans. <PERSON> Auer </PERSON> said <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> `` has not contacted us, and we'd like to know what her plans are.'' <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> press officer <PERSON> Sondra </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarty </PERSON> said her agency was not providing any information on <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON>. In addition to the report that <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> was heading to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, there were reports after her arrival here that she might go to <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> is where the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION> Gymnastics Federation is based, while <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON>'s former Romanian coach, <PERSON> Bela </PERSON> <PERSON> Karoly </PERSON>, now is a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen and runs an elite gymnastics training camp north of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. Another Romanian exile, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Boularca </PERSON> of <PERSON> Davie </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, said that <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> was coming to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> to stay with <PERSON> Konstantin </PERSON> <PERSON> Panit </PERSON> and his family. Panit accompanied <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> at her news conference Friday; he lives with his wife and three children in a community of Romanians in south <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> was 14 years old when she gained worldwide fame by becoming the first gymnast ever to score a perfect 10 at the Olympics _ an achievement she repeated seven times at the 1976 games. She won 21 gold medals altogether in Olympic and other international meets during her career, earning a life of privilege in her hard-line Communist homeland. <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> _ accompanied by six fellow Romanians _ crossed the border into <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> on Tuesday and went into hiding. She told a border guard she was leaving <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> `` for the sake of freedom.'' <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, unlike other Eastern European countries, has resisted the recent trend toward political and personal liberty for its residents. <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> would be eligible to apply for permanent resident status in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in one year, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said. <PERSON> Karolyi </PERSON>, who was in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> last week, said Friday that he planned to return to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> this weekend and hoped to meet up with <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON>, perhaps in <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacki </PERSON>, the gymnastics federation's executive director, said late Saturday that he understood <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> would initially stay in a Romanian immigrant neighborhood in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. `` I'm anticipating that she'll be there as long as she needs to be there,'' <PERSON> Jacki </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jacki </PERSON> said <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> has been granted refugee status and now needs to select a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen as a sponsor. `` Regardless of where she ends up, at least in the immediate future, we are hopeful to have dialogue with her and give her some advice and guidance,'' he said. `` I'd hate to have her make a decision that would be without that guidance. This is <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, and we want her to like it here and a have a positive and honest experience in everything she does.'' He said among her options would be working for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> federation, `` or public relations, or be a candidate for the international federation. As a coach, she could touch many athletes.'' <PERSON> Jacki </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Terry </PERSON>, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indianapolis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> is welcome to stay with her and her husband, adding, `` I think she kind of wants to stay here awhile.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-03-89 0057AET</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HUD-Pierce     12-03 0343</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-HUD-Pierce,0354</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Pierce Awarded HUD Grant To Friend Despite Protests</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former federal housing secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> awarded a $ 350,000 grant to a longtime friend although other housing officials had rejected the project, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported. The 1985 grant was awarded to <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Singletary </PERSON>, a Republican who helped direct <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s unsuccessful campaigns for election as a <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> judge in 1959 and 1960, the Times reported in its Sunday editions. <PERSON> DuBois </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilliam </PERSON>, a former <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> aide, told the Times that <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> ordered him to give the grant to <PERSON> Singletary </PERSON> even though others at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> opposed it on the ground that <PERSON> Singletary </PERSON>'s firm had too little experience. `` I think it was a case where there was a longterm friendship between <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> and <PERSON> Singletary </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Gilliam </PERSON>, who is serving an 18-month prison sentence after pleading guilty to conspiracy charges involving other <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> grants. <PERSON> Gilliam </PERSON> said <PERSON> Singletary </PERSON> repeatedly called <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> about <PERSON> Singletary </PERSON>'s Washington-based consulting firm, the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resource </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> `` told me he wanted us to help <PERSON> Singletary </PERSON> get some money _ he said <PERSON> Singletary </PERSON> is a good guy,'' <PERSON> Gilliam </PERSON> told the Times. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said through a lawyer, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Plotkin </PERSON>, that he did not remember the grant to <PERSON> Singletary </PERSON>. Even if he had ordered it, there would not have been anything improper about it, the lawyer said. `` This was a discretionary fund. This was his absolute right and authority,'' <PERSON> Plotkin </PERSON> told the Times. <PERSON> Singletary </PERSON> told the Times that he met with <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> several times but said he never discussed the grant. `` Are you asking me if <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> did me a favor? Absolutely not,'' <PERSON> Singletary </PERSON> said. The Times said <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> records indicate that <PERSON> Singletary </PERSON>'s group was supposed to use the grant to assist the cities of <LOCATION> Camden </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> in programs to attract private development money to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. In recent months, <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, citing his Fifth Amendment right against self incrimination, has refused to cooperate with congressional inquiries into political favoritism and fraud at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Administration.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-89 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-US-Philippines 1stLd-Writethru a0682 12-03 0317</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Philippines, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0682,310</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reports: Philippines Asked For US Air Attacks on Rebel Targets</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES throughout with second newspaper report; no pickup</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Philippine government asked for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warplanes to attack rebel targets to help put down the latest military coup attempt against President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s government, two newspapers reported in their Sunday editions The `` urgent'' requests, which the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration refused late Thursday, were made by <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> through military and intelligence channels, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported, citing a variety of unnamed administration sources. The Los Angeles Times, also citing an anonymous source, reported that the <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> government asked that American planes bomb rebel-held air bases, fuel dumps and a seaborne freighter. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Manilla </LOCATION> received telephone calls from Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> and another senior defense official, the Times said. The requests were numerous and confused, making it difficult for Gen. <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION>, to sort them out, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. The request for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> planes to bomb some positions was turned down because Americans may have been on bases commandeered by the rebels and out of concern for the political impact of direct <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intervention, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> F-4 fighter-bombers flew cover for government troops on Friday and early Saturday morning but were idle on Sunday and never fired a shot at ground targets, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said. According to earlier administration accounts, the jets were not deployed until Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> made a formal request through <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Platt </PERSON>. The Times said <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> `` wanted the fuel dumps and an armored column'' to come under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attack. <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> called for attacks on the air bases to disable rebel-controlled aircraft on the ground. The Philippine military official, who was not identified, wanted the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> to attack the freighter believed to be carrying munitions or reinforcements for the rebels.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-89 0216EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Nicaragua-US     12-03 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua-US,0188</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING a0683 to RESTORE cycle designator</HEAD>
<HEAD>U.S. Congressmen Protest Nicaragua Entry Denial</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four members of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> congressional delegation criticized <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> Saturday after they were denied entry by that country's leftist government to observe its elections. Rep. G.V. <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON>, D-Miss., a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> `` stuck its foot in its mouth. Also denied entry were Rep. <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON>, D-Ga.; <PERSON> Dana </PERSON> <PERSON> Rohrabacher </PERSON>, R-Calif., and <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, The four are part of a 20-member delegation named by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to inspect preparations for the Feb. 25 elections. Nicaraguan President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> blocked their entry, saying they were not impartial observers because they had been appointed by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The group came to <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION> after they were denied Nicaraguan visas. <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s elections are part of a Central American peace plan that also calls for the disbanding of U.S.-supported Nicaraguan rebels known as Contras. The congressmen planned to spend two days in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> visiting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces based at <LOCATION> Palmerola </LOCATION>, 40 miles from <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION>, and Contra camps in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> near the border with <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-89 0324EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-Philippines-CoupLeader     12-03 0452</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Philippines-Coup Leader,0464</SECOND>
<HEAD>Coup Leader Claims U.S. Intervention Stopped Successful Takeover</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A leader of the Philippine coup attempt said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military intervention was all that had kept President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s government from toppling and vowed to continue the insurrection, in an interview published Sunday. `` It ai n't over until it's over,'' Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Edgardo </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Abenina </PERSON> told the the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. `` We shall fight, and we shall continue fighting for what we believe in, for the honor of our nation and the dignity of our people _ even if it means going into a stage of civil war.'' Rebel soldiers battled loyalist troops in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>'s financial district and at armed forces headquarters Sunday, the third day of an attempt to overthrow <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>. <PERSON> Abenina </PERSON>, a former officer of the Philippine constabulary, said the insurgents are mostly present or former members of the Philippine armed forces and none are politicians. He described them as reform-minded nationalists. <PERSON> Abenina </PERSON> said rebels were fighting <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> to `` free the Filipinos from the shackles of poverty and subservience that have been forced upon us by the rich and powerful, by elitist governments like that of <PERSON> Cory </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>.'' He added, `` Our whole point is that, for centuries, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> have been under the mercy and control of a very few politicians and moneyed people.'' The coup, according to <PERSON> Abenina </PERSON>, has been planned for more than a year. <PERSON> Abenina </PERSON>, who <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> has identified as a rebel ring-leader, said, `` Our goal is to purge the armed forces and the political leadership of the government of the rampant corruption and patronage that has set in from the highest to the lowest levels.'' Lt. Col. <PERSON> Gregorio </PERSON> `` Gringo'' <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> is part of the coup's leadership, <PERSON> Abenina </PERSON> said <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> led an August 1987 coup attempt that left 53 dead. He was imprisoned but escaped in April 1988. <PERSON> Abenina </PERSON> also took part in the coup attempt and was jailed and later escaped. <PERSON> Abenina </PERSON> said if the coup succeeds he will establish a military-civilian governing council with himself in charge. The council would have five to seven members, exercise unchallenged executive power and include dozens of Filipino experts, technocrats and professors, <PERSON> Abenina </PERSON> said. He said the coup attempt, which began Friday, would have been successful if the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mililtary had not intervened. When President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> announced that he was extending air support to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> military, `` we were about to take over the government,'' <PERSON> Abenina </PERSON> said. `` Then the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warplanes appeared. We simply can not hope to win against the stronger power of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>.'' According to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> officials, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> F-4 fighter-bombers flew cover for loyalist troops on Friday and early Saturday morning but never fired a shot at ground targets.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-89 0358EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-US-Philippines     12-03 0326</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-US-Philippines,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Prepared To Give Aquino Government More Assistance If Needed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MARSAXLOKK BAY, Malta (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Sunday that he is prepared to take additional military action to defend the <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> government against mutinous troops if American lives are threatened or President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> requests it. In a letter to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> congressional leaders under the War Powers Act, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> formally notified <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that, at Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s request, he had ordered military support for the <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> government to prevent rebel aircraft from taking off from two air bases briefly held by the rebels The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday that the Philippine government had requested that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warplanes attack rebel targets. The <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said the request was turned down because Americans may have been on bases commandeered by the rebels and out of concern for the political impact of direct <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intervention. At least 51 people have been killed and nearly 300 wounded since the insurgents launched their attempt Friday to overthrow the Aquino government. Rebel soldiers continued to battle loyalist troops in the capital's financial district and at armed forces headquarters Sunday. In his letter to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wrote, `` At present, I do not foresee the need for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military action in addition to the measures described above. I am prepared, however, to take additional actions to protect the lives of <LOCATION> Americans </LOCATION>, should they be threatened, and, if requested, to provide further assistance to the government of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said there were no American casualties during the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> action Friday. `` No rebel aircraft attempted to take off,'' he said, `` and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aircraft did not fire.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he also had ordered a company of Marines to reinforce the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> guard in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he had acted `` in accordance with recognized principles of international law'' in backing the constitutional government of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and within his authority as president and commander-in-chief of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> armed forces.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-89 0441EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Philippines 8thLd-Writethru a0703 12-03 0921</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines, 8th Ld-Writethru, a0703,0947</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gov't Forces Crush Rebel Attack, Hundreds of Insurgents Surrender</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 8 grafs to UPDATE with hundreds more rebels surrender;
picks up 7th pvs, ``The attempted...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN GUERRERO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Government forces on Sunday repulsed an attack on military headquarters by rebel soliders seeking to topple President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, and hundreds of insurgents surrendered. However, fighting continued between loyal troops and other rebels in the country's financial center. Military officials said the failure of the rebels to capture the Camp Aguinaldo military headquarters dealt a fatal blow to the 3-day-old coup attempt. `` I will fulfill what I said _ no cease-fire. What they started, we will finish,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> said in a national radio address. At least 51 people have been killed and nearly 300 wounded since the insurgents launched their revolt Friday. Rebels bombarded the military headquarters at <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aguinaldo </LOCATION> early Sunday with 105mm howitzers, and government jet fighters and helicopter gunships attacked the mutineers' positions. The military said the rebels also launched a ground attack on Camp Aquinaldo, five miles east of Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s office, but it was repulsed after a four-hour battle. The commander of the rebel assault, Lt. Col. <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> <PERSON> dela </PERSON> <PERSON> Pena </PERSON>, later surrendered with more than 200 men. Later Sunday, Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Marcelo </PERSON> <PERSON> Blando </PERSON>, commander of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Magsaysay </LOCATION>, surrendered in the city's <LOCATION> Greenhills </LOCATION> <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> with about 400 army soldiers and <ORGANIZATION> Scout </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rangers </ORGANIZATION>, military officials said. `` The attempted coup by rebel soldiers has been crushed,'' Defense Minister <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> said after <PERSON> dela </PERSON> <PERSON> Pena </PERSON> surrendered. Scattered sniper fire around the camp was reported later although there was no sign of substantial rebel forces in the area. In suburban <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION>, the country's financial district, hundreds of heavily armed rebels were still holding out in luxury hotels, condominiums, banks and office buildings after battles broke out Saturday. Military sources said it would be difficult to remove the rebels because of the potential for damage and loss of civilian life. Police had planned to attack the mutineers late Saturday, but the rebels struck first, killing one policeman and wounding 14 others. Rebels fired volleys of machine-gun fire from <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION> skyscrapers and snipers shot at vehicles on <PERSON> Epifanio </PERSON> delos Santos Avenue. Radio station <ORGANIZATION> DZRH </ORGANIZATION> broadcast an appeal for ambulances, saying many civilians lay wounded along <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Pasay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION>. A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-run </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> said there were no American warplanes in the skies over <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> Sunday. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military planes began flying cover for government troops Friday, hours after rebels launched their assaults, but American officials said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> planes ended those flights at 6 a.m. Saturday. A government spokesman said Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> and her family attended Mass at the Malacanang Palace and prayed for an end to the carnage. The rebel shelling of Camp Aguinaldo set fire to the <ORGANIZATION> Headquarters </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> building and hundreds of military families fled. Hospitals reported three people were killed and 25 wounded by the bombardment. Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Rodolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Biazon </PERSON>, chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, said some mutinous marines infiltrated the camp, seizing the chapel, dispensary and other small buildings near the main gate. He said the rebels smashed through the main gate with an armored vehicle that was immediately hit by ground fire from the defenders and the mutineers were unable to advance. The country's two international airports in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cebu </LOCATION> remained closed Sunday, and domestic flights were also canceled. In <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION>, rebels roamed through the affluent shops and Intercontinental Hotel Saturday. It was not known how many guests were registered at the hotel. The guests were allowed to stay inside, but mutineers ran other people out. Rebels blocked off a major street with commandeered trucks. One mutineer said his group changed the color of its shoulder patches from white to red `` because red is the color of blood, and we want to shed blood for our cause.'' Military Chief of Staff Gen. <PERSON> Renato </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Villa </PERSON> said rebels controlled parts of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Mactan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Base </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Cebu </LOCATION>, 350 miles south of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. The army commander, Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Cacanando </PERSON>, estimated that from 800 to 2,000 troopers had joined the revolt, the sixth attempted coup against Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> in less than four years and the most serious challenge to her government. Police said some assailants may be Communist insurgents seeking to take advantage of confusion brought on by the revolt, which began Friday when mutineers seized air force headquarters at <LOCATION> Villamor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Base </LOCATION>, the government television station and other strongpoints. The rebels later gave up the air base and station. Warplanes had attacked rebel positions around Camp Aguinaldo Saturday and the insurgents fired back with tanks, mortars and machine guns. In one attack, air force jets accidentally strafed 2,000 pro-government troopers, killing six. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s failure to crush the 20-year-old Communist insurgency is one reason for the discontent with her government, particularly within the military. She also has been criticized for not improving the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>' economy since coming to power in a 1986 military-civilian uprising that ousted President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. Military officials said one coup leader _ an associate of renegade Lt. Col. <PERSON> Gregorio </PERSON> `` Gringo'' <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON>, who led an August 1987 coup try _ had been arrested. Rebel sources said <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> was among the key planners of the current coup attempt. Maj. <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Gutierrez </PERSON> identified the rebel leader as Lt. Col. <PERSON> Tito </PERSON> <PERSON> Legazpi </PERSON> and said he was arrested after taking part in an attack on the <LOCATION> Sangley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> naval air station outside <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, which the rebels briefly held.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-89 0917EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-SummitRdp 8thLd-Writethru a0719 12-03 1061</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Summit Rdp, 8th Ld-Writethru, a0719,1,000</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush, Gorbachev: Progress Made Toward Better East-West Relations</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Combines a0719-a0717</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MARSAXLOKK BAY, Malta (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> ended two days of storm-tossed summitry Sunday and said they were satisfied they had made progress toward a better East-West relationship in a time of tumultuous change in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. But neither man pointed to a specific agreement on a key range of arms control or other issues, and at an unprecedented joint news conference, cited specific disagreements over weapons shipments to leftist rebels in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and proposed naval arms reductions. The two men seemed at ease as they fielded questions aboard the Soviet luxury liner Maxim Gorky, shaking hands and leaving the news conference together at its conclusion. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said he was `` encouraged and inspired'' by the changes in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, where hardline regimes have been swept away in recent weeks. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the Soviet leader had `` laid to rest'' the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> doctrine under which the Kremlin had invaded <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> in 1956 and <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> in 1968. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said that in his two days of talks with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, there were `` elements of optimism and pessimism here and I would n't dwell into the details.'' `` It was a no agenda meeting, it accomplished everything I hoped it would,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said there was no specific timetable for a new arms agreement to cut long range nuclear forces by 50 percent, but he hoped one could be agreed on before a summit set for next June in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The two men directed Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> and Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> to meet again soon on arms control issues. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> also said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had made a new proposal to reduce chemical weapons that was positive, and that top-ranking officials on both sides would be meeting to continue negotiating a treaty. Both <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> stressed the importance of their personal relationship, despite their repeated references to the differences they found over the two days. `` We stated, both of us, that the world leaves the one epoch of cold war and enters another epoch,'' he said. `` This is just the beginning. We are just at the very beginning of our long road to a longlasting peaceful period.'' Near the end of their news conference, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> suggested thanking reporters for their cooperation, but he added, `` although of course we do n't know what they've written yet or what they will be writing.'' Said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: `` Reserve the right to thank them afterwards you mean? after we've seen what they've written?'' Replied <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>: `` No, right now, and they will write better.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the two men had begun to develop a future that `` can realize a lasting peace and transform the East-West relationship.'' But when asked about <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s desire for naval arms reductions, he said he was `` disinclined to think that is an area where we will make immediate progress.'' Asked about <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, where the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has complained about continued flow of Soviet arms to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> rebels, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said `` we had an in-depth discussion on these questions as President <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has said.'' He added, `` I ca n't say there are no differences between us, but we had a chance to talk about them.'' The two men fielded questions after ending nearly eight hours of talks over two days that focused on arms control, trade, regional conflicts in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and elsewhere as well as <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was flying to <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> after the summit to brief <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> leaders on the summit talks. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was going to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to hold a similar meeting with <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact leaders _ many of them newly installed as a result of Eastern European changes. Howling winds and heavy seas have plagued the summit throughout, curtailing Saturday's sessions and forcing the leaders to meet aboard a Soviet luxury liner rather than <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet warships. But the rains that flooded this Mediterranean island abated Sunday, and skies were gray but clearing. `` Long time, no see,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> told <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> at the opening of Sunday's meeting. `` Back again,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, smiling. `` You did a little sea travel,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said. Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> was wearing a medicinal patch behind his ear to ward off seasickness, but White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was feeling `` terrific'' and enjoying the rough weather. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>,'' he added, `` does n't share our love of the sea.'' As he was departing the USS Belknap, the president was asked if the weather had made the summit a failure. `` Hell no. Hell no,'' he replied. `` This summit's going just fine, thank you.'' Said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: `` We do n't care where we're meeting. The big thing is we're getting something done, and it's good. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> attended a worship service aboard the USS Belknap before leaving for the Soviet cruise ship. During a storm-shortened opening summit session Saturday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> invited <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in the last two weeks of June 1990, setting a target date for a meeting that was agreed on last September. They worked to fix target dates for signing treaties that would slash strategic nuclear arms, conventional forces in central <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and chemical weapons on both sides. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> suggested signing a treaty providing a 30 percent to 50 percent cut in long-range nuclear arms by the June summit, and signing an accord on reducing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet ground forces in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> at a NATO-Warsaw Pact meeting in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> late next year. On Saturday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> took note of the dramatic changes under way in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, where the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall has crumbled and several hardline Communist regimes have been swept aside recently, by urging <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to join him in recommending that <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> be the site of the 2004 Olympic Games. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also expressed willingness to help the Soviet economy as a means of bolstering the <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s domestic reforms. A White House official, who spoke only on condition he not be identified, said that if the Soviets pass a liberal emigration law that is being pushed by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will grant <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> a range of trade favors. The assistance could include steps to grant the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> most-favored-nation trading status, lower tariffs on Soviet imports into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and observer status for the Soviets at the 97-nation General Agreement on Trade on Tariffs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-89 1019EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-EastGermany 4thLd-Writethru a0728 12-03 0861</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-East Germany, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0728,0883</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>East German Politburo Resigns; Ousted Members Arrested</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 10 grafs to UPDATE with other former party leaders
ousted, INSERT number who served on Central Committee. Pickup 9th graf,
`One of...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NESHA STARCEVIC</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>EAST BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Communist leader <PERSON> Egon </PERSON> <PERSON> Krenz </PERSON> and his ruling party Politburo resigned Sunday along with the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, hounded from office by increasing demands from <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s emboldened pro-democracy movement Former hard-line party leader <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> was expelled from the party he had led for 18 years until he was ousted and replaced by <ORGANIZATION> Krenz </ORGANIZATION> on Oct. 18. Three recently fired Politburo members were arrested on corruption charges, and a senior trade official fled <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Politburo member <PERSON> Guenter </PERSON> <PERSON> Schabowski </PERSON>, who was generally considered a reformer, announced the resignations of the 10-man Politburo and the 163-member <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on state radio. They came as the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s policy-making <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> met in an emergency session following demands from the burgeoning pro-democracy movement that <ORGANIZATION> Krenz </ORGANIZATION>, 52, resign. He was jeered by party members Saturday. The resignations were the latest development in a historic series of political changes that have transformed <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> from a hard-line <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> nation to one that is at the forefront of <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s reform movement. Under pressure from mass demonstrations and the exodus of thousands, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> has thrown open its borders and the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall, and lawmakers eliminated the Communists' constitutionally guaranteed leading role in society. In a deperate attempt to retain power and put a lid on the pro-democracy movement, <ORGANIZATION> Krenz </ORGANIZATION> had promised the people that he would investigate disclosures of corruption and high living among top party officials. The Communist Party on Sunday expelled a large number of its former leadership, including <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>, former Premier <PERSON> Willi </PERSON> <PERSON> Stoph </PERSON> and former <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> speaker <PERSON> Horst </PERSON> <PERSON> Sindermann </PERSON>, the state-run news agency <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> said. The move came after growing calls for the resignations of <ORGANIZATION> Krenz </ORGANIZATION> and the entire leadership amid charges of massive corruption in the top party ranks. One of those arrested was the senior economic adviser to <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>. <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Schalck-Golodkowski </PERSON>, a state secretary in the foreign trade ministry, fled <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> after authorities opened an investigation against him for suspected illegal weapons sales, <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday. <PERSON> Schalck-Golodkowski </PERSON> was <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s chief trade negotiator and had headed a department responsible for making hard-currency sales. Government spokesman <PERSON> Wolfgang </PERSON> <PERSON> Meyer </PERSON> said <PERSON> Schalck-Golodkowski </PERSON> was stripped of his functions following his escape. <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> said he went to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> on Saturday for trade talks and returned to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> later the same day. <PERSON> Wolfgang </PERSON> <PERSON> Vogel </PERSON>, the country's most prominent lawyer, told authorities early Sunday that <PERSON> Schalck-Golodkowski </PERSON> was `` at an unknown location outside <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'' and that he had asked <PERSON> Vogel </PERSON> to represent him, according to ADN. The investigation was opened after officials Saturday discovered a secret operation to ship weapons to the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> said. Hard-currency earnings from the sales went to the country's foreign trade bank addressed to <ORGANIZATION> Schalck-Golodkowski </ORGANIZATION>, it said. On Saturday, 3,000 <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> members jeered <ORGANIZATION> Krenz </ORGANIZATION> and whistled when he promised the party would investigate disclosures of corruption and high living among top party officials. `` Too late!'' they shouted. Ousted Politburo members <PERSON> Guenter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mittag </PERSON> and <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Tisch </PERSON> were taken into investigative custody suspected of `` heavily damaging socialist property and the people's economy through abuse of power,'' <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday. Also arrested was <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> Mueller </PERSON>, a former party leader in the city of <LOCATION> Erfurt </LOCATION> and former candidate member of the Politburo. Prosecutors issued the arrest warrants Saturday, and they were apprehended later, the news agency said. It did not specify which day. <PERSON> Mittag </PERSON> had been the senior economic adviser to <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>. The Communist Party has blamed the two for <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s economic crisis and has begun a disciplinary investigation of them. <PERSON> Mittag </PERSON> was ousted from the party last month. <PERSON> Tisch </PERSON> had been the chief of the Communist-run trade unions federation until the organization expelled him on Nov. 27. He also was removed from the ruling Politburo last month for allegedly abusing his powers. Two other former high-ranking Communist officials were arrested on Saturday. <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Albrecht </PERSON>, the former party chief in the <LOCATION> Suhl </LOCATION> region, and <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON>, director of a large home construction company in <LOCATION> Suhl </LOCATION>, were arrested under suspicion of `` fraudulently damaging socialist property,'' <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> said without elaboaration. On Friday, lawmakers heard complaints at a parliamentary session that top officials had taken bribes, indulged themselves with luxuries at state expense and stashed away more than $ 54 billion in foreign bank accounts. Since taking over from <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> on Oct. 18, <ORGANIZATION> Krenz </ORGANIZATION> has begun a program of sweeping reforms that includes promises of free elections and abolition of the Communists' 40-year monopoly of power. <PERSON> Krenz </PERSON> was jeered in a speech Saturday night outside the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> building. It was his latest attempt to distance himself from the old hard-line leadership, of which he was a prominent member. He has denied living opulently, as other leaders did under <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>. The lavish lifestyles of top party officials have been a major source of discontent in a country where the average citizen has to wait 10 years or more for a car.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-89 1026EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Czechoslovakia 3rdLd-Writethru a0727 12-03 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Czechoslovakia, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0727,0629</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Government Names Communist-Dominated Government; Opposition Angered</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 13 grafs to UPDATE with students scoffing, government
comment, Interior Ministry going to Communists. Pickup 10th graf, `But
in...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALISON SMALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PRAGUE, Czechoslovakia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Embattled Communist leaders on Sunday named five non-Communists to a new coalition government, but an angered opposition called the appointments an `` outrage'' and vowed to resume demonstrations. The Communists held on to 16 of the 21 Cabinet seats, including the premiership and the powerful defense ministry, the state-run media said. Thirteen members were holdovers from the previous Communist Cabinet. The appointments were made by Communist Premier <PERSON> Ladislav </PERSON> <PERSON> Adamec </PERSON> and President <PERSON> Gustav </PERSON> <PERSON> Husak </PERSON>, a hard-liner who took control of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> after <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION> tanks crushed the democratic `` Prague Spring'' reforms in 1968. It is the first time non-Communists have held top government positions since 1968. <PERSON> Jiri </PERSON> <PERSON> Dienstbier </PERSON>, a spokesman for Civic Forum, the nation's largest opposition group, rejected the new government, saying: `` It is more complicated than that. He said Civic Forum would call another mass rally Monday at <LOCATION> Wenceslas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, the focal point of two weeks of pro-democracy protests that ended the Communists' 41-year monopoly on power. One Civic Forum leader, speaking on condition of anonymity, called the new government an `` outrage,'' and said the Monday rally would get Czechoslovakians back on the street. Striking students whose protest of police brutality at a Nov. 17 demonstration spurred the nation's peaceful revolt, laughed derisively as they listened to a radio announcement of the new Cabinet. `` It is a disappointment,'' said a strike leader, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Cech </PERSON>. `` We will now have to decide what to do.'' <PERSON> Adamec </PERSON>, who opened negotiations with the opposition 12 days ago, retained his post, the state-run news agency <ORGANIZATION> CTK </ORGANIZATION> reported. Among the new Communist appointees was <PERSON> Miroslav </PERSON> <PERSON> Vacek </PERSON>, who took over the post of defense minister. <PERSON> Vacek </PERSON>, an army general, was named despite an opposition demand that the ministry be headed by a civilian. <PERSON> Vacek </PERSON> had served as deputy minister under former <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Minister <PERSON> Milan </PERSON> <PERSON> Vaclavik </PERSON>, also an army general. The new interior minister, <PERSON> Frantisek </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinc </PERSON>, is a civilian, as the opposition had demanded, but he is a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Civic Forum had demanded a non-Communist. Asked why Civic Forum's demands had not been fully met, Deputy Premier <PERSON> Bohumil </PERSON> <PERSON> Urban </PERSON> told reporters, `` This is what life is like. You ca n't take into account everybody's demands immediately.'' But in a move obviously calculated to appease demands for more religious freedom, <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Hromadka </PERSON>, a high-ranking leader of <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> church, was named one of seven deputy premiers. Of the five non-Communists named to the government, three had no official party affiliation. The new Cabinet appointees were for the most part political unknowns. <PERSON> Adamec </PERSON> agreed Tuesday in talks with Civic Forum to appoint a new government that would include non-Communists. He said last week that many of the old <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> members had wanted to implement reforms, but were unable to because of the hard-line policies of the ruling Politburo. <PERSON> Dienstbier </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Saturday that the opposition did not propose specific candidates for the new Cabinet, but concentrated on outlining what characteristics office holders should have. Communists, members of previously docile allied parties and non-party people are acceptable to Civic Forum if they have no obvious blemish in their past and are willing to implement reforms now that will lead to free elections and genuine democracy, <PERSON> Dienstbier </PERSON> said. Civic Forum, established only two weeks ago, is an umbrella movement of opposition groups. Its leaders say they are not putting themselves forward for Cabinet posts, but have left open the possibility of accepting nominations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-89 1127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-FurWars Bjt   12-03 0742</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fur Wars, Bjt,0764</SECOND>
<HEAD>Furriers Fight Back Against Animal Rights Protesters</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANA KENNEDY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American furriers are feeling the heat _ and it's not from their mink coats Increased pressure from animal rights advocates picketing fur stores, holding annual `` Fur-Free Fridays'' and chanting slogans like `` Buy a fur and slip into something dead'' have taken a toll. Now the fur industry is fighting back. Fur manufacturers, some facing financial losses, recently hired one of the world's largest public relations agencies to represent them and have paid for dramatic newspaper ads claiming activists will soon tell people not to eat meat. `` If those people really want to be socially conscious, they should n't wear gold jewelry or diamonds from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> or leather shoes,'' said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennad </PERSON>, owner of <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennad </PERSON> <PERSON> Furs </PERSON>, one of the largest fur stores in the <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> area. Last month, the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> firm of <ORGANIZATION> Burson-Marsteller </ORGANIZATION> sent out kits to fur retailers that included guidelines for handling the media and dealing with anti-fur demonstrations. The kit also included a hotline number for furriers faced with questions about the fur trade and provided form letters for use in writing letters to the editor. The fur industry also took out ads twice last month in <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> Sunday editions that read, in part, `` Today fur. Tomorrow leather, then wool. Then meat.'' Fur farmers have also joined the effort. <PERSON> Marsha </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>, associate executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Fur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welfare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paul </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, said the coalition is `` redoubling efforts to re-educate the public about the industry.'' Fur farmers are being briefed on issues, educational materials about the fur industry are being sent to schools, and a communications network has been established linking fur farmers around the country, <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> said. The public relations effort faces an uphill battle. Magazine and billboard advertisements paid for by animal rights groups have become increasingly more common _ and graphic. A full-page ad in this month's Spy magazine contains photographs of a trapper approaching a fox whose leg is caught in a trap, then standing on the animal and suffocating him. Ads at bus stops in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> depict a leghold trap with a raccoon's foot caught in it. Another print ad shows a simple leghold trap accompanied by the words `` Get a Feel for Fur. Slam Your Fingers in a Car Door.'' Other anti-fur tactics are on the rise as well. The fourth annual `` Fur-Free Friday'' last month drew 2,500 animal rights activists in a march in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Protesters also targeted a dozen other cities. More than 140 celebrities, including <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> and <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Basinger </PERSON>, <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON>, <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Linkletter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Christie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brinkley </PERSON>, have signed anti-fur statements circulated by the animal rights group Beauty Without Cruelty. Animal rights activists claim fur farming is inhumane and caters to vanity. The furriers maintain that the protesters are infringing on freedom of choice. They also claim that the fur industry is strictly regulated and that animals receive excellent care. `` A rat is a pig is a dog is a boy,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Meltzer </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Evans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, the nation's largest retailer of fur, repeating a phrase used often by furriers and their representatives. `` This is just the beginning for them. This is all about freedom of choice. They're trying to take away First Amendment rights.'' Despite the hiring of <ORGANIZATION> Burson-Marsteller </ORGANIZATION> last summer and the newspaper ads last month, the fur industry denies animal rights protesters have had an impact on business. Most say the public relations effort is an attempt to forestall any future harm. Though the fur industry tripled sales from 1979 to 1986, jumping from $ 850 million yearly to $ 1.8 billion, the boom has since leveled out. The Fur Vault, the country's second-largest American fur chain, reported losses of over $ 7 million in the last two years. Its retail operation is for sale. The two other publicly held fur companies in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> also reported recent considerable quarterly earnings losses. But industry spokesmen insist business is basically good and blame any losses on recent warm winters and a soft economy _ not protesters. `` There's been no impact on business,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Parsons </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Fur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. `` The impetus -LRB- for the newspaper ads -RRB- was a feeling among the furriers that the public was ready to hear from the fur industry. Our customers were asking, what's the story?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-89 1132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MontoyaTrial     12-03 0848</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Montoya Trial,0876</SECOND>
<HEAD>California State Senator Goes On Trial in Corruption Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVE LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SACRAMENTO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A powerful state senator goes on trial Monday amid strong indications that the federal corruption investigation that led to his indictment could result in charges against two other lawmakers. State Sen. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>, who chairs the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Professions </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, has pleaded innocent to 12 felony counts that accuse him of racketeering, extortion, bribery and money laundering. Among the alleged victims of his shakedown efforts: actor <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Asner </PERSON>. If convicted, <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> faces a maximum of 220 years in prison and more than $ 3 million in fines. The Democrat from the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monte </LOCATION>, who's been in the Legislature for 17 years, is the first person to be tried as a result of an investigation that began in 1985. The investigation included agents who posed as <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> businessmen seeking a bill to aid a shrimp-importing company they hoped to establish, and a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> aide who cooperated with the agents by wearing a hidden recording device. The bill was eventually passed, but Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON>, who had been tipped off by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, vetoed it. The probe became public in dramatic fashion in August 1988, when 30 federal agents raided the Capitol offices of <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>, three other lawmakers and their aides. There were reports that during the raid, aides in some offices shredded documents and erased sensitive computer information. Besides <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>, one of his former aides, an Assembly aide, a former <LOCATION> Yolo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff and a former undersheriff have also been charged. And while prosecutors are saying little about the investigation, a plea bargain reached last week could mean at least two other lawmakers will face charges. <PERSON> Karin </PERSON> <PERSON> Watson </PERSON>, a key aide to Assembly Republicans, pleaded guilty Tuesday to one extortion count and agreed to help prosecutors. That development could spell trouble for the two <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> members whose offices were searched 15 months ago, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Nolan </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Glendale </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Whittier </LOCATION>. According to papers filed in the case, <PERSON> Watson </PERSON> played a key role in setting up two meetings in June 1988 at which $ 12,500 was paid to an undercover agent. News articles have linked <PERSON> Nolan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> to those meetings. Both have denied wrongdoing. <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Sands </PERSON>, refused to discuss the case last week. But <PERSON> Sands </PERSON> said in an earlier interview that he was `` convinced that <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>'s position can be sustained.'' According to <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> aides, defense attorneys have subpoenaed about half the 40 members of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to testify at the trial, apparently in an attempt to show that <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>'s actions were not out of the ordinary. Among other things, <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> is accused of accepting a $ 3,000 `` honorarium'' from an undercover agent in exchange for help in getting the bill to help the fictional shrimp business through the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The charge alleging an extortion attempt against <PERSON> Asner </PERSON> stems from a 1985 meeting, at the time the popular actor, known for his roles in `` The <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyler </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> Show,'' `` <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>'' and `` Roots,'' was president of the <ORGANIZATION> Screen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Actors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION>. According to a memorandum filed by prosecutors last month, <PERSON> Asner </PERSON> and a lobbyist for the guild went to see <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> in May 1985 to seek his vote against a bill their union opposed. `` <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> took the two into his office and closed the door,'' the memorandum said. `` He then stated in no uncertain terms that he did not see why he should support the guild since the guild had not made financial contributions to him.'' The memo said <PERSON> Asner </PERSON> and the lobbyist were `` infuriated and disgusted'' and the meeting ended abruptly. <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> voted against the guild's side that afternoon, the memo added. In another incident, prosecutors alleged, <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> wrote letters to all <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> high school principals, urging them not to insure their athletes with a particular insurance company. The letters were written after the company's owner refused to pay <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> $ 10,000 for support of legislation backed by the company, the memorandum said. A key figure in the investigation, the memorandum said, was <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Shahabian </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> staffer who tried to extort an undercover agent and then agreed to cooperate with the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> in exchange for lenient treatment. In June 1988, <PERSON> Shahabian </PERSON> asked an unidentified legislator what it would take to get the shrimp legislation out of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, the memorandum said. `` Well, you need to make some arrangements with <PERSON> Joe </PERSON>,'' the lawmaker reportedly told <PERSON> Shahabian </PERSON>. `` What it'll take with <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> is a little envelope.'' Later that month, Shahabian, wearing a hidden recording device, went to see <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>. <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> asked if the organizers of shrimp deal were `` doing well,'' and learning that they were, replied, `` OK, so they can be helpful.'' Later in the conversation, after <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> was assured that the bill would attract little attention, <PERSON> Shahabian </PERSON> asked, `` How can we be helpful to you?'' `` Either way, -LRB- campaign -RRB- contributions and @ or honorariums,'' <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> reportedly said. A luncheon meeting was set up with the undercover agent, at which time the $ 3,000 check was passed to <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>, the memo said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-89 1139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ToxicLake     12-03 0346</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Toxic Lake,0356</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rare Toxic Algae Bloom in Lake Near Tacoma, Wash.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TACOMA, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A rare algae toxin in a suburban lake killed two cats, said health officials who want people to stay away from the deadly water. The soupy, blue-green masses of algae in <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> are so toxic that a few glassfuls of contaminated water could kill a human being, said <ORGANIZATION> Tacoma-Pierce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials. So far, officials have found the toxin only in a northern cove of the lake. Its presence was confirmed Friday. Signs and leaflets were being distributed, and further tests in the lake and others were planned Monday, said <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Coble </PERSON>, head of the agency's water resource section. The toxic algae normally live two weeks to a month, but health officials plan to kill it with copper sulphate Monday. The chemical itself is toxic, but it must be used in this case because of the danger of the algae, <PERSON> Coble </PERSON> said. `` It's pretty rough environmentally, but we're worried that the wind might shift and it -LRB- the algae -RRB- could spread,'' she said. The toxin affects the nervous system, and most mammals killed by it die of respiratory failure. There have been no recorded toxin-related human deaths in the state. Health officials confirmed the toxin was in the lake after testing at <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lutheran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> showed that mice injected with it died within minutes. Emergency rooms and veterinarians were alerted to watch for signs of the algae toxin in patients. `` It suddenly turned into an emergency,'' <PERSON> Coble </PERSON> said. The tests followed an autopsy on two cats taken to the health department a week ago. Green matter was found in their stomachs and on their fur, indicating they probably ingested the toxin by cleaning their coats. W.T. <PERSON> Edmondson </PERSON>, a retired <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> professor who specializes in lake ecology, said no one knows exactly what triggers the usually harmless algae to produce the toxin, but sewage appears to play a key role. The toxin is common in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> and has killed cattle and other large mammals, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-89 1146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-WiretapTrial     12-03 0639</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wiretap Trial,0731</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wiretap Trial Wraps up First Week of Testimony</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOE McDONALD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> and two fired employees resume a court fight Monday over whether the company made the two men set 1,200 illegal wiretaps, including one on President <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>'s hotel telephones during a 1976 visit. <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bell </LOCATION> is suing <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Draise </PERSON> for defamation, alleging they lied to damage the company's reputation after they were dismissed. Gates and Draise are countersuing for $ 11 million, contending their reputations were damaged when the company said they lied. The two men contend that <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bell </LOCATION> is a longtime lawbreaker and that the company's lawsuit is an attemptces were searched 15 months ago, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Nolan </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Glendale </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Whittier </LOCATION>. According to papers filed in the case, <PERSON> Watson </PERSON> played a key role in setting up two meetings in June 1988 at which $ 12,500 was paid to an undercover agent. News articles have linked <PERSON> Nolan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> to those meetings. Both have denied wrongdoing. <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Sands </PERSON>, refused to discuss the case last week. But <PERSON> Sands </PERSON> said in an earlier interview that he was `` convinced that <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>'s position can be sustained.'' According to <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> aides, defense attorneys have subpoenaed about half the 40 members of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to testify at the trial, apparently in an attempt to show that <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>'s actions were not out of the ordinary. Among other things, <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> is accused of accepting a $ 3,000 `` honorarium'' from an undercover agent in exchange for help in getting the bill to help the fictional shrimp business through the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The charge alleging an extortion attempt against <PERSON> Asner </PERSON> stems from a 1985 meeting, at the time the popular actor, known for his roles in `` The <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyler </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> Show,'' `` <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>'' and `` Roots,'' was president of the <ORGANIZATION> Screen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Actors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION>. According to a memorandum filed by prosecutors last month, <PERSON> Asner </PERSON> and a lobbyist for the guild went to see <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> in May 1985 to seek his vote against a bill their union opposed. `` <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> took the two into his office and closed the door,'' the memorandum said. `` He then stated in no uncertain terms that he did not see why he should support the guild since the guild had not made financial contributions to him.'' The memo said <PERSON> Asner </PERSON> and the lobbyist were `` infuriated and disgusted'' and the meeting ended abruptly. <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> voted against the guild's side that afternoon, the memo added. In another incident, prosecutors alleged, <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> wrote letters to all <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> high school principals, urging them not to insure their athletes with a particular insurance company. The letters were written after the company's owner refused to pay <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> $ 10,000 for support of legislation backed by the company, the memorandum said. A key figure in the investigation, the memorandum said, was <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Shahabian </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> staffer who tried to extort an undercover agent and then agreed to cooperate with the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> in exchange for lenient treatment. In June 1988, <PERSON> Shahabian </PERSON> asked an unidentified legislator what it would take to get the shrimp legislation out of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, the memorandum said. `` Well, you need to make some arrangements with <PERSON> Joe </PERSON>,'' the lawmaker reportedly told <PERSON> Shahabian </PERSON>. `` What it'll take with <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> is a little envelope.'' Later that month, Shahabian, wearing a hidden recording device, went to see <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>. <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> asked if the organizers of shrimp deal were `` doing well,'' and learning that they were, replied, `` OK, so they can be helpful.'' Later in the conversation, after <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> was assured that the bill would attract little attention, <PERSON> Shahabian </PERSON> asked, `` How can we be helpful to you?'' `` Either way, -LRB- campaign -RRB- contributions and @ or honorariums,'' <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> reportedly said. A luncheon meeting was set up with the undercover agent, at which time the $ 3,000 check was passed to <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>, the memo said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-89 1150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-PensionDropouts Bjt   12-03 0910</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pension Dropouts, Bjt,890</SECOND>
<HEAD>Small Businesses Bailing Out of Pension Plans Because of Complex
Laws</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYNA BRENNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of small businesses across the country are ditching their employee pension plans, saying federal rules make the benefit programs too costly and complex to maintain. Employers claim congressional tinkering with a 1974 pension law has dramatically increased the paperwork, accountants and administrative personnel needed to comply with the law. `` It's impossible,'' said <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, a third generation lumber company owner in <LOCATION> Clarksburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> `` We're going to drop the plan. <PERSON> Alvin </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lurie </PERSON>, a former assistant commissioner for the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, says <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> is typical of small business owners who tried but failed to keep current with the ever-changing provisions of the 1974 Employee Retirement Income Security Act. `` It has become much, much too complicated,'' said <PERSON> Lurie </PERSON>, now chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Special </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Pension Simplification. `` It's frightful. People ca n't afford it, do n't understand it.'' A <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, attorney who handles the pension plans for several hundred small businesses said he is advising his clients to drop them. A <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, plan administrator said about 30 percent of the small businesses she works with are terminating their programs. But some say the business owners are simply using regulations as an excuse. `` I do n't think it's that clear cut that the -LRB- congressional -RRB- revisions have led small businesses to drop their plans,'' a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> aide said, asking that she not be further identified. `` I'm skeptical because they can go into simplified plans.'' Many of the employers bailing out of the federally insured pension plans are setting up profit-sharing or other programs seen as less beneficial to employees because they usually require the workers to put up some of the money. The pension law, known as ERISA, was enacted by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to protect the 76 million <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> workers with pension plans and their $ 2 trillion in pension assets. Always complex, the law saw a series of amendments over the years that proved, in some cases, expensive or frustrating for employers. The <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s inspector general's office, cautioning that the pension system is open to fraud and embezzlement, wants <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to enact additional laws to prevent possible abuses. `` I think the people writing the laws are trying to be fair and equitable, but they do n't understand what the costs mean,'' said <PERSON> Paula </PERSON> <PERSON> Calamafde </PERSON>, a tax lawyer and head of the <ORGANIZATION> Small </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, who plans to give his employees the cash due to them from the pension fund, said he always tried to keep up with the laws. The required paperwork grew from 35 pages to 77 pages this year, he said. Then the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> came in to check out his plan and disqualified it on a technicality. His report lacked this phrase: `` These are the rules we will follow if the plan becomes top heavy,'' a measure designed to prevent employers from favoring top management. `` We felt like the Gestapo had been turned loose on us,'' he said. `` It's not fair. I have always told the Internal Revenue I'll do what ever I have to do to stay qualified. The Social Security Administration says the number of full-time workers with employer-financed pension plans fell to 46 percent last year, down from 50 percent in 1979. Only 29 percent of the workers in companies employing between 25 and 49 workers have such plans, while 67 percent of those in companies of 250 workers or more are covered. The federal insurer of private pension plans, the <ORGANIZATION> Pension </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Benefit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guarantee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corporation </ORGANIZATION>, received 10,790 notices of planned termination in fiscal 1988. But the organization, already $ 1.5 billion in the red, does not separate large from small businesses. Business owners are required to notify the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> PBGC </ORGANIZATION> and all plan participants before they end pension plans. <PERSON> Chet </PERSON> <PERSON> Salkind </PERSON>, executive director of the New York-based <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pension </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Actuaries </ORGANIZATION>, said there has been a constant decline in employer-financed plans and an increase in programs in which employees contribute, such as the 401 -LRB- k -RRB- savings plans. `` From the employee angle there's a tremendous difference,'' <PERSON> Salkind </PERSON> explained. `` Usually it's employee money and not a guaranteed amount.'' <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopson </PERSON>, a plan administrator and president of the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ana </LOCATION>, Calif.-based <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pension </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administrators </ORGANIZATION>, said her office used to see about four plan terminations a year but that this year there have been about 60 terminations among her 250 clients. Employers who end the plans pay their workers the amount accrued, but Ms. <PERSON> Hopson </PERSON> said bailing out undermines the nation's retirement program `` The feedback I get is they take the money and spend it,'' she said. Ms. <PERSON> Hopson </PERSON> puts the blame on laws that add to the cost of compliance, requiring detailed reports, accountants, actuaries and plan administrators. `` We ca n't spend the amount of time necessary to keep the plan updated and comply with the provisions,'' said a <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> employer who spoke on condition of anonymity because she is still in the process of terminating her plan. `` It took two months of my time.'' A <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> restaurant owner, who asked not to be further identified because `` I do n't trust the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION>,'' said he dropped his employer-paid plan and set up a profit-sharing program. `` With a profit-sharing plan I can put into it whatever I want,'' he said, adding that the government required him to put $ 113,000 into his employer-paid pension plan last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891203-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-89 1239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Summit-Q&amp;AText 4thAdd   12-03 1119</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Summit-Q&amp;A Text, 4th Add,1110</SECOND>
<HEAD>MARSAXLOKK BAY: contribution to that.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
