<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0009EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     08-12 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0026</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 03; 07; 32; 37; 38; 39.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0013EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     08-12 0082</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0087</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 03; 07; 32; 37; 38; 39.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 6-3-8-2.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 04; 14; 16; 31; 35; 41. Bonus: 2-5-0-6-1.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto Game: 21; 24; 29; 42; 43; 44. Supplementary 41.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 02; 06; 09; 14; 16; 17.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 0-1-4-6.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 5-4-2; 0-7-5-0; 2-6-2-7-6; 2-6-7-7-9-2.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EndofTolls     08-12 0332</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-End of Tolls,0339</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tolls End in Jacksonville Amid Demolition, Fireworks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RON WORD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JACKSONVILLE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mayor <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hazouri </PERSON>, at the controls of a crane wielding a wrecking ball, officially marked the end of 36 years of toll bridges in <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION> by helping demolish several toll booths. After collecting some $ 370 million in tolls from 1.5 billion motorists, the tolls were removed Friday from four local bridges and a four-lane expressway. `` We have taken a quantum leap forward in improving the quality of life for our city. Today is like New Year's, Christmas and the Fourth of July rolled into one,'' <PERSON> Hazouri </PERSON> said at ceremonies at the <LOCATION> Mathews </LOCATION> bridge, which opened in 1953. Moments earlier signs were unveiled on the <LOCATION> Mathews </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION> toll plazas reading, `` No Tolls, Pass Thru.'' At the same time, the tolls also ended on the <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON> <PERSON> Warren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Trout </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> bridges and on <LOCATION> Butler </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Boulevard </LOCATION>, a four-lane expressway linking <ORGANIZATION> Interstate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> 95 </ORGANIZATION> to the beach. There was a festive party atmosphere on the <LOCATION> Mathews </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION>, with crowds cheering, horns honking and the <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Johns </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Band </LOCATION> playing. Fireworks were ignited on Quarantine Island in the middle of the <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Johns </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. The mayor and <PERSON> Chester </PERSON> <PERSON> Stokes </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Jacksonville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION>, climbed aboard a large yellow crane, and with the help of a crane operator, toppled several toll booths. In a large front-page headline, The <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times-Union </ORGANIZATION> proclaimed Friday, `` Un-tolled joy: KEEP THE CHANGE.'' The removal of the tolls was made possible by the passage in March 1988 of a half-cent city sales tax. In addition to removing tolls on existing bridges, the new <LOCATION> Dames </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION> opened toll-free earlier this year. The removal of the tolls cames 18 months after the voters approved the concept. The wait was necessary to convince state officials that the sales tax revenue would generate sufficient funds to cover the refinancing of $ 200 million in outstanding toll-revenue bonds issued in 1963, 1977 and 1985.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-NightStalker     08-12 0319</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Night Stalker,0326</SECOND>
<HEAD>Juror Is Dismissed For Sleeping In Night Stalker Deliberations</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDA DEUTSCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 13th day of jury deliberations in the `` Night Stalker'' trial was interrupted Friday when the judge dismissed a juror for sleeping and ordered the panel to start all over again. An alternate juror was chosen to replace the sleeping juror in the complex case involving 13 murders and 30 felonies committed during the summer of l985. Jurors heard six months of testimony after six months of jury selection. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>, a 29-year-old drifter from <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, is accused of being the devil-worshipping `` Night Stalker'' who raped, murdered and robbed victims in a rampage that terrified <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Deputy District Attorney <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Halpin </PERSON> said he and defense lawyer <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> were summoned Friday to the courtroom of <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Tynan </PERSON> after the jury foreman sent a note saying that one juror had been seen sleeping at the deliberation table. <PERSON> Tynan </PERSON> interviewed the foreman who said two other jurors had reported seeing the man in question nodding off and snoring in the deliberation room. After a brief discussion with attorneys, <PERSON> Tynan </PERSON> summoned the juror and told him he was being dismissed for sleeping. The juror did not protest. The judge then brought the entire panel into the courtroom. He told them not to speculate on why the juror was being dismissed and instructed them to begin their talks anew with the alternate filling the dismissed juror's place. <PERSON> Halpin </PERSON> said it was impossible to tell how long it would take now for the jury to reach a unanimous decision on the 43 counts involved. Earlier this week, the jury returned to the courtroom to ask for a repeat of testimony involving <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>' dental problems. It was the first time they had asked for testimony to be read back since they began deliberating July 26.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0625EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--CrackCall     08-12 0172</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Crack Call,0175</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Nab Suspected Dealer Who Calls 911 for Information</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HATTIESBURG, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A suspected crack dealer curious about a police round-up called a 911 emergency number to ask if authorities were looking for him. When he hung up, he had his answer _ officers were at his door. Police said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Mays </PERSON>, 33, of <LOCATION> Forrest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> telephoned the police emergency line on Thursday night to ask about a report he heard on the street _ a grand jury had indicted 101 people suspected of dealing crack and police were looking for them. A computerized system flashed the address from which <PERSON> Mays </PERSON> was telephoning, and officers sped to the house and arrested him, a sheriff's office spokesman said. The indictments were issued Thursday, and by Friday afternoon officers had arrested more than 50 people accused of selling crack to undercover agents working with the <ORGANIZATION> Metro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Narcotics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Task </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>. District Attorney <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> said arraignments would be held Aug. 25. The investigation began early this year, authorities said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Hostages     08-12 0672</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Hostages,Bjt,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Taking `Wait and See' Attitude on Hostage Offer</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The White House, sifting through offers, hints and statements from the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> about American hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, says the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> wants to `` let these issues play out for a few days and see what happens.'' `` We get a lot of different statements, some optimistic, some pessimistic, some critical, some crazy,'' said White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. `` We watch them all, analyze them all and in a sense, the public and -LRB- the press -RRB- all are seeing the process pretty much as it is.'' The latest development was a conditional offer of assistance from the spiritual leader of the pro-Iranian group <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, believed to be the umbrella for Shiite Moslem factions holding most of the 16 Western hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> <PERSON> Fadlallah </PERSON>, during a Friday prayer service in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, said he was ready to help free the hostages if the West helps release Arab prisoners in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON>, using identical language at separate briefings, called it `` an interesting statement.'' `` They should release the hostages,'' Ms. <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> said. `` You do n't need to talk about it. Just release the people who are held against their will by <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>. Any help which any party can provide in the unconditional, safe and immediate release of the hostages is welcome.'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the administration has not had any direct contact with <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> and is n't seeking any. Ms. <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> reiterated the administration position that it was willing to talk with anyone. Elaborating on his answer, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, `` We always said we'd talk to anybody and seek any avenue for getting the release of the hostages, but there's never really been an opportunity for direct discussions'' with the hostage holders `` Partly they have n't wanted to. We've said we wo n't negotiate for hostages. It just has n't been fruitful.'' An administration official, speaking on condition of anonymity, expressed skepticism about <PERSON> Fadlallah </PERSON>'s offer. `` This is the kind of thing we've seen him say on frequent occasions, and he's never done anything,'' the official said. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, describing that state of play after two weeks of intense activity, said, `` It's a long process and we need to be patient and let discussions flow back and forth.'' He said President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has a sense of urgency on `` the overall situation, but the most important traits right now are patience and determination, to not let urgency push you to say things or do things that would be counterproductive.'' Insisting there were no new developments, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, `` We would like to lower our voices a little and let these issues play out for a few days and see what happens.'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> also played down the prospect of direct <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> contacts with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> after saying a day earlier that the administration expected there would eventually be talks with <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> on the hostages and communications through third parties. `` The whole question of direct contacts has gotten so far out of proportion that I do n't want to lend any credence to it,'' he said. `` We are having any number of contacts through any number of channels ... but this direct-contacts business, I'm afraid, has gotten you off track in terms of focusing on what's really happening there,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. `` There's no miracle there -LRB- in direct talks with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> -RRB-. It's not that big a deal. There's all kinds of contacts that can and will be made _ that have to be made preparatory to direct -LRB- talks -RRB-, and there need never be direct contacts to solve many of these issues, to change relationships and so forth.'' Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported today that <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> had sent messages to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and Palestinian groups urgently appealing for release of the Western hostages. `` The Soviet response has been constructive, helpful and forthcoming,'' the newspaper quoted an administration official. `` It's less than we would like them to do, but more than they would have done in the past.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0115EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BlochProbe     08-12 0510</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bloch Probe,Bjt,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Justice Department Says Disclosure Hurt Bloch Probe</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is hardening its assessment of the damage done by public disclosure to its investigation of suspected <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> spy <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> said flatly Friday that the July 21 disclosure that the 54-year-old <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomat was under investigation had compromised the investigation. `` There is no doubt that the premature disclosure of that case, the premature disclosure that there was an ongoing investigation, did compromise the investigation,'' <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> said. He did n't explain how the investigation had been compromised. However, <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON>'s assessment was much stronger than one he delivered July 31 when asked about the impact of unprecedented publicity on an espionage investigation that so far has produced no criminal charges. He said then that `` the premature disclosure may have had an adverse impact on the development of new evidence in the case.'' The investigation of <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>, the No. 2 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomat in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> for much of the decade, was disclosed July 21 by <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>. `` The differences in the statements reflects a different view, based on how people in the department see the situation today,'' <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> said Friday when asked about the contrast between his two assessments. He acknowledged the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> opposed the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s decision to issue a statement after the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> broadcast that essentially confirmed the accuracy of the report. The television report and a series of disclosures have produced what <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> called `` the circus going on out there'' of reporters and <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents tailing <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> each day on daily excursions from his apartment. On Thursday, <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> acknowledged the department does n't have an espionage case against <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>, who was placed on paid leave by the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Asked why there were no charges despite continuous <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> surveillance of <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>, <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> said: `` The department does not bring charges unless it believes it has sufficient evidence to convince a jury beyond a reasonable doubt that a person is guilty of violating the law.'' The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> has been conducting a round-the-clock surveillance of <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> to prevent him from leaving the country while investigators try to find evidence to charge him with espionage. <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> refused to comment when asked if the department had evidence that it was unwilling to disclose in court for fear of hurting counterintelligence operations. <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>, meantime, led reporters and photographers on a Friday afternoon shopping excursion to a suburban supermarket. About 1 p.m., <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> announced he was about to leave his apartment. Two hours later, <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> finally emerged, driving his light-blue <ORGANIZATION> Mercedez-Benz </ORGANIZATION>. He invited two television crews to ride along while he went on errands. Followed by a 20-car caravan of reporters, TV crews and <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents, <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> drove to a shopping center in nearby <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, where he shopped at a supermarket and a bookstore. The supermarket manager asked the TV crews to leave the store after a cameraman who was backpeddling to film <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> buying groceries knocked over an elderly woman, who cut her hand on the floor.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0114EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--France-Angels     08-12 0186</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--France-Angels,0192</SECOND>
<HEAD>Group to Start Setting Up Parisian Branch</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Guardian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angels </ORGANIZATION> intend to set up a subway patrol in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> despite opposition from local officials, one of the group's leaders says. <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Sliwa </PERSON> completed a five-day tour of the subway system on Friday and told reporters she would return in September to recruit and train French Guardian Angels. `` We are really needed here,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Sliwa </PERSON>, who wore the red beret and white T-shirt that the New York-based group has adopted as a uniform. The <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> transit authority and police unions have said they oppose a Guardian Angel patrol. `` We are completely opposed to those who act as a militia or other police force,'' said a statement issued Monday by the transit authority. Ms. <PERSON> Sliwa </PERSON> said she had since met with police and transit authority officials and, while not getting their approval, plans to go ahead with setting up a subway patrol. `` We are not a militia,'' she said. She said the Guardian Angels, founded in 1979, patrol subways in 44 American cities, as well as in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Paraguay-Minister     08-12 0076</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Paraguay-Minister,0121</SECOND>
<HEAD>Defense Minister Resigns</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ASUNCION, Paraguay (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Army Gen. <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Samaniego </PERSON> has resigned as national defense minister, President Gen. <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> announced. <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> gave no reason for the resignation, which he disclosed to reporters at the national palace on Friday. <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> ousted former President Gen. <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> in a coup Feb. 3 and was elected president in May. <PERSON> Samaniego </PERSON>, 65, served as ambassador to <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> under <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>. A replacement was not immediately named.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NorthSentence     08-12 0344</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North Sentence,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>North Sentence Could Have Been Harsher Under Federal Guidelines</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A legal publication says <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> could have been sentenced to more than 4 -LCB- years in prison if federal sentencing guidelines had been applied to his Iran-Contra conviction. However, the guidelines that recommend ranges of possible sentences to judges were n't applied in the North case because they cover only federal crimes committed after Nov. 1, 1987. The editors of the Federal Sentencing Reporter, a non-profit publication circulated among federal judges, probation officers, law professors and lawyers, concluded <PERSON> North </PERSON> could have been sentenced under the guidelines to 21 to 57 months in prison. North was convicted of aiding and abetting obstruction of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, destroying government documents and accepting an illegal gratuity while working at the White House in 1986. He was fined, put on probation and ordered to do community service _ but was sentenced to no jail time. North began his community service work this week. The ranges `` sketch possible avenues guideline sentencing might have taken,'' <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Emory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. Freed of <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> said in their analysis. If <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s had been a guidelines case, <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> still could have imposed no jail time but prosecutors would have been able to appeal. Under the guidelines, `` there is a degree of flexibility, but the challenge for the judge is to persuasively explain why there is a substantial departure,'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said Friday in an interview. `` When the appeals courts find the explanations unpersuasive, they've reversed sentences.'' The length of a recommended sentence under the guidelines in the North case would depend partly on a judge deciding whether the former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide substantially interfered with the administration of justice. Other factors would be the value assigned to classified documents that <PERSON> North </PERSON> destroyed, whether he was a major or minor participant in the crime of aiding the obstruction of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and whether he was considered to be in a high-level decision-making capacity.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0128EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Shoreham     08-12 0267</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shoreham,270</SECOND>
<HEAD>Justice Department Joins Shoreham Suit</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, saying <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Shoreham </LOCATION> nuclear power plant is `` safe, efficient and much-needed,'' is joining in a lawsuit to prevent the plant from being dismantled The intervention in a state court came on behalf of the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, which has strongly opposed the shutdown of the 813-megawatt plant on <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, deputy energy secretary, said the state, in its approval of the dismantling plan, had not adequately considered the impact on the environment. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> argues that the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> and the state <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> should have prepared formal environmental impact statements before approving the plan. The plant, <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said, is `` safe, efficient and much-needed,'' adding that its closure would require the region to rely more heavily on fossil fuel. Those fuels, he said, will have `` adverse environmental consequences'' through the increased release of chemicals that contribute to acid rain and global warming. Some <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> residents and a group called Scientists and <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Secure </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> filed the suit against the plant. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration previously has made clear its opposition to the closing of the $ 5.5 billion plant completed in 1985 and licensed last year. It has yet to produce any commercial electricity. State and local officials contend the plant should not be allowed to operate because evacuation of the area 50 miles east of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> would be impossible. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> plans to meet with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> next week to discuss White House opposition to the plant being torn down.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-12 0871</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0905</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SWAN LAKE, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Woodstock alumni <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sebastian </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Sommer </PERSON> and <PERSON> Melanie </PERSON> will join <PERSON> Papa </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Creech </PERSON>, former <ORGANIZATION> Byrds </ORGANIZATION> guitarist <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> McGuinn </PERSON> and at least 10 other bands for a `` Remember Woodstock'' concert next week. The concert, billed as another three days of peace, love and music in celebration of the <LOCATION> Woodstock </LOCATION> concert held 20 years ago, is scheduled Aug. 17-19 in this <LOCATION> Catskills </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> resort town, said promoter <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON>. Other acts scheduled are The Woodstock All-Star Band, <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nininger </PERSON> and Family, Futu Futu, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Massengill </PERSON>, The <ORGANIZATION> Lisa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Best </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Blues </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Cliff </PERSON> <PERSON> Eberhardt </PERSON>, The <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Earle </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> Latin Jazz Band, <PERSON> Savoy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, and <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nichols </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> said Friday. Blood, <ORGANIZATION> Sweat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Tears, <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Winter </PERSON> and the duo of <PERSON> Edgar </PERSON> <PERSON> Winter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> are also expected to play, and clown <PERSON> Wavey </PERSON> <PERSON> Gravy </PERSON> will repeat his role as concert emcee on the first day of the concert, the promoter said. State health officials approved the concert Thursday, saying promoters had complied with all health requirements. Authorities rejected an earlier proposal for the concert, saying it did n't adequately plan for congestion of traffic and people. Promoters then limited the number of tickets to 4,000 _ a far cry from the estimated 450,000 people who inundated the tiny town of <LOCATION> Bethel </LOCATION> in August 1969. `` The local people are afraid that <LOCATION> Woodstock </LOCATION> is going to happen all over again, so they want to make sure that it does n't,'' <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HALLANDALE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Millionaire industrialist <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Posner </PERSON> has decided to build five 30-story condominium buildings on his oceanfront property after rejecting a state offer for a land swap. The <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> had been trying since March to persuade the <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> executive to swap his 13 acres of oceanfront property for 67 acres of state-owned land near the Doral Country Club in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. The Posner tract, the city's only undeveloped oceanfront land, is wedged between a strip of high-rises and would have made a perfect setting for a park, state officials said. But <PERSON> Posner </PERSON> thought the swap would not have been profitable for him, said his attorney, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> land, formerly owned by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, is worth $ 8 million while <PERSON> Posner </PERSON>'s land is worth $ 15 million, state officials said. <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> said <PERSON> Posner </PERSON> would proceed with plans to build the condominiums with 1,500 units on the site. <PERSON> Posner </PERSON> faces one more hurdle: state approval for two of the five buildings that would be built near the ocean.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A verion of the following moved on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION> pitcher <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Dravecky </PERSON>, who made a remarkable comeback from cancer surgery, also made a pitch for a 6-year-old boy suffering from leukemia. <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Vlahos </PERSON> of <PERSON> Hillsborough </PERSON> sat in the stands Thursday as his friend tossed eight strong innings in his first major-league appearance since surgery on his pitching arm 10 months ago. <PERSON> Dravecky </PERSON> won the game, 4-3. His pitching performance also helped raise tens of thousands of dollars for <PERSON> Alex </PERSON>, who desperately needs a bone marrow transplant to beat leukemia. <PERSON> Dravecky </PERSON> and radio station <ORGANIZATION> KNBR </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> launched a fund drive this week in an effort to find a bone marrow donor for <PERSON> Alex </PERSON>. Listeners could pledge any amount on <PERSON> Dravecky </PERSON>'s pitching performance, with the money going to offset the $ 75 it costs to screen each of the potential bone marrow donors. The response was overwhelming. It may be several days before <ORGANIZATION> KNBR </ORGANIZATION> knows how much was raised, but the station said Thursday night that pledges finally came to $ 500 to $ 1,000 for each Dravecky pitch _ totaling between $ 46,000 and $ 92,000.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ENID, Okla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Country music singer <PERSON> Janie </PERSON> <PERSON> Fricke </PERSON> canceled a performance in favor of a spot on a Canadian television show, and promoters want their $ 3,500 back. Ms. <PERSON> Fricke </PERSON> was to perform Sept. 8 in <PERSON> Enid </PERSON> at the <LOCATION> Garfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fair </LOCATION>, but she canceled the appearance and three other shows to accept the spot on the anniversary special in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. `` We've had tickets printed and posters made,'' said <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Koechel </PERSON>, fair secretary. The board had already paid her $ 3,500 _ 20 percent of the $ 10,500 cost. `` We want that money back,'' <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON>, fair board chairman said. `` She broke a signed contract. I think we should see the district attorney about filing a lawsuit.'' Ms. <PERSON> Fricke </PERSON> was not available for comment.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>JERSEY CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>'s name will remain on the <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> courthouse despite protests by veterans who object to his opinion allowing the burning of the American flag. The county Board of Freeholders on Thursday unanimously agreed to name the 83-year-old building after <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON>, who served as <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>'s assignment judge from 1947 to 1951. <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> authored the recent <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> opinion that said burning the American flag was protected by the Constitution. Ten veterans, wearing their military caps, attended the meeting, and said they were upset over the vote. `` It's wrong,'' said <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Duffy </PERSON>, vice commander of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> 52 in <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. `` Anybody can burn the American flag at this moment and nothing will be done to them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;LWithdrawals     08-12 0291</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;L Withdrawals,290</SECOND>
<HEAD>Withdrawals in Nation's S&amp;Ls Double</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government says that net deposit withdrawals at the nation's thrifts more than doubled in June _ to $ 4.6 billion. The Office of Thrift Supervision, known as the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> until enactment of the new savings and loan law earlier this week, attributed the outflow to intentional shrinkage by thrifts as they prepared to meet the law's tough capital rule. `` Everybody knew about the legislation in June,'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Barth </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> OTS </ORGANIZATION> chief economist, said Friday. `` They knew it was just a matter of time and they were doing the things they will have to do in order to meet higher capital requirements.'' About one in four of the nation's 2,933 S & amp; Ls do n't meet the new standard _ $ 1.50 in tangible capital for every $ 100 in lending _ that becomes effective in four months. The only way thrifts that ca n't attract new capital can comply is to sell off assets such as loans and pay off liabilities such as deposits. <PERSON> Barth </PERSON> said S & amp; Ls in June reduced their assets by a near-record $ 7.6 billion, a monthly total exceeded only by the $ 8 billion reduction in January. Most of the June reduction was accounted for by a record $ 5.1 billion drop in mortgage-backed securities, one of the most easily sold assets in a thrift portfolio. The June deposit outflow was the 14th in a row. Although it was more than twice the $ 2.1 billion drain in May, it was still far below the $ 10.8 billion record set in January. For the first six months of the year, a net $ 40.3 billion have flowed out of thrift accounts compared with an inflow of $ 11.8 billion in the first half of 1988.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0138EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Nofziger     08-12 0266</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nofziger,270</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prosecutors Move to Reinstate Former Reagan Aide's Conviction</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prosecutors want a federal appeals court to reconsider its decision to overturn the illegal lobbying conviction against former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide <PERSON> Lyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> panel `` undermined critical provisions of the Ethics in Government Act'' when it ruled June 27 that <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>'s conviction must be set aside, prosecutors said in court papers filed Friday. The office of independent counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> asked the court to grant a rehearing before the three-member panel or set the case for rehearing by all 10 members of the appeals court. <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> was convicted Feb. 11, 1988, on three counts of lobbying top presidential aides on behalf of private clients shortly after he left the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> White House. Prosecutors say the lobbying violated a one-year ethics law ban against lobbying former government colleagues. But the appeals panel, in a 2-1 ruling, said that to get a conviction, prosecutors were required to show that <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> knew he was lobbying his former colleagues on matters in which the White House had a `` direct and substantial interest.'' Prosecutors maintain the law required only that they show <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> intended to influence the officials on those matters. One of <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>'s lawyers, <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Barcella </PERSON>, said the prosecution arguments present `` absolutely nothing new'' and there is `` no reason to disturb'' the appeals court decision. The lobbying <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> performed was for the scandal-plagued <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a maritime engineers union and the manufacturer of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>'s A-10 anti-tank plane. <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>, 65, was sentenced to 90 days in prison and fined $ 30,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-AbortionTrial 2ndLd-Writethru a0404 08-12 0489</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Abortion Trial, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0404,0498</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Protesters, Man Who Torched Clinic Guilty in Abortion Racketeering
Trial</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 4th graf, `He and ...' to clarify that all three were found
to have conspired to violate the racketeering statute; picks up 5th graf,
`Beseda was ...'.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATIA BLACKBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two abortion protesters and a man who insisted <PERSON> God </PERSON> told him to set fire to an abortion clinic conspired to violate federal racketeering laws, a federal court jury ruled Friday in a civil lawsuit. <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON> <PERSON> Beseda </PERSON>, already serving 20 years in a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> federal prison for setting fire to the Feminist Women's <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Everett </LOCATION>, also violated the racketeering statute through arson and extortion aimed at the abortion clinic, the jury concluded. The Everett clinic was burned three times between December 1983 and April 1984, then closed its doors. <PERSON> Beseda </PERSON> earlier told the jury he had no intention of setting any fire until he heard God tell him to do it. He and protesters <PERSON> Dottie </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Codispoti </PERSON>, both of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stevens </LOCATION>, were found to have conspired to violate the racketeering statute. <PERSON> Beseda </PERSON> was ordered to pay $ 268,500 in civil damages while <PERSON> Beseda </PERSON>, <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> and <PERSON> Codispoti </PERSON> will share another $ 11,000 fine. All damages can be trebled. Two other defendants, <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Undseth </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Snohomish </LOCATION>, were acquitted. Jurors in Judge <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Zilly </PERSON>'s court deliberated 3 -LCB- days before reaching a verdict in the month-long trial. The lawsuit is only the second time the racketeering statute, intended to fight organized crime, has been used against abortion protesters. Damages will go to several clinic employees and to the <ORGANIZATION> Feminist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yakima </ORGANIZATION>, parent clinic to the one that burned. <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>' lawyer <PERSON> Theresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Schrempp </PERSON> promised an appeal. <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, holding her young grandson <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON>, said she thinks the jury was confused by the complexity of the case, involving 52 pages of jury instructions. `` It's a perversion of the First Amendment,'' she said. `` This one's going to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>.'' She said the plaintiffs `` wo n't get anything out of me ... because I do n't have anything. In <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, the case that set precedent in the <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> case was upheld on appeal in March and defendants have asked the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> to hear it. Twenty-six individuals were found guilty of multiple acts of extortion at an abortion clinic there. The clinic was awarded $ 100,000. Lawyers for the plaintiffs alleged <PERSON> Beseda </PERSON> and the other defendants conspired to shut down the clinic by arson, personal and telephone harassment of patients and staff, blocking access to and from the clinic, picketing and helping <PERSON> Beseda </PERSON> escape to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. A successful action under the racketeering statute must show an enterprise adversely affects interstate commerce and engages in a pattern of racketeering, meaning a serious violation of the law such as arson, extortion, wire fraud, robbery, kidnapping or murder, said <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Tiryak </PERSON>, the civil rights attorney who tried the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> case.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CrashTests     08-12 0540</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crash Tests,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Peugeot Shows Worst Injury Potential In Government Crash Tests</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Crash tests indicate that a driver of a <ORGANIZATION> Peugeot </ORGANIZATION> 505S has a greater chance of head injury than drivers of 28 other cars and small trucks tested so far, federal engineers say. However, a <ORGANIZATION> Peugeot </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said the tests conducted by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Traffic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> using instrument-equipped dummies do n't accurately test the effects of real highway accidents. `` Our top concern is protecting human beings, not dummies,'' <PERSON> Pascal </PERSON> <PERSON> Henault </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Peugeot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, said Friday. The new series of tests included 10 different car and van models by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and foreign automaker. In previous tests involving 19 vehicles, the Chevrolet Astro Van fared worst. The Astro now stands second among cars tested for injuries in a 35-mile-per-hour collision. The vehicles were tested under <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION>'s program to provide consumers a guide to the safety of 1989 cars and small trucks. The car in which the lightest injury potential was recorded so far is the <ORGANIZATION> Dodge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daytona </ORGANIZATION>, followed by the Ford Thunderbird and the <ORGANIZATION> Audi </ORGANIZATION> 80. The <ORGANIZATION> Audi </ORGANIZATION> was among the 10 cars tested in the most recent round. Others, in addition to the Peugeot 505S, were <ORGANIZATION> Volkswagen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Hyundai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sonata </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Isuzu </ORGANIZATION> Trooper II, <PERSON> Suzuki </PERSON> <PERSON> Sidekick </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Toyota </PERSON> <PERSON> Cressida </PERSON>, Corolla, pickup and van. After the latest tests were made public, <ORGANIZATION> Peugeot </ORGANIZATION> issued a news release including comments from <PERSON> Henault </PERSON> and from four automotive and consumer experts who criticized the government tests as inaccurate measures of the varied circumstances that exist in real crashes. `` <ORGANIZATION> Peugeot </ORGANIZATION>'s commitment to building cars that are safe in the real world can not be overshadowed by these experimental crash-test results,'' said <PERSON> Henault </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> tests consist of crashing a single model of each car containing two crash dummies into a fixed barrier at 35 mph. The stresses that result on the dummies are measured by sensors. The artificial occupants are protected by seat belts and other safety devices used in the cars. <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> engineers reported stresses on the head as an index called the `` head injury criterion.'' The higher the index, the greater the likelihood of injury. The Peugeot crash produced a head injury criterion of 1,983 on the driver-side dummy. The earlier Astro test registered 1,849. Federal regulations require cars to produce a head injury criterion no greater than 1,000 in tests conducted by the automakers at 30 mph. The <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> tests are not considered comparable because they are done at a speed 5 mph faster. The tests are continuing, but here is how all models so far tested rank in head injury criterion to the driver: <ORGANIZATION> Peugeot </ORGANIZATION> 505S, 1,983; <PERSON> Chevrolet </PERSON> <PERSON> Astro </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON>, 1,849; <ORGANIZATION> Toyota </ORGANIZATION> Pickup, 1,520; <ORGANIZATION> Dodge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Spirit </ORGANIZATION>, 1,421; <ORGANIZATION> Suzuki </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sidekick </ORGANIZATION>, 1,345; <ORGANIZATION> Chevrolet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caprice </ORGANIZATION>, 1,328; <PERSON> Suzuki </PERSON> Trooper II, 1,269; <ORGANIZATION> Toyota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Van </ORGANIZATION>, 1,183; <ORGANIZATION> Hyundai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sonata </ORGANIZATION>, 1,196; <ORGANIZATION> Toyota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corolla </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bronco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> II </ORGANIZATION>, 994; <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Galant </ORGANIZATION>, 971; <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> Probe, 970; Jeep Cherokee, 968; <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mirage </ORGANIZATION>, 960. Others were the Mercury Tracer, 940; <ORGANIZATION> Eagle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Premier </ORGANIZATION>, 877; <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION>, 863; Chevrolet S10 Blazer, 834; <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Van </ORGANIZATION>, 805; <ORGANIZATION> Toyota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cressida </ORGANIZATION>, 790; <ORGANIZATION> Volkswagen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION>, 787; <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> 5th Avenue, 786; <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> CRX </ORGANIZATION>, 750; Eagle Medallion, 745; <ORGANIZATION> Plymouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Acclaim </ORGANIZATION>, 663; <ORGANIZATION> Audi </ORGANIZATION> 80, 600; Ford Thunderbird, 541; <ORGANIZATION> Dodge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daytona </ORGANIZATION>, 399.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0226EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FDA-GenericDrugs     08-12 0297</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-FDA-Generic Drugs,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>FDA Revokes Two Generic Drug Approvals</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> is taking the first formal action against generic drug companies being investigated by the agency, revoking recent drug approvals of two manufacturers. The revocations were issued Friday against <ORGANIZATION> Par </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pharmaceutical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Spring </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Therapeutics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Bohemia </LOCATION>, N.Y. Both actions involved chlorozoxazone, the generic name for <PERSON> Parafon </PERSON> <PERSON> Forte </PERSON>, a muscle relaxant made by <ORGANIZATION> Johnson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. Par received approval to market its version June 5 and <ORGANIZATION> ATI </ORGANIZATION> was granted approval June 23. <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Nesbit </PERSON> said the approvals were rescinded because the reports on which they were based did n't include `` substantial deficiencies in manufacturing practices'' found during a recent special inspection. The approvals were revoked Aug. 3, <PERSON> Nesbit </PERSON> said. Both companies disputed the legal ground on which <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> issued the revocations. `` The agency just ca n't summarily rescind a new drug approval without providing sponsor due process of law,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Weeda </PERSON>, a lawyer for <ORGANIZATION> ATI </ORGANIZATION>. He said the manufacturing problems cited by the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> involved `` minor labeling and packaging deficiencies, which the company made prompt corrective action.'' <ORGANIZATION> ATI </ORGANIZATION> had not shipped its product when the approval was rescinded, but Par had begun shipping, a spokeswoman said. `` It's not being shipped anymore, but it's not being recalled either,'' said Par lawyer <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Manners </PERSON>. She said <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> had n't raised any questions about the safety of the product Par and <ORGANIZATION> ATI </ORGANIZATION> are among 11 generic drug companies being investigated by the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> in the wake of allegations of fraud and corruption in the generic drug industry. Par recently pleaded guilty to providing an improper gratuity to an <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> employee. Par also has admitted giving the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> false information about one of its drugs, which it has recalled.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0231EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtonInBrief 750   08-12 0756</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington In Brief, 750</SECOND>
<HEAD>No. 2 HUD Official to Decide Fate of Troubled Housing Agency</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The No. 2 official at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> says he'll ask Cleveland-area officials to shake up the management of their housing authority. But <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Undersecretary <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Dellibovi </PERSON> opposes a federal takeover of the long-troubled agency. `` The problem is basically a management problem and I think clearly the management in place is not up to the challenge at hand,'' <PERSON> Dellibovi </PERSON> said Friday about the <ORGANIZATION> Cuyahoga </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION>. `` The solution to this kind of local problem is not a federal takeover.'' <PERSON> Dellibovi </PERSON> will go to <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> on Monday to meet with Mayor <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Voinovich </PERSON>, who repeatedly has asked the federal agency to take over the housing authority.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>US Condemns Syrian Role In Beirut Fighting</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is taking the unusual step of singling out <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> for its role in the latest round of fighting in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. The criticism came Friday as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials continued to seek Syrian help to obtain the release of eight American hostages held by pro-Iranian militants in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. `` We again call upon <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, an active participant in the fighting, the Lebanese armed forces, as well as the various Lebanese factions, for an immediate cease-fire, the lifting of all blockades and the initiation of a dialogue for the political reconstruction of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>,'' said <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has generally refrained from singling out the combatants by name, preferring to call for restraint by all sides. The latest round of fighting in the five-month artillery war over control of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> came Friday, when <LOCATION> Syrian </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> gunners dueled with howitzers and rocket launchers, killing six people. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy toward <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> treads a delicate balance of criticism of the Soviet-backed government for its support of <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> terrorism and seeking to enlist its support for the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> peace process and other negotiations in the volatile region.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>No Evidence of Uncontrolled Chain Reaction: DOE</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Energy Department says investigators found no evidence that an uncontrolled nuclear chain reaction occurred at the Rocky Flats weapons plant near <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. However, the department said Friday that plutonium was found in situations that require `` immediate attention.'' The DOE did not detail those situations or what would be done about them. Plutonium is the nuclear material recovered from weapons being retired and reprocessed at Rocky Flats to make triggers for new weapons. It is highly toxic. The question of a chain reaction arose after radioactive isotopes of strontium and cesium, which do n't occur in nature, were found in groundwater near the plant. Some plant employees claimed that conditions existed routinely that could lead to a chain reaction. An uncontrolled chain reaction produces an explosion in a bomb and a controlled reaction is the basis for nuclear power plants. Officials from the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> and state agencies said the strontium and cesium radioactivity was so low that it was almost undetectable, and might have been the result of fallout from atmospheric nuclear tests of the 1950s and 1960s. Rocky Flats has been criticized for polluting the environment, and the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> has begun an investigation of past practices.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>One Pentagon Official Sworn In; Another Resigns</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> executive <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Betti </PERSON>, sworn in as the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s undersecretary of <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> for acquisition, says there will be a `` fundamental change'' in the way the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spends its money. <PERSON> Betti </PERSON> has been put in charge of streamlining the agency's $ 150 billion-a-year purchasing bureaucracy. `` A fundamental change is required if we are to optimize the overall acquisition process and provide the highest quality products and services to the men and women in the field _ on time and on cost,'' <PERSON> Betti </PERSON> said in a statement Friday. <PERSON> Betti </PERSON> had worked for <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> since 1962, most recently as executive vice president for <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>'s diversified products operation. Also Friday, <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Marsh </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> stepped down from his <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> job after serving the longest term of any such service secretary in the nation's history _ 8 years, 6 months and 15 days. He will be succeeded by <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON>, undersecretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. However, <PERSON> Marsh </PERSON> will be back at the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> on Monday as an adviser to <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>. In February, <PERSON> Marsh </PERSON> broke the record for longevity set by <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON>'s secretary of war, <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Dearborn </PERSON>, who served from 1801 to 1809, according to figures provided by the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s office of public affairs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Poland Bjt   08-12 0634</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland, Bjt,0655</SECOND>
<HEAD>Strike In Gdansk, Soviet Ambassador Meets Communists, Moscow Warnings</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DANISZEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARSAW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tens of thousands of Poles stopped work for an hour in a Solidarity-organized strike, while the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> ambassador met with <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> leaders and officials in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> spoke against upheaval in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. It was the first Soviet government comment on the parliamentary maneuvering in which Solidarity is trying to form a non-Communist government to lead the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s largest <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc ally. The independent Solidarity trade union movement staged the strike in <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> province to demand more pay and an end to <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> influence on management. Soviet Ambassador <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Brovikov </PERSON> held an unusual series of meetings in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> on Friday, including sessions with the chairmen of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peasant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. The parties traditionally have been allied with the Communists, but Solidarity is courting them to form a government. According to the Polish government's <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> news agency, the party leaders and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> ambassador met to discuss starting `` direct cooperation'' with the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and to review reforms in both countries. <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Brovikov </PERSON> met also with Prime Minister Gen. <PERSON> Czeslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiszczak </PERSON>, who is trying to assemble a Communist-dominated Cabinet. Since neither Solidarity nor the Communists have a majority in parliament, support from the Peasants and Democrats is crucial for both sides' efforts to form a government. A Soviet official in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, quoted by the official <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency, hinted that Solidarity's attempts to shut the Communists out of a coalition government could hurt stability in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. The unidentified official did not mention Solidarity by name but criticized `` attempts to use the process of forming the Polish government for destabilizing the situation in the country.'' <PERSON> Vadim </PERSON> <PERSON> Perfiliev </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> first deputy, was quoted as telling a news conference that any acts that threaten <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s treaty obligations, `` including those under the <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> and on Soviet-Polish cooperation, would not promote the interests of stability in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>.'' Forming a new government was <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s affair, <PERSON> Perfiliev </PERSON> said, but added that the hoped a `` balanced approach'' would prevail, according to <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION>. The general strike in <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> province by bus drivers, shipbuilders, dockhands and factory workers was Solidarity's first since regaining legal status in April. <PERSON> Bogdan </PERSON> <PERSON> Borusewicz </PERSON>, an organizer, described it as `` exceptionally'' successful. Solidarity said more than 200,000 workers participated and many signed up to join the union, which has grown slowly since legalization. `` Even those enterprises where Solidarity is weak went on strike,'' <PERSON> Borusewicz </PERSON> said. Solidarity's regional council for <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> province estimated more than 90 percent of the 500 enterprises in which it had members took part in the strike. Organizers said it encompassed <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sopot </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gdynia </LOCATION> along the <LOCATION> Baltic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> and inland towns. The province has 1.5 million people. Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, addressing workers in <LOCATION> Gdynia </LOCATION>, referred to parliament's election of <PERSON> Kiszczak </PERSON> as prime minister Aug. 2, and said: `` Let's not allow the monopoly of generals to be reborn.'' The opposition newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Gazeta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wyborcza </ORGANIZATION> said reports were circulating that the opposition was proposing <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> for prime minister. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Madajczyk-Krasowska </PERSON>, a Solidarity spokeswoman, said <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> made no comment on that report Friday. The strike, announced by wailing sirens and whistles at noon, idled the Northern and Repair shipyards in <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> Commune shipyard in <LOCATION> Gdynia </LOCATION> and all ports in both cities, Solidarity said. Buses and streetcars stopped running, and factories displayed banners to show they were participating. Solidarity's birthplace, the <ORGANIZATION> Lenin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipyard </ORGANIZATION>, supported the demands but did not strike. Workers said they did not want to risk upsetting a tentative deal under which American philanthropist <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Piasecka-Johnson </PERSON> would invest in the state-owned yard to save it from bankruptcy. The official trade union federation <ORGANIZATION> OPZZ </ORGANIZATION> said its unions approved of Solidarity's economic demands and it supported the protest.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0255EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-BuffaloMayor Bjt   08-12 0454</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Buffalo Mayor, Bjt,0465</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dog Days of Summer Finds A Three-Way Dogfight for Buffalo Mayor</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DARREN DOPP</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUFFALO, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Politics in this working-class city have never been pretty, and it is not surprising this summer's three-way mayoral race has turned downright ugly. Mayor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> has been called `` a six-pack politician.'' State Assemblyman <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyt </PERSON> was dubbed a `` silk-stocking liberal.'' And, former chief city judge <PERSON> Wilbur </PERSON> <PERSON> Trammell </PERSON> can not shake the tag of being a spoiler. When the candidates are n't calling each other names, they have some choice words for the reporters who cover them. <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> said Monday that 90 percent of the city's journalists were dishonest and he advised them all to `` mind their own business.'' Things began to turn nasty last week when <PERSON> Trammell </PERSON> confirmed he was circulating petitions to qualify himself for an independent line in the Nov. 7 general election. The move was interpreted to mean that even if he lost the Sept. 11 Democratic primary, he would stay in the race. `` Nobody controls me,'' <PERSON> Trammell </PERSON> said. Aides to <PERSON> Hoyt </PERSON>, who has the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s endorsement, blasted <PERSON> Trammell </PERSON> for being a spoiler. <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, a registered Democrat running with the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> endorsement for his fourth, four-year term as mayor, has benefited in past campaigns from having the Democratic vote split among two or more challengers. Polls indicate the same thing may happen this year. In an emotional rebuttal of allegations that he was in the race to help keep <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> in office, <PERSON> Trammell </PERSON> said, `` No six-pack mayor or silk-stocking liberal is going to defeat -LRB- me -RRB- no matter what they try.'' During a major snow storm that hit <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION> in 1985, <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> advised residents to stay in their homes and relax with a six-pack of beer. In addition, <PERSON> Trammell </PERSON> charged that <PERSON> Hoyt </PERSON> `` is in bed with <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, a bigot from day one.'' <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hoyt </PERSON> are white; <PERSON> Trammell </PERSON> is black. <PERSON> Hoyt </PERSON>, in turn, claims that <PERSON> Trammell </PERSON> has `` zero chance'' of winning the primary and should get out of the race. If <PERSON> Trammell </PERSON> quit, <PERSON> Hoyt </PERSON> said his polls show that he would have enough support to beat <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> in a head-to-head matchup either in the primary or the general election. <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> ridiculed <PERSON> Hoyt </PERSON> for having paid $ 50,000 to a pollster `` just to tell him he's losing.'' Added the mayor at a news conference, `` I could have told him that.'' The mayor brushed aside reports that except for his monthly news conference, he has avoided both his opponents and the media. The mayor said that if reporters want to cover him on the campaign trail they should follow him around. He admitted he has n't been making his campaign schedule available, but said he might on request
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0305EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MurderRewards     08-12 0358</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Murder Rewards,358</SECOND>
<HEAD>D.C. Offers Money For Tips on Murders</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Note language in 5th graf.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Informants with tips leading to the arrest of murder suspects will be paid up to $ 10,000 under a program that District of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> police hope will slow a record homicide rate. Police Chief <PERSON> Isaac </PERSON> <PERSON> Fulwood </PERSON>, holding his first news conference Friday, said the new reward system is based on an existing program that pays anonymous individuals up to $ 1,000 for information that leads to convictions in robbery, theft and assault cases. At the same time, Mayor <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> said a new police overtime plan to help slow the pace of killings probably will be scrapped because it is too expensive. <PERSON> Fulwood </PERSON> said the more lucrative reward system was needed because many district residents have become intimidated by drug-related violence and were afraid to speak up. `` There is a tolerance of this. What you have to do, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, is get up off your ass, if you'll pardon the expression, and call us,'' said <PERSON> Fulwood </PERSON> who, along with <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>, unveiled a poster with photographs of 18 murder suspects. Later Friday, police discovered one of the suspects is already in the city jail. Police have made arrests in 181 murder cases this year, <PERSON> Fulwood </PERSON> said. Through Friday, 274 persons had been killed in the nation's capital this year, compared with 191 at the same time last year In 1988, a record 372 persons were killed in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>; police blame more than 60 percent of these slayings on drugs. The program is <PERSON> Fulwood </PERSON>'s second attempt in a week to slow the city's record homicide rate, which increased sharply several weeks ago. On Monday, <PERSON> Fulwood </PERSON> announced that officers working between 3 p.m. and 11 p.m. _ traditionally the period of highest crime _ will now work until 3 a.m. to help stop the murders. However, <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> said after the press conference that the new overtime program likely will be abandoned because it costs too much. Police spokesman Lt. <PERSON> Reginald </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said the new overtime concept will be reviewed next week, and he added that cost will be one of the factors considered.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0306EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Edsels     08-12 0521</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Edsels,0537</SECOND>
<HEAD>To Know Them Is to Love Them, Edsel Owners Say</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto AX1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARC RICE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 To know an Edsel is to love an Edsel, owners of the car say. And to own one is to put up with a lot of jokes. The Edsel, <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'s great failure of the late 1950s, lives on, though only about 3,500 of them are left on the road. The car has a certain mystique that draws many Edsel owners to gatherings such as the 21st annual meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Edsel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, a four-day affair that ends today. The club, which claims 1,500 members, holds parts auctions, exhibitions and awards banquets at its annual gathering, which also provides a chance for the Edsel owners to get together and talk about their passion _ the car whose name for many is synonymous with failure. `` We're proud of our Edsels,'' said <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>, who brought his white 1959 model from <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, for the meeting. `` We talk about the love and labor we put into them.'' Because of the car's lack of success during its time, jokesters enjoy taking the Edsel and its owners for a ride. `` I think they're jealous,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Watson </PERSON>, an Edsel owner from <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> launched the gadgety Edsel on Sept. 4, 1957, with an unprecedented marketing blitz <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> lost about $ 450 million, and the car was discontinued by 1960. But it has since become the stuff of legends. There have been different theories as to why the Edsel bombed. Some say it was a combination of a reaction against the hype, a recession in the auto industry at the time and the car's unusual `` horse collar'' grill. `` I love the design of it now. It was way before its time,'' said <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Sica </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jefferson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, who drove his white'59 model to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, said the meetings provide a chance for Edsel owners to swap or bid to buy parts for their cars. He said his <ORGANIZATION> Edsel </ORGANIZATION> gets him lots of attention, both for its unusual looks and its frequent breakdowns. `` It's embarrassing when they break down, and they do that a lot. But all old cars do that,'' said <PERSON> Sica </PERSON>, an electrician. `` When you break down and pull over on the side of the road, everybody ribs you.'' <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Mableton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, who helped organize this year's club meeting, said the scarcity of spare parts is a problem for Edsel owners `` Edsels are difficult to restore,'' he said. `` It's not like a Mustang or a Corvette, where you can buy parts over the counter. Most -LRB- Edsel -RRB- parts were destroyed because <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> was so distraught over the failure.'' Many of the Edsel owners say their classics are for special purposes only. They work on them as a hobby and take them out for shows. But <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Daumiller </PERSON> -LRB-'59, yellow -RRB- of <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, said his Edsel is his main car. He takes it to the shows but also uses it to go grocery shopping. `` It's a wonderful car,'' he said. `` Kind of stupid and ugly looking, though.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0307EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Voyager-Neptune Bjt   08-12 0656</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Voyager-Neptune, Bjt,0672</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ring Arcs Added to Voyager 2 Discoveries as Spacecraft Nears Neptune</HEAD>
<HEAD>With LaserGraphic</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE SIEGEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PASADENA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Voyager 2, now 12 days from its close encounter with <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>, has made another discovery that thrilled scientists: two partial rings of debris orbiting the solar system's fourth-largest planet `` There is a mood of total elation here,'' said astronomer <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> <PERSON> Terrile </PERSON>, of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>'s Jet Propulsion Laboratory. `` We're really just ecstatic. ... Everything we've hoped to look at we're going to get to see.'' Early Friday, <ORGANIZATION> Voyager </ORGANIZATION> 2 photographed the two partial rings, called `` ring arcs.'' They are arc-shaped belts different from the complete rings that encircle <ORGANIZATION> Saturn </ORGANIZATION>, Uranus and Jupiter. Since early July, <PERSON> Voyager </PERSON> has discovered four small moons orbiting <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> in addition to the previously known moons, Nereid and <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION>. The probe also has discovered 2,700-mile-wide dark bands _ possibly jet stream-like belts of windblown clouds _ forming a collar around <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>'s south pole and possibly its north pole. Voyager 2 earlier revealed a 6,200-mile-wide dark spot in the planet's atmosphere, probably a giant storm like <ORGANIZATION> Jupiter </ORGANIZATION>'s Great Red Spot. Today, Voyager 2, traveling at 42,198 mph, was 2.72 billion miles from <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> and 11.3 million miles from <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>, the fourth largest planet of the solar system and eighth planet from the sun. On Aug. 24, Voyager 2 is expected to fly about 3,000 miles above <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>'s cloudtops. The probe was launched in 1977, and explored Jupiter in 1979, <ORGANIZATION> Saturn </ORGANIZATION> in 1981 and Uranus in 1986. One of the two ring arcs detected Friday extends one-eighth of the distance around <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>'s equator, and the other only one-thirty-sixth around the planet. That makes them about 30,000 miles and 6,000 miles long, respectively, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Terrile </PERSON> said they may prove longer upon closer examination. `` Voyager scientists said the ring arcs may be comprised of debris associated with nearby moons, or may be remnants of moons that have been torn apart or ground down through collisions,'' <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> said. Scientists do n't yet know if the ring arcs are made up of dust, pebbles or boulders, or if the debris consists primarily of rock or ice, said <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> planetary scientist <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, who heads the team analyzing photographs taken by the spacecraft. Researchers also do n't know if the two partial rings found by <PERSON> Voyager </PERSON> are among the three to six ring arcs that scientists previously believed they detected from <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, but `` it would be surprising if they were n't,'' he added. Voyager project scientist <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> has said <PERSON> Voyager </PERSON> may discover 50 to 100 partial rings orbiting <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>. `` Astronomers have long suspected the existence of ... an irregular ring system around <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> said. `` Voyager's photographs of the rings arcs are the first photographic evidence that such a ring system exists. The three to six previously suspected ring arcs were detected by telescopes on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> as <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> passed in front of a distant star. <ORGANIZATION> Saturn </ORGANIZATION>'s extensive rings are made mostly of marble-sized ice pebbles, while Uranus' rings contain very dark boulders of unknown composition, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. Jupiter is encircled by a single thin ring and a sheet of fine dust, while <ORGANIZATION> Saturn </ORGANIZATION> has some ring arcs in addition to its rings, <PERSON> Terrile </PERSON> said Why does <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> have partial rather than complete rings? `` That's the $ 64,000 question,'' <PERSON> Terrile </PERSON> said. `` Rings come in a variety of shapes and sizes, all the way from complete disks of material like we've seen at <ORGANIZATION> Saturn </ORGANIZATION>, to narrow thin complete ringlets like we've seen at Uranus. ... We believe the gravitational influence of moons that orbit nearby give rings their particular form.'' Voyager 2 detected the 30,000-mile-long arc just outside the orbit of one of the newly discovered moons, designated 1989 N4, which orbits about 23,300 miles above <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>. The 6,000-mile long arc seems to trail about 50,000 miles behind moon 1989 N3, which orbits about 17,000 miles above <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>'s cloudtops, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Springsteen     08-12 0164</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Springsteen,0168</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Boss Takes Stage With Ringo in New Jersey</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HOLMDEL, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rock star <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON>, watching <PERSON> Ringo </PERSON> <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> and his band at a performance, gave the audience a treat by jumping on stage and playing alongside the former Beatles drummer. <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON>, who made his name playing small venues on the <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> shore, joined <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> on Friday at the <ORGANIZATION> Garden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> for the concert's final four songs, beginning with the Beatles classic `` Get Back.'' <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> is on a 30-city <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tour which began in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> on July 23 and closes in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> on Sept. 4. Among those accompanying him are two members of <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON>'s E Street Band, saxophonist <PERSON> Clarence </PERSON> <PERSON> Clemens </PERSON> and guitarist <PERSON> Nils </PERSON> <PERSON> Lofgren </PERSON>. <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON> joined the band in `` Have Some Fun Tonight,'' <PERSON> Starr </PERSON>'s early solo hit `` Photograph,'' and the finale, the Beatles' `` With A Little Help From My Friends. Also joining the band for the finale was comedian <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Candy </PERSON>, who clowned and played the tambourine.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0316EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Women'sDepression Bjt   08-12 0501</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Women's Depression, Bjt,0517</SECOND>
<BYLINE>Women Run High Depression and Misdiagnosis Risk, Committee Says
^By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Women run about twice the risk of men of becoming depressed, and it is misdiagnosed in them up to half the time, a new report said. Cultural factors are a major reason for the higher incidence, and a tendency of physicians to interpret depressive symptoms as physical illness causes misdiagnosis, said <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON>, head of the group that drafted the report. Findings of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Task </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> on Women and Depression were discussed Friday at the association's annual meeting. The task force examined several studies, which have consistently found that women run twice the risk of depression as men, <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON> said. The `` average'' woman runs about a 25 percent chance of major depression, and the risk jumps to 51 percent for female physicians and 37 percent for female psychologists, <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON> said. One reason for the high rates is biology, since women run about a 50 percent chance of mild mood disturbance premenstrually and a 50 percent to 80 percent of mild depression after giving birth, she said. Women who take birth control pills also run a heightened risk of depression, she said. Another reason is what <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON> called a surprisingly high incidence of violence against women. Research suggests 37 percent of women have experienced sexual or physical abuse before age 21, and some estimates run higher than 50 percent, she said. Such abuse can lead to prolonged depression in adult women, she said. Women are taught to be passive and dependent, contributing to their depression risk, she said. Calling poverty a `` pathway to depression,'' she said 75 percent of the nation's poor are women and children. Some 71 percent of women have had a significant instance of sexual harassment on the job, she said. Several studies suggest a misdiagnosis rate of 30 percent to 50 percent in women, she said. The problem appears because depressed women often seek help by telling obstetricians, family doctors or internal medicine specialists that they feel poorly or are tired, <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON> said. The physicians frequently approach it as a medical problem and try to treat it that way, which does not work, she said. <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON> said she did not know how frequently male depressives are misdiagnosed. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Scheiber </PERSON>, a psychiatry professor at <ORGANIZATION> Northwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said in a telephone interview that a 50 percent misdiagnosis estimate `` sounds high.'' `` Certainly we all know it happens,'' he said, but he knew of no study of rates of misdiagnosing depression. Physicians learn about depression as part of their training, he said. But he also noted that federal mental health officials are encouraging family physicians and specialists to recognize depression in their patients. <PERSON> Scheiber </PERSON> also said the doubled rate of depression for women in comparison to men showed up in a recent study of five communities. While not a nationally representative sample, the work provides the best available estimate of depression rates, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Panama Bjt   08-12 0603</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama, Bjt,0622</SECOND>
<HEAD>Troops Again Detain U.S. Soldiers; Noriega Blasts Plebiscite Proposal</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALINA GUERRERO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Panamanian troops briefly detained American soldiers in another confrontation between both sides, and Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> again indicated he has no intention of stepping down as <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s leader. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> today marked six years as head of the Panamanian <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> and the nation's de facto ruler. He said Friday that a plebiscite proposed by the opposition for Aug. 20 on whether he should resign was tantamount to turning <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> into `` a colony that accepts arrogance, vassalage and indignity.'' He spoke during a parade of thousands of troops and paramilitary civilian units ending a 10-day exercise called `` Zap the Intruder.'' White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Friday that the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration `` would not rule out'' seizing <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and taking him to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> to face drug trafficking charges. But <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was not contemplating such a move at this time. The latest confrontation between Panamanian and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops occurred in a remote area known as <LOCATION> Curundu </LOCATION> near the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> says the area is a military zone shared by both countries, while the Panamanians claim it is exclusively their domain. A Defense Forces patrol detained four vehicles carrying a number of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military police, and the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> said it quickly dispatched troops backed by armored cars and helicopters. The incident started when `` American troops went around in civilian clothes, with their weapons, riding in private vehicles in violation'' of the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> treaties, said Panamanian Maj. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Saldana </PERSON>. `` No country in the world can accept that units, claiming to be part of an army, move in within its territory armed and in civilian clothes,'' he said. `` If they tried to do this in any other nation they would be killed like common muggers, like a vulgar thief.'' The confrontation ended after a meeting between <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> and American military officers, a <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> news release said. The command called the detentions `` unjustified.' `` The vehicles were freed after <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military officers discussed the situation with officers of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>,'' said a news release issued by the command. Neither the Panamanians nor the Americans said how many <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military police or what kind of vehicles were involved. Similar incidents in recent weeks coincided with <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> exercises and there have been arrests on both sides. Earlier this week, American troops blockaded <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Amador </LOCATION>, which contains <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Panamanian military facilities. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials insist they have the right to conduct exercises under the 1977 <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> treaties to assure canal security. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, however, accuses the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> of seeking to abrogate the treaties and keep the canal, which is to be turned over to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> at the end of 1999. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has been trying to pressure <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to quit as head of the military since two federal grand juries in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> indicted him on drug trafficking and money laundering charges in February 1988. However, tactics that have included economic and trade sanctions have failed to budge <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Endara </PERSON>, the opposition leader who proposed holding the plebiscite on <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s rule, responded a few hours after <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s rejection Friday by calling the leader a dictator <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> also accused <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> of subservience to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` We never were and never will be employees of the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>, while he himself was one,'' <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> said in an interview. International observers say the opposition won the May 7 presidential election by a landslide. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s regime annulled the balloting a few days later, saying there had been vote fraud.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0321EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Bloch     08-12 0560</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bloch,0580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bloch Says He Was In Paris In May, Leaves Open Spying Question</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALISON SMALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Suspended <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomat <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> said he was in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> the day he allegedly left a briefcase in a restaurant for a Soviet agent, but he declined to confirm or deny spying allegations against him. <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> spoke in an Austrian television and radio interview broadcast Friday from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. It was the second time in the past week that he declined opportunities in interviews with Austrian media to deny the suspicions. The Austrian-born diplomat, formerly the No. 2 man in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>, was suspended from the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> on June 22 In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> Friday said public disclosure of its investigation of <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>, 54, had compromised the government's ability to obtain evidence against him. `` There is no doubt that the premature disclosure of that case, the premature disclosure that there was an ongoing investigation, did compromise the investigation,'' department spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> said without elaboration. No charges have been brought against <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>. He remains under investigation and surveillance by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, and reporters have followed him around <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in recent days. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> has reported that on May 14, <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> arrived in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and met his alleged contact for dinner. <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> left his briefcase under the table to be picked up by the suspected Soviet agent, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> said. Asked by Austrian TV correspondent <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiesner </PERSON> whether he was in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> May 14, <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> said after a long pause, `` Yes.'' He declined, however, to specify whether he met <PERSON> Reino </PERSON> <PERSON> Gikman </PERSON>, a man holding Finnish documents who regularly visited <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> during <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>'s 1980-87 tour in the Austrian capital. <PERSON> Gikman </PERSON> has been identified by Austrian and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> authorities as a suspected <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> agent who might have been a contact man. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sources have said <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> contends he only knew the man as a stamp collector. When <PERSON> Wiesner </PERSON> pressed <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> for details of the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> trip, <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> said, `` I was in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> May 14. I was in a restaurant, and there were very many people in that restaurant, and I enjoyed the food there very much.'' `` Have you missed your briefcase since?'' asked <PERSON> Wiesner </PERSON>. After another long pause, <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>, who seemed relaxed and spoke in his native German, said: `` No.'' <PERSON> Wiesner </PERSON> repeatedly pressed <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> to deny he was a spy. `` Why do n't you just say it was all just invented?'' he asked. `` I could say much on this topic, but I will restrain myself,'' <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> answered. By remaining silent, <PERSON> Wiesner </PERSON> noted, <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> only heightens suspense. `` I do n't want people to feel bored during August,'' <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> said, smiling. `` Are the accusations against you justified?'' <PERSON> Wiesner </PERSON> asked again several minutes later. `` This question I can not answer now,'' <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> responded. In a much briefer interview in the current issue of the Austrian weekly <ORGANIZATION> Profil </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> was similarly elusive. Asked why he did not say straight out he is not a spy, he replied: `` There are accusations, there is no proof. My guilt must be proved.'' <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> first accepted an invitation to visit the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> offices of <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>'s state-run television 10 days ago, but declined then to be interviewed. <PERSON> Wiesner </PERSON> said the second visit on Thursday began with <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> viewing cassettes of <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>. The two chatted about Viennese cemeteries, and then <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> agreed to answer questions, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890812-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-89 0323EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SculptureCity     08-12 0646</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sculpture City,0666</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Sweetheart City' Becomes Haven for Sculptors</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JULIA RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOVELAND, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
