<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0042EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     01-21 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0026</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 07; 14; 17; 29; 34; 40.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0042EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     01-21 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0090</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 07; 14; 17; 29; 34; 40.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 0-0-6-6.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 02; 09; 13; 25; 27; 33.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 06; 08; 20; 21; 25; 37. Bonus 22730.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 02; 06; 21; 22; 30; 48. Supplementary 52.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 0-8-0-8.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 1-6-5; 9-4-6-9; 7-6-9-9-6; 3-1-6-5-5-6.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0108EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Burma-Fighting     01-21 0204</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Burma-Fighting,0208</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fighting Inside Burma Spills Over Border Into Thailand</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TAK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mortar shells from fighting between <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> troops and rebel forces destroyed 55 houses and wounded two people at a village just inside the <LOCATION> Thai </LOCATION> border, a senior police officer said today. Col. <PERSON> Amphol </PERSON> <PERSON> Ngamchit </PERSON>, police chief of <ORGANIZATION> Tak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Province </ORGANIZATION>, said a woman and a young girl were wounded in <LOCATION> Mae </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salit </LOCATION> village, which straddles the Burma-Thailand frontier. Damage was estimated at $ 500,000. The fighting Friday was part of an intensified campaign by the <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> military against the <ORGANIZATION> Karen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, the strongest of a dozen ethnic minority organizations seeking greater autonomy. The Karen groups fields about 4,000 guerrillas and operates primarily along the rugged <LOCATION> Thai </LOCATION> border. Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Khin </PERSON> <PERSON> Nyunt </PERSON> told journalists in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> capital, that <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> forces captured the <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> stronghold of Kler Day a week ago and last Thursday seized <PERSON> Maetri </PERSON>, another <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> settlement. Thai officials said hundreds of armed Karens fled to areas southeast of Kler Day where the guerrillas hoped to regroup. Late last year, the <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> army retook the vital border village of <LOCATION> Mae </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Waw </LOCATION>, disrupting the rebels' main source of revenue _ a lucrative smuggling trade between <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Afghanistan     01-21 0679</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghanistan,0702</SECOND>
<HEAD>Steady Stream of Wounded in Kabul; Some Fear Worst To Come</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MAUREEN JOHNSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The victims arrive day and night at the sand-bagged <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>: men with shattered legs or stomachs ripped open by bullets, and children burned by anti-missile flares. There are fears of worse to come as the last of the Soviet troops depart <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in the next few weeks to try to meet a Feb. 15 deadline. The nation's pro-Marxist regime led by President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> will be left with its poorly trained army to face the guerrillas alone, and some Western diplomats say the guerrillas will win. Gunfire and explosions have been heard regularly the past few nights, and rifle-toting Afghan soldiers are deployed throughout the city. The Swiss-run <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> opened the 50-bed hospital in October in a villa beside the frozen <LOCATION> Kophen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> in central <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. It has 16 foreign and 140 Afghan staff members. Victims arrive in ancient taxis or are carried by relatives. Some of the latest arrivals were shot or wounded hours earlier by mines, which are planted around <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> and villages in the surrounding hills. Other victims were wounded weeks or months ago and have infected limbs, sometimes the result of botched surgery at government hospitals. As several victims arrived, <PERSON> Ingrid </PERSON> <PERSON> Andersson </PERSON>, the Swedish chief nurse, cajoled an apprehensive middle-aged man into giving blood for the relative he had brought in with shrapnel wounds to the chest. Minutes later word came that seven more patients were on their way. Nurses chased relatives from a waiting area to make room, and set up brightly colored lounge chairs as temporary beds. `` There's a lot of shooting in the city. Most of the ones coming now seem to have been hit by stray bullets,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Kari </PERSON> <PERSON> Koskinen </PERSON>, a Finnish surgeon. <PERSON> Koskinen </PERSON>'s three-member team and one led by Dr. <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Hewitson </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> surgeon who arrived this week, alternate shifts and are on call around the clock. Most of the foreign staff, from a half-dozen Western European countries and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, have worked civil wars in <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, and in <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>'s refugee camps. Many say they sense there is a lot more killing to come in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. The guerrillas began fighting after a communist coup in April 1978, and Soviet troops entered <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in December 1979. Since then, an estimated 1 million people have been killed in the civil war, and one-third of the nation's population of 15 million has sought refuge in neighboring <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. In the past two weeks, the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> has readied a 100-bed extension to the hospital. `` I just have the impression that this is the beginning of a very, very bad time,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Keusen </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Swiss </LOCATION> radiographer and laboratory technician who arrived eight months ago from <LOCATION> Uganda </LOCATION>. `` We could set up a hospital for 500 patients, for 1,000, it would still be too small.'' But somehow, the hospital staff finds room for the wounded. Beds are jammed together. An old man with leg injuries lay semi-conscious next to a cheerful 12-year-old boy who was shot in the spine four months ago during a clash betweeen guerrillas and government troops outside <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. The boy will never walk again. A 10-year-old girl shows a visitor the healing burns that cover her left leg. At the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> artificial limb center in the city's industrial district, French physiotherapist <PERSON> Christoph </PERSON> <PERSON> Etienne </PERSON> makes tough choices daily. There's a waiting list of 1,500. Most of the patients are disabled soldiers, but women and children get priority, followed by young men over old, and amputees with one leg over people who have lost both legs and are least capable of using artificial limbs. The center opened in 1987, making it the first international facility the Afghan government allowed into the country to help the war-wounded. The <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> has run hospitals and clinics in <LOCATION> Pakinstan </LOCATION> throughout most of the <LOCATION> Afghan </LOCATION> conflict, mainly serving civilians and guerrillas.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0030EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-InauguralBalls 5thLd-Writethru a0826 01-21 0955</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Inaugural Balls, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0826,950</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Lauds Military Heroes, Dances Reluctantly at Inaugural Balls</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 3rd graf with color on crowd at Kennedy
Center.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of jubilant Republicans celebrated <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s brand-new presidency at 11 inaugural balls Friday night, and during a fast-paced tour of the merrymaking <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> took a few reluctant whirls around the dance floor. He called himself `` a lousy dancer'' and told one crowd rocking to the music of <PERSON> Lionel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hampton </PERSON>: `` I hope you do n't judge my being a president by the way I dance.'' A chill wind whipped evening gowns and fur stoles as 60,000 party faithful thronged from Union Station to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> and Space Museum to the Kennedy Center on the banks of the moonlit <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION> for a night of dancing and carousing. Inside the <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, the air was hot and thick as 5,000 guests were jammed shoulder-to-shoulder in the Grand Foyer to awaiting the president's arrival. Several people fainted, and for one woman, the crowd was so dense that she could n't fall down after she passed out. Hours after he was sworn in as President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s successor on the steps of the Capitol, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> began his tour of the invitation-only balls with a visit to an American Legion affair for 149 Medal of Honor winners _ including freshman Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON>, D-Neb. _ and other military heroes. `` I'll do my level best to be a president who respects the military ... and keeps the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> strong,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who was accompanied by former Rep. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON>, R-Ill., his choice to be secretary of the new Department of Veterans Affairs <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also let slip that he's not particularly keen on dancing. `` This is the first formal event ... and perhaps the most humane,'' he said, `` a ball at which you do not have to dance.'' But by the time he reached Union Station, the president finally took his wife, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>, onto the dance floor as the band struck up `` I Could Have Danced All Night.'' `` You can say that you saw it first here,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` a lousy dancer trying to dance his first dance with the first lady of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' A while later, at the cavernous Pension Building, the president quipped, `` the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> family is going to give dancing a bad name.'' He took a few turns with Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and stopped abruptly. `` That's it,'' he said. `` That's the only step I know.'' Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> apparently felt the same way. He told revelers at another hotel ballroom that `` I guess protocol allows you to witness my inability to dance.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> then took a few stiff turns on the dance floor with his wife, <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON>, as the band played a tune from `` My Fair Lady.'' Tickets to the nine crowded black-tie balls sold for $ 175 each, assuring guests the privilege of jostling for drinks at cash bars and catching brief glimpses of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. Tickets were easier t obtain for two casual-dress balls for the 30-and-under crowd, where the drinks had more fizz than kick. `` To be included in this is incredible,'' said <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Trost </PERSON>, 16, of <LOCATION> Fairfax </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, who got her $ 30 ticket from a friend and joined several thousand other youngsters in dancing to loud recorded rock music and videos. When <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> showed up at one of the youth balls, he recalled the inaugural parade and said, `` It was the young people that brought that thing alive.'' Outside one hotel, a group protesting the killing of animals for their fur hides picketed arriving guests, many of whom wore fur coats. The demonstrators carried signs reading, `` Fur Is Murder'' and `` I'm Warm. I'm Not Wearing Fur.'' A star of one hotel ball was 7-year-old <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Catonia </PERSON>, the current <ORGANIZATION> Little </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Miss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Buffalo </ORGANIZATION>. The girl's mother, <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON>, said her daughter was conceived at the same hotel during <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s first inauguration in 1981. Before the hoopla began, inaugural officials had said a $ 175 ticket to the black-tie events, reserved for invited guests, would get them little more than `` the honor of being there.'' Bars at each site were charging for drinks, there was no food and the dance floors promised to be gridlocked. The partying continues Saturday with scores of social events around the capital, including a `` Black Tie and Boots'' ball for 5,500 Texans that sold out within 24 hours. The four days of inaugural festivities costing a record $ 22 million to $ 25 million will end with a Sunday morning worship service at <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Cathedral which was requested by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. One highlight of the week was a two-hour variety show Thursday night at the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Convention Center, where <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> joined 12,000 black-tie guests in applauding big-name performers from <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> to country singer <PERSON> Loretta </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON>. The gala was broadcast live on television and grossed about $ 9 million from ticket and TV commercial sales to help defray costs of the privately financed inauguration week. Meanwhile, those protesting the policies of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and what they fear will be those of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration held their own Counter-Inaugural Ball at the <ORGANIZATION> Crispus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Attucks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> on Friday night, with a $ 6 to $ 10 sliding scale admission charge. The dance party was arranged by the <ORGANIZATION> Counter-Inaugural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> a </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agenda </ORGANIZATION>, a coalition of 80 groups ranging from the <ORGANIZATION> Gray </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Panthers </ORGANIZATION> to the Student Coalition Against Apartheid and Racism. Those attending were asked to wear `` their finest trash,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Hasty </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Peace Center, a member of the coalition. Live music was planned for the first hour, followed by a disk jockey playing tapes `` so people can dance the night away.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Striptease-Homeless     01-21 0375</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Striptease-Homeless,0385</SECOND>
<HEAD>Restaurateur Defends Exotic Male Dance Fund-raiser For Shelter</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CLARKSBURG, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A restaurateur who held an exotic male-dance show to raise money for a shelter for the homeless says she does n't understand why some people objected to the show. `` I ca n't understand the uproar'' over Friday's show, said <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Beaudin </PERSON>, owner of the <LOCATION> Mountainview </LOCATION> Restaurant in this northwestern <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> town. `` I just thought it would be nice -LRB- for patrons -RRB- to donate $ 10 and get something in return.'' However, some people in nearby <PERSON> North </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> strenuously objected to the show, saying they believed it was in poor taste. `` I do n't think it's right to hire male dancers for a cause like this,'' said City Council Member <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Babeu </PERSON>. `` It tarnishes it somewhat.'' Ms. <PERSON> Beaudin </PERSON> said she sold all 220 tickets nearly a week before the two-hour performance, and said she was pleased it all worked out well. `` Now I feel fine,'' she said. `` I was just hoping it went well because it really is to benefit the homeless. People are just having a good time.'' Ticket sales brought in about $ 2,000. The money will go to a 24-bed shelter for the area's homeless, which welfare workers say is urgently needed to house the increasing numbers of families seeking shelter. <ORGANIZATION> Northern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Berkshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> Action _ a branch of the private, non-profit <ORGANIZATION> Berkshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> which uses state grants to help the homeless _ has been handling 10 to 15 family or individual cases a month, said branch Director <PERSON> Theresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Louison </PERSON>. That compares with one case every month or two five years ago. Ms. <PERSON> Beaudin </PERSON> said the situation prompted her to look for a creative solution. She held a spaghetti supper fund-raiser in November, but made only $ 900. She said she saw the dance as an easier way to raise money. The <LOCATION> Clarksburg </LOCATION> board of selectmen waived the usual $ 75 entertainment license fee so Ms. <PERSON> Beaudin </PERSON> could use the money to hire police guards. `` She has the right to put it on if it's done properly and there is no physical contact,'' said <PERSON> Selectman </PERSON> <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Deneault </PERSON>, who added that he had heard no complaints from people in the town of 1,890 people. `` Most of the people doing the complaining are from <PERSON> North </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0034EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ShuttleTest 1stLd-Writethru a0406 01-21 0429</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Shuttle Test, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0406,0436</SECOND>
<HEAD>Last Of Six Space Shuttle Booster Tests Conducted Friday</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: RETRANSMITTING to restore writethru designation; UPDATES throughout
with test deemed a success; no pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURIE SULLIVAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BRIGHAM CITY, Utah (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> successfully tested its redesigned space shuttle booster Friday, firing the rocket in colder weather than that which contributed to the Challenger disaster. `` The nation has a new president today and a new success in its space flight program,'' said <PERSON> Royce </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s solid-fuel rocket motor project manager at the <ORGANIZATION> Marshall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Flight </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, in <LOCATION> Huntsville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala </LOCATION>. The $ 20 million test, the last of six qualifying tests, was designed to show the strength of the rocket's casing and the behavior of its solid-fuel propellant, which has n't as much `` oomph'' in cold weather, <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said. Early test data showed the propellant's burn rate was normal for the conditions and there was no evidence of the uneven burning that could have occurred at that temperature, he said. The horizontal 126-foot-long booster, its 1.1 million pounds of propellant chilled to a coldest-ever 40 degrees, was fired for 125 seconds at the company's <ORGANIZATION> Wasatch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION> center 25 miles west of here. The bright orange plume from the rocket's tail melted the snow from a nearby hillside during the test, which was delayed for 90 minutes by a lack of wind to blow away dust from the blast. About 300 company and space officials cheered as the rocket ignited. If post-test analysis turns up no serious problems, the experiment will qualify the rocket for cold-weather launches, although further testing on a smaller scale is planned, said <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>, vice president of engineering for space operations. Identical boosters already have been used on two shuttle flights in the four months since <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s return to manned space flight. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> ordered <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> to redesign the booster after a Jan. 28, 1986, explosion destroyed the shuttle Challenger and killed its seven astronauts. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> required only five qualifying tests before the shuttle program resumed with the launch of Discovery on Sept. 29. The shuttle Atlantis was sent into space Dec. 2, and in both cases the boosters performed with no problems. A presidential commission blamed the Challenger disaster on a booster joint that allowed a plume of superhot gas to burn through an O-ring, triggering the explosion of the craft's liquid fuel tank. Investigators also found that freezing temperatures the night before the launch stiffened the joint's rubber-like O-ring seal, causing it to lose pliability and contributing to the failure.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SeaLions     01-21 0617</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sea Lions,0633</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sea Lion Relocation Planned To Cut Fish Losses In Seattle</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DERMOT COLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nets, firecrackers and recordings of killer whales have n't stopped sea lions from gobbling trout and salmon swimming through a ship canal, so wildlife officials are going to send the overeaters into exile. This year's run of steelhead, a seagoing rainbow trout that returns to fresh water to spawn, was about 1,650 at a fish ladder that lets fish bypass a set of locks, down from about 2,600 last year, officials said this week. Seven to nine <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> sea lions `` hanging around'' the locks are gulping an average of 14 fish a day each, said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>, state <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. Despite a net barrier erected last year, the 300 - to 800-pound animals ate 53 percent of the run, <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> said Sea lions eat 5 percent of their body weight daily, said <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ewing </PERSON>, a department spokeswoman. The new plan calls for installing a cage near the mouth of Salmon Bay below the locks on the <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ship </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canal </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON> section, said <PERSON> Tag </PERSON> <PERSON> Gornall </PERSON>, a Marine Animal Resource Center veterinarian The cage of five-sixteenths-inch steel mesh will be mounted on a buoy that was a favorite sea lion resting place and will have a trap door that can be closed by rope from a nearby boat, said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> DeLong </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fisheries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> mammals laboratory. Sea lions heading for their usual easy pickings in the pool below the fish ladder at the locks will be trapped, tagged with radio collars and trucked about 200 miles to the <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>, just north of the mouth of the <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, and released on the coast. <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION> was chosen `` because you ca n't extradite them,'' <PERSON> Gornall </PERSON> said, `` and besides <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> have enough of their own sea lions and do n't want any more.'' Asked about the difficulty of moving one of the animals, <PERSON> DeLong </PERSON> said it could be about the same as moving a `` leather bag filled with 600 pounds of rocks.'' <PERSON> DeLong </PERSON> said he expects the sea lions will be back for more fish, perhaps as soon as five days after they are removed. He said the animals migrate from their <LOCATION> Baja </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> breeding grounds every year and they know the route. `` I reckon they'll know where they are when we put them off the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> coast,'' he said. The operation will begin as soon as the cage is completed, said Ms. <PERSON> Ewing </PERSON>. The feasting sea lions have been the bane of fishermen and others concerned about the salmon run but have delighted residents and tourists who flock to the locks to watch the spectacle and applaud the frolicking animals. The sea lions have become a problem at the locks only in the last couple of years. Scientists have said sea-lion populations have been growing since federal legislation protecting marine mammals took effect several years ago. Only one or two sea lions feasted outside the <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ship </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canal </ORGANIZATION> in 1984, but others caught on quickly, <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ewing </PERSON> said. `` They kind of see their buddies over there. Since 1984 that one or two has grown to the neighborhood of 20 problem animals,'' she said. Along with firecracker noisemakers and recordings of sea lion predators such as killer whales, offerings of dead fish injected with a sickening substance failed as deterrents. Rubber bullets have been rejected _ for now. `` We must exhaust all other viable options before we even consider shooting the sea lions _ the last option,'' <PERSON> Gornall </PERSON> said. `` We're trying to save and manage the fishery and the animals.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Reagan Bjt   01-21 0590</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagans in California, Glad to be There</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his wife say there are no movie parts in his future, but they both plan to keep busy in the home state that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> says is not so much a place as a way of life. `` I do n't even use the word retirement,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told reporters aboard the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> plane that flew him here Friday after the inauguration of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The former president and first lady came back toward the reporters' seats early in their flight West and answered questions for about 20 minutes. When the plane arrived at <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> were greeted by an enthusiastic crowd and then driven to their new home in the fashionable Bel Air neighborhood by motorcade. Their spokesman, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON>, said they planned a private weekend and no announcements would be made about their activities. `` We're just moving into a new house,'' said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. `` We did n't get the job done over the holidays when we were there. The <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> slept a total of nine nights in the home around Christmas and just after New Year's Day. `` Obviously, we have to unpack,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, a movie actor before he entered politics, was asked if he could n't be tempted to re-enter films, even in a cameo part. `` No, there is kind of a lingering feeling that would look a little bit like trying to cash in on this job that I've had,'' he said. But, a reporter asked, aside from making money, would n't it be appropriate to go back to what he did before politics? `` Well ...'' said the former president. `` You do n't go back,'' said his wife. `` No,'' he agreed. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said he plans to write a book and to speak out on behalf of such causes as a presidential line-item veto, a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution and repeal of the two-term limit for presidents. Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said she does n't believe in retirement either and plans to finish a book she is writing and work on behalf of a drug abuse treatment center she is backing in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who had changed to a blue <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> jacket with his name on the pocket after boarding the plane, told reporters he was prepared to hand over power to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` For a long time I had to accept this day and know it was coming,'' he said. Returning to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, he said, `` will be a return to a life we did love very much. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> is n't a place in my mind, it's a way of life, so that is the sweet part of the bittersweet experience.'' There was just one more thing, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said, that the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> wanted to clear up. `` He never took naps,'' she said, bringing the subject up herself. `` No, in eight years, he never took a nap.'' `` She sometimes gets edgy because she thinks I should be able to take a nap,'' the former president said. At the airport <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told the crowd it had been `` a bittersweet several hours this day'' and added, `` I have to warn you, when you have to stay eight years away from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> excerpt for an occasional visit, you live in a perpetual state of homesickness.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> spent 458 days in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> during his eight years as president. By contrast, his predecessor, <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, spent 77 days in his native <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> during his one four-year term.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-InauguralProtests     01-21 0320</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Inaugural Protests,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Slogan Echoed by Inaugural Protesters</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Protesters rebuked President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on his Inauguration Day by twisting his oft-mentioned `` thousand points of light'' into their own `` thousand lights for women's rights'' and `` 1,000 sparks of dissent.'' Nearly 1,000 <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION> demonstrators strewn through the inaugural parade crowd of 300,000 wore buttons Friday that lighted up to read, `` Keep Abortion Legal.'' `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ca n't get to the White House without knowing there are a lot of us who feel very strongly about our constitutional rights,'' said NOW President <PERSON> Molly </PERSON> <PERSON> Yard </PERSON>. In a separate demonstration, four <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> women _ three wearing rubber masks of <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ marched along the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION> sidewalk wearing signs protesting the extravagance of the inauguration and contrasting it to the nation's need to address problems of the homeless, AIDS and other social issues. `` This is pretty much like a coronation in a monarchy,'' said <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Barehr </PERSON>. `` The only difference is <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is n't <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s son. As the Bushes moved by in their car, other protesters shook their fists and jeered, but were virtually drowned out by cheers. Meanwhile, members of the <ORGANIZATION> Counter-Inaugural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> a </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agenda </ORGANIZATION> _ a coalition of 80 groups ranging from the <ORGANIZATION> Gray </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Panthers </ORGANIZATION> to the <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in Solidarity with the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Salvador </ORGANIZATION> _ distributed thousands of leaflets calling for changes in administration policies. Their slogan was `` 1,000 sparks of dissent.'' The coalition called for all people to `` have the right to adequate food, housing, clothing and quality health care and education.'' In addition, the coalition called for a clean environment, the right to safe, legal abortions, and no discrimination against minority groups or AIDS victims. `` We demand a government responsive to the needs of the people and the planet rather than corporate and military interests,'' the group said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SpaceJunk     01-21 0291</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Junk,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>NASA Looks for Super-Precise Radar</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> is looking for a kind of radar that can spot orbiting debris as small as a dime which someday could pose a hazard to its planned space station. The space agency has access to space debris reports from the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, but it says information is still `` extremely limited about the number and size of small debris pieces at the operational altitude range of the space station.'' The station will operate 180 to 360 miles above <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> needs radar that can see debris as small as one centimeter in diameter, compared with the 10-centimeter capability of current systems. The new equipment also would need to calculate the altitude of the objects. A request issued this week for proposals specifies that the new system must be available by October 1991. The space station, named Freedom, is scheduled to be in orbit in 1996. As of Jan. 11, the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> was tracking 7,087 pieces of space junk, 3,142 put into orbit by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and 3,302 left behind by Soviet spacecraft. Space junk has included items such as screws 1 @ 8-inch in diameter missing after a 1984 space shuttle mission, a thermal glove that floated out of Gemini 4 in 1965, and a screwdriver dropped by a spacewalking astronaut aboard the Soviet Mir space station. `` Even the smallest pieces of orbital debris pose a potential hazard'' to the space station, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> said. `` It is important that the pressurized modules of Freedom be built to withstand as much orbital debris damage as possible.'' The station is planned to remain in <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> orbit for up to 30 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-InauguralParade     01-21 0611</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Inaugural Parade,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Leads Own Parade up `America's Main Street'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> led his inaugural parade of floats, bands and military marchers up <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>, walking for a time under bright sunshine along the route to the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> he now calls home. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>, emerged three times from their armor-plated limousine to walk along parts of the parade route from the Capitol to the mansion at 1600 <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION> where they have a four-year lease. At one point, the first lady left her husband's side and rushed over to kiss television weatherman <PERSON> Willard </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, who was broadcasting from the sidelines. The Bushes, followed by Vice President <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON>, and the <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s children, walked the final leg of the 1.6-mile parade route past the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> and into the presidential reviewing stand outside the White House. For nearly three hours, the president and his new vice-president sat with their families, <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> officers, <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> justices and other guests to review floats, bands, dance troupes and equestrian teams representing all 50 states. Darkness fell and bone-chilling cold set in before some 12,000 marchers, 70 floats and 457 horses had filed past the presidential reviewing stand. Most of the people who paid $ 100 a seat in bleachers nearest the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> had left long before the parade ended. For the finale, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his guests stood to sing `` The Battle Hymn of the Republic'' with the <ORGANIZATION> Mormon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tabernacle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Choir </ORGANIZATION>, which arrived on a white float bearing the slogan `` Peace, Prosperity and Independence.'' `` It's a grand day sir, and it's a grand old flag,'' conductor <PERSON> Jerold </PERSON> <PERSON> Ottley </PERSON> told <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, whereupon choir members, sporting yellow plaid scarves, broke into a spirited version of `` It's a Grand Old Flag.'' Like any firemen's parade in towns across <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s inaugural procession had a stream of high school bands, flags, baton twirlers and antique cars But unlike most local parades, this one also had the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> State Marching Band, the Budweiser Clydesdales and the `` President's Own'' <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION> all in the same line. The two grand marshals, comedian <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> and test pilot <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeager </PERSON>, rode to the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on the lead `` Flag Float'' and joined the Bushes in the front row of the reviewing stand. The president's son, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, donned a white ten-gallon hat when the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> float, followed by the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Longhorn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION>, arrived on the scene. The line of march also included a band from <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION>, the president's alma mater, and another from <ORGANIZATION> DePauw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> college that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> attended Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s alma mater, <ORGANIZATION> Purdue </ORGANIZATION>, was represented by a marching band that boasted `` the world's largest drum.'' An obviously delighted president stood up and waved as a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> TBM Avenger torpedo bomber, a duplicate of the plane he piloted during World War II, went by on a float. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> shared a joke as the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrolmen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the first police union to endorse the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> presidential ticket last fall, filed by along with a large float representing <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>'s finest The endorsement was particularly embarrassing for <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s Democratic challenger from <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. During the parade, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> dangled grandchildren on his knee, greeted Cabinet officers and chatted with his children. Across the aisle, the <ORGANIZATION> Quayles </ORGANIZATION> sat alone, speaking only infrequently with the Bushes or others on the platform. Arriving on the platform, Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> greeted <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> with a kiss, then quickly froze to attention after noticing that a color guard was passing by. Each time a flag appeared, Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> stood up and placed her hand over her heart.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BushSpeech-Reaction     01-21 0476</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush Speech-Reaction,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan's Democratic Foes Generally Like What They're Hearing from
Bush</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic lawmakers welcomed <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s inaugural speech as a sign that the new Republican president will have better relations with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> than <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> did, but they also said it offered too few specifics `` I think we're off on a good foot,'' said Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Conyers </PERSON>, D-Mich. `` This has genuinely established a kind of bipartisanship and friendship that should go beyond inaugural speeches. `` I've been very touched by the things he's said in the last several days,'' said Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, D-Ga. `` It's better than what we've had in the past eight years. `` It was a very sensitive speech,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON>, D-Kan. `` In style, it's a dramatic break from <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> It was humane, and it showed a recognition that the Democrats control both houses of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.'' He said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s suggestion in his 20-minute address that the federal government's money needs be reallocated clearly implied a shift from <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s emphasis on military spending to domestic priorities. `` He repeated the themes he's been stating since the election: cooperation and conciliation,'' said <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, D-Wash. `` It is all very well received, and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will respond with an equal effort and attitude. `` <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is extending the hand of friendship, and we intend to extend ours in return,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said he planned to make a speech in response on Wednesday, when the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> reconvenes, `` setting forth some of our objectives for this Congress.'' He said he had discussed his plans for the response with <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said the speech represented `` a good start,'' but added: `` Now the hard part comes _ doing all these things the president wants to do. Former House Speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON>, D-Mass., also welcomed the change `` It's the dawn of a new era,'' he said. `` We're back to normalcy in the White House. How delighted I am.'' Sen. <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.C. </LOCATION>, praised <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s address and predicted he will be a different type of president than <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. `` He remembered the real problems, like the deficit and drugs,'' <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON> said. `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, you can tell by the way he talks, will be a hands-on president. Rather than trying to dismantle the bureaucracy, he'll try to make it work.'' Some lawmakers said that while they welcomed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s heavy emphasis on volunteerism to meet the country's social needs, they were concerned that it might indicate an intent not to put federal money into programs like housing and welfare. `` I just do n't understand how he's going to have <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> be more generous and not spend any more money on the people who need help,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION> `` Be happy, do n't worry _ that's what we heard today.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Fireball 3rdLd-Writethru a0419 01-21 0516</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fireball, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0419,0530</SECOND>
<BYLINE>Falling Soviet Rocket Body Lights Up The Skies</BYLINE>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 8 grafs to UPDATE with fireball sighted in Kentucky,
NORAD spokesman saying object will not be positively identified until Saturday,
edit for transition; picks up 8th graf, ```We've gotten ...''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 A fireball that blazed across the night skies of the central <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on Friday was a Soviet rocket body launched in December and re-entering the atmosphere, authorities said. The rocket was sighted in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, and a number of witnesses called officials to say they had seen it blaze across the sky about 8:10 p.m. CST. Some witnesses said the fireball had fiery tail 30 to 40 miles long. Maj. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Space Command identified the object as a Soviet-built rocket body that was launched sometime last year. `` It came down about 9 p.m. EST,'' <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said. `` There is no way to know as to what happened to it.'' The space command tracks about 7,100 manmade objects and once they start to notice an object falling out of orbit they try to predict its re-entry, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said the object would not be positively identified until Saturday. Earlier in the evening, before the rocket body was tentatively identified, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Cmdr. <PERSON> Dugald </PERSON> <PERSON> Gillies </PERSON>, deputy director of public affairs for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Space Command, said the Space Surveillance Center was monitoring the object. `` We've gotten many calls as well,'' <PERSON> Gillies </PERSON> said. `` To the best of our estimation, it would be a re-entering of a Soviet rocket body from a launch that took place last year. `` -LRB- That's -RRB- as much detail as we have. -LRB- It was -RRB- one of the objects that we track. This re-entry correlates with what we were tracking.'' He said the sightings were made better because of weather that was clear and perfect for such sightings. A dispatcher at the <ORGANIZATION> Oklahoma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> said the office had received calls from `` all over the state.'' `` Altus, <PERSON> Enid </PERSON>, Pawnee, <LOCATION> Muskogee </LOCATION> ... you name it, they've seen it,'' she said. `` We're not sure yet what it was.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and military bureaus and bases across the midwest and southwest were swamped with calls from the curious, officials said. `` It just appeared all of a sudden out of the south and fell straight due north and it left a line just as straight as could be,'' <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> England </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Abilene </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, told the <ORGANIZATION> Abilene </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reporter-News </ORGANIZATION>. Ms. <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> said the rocket was in the sky for about three minutes, slowly streaking across the sky. Sgt. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Lenzini </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Macon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, division of the <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION>, said the display was spectacular. `` I went to the front door about 8:10 p.m. and saw what looked like a cluster of five pieces of some kind of burning debris in the sky,'' <PERSON> Lenzini </PERSON> said. `` It had the effect of Fourth of July, or Roman candles trailing fire behind it,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0158EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Bundy-Crimes 1stLd-Writethru a0430 01-21 0395</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bundy-Crimes, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0430,0403</SECOND>
<HEAD>Attorney: Bundy Confessing To Murders</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 4th graf, ``Tanner would ...,'' to CORRECT spelling of
Washington official to Keppel, sted Kepple.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ORLANDO, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Condemned killer <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> began confessing to the murders of about 30 young women in five Western states, a newspaper reported Saturday. Volusia State Attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON>, a personal friend of Bundy, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orlando </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sentinel </ORGANIZATION> Friday night that he learned of the confessions from law enforcement agents at <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> State Prison near <LOCATION> Starke </LOCATION>. `` It's my information that murders are being solved,'' <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON> said. `` This is coming from law enforcement officers who are participating in these meetings. The information they are giving me is that he is giving them verifiable hard facts concerning unsolved murders.'' <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON> would not identify the officers who spoke to him, but said <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> met Friday with <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Keppel </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state attorney general's office, and <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Hagmaier </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Behavioral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unit </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Quantico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>, who faces execution Tuesday in the slaying of a 12-year-old <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> girl, is scheduled to meet this weekend with authorities from <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON> and his wife met with the killer for about two hours Friday morning before the law enforcement meetings began. Police have mentioned <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> as a suspect in as many as three dozen slayings in the early and mid-1970s in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>. The victims were young women between the ages of 16 and 26. Many were never found. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> has frequently met with investigators and reporters over the past 11 years, but has refused to talk specifically about any of the cases. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>, facing the electric chair for the 1978 murder of <PERSON> Kimberly </PERSON> <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, has tried to trade information about the unsolved murders for a delay in his execution, but Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> rejected the offer. <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON> has been meeting regularly with <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> for about two years. He said the killer told him about a year ago that he wanted to confess to everything he'd done. <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON>, a defense attorney before being elected in November, said they specifically did not discuss details of any of the cases because he is a lawyer. `` I know people wo n't necessarily accept this, but -LRB- <LOCATION> Bundy </LOCATION> -RRB- says it's the right thing to do,'' the attorney said. `` People think he's just trying to buy time.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Bundy 2ndLd-Writethru a0432 01-21 0568</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bundy, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0432,0585</SECOND>
<HEAD>Florida Supreme Court Rejects Bundy Death Appeal</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 5th graf, ``Tanner would ...,'' to CORRECT spelling of
Washington state official's name to Keppel, sted Kepple.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRENT KALLESTAD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Condemned murderer <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> began confessing to the murders of about 30 young women in five Western states Friday, a newspaper reported, and the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Supreme </LOCATION> refused to block his execution. The 42-year-old former law student is slated to die in the electric chair Tuesday for the murder of a 12-year-old <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> girl. Volusia State Attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON>, a personal friend of Bundy, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orlando </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sentinel </ORGANIZATION> Friday night that he learned of the confessions from law enforcement agents at <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prison </ORGANIZATION> near <LOCATION> Starke </LOCATION>, the newspaper said Saturday. `` It's my information that murders are being solved,'' <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON> said. `` This is coming from law enforcement officers who are participating in these meetings. The information they are giving me is that he is giving them verifiable hard facts concerning unsolved murders.'' <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON> would not identify the officers who spoke to him, but said <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> met with <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Keppel </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state attorney general's office, and <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Hagmaier </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Behavioral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unit </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Quantico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> is scheduled to meet this weekend with authorities from <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, said it did n't want to hear from <LOCATION> Bundy </LOCATION> again. Defense attorney <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> was expected to take his appeal to <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION> for a hearing on Saturday morning. The high court rejected three claims from <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> and said his attempt to again raise the issue of mental competency constituted an abuse of process. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> said the issue had not been raised in a timely fashion, should have been raised at an earlier stage and had already been settled in an case in which <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> was convicted of murdering two sorority sisters. The court also said no petition for rehearing will be permitted. `` The question really was, was he able to assist his lawyers?'' said <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, who sought to stop the execution to determine whether <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> was competent during his trial for the murder of <PERSON> Kimberly </PERSON> <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> schoolgirl. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> served as his own attorney through much of that trial. `` Much of what he did, even at the hearing, undermined his defense and his lawyers were having problems controlling him, getting him to make decisions, having problems getting him to stick to decisions,'' said <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>. Attorney General <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Butterworth </PERSON> said after the hearing that <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s attorneys were `` grasping at a straw.'' `` All the courts have found <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> to be competent,'' said <PERSON> Butterworth </PERSON>. The appeal centered on allegations that <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s competence to stand trial was n't adequately reviewed in either the <PERSON> Leach </PERSON> case or an earlier conviction in the 1978 slayings of sorority sisters at <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. They also claimed the judge at the <PERSON> Leach </PERSON> trial improperly discussed the case with prosecutors without defense attorneys present. Those claims were rejected by the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, which said they were not raised in timely fashion in accordance with rules of procedure. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> is under his fourth death warrant. Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> signed the most recent warrant Tuesday after the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> declined to hear the case. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s last stay of execution was in 1986, six hours before he was to go to the electric chair.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0214EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PoliceShooting 3rdLd-Writethru a0433 01-21 0385</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Police Shooting, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0433,0391</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Policemen, Transient Die In Downtown Shootout</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 5-6, `The videotape,' with one graf to indicate videotape
showed man holding a gun until the moment he is seen lying in the street</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto SNJ1</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN JOSE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A homeless man `` cold-bloodedly'' chased and shot two policemen to death Friday before he was killed by other officers in a noontime gun battle recorded by a student television crew. The man, a transient, grabbed the gun of an officer questioning him outside a doughnut shop, then chased the officer and opened fire, wounding him and then fatally shooting him in the head, police and witnesses said. The homeless man then mortally wounded a second officer before other police officers arrived and killed him in a fusillade of pistol and shotgun fire, witnesses and police officials reported. Police said there were 30 witnesses to the incident, which was at least partly recorded by a student television crew from <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clara </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> that was making a film about the homeless across the street from the shooting. The videotape they shot is jumpy and incomplete, but apparently shows the transient firing at the wounded officers, then running across the street while still holding the gun. A moment later, he is shown lying in the street. The second officer died about six hours after the shooting, after undergoing three hours of surgery at the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jose </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, doctors said. Coroners officials in this city, about 40 miles south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, withheld the officers' names until their families could be notified. <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> was driving through the area when he saw a man pointing a gun at the officer. `` He began pursuing the officer. The officer hit the ground. He -LRB- the transient -RRB- cold-bloodedly pursued him,'' said <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>. `` I saw the officer disappear behind a truck. I saw the man lower his gun and shoot.'' The 3 -LCB- - minute audio track of the tape carries the sound of 26 shots, 21 of them during the final 30-second volley that killed the transient The shooting came three days after another drifter, <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON>, opened fire in an elementary school playground in <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>, 80 miles to the east, killing five children and wounded 30 other people before taking his own life.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PrisonFire 7thLd-Writethru a0437-a0439 01-21 0927</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Prison Fire, 7th Ld-Writethru, a0437-a0439,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Fire Breaks Out at Prison, One Inmate Killed</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Combines pvs; SUBS 3rd graf pvs, Mayor Marion, to specify that
Barry mayor of Washington; ADDS one graf after 17th graf pvs, Early today,
with FBI investigating; May stand for AMs.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANITA WOMACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LORTON, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fires set by inmates erupted Friday night in a prison south of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and authorities said an unknown number of inmates were free within the sprawling complex. One inmate was killed and one was injured, authorities said. At least four fires were set in the <LOCATION> Lorton </LOCATION> Reformatory complex, according to authorities. The administration building of the central facility was destroyed by the flames, according to officials at the mayor's command center. District of <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> Mayor <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>, accompanied by his wife <PERSON> Effi </PERSON>, both dressed in formal clothes they wore to Friday night's inaugural balls, arrived early today for a briefing The fires were at the corrections complex, which is operated by the district and located about 20 miles south of the city. The medium-security complex houses about 1,280 inmates from the district in dormitories and has been the scene of numerous inmate protests because of overcrowded conditions. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Wheeler </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the city corrections department, said one inmate was killed in the outbreak and another was injured. No details about the circumstances of those casualties were immediately available. Ms. <PERSON> Wheeler </PERSON> said all inmates had been accounted for and none had escaped from the complex. Firefighters remained outside for about an hour while city corrections officers herded inmates who had been loose in the complex onto a baseball field. Lt. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Fairfax </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, said firemen did not try to put out the fires until it was certain the situation was safe. `` Until we get an area that is confirmed secure, we are keeping our firefighters out,'' he said. It was not clear how many buildings were on fire in the sprawling complex, which sits in a wooded, rolling area near the <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. One official said four buildings had fires, but there were other reports that only two buildings were aflame. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> police were rushed to the area, including officers who had been assigned to protection duties at inaugural balls around the city. The galas were celebrating the inauguration of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> earlier Friday. The fire did not disrupt <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s schedule as he made the rounds of inaugural events, but six police cars, their sirens wailing, sped by on their way to the prison just as the president's motorcade pulled up to a private dinner at the Organization of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> building near the White House. The incident began with a power failure about 9:15 p.m. at the prison's central facility. With the lights out, fires were set by inmates in the building, said Ms. <PERSON> Wheeler </PERSON>. `` We have no idea what specifically is going on inside'' the central facility, she said in answer to a question about the location of inmates. Inmates were herded into a nearby baseball field where they were being guarded by police, Ms. <PERSON> Wheeler </PERSON> said. The fires continued to burn several hours after the first alarm was sounded. Early today, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> fire units arrived to aid <LOCATION> Fairfax </LOCATION> firefighters. <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents also went to the prison, said Ms. <PERSON> Wheeler </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> investigates crimes at the complex. A district police helicopter hovered overhead and some inmates were running loose in an open area within the prison complex. The chronically overcrowded prison complex, made up of a series of smaller prisons, held a total of 6,165 inmates last month, when the district government asked a federal judge to bar newly sentenced felons from the entering city institutions. The city closed its doors to new inmates for six weeks last fall, opening them again only under a federal judge's order. The federal government was forced to take charge of 300 city inmates during that time. The district has also sent more than 200 inmates to the states of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>. Rep. <PERSON> Stan </PERSON> <PERSON> Parris </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>., responding to the violence and frequent escapes from the facility, introduced legislation in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last fall to give <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> some control over the prison complex At the time, he said, `` The situation at <LOCATION> Lorton </LOCATION> reached crisis proportions a decade ago, and it has continued to deteriorate.'' Although there have been isolated incidents at the complex, Friday night's outbreak was the largest since an inmate riot broke out in July, 1986 at the Occoquan I and II facilities, two sections within the <LOCATION> Lorton </LOCATION> institution. One inmate was killed by buckshot wounds to the head suffered when guards tried to quell the uprising. Twenty-nine inmates, nine guards and three firefighters were injured in that riot. The fiery outbreak damaged 13 buildings and many inmates were kept in temporary shelters for a time afterwards. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Koren </PERSON>, an attorney with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Project </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` This is not anything new, we have a long, sad history of overcrowding at these facilities. Inevitably, there are disturbances.'' `` It's really a very dangerous place. They claim it is medium security, but really its used for long timers. It's really just a dormitory. There's a lot of violence, a lot of idlness, conditions are poor, and that's a real dangerous mix.'' The district has been unable to build new facilities at the complex because of political opposition from <LOCATION> Fairfax </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> officials, who oppose the presence of the district prison and hold more power than the city in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0225EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-InauguralBalls Bjt   01-21 0860</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Inaugural Balls, Bjt,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Says He's `a Lousy Dancer' but He Takes a Whirl Anyway</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> called himself `` a lousy dancer'' but gamely took a few whirls with his wife during an exultant tour of inaugural balls where 60,000 Republican stalwarts toasted his swearing-in and caroused into the wee hours today. During the gaudy, noisy and slightly wacky evening, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also bragged about his `` fantastic'' new living quarters at the White House and Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> had one hotel ballroom throng erupting in laughter with an offhand remark with a double meaning. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s choice for secretary of state, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, sashayed with fellow Texans beneath the <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> brothers' plane at the National Air and Space Museum, where <PERSON> Crystal </PERSON> <PERSON> Gayle </PERSON> sang her country best. It was so crowded and the air so heavy in the red-carpeted grand foyer of the Kennedy Center that several black-tie guests fainted in front of the stage. One woman who lost consciousness was kept from sagging to the floor by the crush of more than 5,000 people around her. Presidential son <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> introduced his wife, who wore a full-length blue velvet gown, and told several thousand partygoers at the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Convention Center: `` I paid a lot for this dress and, damn it, I wanted you to see it.'' One of the belles of the ball at another hotel was 7-year-old <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Cartonia </PERSON>, the current <ORGANIZATION> Little </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Miss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Buffalo </ORGANIZATION>. Her mother, <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON>, proudly confided that <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> was conceived in the same hotel during President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s first inauguration in 1981, when `` we thought we were never going to have children.'' Outside one of the 11 invitation-only inaugural balls, animal rights protesters shouted `` Fur is Murder'' and `` I'm Warm _ I'm Not Wearing Fur'' at arriving guests, many of whom wore fur coats in the chill wind. The bass player for the Bus Boys rock band at a $ 30-a-head youth ball stood up and shouted: `` It's the inaugural day for a brand-new, get-down president.'' During his hurried ball-hopping tour from Union Station near the Capitol to the Kennedy Center on the banks of the moonlit <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, the new president made it laughingly clear that he's not very fond of dancing. Each time the band struck up `` I Could Have Danced All Night,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> took his wife, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>, out for a brief cheek-to-cheek turn on the floor. He took a few steps of an old-fashioned fox trot _ and no more. He told the crowd at Union Station that `` you can say that you saw it first here: a lousy dancer trying to dance his first dance with the first lady of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' Later, at the sprawling Pension Building, he quipped, `` The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> family is going to give dancing a bad name.'' After taking a few steps with Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, he stopped abruptly and announced: `` That's it That's the only step I know.'' At the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Convention Center, which rocked to the music of his old friend <PERSON> Lionel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hampton </PERSON>, the president pleaded with the crowd to overlook his footwork. `` I hope you do n't judge my being a president by the way I dance,'' he said. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> told revelers at a hotel ballroom that he feels the same way about dancing as his new boss. `` I guess protocol allows you to witness my inability to dance,'' he said, taking his wife, <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON>, onto the floor for a few stiff turns. At another hotel, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> appeared with his wife and, recalling their departure from the oath-taking ceremony at the Capitol, remarked that `` we went behind the Bushes.'' The crowd erupted in laughter at the double-entendre. `` <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> could not do it better,'' the vice president said with a grin. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> seemed elated by his new home at 1600 <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>. `` Do n't worry about our housing,'' he told one ballroom assembly. `` We were over at the White House for two hours and, boy, is it something special. Unbelievable.'' At his first stop, an American Legion affair for 149 Medal of Honor winners and other military heroes, the president vowed to keep <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> strong. By the time he reached the <LOCATION> Omni </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Shoreham </LOCATION> for his 12th visit, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s energy was flagging. `` Where do you get all that life from?'' he asked the cheering throng. At his 15th and final stop on the party circuit, standing in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Hilton Hotel ballroom at 12:30 a.m., a hoarse <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> seemed in a reflective mood as he recalled his emotions when he took the oath of office at the West Front of the Capitol at midday Friday. `` I did feel moved standing there today and looking across that sea of faces,'' he said, `` thinking of the continuity of the presidency, thinking of my gratitude to my predecessor, thinking of the joy that I have and the strength that I get from my family, thinking of how lucky we are to be a nation under <PERSON> God </PERSON> and thinking how lucky I am to have friends like you.'' With that, he departed in his limousine. Fifteen minutes later, he arrived home for his first night in the White House.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0235EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Bush-World     01-21 0675</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-World,0697</SECOND>
<HEAD>World Leaders Look For Peace, Moderation From Bush</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Bush, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 World leaders showered President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> with congratulations as he took office, with Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> hoping he would bring peace and Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> wishing him `` an abundance of divine blessings.'' The leftist Nicaraguan government extended an olive branch and <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> leaders were optimistic that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would move the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> from former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s staunch pro-Israeli position in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. One European newspaper hailed the return of pragmatists to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government and another `` the down-to-earth <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'' over `` <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> the romantic.'' A British daily said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would need some of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s luck. While the sendoffs for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> were mostly warm, about 5,000 Panamanians shot off fireworks in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and Nicaraguans danced in the streets of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> to celebrate his departure. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> told <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> he hoped his term would bring `` stable and diverse development of relations between our countries,'' and said <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> was ready to work in that direction, the official news agency <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said, `` Further joint efforts by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will make it possible to substantially bring closer the solution of the most painful problems of the present time, above all, the need to eliminate the threat of war.'' Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> sent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a congratulatory message, as did West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and other European leaders. In <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, the pope, leader of the world's Roman Catholics, wished <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> `` an abundance of divine blessings.'' Also among the well-wishers were King <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> and presidents <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaunda </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Zambia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> de Gortari of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Panamanians, led by Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, celebrated <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s departure by shooting off fireworks and dancing to bands in a plaza on <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s main thoroughfare. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> denies <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drug charges against him and has outlasted <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> efforts to force him to quit as the nation's de facto leader. In <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Sandinistas </PERSON> celebrated the end of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> era with dancing in the streets and parades that mocked him. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s administration has financed the anti-government <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> rebels since 1981 One float Friday showed Uncle <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> throwing dollars and the local opposition picking them up. However, Foreign Minister <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Escoto </PERSON>, saying he was optimistic U.S.-Nicaraguan `` relations will improve'' under <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, announced that it would begin issuing visas for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials. <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> imposed visa restrictions after each country expelled eight of the other's diplomats, including the ambassadors, during a diplomatic tiff in July. In the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> commentators appeared to agree that the changeover from <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s loss and the Arabs' gain. In <LOCATION> Jeruslaem </LOCATION>, the daily <ORGANIZATION> Hadashot </ORGANIZATION> said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> must be prepared for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` to be less sensitive and more pragmatic in approaching the -LRB- Arab-Israel -RRB- conflict.'' President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> said he believed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` understands the Palestinian problem and has good intentions,'' according to an interview with the <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> daily Al-Rai Al-Aam. <PERSON> Bassam </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharif </PERSON>, spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>, and other officials of the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> expressed cautious optimism that their cause may fare better with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` The pros are back,'' said the conservative <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Libre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Belgique </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>, but added they were `` a network of serious patricians who risk being boring.'' In <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, the leftist newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Le </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monde </ORGANIZATION> asked: `` After ` the Great Communicator,' ` the Great Corrector?''' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s `` big challenge will be peace, of which Mr. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> made himself the champion,'' the paper said. The center-left <ORGANIZATION> Het </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parool </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Amsterdam </LOCATION> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s presidency will be less flamboyant than that of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. `` But better than <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> the romantic, the down-to-earth <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> may be expected to draw the line between dream and reality. And that holds no small promise.'' The Financial Times anticipated `` a preference for management and a recognition of interdependence,'' but added <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would need luck _ `` a commodity that Mr. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had in abundance but can not bequeath.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0247EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Quayle     01-21 0511</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vice President Deals with First Heckler, Dances Reluctantly</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Inaugural Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> danced gamely into his second day on the job, partying with wife <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> until well past midnight and facing down a heckler in the only moment of discord on a night of celebration. The Quayles stopped at 14 inaugural balls and parties over more than four and a half hours Friday night after being sworn in as the 44th vice president. It was after 1 a.m. before they headed to the vice president's residence for their first night's sleep in their new home. At the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legion </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Salute to Heroes' Banquet,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was interrupted by a shout from the audience just as he was speaking of freedom as `` the most precious thing we have.'' `` What do you know about it?'' shouted a woman who appeared to be a guest but could not be identified. Pausing only briefly, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said: `` Freedom, people have the freedom to speak. We have free speech in this country.'' He received a long and loud applause from the crowd made up largely of war veterans, including 149 of the 225 living recipients of the Congressional Medal of Honor, the nation's highest military honor. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> savored the sound of his new title at several stops. After praising <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> at length, he said, `` As a matter of fact, Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> does n't sound too shabby.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> danced with his wife briefly at each of the balls on their motorcade tour of the city. He told reporters before stepping out for the evening that his wife says he is a `` terrible dancer,'' and he pledged `` to keep it to a minimum.'' He did little to dispel that judgment, and the dances were brief. At the lavish ball in newly restored Union Station he danced with his mother, and at several other stops he and <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> danced with guests selected from the audience _ after first dancing with each other. But as the night wore on both appeared weary, and by midnight he had lost track of how many parties they had been to. `` Ask the press,'' said <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. He did. `` The press says it's the 11th ball,'' the vice president announced. `` They're usually wrong _ so for the record, it's either 10 or 12.'' He won more applause. At a stop at the youth inaugural ball, the 41-year-old <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was greeted warmly. One woman on the front row, 24-year-old <PERSON> Cindy </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, yelled to him, `` <PERSON> Dan </PERSON>, blow me a kiss,'' and, `` Take your coat off, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON>.'' At another stop he told of his unease at the new protocol that put him ahead of former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> upon leaving the inaugural ceremony. He said he and <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> `` went out behind the Bushes,'' and then paused to consider what he'd said. Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> put her hand to her face in embarrassment. The crowd roared. `` <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> could do no better,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said finally. With that, it was time to dance.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0316EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Mexico-Union     01-21 0204</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico-Union,0210</SECOND>
<HEAD>Oil Union Bosses Kicked Out Of Workers Federation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Oil union bosses <PERSON> Joaquin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Galicia </PERSON> and <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> <PERSON> Barragan </PERSON> <PERSON> Camacho </PERSON> have been kicked out of the <ORGANIZATION> Mexican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> in the wake of their arrests in a government crackdown, the official news service <ORGANIZATION> Notimex </ORGANIZATION> said. The federation cleared their belongings out of their offices at the union headquarters Friday on the orders of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s top labor leader, <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Velazquez </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Notimex </ORGANIZATION> said. Their offices are to be occupied by meat union leaders. <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Galicia </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barragan </PERSON> <PERSON> Camacho </PERSON> were among 46 people arrested in a Jan. 10 crackdown on oil union leaders. <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Galicia </PERSON>, 66, was arrested after soldiers and federal agents raided his home in <LOCATION> Ciudad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Madero </LOCATION>. A federal agent was shot to death in the attack. The federal Attorney General's office reported it found 200 <PERSON> Uzi </PERSON> machine guns, believed to have been smuggled in from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, in the <LOCATION> Hernandez </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Galicia </LOCATION> home in the northeastern state of <LOCATION> Tamaulipas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Galicia </PERSON>, also known as <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Quina </LOCATION>, is in a <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> jail on weapons and homicide charges. <PERSON> Barragan </PERSON> <PERSON> Camacho </PERSON> is under arrest in a <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> hospital, where he was taken with heart troubles the day of the arrests.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890121-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-21-89 0311EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Names     01-21 0885</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0922</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BURBANK, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A touch of the flu forced <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> to cancel his appearance on `` The Tonight Show,'' sending several hundred audience members home when no substitute host could be found. `` We hoped to get <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Leno </PERSON> as a replacement, but he had an engagement in <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>,'' show spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> said Friday. He said <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> rarely misses a taping, adding that <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>'s last sick day came about two years ago. Scheduled guests for Friday's show included actor <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Selleck </PERSON> and singer <PERSON> Emmylou </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> televised a rerun of the show.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> correspondent <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Donaldson </PERSON> did it one last time. As <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> headed for the plane that would carry him off to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Donaldson </PERSON> shouted: `` How about a word, Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>? How about a word?'' As usual, the president just grinned and shrugged. When <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> left the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Friday morning, <PERSON> Donaldson </PERSON> left, too, after 12 years as <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s chief White House correspondent. `` I'm going out with no regrets,'' <PERSON> Donaldson </PERSON> said. `` And it's a pleasure they're not carrying me out feet first and not pushing me out, but I'm going of my own will.'' <PERSON> Brit </PERSON> <PERSON> Hume </PERSON> took over the job as of noon Friday with <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s inauguration <PERSON> Donaldson </PERSON> is expected to be named co-anchor of a new, prime-time <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> news </ORGANIZATION> program and will continue to appear on `` This Week with <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Brinkley </PERSON>.'' His habit of shouting questions at <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> during `` photo opportunities'' was often cited as an example of an arrogant and disrespectful news media. But <PERSON> Donaldson </PERSON> maintained he shouted questions only when there was no other way to get an answer.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actresses and pop stars modeled T-shirts to support a retail venture in the campaign against furs, while a half-dozen furriers protested outside the shop. Actresses <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rita </PERSON> <PERSON> Tushingham </PERSON> and Twiggy, <PERSON> Chrissie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hynde </PERSON> of The Pretenders and Siouxsie of the group <ORGANIZATION> Siouxsie </ORGANIZATION> and The Banshees on Friday donned T-shirts designed by the animal rights group <ORGANIZATION> LYNX </ORGANIZATION>. The 3-year-old group has opened a store in Covent Garden, making its case by selling T-shirts bearing slogans like, `` Yuck, Your Disgusting Fur Coat.'' `` I modeled a fur coat when I was 16 _ that is the first and last time I have ever worn one,'' said <PERSON> Twiggy </PERSON>. `` Wearing a fur coat is absolutely unnecessary, absolutely disgusting, and complete vanity. We have got to stop women wanting them so there would be no point selling them.'' Some of the protesting furriers handed out leaflets with a distorted <ORGANIZATION> LYNX </ORGANIZATION> logo which they had embellished with horns and forked tongue. `` LYNX's stated purpose is to destroy the fur trade,'' said <PERSON> Mihran </PERSON> <PERSON> Allalemdjian </PERSON>, who buys and sells skins. `` There is a question whether their literature and posters do incite other people to act in a violent manner.'' <PERSON> Hynde </PERSON> said she had no sympathy for violence. The fur trade, she said, `` is an immoral industry but not an illegal one. The only way to stop it is to boycott the products.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>KNOXVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Cicely </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> says blacks have lost some of the unity they had before the civil rights era blossomed. <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON>, spoke at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION> here on Friday in one of the many events across the country this week in memory of slain civil rights leader <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>. <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON>, 55, said the 1960s movement was essential for blacks, but said `` before the civil rights movement came, people needed each other and relied on each other to survive Somehow we have lost this.'' The actress, who has spoken out against typecasting blacks as drug addicts and prostitutes, also said overt racism has given way to more subtle forms of discrimination. <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON>'s film credits include `` Sounder,'' for which she received an Oscar nomination, and `` The Heart is a Lonely Hunter.'' She also received an Emmy nomination for her role in the TV miniseries `` Roots.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW HAVEN, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Poet <PERSON> Edgar </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowers </PERSON>, an English professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION>, has been awarded <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s prestigious Bollingen Prize in Poetry. The university announced Friday that <PERSON> Bowers </PERSON> received the award, which carries a $ 10,000 prize, in recognition of his entire body of work. Past winners include <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, <PERSON> Archibald </PERSON> <PERSON> MacLeish </PERSON>, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, e.e. cummings, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Frost </PERSON>, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Penn </PERSON> <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> and <PERSON> Marianne </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>. The Bollingen Prize, established in 1949, was awarded annually at first, but has been bestowed every two years since 1965. The judges said <PERSON> Bowers </PERSON>, 64, has `` consistently exhibited a vigor of image and idea that extends beyond the comparatively small compass of his collected poems.'' <PERSON> Bowers </PERSON>' first book, `` A Form of Loss,'' was published in 1956. His last collection of verse, `` Witnesses,'' was published in 1981.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former astronaut <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> <PERSON> Wang </PERSON>, now a <ORGANIZATION> Vanderbilt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> professor, says one of his priorities is teaching students to learn by writing research papers rather than studying textbooks. <PERSON> Wang </PERSON>, 48, flew on a 1984 space shuttle mission, then worked at the <ORGANIZATION> Jet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Propulsion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> before joining the <ORGANIZATION> Vanderbilt </ORGANIZATION> faculty last summer to teach engineering. `` Students have a tendency to learn from the textbook,'' he said. `` I want them to learn from research.'' <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> is developing a center for microgravity research.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
