<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 2343EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TeacherContract 1stLd-Writethru a0781 02-03 0441</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Teacher Contract, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0781,0449</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teachers Refuse To Report Official Grades To Protest Contract Dispute</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 4-6, `United Teachers-Los ...,' with 3 grafs to UPDATE
with number of teachers joining union action. Picks up 7th graf pvs, `Carey
also ... .'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN ANTCZAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Teachers pressing stalled contract demands defied threats of withheld paychecks and gave out students' midyear grades on union report cards Friday rather than report them to the school district as required. The action came after weeks of student demonstrations supporting the teachers and amid talk of a possible teacher strike. Meanwhile, a state mediator organized a weekend meeting between the union and the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Unified School District. A union spokeswoman said the `` vast majority'' of teachers at junior and senior high schools refused to report grades to the school district, as required by school regulations. District spokeswoman <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Sims </PERSON> said 69 percent of the high school teachers did not turn in grades. The school system's tally for junior high teachers was not completed by Friday night, she said. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers-Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> printed up 400,000 report cards to give to students, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Catherine </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carey </PERSON>. `` Both members and non-members are participating,'' <PERSON> Carey </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Carey </PERSON> also said the union agreed to a state mediator's urging that both sides in the long-running dispute meet Sunday. On Thursday, union President <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> called for a negotiating session between just the seven school board members and seven union officers. But the meeting Sunday will include the district superintendent and the district's chief negotiator. The union action on grades involved the 117,477 students in junior highs, the 119,904 students in senior highs, and secondary students among the 27,000 students at so-called magnet schools and centers, <PERSON> Carey </PERSON> said. High school seniors have been concerned that the action would affect their university applications, but <PERSON> Carey </PERSON> said those students have been told to take the union report cards to their counselors for forwarding to universities. The spokeswoman said both <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> university systems and the Ivy League schools have said the grades will be recognized. The contract covers 26,000 classroom teachers and about 6,000 librarians, nurses, counselors and other certificated employees, <PERSON> Carey </PERSON> said. Of that 32,000, about 22,000 are union members. The teachers have been without a contract since June. The union has been seeking a 12 percent pay hike while the district offered about 17 percent over three years. Current salaries range from starting pay of $ 23,440 to a maximum of $ 43,319. The average salary is $ 36,600. Total district enrollment from the elementary level through high school is more than 594,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0005EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ColdRdp 2ndLd-Writethru a0802 02-03 1065</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cold Rdp, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0802,1089</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cold Works Its Way to East Coast</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Tightens 1st graf. SUBS grafs 11-13, `Temperatures overnight...,'
to UPDATE temperatures; SUBS 19th graf, `The boy...', to UPDATE condition
to stable; INSERTS one graf after 20th graf, `Heaviest snow...', to ADD
snowfall in California. Mardy is cq in 23rd graf.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto SP1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By POLLY ANDERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 The February Freeze spread Thursday to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> mid-Atlantic </LOCATION> states, while wind and cold lingering in the nation's heartland and <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> endangered livestock and crops and made venturing outside hazardous A band of freezing rain extended from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>; heavy snow was reported in parts of the central <ORGANIZATION> Rockies </ORGANIZATION>; and wind-chill readings hit 75 below or lower in parts of <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Dakotas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. The cold and snow led to a short workday for state workers in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, unexpected school and university holidays in several states and highway accidents. Ranchers reported that newborn calves were dying in the cold, and citrus growers took precautions to keep the deep freeze from harming their crops. The misery stemmed from an ocean of cold air that poured down from <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> early in the week, after a shift in the jet stream. By midday Thursday, its effects in the Lower 48 were being felt across a vast, roughly triangular area from the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, areas that had enjoyed in many cases their warmest January in years. Bostonians enjoyed a record-high 66 degrees Wednesday. Twenty-four hours later, the city shivered in 31-degree air, and light freezing rain was falling. In <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, which continued to post the lowest temperatures outside <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, Gov. <PERSON> Stan </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON> sent all non-essential state workers home Thursday. The capital, <PERSON> Helena </PERSON>, grappled not only with the bitter cold but with a train derailment and explosion that forced the evacuation of thousands of people and disrupted electrical power. <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>'s two largest universities shut down through the weekend. `` It's not the cold, because we've been open in much colder weather,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Tietz </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Montana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> at <PERSON> Bozeman </PERSON>. `` It's the wind chill we're concerned about.'' Classes were canceled at many <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> schools because of the wind chill and blowing snow. Schools also were closed <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and elsewhere. Temperatures overnight dipped to 34 below in three <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> towns: <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lewistown </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Cut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>; and their wind-chill readings were as low as 78 below. In Billings, the record low for a Feb. 2 used to be 13 degrees below zero; on Thursday, it went to 28 below, and 20 below was the high for the day. In all, six record lows for the date were posted, including <LOCATION> Astoria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, with 18 above; Casper, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, 27 below; and <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, 28 below. But temperature records at the other end of the scale, though not so widespread as on Wednesday, also were racked up Thursday. Nearly 30 record highs were set, including <LOCATION> Asheville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, 76 degrees; <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hatteras </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, 74; <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, 80; <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, Va. 80; <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, 78; and <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, 80. In <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, temperatures remained in the cellar near the Canadian border but warmed up elsewhere. Early Thursday it was 37 degrees at <LOCATION> Adak </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Aleutian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, and 59 degrees below zero at <LOCATION> Northway </LOCATION>. At least four traffic fatalities were blamed on the weather, and in <LOCATION> Edmonds </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, a 35-year-old utility worker died Thursday when he fell while trying to repair a downed power line. In <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, a 50-year-old man was found dead Thursday morning in a vacant lot. <LOCATION> Bennett </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Chief Deputy Sheriff <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Dillon </PERSON> said the man's death apparently was caused by exposure. The overnight temperature in <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> was about 25 below zero, with a wind chill of 60 below. The man `` fell down and you could see where he struggled in the snow to regain his feet, but he was unable to do so,'' <PERSON> Dillon </PERSON> said. But a life was saved in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, when searchers Thursday found a 16-year-old boy who got lost Monday while driving to his family's farm. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> <PERSON> Stebleton </PERSON> of rural <PERSON> Egeland </PERSON> was coherent but `` too wrung out to show any emotion'' aside from saying `` I'm thankful that I'm alive,'' said volunteer rescuer <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> The boy, who had only light clothing and car mats to keep him warm, had badly frostbitten feet and hands and was hospitalized in stable condition. Overnight temperatures in the area had plunged to 30 degrees below zero. Heaviest snow was reported in the <LOCATION> Rockies </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Craig </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, reported 6 new inches by midmorning, while 11 -LCB- inches were reported in northern <LOCATION> Larimer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, and 4 inches at <LOCATION> Laramie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyo </LOCATION>. Snow also fell in the upper <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>. In northern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, snow blanketed the <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION>, dusted <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area mountains and fell over beachfront communities. Freezing rain extended as far south as <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, and forecasters said there was a chance that below-freezing temperatures could extend to the southern part of the state by the weekend. Nervous citrus growers in south <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, still recovering from a devastating freeze in 1983, were taking precautions, officials said. `` As people have been leaving my store today I've been telling them to go to church Sunday and pray for us,'' said <PERSON> Mardy </PERSON> <PERSON> Eggers </PERSON> from her family's <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> citrus farm, <ORGANIZATION> Eggers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Acres </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> ranchers said cattle were giving birth to calves that died from exposure within hours. One rancher, Dr. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Ingham </PERSON>, said he lost two calves. `` We had one up and nursing, and came back and that big 100-pounder was dead,'' <PERSON> Ingham </PERSON> said. `` It's the wind chill out on this prairie.'' Workers at Double M Farms feedlot near <LOCATION> Kearney </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, put acetylene torches to some water tanks for cattle, part-owner <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Mercer </PERSON> said. They also had to stir the cattle feed so it would n't freeze Power outages blamed on the weather were reported in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>. Officials in <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, theorized that a power line contracted so tightly in 58 below wind-chills that it just snapped. Still, there were signs that people were getting used to the weather. `` A lot more people are staying home,'' <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, police spokesman <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Groepper </PERSON> said Thursday. `` Traffic was definitely lighter today ... -LRB- and -RRB- I think people have just adjusted more to the weather.'' Forecasters said the deep freeze would last for at least a few more days in most affected areas.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AIDS-Stats     02-03 0222</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Stats,0245</SECOND>
<HEAD>CDC Statistics On U.S. AIDS Cases</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest statistics on acquired immune deficiency syndrome in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, as reported this week by the national Centers for Disease Control:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Number of Cases</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Total cases reported since June 1981: 84,985. Cases, year to date: 2,228. Total deaths: 48,582, or 57 percent of all cases.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Transmission Categories</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Homosexual or bisexual males: 51,581, or 61 percent. Intravenous drug abusers: 16,672, or 20 percent. Homosexual male and drug abusers: 6,013, or 7 percent. Heterosexual cases: 3,685, or 4 percent. Transfusion or blood cases: 2,256, or 3 percent. Hemophilia patients: 882, or 1 percent. Children of parents with AIDS or at risk: 1,080, or 1 percent. Undetermined transmission cause: 2,816, or 3 percent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Age and Race</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Childhood cases -LRB- under age 13 -RRB-: 1,393, or 2 percent. Cases among whites: 48,808, or 57 percent. Cases among blacks: 22,579, or 27 percent. Cases among Hispanics: 12,817, or 15 percent. Cases among Asians or Pacific Islanders: 502, or 1 percent. Cases among American Indians or Alaskan natives: 90, or 0 percent. -LRB- NOTE: These statistics are through Jan. 30 and have been rounded to the nearest whole percent. Cumulative totals are for AIDS cases reported since June 1981, and include 75 cases subsequently found to have occurred prior to that date. -RRB-
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0103EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SAfrica-Racism     02-03 0775</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SAfrica-Racism,0800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Racist Incidents Prompt Condemnation But Little Action</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID CRARY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the mining town of <LOCATION> Carletonville </LOCATION>, officials voted this week to erect a fence to keep blacks off the civic center's lawn. In <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>, a mob of whites threatened to kill an Indian man who hoped to be their neighbor. Near <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION>, a blond, 5-year-old boy was expelled last week from an all-white nursery school. <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> was `` a lovely and intelligent boy,'' the principal in <PERSON> Kraaifontein </PERSON> said, and he was legally classified as white, but he could not stay because his mother had mixed racial ancestry. Practices like these pervade South African society. What sets the country apart, however, is not the existence of racism, but the fact that it is permitted, even mandated, by many of the people in power. When right-wing whites resegregated parks in the city of <LOCATION> Boksburg </LOCATION> last year and blocked the Indian man from moving into their neighborhood last weekend, they were scolded by the government and the press. But they had the law on their side. Employers face no penalties if they hire according to race, but colorblind landlords face heavy fines. Government schools must practice segregation, and private schools are entitled to do so. Municipal governments are empowered to bar blacks from parks, buses or beaches. `` The racists and bigots will exploit laws as long as they remain on the statute books,'' said <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Currin </PERSON>, director of <ORGANIZATION> Lawyers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION>. President P.W. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>'s government has spoken out against racism with increasing frequency in recent years. In November, it banned a small white-supremacist group, and it has outlawed the incitement of racial hostility. `` If apartheid means ... racial discrimination and encroachment on human dignity, then I reject it out of hand,'' <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> said in 1986. But rarely is the government's rhetoric accompanied by tough action. The recent banning of the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> has not been followed by steps against the larger, more powerful <ORGANIZATION> Afrikaner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, despite its white-supremacist ideology, Nazi-style symbols and paramilitary training programs. Nor did police disperse the mob that gathered Sunday outside a house in <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Mayfair </LOCATION> <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> district </LOCATION>, draped a noose over a wall, and shouted threats at the Indian who planned to move his family into the white neighborhood. `` Years of forced separation and years of racist indoctrination have resulted in people behaving in such abominable ways,'' said The Sowetan, a black newspaper, in a subsequent editorial. Information Minister <PERSON> Stoffel </PERSON> <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> der </PERSON> <PERSON> Merwe </PERSON> said in an interview that the Mayfair West incident could have happened in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. The government was conducting a `` campaign of persuasion'' to diminish white racism, he said, `` but if you overdo that, you create a reaction.'' `` The eradication of racism from a society is a very complicated, long-term undertaking, as evidenced by the American experience,'' <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> der </PERSON> <PERSON> Merwe </PERSON> said. `` Compared to 10 years ago, we've made tremendous progress.'' <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> der </PERSON> <PERSON> Merwe </PERSON> described <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON>'s expulsion from nursery school as `` very unfortunate.'' `` When one lives in a society in a state of change, there is a gap between morality and legality,'' he said, noting that the principal acted lawfully. The government says blatant racism will worsen <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s international isolation, but it refuses to outlaw segregation of local facilities or residential areas `` Unfortunately, the government is unable to act decisively in such matters,'' said The Citizen, a pro-government newspaper. Prosecuting non-whites who live in white areas would `` create racial tensions at home and damaging publicity abroad,'' it said this week. But if the government scrapped the Group Areas Act, `` it would lose its constituency.'' Racism is practiced most enthusiastically by extreme-right whites, who Thursday launched a whites-only rugby league. But bigotry exists in relatively liberal neighborhoods as well. In <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>'s wealthy northern suburbs, where most voters back anti-apartheid candidates, doctors willing to treat black servants ask them to use separate waiting rooms. Neighborhood newspapers in those suburbs carry ads for `` European-supervised'' plumbing or electrical services. Readers know this means that if blacks come to their house to do repairs, a white man will be in charge. Despite the entrenchment of racial divisions, many South Africans are working to overcome them. Church groups have sponsored workshops in which whites stay overnight in black townships, while blacks live with whites. Several multiracial private schools are flourishing. <PERSON> Amanda </PERSON> <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON>, the mother of the expelled nursery school student, said she will seek out one of these schools for her children, `` where they will realize that they are equal to and no better than any other child.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Superstition     02-03 0733</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Superstition,0759</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cartoonists Attack Superstition, Buddhism</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Satirical cartoonists have launched a scathing attack on Buddhism and superstitious rituals such as fortunetelling, which are enjoying a resurgence after 40 years of communist suppression. `` Today you will suffer financial losses,'' a fortuneteller in one cartoon intones as he holds a customer's palm in one hand and takes a hefty fee with the other. Another shows a man with a bad leg going from temple to temple to pray for healing and finally being carried into a hospital on a stretcher. More than 120 such cartoons were part of an exhibit called `` Away With Superstition and Ignorance,'' shown this week in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and four other cities. Cartoonist <PERSON> Xu </PERSON> <PERSON> Jin </PERSON> said the artists timed the show for just before the Feb. 6 celebration of the Lunar New Year, traditionally one of the most superstitious dates on the Chinese calendar. Setting off firecrackers, still popular on the holiday, originally was intended to scare away evil spirits. `` We have a mission to help educate people,'' <PERSON> Xu </PERSON> said. `` It's not just a matter of people losing money to witch doctors and fortunetellers, it's also a problem of increasing the scientific spirit.'' The rebuilding of temples and the worship of <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> gods also come in for heavy attack. One cartoon shows a man answering the telephone in a government office and telling the caller that all the officials have `` gone to the front line.'' `` Where exactly?'' `` To the Dragon King Temple to burn incense,'' comes the answer. <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiuqiao </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Popularizing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION>, which helped organize the exhibit, said it often is hard to separate religion from superstition. `` Religion often uses superstitious elements, for example, if it claims to be able to cure people who are ill,'' she said. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> says it allows freedom of religion. But it is more tolerant of Christianity _ which most Chinese see as alien _ and other minority religions than it is of Buddhism, which has deep roots among the Chinese and greater potential to spread. Religion and superstition played a large role in daily life in pre-Communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, especially in the countryside. Omens were seen in everyday events _ such as a crow passing overhead _ and people consulted diviners before making important decisions. Single women made offerings at `` maidens' temples'' in hopes of finding good husbands, and married women prayed to other gods for sons. The communists quashed most such practices after taking power in 1949. But the rituals have enjoyed a comeback recently as the government has relaxed controls and peasants have acquired more money. In the prosperous southeast, rice fields once again are dotted with small ancestral shrines and tombs newly built by peasants or renovated after decades of neglect. `` After they build a new house and buy a washing machine, -LRB- rich peasants -RRB- have nothing else to spend money on so they rebuild the family shrine,'' Ms. <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> said. `` Also, they want to show their gratitude for their wealth and ask the gods to keep the government from changing its policies'' of allowing some private industry. The official media often complain that building shrines and tombs wastes money and land, and call diviners and witch doctors cheats. All were targets at the cartoon exhibit, which drew about 24,000 viewers during an eight-day showing at the <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> Art Gallery in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. One that drew chuckles from viewers showed a spiritualist telling a fearful family that their goat, chicken and TV set harbored evil spirits. The spiritualist loaded them onto his cart and set off, calling cheerfully, `` Now I have all the evil spirits.'' Others took swipes at the new fad of computerized fortunetelling, touted by its hawkers as scientific. Customers feed their birthdate into a computer and get a printout with their fortune. `` We just came to laugh; hardly anyone in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> believes in these things,'' said a young woman who giggled over the cartoons with her boyfriend. Ms. <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> agreed most city dwellers are n't as superstitious as rural residents. But she said even in the cities people are turning to old beliefs because of a crisis of faith in the government. During the 1960s and 1970s, she said, `` people developed the habit of worshipping Chairman <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> -LRB- Tse-tung -RRB- as a god. Now they do n't have <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> so they look for other gods.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0013EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Farrakhan 1stLd-Writethru a0401 02-03 0541</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Farrakhan, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0401,0551</SECOND>
<HEAD>Black Leader Prompts Protests At Racially Troubled Campus</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: CORRECTS to Farrakhan sted Farrahkan in grafs 1, 2, 9, 11 and
12.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN LUMSDEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AMHERST, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Muslim </ORGANIZATION> minister <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON> appeared Thursday at the racially troubled <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> and angrily told Jewish protesters they had no right to call him a hate-monger. <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON> told an audience of 2,000 that he did not come to the college to pit blacks against Jews, but he said blacks learned how to hate from the hatred directed at them. `` To those Jewish students who see me as a <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>, as a hater, I wish you life, I wish you life. I do n't wish to see any human forfeit his life,'' said the leader of the Chicago-based Nation of Islam. But, <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON> added, `` Your people taught us to hate ourselves for years, and you have a hell of a nerve to see me today and call me a hate-monger.'' <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON> said whites should leave blacks to solve their problems themselves. `` If the Jewish students come together to work out some family matter, we should n't call that racism,'' he said. `` No one outside the family should dare to interfere with our family problems.'' He said more separation between the races is needed to combat black feelings of inferiority. `` We do n't need a bedroom relationship with white people, we want a boardroom relationship. Perhaps some other time we might want to entertain some social contacts.'' <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON> added, `` When we awaken, we will march against every vestige of oppression, and if you challenge us, then we are going to clash with you until death separates us from life or you from life. But why should that be?'' More than 500 students held a quiet candlelight march prior to <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON>'s visit, while members of a militant Jewish group led students in a loud demonstration outside the hall in which the black leader spoke. `` Farrakhan is a Nazi without a swastika,'' declared <PERSON> Mordechai </PERSON> <PERSON> Levi </PERSON>, the New York-based head of the <ORGANIZATION> Jewish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. `` He should be in <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, not in this campus.'' The visit by <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON> and the 38 guards he calls the Fruit of Islam nearly coincided with the first anniversary of a campus building takeover by 100 minority students to protest racial violence at this 30,000-student school in western <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON> was promised $ 11,000 by a black fraternity and a campus speaker program to talk at the university's Fine Arts Center. Tickets sold out within a day. <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON> came to national attention in 1984 for calling Judaism `` a gutter religion'' and making other anti-Semitic remarks that his supporters say have been taken out of context in his campaign to foster black pride. The <LOCATION> Amherst </LOCATION> campus has been the scene of racial strife since a fight broke out among black and white students after the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sox </ORGANIZATION> loss to the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> in the final game of the 1986 World Series. On Feb. 11, 1988, minority students began a weeklong occupation of a university building to protest another racial scuffle. The takeover, which was the first of several around the <LOCATION> Northeast </LOCATION>, ended with the chancellor's agreement to boost programs for minority students.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0101EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Obit-Stephenson     02-03 0548</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Stephenson,0564</SECOND>
<HEAD>William Stephenson, Famous Spymaster, Is Dead</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Stephenson and author William Stevenson are cq</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROGER SCOTTON</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HAMILTON, Bermuda (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 British spymaster Sir <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephenson </PERSON>, the legendary `` man called Intrepid'' whose vast intelligence web snared German spies in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> during World War II, died at his home. He was 93. <PERSON> Stephenson </PERSON> operated out of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> during the war and was given his famous code name and a virtual carte blanche to conduct espionage by British Prime Minister <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON>. He died on Tuesday and was buried the next day. Sources close to him said he died peacefully at home and had instructed that his death not be announced until after his burial. <PERSON> Stephenson </PERSON>, the son of a lumber mill owner, was born in <LOCATION> Winnipeg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, in 1896 and became an engineer. During World War I, he was a pilot in the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> and shot down 26 German planes. He became a millionaire industrialist by the age of 30, largely as a result of inventing in the 1920s a method of sending pictures by wire. He made a fortune through other business ventures and even found time to win the world amateur light heavyweight boxing championship. But his most famous exploits came after 1940, when he was tapped by <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON> to put together the most potent intelligence netork of its kind. He was sent to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> officially to establish an organization to protect British shipping during the war and counter the activities of Nazi spies. But in fact, the operation he set up was later acknowledged to be the hub of all the branches of British intelligence. He also was reported to be the link between <LOCATION> Churchill </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Roosevelt </LOCATION> in the years before the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> entered the war. He became <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s top operator in the <LOCATION> Americas </LOCATION> and was responsible for training in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> a cadre of spies and saboteurs who operated in Nazi-occuped <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. He set up shop in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>'s Rockefeller Center with the approval of President <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> director <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Edgar </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON>, but without of the official knowledge of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, which was observing neutrality because the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had not yet entered the war. <PERSON> Stephenson </PERSON> and his agents secretly killed at least three German operatives in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and ran clandestine operations to discredit <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> politicians who opposed aid to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, according to the popular book on the operation, `` A Man Called Intrepid'' by <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevenson </PERSON>. The book chronicled a dazzling series of successes ranging from code-breaking to dropping agents into occupied <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. He was a severe anti-communist after the war. He already had retired by the time his exploits became public, mostly through <PERSON> Stevenson </PERSON>'s 1976 book and the author's subsequent `` Intrepid's Last Case'' in 1983. <PERSON> Stephenson </PERSON> stayed out of the public eye until 1987, when <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s book <PERSON> Spycatcher </PERSON> became famous because of the British government's attempts to suppress it. He went on record as saying that he believed the late Sir <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Hollis </PERSON>, head of the MI5 British spy agency, was a Soviet double agent. `` <PERSON> Hollis </PERSON> ... was a bad egg if ever there was one,'' he told the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION> newspaper in <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Stephenson </PERSON> was married in 1924 to <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>, who died in 1978.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LaRouche-Royko     02-03 0385</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-LaRouche-Royko,0396</SECOND>
<HEAD>LaRouche Followers Seek To Block Further Distribution of `Dangerous'
Column</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BERNARD SCHOENBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Jailed political extremist <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> has filed a lawsuit to stop distribution of a newspaper column that he says could incite other inmates to harm him because it calls him a `` cat-killer,'' a lawyer said. The column by <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Royko </PERSON>, syndicated through the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>, contends that <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> followers have killed cats of <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> opponents _ a claim LaRouche followers deny. `` I hope that this column finds its way to his fellow inmates,'' <PERSON> Royko </PERSON> wrote in the column, printed Monday in the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> and distributed to about 500 newspapers. `` They should know that they have a cat-killer in their midst. And I hope any cat-lovers among them do whatever they feel is appropriate.'' <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Null </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> lawyer who filed the lawsuit in <ORGANIZATION> Cook </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday the column is `` nothing less than inciting people to violence.'' Null said that is not something writers can do under constitutional protections of freedom of the press. `` This is a case of a verbal act ... solicitation to commit a crime, to do great bodily harm to Mr. <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> or do murder,'' Null said. But <PERSON> Royko </PERSON>, in a telephone interview later Thursday, said violence against <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> was not his intent. As to what is `` appropriate'' for other inmates to do with <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, <PERSON> Royko </PERSON> said, `` They should lecture him ... they should tell him to caution his people against picking on cats.'' A federal judge in <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, sentenced <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> to 15 years in prison Friday for scheming to defraud the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and deliberately defaulting on more than $ 30 million in loans from supporters. <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, 66, a three-time presidential fringe candidate, was sent to the <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Jail to await transfer to a federal prison. The lawsuit, filed Wednesday, originally stressed the importance of keeping the <PERSON> Royko </PERSON> column out of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, which <PERSON> Null </PERSON> said is distributed in the <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION> jail. However, the column ran in the newspaper on Wednesday. Null said the lawsuit would still be pressed to avoid any further distribution, and to seek a permanent injunction against any further columns that might incite people to harm <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>. A hearing on the lawsuit was set for Friday, <ORGANIZATION> Null </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0030EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TampaDisturbance 3rdLd-Writethru a0829 02-03 0912</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tampa Disturbance, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0829,0933</SECOND>
<HEAD>Second Disturbance Erupts After Drug Suspect Dies in Custody</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 10 grafs to UPDATE with nine arrests, quotes from
mayor, officer treated and released from hospital. Picks up 10th graf pvs,
`Price, a...'. Deletes 18th graf pvs `The size...' to conform.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto SPB1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAT LEISNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TAMPA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rioters threw rocks and bottles and set trash bins on fire Thursday in the second night of violence after a suspected drug dealer died in police custody. Police cordoned off the same predominantly black neighborhood where about 100 officers in riot gear quelled the first outbreak Wednesday night by about 75 young people, many ages 12 to 14. The melee erupted after the arrest of <PERSON> Edgar </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>, 40, in an undercover bust. It took eight police officers to subdue Price. Police attempted to ward off further trouble in the <LOCATION> College </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> section Thursday by releasing details of the arrest. Price, who is black, was not beaten or choked but died of cardiac arrest of undetermined cause, Deputy Chief <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> DePolis </PERSON> said at a news conference. At sundown, however, more violence erupted, and 70 officers responded. Police reported making nine arrests for inciting to riot, including two juveniles and four members of the <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Petersburg </LOCATION> There was no official estimate of the number of people involved in the unrest. `` Many of these people that were arrested tonight were outsiders,'' said <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON> <PERSON> Freedman </PERSON>, who added the situation was under control late Thursday. `` The message is very clear. You come over here and incite riots, you're going to get arrested,'' she said, vowing to stay in the area as long as necessary. An officer hit by a brick, Sgt. <PERSON> B.J </PERSON>. <PERSON> Curry </PERSON>, was treated and released at <ORGANIZATION> Tampa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. A couple of trash bins were set ablaze and there was sporadic rock and bottle throwing over a three-hour period, said Sgt. <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Sluga </PERSON>. On Wednesday night, a grocery store was looted and torched and two shotgun blasts were fired at a news van. One man was arrested, and at least four officers injured in the disturbance. Price, a 6-foot-3, 300-pound man, struggled with two undercover officers after an informant made a drug buy in the housing complex, said police spokesman <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>. <PERSON> DePolis </PERSON> gave this account of events: When the two plainclothes officers tried to arrest Price, he picked one up off the ground with one hand and punched the other repeatedly in the face. Price suffered a 2-inch gash from a blow to the head, then wrestled free and tried to flee to his girlfriend's apartment as two backup officers arrived The four officers struck Price with their nightsticks on his arm and leg, but he again pulled free. `` Two more officers arrived and all six officers go tumbling into the living room fighting with this man,'' <PERSON> DePolis </PERSON> said. The officers finally managed to slap handcuffs and leg manacles on Price. The girlfriend's mother, who uses a pacemaker and a walker, ended up under the pileup. Paramedics arrived to treat the woman, who was not identified, the officer with the broken nose and to dress Price's head wound. When the rock - and bottle-throwing began, police put Price in a cruiser and drove around the block for safety, which took about 45 seconds `` Medical personnel looked in the car and realized he was suffering cardiac arrest,'' said <PERSON> DePolis </PERSON>. Paramedics treated Price and rushed him to <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joseph </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, where he was pronounced dead less than 90 minutes after the arrest. The suspect was carrying 25 pieces of crack cocaine and a loaded 25-caliber derringer in his pockets, <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> said. Price, of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, was sentenced in 1974 to 50 years on a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> robbery conviction and also had a 1967 robbery arrest on his record, said <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>, adding he did not know the disposition of that case. Officials cordoned off four intersections in the 22-block housing development and summoned 100 police officers and 30 firefighters to quell the disturbance. <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Bexley </PERSON>, owner of <PERSON> Bexley </PERSON>'s Bar-B-Q in the neighborhood, said some of the young people looted a grocery store before it was set on fire. `` Once they broke it, it took 10 to 15 minutes and they cleared it out,'' he said. `` Some went in, then things come flying out windows and doors.'' The fire forced choir members at the <ORGANIZATION> Deliverance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tabernacle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> to move an organ and other valuables into a truck as a precaution. A young man with a 10-gauge shotgun fired on a <ORGANIZATION> WFLA-TV </ORGANIZATION> van, said cameraman <PERSON> Rugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, who was not injured. The College Hill neighborhood and housing development have been the site of frequent confrontations between residents and police in recent years, including an incident last April when a crowd 400 threw rocks and bottles after the arrest of a robbery suspect, and a violent outbreak in February 1987 after a 23-year-old black man died in police custody. A white police officer who used a neck hold to subdue him eventually was cleared of wrongdoing and the neck hold was banned. `` People feel trapped and they're ready to explode when something even looks like brutality,'' said <PERSON> Eliott </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, pastor of Blessed Hope Ministries two blocks from the looted grocery store. `` ... We're still sitting on a keg of dynamite down here.' Last month, blacks in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> rioted for several days after a police officer fatally shot a speeding black motorcyclist.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Burma-Crash 1stLd-Writethru   02-03 0298</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Burma-Crash, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0842,0306</SECOND>
<HEAD>Burmese Airliner Crashes On Takeoff, 26 Dead</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: LEADS throughout to UPDATE with 26 dead, details. No pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RANGOON, Burma (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A domestic airliner taking off from <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> airport crashed Friday after striking a tree, killing 26 people and injuring the three other people aboard, the state radio said. Four more people were injured on the ground when the <ORGANIZATION> Burma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fokker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Friendship </ORGANIZATION> 27 crashed near housing for families of air force personnel at <LOCATION> Mingaladon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rangoon </ORGANIZATION> said. The radio gave engine failure as the cause of the crash, <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s fourth since mid-1987 It said the turboprop failed to gain altitude and hit the tree shortly after takeoff on a flight to <LOCATION> Kengtung </LOCATION>, 380 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>. The aircraft carried 25 passengers, a pilot, co-pilot and two stewards. The report did not identify the three survivors and described victims on the ground as family members of air force personnel. All on board were presumed to be Burmese nationals, since <LOCATION> Kengtung </LOCATION> is normally off limits to foreigners due to security problems in the area. <ORGANIZATION> Burma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> has lost four <ORGANIZATION> Fokker </ORGANIZATION> 27s, a Dutch-manufactured aircraft, since June 21, 1987, when 45 people were killed after a takeoff from Heho airport in the <LOCATION> Shan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. All 49 persons on board were killed near <LOCATION> Pagan </LOCATION> in central <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> in a crash on Oct. 11, 1987. On June 16, a chartered aircraft crashed on a flight from <LOCATION> Myitkyina </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Putao </LOCATION> in northern <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> and all four persons aboard were killed. Several others crashes occurred in earlier years. <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s tiny fleet of eight aircraft is plagued by a shortage of spare parts and poor maintenance. After Friday's crash, the airline has only five <ORGANIZATION> Fokker </ORGANIZATION> 27s for domestic service and three <ORGANIZATION> Fokker </ORGANIZATION> 28 jets for international flights.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     02-03 0921</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,920</SECOND>
<HEAD>Producers Reduce Flocks to Raise Egg Profits</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's egg producers are shipping lazy hens off to the soup factory in an effort to reduce flock sizes, but even those stern measures are unlikely to return quick profits to the battered industry. Department economists say that losses to egg producers in 1988 were the highest since <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> began keeping those financial records 17 years ago. As of Jan. 1, the hen flock that produces table eggs _ the kind in cartons _ was estimated by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> at 233.4 million birds, 6 percent fewer than a year earlier. Overall hen flocks, including hens producing eggs to hatch new chicks, declined 5 percent to 271.3 million birds. `` This was the largest liquidation of layers since the avian influenza outbreak in 1983,'' says economist <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON>. Egg consumption is expected to continue its decline to around 235 eggs per person this year from an average of about 243 in 1988 and 259 in 1984. according to the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> `` Health concerns relating to cholesterol content may be affecting egg consumption,'' the agency said in a recent report. `` At the same time, egg producers have spent little money on changing the image of eggs or convincing consumers that eggs are not just for breakfast.'' Meanwhile, egg prices at the farm were erratic at times in 1988 but wound up the year averaging 62.1 cents per dozen, about the same as in 1987. But production costs have risen in recent years, and in 1988 producers nationally lost an average of 5.2 cents per dozen. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Witucki </PERSON>, another <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> economist, said Thursday in a telephone interview that the 1988 loss of 5.2 cents per dozen eggs was the second poor year in a row for egg producers, who barely broke even nationally with an average net return of 0.2 cents in 1987. According to agency records, he said, producers averaged a net profit of 6.9 cents in 1986 before rising feed costs and other expenses cut margins. Last year was the first real loss since 1980, when producers had a negative average of 3.5 cents per dozen, he said. Further, <PERSON> Witucki </PERSON> said, last year's 5.2 cents was the largest annual loss since the agency began keeping track in 1972, a year when egg producers lost an average of 2.8 cents per dozen. As with any national figures, he said, some egg producers have made money and others have lost. The yearly averages are general indicators of how the industry is faring. `` We expect more negatives in the first half -LRB- of 1989 -RRB-, with feed prices playing a role,'' <PERSON> Witucki </PERSON> said. `` Hopefully, with normal crops, feed prices should decline in the second half. But I'm afraid it does n't look real bright.'' All states have some commercial egg production, even <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> with an output of about 700,000 eggs last year. The top 10 and their 1988 output in millions of eggs: <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, 7,718. <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, 5,644. <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, 5,302. <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, 4,477. <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, 4,294. <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, 3,784. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, 3,396. <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, 3,363. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, 2,758. <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, 2,596.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is a growing consumer of nuts, but an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report says <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> exporters are finding the market a bit hard to crack. The department's <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said that Japanese imports of tree nuts increased more than 40 percent in five years to almost 64,000 metric tons worth $ 220 million in 1987. Although <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> almonds and walnuts are on the upswing in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, some other foreign suppliers are much bigger for certain kinds of nuts. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> has no quotas on the import of tree nuts, the report said. But import duties have ranged from 4 percent for almonds to 9 percent for pistachios and macadamia nuts, 10 percent for hazelnuts and 16 percent for chestnuts and walnuts. However, under the U.S-Japan beef and citrus agreement signed last July, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> agreed to eliminate the duty on pistachios, lower it for macadamias and pecans to 5 percent, and reduce the walnut duty to 10 percent, the report said. `` Although the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> share of the market for pistachios, hazelnuts and macadamia nuts are relatively small, sales have increased notably in the past few years and the future appears bright,'' the report said. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> is the main supplier of pistachios to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> is the largest provider of hazelnuts, and <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> has more than half of the market for macadamia nuts.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has proposed to sharply increase inspection user fees on imported flue-cured and burley tobacco. <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyle </PERSON>, administrator of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marketing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday that all flue-cured and burley that is affirmed by importers to be free of prohibited pesticides is currently assessed fees of 0.1 cents per pound for <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> verification. The proposal would raise the fee to 0.35 cents per pound and establish a minimum fee of $ 162 per shipment for sampling and testing. <PERSON> Boyle </PERSON> said that tobacco not affirmed by importers to be free of banned chemicals is currently charged an additional fee of 0.3 cents per pound to cover <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s more extensive testing. The proposal would raise this fee to 0.35 cents. The 1985 farm law required <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> to revise its fees to reflect changing costs in the inspection and testing of imported tobacco, he said. Public comments on the proposed rule changes can be sent by March 6 to: Director, Tobacco Division, Room 502 Annex Building, AMS, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>, P.O. Box 96456, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> 20090-6456.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SickPresident Bjt   02-03 0555</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sick President, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush: `I'm a Totally New Man. All Well. Totally Recovered'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says he is much better, thank you, and so all <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> can breathe a sigh of relief and put <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> out of mind. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> caught a stubborn cold a few days after taking office two weeks ago, and it was the sort thing that calls attention to itself in a new president. His voice turned raspy, and he apologized to an audience of sailors in <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, Tuesday for `` just croaking away.'' On Wednesday he lost his voice altogether to laryngitis, and greeted guests at a diplomatic reception that night in a bare whisper. He canceled a speech, looked flushed, said he was taking antibiotics for an ear infection, and kept saying it was only a cold. But, `` I'm a totally new man,'' he reported Thursday. `` All well. Totally recovered.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> likes to compare himself to <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Buren </PERSON>, but it was <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Buren </PERSON>'s successor in the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, who came uneasily to mind. <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, 68, gaunt, malnourished and apparently suffering from ulcers, delivered the longest inaugural address on record _ one hour and 45 minutes _ in cold, blustery, wet weather on March 4, 1841. A month later, he was dead in the White House. He refused to wear a hat or coat when riding a horse to his inauguration and then, despite the weather, declined to shorten his 8,578-word speech. He led a parade back to the White House and that night attended three inaugural balls. He caught a cold. Harassed and fatigued from the demands of office seekers, he was unable to shake it off. No help was offered by the environment of a poorly heated White House. According to `` Medical Cover-Ups in the White House,'' by <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> MacMahon </PERSON>, a doctor, and <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Curry </PERSON>, a journalist, published in 1987, <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> _ like many presidents _ was given inadequate care. `` American presidential history is filled with examples of medical treatment that has ranged from questionable to downright incompetent,'' the authors say. By March 27, <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, who had avoided standard medical treatment all his life, was willing to submit to the doctors. He and they both `` knew that the diagnosis _ pneumonia of the right lower lobe of the lung with congestion of the liver _ constituted, in those days, a fatal complication,'' the book says. The doctors first blistered the skin on the right side of his chest, then applied suction cups to draw out what they considered to be the offensive substance making the president ill. That weakened him Next they induced vomiting, gave him castor oil to purge his bowels and finally gave him sedatives in the form of opium and brandy. As a last resort, they tried a Seneca Indian remedy, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> snakeweed. It did n't work, either. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s treatment was presumably more medically relevant than <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>'s and presidential spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> was able to pronounce his boss fit Thursday afternoon. `` His prognosis is excellent,'' he said. `` He's in good shape. His voice is getting stronger. He feels well.'' So <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> relaxed. People here laughed again at what comedian <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> said during an inauguration event _ that the five most feared words in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> were, `` <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>, I do n't feel well.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0203EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-IndianInvestigation     02-03 0637</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Indian Investigation,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Panel May Seek Testimony from Navajo Chairman</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> investigative committee may summon the head of the nation's largest Indian tribe to address allegations he accepted cash payments and favors from contractors seeking work on its reservation. Sen. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ariz </LOCATION>., said after Thursday's committee session that he is `` pursuing'' the question of whether to invite <ORGANIZATION> Navajo </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> MacDonald </PERSON> to testify before the panel, and whether to subpoena him if necessary A special investigative committee of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Indian Affairs has been holding hearings all week in which allegations have been made of corruption and mismanagement in federal Indian programs and on reservations. The investigation was inspired by a series of reports in The <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> and other publications. Two white construction company owners and a <ORGANIZATION> Navajo </ORGANIZATION> contractor, testifying under immunity, spoke Thursday of free airplane rides, cash payments and other favors they gave <PERSON> MacDonald </PERSON> in hopes of increasing their business on the 25,000-square-mile Navajo Nation reservation in northeastern <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> and adjoining parts of <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. They and another Indian construction official also said it was common for non-Indians to create dummy companies headed by Indians in order to qualify for federally financed projects set aside for members of the minority group. Tribal spokeswoman <PERSON> Tazbah </PERSON> <PERSON> McCullah </PERSON>, speaking from tribal offices in <LOCATION> Window </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, said the accounts of fraud and abuse made during the week were `` malicious allegations'' designed to `` discredit the integrity of the Navajo nation, its people, government and sovereignty.'' She said a delegation of 11 tribal officials would travel to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, perhaps by Monday, to testify to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> panel. She said <PERSON> MacDonald </PERSON> would not be among them. <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON> said the committee would hear next week about organized crime and sexual abuses connected with Indian programs. Thursday's session focused on favors allegedly provided to <PERSON> MacDonald </PERSON>, 60. Contractor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Paddock </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Marana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, testified he had offered <PERSON> MacDonald </PERSON> the use of a company airplane and pilot during the chairman's 1986 re-election campaign. He said <PERSON> MacDonald </PERSON> ended up taking about 35 flights, many of them after his November 1986 election and including two trips to <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Paddock </PERSON> said he had not been reimbursed for the trips He said the flights cost him $ 12,000 in pilot and fuel costs, and would have been worth more than $ 60,000 commercially. <PERSON> Paddock </PERSON> said his company was declared ineligible to work on the Navajo reservation by <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON> <PERSON> Zah </PERSON>, who had ousted <PERSON> MacDonald </PERSON> from the chairmanship in 1982. The company was recertified for contracts after <PERSON> MacDonald </PERSON> recaptured the position. <PERSON> Paddock </PERSON> said <PERSON> MacDonald </PERSON> asked him for a $ 35,000 one-year loan in December 1987, money Paddock gave <PERSON> MacDonald </PERSON> and has not been repaid. The contractor said he paid many of the expenses of the two <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> trips he and <PERSON> MacDonald </PERSON> took with their wives and other couples; lent a company truck to <PERSON> MacDonald </PERSON>'s daughter, Hope; and paid a $ 400 bill he received for her use of the vehicle's telephone. He said he also contributed $ 2,500 to a birthday party for the chairman's wife, <PERSON> Wanda </PERSON>, and was later reimbursed for only about half of the amount. <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Springer </PERSON>, a contractor from <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, and his Navajo partner, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Chee </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, told of giving <PERSON> MacDonald </PERSON> $ 1,000 during his re-election campaign in 1986. They also described separate payments of $ 1,000, $ 5,000 and $ 3,000 they said were made last year, and an effort to purchase <PERSON> MacDonald </PERSON> a $ 5,500 replica of a Model A <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> that was thwarted after an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent began making inquiries. `` In my culture, when an elder asks you for help, I did n't see any problem with $ 3,000 or $ 4,000 at the outset,'' said <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>. `` It was just a small favor, but I did n't realize it would get this large.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0205EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RecruitingBan     02-03 0524</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Recruiting Ban,0538</SECOND>
<HEAD>Firm Barred From Recruiting at Law School After Partner Makes Racist
Remarks</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Note language in grafs 8-10.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> law school has barred a prestigious law firm from on-campus recruiting for one year because a partner made racist, sexist and anti-Semitic remarks during an interview with a student. <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON>, dean of the law school, commended the Chicago-based law firm of <ORGANIZATION> Baker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> McKenzie </PERSON> on Thursday for displaying `` sensitivity, professionalism and ... integrity'' after the incident became public. But, he added in a statement, `` just as <ORGANIZATION> Baker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> McKenzie </PERSON> has assured us it will take strong steps to condemn this behavior and to prevent its repetition, so too must we take strong steps to protect our students against insulting and degrading conduct in the interview process.'' The ban, which covers the 1989-90 academic year and had been recommended by the university's <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Students </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Students </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Placement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, came nearly a week after initial reports of the job interview. `` This is especially painful because we've always taken great pride in being part of the solution rather than part of the problem,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON>, chairman of the executive committee at <ORGANIZATION> Baker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> McKenzie </PERSON>, one of the world's largest law firms. `` But obviously, when something like this happens, you must take a look at yourself again.'' According to last Friday's edition of the law school student newspaper, the <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>, a partner from <ORGANIZATION> Baker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> McKenzie </PERSON> later identified as <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Kane </PERSON> conducted the interview with a black female law student. Neither the law school nor the firm has disputed the account. The student has not been identified. Among other things, <PERSON> O'Kane </PERSON> asked the student during a discussion about the practice of law how she would react to being called a `` black bitch'' or `` nigger'' by adversaries or colleagues. When the student remarked at another juncture that she played golf, the partner responded: `` Why do n't blacks have their own country clubs?'' He then answered his own question, saying, `` There are n't too many golf courses in the ghetto.'' The newspaper also paraphrased <PERSON> O'Kane </PERSON> as remarking he would n't want to belong to a Jewish country club, `` but at least they had their own. <PERSON> O'Kane </PERSON> declined to comment when reached by telephone Thursday night at his suburban <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION> home, and referred all questions to <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Cox </PERSON> said <PERSON> O'Kane </PERSON>, a partner for 20 years, has taken an `` indefinite leave.'' He said that <PERSON> O'Kane </PERSON> is `` not a racist,'' and suggested his commments may have been a kind of `` stress test'' for the applicant. `` But let me reiterate there is no attempt to excuse what he did. We'll deal with what -LRB- disciplinary action -RRB- is appropriate in the days ahead,'' he said. <ORGANIZATION> Baker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> McKenzie </PERSON> operates 44 offices in 26 countries and has approximately 1,300 lawyers worldwide. Of the estimated 400 lawyers working in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION> said there would be 10 blacks after the current round of hiring. Of the firms' 432 partners, <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION> said about 30 were women and none are black; 23, however, are graduates of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> law school.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0612EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a BC-Dance     02-03 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Dance,0440</SECOND>
<HEAD>NYC Ballet Presents Two New Peter Martins Ballets</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: No PMs Planned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An attractive, major new ballet and a brief, rather insignificant ballet duet, both choreographed by <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Martins </PERSON>, were danced for the first time by the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ballet </LOCATION> on Thursday night. `` Mozart Serenade,'' for four couples, four women soloists and a corps de ballet, filled the stage in a balanced, flowing, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Balanchine </PERSON> way, without looking like an imitation of a Balanchine ballet. Balance is appropriate because the music is selections from <PERSON> Mozart </PERSON>'s `` Serenades in D Major.'' However, the symmetry is more relaxed than rigid, giving the dance a contemporary look. When one of the four lead couples has a duet, the other six dancers stand as onlookers in two rows of three rather than staying always as couples. The corps de ballet flowed smoothly, melting from three rows of dancers, which gave soloists aisles to dance in, to form a picture frame outlining the soloists. The dancing was of a high order and stressed ensemble _ with soloists and corps presenting one picture. The main costume color, by <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Maters </PERSON>, was pearl gray, accented attractively by darker grays. Gray draperies were hung at each side of the stage. The four lead couples, mostly relatively new to the company, were <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, <PERSON> Roma </PERSON> <PERSON> Sosenko </PERSON>, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Byars </PERSON>, <PERSON> Zippora </PERSON> <PERSON> Karz </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Huys </PERSON>, <PERSON> Marisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Cerveris </PERSON> and <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Neal </PERSON>. <PERSON> Martins </PERSON> also was in a formal mood for the brief pas de deux titled `` Beethoven Romance.'' <PERSON> Kyra </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON> wore green over purple chiffon and <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Luders </PERSON>' costume suggested a Viennese cavalry officer's uniform and boots. The dance was romantic. The couple, both dancing beautifully, moved away from each other and met again in embraces. Miss <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON> had a brief solo but there were no solo variations for <PERSON> Luders </PERSON>. He had to be content with dancing away from the ballerina and jumping, thrusting one leg high and behind him as he reached a far corner, a step he does very well. A viewer was left with the feeling that there might have been more. <PERSON> Lamar </PERSON> <PERSON> Alsop </PERSON> was the noteworthy soloist in <PERSON> Beethoven </PERSON>'s `` Romance in F Major for Violin and Orchestra.'' <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> conducted. The evening began with a terrific presentation of `` Interplay,'' <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Robbins </PERSON>' 1945 witty working of <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Gould </PERSON>'s music. <PERSON> Byers </PERSON> shone, leading the section titled `` Horseplay.'' The finale was <PERSON> Balanchine </PERSON>'s exhilarating `` Stars and Stripes.'' The company is dancing through Feb. 26 at the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> State Theater.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Mideast Bjt   02-03 0771</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Mideast, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Congress Ponders Arab Arms But Has No Peace Plan
Yet</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has begun to weigh a new package of potential <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms sales to the Arab world even as prospects for <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> peace talks remain cloudy. The possible purchases under discussion with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration officials are bound to touch off a row with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s supporters. <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>, for instance, might get 315 Abrams tanks, probably the best in the world, and the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emirates </ORGANIZATION> 40 jet fighters. The list is far from final. It's only a wish list _ what the oil-rich Arab countries and other potential customers would like to buy. Reaction to the soundings that began last Friday on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> could force changes before the White House makes formal requests for approval. In the meantime, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> has unveiled a proposal to extend autonomy _ but not statehood _ to <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabs </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>. The plan was rejected outright by the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, which is gaining diplomatic support in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and apparently sees no reason to compromise on its demand for a state carved out of Israeli-held territory. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> also has not engendered any enthusiasm from the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration despite his offer to withdraw troops from some of the population centers on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> once Palestinians there accept autonomy. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> simply has had nothing to say about the offer. In the Camp <PERSON> David </PERSON> agreements 10 years ago, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> called for autonomy for the Palestinians. After five years of managing their own local affairs, negotiations would be opened for a permanent arrangement. All options, including statehood, would be on the table. The idea was to see how living together would work, but <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> was ostracized for approving something less than immediate statehood for the Palestinians and the plan never got off the ground. If the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration has another approach in mind it has not tipped its hand, although Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> ruled out <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support for an independent Palestinian state at his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation hearing. The classified arms list under discussion in <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> corridors and over lunches reflects a traditional <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> approach of trying to lubricate <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> diplomacy with weapons. A copy obtained Thursday by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> showed <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> under consideration for 200 shoulder-fired Stinger missiles, four helicopters and some new radar and equipment for its jet fighters. The potential Arab purchases have far more punch. <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>, a wealthy <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> state, could receive 200 <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> tanks, known also as the M1A1 and considered by experts to be the best in the world. Other key items include 40 Maverick air-to-ground missiles with an infrared guidance system and electronic warfare gear for <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION> and 24 F-16 jet fighters and 100 <ORGANIZATION> Mavericks </ORGANIZATION> and 100 Sidewinder air-to-air missiles for <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION>. If <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> follows through with specific requests he will have a battle on his hand. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s supporters are concerned that <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> weapons could be turned against the Jewish state in a <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> conflict. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has the power to block a purchase, but only if a majority of both the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> reject a <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> proposal. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, declined to identify any of the weapons under consideration. He stressed it was not a `` sale plan,'' but rather the administration's `` best estimate'' of other countries' weapons needs. `` Each item has to be reviewed by this administration,'' <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s supporters were successful during the Carter and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration in blocking some <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sales to both <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>. But the skillful management of <LOCATION> Baker </LOCATION>, then the White House chief of staff, and other <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration operatives overcame stubborn resistance in 1981 to the sale of Awacs radar planes to <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> which the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved 52-48. The White House, in a cover letter, informed <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> the <LOCATION> Saudis </LOCATION> were in the process of deciding whether to request <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> or European fighter planes to replace their F-5s in the next decade, the sources said. The letter said the <LOCATION> Saudis </LOCATION> were considering jet fighters to be jointly produced by <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and the French Mirage 4000, as well as U.S.-built F-16s and F-18s. Besides the Abrams tanks, on the list for the <LOCATION> Saudis </LOCATION> were seven multiple-launch artillery rocket systems, for battlefield use, and seven of the box-type rockets for <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> along with 1,500 Tow anti-tank missiles.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schweid </PERSON> heads the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> staff.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0612EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BacktotheFuture     02-03 0213</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Back to the Future,0216</SECOND>
<HEAD>Universal to Make Two `Back to Future' Sequels Back-to-Back</HEAD>
<DATELINE>UNIVERSAL CITY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> plans to produce two `` Back to the Future'' sequels this spring and summer starring <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, who had the role of the young time traveler in the original 1985 hit. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Zemeckis </PERSON>, who directed the first `` Back to the Future,'' will return behind the cameras for both follow-ups, the studio announced Thursday. Most of the original co-stars, including <PERSON> Lea </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, also will be reunited. Filming of the first sequel will begin on Feb. 20. The two sequels are scheduled for release in the winter of 1989 and the summer of 1990, respectively. The consecutive filming schedule will keep production costs down and take advantage of an extended opening in <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>'s busy schedule, said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> MCA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> stars as <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Keaton </PERSON> the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> situation comedy `` Family Ties.'' The original `` Back to the Future,'' in which <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> journeyed back to the 1950s and had to make sure his parents fell in love, has grossed $ 350 million in its domestic and international theatrical release. <PERSON> Zemeckis </PERSON>' last film, `` Who Framed <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabbit </PERSON>,'' was last year's No 1 movie at the box office.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Kemp-Finances Bjt   02-03 0787</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Kemp-Finances, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kemp Move Blunts Ethics Question, Senate Confirms Appointment</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> blunted last-minute ethical questions about his acceptance of speaking fees exceeding <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> limits to win unanimous <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation as secretary of housing and urban development. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted unanimously to confirm <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, the former professional football player who served 18 years as a congressman from <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, and unsuccessfully ran for the Republican presidential nomination in 1988. The vote followed by hours the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s vote to recommend <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s nomination to the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, D-Calif., chairman of the housing and urban affairs subcommittee, said Democrats on the committee and the committee's staff concluded that <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s acceptance of thousands of dollars in speaking fees above <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> limits was `` part of a misunderstanding'' and no bar to his confirmation `` There was no reason to do anything to embarrass him or to harass him to block him,'' <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s financial disclosure reports show that in 1988 he accepted or agreed to accept $ 67,350 above what <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> rules allow a member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to accept in one year. The limit is 30 percent of salary, or $ 26,850. In addition, <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> accepted honoraria far larger than the $ 2,000 per event limit. When committee staff raised questions with <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> last week, he agreed to return, forgo or defer more than $ 67,000 in speaking fees to bring his 1988 fees within House limits. Congressional and federal ethics officials said Thursday, however, that it was unclear whether part of <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s remedy _ the deferral of $ 12,500 in excess fees from 1988 to 1989 _ was permitted by <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> rules and federal law. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> declined to comment Thursday on the matter, said his spokeswoman, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Brunette </PERSON>. On Wednesday he attributed the problems to a misunderstanding on his part of the limits. <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON> said, `` There was ambiguity in the rules that led to uncertainty as to what one could or could not do.'' At the federal Office of Government Ethics, deputy director <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> said staff attorneys concluded they could not resolve the questions over <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s fees and the House rules. `` We could n't get anybody there -LRB- at the congressional ethics committees -RRB- that would give us any answers,'' <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> said. As a result, the Office of Government Ethics said in a letter to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committee that it was approving <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s finances within executive branch standards only. House rules forbid members from deferring income from one year to the next `` to avoid the income limitation,'' according to the ethics manual for <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> staff director <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Gottlieb </PERSON> said he did not object to the deferral, however, because he did not believe honoraria were included in that prohibition. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Davison </PERSON>, staff attorney for the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Official </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conduct </ORGANIZATION>, the ethics committee, declined to say whether the committee or its staff had examined the <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> case, saying such information was private. He said the deferral question would be up to the committee, but he added, `` I would suggest caution in making an intentional deferral.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ethics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> ruled on that question in a 1984 case. It said: `` A member may not accept the offer of an organization to defer payment of an honorarium to a subsequent calender year in order to avoid the limitation on honoraria applicable for the year in which the honorarium is earned.'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s move also raised the question of what his 1989 limit would be, since he served only two days as a member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> before resigning Jan. 2. The House rules say the limit is 30 percent of aggregate salary paid during that calender year _ which could mean 30 percent of two day's pay, or about $ 150. Under that interpretation he would have to forgo the $ 12,500 or give most of it to charity. The rules allow members who receive more fees than are permitted in a year to reach the limit by donating the excess to charity. Asked whether <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> would exceed his 1989 limit by deferring the $ 12,500, <PERSON> Davison </PERSON> said, `` I will not interpret that for you ... but it says, aggregate salary, as a member, paid in a calendar year.'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> sought to comply with the rules this week by agreeing to return $ 16,000 in speaking fees and to forgo another $ 39,400 in fees earned but not yet received. He deferred receipt of $ 12,500 in fees earned in 1988 until 1989, a move that left him $ 550 under the 1988 limit. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s spokeswoman Brunette, asked if <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> believed the deferral of the $ 12,500 might still be improper, she said she would relay that question but did not respond further.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0222EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Sweden-Speed     02-03 0096</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Sweden-Speed,0098</SECOND>
<HEAD>Speed Limit To Be Lowered To Protect Environment</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The speed limit on highways in <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION> county will be reduced from 68 mph to 56 mph to reduce pollution from trucks and cars, the county council decided. The council said Thursday that the reduction from 110 to 90 kilometers an hour could cut emissions of carbon dioxide that were affecting the <LOCATION> Baltic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>, the national news agency <ORGANIZATION> TT </ORGANIZATION> reported. Motor clubs and a conservative opposition party on the council protested the decision and said they would appeal to national authorities.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0233EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PayRaise Bjt   02-03 0778</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pay Raise, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pay Raise Spotlight Now on House</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s rejection of a 51 percent congressional pay raise places the spotlight on a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leadership plan to legalize the increase next week but scale it back to 30 percent a day later. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s 95-5 vote Thursday against the raise sent the two houses in different directions, and `` no one knows'' how the controversy will be resolved, said <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan., `` I do n't believe we'll know that for a matter of weeks or months. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> resolution included language to roll back the raise if it becomes law and end the system allowing congressional increases, along with those for top federal executives and judges, to become law automatically unless rejected by both houses. The chief sponsors were Republican Sens. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Pressler </PERSON> of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Grassley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. Also approved, by unanimous voice vote, was a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rules change that would ban senators from keeping fees for speeches, articles and appearances. But the ban on such fees, typically paid by special-interest groups, would only remain in effect while senators were receiving the raise. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> action has strong political appeal to a public angry with the size of the raise, but will have little practical effect under <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s plan to let the increase become law automatically next Wednesday. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> plans to use a risky parliamentary procedure that requires a two-thirds majority to scale back the raise to 30 percent, and to pass a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ban on speaking fees along with other outside income restrictions. House Democratic Whip <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, D-Calif., said there was only a 50-50 chance of getting the two-thirds while Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, and a leading pay raise opponent, predicted it would be `` very difficult for the speaker to find two-thirds to vote for the resolution. Rank-and-file lawmakers would see their salaries rise from $ 89,500 to $ 135,000 under the full raise. But the pay would be $ 116,350 under <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s plan, the same amount <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members can now receive in salary plus honoraria _ defined as fees for speeches, appearances and articles. Even if the <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> plan passed, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> would be unlikely to go along, since senators can now keep $ 35,800 in honoraria and would therefore lose money by accepting a smaller $ 26,850 raise. While the two houses haggled, the 51 percent raise would remain in effect along with the honoraria bans. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> explained his rollback plan at a news conference Thursday, emphasizing the virtue of banning honoraria and taking that same amount in salary. `` The difference is we will be serving one master, not two, that is, the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people,'' he said. `` I do n't like to articulate failure,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said, when asked what will happen if his plan is defeated. `` If for some reason it does n't work, we will regroup.'' The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> could try to pass the 30 percent raise by a majority, like most legislation, but opponents might be able to tack on language rescinding the raise altogether. Under the two-thirds rule, no amendments would be in order. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> plan would scale back the raise for all three branches of government, even though the Constitution prohibits judges' pay from being reduced. `` I think the courts are likely to hold it's unconstitutional to do this to the judiciary,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> released results of a survey showing 57 percent of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members opposing a pay raise vote before the Tuesday midnight deadline and 54 percent favoring instead a vote to reduce the raise to 30 percent. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said his proposed $ 26,850 pay raise was `` a decent raise but not an exorbitant raise,'' compared with the $ 45,500 increase proposed by former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and endorsed by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Actually, most <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members would find their incomes substantially increased, since fewer than half reach the current honoraria limit of 30 percent of income, according to their financial disclosures. The five senators who voted against the package to eliminate the currently-proposed pay increase were <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>.; <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass; <PERSON> Spark </PERSON> <PERSON> Matsunaga </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Murkowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>; and <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>. Their votes do not necessarily mean they support the 51 percent raise. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> honoraria package would: _ Prohibit acceptance of honoraria, but allow a donation to charity on the members' behalf Donations would be limited to $ 2,000 per appearance. _ Prohibit members from receiving any pension or tax benefit resulting from the charitable payments _ Prohibit conversion of the charitable donations to personal use by a member or former member _ Require the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee to issue guidelines for travel expenses reimbursed by outside individuals or organizations
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890203-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-03-89 0238EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Judiciary-ABA     02-03 0676</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Judiciary-ABA,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>ABA, Senators May Meet on Secret Nominations</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
