<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-SeaStallion-Glance     03-19 0161</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Sea Stallion-Glance,0171</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Sea Stallion Helicopter</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Korea-Copter Crash</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 The Sea Stallion helicopter that crashed in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> early Monday, killing 22 of the 37 Marines aboard, is one of a family of heavy assault choppers with a reputation for good performance. CAPACITY: 55 soldiers, or cargo, plus a crew of four. DIMENSIONS: 67 feet, 2 inches long; 24 feet, 11 inches high. WEIGHT: Empty, 23,485 pounds; loaded, 42,000 pounds. RANGE: 540 miles. TOP SPEED: 196 mph. MANUFACTURER: Sikorsky Aircraft of <LOCATION> Stratford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>. HISTORY: First ordered by the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> in 1969 as a successor to the CH-53A, and used in the Vietnam War An advanced version, the CH-53E Super Stallion began service in 1981. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> also use versions of the helicopter with differing model names and numbers. A similar model, the RH-53D Sea Stallion, was used in the abortive <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mission to rescue American hostages held in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 2355EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-SouthKorea-Politics 1stLd-Writethru a0811 03-19 0495</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-South Korea-Politics, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0811,0506</SECOND>
<HEAD>South Korean President Announces Referendum Delay</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 8th graf ``The people...'' with 1 graf to CORRECT to ``foothold''
sted football. Pickup 9th graf `South Korea's...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By M.H. AHN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-woo </PERSON> said Monday he is postponing a national referendum on his performance because `` violent leftist forces'' are trying to use it to overthrow the government. In an address on national television, <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> said `` it would not be of help to the country to hold a national referendum for my performance in office at this juncture.'' <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> said the referendum, which had been widely expected sometime next month, will be held sometime in the future but he gave no date. The president had been expected this week to announce the date to keep a promise he made during 1987 presidential elections. It was not clear if <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> was backing away from the referendum because of concern about potential unrest or because he feared the government could not win the vote and might be forced into new elections. Some opposition and dissident groups had been demanding <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> stake his presidency on the referendum and step down if defeated. It is not clear if <PERSON> Roh </PERSON>, a former general, could win a referendum. The government had said earlier that <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> would not step down if he were defeated, but some senior administration officials have conceded a defeat would put pressure on him to call new elections. <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> said anti-government forces were attempting to use the vote to organize violent protests and topple the government. Dissidents and radical students have organized violent demonstrations in recent weeks, but they have little popular support. `` The people are worried,'' <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> said. `` Leftist forces are trying to use the referendum as a foothold to overthrow the free democratic system.'' <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s divided opposition parties were split over <PERSON> Roh </PERSON>'s decision The Party of Peace and Democracy of <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Dae-jung </PERSON> welcomed the decision, while the <ORGANIZATION> Reunification </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kim </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Young-sam </ORGANIZATION> said it would accept a temporary delay. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Young-sam </PERSON> had been pushing for a referendum after predicting <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> would lose. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Dae-jung </PERSON> opposed a referendum, apparently because <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Young-sam </PERSON>'s party had overtaken his party in opinion polls and could win presidential elections. The two Kims are bitter rivals who split the opposition vote in December 1987 presidential elections, allowing <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> to win with 36 percent of the vote. <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> promised during the election campaign to hold a referendum after his first year in office to give voters a chance to evaluate his performance. <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> also said `` national opinion'' was split on whether to hold the referendum. `` One opposition party said the referendum should be on the question of policy matters, while another party said it should be on a vote of no-confidence,'' he said. `` In view of these developments, the proposed referendum, originally intended to stabilize the political situation and solidify democratization, has lost its meaning,'' <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 2358EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--TankerSinks     03-19 0170</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Tanker Sinks,0172</SECOND>
<UNK>Chemical Tanker Sinks With No Trace Of 23 Missing Crewmen</UNK>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Liberian chemical tanker sank after burning for six days off the coast, with all 23 of its crew members still missing, the coast guard said. A Maritime Safety Agency official said the 23,038-ton Maasgusar broke in two on Sunday and sank, leaving a 700-foot-wide sheet of fire on the water's surface for about an hour, a coast guard official said. The official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said no trace had been found of the 23 crew members _ 19 Filipinos, three Britons and an Irishman. He said water in the area, about 235 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Inubozaki </LOCATION>, was about 18,480 feet deep and it would be difficult to raise the ship. The tanker had been heading for <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> when it was discovered on fire in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> early Tuesday. The tanker was carrying 25,700 tons of chemicals, including ethylene chloride, isopropyl benzene and paraxylene, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 0018EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FourShot 3rdLd-Writethru a0636 03-19 0743</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Four Shot, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0636,0758</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Children And Police Officer Shot By Man With Gun</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 6th graf `The person ...' to UPDATE with
report of teen-agers tossing stones at Proctor's car earlier Saturday,
punching and threatening him.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HENRY STERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WEST ORANGE, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A gunman who neighbors said was harassed regularly by teen-agers shot three young children at an apartment building Saturday and then wounded a police officer before being killed in a gun battle, authorities said. One of the children, <PERSON> Ivory </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 9, died at 9:50 p.m. Saturday in the trauma center of <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>. She had gunshot wounds to the head, said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON>, associate administrator of the hospital. Of the two other children, boys aged 8 and 12, one remained critical and the third was in stable condition at the hospital, <ORGANIZATION> Arnold </ORGANIZATION> said. The administrator declined to identify the children, citing the wishes of family members. `` We do n't have a motive yet,'' Police Chief <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Palardy </PERSON> told reporters at the scene of the shootings. `` It looks like some sort of disaster in there. A man appears to have gone berserk and started shooting.'' The gunman, identified as <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Proctor </PERSON>, in his 40s, died at 4:10 p.m. of gunshot wounds, said <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Francois </PERSON>, assistant director of nursing at <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. `` The person that was involved, for whatever reason, became very antagonistic when he returned home this afternoon,'' said West Orange Mayor <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Spina </PERSON>, who visited the scene. Two witnesses, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, said they saw teen-age boys tossing stones at <PERSON> Proctor </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Cadillac </ORGANIZATION> earlier Saturday while he was driving in <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION>, which borders West Orange. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Green </PERSON> said <PERSON> Proctor </PERSON> left his car to confront the youths, and one of the teen-agers punched him in the face and threatened him. The three children who were shot apparently had no connection to the earlier incident, the witnesses said. Police said they had heard reports of that incident but would not say whether it was a motive in the shooting. One neighbor, a 15-year resident who said he went fishing regularly with the gunman, said <PERSON> Proctor </PERSON> had been physically and verbally harassed recently by teen-age boys in an increasingly drug-infested neighborhood. `` His mind probably just snapped,'' said the neighbor, who added that he would not give his name for fear of an attack on his family by neighborhood youths. `` He's a nice guy. ... It's a shame this had to happen to him.'' One witness, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gress </PERSON>, who lives across an intersection from the apartment building in this <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> suburb, said he was playing solitaire in his home shortly before 3 p.m. when he heard gunfire that `` sounded like firecrackers.'' <PERSON> Gress </PERSON> said when he looked outside, he saw a young boy by a parked car across the street screaming, `` The guy's a maniac.'' <PERSON> Gress </PERSON> said he then saw a police car pull up to the corner, and the gunman started shooting at the cruiser. He went to telephone police and when he returned to the window, the gunman was lying on the ground and the police officer also lay wounded on the ground. The police officer, who works for the <ORGANIZATION> Orange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, was not seriously injured, <PERSON> Spina </PERSON> said. He was admitted in stable condition at <ORGANIZATION> Orange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Gail </PERSON> <PERSON> Proctor </PERSON>. The officer was on a routine patrol of the neighborhood, which lies on the border of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> and the city of <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION>, when he heard the gunshots and went to the scene, <PERSON> Spina </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Palardy </PERSON> said the identity of the officer was not immediately available. <PERSON> Proctor </PERSON> first started shooting at a woman in a first floor apartment, and police believe the gun misfired, allowing the woman time to run into the bathroom. The gunman then shot a child in the apartment and went outside, where he shot two more children, <PERSON> Spina </PERSON> said. The police officer hit the gunman with four rounds, officials Residents of the neighborhood said crime there has worsened recently, with older people forced to live in fear of drug-related violence. `` The young teen-agers are jumping people all the time,'' said <PERSON> Deidra </PERSON> <PERSON> Biggest </PERSON>, a 25-year-old resident who has lived in the area for eight months. `` Houses are getting robbed and cars are getting stolen.'' `` It's getting worse all the time,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorham </PERSON>, 26, who has lived in the area for six months. `` It's crazy out there.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BoatingRdp 1stLd-Writethru a0619 03-19 0353</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Boating Rdp, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0619,0356</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Boys Presumed Drowned in Rhode Island; One Hurt in Florida</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 6-10, `The unidentified ... by authorities' with
5 grafs to UPDATE with boy's name, surgery continued into night, teen-age
drivers of boat taken into custody. No pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Boating accidents Saturday left two boys missing and presumed drowned in <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>, and another critically injured near <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, authorities said. In <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION>, police saw two youths jump into the water from a boat in <LOCATION> Mashapaug </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pond </LOCATION> and try to swim to shore just as a thunderstorm began pelting the area with rain, according to a police spokesman, Lt. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Verrechia </PERSON>. A bystander jumped into the water and began swimming toward one of the youths and was joined by a police officer, but the boy went beneath the surface before the men could reach him, <PERSON> Verricchia </PERSON> said. The other boy, who was about 25 yards beyond the first, went beneath the water as a uniformed officer and an off-duty police officer climbed aboard the youths' boat and paddled towards him, the spokesman said. Divers called off the search after four hours, but were expected to resume Sunday morning, <PERSON> Verrechia </PERSON> said. No one had reported the boys missing and their identities were not known, he said. In <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, a boy suffered multiple cuts to his head and chest after he fell off a jet ski and was run over by a boat driven by teen-agers in the <LOCATION> Intracoastal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Waterway </LOCATION>, authorities said. <PERSON> Ami </PERSON> <PERSON> Missika </PERSON>, 5, was hit at about 3:30 p.m. EST after he fell into the water in north <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, authorities said. The child, who was airlifted to <ORGANIZATION> Jackson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, underwent surgery `` well into the night'' and was in critical condition, said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Santo </PERSON>, a hospital spokesman. `` He had lacerations to the head and the body from the propeller,'' <PERSON> Santo </PERSON> said. The boat left the scene of the accident but returned later, said Capt. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamphear </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION>. The teen-agers, ranging from 13 to 15 years old, were taken into custody for questioning, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 0232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HostageStalemate     03-19 0311</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hostage Stalemate,0323</SECOND>
<HEAD>Armed Man Holds Family Hostage</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SPRINGFIELD, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An armed man who police say had been hospitalized recently for depression was holding his girlfriend, her sister and the girlfriend's 4-year-old daughter hostage late Saturday. Heavily armed police remained in position around a one-story home where <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> `` Dougie'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, 20, was holding the three hostages. A fourth hostage, the 2 -LCB- - month-old daughter of <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> and his girlfriend, was released in the morning, pushed out of the house wrapped in a quilt, police said Police blocked off streets leading to the house and evacuated about 32 families about five hours after receiving the first reports of the disturbance late Friday. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> was reportedly armed with a handgun and threatened to kill himself and the hostages. Twice during the day he fired shots inside the house, but he allowed the hostages to talk to police each time to show they had not been harmed, police said. `` We're just going to wait,'' said Police Chief <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Walton </PERSON>. `` Right now, everything is under control.'' Police spokesman <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON> said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> had made no specific demands but he repeatedly asked to talk to friends and relatives by telephone. `` He seems like he's almost hallucinating,'' said police spokesman <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON>. He said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> was hospitalized recently for depression and apparently had been taking medication that might affect his mood. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON>, a friend who talked to Thomas by telephone during the afternoon, described him as `` paranoid and insecure.'' Although <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON> refused to identify him, relatives, friends and other police sources confirmed <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>' identity, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Springfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal-Register </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> spent a year in prison for aggravated battery for shooting two men at a dance in 1985, the newspaper reported. Police also did not identify the hostages. However, others said they were <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Lambert </PERSON>, 20, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>'s girlfriend; <PERSON> Nikki </PERSON> <PERSON> Lambert </PERSON>, 14; and <PERSON> Katrina </PERSON> <PERSON> Lambert </PERSON>, 4.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 0421EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BlindEscape 4thLd-Writethru a0649 03-19 0544</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Blind Escape, 4th Ld - Writethru, a0649, a0650,0555</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Free Two Children, Kill One Captor, Capture Other</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Combines pvs; INSERTS 6th graf, `Basically, they ...' to UPDATE
with quote from Cook; EDITS to tighten.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>APPLE VALLEY, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police stormed a townhouse early today and freed two children who had been held hostage for more than a day by a blind prison escapee and an accomplice. One of the two captors was shot dead in the attack, police said. A special weapons and tactics team rescued <PERSON> Dominic </PERSON> <PERSON> Platt </PERSON>, 8, and his 6-year-old sister, Cameo, unharmed around 1:30 a.m. this morning, police Capt. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Erickson </PERSON> said. They had been held since Friday afternoon. Police threw a stun grenade into the house when one of the children came out to pick up drinks the authorities had arranged to deliver, Capt. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> said. Police shot one of the captors when he grabbed the girl at knifepoint, <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> said. Police would not immediately identify whether inmate <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> or his accomplice, <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, had been killed, pending notification of relatives. The other captor was taken into custody, police said. `` Basically, they said they had to be allowed to leave. If they did n't, they were going to throw a dead child out,'' <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> said. The children's grandmother, <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Platt </PERSON>, had pleaded to the gunmen on television Saturday night. `` Please <PERSON> Larry </PERSON>, please let them go,'' she said. `` Stop and think. They are very innocent.'' Earlier Saturday, police seized the children's mother, <PERSON> Lois </PERSON> <PERSON> Platt </PERSON>, when she left the house at 10:30 a.m. to start a car in what police described as an escape attempt by the two men. <PERSON> Platt </PERSON> was taken to a hospital for treatment of exhaustion and stress. Police Chief <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivers </PERSON> said he did not know whether <PERSON> Platt </PERSON>'s role in the incident was willing or unwilling, but said she offered no resistance when officers prevented her from going back into the building because of concern over her children `` We just plain stopped her. We did n't let her back inside,'' <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> said. `` It was a decision we had to make. We could not allow her back in when we had a hostage out.'' <PERSON> Platt </PERSON> had corresponded with <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> in prison, but her sister-in-law, <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Platt </PERSON>, said she broke off the relationship more than 18 months ago when she discovered <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> was a convicted murderer. Police had negotiated with the men throughout the day as SWAT officers ringed the building. <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, a blind inmate at <ORGANIZATION> Stillwater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prison </ORGANIZATION> outside <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, escaped from a medical office Friday morning while he was being escorted by two guards to an appointment for a replacement glass eye. <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> had been met at the office by <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, who had a handgun, officers said. The two men disarmed the guards, tied one of them up and fled, police said. <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, 49, was convicted of second-degree murder for strangling his girlfriend in 1982 and was serving his fifth prison stint, said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Dowdle </PERSON>, associate warden at the <LOCATION> Stillwater </LOCATION> prison. He has other convictions for two counts of rape, as well as robbery, criminal sexual assault, burglary and illegal handgun possession. Police have identified his accomplice as a former <LOCATION> Stillwater </LOCATION> inmate, Capt. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. `` I'm sure it was all prearranged,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 0807EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Salva`or     03-19 0315</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Salva`or,0325</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING TO FIX GARBLE IN SLUG</HEAD>
<HEAD>Two Journalists Shot In El Salvador, One Fatally</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CANDICE HUGHES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Security forces shot to death a news photographer and wounded his colleague at a checkpoint near <LOCATION> Ilopango </LOCATION> Air Force Base on the eve of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>'s presidential election, officials said Sunday. Both men were Salvadoran free-lance photographers who worked regularly for the <ORGANIZATION> Reuters </ORGANIZATION> news agency. Representatives of the agency in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> declined to comment. Armed Forces officials were not immediately available for comment. Justice of the Peace <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Aguilar </PERSON> said troops who brought in the body of <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Navas </PERSON>, 28, said the shooting occurred when the two men's motorcycle failed to stop at an air force checkpoint late Saturday night. The magistrate said soldiers radioed the next checkpoint and that troops there shot the two men when they again refused to stop. The armed forces have been on full alert since Tuesday when leftist guerrillas stepped up their campaign to disrupt Sunday's election <PERSON> Navas </PERSON> was shot twice, in the back and the side. The judge said he found at least 22 spent rounds at the scene. <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Galdamez </PERSON>, 34, was shot once in the back and underwent emergency surgery at <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rosales </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. Dr. <PERSON> Marcelino </PERSON> <PERSON> Caballero </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> the bullet entered <PERSON> Galdamez </PERSON>'s back and exited through his upper right arm, injuring a lung. The doctor described the injuries as serious. Colleagues said <PERSON> Navas </PERSON> lived near the base, one of the most strategic military installations in the country, and was on his way home from work. <LOCATION> Ilopango </LOCATION> is five miles from the capital. The shooting occurred on the PanAmerican Highway, which runs past the base. A nurse at the hospital who asked not to be named told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that an air force ambulance brought <PERSON> Galdamez </PERSON> to the hospital.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 0900EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Salvador 2ndLd-Writethru a0654 03-19 0516</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Salvador, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0654,0531</SECOND>
<HEAD>Battle Outside San Salvador On Election Day</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: New thruout to UPDATE with more details on the fighting and
soundman's death, CORRECTS name of justice of the peace. No pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CANDICE HUGHES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soldiers and leftist guerrillas fought near a power station on the outskirts of the capital early Sunday, several hours before voting began in the presidential election. Elsewhere, soldiers shot three local journalists at military checkpoints, killing two of them, officials said. Troops from the 1st Infantry Brigade and guerrillas battled near the power substation in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ramon </LOCATION>, radio reports said. The sounds of the pre-dawn battle could be heard in downtown <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. Afterward, military helicopters circled overhead, occasionally firing rockets at rebel positions. No casualty report was immediately available, and it was not known whether the battle would affect voting in that area. The rebels have knocked out much of the electrical power in the capital and threatened to attack people who drive on the nation's highways in a bid to disrupt the election, which they are boycotting The <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> of President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> is trying to retain power in the election with candidate <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> <PERSON> Mena </PERSON>, a former foreign minister who says he represents new leadership and dismisses charges of corruption and incompetence. <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> by law can not run for re-election. The front-runner, according to the polls, is businessman <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON>, leader of the rightist and free market <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION>, or Arena. That party, which in the past has been linked to rightist death squads, already holds a slim edge in the Salvadoran congress. Soldiers reportedly shot and killed a soundman from a local television crew early Sunday morning in eastern <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. Preliminary reports indicated that <PERSON> Mauricio </PERSON> <PERSON> Pineda </PERSON>, 24, died when soldiers opened fire on the crew's vehicle at a checkpoint near <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, acccording to a newsman at Channel 12, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Figueroa </PERSON>. The crew was traveling from <LOCATION> Morazan </LOCATION> province to the coastal city of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, 115 miles from the capital, <PERSON> Figueroa </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. Late Saturday night, soldiers shot to death a news photographer and wounded his colleague at a checkpoint near <LOCATION> Ilopango </LOCATION> Air Force Base, officials said. Both men were Salvadoran free-lance photographers who worked regularly for the <ORGANIZATION> Reuters </ORGANIZATION> news agency. The agency's <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> office declined to comment. Armed forces officials were not immediately available to comment on either shooting incident. Justice of the Peace <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Aguilar </PERSON> said troops who brought in the body of photographer <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Navas </PERSON>, 28, said the shooting occurred when the two men's motorcycle failed to stop at an air force checkpoint. The magistrate said soldiers radioed the next checkpoint and that troops there shot the two men when they again refused to stop. <PERSON> Navas </PERSON> was shot twice, in the back and the side. The judge said he found at least 22 spent rounds at the scene. The other photographer, <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Galdamez </PERSON>, 34, was shot once in the back and was in serious condition at <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rosales </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 0919EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-YeltsinProtest 1stLd-Writethru a0656 03-19 0469</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Yeltsin Protest, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0656,0475</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thousands of Yeltsin Supporters March Through Central Moscow</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: New thruout to UPDATE with background on party's apparent moves
earlier this month to discredit Yeltsin. No pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of supporters of maverick communist <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> marched through downtown <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> Sunday and vowed to hold a general strike if he does not win election next week to the new national parliament. <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>, who was ousted as <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> party boss after criticizing the pace of President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms, claims the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> party machine is working to defeat him. For many Soviets, <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> epitomizes the quest for more democracy and an end to special privilege for the government and party elite. Chanting `` <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>! <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>!'' at least 3,000 Muscovites set off from <LOCATION> Gorky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> after they were refused permission to hold a pro-Yeltsin election rally there. They marched to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> City Hall after scores of uniformed police sealed off <PERSON> Kalinin </PERSON> <PERSON> Prospekt </PERSON> leading to the Kremlin. At city hall, the protesters demanded a meeting with <PERSON> Lev </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Zaikov </PERSON>, the official who replaced <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> as the Soviet capital's <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> boss in November 1987, and who is in charge of the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> party machine they claim is trying to engineer <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>'s A city official armed with a bullhorn clambered on top of a bus to demand that the crowd disperse, but it remained in front of the municipal building for more than two hours. One pro-Yeltsin speaker perched beside the city hall door called on the crowd to approve a general strike if <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> does not win the right to represent <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in the March 26 elections for the <ORGANIZATION> Congerss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION>, and the protesters raised their hands in agreement. It was not immediately clear when the strike would take place. Earlier this month, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> released a transcript of <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>'s remarks at a private <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> meeting in 1987 that cost him his job as <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> party boss. The transcript said <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> told the gathering that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> had become the object of `` intolerable'' glorification. <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> was named <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> party chief in December 1985 and a non-voting Politburo member two months later. He lost both posts as a result of his remarks at the Oct. 21, 1987 meeting. The party said it was publishing a transcript of the meeting in its new monthly journal, News of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, because of requests by workers and party members. But a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> specialist said the release of 40 pages of scathing attacks on <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and other leaders appeared designed to hurt the 58-year - old <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> in his bid for political office The transcript showed <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> criticized not only <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, who brought him into the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leadership, but <PERSON> Yegor </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>, a conservative force on the ruling Politburo.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 1151EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Kinder-GentlerBush Bjt   03-19 0931</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Kinder-Gentler Bush, Bjt,920</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mostly Talk, So Far, Interest Groups Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> still talks about wanting to build a `` kinder-gentler'' nation, but many of the groups keeping an eye on the new president are taking a wait-and-see attitude on whether he translates words into results. The president has made several strides to demonstrate his commitment to a government that is more compassionate to those in need, and more attuned to such issues as the environment, minority concerns and women. He often describes that aspect of his administration by reviving a phrase he used in the campaign when he pledged to make a `` kinder-gentler'' nation. In that vein, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> last week submitted to <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> his legislative proposal for child care _ a plan that would give a tax credit or refund of up to $ 1,000 per child to low-income people. He also proposed a 29 percent increase in spending for the homeless, to $ 645 million next year. He recently spoke about how he was disturbed by the sight of homeless people huddled on the grounds near the White House. And <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> tempered his opposition to federal gun control and bucked the displeasure of his fellow <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> members by halting the imports of semiautomatic assault guns until their usage can be reviewed. These and other actions give <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a boost simply by comparison with his predecessor, <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, whose record was considered distinctly not kinder or gentler by such groups as women, minorities and environmentalists. But these groups are reserving judgment. Some are waiting for more dramatic leadership, and others, including the environmentalists are waiting to see the fine print that goes with his positive sounding rhetoric on such issues as acid rain. `` He deserves an A for a new tone,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, the two-time democratic presidential candidate who has developed a friendly relationship with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and who has visited with the president at the White House. He said the access <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has given to people who felt locked out of the <ORGANIZATION> Reagan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> has been `` very positive.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has set `` the right tone but not enough boldness in a right direction,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> contended. `` Now the question comes to a test of leadership. It must be bold, it must take a direction that will remedy fundamental problems.'' <PERSON> Heather </PERSON> <PERSON> Booth </PERSON>, president of the liberal lobbying organization Citizen Action, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s `` rhetoric is wonderful'' and that some of his actions have been what she called a welcome break from the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> years. `` I am giving him credit for understanding there's a new progressive opening,'' in the country, she said, but added, `` I have n't seen a substantive set of proposals that are convincing in being able to rise to the challenges.'' Some complain that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, or those around him, often as not have undermined some of the very kinder-gentler signals he has sent. Some examples: _ <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> cheered environmentalists when he indefinitely postponed offshore oil leasing key environmental tracts off <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> But environmentalists were dismayed that he failed one of their highest priority litmus tests when his <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON> announced the administration will allow oil exploration in the <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refuge </ORGANIZATION>. _ <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> called for banning of ozone-depleting chloroflourocarbons by the end of this century, but that was a position that was already advocated by many other nations, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was seen as `` playing catchup,'' said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Stoel </PERSON>, senior attorney for the <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> `` It was n't so much that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was anti-environmental as that he did n't have his act together,'' he said. `` He indicated he was going to be an environmental leader and so far there's been very little environmental leadership shown.'' _ <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposed an increase in the minimum wage to $ 4.25, but coupled it with a lower so-called training wage for first-time workers And he angered labor activists by refusing to intervene in the <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> strike. _ <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> cast a well-publicized and wide net to draw more women into his administration He named two women to his Cabinet, <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Trade Representative <PERSON> Carla </PERSON> <PERSON> Hills </PERSON>. But he has disappointed feminists by lunching at a private all-male club and joining in the merriment at the annual men-only <ORGANIZATION> Alfalfa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> dinner. _ <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> made a strong pitch throughout the pre-inaugural period and in the first two weeks of his presidency for the highest ethical standards in the people he appointed to his administration That message was somewhat diluted when Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> and White House Counsel <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyden </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> both voluntarily disentangled themselves from financial affairs that became the subject of news stories. Neither was engaged in illegality, but said they did not want to permit any appearance of impropriety. Administration spokesman insist the kinder-gentler concept is not on the back burner even though it often is overshadowed by day-to-day events. `` We look for opportunities for getting out any of the messages he's trying to get across,'' said <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> communications Director <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Demarest </PERSON>. `` We'll see more kinder-gentler. We'll see more of the entirety of the program.'' For her part, first lady <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has had no trouble making a kinder-gentler image a big part of her White House life. Her first public event outside the White House was a visit to a daycare center for homeless children. In addition to her longtime promotion of literacy efforts, she has visited soup kitchens, nursing homes, and a schoolchildren's celebration of black history month. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also has set up a foundation to raise money for literacy programs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 1152EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Spring     03-19 0761</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Spring,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spring is Here: The Weather is Changing, So Are The People</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The long, dreary wait for the end of winter is nearing its end as nature gradually edges into change. Human patience, also nearing its limits with winter, can draw encouragement from the spring equinox Monday. While the change of seasons is a gradual, often fitful thing, calendars usually list the solstices and equinoxes as unofficial markers of these transitions. `` The first day of spring is one thing, and the first spring day is another,'' observed the late <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyke </PERSON>, aware that March weather can be fickle and also that the change of seasons can occur at markedly different dates in different parts of the nation. Even so, millions will welcome spring at 10:28 a.m. EST, the moment of the vernal equinox, when the sun crosses the equator on its apparent journey northward, according to astronomers at the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Naval Observatory in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. This, and the autumnal equinox in September, are the only two dates on which the sun rises directly in the east and sets precisely in the west, the Observatory reports. These directions were used to align the Great Pyramids in <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> with an error equivalent to the thickness of a piece of string seen at a distance of six feet, said observatory spokeswoman <PERSON> Gail </PERSON> <PERSON> Cleere </PERSON>. Ancient graves in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and temples in <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> are also aligned to the equinoxes, she said. For the human mind, too, the change may be a point of alignment. `` Spring is a transition season when things change very rapidly,'' observed the late <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Landsberg </PERSON>, professor emeritus of meteorology at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION>. `` One major thing is apparently the change in light ... the most rapid increase in light intensity occurs between February and April,'' <PERSON> Landsberg </PERSON> explained, and this seems to affect human glands and internal reactions. Other fluctuations causing humans to react include `` rapid temperature changes in many places, sometimes highly irregular, changing from low to high to high to low again,'' said <PERSON> Landsberg </PERSON>, who researched the biological effects of weather. Poets and philosophers have lauded spring over the centuries with a curious mixture of cheer and woe, reflecting the differing reactions of humans to the stress of changing weather. As <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Twain </PERSON> observed of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>'s weather, `` it gets through more business in spring than in any other season. I have counted 136 different kinds of weather inside of 24 hours.'' This places stress on the body and, scientists are beginning to believe, the mind also. Human responses vary. Malaise, romance and even depression are among the reactions to these seasonal changes _ although so-called spring fever has been most widely identified with that vague feeling of disinterest, mind-wandering and restlessness. Nature writer <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Borland </PERSON> reflected on the seasonal change in the book `` Twelve Moons of the Year:'' `` There is something in a mild March day that can touch a man to the very quick of his being. Just what it is can not readily be stated, but it must be compounded of sunlight and air and warmth and an immeasurable mystery that is partly summed up by the word ` promise.''' `` When the first warm days of spring come, we all feel a desire to escape, to run away. It becomes difficult to concentrate on serious matters, and we experience indefinable, vague yearnings that disturb our psychic balance and have a bad influence on our professional activities,'' wrote Dr. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Gauquelin </PERSON>, a French psychologist, in his book `` How Atmospheric Conditions Affect Your Health.'' `` Spring is a period when new romances start, when fresh plans are made ... But it is also a season when people experience frequent changes of mood and have bitter arguments with one another,'' <PERSON> Gauquelin </PERSON> wrote. His volume attributes people's response to `` spring hormonal crisis,'' when the endocrine glands are more active and sexual interest heightened. Whether the changes are the result of hormones, sunlight or other factors, nearly everyone observes and reacts to them. German studies in the 1960s found that most illegitimate conceptions tended to occur in May which, the researchers suggested, `` seems to indicate that spring may well be the season for all forms of impulsive behavior.'' On the darker side, French sociologist <PERSON> Emile </PERSON> <PERSON> Durkheim </PERSON> noted a half-century ago that suicides increase in the spring. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> studied the nation's suicide rates between 1969 and 1978 and found that during that decade `` the suicide pattern was distinctly seasonal, above average all spring and below average all winter.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 1158EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Egypt-Taba     03-19 0198</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Egypt-Taba,0204</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mubarak Raises Egyptian Flag Over Taba</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAIRO, Egypt (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> called for world peace Sunday in a ceremony in which he raised the Egyptian flag over <LOCATION> Taba </LOCATION>, the disputed border area that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> withdrew from last week. <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> was on a European tour when the last Israeli policeman left the 250-acre strip of beach overlooking the Gulf of <LOCATION> Aqaba </LOCATION> last Wednesday. In a 20-minute televised ceremony, <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> personally raised the black, red and white Egyptian flag. `` World peace will never be an impossible aim. It is the noble aim which can be reached,'' <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> said. `` Leaders of the superpowers know this and have been moving toward peace.'' Before flying to <LOCATION> Taba </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> laid a wreath at the tomb of President <PERSON> Anwar </PERSON> <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON>, who was assassinated by Moslem extremists in 1981. It was <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON> who signed a peace treaty with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in 1979. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> retained control of <LOCATION> Taba </LOCATION> when it pulled out of the rest of the Sinai in 1982 under the Egyptian-Israeli peace treaty. An international arbitration panel awarded <LOCATION> Taba </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> in September, and in February, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> signed agreements that included $ 37 million in compensation for <LOCATION> Taba </LOCATION>'s main hotel.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 1200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-France-Drownings     03-19 0138</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-France-Drownings,0140</SECOND>
<HEAD>Five Drown When Auto Falls Into Seine River</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MELUN, France (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A small car with 10 youths jammed inside fell into the <LOCATION> Seine </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> early Sunday in the town of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mammes </LOCATION>, and five of the passengers drowned, police said. The automobile, a four-seated <ORGANIZATION> Fiat </ORGANIZATION>, was being driven down a riverside street at about 4 a.m. in the town 45 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> when it went into the river, police said. The 22-year-old driver and four of the passengers were able to pull themselves out of the water, but the others drowned. Three bodies were found trapped in the car, and divers found two more in the river. Police said the victims lived nearby and ranged in age from 14 to 17, but did not immediately identify them or the driver by name.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 1202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Salva`or-Glance     03-19 0275</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Salva`or-Glance,0282</SECOND>
<HEAD>Salvador Elections at a Glance</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Salvador, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here at a glance are some facts, figures and issues related to Sunday's presidential election:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 THE INCUMBENT _ President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>, who suffers from terminal liver cancer, was elected in 1984 and can not by law succeed himself. He steps down June 1; his successor will serve a five-year term.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 THE CONTENDERS _ Seven candidates were running, including: <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> <PERSON> Mena </PERSON> of the centrist <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> of the rightist <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION>, or Arena; <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ungo </PERSON> of the leftist Democratic Convergence. Four minor party candidates were not expected to be significant factors. If no candidate wins a majority, a runoff election will be held in April.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 THE ISSUES _ The main issues were ending a nine-year civil war that has cost 70,000 lives, and restarting a stagnant economy that suffers high unemployment and is heavily dependent on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 THE BOYCOTT _ The rebel <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> called for an election boycott, saying political solutions are impossible without participation by the rebels and the social and political forces they represent. The guerrillas paralyzed most highway traffic, sabotaged electricity, telephones and water, and called on election workers to quit. But they said they would not retaliate against those who wished to vote in defiance of the boycott.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 THE VOTERS _ About 1.8 million Salvadorans are registered; the nation's population is more than 5 million. Voting began at 7 a.m. and ended by 5 p.m. There are 260 municipalities, but 24 were controlled by the rebels and no voting was scheduled.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 1211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Soviet-Democracy Bjt   03-19 0779</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Democracy, Bjt,0802</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING a0670 to fix garble in keyword.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Soviets Discover Democracy, Warts And All</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANN IMSE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet leaders warned last year that their definition of democracy might be a bit different from the Western one. So far, they're right. As the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> lurches toward its first multicandidate elections, it is clear that President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms have brought amazing latitude in public debate to a country that punished unorthodox ideas with harsh prison terms just a few years ago. Now, even the evils of democracy are taking seed in this changing landscape. Political neophytes are battling entrenched <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> officials using classic tactics of election rigging: They pack caucus halls with hand-picked voters, bar electors from holding nomination meetings by denying them a hall, or simply toss candidates off the ballot. Traditional authoritarianism is entangled with the new freedoms. Two weeks ago, <LOCATION> Ukrainian </LOCATION> activists were detained for distributing dangerous literature _ which turned out to be copies of the election law. At meetings during the campaign for the new <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION>, passions run wild Across the country, tens of thousands of people are seizing microphones and the opportunity to speak out on everything from human rights to snow removal. On Sunday, at least 3,000 people marched in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to back <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>, an independent candidate. One recent caucus debate ran 13 hours, yet only 13 of 888 people had left by 3 a.m., said <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> election official <PERSON> Igor </PERSON> <PERSON> Orlov </PERSON>. Despite the publicity over the multicandidate elections, one in four districts has only one name on the ballot. Many of the unopposed candidates are local <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chiefs. `` It's just the same as 10 years ago, in the <LOCATION> Brezhnev </LOCATION> era: one candidate for each district, and each one a power in the party,'' complains <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> Deravyankin </PERSON>, an independent <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> member from the <LOCATION> Volga </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Saratov </LOCATION>. Still, new ideas are holding sway. Newspapers have exposed hundreds of cases of `` non-democratic'' behavior. Citizens have flooded the national commission overseeing the elections with more than 77,000 complaints. And reformers are discovering political tricks of their own. `` There are dozens of violations of the letter of the law,'' acknowledged election commission deputy <PERSON> Dmitri </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Golovko </PERSON> at a recent news conference. The law itself will be revised, he promised. At this point, it seems possible that the same men who run the country on the 12-member Communist Party Politburo could wind up controlling the key legislative committees in the new parliament. But it also seems possible the congress will be full of new faces determined to make the Soviet government responsive to the public. The candidates include former political prisoners; <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> historian and party outcast <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Medvedev </PERSON>; reform economist <PERSON> Oleg </PERSON> <PERSON> Bogomolov </PERSON>, who disclosed the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s huge deficit; <ORGANIZATION> Estonian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Marju </PERSON> <PERSON> Lauristen </PERSON>; environmental activists; and the patriarch of the Russian Orthodox Church, according to a <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> diplomat tracking the election. <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>, the pugnacious former <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> chief who was demoted in November 1987 after stepping on toes with an anti-corruption campaign, is running for the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> seat against organized party opposition. As always, though, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> dominates. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> News found 82 percent of the candidates are party members. The law itself is partly to blame for the manipulation, some people complain. Since a third of the deputies are being elected by certain public organizations, a <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> member who also belongs to the Union of Writers and the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> can participate in all three of those elections and vote in his residential district as well. Election caucuses can legally slash the number of candidates, and they have often rejected reformers. Nuclear physicist and human rights activist <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>, for example, was nominated by 60 research institutes, but the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presidium </ORGANIZATION> rejected him in favor of a slate of old guard managers. In many of the public organizations, there is even less choice, because leaders bar rank-and-file members from voting. The Communist Party itself set the tone when it took 31,000 names and boiled them down to 100 candidates _ for 100 seats. Moreover, even if reformers manage to win a place in the 2,250-seat <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> Deputies in March 26 voting, they still may not wield much power. No official date has been announced for the body's first session. But the law calls for it to meet just one day a year _ to elect the real, working parliament with fewer than 500 members. A <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> majority in the congress could easily elect only its own members to the real positions of legislative power.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 1224EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-CongressRdp     03-19 0642</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Congress Rdp,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>House To Consider Legislation On Minimum Wage, Protecting Whistleblowers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is making one of its slowest starts in recent memory as it heads toward April with little accomplished but a series of bruising internal battles. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will be on a two-week Easter break starting Monday, but before leaving Friday it confirmed Rep. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> as defense secretary. The non-controversial ratification was a breeze after the bitter struggle over President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s first choice for the job, former Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON>. The rejection of Tower by a 53-47 vote, largely along party lines, handed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a major defeat and absorbed the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> for nearly two months. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, which does n't start its Easter break until Friday, faces floor votes this week on raising the minimum wage and legislation protecting whistleblowers _ government workers who report corruption within their own agencies. House members also may this week get a report from the <ORGANIZATION> Ethics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. The 12-member committee, which undertook the inquiry into the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Democrat's financial dealings nine months ago, began deliberating last week on whether <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> broke House rules. Their investigation coupled with the ill-fated fight to raise congressional pay, and now a search among Republican members for a minority whip, have sidetracked <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> action on any major legislation so far this session. House Republicans are expected to choose Wednesday between two candidates vying for the number two leadership post. Reps. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Madigan </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Newt </PERSON> <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> are competing to succeed <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, who resigned last week after being confirmed as defense secretary. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> is the leader of an activist conservative wing of the party while <PERSON> Madigan </PERSON>, currently the deputy whip, is regarded as a pragmatist who would probably be more willing to work with the Democrats to win support for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s programs. The House is scheduled to vote Tuesday on a bill to expand the rights of federal employees who blow the whistle on fraud. The measure sailed through the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> last Thursday, 97-0, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has promised to sign it after the House completes its work. Similar legislation was the subject of one of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s most controversial vetoes The legislation would lower the burden of proof for whistleblowers who claim they have been punished by their employers for disclosing misdeeds within their agencies, and increase the burden of proof for the federal agencies defending their decisions. House floor debate over the minimum wage is expected to begin Wednesday, with Democrats seeking an increase from $ 3.35 to $ 4.65 by 1992. Republicans are supporting the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposal that minimum wages raise only to $ 4.25 by 1992, with a provision that employers be allowed to pay new workers $ 3.35 for the first six months. The minimum wage has not increased since 1981. Budget negotiators from both the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> are to exchange offers this week, with Democrats expected to push for military cuts equal to domestic spending cuts in the fiscal 1990 budget. Rep. <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, D-Calif., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said he and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>, D-Tenn., planned to work together in drafting a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> budget In addition to the balance between domestic and military spending cuts, <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON> said he wants new revenues to equal the overall spending cuts. Also this week, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> banking subcommittee will hold the last of more than three dozen congressional hearings on the savings and loan crisis, listening a final time to <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> budget director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> before writing a $ 100 billion bailout plan. Banking committees in both houses, using <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposal as the foundation but possibly altering many of its key provisions, plan to put the actual bailout package together the first week <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is back in session after Easter.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 1232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Salvador-Geography     03-19 0371</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Salvador-Geography,0385</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING a0677 to fix garble in keyword.</HEAD>
<HEAD>El Salvador at a Glance</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Salvador, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a look at <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, a nation nestled in the soft <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> curve of <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, a land with a history of violence that is named for <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 GEOGRAPHY _ The country covers 8,260 square miles, about the size of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. It is rugged, a land of volcanoes and lakes and rich soil. It is about 950 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, 950 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 POPULATION _ Its more than 5 million people are mainly Roman Catholic and mestizo _ people of both <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> heritage. More than 500,000 of its residents have fled its 9-year-old civil war, most of them to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 HISTORY _ It was conquered in 1525 by the Spanish. It became independent on Sept. 15, 1821 and joined the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION>, which later split into the nations that now make up <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. It was ruled for most of this century by a land-owning oligarchy in alliance with the military. In 1932 a peasant rebellion organized by <PERSON> Farabundo </PERSON> <PERSON> Marti </PERSON> was crushed by a military regime that killed 30,000 people; the leader of that rebellion inspired the present guerrillas, the <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 ECONOMY _ It is mostly agricultural, with coffee the main cash crop. In the 1960s and 1970s it became a manufacturing center for the Central American market. Its largest input is <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military and civil aid, which comes to $ 1.5 million a day.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 THE WAR _ The conflict began in 1979 when a group of young officers overthrew former president Gen. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Humberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Romero </PERSON>. A junta tried to impose agrarian and social reforms, but dissatisfied leftists began a rebellion in late 1979. The conflict has led to more than 70,000 deaths, most of them civilian, and many suspected leftists killed by right-wing death squads in the early 1980s. In 1984, <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>, a Christian Democrat, became the first popularly elected president in 50 years. Sunday's election marks the first time Salvadorans have had a chance to replace an incumbent civilian government with a different party.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 1232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SAfrica-Crash     03-19 0115</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-SAfrica-Crash,0120</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Killed, 150 Hurt In Train Wreck In South Africa</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two passenger trains collided head-on Sunday, killing two people and injuring at least 80, a railroad spokeswoman said. The collision occurred at 2:30 p.m. at a commuter station on the western outskirts of <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>. The two trains were traveling in oppositie directions on a rail line linking <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> with <ORGANIZATION> Randfontein </ORGANIZATION>, a town 20 miles to the west. The driver of one of the trains and a passenger were killed, according to <PERSON> Yvette </PERSON> <PERSON> Marais </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for South African Transport Services. She said from 80 to 100 passengers were injured. The cause of the crash was not known.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 1233EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-China-Conference     03-19 0400</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Conference,0013</SECOND>
<HEAD>Key Speeches At Advisory Conference Stress Party Line, Unity</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A major government advisory conference convened Sunday with speakers urging unity in solving <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s growing economic problems, setting the tone for a legislative session that opens Monday. The brief and businesslike opening session of the 2,081-member <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Political </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Consulative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> emphasized working together under the leadership of the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. The somber theme was in sharp contrast to the conference's last full meeting in April 1988, which saw unprecedented lively debate and calls for democracy. Since then, however, overheated economic growth has produced chronic shortages, widespread corruption and annual inflation of 36 percent, causing a slowdown in both economic and political reforms. Conference Chairman <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiannian </PERSON> urged the delegates to share the government's concerns, offer their suggestions and dedicate themselves to finding solutions. Vice Chairman <PERSON> Qian </PERSON> <PERSON> Weichang </PERSON>, who delivered a 13-page work report, called on the delegates to `` be ceaselessly diligent'' in pushing forward the government's economic policies. The speeches were greeted with only perfunctory applause by the delegates who attended the 80-minute session in the Great Hall of the People in central <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. The conference draws delegates from among scientists, scholars, writers and official organizations. Its annual plenary session, scheduled to last 10 days, is always timed to coincide with the annual meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s legislature The congress begins its 16-day session Monday. Officials reportedly have attempted to discourage unwelcome debate and criticism of government policies at both meetings this year because of concern that the economic problems could trigger social instability. Conference official <PERSON> Cheng </PERSON> <PERSON> Siyuan </PERSON> reported that delegates have made more than 2,000 suggestions to the government since their last full meeting, and that more than a quarter of these have been adopted. But he gave no details about the nature of the suggestions. He said delegates have been briefed from time to time by officials on government policy and helped carry it out, especially by joining in efforts to police prices and cut back on wasteful construction projects. The speakers' clear message was that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s increasingly restive intellectuals can best serve the country by using their talents to implement party decisions rather than questioning or criticizing them. The opening session was attended by senior party and government leaders, including General Secretary <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziyang </PERSON>, Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> and President <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> <PERSON> Shangkun </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 1236EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RinehartProbe     03-19 0960</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rinehart Probe,0987</SECOND>
<HEAD>1978 Sex Abuse Charge Still Follows Popular Columbus, Ohio, Mayor</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Note contents of 12th paragraph, `In 1978...'.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With LaserPhoto</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BETH GRACE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The political wounds of a 10-year-old sexual assault allegation have been reopened for Mayor <PERSON> Dana </PERSON> <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON> with a city council probe and filing of a lawsuit that could mean the end of his hopes of running for governor. <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON> was <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> treasurer, a rising star in the local <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in 1978, when his children's 13-year-old baby sitter accused him of sexually assaulting her while she slept on a couch in <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON>'s home. He has denied the allegation and a grand jury failed to indict him. But a newspaper story last fall resulted in the council investigation and one by the police department into whether a police officer spied on the girl's family in 1983 in an attempt to discredit her and gain a police endorsement for <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON>, who was running for mayor. <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON> did n't get the endorsement, but he won the election. He is now serving his second four-year term as mayor of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>'s capital city. <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON>, 43, said he does not know how the resurrection of what has become known locally as `` the baby sitter incident'' will affect his political future, which he at one time had hoped would be spent in the governor's office. Once-plentiful rumors that <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON> planned to run for governor in 1990 have died down since the investigations, despite an <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> poll in January that showed he had a 78 percent approval rating in the city of approximately 600,000. It was his highest rating ever. `` Part of me would love to -LRB- be governor -RRB-, but part of me says no. I've had a taste of politics that has not been good. The jury is still out in my heart and in my head,'' he said. The former baby sitter, <PERSON> Vicki </PERSON> <PERSON> Rae </PERSON> <PERSON> Pardue </PERSON>, now 23, said she hopes <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON>'s political future is indeed wounded. `` I do n't think <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON> has any business being anywhere in politics, which includes governor,'' she said at a news conference on Wednesday. On Thursday _ two weeks after the council hearings _ Ms. <PERSON> Pardue </PERSON>'s stepmother, <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Pardue </PERSON>, filed suit in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> against <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON> and the police officer accused of spying, contending they engaged in a political conspiracy against the family In 1978, Ms. <PERSON> Pardue </PERSON> told police that she was asleep on <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON>'s couch when she awoke to find him performing oral sex on her She contended he then kissed her on the mouth, said he would be back later and walked out of the room. Ms. <PERSON> Pardue </PERSON> later passed a police-administered polygraph test. <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON>, who was advised by his lawyer not to submit to a police test, said he passed a privately administered polygraph test. For 10 years, questions have surrounded the propriety of a <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> grand jury hearing into Ms. <PERSON> Pardue </PERSON>'s allegations. <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON> was allowed to testify before the grand jury _ an opportunity that is only rarely afforded the accused in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. Also permitted to testify on <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON>'s behalf was a psychiatric expert who told the jury that, although he had not interviewed Ms. <PERSON> Pardue </PERSON>, she may have dreamed the incident and believed it had actually happened. The grand jury declined to indict <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON>. The `` baby sitter incident'' resurfaced last October when The Plain Dealer in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> reported that police officer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, a devoted <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON> supporter, had conducted secret, politically motivated surveillance on the <PERSON> Pardue </PERSON> family for two months in 1983. After <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON> was elected, <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> was promoted from the police force to deputy city safety director and then deputy city development director. He was fired after he refused to cooperate in a police investigation a few days after the Plain Dealer story. <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON> says he knew nothing about <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>'s investigation or the officer's 13-page report of his findings until the newspaper queried <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> about it Oct. 7. He plays down the controversy surrounding <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>'s activities. `` We've had city employees who, unfortunately, have done things that are out of line. We've had worse stuff than this. We had a police officer who robbed banks,'' <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON> said. The internal police investigation of <LOCATION> Morgan </LOCATION>, which ended in November, found no criminal activity, although police said their investigation was hampered by the fact that <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> refused to be interviewed. The findings of a council investigation _ which concluded March 2 after three days of testimony from <LOCATION> Rinehart </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> and others _ will be known next month. Testimony at the hearings raised questions about whether <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON> knew of the report and who in the police department and his campaign may have authorized the surveillance. <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, who testified under a grant of immunity, said he conducted the surveillance with neither the knowledge nor permission of his superiors, <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON>, or any member of the <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON> campaign. `` I did n't feel they had a need to know,'' <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> said. He testified that he researched the <PERSON> Pardue </PERSON> family's geneological history, recorded license numbers of mourners at the funeral of Miss <PERSON> Pardue </PERSON>'s father in 1983, and obtained information on the family's banking records without obtaining a subpoena _ an order required under federal bank right-to-privacy laws <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> said he conducted the investigation on city time and used city equipment. <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON>'s testimony that he did n't know about <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>'s report until last fall was contradicted by testimony from two local reporters, who told the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> they had confronted <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON> with a copy of it in 1983. A third said he'd seen a copy of the report in 1983. The Pardue lawsuit seeks unspecified compensatory and punitive damages as well as preliminary and permanent injunctions ordering the defendants to halt any further investigation of the family. No hearing date was set.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 1240EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-DisneylandStall     03-19 0258</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Disneyland Stall,0265</SECOND>
<HEAD>Disneyland Tram Ride From Fantasyland To Tomorrowland Stalls</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANAHEIM, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A stalled aerial ride left about 150 persons dangling in the sky over <ORGANIZATION> Disneyland </ORGANIZATION> up to five hours while workers struggled to rescue them. The Skyway cable stopped Saturday, apparently after someone in one of the four-person gondolas began rocking their car vigorously, said <ORGANIZATION> Disneyland </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> McTyre </PERSON>. About 150 people were aboard the ride at the time. No injuries were reported during the shutdown and ensuing five-hour rescue effort, <PERSON> McTyre </PERSON> said. All the attractions in Fantasyland and several in <LOCATION> Tomorrowland </LOCATION> were closed because fire trucks had to maneuver underneath each car during the prolonged rescue effort. Firefighters used hydraulic lift equipment to rescue passengers, one by one, from gondolas suspended about 40 feet overhead. The gondola ride shut down automatically Saturday evening, the spokesman said. Riders had to be lowered to the amusement park floor by firefighters using extension equipment. `` Eyewitnesses reported one guest car being swung by a guest severely back and forth,'' <PERSON> McTyre </PERSON> said. `` We're speculating that's what triggered the Skyway safety system to shut down like it did. Firefighters from the <LOCATION> Anaheim </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> and Garden Grove fire department assisted in the rescue effort, he said. `` The guests have all been calm and no one was injured,'' <PERSON> McTyre </PERSON> said. `` It's just been a big inconvenience, both for people stuck up in the air and those on the ground.'' No legal action was planned against the riders blamed for setting off the ride's emergency shutdown system, the spokesman said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 1245EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-MinimumWage Bjt   03-19 0791</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Minimum Wage, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>Raising The Minimum Wage Will Cost Taxpayers As Well As Employers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As business and labor argue over raising the minimum wage, the potential impact on the federal budget and major jobs programs has been virtually lost in the debate. That changes this week when the bitterly partisan debate reaches the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor. Some say raising the minimum wage from its current $ 3.35 an hour to $ 4.65 as proposed would have virtually no impact on the federal budget. Others argue it would cost the budget, and taxpayers, as much as $ 5 billion. Although most Democrats have downplayed any budget impact, an analysis prepared last week by the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> for the Democratic sponsors of the legislation conceded that raising the minimum wage could cost the government money and possibly force cuts in at least four jobs programs. The nonpartisan <ORGANIZATION> CBO </ORGANIZATION> said it could not estimate the potential cost because of insufficient data. But a House Republican analysis estimates that if the Democrats' bill becomes law it would cost $ 570 million a year by 1992 to maintain current staffing levels in just those four programs, College Work Study, <ORGANIZATION> Head </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Start </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> for Older Americans and the federal government's summer youth employment program Without that money, those programs will be forced to cut more than 435,000 jobs, with work study, the campus jobs often awarded as part of a student's financial aid package, accounting for half the total, according to the Republicans. `` Somebody must speak out on behalf of the victims of this legislation,'' Rep. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Armey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>, said in an interview. `` The Democrats like to talk about these programs, but compassion without understanding can be cruel and wasteful.'' <PERSON> Armey </PERSON> tried unsuccessfully to amend the Democratic bill in committee last week to exempt the four programs from having to pay their workers any increase in the minimum wage. Only four fellow Republicans sided with <PERSON> Armey </PERSON> as the amendment was trounced. He promised to try again during floor debate. <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON>, an aide to Rep. <PERSON> Augustus </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, D-Calif., sponsor of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> legislation, said <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> would support increased spending on the programs to save the jobs but opposes paying their workers less than the minimum wage The prospects of getting more money for the programs to offset the added payroll costs `` are between zero and none,'' countered <PERSON> Armey </PERSON>, also a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. Republicans are supporting President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposal for a more modest increase, to $ 4.25 an hour by 1992, provided employers are allowed to pay new workers $ 3.35 an hour for six months. That would alleviate some of the cost to the government, the Republicans say. Their analysis did not include data on the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plan. White House estimates of the impact the Democratic minimum-wage bill would have on the budget range up to $ 5 billion. That figure came from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisers </ORGANIZATION>, which in a report to the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said a higher minimum wage would cause an inflationary spiral in all wages and a subsequent hike in interest rates. It estimated those higher rates would result in the government having to pay from $ 2 billion to $ 5 billion in higher interest for the money it borrows. Two other topics have dominated the debate over the minimum wage _ whether a `` training wage'' should be included in the legislation and to what degree raising the minimum wage results in job losses. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> insists his support hinges on raising the minimum no higher than $ 4.25 an hour with the accompanying provision allowing employers to pay the sub-minimum for six months. Democrats, apparently convinced they can not override a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> veto, have shown increased willingness to support some form of training wage and plan to tag such a provision onto the House bill this week. But it will require specific training, unlike <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposal, and have a far shorter life span than the six months espoused by the president. <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> was reviewing a handful of training wage proposals and, although he has been a staunch critic of the idea, will select one to add to his bill. `` He knows President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will be there for four years and would accept a bonafide training wage,'' <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> said. As for potential job losses, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration maintains the Democratic bill would cost 650,000 jobs by 1992 while the president's more modest proposal would cost about 200,000. The Democrats have assailed those figures, saying past increases in the minimum wage have not caused significant job losses. But the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, in a report sent to <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> on Friday, estimated that raising the minimum to $ 4.65 would cause a loss of from 125,000 to 250,000 jobs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 1259EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SAfrica-Violence     03-19 0254</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-SAfrica-Violence,0260</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Policemen Wounded in Grenade Attack</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four black policemen were wounded when a hand grenade was hurled through the gates of a police training center in <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION>, police said Sunday. No arrests were reported, and no one claimed responsibility for the Saturday night attack. Police have blamed similar past attacks on the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> guerrilla movement. Police said 19 black youths were arrested after attackers firebombed a government building in a black township near the port city of <LOCATION> Durban </LOCATION>, also Saturday night. Officers fired tear gas, shotguns and pistols to disperse the bombers, and one youth was wounded, police headquarters said. In <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION>, the main black township outside <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>, a mob caught a suspected rapist, and stoned and burned the man to death Saturday. Police confirmed the killing, and two newspapers published photographs of the burning body. In another development, anti-apartheid groups announced prayer services nationwide on Tuesday in support of detainees, particularly those staging hunger strikes to protest being held without charge. They are held under provisions of a state of emergency in effect since 1986. Tuesday will be the 29th anniversary of the <LOCATION> Sharpeville </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Massacre </LOCATION>, in which police shot and killed 69 unarmed blacks protesting <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s policies of racial separation. Two hunger strikers are reported in critical condition. Lawyers and activists say <PERSON> Sandile </PERSON> <PERSON> Thusi </PERSON>, held in <LOCATION> Durban </LOCATION>, has not eaten for 31 days, and <PERSON> Donsie </PERSON> <PERSON> Khumalo </PERSON>, a union leader held in <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION>, has refused both food and liquids for 10 days.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 1302EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Afghanistan     03-19 0499</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Afghanistan,0519</SECOND>
<HEAD>More Than 200 Afghan Army Troops Reportedly Surrender to Guerrillas</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN WILDER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 200 Afghan army troops defected with tanks and weapons to Moslem guerrillas, and another 37 soldiers were captured during fighting in northern <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, insurgent sources claimed Sunday. <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s state radio, monitored in <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION>, said Sunday that 215 guerrillas were killed and 64 others injured in the last 24 hours of fighting in the strategic eastern Afghan city of <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION>. It also said `` huge amounts of arms, including missiles, were seized.'' Neither the guerrilla or communist government claims could be independently verified. A spokesman for the fundamentalist <ORGANIZATION> Jamiat-i-Islami </ORGANIZATION> guerrilla group said 43 officers and 165 enlisted men of the Afghan 18th Division defected to insurgents Tuesday about 72 miles north of <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. They handed over 12 tanks, 38 ammunition trucks, long-range rockets and other military equipment, <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Shoaib </PERSON> said from Jamiat's headquarters in <LOCATION> Peshawar </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. He said the guerrillas also captured five government officers and 32 soldiers in attacks on communist security posts along the strategic <LOCATION> Salang </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION> on March 10. The rebels control much of northern <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Panjshir </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Salang </LOCATION> road, <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>'s main land route to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, runs through the valley. Soviet forces in February ended a nine-year intervention in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, but <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> continues to send supplies to <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>'s beleagured communist government. The communists maintain their hold on <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s cities, but guerrillas control more than 90 percent of the countryside. In <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, Afghan authorities said two Pakistani military men, <PERSON> Bashir </PERSON> <PERSON> Majid </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Afzal </PERSON>, were captured near <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION>, 300 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, which backs the guerrillas, has denied any nationals are fighting in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government radio reports said guerrillas fired several rockets into <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> on Sunday, killing three civilians and injuring 19, including eight communist troops. The radio claimed 214 guerrillas were killed and 64 people injured around the city in the last 24 hours. It gave no army casualties. Insurgents two weeks ago chose the city, <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s third largest, for their first major offensive against the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government since the Soviet pullout. They captured a key garrison at <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> and breached airport defenses, but communist forces have stalled the advance with massive aerial and artillery bombardments. Hundreds on both sides are believed to have been killed and wounded since rebels began their attack on March 6. Pakistani officials say more than 10,000 civilians have fled the fighting to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, which already shelters more than 3 million Afghan refugees. <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> lies on a key road between <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. Observers believe its fall would be a major blow to the communists. Speaking in a news conference in <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> Sunday, guerrilla leader <PERSON> Gulbaddin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hekmatyar </PERSON> said the insurgents favored a `` gradual fall of big cities in order to avoid massacre and genocide of the Afghan people.'' Guerrilla leaders have formed their own provisional Afghan government-in-exile, which would come from <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> to establish an Islamic republic if the communists fall.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890319-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-19-89 1308EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Tibet     03-19 0505</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tibet,0521</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING a0688 to fix garble in keyword.</HEAD>
<HEAD>China Condemns U.S., European Resolutions on Tibet</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
