<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 2327EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SemiautomaticWeapons     03-23 0486</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Semiautomatic Weapons,0501</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sheriff Had Issued Statement against Semiautomatics Hours before
Rampage</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Hostage Shot</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN K. PAULSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A sheriff who came out against semiautomatic weapons found his fears borne out only hours later when a gunman cut a bloody path through his district, killing two people and wounding three, including two deputies. During Thursday's rampage by a man wielding a semiautomatic MAC-11 machine pistol, <LOCATION> Arapahoe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> again lashed out at the sale of such weapons. `` Our officers are out-gunned by these weapons of war. These guns are designed to kill and maim people,'' he said. He held up a blood-stained revolver one of his deputies had used against Thursday's suspect, and said the deputy was totally out-gunned. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said the MAC-11 can hold 32 rounds and fire 10 times faster than the standard .38 - caliber pistol issued to all deputy Deputies said 20-year-old <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> went on a 12-hour rampage in which he abducted a woman, killed her and her mother-in-law, raped another woman, shot two police officers, shot a hostage in the back and then killed himself Thursday, ending 12 hours of terror. In his position paper issued Wednesday, <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said, `` I am a western Coloradan who enjoys big game hunting and I do n't want to see anything that would hurt sport hunting. But we have to do something about these weapons of war.'' <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said laws should be tightened to control who can buy such weapons, and if they ca n't be controlled, he urged the <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> to pass a law to ban their sale. In his paper, <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> cited the January shooting in <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, in which five children were killed and 29 children and a school teacher were wounded by a man carrying a copy of the Chinese-made AK-47 semiautomatic rifle. `` This tragic event has stimulated city, county, state and federal legislative efforts to control or ban these weapons of war,'' <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> has approved a ban on 40 types of assault-type weapons, and similar bills are pending in other states. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> Administration temporarily has banned the import of semiautomatic assault rifles. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>'s paper said that although the Constitution gives citizens the right to import, manufacture, sell and possess semiautomatic weapons, there is also `` a burden to place some reasonable controls on these weapons of war without abridging the sportsman's right to legitimate sporting rifles.'' `` I do not propose their absolute ban, but simply to bring them under the same or similar controls'' as machine guns, silencers, sawed-off rifles, sawed-off shotguns, anti-tank guns, bazookas, mortars, and caneguns, he said. Included in his list of weapons to be restricted are the MAC-10 and MAC-11, the gun used in Thursday's attacks. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said recent raids in <LOCATION> Arapahoe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> have netted a fully automatic AK-47, a fully automatic MAC-10 with a silencer, an AR-15 and a semi-automatic shotgun.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PizzaHostages     03-23 0265</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pizza Hostages,0273</SECOND>
<HEAD>Noid Ruled Incompetent To Stand Trial</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DECATUR, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man named <PERSON> Noid </PERSON> who believed he was the target of Domino's Pizza's `` Avoid the Noid'' advertising, was ruled mentally incompetent Wednesday to stand trial for holding two Domino's employees hostage. <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamar </PERSON> <PERSON> Noid </PERSON>, 22, of <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, could be tried later under an order entered by Superior Court Judge <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON> <PERSON> Tillman </PERSON>. For the next 90 days, he is to be evaluated by the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION>. The department `` will decide whether he's likely to become competent,'' <LOCATION> DeKalb </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Public Defender <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> said. `` We do n't know at this point what Mr. <PERSON> Noid </PERSON>'s prospects are.'' Police said Noid apparently believed that the advertising campaign, which features a mischievous animated character called `` The Noid,'' was directed at him. He held two hostages at gunpoint for nearly six hours Jan. 30 at a Domino's Pizza outlet in <LOCATION> Chamblee </LOCATION>, east of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, and at one point fired four shots into the ceiling. The hostages finally escaped when he turned his back. During the standouff, Noid demanded $ 100,000, a getaway car and a science fiction novel. He also ordered and ate a pizza. <ORGANIZATION> Chamblee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said <PERSON> Noid </PERSON> told police that he thinks <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Monaghan </PERSON>, owner of the Detroit-based pizza chain and the <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION> baseball team, `` comes into his apartment and looks around.'' A grand jury indicted Noid on two counts of aggravated assault, two counts of false imprisonment, one count of possessing a firearm in the commission of a crime and one count of attempted theft by deception.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0510EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-CornyLogo     03-23 0133</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Corny Logo,0138</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farming Community Seeks Less Corny Identity</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AUBURN, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Corn is king in this small town, but officials have turned a deaf ear on a proposal to feature the vegetable in a new city logo. Officials met Tuesday at a table lined with corn-emblazoned coffee mugs that city Administrator <PERSON> Phillip </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Belcher </PERSON> said could be used to help promote <ORGANIZATION> Auburn </ORGANIZATION>. But leaders opted for a contest to create an easier-to-swallow emblem, <PERSON> Belcher </PERSON> said. `` We're trying to get a little more notoriety,'' he said, adding that many people never heard of the farming community of 1,900 residents. Officials in the town 100 miles north of <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> will work with schools this fall to come up with a new logo for road signs, promotions and a city flag, <PERSON> Belcher </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0055EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Painted-OverArt     03-23 0159</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Painted-Over Art,0162</SECOND>
<HEAD>City Asks Artist To Redo Painted-Over Frescoes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BRUSSELS, Belgium (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The mayor of a <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> suburb who ordered three <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Somville </PERSON> frescoes to be painted over because she found them too glaring has asked the Belgian artist to restore them _ for free. The frescoes in the offices and restaurant of the Watermaal-Bosvoorde City Hall were covered over with paper and painted over last week when <PERSON> Somville </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Barcelona </LOCATION> opening a retrospective show of his art, to much acclaim. Mayor <PERSON> Andree </PERSON> <PERSON> Payfa </PERSON>'s view of <PERSON> Somville </PERSON>'s work stirred widespread protests. On Wednesday, she changed her mind and suggested <PERSON> Somville </PERSON> could return the works to their former glory, free of charge. But earlier, <PERSON> Somville </PERSON> called <PERSON> Payfa </PERSON>'s decision `` a crime ... pure lunacy.'' And even if the covering is removed, <PERSON> Payfa </PERSON> still wants to put the frescoes behind curtains. The harsh greens, yellows and blues made it difficult for her staff to work normally, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0055EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--France-SovietPoll     03-23 0170</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--France-Soviet Poll,0172</SECOND>
<HEAD>Copy The West, Say 82 Percent Of Soviets In French Poll</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Eight out of 10 Soviet citizens want their government to be modeled more on Western lines, according to an opinion poll conducted for a leftist French magazine. Of 1,000 people interviewed by telephone between Feb. 15 and 20 in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, the 82 percent wanting a Western system were just as strongly represented among <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> members as among non-party members, <ORGANIZATION> Le </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nouvel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observateur </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Wednesday editions. But it said 59 percent of those polled opposed creation of a political party described as `` democratic and bourgeois,'' standing for free enterprise and parliamentary democracy. Also, 65 percent wanted the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> to play a bigger role in the nation's future political development, the survey reported. The poll, conducted by <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sociology </ORGANIZATION>, found 74 percent of those interviewed wanted an ecological party in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, and 20 percent were in favor of a Christian party.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-NorthernIreland     03-23 0140</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Northern Ireland,0142</SECOND>
<HEAD>IRA Says It Seized Confidential Files; Police Deny It</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BELFAST, Northern Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> says it seized confidential files on cross-border security from the car of two senior police officers it killed in an ambush this week. But the <PERSON> Royal </PERSON> <PERSON> Ulster </PERSON> <PERSON> Constabulary </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s police force, said in a statement that the guerrillas escaped only with the officers' personal diaries. Chief Superintendent <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Breen </PERSON> and Superintendent <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchanan </PERSON> were killed in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Armagh </LOCATION> as they returned Monday from a meeting with police officials of the Republic of <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. The outlawed <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> made it claim in a message to <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> news organizations Wednesday night. The mainly <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> wants to drive the British from <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and to unite the Protestant-led province with the 95 percent <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> under <ORGANIZATION> socialist </ORGANIZATION> rule.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Egypt-Israel     03-23 0895</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Egypt-Israel,0929</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Decade of Peace For Wary Neighbors</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 On March 26, 1979, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> signed a historic peace treaty to try to break the cycle of <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> wars. For <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> it has meant better produce in the shops, but also a feeling of mistrust. Here is the second of two reports.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By NEJLA SAMMAKIA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAIRO, Egypt (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> have been on speaking terms for a decade, but it's the relationship of next-door neighbors who keep a wary eye on each other. <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> is whole again on the maps. Under the peace treaty signed March 26, 1979, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> returned most of the Sinai in 1982, 15 years after capturing in the 1967 war. It completed the turnover last week by delivering <LOCATION> Taba </LOCATION>, a tiny beach enclave on the Gulf of <LOCATION> Aqaba </LOCATION>. Oil wells in <LOCATION> Sinai </LOCATION> and the Gulf of <ORGANIZATION> Suez </ORGANIZATION>, developed under Israeli occupation, pump money into <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which under President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> sponsored the first peace between Arab and Jew, provides more than $ 2 billion a year in aid. Even the Arab diplomatic boycott caused by the treaty has ended except for <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. There will be no celebration of the 10th anniversary, however. For the average Egyptian there is little to show for the government's cool friendship with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> except juicier grapes, redder strawberries and fatter cucumbers in the market. Peace `` is so important to the Israelis and Arabs,'' President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> said after the red, black and white Egyptian flag rose over <LOCATION> Taba </LOCATION> for the first time in 22 years. `` It is worth whatever concession.'' He called for mutual flexibility to solve the remaining problem, which has led to four <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> wars: the future of the Palestinians. <PERSON> Butros </PERSON> <PERSON> Ghali </PERSON>, minister of state for foreign affairs, said <LOCATION> Taba </LOCATION> could be the key: `` Solving the <LOCATION> Taba </LOCATION> problem peacefully ... opens the door to joint action ... to solve the Palestinian problem.'' By terms like flexibility and joint action, Egyptian officials mean <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> should change its policy, negotiate with the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> and give back <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> territories occupied since 1967. Egyptians tend to mistrust <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> because of the four wars and many years of regarding it as the eternal enemy. <PERSON> Ghali </PERSON> once characterized the relationship as Cold Peace. Many Israeli tourists visit <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> but few Egyptians go the other way. The government discourages trips to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and some prosperous Egyptians say it is too expensive. Also, Egyptians generally sympathize with the Palestinians, especially since the uprising against <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> occupation began in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> more than 15 months ago. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> often asks <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> to use friendlier language and fully implement treaty provisions designed to improve relations through trade, tourism and cultural exchanges. Experts on both sides say agricultural technology is about the only field in which cooperation flourishes. <PERSON> Hany </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdel-Nour </PERSON>, whose company sells irrigation systems that involve Israeli innovations, said the advantage of working with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> is `` that our climatic conditions are similar.'' Most of his clients are former expatriate workers home from Arab oil states with money to invest. `` They are broad-minded and ready to accept new techniques,'' <PERSON> Abdel-Nour </PERSON> said. `` Some people had reservations at the beginning, but after a while their misgivings vanished.'' Another businessman who uses Israeli technology is a former ranking army officer who fought in the 1967 war, was captured and spent eight months as an prisoner of war. The officer, who requested anonymity, grows grapes with Israeli know-how and equipment. `` This has no relation to war,'' he said. `` My brother was killed in the war, so my hard feelings should be double, but I still take technology from them.'' His family is less pragmatic. The former officer said his wife refuses to socialize with his <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> colleagues. Four years after President <PERSON> Anwar </PERSON> <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON> went to <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, and two after he signed the peace treaty, Moslem extremists assassinated him in 1981. <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON>'s campaign to win over Egyptians included repeated promises of prosperity for a people shackled with spending billions on war. Early in the peace decade, billboards depicted a long-stemmed red rose with a slogan assuring citizens of a happy future. Now the bloom is off the rose. `` I was against the whole peace move,'' said <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON>, a young agriculture graduate. `` I was n't fooled that the treaty would bring prosperity. You can see there is no prosperity; quite the contrary.'' Rising inflation aggravated by mismanagement, corruption and lower prices for oil exports has disappointed many Egyptians and dashed much of <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON>'s dream, although none of it can be blamed on the treaty. <LOCATION> Taba </LOCATION> will be a test for both sides. Egyptian and <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> employees will work together in large numbers for the first time, at a resort hotel <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> bought from its Israeli owner. `` I do n't know how it'll be, working with <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>,'' cook <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> <PERSON> Zerber </PERSON> said on the day the Egyptians took over. `` I do n't know whether I'll accept taking orders from them.'' Egyptian law requires that 90 percent of a company's employees be Egyptian, but when and or how that will be implemented at <LOCATION> Taba </LOCATION> is unclear. About 20 waiters and cooks sent from <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> arrived minutes after the 326-room hotel became Egyptian and filed into the poolside dining room to take instructions from their <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> counterparts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0516EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Oscar-SupportingActor     03-23 0830</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Oscar-Supporting Actor,0842</SECOND>
<HEAD>Supporting Actor: Will A Film Veteran Win Again?</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB THOMAS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If the Academy Award race for supporting actor goes according to form, the winner would be <PERSON> Alec </PERSON> <PERSON> Guinness </PERSON> for `` Little Dorrit.'' Or so the experts say. After all, the reasoning goes, for the past three years the award has gone to veterans who have amassed an impressive body of work: <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Ameche </PERSON>, `` Cocoon,'' 1985; <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Caine </PERSON>, `` <PERSON> Hannah </PERSON> and Her Sisters,'' 1986; <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Connery </PERSON>, `` The Untouchables,'' 1987. The trouble is that Academy Award voters do n't always follow tradition, and some of them may have had trouble sitting through the six hours of `` Little Dorrit.'' The British-made film is based on <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickens </PERSON>' last, often overlooked novel. Guinness, <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> winner as best actor for `` The Bridge on the River Kwai'' in 1957, was cast as <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorrit </PERSON>, longtime resident of debtors' prison. `` The character itself I found fascinating,'' said the 74-year-old actor in a magazine interview, `` because in many ways it's unsympathetic, feckless and foolish. You know, you'd like to kick him. ... And yet, at the same time, there is a sympathy for him because of the social situation at that time, being chucked into prison for 20-odd years for debt.'' But Oscar voters other veterans for whom to vote. First, there's <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Landau </PERSON>, nominated for `` Tucker: The Man and His Dream. For 30 years he has been contributing solid performances in films such as `` North by <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION>, `` Cleopatra'' and `` <PERSON> Nevada </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>,'' though he is best known as the master of disguises in the original TV series `` Mission: Impossible.'' <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Coppola </PERSON> gave <PERSON> Landau </PERSON> the role of his life as <PERSON> Abe </PERSON> <PERSON> Karatz </PERSON>, financial adviser to car builder <PERSON> Preston </PERSON> <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>. Of <PERSON> Coppola </PERSON>, <PERSON> Landau </PERSON>, 54, remarks: `` Like all the good ones, he lets you go. He hires you, that's a vote of confidence. <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> really creates a background for you. The more you bring the happier he is.'' <PERSON> Landau </PERSON> is a director of the Actors Studio in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, and he prepared for the role with customary thoroughness. Once an illustrator for the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, he drew portraits of <PERSON> Abe </PERSON> and analyzed him as `` a lonely <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> businessman who really has no family, no friends and no life outside work.'' Then there's <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Stockwell </PERSON>, nominated as the outrageous Mafia don in `` Married to the Mob.'' He's been in films for 46 of his 52 years. The son of singer <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Stockwell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> was a child actor in such films as `` Anchors Aweigh,'' `` Gentleman's Agreement'' and `` The Boy With the Green Hair.'' His career since then has been a roller coaster: obscurity after his child-star days; success as a young man in `` Compulsion,'' `` Sons and Lovers'' and other films; descent into hippiedom during the 1960s. He tried to return to acting after cleaning up his act, but found jobs scarce. Thinking his career over, he and wife, <PERSON> Joy </PERSON>, moved to <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fe </LOCATION>, N.M. Suddenly, producers were sending for him. <PERSON> Stockwell </PERSON> credits director <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Demme </PERSON> for taking a chance on him in `` Married to the Mob.'' He remarked: `` No one had ever thought of me for this type of role. It's a romantic comedy, and I play a charismatic guy who chases after women and people are afraid of, and it's charming and funny. Prior to that, everyone always thought of me as this serious actor who plays psychotics and neurotics and sensitive people.'' <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Kline </PERSON> won his nomination as the madcap but vicious underworld type in `` A Fish Called <PERSON> Wanda </PERSON>.'' Known for his flamboyant roles in the theater, <PERSON> Kline </PERSON>, 41, has created a series of indelible performances on the screen: as <PERSON> Meryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Streep </PERSON>'s erratic lover in `` Sophie's Choice''; the college reunion host in `` The Big Chill''; the swashbuckling buccaneer in `` The Pirates of Penzance.'' The actor believes that his screen potential has n't been reached: `` I've done tons of roles on the stage that I have n't even approached on the screen. I see my film career as wide open. I'd like to do serious dramas, love stories, action-adventures, comedies No one has pigeonholed me yet, and I hope to keep it that way.'' The youngest nominee is 18-year-old <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>, named for his `` Running on Empty'' role as the son of political activists on the run from the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> has established himself as one of the screen's best young actors in such films as `` Stand by Me,'' `` The Mosquito Coast'' and `` Little Nikita.'' As part of a free-thinking family that was repeatedly on the move, <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> had a similar childhood to the one he portrays in `` Running on Empty.'' He believes that his peripatetic upbringing was good training for acting. `` I think it helps you become versatile in adapting to new situations, new atmospheres, new people, just as you do when you go from film to film,'' he said. `` It also gives you an insight on different forms of life and different perspectives.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Poland-Independence     03-23 0748</FIRST>
<HEAD>Independence Movement Seeks Greater Following In Poland</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH G. SEWARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KRAKOW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 While Solidarity seeks agreement with authorities at round-table talks, the small but noisy Confederation for an Independent <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> has stepped up street protests in a drive for followers to fight communism. Shouts of `` <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION>,'' the group's initials in Polish, can be heard at most demonstrations these days. Its banners painted with a black anchor, the symbol of the Polish resistance during World War II, often appear in the front ranks of marches, even those called by other groups. `` Strikes and demonstrations awaken people's emotions and they become enthusiastic,'' said <PERSON> Zygmunt </PERSON> <PERSON> Lenyk </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION> leader in <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION>. `` It's easier to awaken the enthusiasm of people who strike and demonstrate than among those who sit.'' <PERSON> Lenyk </PERSON>'s tiny <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION> apartment serves as the headquarters for a determined core of young activists dedicated to publicizing the name of the organization, even though it is illegal. <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION> is the largest and most active of a range of smaller opposition groups that reject cooperation with the government and criticize Solidarity on grounds that it is too moderate. The groups, which also include Fighting Solidarity and the banned <ORGANIZATION> Polish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, have become more active in recent months and appear to be trying to coordinate activities through joint meetings of the self-styled `` anti-system opposition.'' During a recent national <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> congress </ORGANIZATION>, a small brigade of young people covered city walls with black anchors until they ran out of paint, while more than 200 of their elders debated the organization's future strategy. `` If we want to be a civilized country, we must liquidate socialism,'' <PERSON> Lenyk </PERSON> said. `` We have to become a parliamentary country, and we want to liquidate communism.'' Socialism and communism often are used interchangeably. <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION>'s straightforward strategy has begun to win new sympathizers, many of whom once belonged to Solidarity. But <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION> is far from becoming a movement on the scale of Solidarity, which as a labor union claimed 10 million members in 1981. <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION> claims an active membership of 1,600 and 1,000 more in youth organizations. <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION> was founded by the historian <PERSON> Leszek </PERSON> <PERSON> Moczulski </PERSON> on Sept. 1, 1979, the 40th anniversary of <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s invasion of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. Supporters say they are attracted by the clarity of <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION>'s call for <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s independence from Communist authorities and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Though the group claims to favor a peaceful path to independence, young members of <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION> often wear military caps and pants and shirts made of camouflage fabric and have thrown stones at police in protests. They say such action is taken only in self-defense. The organization's militarism and staunch anti-communism has resulted in a rift between <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION> and Solidarity leaders who are now seeking change by talking with Polish government officials. `` KPN, Fighting Solidarity and other independence groups are treated by us as rival organizations,'' said <PERSON> Zbigniew </PERSON> <PERSON> Bujak </PERSON>, head of the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> region of Solidarity. But <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION> appeals to those who favor fighting Communists rather than supporting a strategy of negotiating changes with authorities. `` I was always engaged in the fight for a free <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. Solidarity is a trade union, so now I'm going with <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> Henryk </PERSON> <PERSON> Holfeier </PERSON>, a retired economist and former Solidarity member who joined <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION> a year ago. `` I was attracted to a program with very decisive and clear goals,'' said <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Grcor </PERSON>, a psychologist and editor of <LOCATION> Opinia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Krakowska </LOCATION>, a bimonthly underground publication. `` Solidarity's goals are clear, but they are too few and too small.'' Grcor is also a former Solidarity member. `` <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION>'s ultimate goal is full independence for a democratic, free <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>,'' she said. `` Solidarity is a bridge to this goal and our interests are linked together.'' While Solidarity defends the right of independent groups to exist, the union leadership has kept its distance from <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION>, maintaining it intends only to be a trade union. <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION>'s main activity is street protests. `` Street demonstrations break down the barrier of fear and encourage the belief that people can do something,'' said <PERSON> Grcow </PERSON>. `` Our main goal is for the group to become a mass organization that will have an influence on society.'' <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION> has attracted strong support among students, especially in <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION> where university students allied with <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION> founded a new group they call the <ORGANIZATION> Student </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. The historic center of this southern city has been the scene recently of several violent clashes between young people and police, and <ORGANIZATION> KPN </ORGANIZATION> has been represented at almost every demonstration.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-MissAmerica     03-23 0349</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Miss America,0361</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Role Model Halfway Through Her Reign</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOYCE A. VENEZIA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Miss America <PERSON> Gretchen </PERSON> <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> is midway through her reign, but only one event so far has been less than enjoyable for the 22-year-old self-described overachiever from <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. She said Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> pageant officials had set her up as the victim on a `` bloopers and blunders'' television show, an episode that forced her to ad-lib a description of a complicated satellite dish. `` It was the perfect joke for me _ an attempt to make me look stupid,'' she said. `` That's my biggest pet peeve _ making me look stupid.'' Her most memorable occasion so far was meeting President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in the Oval Office. `` He reminded me exactly of my grandfather _ I wanted to hug him,'' she said. As she discussed her reign at its halfway point, the <LOCATION> Anoka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, resident shivered and explained she is recovering from a cold. She was deliberately keeping a quiet schedule Wednesday until a <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> luncheon, where she had to play the violin. Such performances are a part of many functions, giving Miss <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> the opportunity to show off the talent that won her the crown. `` I would n't mind if the pageant got away from the crown,'' she said. `` Yes, it makes you immediately recognizable, but that's not the point. I'd rather have people know me from the inside rather than the outside.'' During the past six months, she has visited schools, conventions, nursing homes, ribbon cuttings, state pageants and endless events on behalf of the pageant sponsors. On a typical evening, she irons her outfit for the next day and writes back to admiring young girls and women who have asked for her photograph. After her reign, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> intends to complete her senior year at <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. She wants to go to law school, and to become `` a very successful corporate executive.'' She added, however, that she does n't consider herself a celebrity. `` I like the term ` role model,''' she said. `` The more approachable I am, the better.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0027EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-ANorwegianEaster Bjt   03-23 0561</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-A Norwegian Easter, Bjt,0576</SECOND>
<HEAD>Banned from Easter Dancing, Norwegians Go Skiing Instead</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUG MELLGREN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OSLO, Norway (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 250-year-old ban on dancing during Easter may finally become a thing of the past. Authorities acknowledge the law sends few Norwegians to church for solemn prayer _ so many are on the slopes. Every Easter holiday, Norwegians abandon their cities and close their shops, jamming up mountain roads and ski trails. Few actually go to church. The dancing ban, made law in 1965, stems from strict 1735 decrees by the Lutheran Evangelical state church that limit public entertainment and sports events on religious holidays, said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Selaeg </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>. But he added: `` The rules get a little confusing and may be relaxed when the government finishes reviewing them next spring.'' Almost everything but church services and skiing is banned on Good Friday and Easter Sunday. Dancing is allowed Saturday until 9 p.m., though municipalities are empowered to override the rules or make them stricter. Similar blue laws and entertainment bans exist on Good Friday and Easter in <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>, where the Lutheran church also is an arm of the state. <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>'s state-run liquor stores are closed until Tuesday, but restaurants can still serve alcohol over parts of the long weekend. At certain times, it's possible to buy a drink at a discotheque, though customers must keep their feet under the tables and off the dance floor. The <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> says 87.8 percent of Norwegians belong to the state church. In a recent newspaper survey, however, 14.3 percent of those asked said they would consider attending an Easter church service. About 75 percent of the 604 Norwegians surveyed said they no longer consider Easter a religious holiday, and would rather go skiing, said the <LOCATION> Oslo </LOCATION> newspaper Aftenposten. Some Norwegians say Easter has become more like a Viking spring festival than a Christian ritual. The Easter holiday has been five days long since the 1700s, but many Norwegians now begin the traditional exodus to the mountains the weekend before, drawing on their vacation time. The <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> says it's a myth that cities are totally abandoned. `` Only 25 percent of the population is on vacation,'' said a bureau official. However, the figure does not include people merely gone for the weekend, he added. With more than 1 million of their 4.2 million residents skiing in the mountains, relaxing in cabins by the fjords or flying off to sunny lands, a strange calm engulfs <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>'s largest cities during the last workdays before the holiday. City traffic jams disappear. Chronic parking shortages become parking space gluts. Skeleton office crews explain that nothing can be done `` because it's Easter.'' Among the few people left working by Wednesday afternoon were <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> personnel, foreign businessmen and thieves. Police say Easter brings a wave of burglaries, as thousands of people leave their homes vacant. The <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>' 8,000 volunteers, with blood hounds, helicopters and other equipment, staff 280 mountain posts to help skiers who get lost, exhausted or swept up in avalanches. For those left in the cities, the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> published a list of cafes and places of holiday entertainment. `` A city emptied by Easter can intensify the loneliness and isolation felt by those left in the lowlands,'' said a <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> statement.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HouseRepublicans Bjt   03-23 0834</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-House Republicans, Bjt,830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gingrich Off the Back Bench and onto the Firing Line</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House Republicans gave new status to their most ardent Democrat-basher by electing <PERSON> Newt </PERSON> <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> as their No. 2 leader, but they also put him on the firing line with the Democrats loaded up. `` I think it is manna from heaven,'' said <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Majority Whip <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, D-Calif., who said Democrats would remind voters of the many controversial stands _ such as support for <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> cuts _ that the right-wing <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> lawmaker has taken over the years `` We're no longer talking about someone who is just another member of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> emerged from a closed meeting of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Republicans on Wednesday with an 87-85 victory over <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Madigan </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> in the race to become <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> minority whip, the post made vacant when <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> became secretary of defense. His was a victory for those Republicans who, after 34 years of minority status in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, want more confrontation with the Democrats. The <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> now holds just 174 of the 435 House seats. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> filed the complaint last year that launched an ethics committee investigation into <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>. And that was only the most notable salvo in a career of using television and the House rules to agitate against the majority party. After the vote, <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> insisted he also could work with the <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> as one would expect in his new leadership role, if they give him a chance. He walked across the aisle in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> chamber that divides the two parties and shook Democratic hands. `` I will be fair with anyone who will be fair with me,'' he told reporters. `` But I'll be ruthless on corruption,'' he said, insisting that he wo n't give up his fight against <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. Democrats said they hoped <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> was sincere about focusing on the vote-counting and other legislative tasks of the whip and would leave behind his longstanding tactics of disruption. But they were skeptical and wasted no time serving notice that <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> will feel the political heat. `` One of the prices on leadership is a certain moderation. Sometimes learning that is a costly lesson,'' said Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, D-Mich., the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, D-Ark., took to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor to confront <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> had `` made his name'' with a `` personal attack on the good name of <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> said, because of allegations surrounding the speaker's book publishing royalties. Now questions are being raised this week about <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>'s financial arrangements surrounding a 1984 publishing deal of his own `` I think he should answer for all of the members of this House and for all of the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people who have observed this action,'' <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> himself made the same point, but with subtly, in the unusual way in which he congratulated <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>. The speaker sent <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> a copy of his book, `` Reflections of a Public Man,'' and inscribed it: `` For <PERSON> Newt </PERSON>, who likes books too. Congratulations! And if you think a two-vote victory is thin, try it sometime with one, as I had to settle for in'76. To be chosen by your peers is a great honor,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said, referring to his first leadership race. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> signed and dated the inscription, and decorated it with a sketch of himself, bushy eyebrows and all, wielding a gavel overhead. While <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> telephoned <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> in a spirit of conciliation after the vote, he did n't call <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> did n't call him. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> also made clear that his spirit of conciliation was limited and not in the mold of <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON>, the Republican leader. `` All too often in the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and in the news media, bipartisanship means ... Republicans have to be passive and surrender while Democrats and liberals get what they want. That's nonsense,'' he said With that kind of aggressive stance, <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> could well be a unifying factor for the Democrats. Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Durbin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ill </LOCATION>., said if Republicans were looking for legislative accomplishments, they would have picked <PERSON> Madigan </PERSON>, the deputy whip and widely respected master of the legislative process `` They really missed the bet,'' he said. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> was `` fully predictable'' in his tactics, he said. `` Maybe he's trying to wear the robe of a statesman, but I do n't think that's going to work,'' he said Many Democrats said they did n't expect <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> to be much of a problem either way. `` Is a newt like a chameleon? Can they change and adapt to the environment?'' asked Rep. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N </LOCATION>. Either way, he said, `` We lived with the old <PERSON> Newt </PERSON>. We'll live with the new Newt.'' Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Mo </LOCATION>., said he hoped for a new Newt, and in either case the answer would be known quickly `` I think you'll see very clearly which way it's going to go,'' he said. `` I do n't think it's going to be a secret.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0511EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MarijuanaBabies     03-23 0578</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Marijuana Babies,0593</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pot Use During Pregnancy Linked With Stunted Babies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL Q. HANEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pregnant women should be warned that smoking marijuana may stunt the growth of their unborn babies, and even a single joint results in prolonged fetal exposure to the drug, researchers reported today. `` This study documents that marijuana during pregnancy is associated with poor fetal growth,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Zuckerman </PERSON>, who directed the study. The research, based on 1,226 patients at a pregnancy clinic at <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, found that women who smoked pot produced babies who averaged three ounces lighter and two-tenths of an inch shorter than non-users' newborns. <PERSON> Zuckerman </PERSON> said the study underscores the belief that the effects of bad habits during pregnancy add up. While one may have a small impact on the baby, several together can significantly harm the child's growth. For instance, his study suggests that a woman who gains only 10 pounds during pregnancy, smokes a pack of cigarettes a day and uses marijuana and cocaine will produce a baby who is 15 ounces smaller than normal. `` It definitely supports the case that marijuana has an effect on the fetus,'' said <PERSON> Coryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, a research psychologist at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abuse </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>, Md. The study also confirmed earlier reports showing that cocaine users also produce unusually small babies. <PERSON> Zuckerman </PERSON>'s study differs from earlier research, which has not shown a clear association between pot and fetal growth. Those studies were based solely on mother's admissions of drug use. His work, conducted with researchers from <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> and published in the New England Journal of Medicine, used urine tests to document whether pregnant women were taking drugs. The babies of drug-using women `` experience a double jeopardy,'' said <PERSON> Zuckerman </PERSON>. `` They experience biological vulnerability during pregnancy from these drugs,'' and after birth `` they are more likely to experience abuse and neglect because of their parents' use of drugs. They catch it both ways.'' The researchers speculated that the active chemical in marijuana may somehow slow fetal growth. Since the drug can remain in the bloodstream for a month, the study said, `` a single episode of marijuana use will lead to prolonged exposure of the fetus to the drug.'' Marijuana also raises carbon monoxide levels and cuts the amount of oxygen that reaches the fetus. Although cigarette smoking does the same thing, the damage from marijuana may be greater because pot users take bigger puffs and hold in the smoke longer. Twenty-seven percent of the women said in interviews or showed on urine tests that they had used marijuana, while 18 percent had used cocaine. When only urine test results were considered, 16 percent showed signs of marijuana and 9 percent of cocaine. The researchers said those who had drugs in their urine may have been the heaviest users. The researchers compared the babies of mothers with positive urine tests to those of women who had negative tests and also denied drug use. Those who used cocaine produced babies who were slightly smaller than the marijuana mothers', and their babies also had unusually small heads. The women studied were largely poor blacks and Hispanics. However, <PERSON> Zuckerman </PERSON> said their drug use may not have been much different from that of young pregnant women elsewhere. A nationwide study in 1985 found that 31 percent of women in their late teens and early 20s said they had used marijuana during the previous year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AirToxics Bjt   03-23 0732</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Air Toxics, Bjt,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Survey Finds 2.4 Billion Tons of Toxic Air Pollutants a Year</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal officials and environmental groups are calling for stronger laws to control toxic air pollutants in light of a government report showing that at least 2.4 billion pounds of deadly chemicals are released into the air each year. `` The magnitude of this problem far exceeds our worst fears,'' declared Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, D-Calif., after he made a report public Wednesday that provided the first nationwide glimpse into the volume of toxic pollutants released by chemical plants and other industrial sources The report covered 328 chemicals or chemical groups including 60 agents the government has identified as causing cancer. Among the chemicals are phosgene, used as a nerve gas in World War I, and methyl isocyanate, which killed more than 2,000 people in <LOCATION> Bhopal </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, in 1984. Spokesmen for the chemical industry, which accounted for about a third of the total volume of toxic pollutants cited in the report, said it is misleading to link the raw figures to health risk because they do not take into account actual exposure or concentration. They said the emissions are legal and take place within the restrictions of various state and federal permits. `` Anyone who says that there is a national health crisis based on these numbers is wrong. To use those numbers is misleading,'' insisted <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON>, chief spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on health and environment, acknowledged that the raw figures do not provide a clear picture of the health impact because `` we do n't really know how much of which pollutants individuals are actually breathing.'' Many of the chemicals on the list, however, have been linked to cancer, birth defects, reproductive dysfunctions, neurological disorders and genetic mutations, the congressman said. The report was compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> based on information from industry. While the figures, which reflected emissions from manufacturing facilities in 1987, were called staggering by some congressmen, environmentalists and government officials suggested they represent only a fraction _ perhaps no more than one-third _ of the toxic substances that actually leak into the air. The emission totals are based on reports only from large chemical manufacturers and others with emissions of at least 75,000 pounds a year. It does not include smaller polluters such as service stations, dry cleaners and petroleum tank farms. But <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> and other congressmen said they hoped the preliminary government figures _ even though they may not present the entire picture _ will provide fuel for enactment of strong air quality legislation that includes provisions for regulating toxic air pollutants. How to deal with toxic emissions will be a focus of debate when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> rewrites the Clean Air Act later this year. Environmentalists also called for stronger legislation to deal with toxic emissions and <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Clay </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s top air quality official, told reporters `` some other approach is needed'' to deal with toxic air pollution. <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> has been hamstrung because the law requires the agency to act on each chemical separately, a time consuming and expensive process when each action may face legal challenge. `` The idea of going down 320 -LRB- separate -RRB- rules.. is just too cumbersome,'' he said <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> said the report showed higher emissions than he had expected. `` It's a big number. I think it's a health problem that needs to be addressed,'' he said. Only seven of the substances included in the report are now regulated by the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>, although a separate agency, the <ORGANIZATION> Occupational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, has set standards within the workplace for more than 400 toxics including many on the list. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> called on <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to enact legislation that would direct the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> to establish health-based standards for all of the listed toxic pollutants, conduct emission audits and require polluters to put into place the best available emission control technology within five years. Of the 2.4 billion pounds of toxic emissions, the chemical industry accounted for 886.5 million pounds, followed by the primary metals, paper, transportation, rubber-plastics and fabricated metals industries each of which accounted for more than 100,000 pounds. <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> led the nation with 229.9 million pounds of toxic emissions, followed by <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> all with more than 100 million pounds during 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0217EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     03-23 0912</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0948</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT WORTH, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Healey </PERSON>, the 22-year-old blind guitarist who has rocked the charts with `` Confidence Man,'' says he did n't have to cram much for a featured role in the <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Swayze </PERSON> movie, `` Roadhouse.'' `` The movie's about a bar band playing cover tunes in a cruddy dive,'' said <PERSON> Healey </PERSON>. `` I've certainly done that enough in my life, and I'm happy all that practice came in handy.'' The Canadian-born <PERSON> Healey </PERSON> said he hopes the soon-to-be-released movie will provide his band with exposure. He said his blindness has caused him few problems as a musician. `` I did drop off of a stage once into a bunch of people,'' he recalled. `` But I was able to get right back up. I joked about it, and everything was fine.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Grateful Dead's <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> is among the performers lined up for 10 benefit concerts to help fight AIDS. `` We're frustrated and we want to do something,'' <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> told reporters Tuesday at the Fillmore Auditorium. `` We are not making any sacrifice here. We're doing what we always do, which is playing music for people. ... We want to raise money to do something about this.'' Other performers getting set for the concerts May 21-28 include Grammy winner <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lobos </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Tower </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> and guitarist <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Satriani </PERSON>. Organizers hope to raise $ 3 million to fight the deadly disease. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallagher </PERSON>, senior vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION>, said members of the baseball team also will participate.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Country singer <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> has become the first national goodwill ambassador for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> for <ORGANIZATION> UNICEF </ORGANIZATION>. `` As a musician, <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> joins the compassionate tradition started by <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaye </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> UNICEF </ORGANIZATION>'s first international ambassador,'' <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> president, said in announcing the appointment Wednesday. <PERSON> Kaye </PERSON> was the first in a line of celebrities to become goodwill ambassadors for <ORGANIZATION> UNICEF </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> is the first such ambassador for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. The committee is the oldest and largest of 34 national committees that promote <ORGANIZATION> UNICEF </ORGANIZATION> worldwide. <ORGANIZATION> UNICEF </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION>, is a semi-autonomous agency within the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> with its own budget and executive board It promotes the welfare of children worldwide through immunizations, nutrition programs, education and other projects. `` You can achieve success and win awards,'' said <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, in accepting the appointment, `` but this is a way to share all that with you people. As young people go, so goes our world.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and ghostwriter <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Scovell </PERSON> have been working on a memoir of Mrs. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' experiences on the presidential campaign trail. <PERSON> Scovell </PERSON>, who helped <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> write her book, `` <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Takes </PERSON> <PERSON> Off </PERSON>,'' was chosen as a collaborator by Mrs. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, wife of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. She did not make clear whether <PERSON> Scovell </PERSON>'s name will appear on the book cover. <PERSON> Scovell </PERSON> already has begun working on the book, <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaplan </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the governor, said Wednesday. Mrs. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> announced her choice of <PERSON> Scovell </PERSON> at a news conference March 9 when she returned from monthlong treatment for alcoholism. <PERSON> Scovell </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> began working on the book last week at a private home on <PERSON> Martha </PERSON>'s Vineyard.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Schoolchildren joined dozens of best-selling authors and publishing executives to start a nationwide literacy program sponsored by the nation's largest bookseller. `` Team Read,'' a program organized by Waldenbooks, will ask children to read, write their own stories and raise money for teaching other youths to read. The bookseller will conduct, among other events, a `` read-a-thon,'' with sponsors agreeing to pay a child for each book completed, and a writing contest, with $ 1,000 savings bonds awarded to the authors of the best stories and poems. Among the authors at Wednesday's kickoff of the program were animal rights activist <PERSON> Cleveland </PERSON> <PERSON> Amory </PERSON>, children's book writers <PERSON> Stan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Berenstain </PERSON>, mystery writer <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, former basketball star <PERSON> Walt </PERSON> <PERSON> Frazier </PERSON>, Muppeteer <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON>, historian <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McPherson </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> -LRB- Captain Kangaroo -RRB- <PERSON> Keeshan </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PALM SPRINGS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mayor <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> <PERSON> Bono </PERSON>'s former critics are speaking well of him after his first year in office. `` I give him an ` A' for effort,'' said former Mayor <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Bogert </PERSON>. `` I criticized him to beat the band before he got in because he did n't have any experience, but he's learned real fast and has a lot of good ideas.'' `` My earlier views changed because he is working so hard,'' said <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Mihata </PERSON>, businesswoman and founder of a self-appointed watchdog group that has clashed with <PERSON> Bono </PERSON>. The 54-year-old actor and singer conceded: `` The test was n't winning the election The true test was getting the various groups to trust me ... but there is more confidence now because no one is questioning my motives anymore.'' <PERSON> Bono </PERSON>, criticized by those who called his mayoral bid an attempt to resuscitate a lagging show business career, cashed in on his celebrity status to promote tourism and secure corporate sponsors for events in the financially strapped oasis. It was the same kind of energy he used to help vault the pop duo <ORGANIZATION> Sonny </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Cher </PERSON> to stardom in the 1960s. Eager to erase a $ 2.5 million budget deficit and transform <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> from a golf-happy retirement community into a chic international travel destination, <PERSON> Bono </PERSON>, who has kept a home in <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> for 17 years, works at least 60 hours a week at a job that pays $ 15,000 a year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0223EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     03-23 0786</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Saudi Arabia Growing Export Market for US Products</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If you're a <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> barley farmer, a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> sheep producer or a <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> tobacco grower, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has some reasons for keeping an eye on <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>. Scores of other agricultural and food processing operations also are involved in the growing Saudi Arabian market, says <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural trade officer in <LOCATION> Jeddah </LOCATION>. Over the last five years, <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> food imports averaged nearly $ 5 billion annually, up from $ 1.5 billion in 1977. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> says the growth has been fueled by `` the presence of thousands of European and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> expatriates and elaborate consumer food subsidies'' financed by <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>'s oil wealth. `` An influx of immigrant workers in the mid-1970s dramatically changed Saudi consumer spending patterns,'' <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> writes in the April issue of AgExporter magazine. In 1987, <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>, which has a population of about 11 million, imported about 70 percent of its food. Tops in value were: barley, live sheep, tobacco, milk, poultry, meat, rice, spices, canned vegetables, fruit juices, fresh vegetables, sugar and corn. More than 10 percent of the agricultural imports are from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, making <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> the top cash customer in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm products. Consumer subsidies are used to distribute national income, derived almost entirely from petroleum, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said. In 1987, oil accounted for 92 percent of <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>'s total exports of $ 25 billion. Total imports were put at $ 19 billion, including $ 4.5 billion worth of agricultural products. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> share was about $ 486 million. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said the foreign influence has been felt deeply and has helped change <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> food-buying customs and diets. `` The <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> population rarely eats out,'' he said. `` The usual practice is to have parties at home. Even so, with a population of 4 million foreigners, the number and variety of restaurants have increased over the past few years.'' Besides many European, Lebanese, Chinese and other ethnic cuisines, fast-food places serving hamburgers, fruit juice, chicken, pizza and sandwiches are becoming more widespread. Competition for the thriving Saudi food business is also growing, with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> interests vying with European, Asian and South American suppliers. `` The European Economic Community, in particular, places a high priority on expanding sales of farm products to <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said. `` It has used aggressive market development activities and a regular flow of trade delegations to widen its lead over the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in this market.'' <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>, the world's leading barley importer, has been the target of fierce competition among the <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. In 1987, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> captured a third of the <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> barley market with the help of subsidized sales under the department's Export Enhancement Program.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says private exporters have sold <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> an additional 400,000 metric tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat at subsidized prices. <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sims </PERSON>, general sales manager for the department's <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said Wednesday the wheat was part of 2 million tons authorized Feb. 27 for <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> under the Export Enhancement Program, or EEP Under EEP arrangements, private exporters can sell <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commodities at reduced prices in order to meet foreign competition in selected overseas markets and then collect free government surpluses of grain or other commodities as bonuses, or subsidies. The latest sale boosted the amount of wheat sold to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> for 1988-89 delivery under <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION> to about 8.2 million tons. <PERSON> Sims </PERSON> said the latest sales were handled by <ORGANIZATION> Cargill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, 195,000 tons; <ORGANIZATION> Louis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dreyfus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, 50,000; <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, 30,000; <ORGANIZATION> Ferruzzi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, 85,000; and <ORGANIZATION> Richco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, 40,000. The wheat was sold for shipment in May and will carry an average subsidy rate of $ 19.94 per ton, or about 54 cents a bushel, he said. Slightly more than 1.2 million tons are still available under the current authorization. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 36.7 bushels of wheat. The 400,000 tons would be about 14.7 million bushels and, at recent prices of about $ 4.16 per bushel, would have a farm value of around $ 61 million.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Processors of five major vegetables expect to contract for 1.48 million acres this year, a 10 percent increase from drought-plagued 1988, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Acreage intentions for all five vegetables are up, led by an 18 percent increase for tomatoes. Green peas should be up 12 percent; cucumbers for pickles, 11 percent; snap beans, 7 percent; and sweet corn, 5 percent. The department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday that canning contracts cover 1.06 million acres, up 9 percent from last year, and freezer contracts about 419,000 acres, up 13 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;Ls     03-23 0694</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;Ls,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Banks Complain About Proposed Fines</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A trade association representing banks is accusing the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration of overkill in proposing civil fines up to $ 1 million a day for institutions that recklessly violate regulatory rules. <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Yingling </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bankers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said the fines would be `` wholly disproportionate'' and would inhibit the ability of banks and savings institutions to attract quality managers and directors. `` We must guard against an overreaction that may harm innocent parties and fundamental rights,'' <PERSON> Yingling </PERSON> said in testimony prepared for delivery today to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on criminal justice. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is proposing a top fine of $ 25,000 a day for most violations but up to $ 1 million if the violation was made with reckless disregard for the safety of the institution. <PERSON> Yingling </PERSON> said the maximum penalty should be set at $ 2,500. He was appearing before the panel one day after the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' investigative agency, told the subcommittee that it had examined 26 insolvent savings and loans in eight states and found evidence of fraud or abusive insider dealing in each. Meanwhile, at a hearing Wednesday of a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Banking subcommittee, <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON>, acting associate attorney general, urged <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to maintain stiff penalties as a deterrent to financial fraud. `` Because most bankers are honorable people, one might think that modest sanctions are all that is required to enforce compliance with our laws: A slap on the wrist is all that a gentleman requires,'' <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON> said. `` The flaw in this rationale is that it is not the honorable bankers who have caused the massive problems we face today.'' <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> officials said the pattern of fraud and abuse among failed thrifts `` clearly is pervasive.'' `` The bulk of the losses are directly attributable to the failure by management of a minority of the industry to follow basic, prudent business practices,'' Assistant GAO Comptroller General <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON> said. He did not name the 26 <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls it examined. The Justice subcommittee's chairman, Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, complained that of the 11,000 S & amp; L cases the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> has referred to the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> in the last two years for criminal prosecution, fewer than 200 have resulted in convictions. <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON> told the Banking subcommittee that financial institution cases have overloaded the criminal justice system. A survey of <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> field offices showed more than 8,000 pending cases, half of them involving losses of $ 100,000 or more. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is proposing spending $ 50 million a year on discovering and prosecuting fraud at banks and S & amp; Ls. The money would pay for 760 investigators, auditors, attorneys and support staff, <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON> said. Rep. <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnard </PERSON>, D-Ga., chairman of the examination task force of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> committee </ORGANIZATION>, warned of `` increasing shortages of experienced examiners. He noted that the creation of a multi-agency <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L task force with more than 1,200 examiners has left the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deposit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which regulates commercial banks, several hundred examiners under strength. Comptroller of the Currency <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clarke </PERSON>, whose agency regulates nationally-chartered banks, told <PERSON> Barnard </PERSON> that he is having trouble hiring and retaining experienced examiners. Nearly 30 percent of the examination force consists of examiners with, on average, less than 3 years experience, he said, in a plea for authority to offer higher salaries. In another development, <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> said his agency is working closely with the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to develop a plan to handle the billions of dollars in real estate the government will inherit from failed S & amp; Ls. But <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON>, who would be a member of the oversight board of the government entity set up to dispose of the real estate, declined to provide details of the plan to a House Banking subcommittee. Some members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are worried that government `` dumping'' of <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L property at `` fire sale'' prices will ruin regional real estate markets, particularly in the <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION>. Treasury and White House officials are considering a proposal developed by <PERSON> R.T. </PERSON> <PERSON> McNamar </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> investment banker and a former deputy <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> secretary, that would spend state and federal money to hold onto foreclosed real estate for as long as 10 or 15 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0218EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Kemp-EnterpriseZones     03-23 0465</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Kemp-Enterprise Zones,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Housing Secretary Says Tax Incentives Needed to Make Zones Work</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENISE CABRERA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Housing secretary <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> says congressional inaction to create tax incentives is holding up designation of federal enterprise zones. `` President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is in favor of it. It's in the budget. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> is in favor of it. It's now up to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to move,'' he said Wednesday after his appearance before the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Banking, <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> and Urban Affairs subcommitte on economic stabilization. `` In this case we're not looking for an appropriation, we're looking for a tax change ... I do n't want to make any announcements of zones ... until there's actually a tax change,'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said. `` Let's not pass a bill that simply authorizes a zone but does n't do anything to put a dramatic change in that entrepreneurial climate.'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said reduction or abolishment of capital gains taxes, same-year tax deduction on up to $ 100,000 worth of investment and credits on employee income taxes for individuals and businesses located in the zones were needed. Neither the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> nor <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> tax committees has held or scheduled hearings to consider the proposed changes. The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> received 270 applications for the designation before the January 17 deadline. Thirty-seven states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> have enacted local enterprise zone programs. The Housing and Community Development Act of 1987, as amended by the McKinney Homeless Assistance Act of 1988, authorizes the <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> secretary to designate up to 100 federal enterprise zones, one-third of which must be located in rural areas. The zones are expected to encourage economic development and employment in previously depressed areas through tax incentives and reductions, improvements in public services, reductions in government bureaucracy and involvement of public and private agencies to provide jobs and job training. But a December 1988 study by the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, the investigative arm of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, found the program in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> `` did not stimulate local economic growth as measured by employment or strongly influence most employers' decisions about business location.'' <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said the <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> program was similar to many of the federal programs that had been proposed since 1980 when then-Republican congressman <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> and Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, first initiated legislation. `` I just do n't want to go through another eight years of getting these <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> studies of some zone some place that shows that nobody started a business because there were no incentives,'' said <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>. Whether successful or not, the program `` wo n't cost anything,'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said. But <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> estimated more than $ 1 billion in lost tax revenues during the first three years of a program that involved 75 zones and $ 4.75 billion during the first six years of operation. The Bush 1990 budget estimates $ 1.05 billion in lost revenues over a four-year period.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0218EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ComputerVirus     03-23 0453</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Computer Virus,0465</SECOND>
<HEAD>Viruses Infect Hospital Computers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL Q. HANEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When a hospital computer catches a virus, the results can be hazardous to patients' health, a doctor says. In a letter in today's <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>, a radiologist described what happened when computers used for analyzing patients' nuclear scans were infected with two computer viruses. Computer viruses are devious pieces of computer code that move from machine to machine, often reproduce themselves and sometimes make computers sick. Although this time the infection was cured without lasting harm, Dr. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Juni </PERSON> said potential damage was serious. `` The information on these machines was the actual scans we were using to make diagnoses,'' he said in an interview. `` If the data had been lost, it would have affected the diagnoses of patients.'' One of the viruses was relatively benign, making copies of itself while leaving other information in the computer alone. However, the other virus inserted itself into programs and directories of patient information and made the machines malfunction. <PERSON> Juni </PERSON>, of <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Beaumont </PERSON> <PERSON> Hospitals </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Royal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oak </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, said about three-quarters of the programs stored in two Macintosh II personal computers were infected. He said he did not know the origin of the less harmful virus, but the more serious one apparently was on the hard disk of one of the computers when the hospital had bought it. A hard disk is the internal device used by computers to store programs and data. The virus spread from one computer to another when a doctor used a word processing program on both machines while writing a medical paper. <PERSON> Juni </PERSON> said the virus caused occasional random malfunctions. Sometimes the computers would freeze up or garble patients' names. The hospital had backup copies of patient records, and eventually purged the viruses from the computers. It has since instituted precautions in an effort to keep out viruses. <PERSON> Juni </PERSON> said the virus was on a hard disk manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> CMS </ORGANIZATION> Enhancements of <LOCATION> Tustin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> CMS </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> said a virus was inadvertently put on 600 hard disks last October The virus had contaminated a program used to prepare the hard disks for use. It apparently got into the company's plant on a hard disk that had been returned for servicing. <PERSON> James </PERSON> said that of the 600 virus-tainted disks, 200 were shipped t dealers, and four were sold to customers. However, he said, the virus was `` as harmless as it's possible to be.'' It inserted a small piece of extra computer code on hard disks but did not reproduce or tamper with other material on the disk. He said he did not think <PERSON> Juni </PERSON>'s problems were caused by that virus.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0233EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-LastSupper     03-23 0573</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Last Supper,0590</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Theories On Christ's Last Supper</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN ALT POWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 To Renaissance artist <PERSON> Leonardo </PERSON> <PERSON> da </PERSON> <PERSON> Vinci </PERSON> _ and to many Christians since then _ <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>'s Last Supper was a formal, seated gathering at a rectangular table. But scholars at a Bible research center say diners in Christ's era more likely reclined on floor cushions for festive meals, as the <ORGANIZATION> Romans </ORGANIZATION> did in that day They also speculate that <PERSON> Judas </PERSON>, contrary to popular belief, may have had a place of honor at the last gathering of Christ and his apostles. `` Religious art normally pictures the period of the artist, not the period of the Bible,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON> of the Biblical Resources Study Center. `` With apologies to <PERSON> da </PERSON> <PERSON> Vinci </PERSON>, things probably looked different.'' During the Last Supper, commemorated Thursday by most of the world's Christians, <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> broke bread and blessed wine with his closest disciples hours before he was turned over by <PERSON> Judas </PERSON> to Roman soldiers and crucified. Relying on Bible verses, ancient Jewish writings and Roman historical works, <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON> and his associates have concluded that the Last Supper probably was served at a low, U-shaped table that the <ORGANIZATION> Romans </ORGANIZATION> called a `` triclinium.'' `` Straw mattresses generally were placed around the outside, and guests ate _ and sometimes slept _ at the same place,'' <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON> said. The 45-year-old U.S.-educated Bible scholar who has done research in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> for 15 years noted the early Greek versions of the New Testament describe Last Supper participants as reclining. He said the Greek words `` anekaito'' and `` anepesen,'' used in <LOCATION> Matthew </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> and <PERSON> Luke </PERSON>, were often translated as `` sat'' but actually mean `` reclined.'' <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON> agrees with other scholars that <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>'s Last Supper may have been a Passover dinner, held by <PERSON> Jews </PERSON> then as now to commemorate the exodus from <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>. Rabbis of the day urged followers to recline at this meal, in the style of the Romans who ruled the Holy Land in that era, <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON> said. Today, Christian pilgrims visit the Cenacle, a building on <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zion </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> where tradition has it the Last Supper was held. <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON>'s group has built a Pilgrims' Center on the southern edge of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> where visitors can share a Passover feast while reclining around a stone triclinium. The menu, which is as close as the center can get to a Passover meal in Christ's day, typically includes roast lamb, unleavened bread, wine, baked eggs, nuts, and fruits such as grapes and figs. In artistic renderings of the Last Supper, `` Judas generally is seated at one end of the dining table, the guy without the halo,'' said <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON>. But the Biblical Study Center can cite verses from the gospels of <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON>, <PERSON> Luke </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> that indicate <PERSON> Judas </PERSON> was very close to <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>, probably to his immediate left. The most convincing is in the gospel of <PERSON> Mark </PERSON>, which alludes to the practice of sharing food from a common bowl. When the apostle <PERSON> John </PERSON>, at <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>'s right, asked who would betray him, <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> answered: `` It is one of the 12, one who is dipping bread into the dish with me.'' Christ likely would have shared the bowl with only one or two people, <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON> said. `` In the end, what we're really trying to do is give people a better understanding of the Bible, of the world of Christ,'' he said. `` These are just clues that may help.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0234EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Fashion     03-23 0535</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fashion,0550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Saint Laurent Closes Shows With Statement Of Elegance</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUZY PATTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Fashion Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Yves </PERSON> <PERSON> Saint </PERSON> <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON> closed the winter ready-to-wear collections with a pithy statement of elegance. His show Wednesday was short and to the point, with beautiful no-nonsense daytime wear and a burst of colorful folklore for evening. This classic couturier no longer has to invent anything, as he has done it all. But his unmistakably Saint <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON> silhouette and color palette made good sense for women who want to look chic and sexy. Tailoring was easy, emphasizing softness, though the inimitable Saint <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON> sleeves under padded shoulders still gave shape to the outfits. At the end of the show Saint <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON> looked pale and hunched-over, his smile somewhat pained as he walked out and took a bow, kissing a model who wore a smooth and plain black jersey gown. Spokesmen for the designer say he is suffering only from fatigue. The short, knee-revealing or longer skirts were both split, modified versions of Saint <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON>'s theme last season. He wisely carries over ideas from his more expensive couture looks, translating them into clothes many more women can afford in ready-to-wear. The fluid charcoal or oxford gray capes over knickers or wrap skirts, worn with nailhead-studded belts, kicked off the show and set the relaxed tone. Lots of pants and wrapped skirt suits were in caviar tweeds, gray or flecked mustard yellow, with short, fitted jackets. No matter in what color of tweed, flannel or jersey, Saint <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON>'s pants were invariably fullish with pleats at the hips, and tailored to ankle length. Not all of the wrapped or split skirts looked comfortable, but they did n't look brazen, either. Saint <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON>'s ace in the hole was a sleek exercise in false modesty: a semi-fitted, black, midlength jersey dress piped in satin, with a line of big buttons marching down the front and up the sleeves. Black, black and more black came out in many tuxedo looks, first created by Saint <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON> in 1966. The elegant simplicity of all this was highlighted by an occasional jewel, like a rhinestone star at hip level where the skirt split. But when Saint <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON> got into color he did it in a big way, using shades of violet, prune and teal in one tuxedo outfit with soft jersey pants. While some fairly loud folklore prints have been seen in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> this week, Saint <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON> did n't pull his punches, and offered some of the most showy models in folklore-knit sweater suits with dazzling color combinations of yellow, gold and pink or green and turquoise. Although color combinations in cocktail dresses and pajama suits were shimmering with colors like flame red, shocking pink and fuchsia, the whole effect was as light as the softest caress. The handsome Turkish zouave idea for party time featured short velvet-calfskin jackets trimmed with arabesques of gold braid with satin blouses and easy gathered satin pants, sashed with a nailhead-studded belt _ all topped by a fez-type hat with nailheads. The beauty of all this was that any item could be worn separately with other clothes, especially if they are signed <ORGANIZATION> Yves </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Saint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laurent </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-AlexandriaShootout     03-23 0209</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Alexandria Shootout,210</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING a0836 to correct category code</HEAD>
<HEAD>Two Killed in Shoot-out</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALEXANDRIA, VA. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A policeman and an unidentified gunman who had taken five persons hostage were killed Wednesday in a gun battle that reportedly began with the gunman trying to obtain cocaine. A second <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION> policeman was shot and seriously wounded and was undergoing surgery in nearby <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, police said. The incident began when the man entered a home in the city's north end Wednesday afternoon and held five persons hostage, according to police spokesman <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Hilleary </PERSON> Police did not say what prompted the incident, but <ORGANIZATION> WUSA-TV </ORGANIZATION> reported the man entered the home, demanded crack cocaine, and threatened to kill the people there unless they supplied it. One neighbor, who declined to be identified, said the address was known in the neighborhood as a crack house. Police began negotiating with the gunman and the hostages were released one at a time, <PERSON> Hilleary </PERSON> said. The gunman eventually emerged from the backdoor, holding a shotgun to the head of a hostage and demanding that police drop their weapons. One officer fired at the gunman, who fired back, shooting two policeman. In the ensuing fight, the hostage escaped unharmed and the gunman was killed, <PERSON> Hilleary </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890323-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-23-89 0244EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NBCPreview     03-23 0499</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-NBC Preview,0519</SECOND>
<HEAD>NBC Promises Improved Program Quality Next Season</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY BUCK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BURBANK, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
