<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 2328EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Spending-Taxes 7thLd-Writethru a0793 10-13 1017</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Spending-Taxes, 7th Ld-Writethru, a0793,940</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Approves $14.1-Billion Deficit Reduction Bill</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS grafs 11-12 bgng: ``Voting against,'' with negative
votes and those not voting in lieu of roll call. Stands for AMs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Senators approved a $ 14.1-billion deficit-reduction package Friday night after junking extraneous tax breaks and spending increases and postponing a showdown on President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposed cut in capital-gains taxes. The 87-7 vote sent the plan to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, which earlier passed a version that includes a capital-gains reduction. Negotiators from the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> are expected to try to work out a compromise starting next week. The legislation is designed to push the estimated deficit for the 1990 fiscal year, which began Oct. 1, slightly below $ 110 billion and avoid automatic, almost across-the-board cuts in most federal spending programs on Monday. With the House not in session until Monday, it appeared all but certain that the cuts would be triggered temporarily. But the reductions can be restored later. The way for final <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> action on the bill was cleared when senators approved by voice vote an agreement to strip from the bill hundreds of provisions prized by one member or another but which did nothing to cut the deficit. Stripping the bill of pet projects `` asks sacrifice ... -LRB- and -RRB- discipline of every senator,'' Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, said in urging approval of the agreement. `` The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people recognize responsibility when they see it,'' said Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, `` and tonight they are seeing responsibility in action.'' Among provisions dropped from the bill: Extension of the 3 percent tax on local and long-distance telephone service, due to expire at the end of 1990; new tax credits for low-income families; extension of tax benefits for first-time homebuyers and workers who receive education and legal aid from their employers; dozens of narrowly targeted tax cuts; improvements in Medicare, Medicaid and child-welfare programs, and overhaul of the formula for government reimbursement of doctors. `` We think this is absolutely the best approach,'' Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, senior Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said of the agreement to strip all but bare essentials from the bill. `` We get good government in the fair-deal sense.'' `` It is a very major step,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. Voting against the bill were Sens. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Ill.; <PERSON> Howell </PERSON> <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON>, D-Ala.; <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.C. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Mitch </PERSON> <PERSON> McConnell </PERSON>, R-Ky.; <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shelby </PERSON>, D-Ala., and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, D-Ill. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>.; <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ariz </LOCATION>.; <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, R-Ore.; <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallop </PERSON>; <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, R-Calif., and <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON>, D-Colo. At the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, one official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will not likely veto the The official said that the administration was not happy with the turn of events, but that `` the stripped down bill gets back to budget basics.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will continue searching for ways to get his capital-gains proposal through <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in other legislation, the official said. The essential part of the bill would raise taxes by about $ 5.3 billion and cut spending by $ 8.7 billion. But as the measure worked its way through eight committees, it picked up hundreds of amendments to benefit farmers, loggers, low-income families, the poor, the sick, the oil industry and higher-income retirees. The bill became so laden with benefits for one group or another that it had to include $ 38 billion worth of tax increases over five years to have enough money left over to meet deficit-reduction targets. Under the agreement, everything that did not cut the deficit would be removed from the bill. Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, senior Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said the agreement `` ensures that we will have another tax bill very soon _ two or three weeks'' to which the capital-gains reduction, expanded <ORGANIZATION> Individual </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retirement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounts </ORGANIZATION> and any other amendment could be added. Echoing <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, Republicans insisted they were not giving up the fight to cut the tax on capital gains, which are profits from the sale of stocks and other investments. At the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he was troubled by Democratic efforts to substitute expanded tax-deductible IRAs for the capital-gains cut, which he promised during last year's presidential campaign. `` We early on took a very clear-cut position on capital gains,'' he said. `` When I became president, there was no doubt at all where I stood on this.'' He refused to rule out a final compromise that might include both a capital-gains cut and liberalized IRAs. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> agreement was reached without concurrence from the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, which already has passed a deficit-reduction plan that includes a bitterly fought cut in taxes on capital gains. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> passage of its bill would require negotiators from the two houses to work out a compromise between the stripped-down version and the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> package, which has its share of provisions that do nothing to cut the deficit. The final compromise could include a capital-gains cut plus expanded tax-deductible IRAs for all workers. Or, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiators could agree to consider those issues as part of some other tax bill later this year. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> action on deficit reduction had been delayed as Democrats _ who control the chamber by a 55-45 margin _ sought to keep a capital-gains cut out of the bill. In the end, it appeared Democrats had won the battle because Republicans could find no way to overcome a rule that would have required them to get 60 votes to add capital-gains to the legislation. When that became clear, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON> offered to drop the issue as part of an agreement that would strip away all other provisions that would not cut the deficit, including the Democrats' <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> provision Most of the tax increase in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> deficit-reduction plan would fall on corporations. Spending would be cut in scores of programs, including <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> reimbursements for doctors and hospitals and lower deficiency payments for some crops. User fees charged for a variety of activities, such as <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> services, would be raised to boost revenues.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 2349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-USNewsEditors     10-13 0127</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US News Editors,130</SECOND>
<HEAD>Married Couple New Co-Editors At U.S. News</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A husband-wife team is taking over as co-editors of <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; World Report, a spokeswoman for the magazine said Friday. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruby </PERSON> and <PERSON> Merrill </PERSON> <PERSON> McLoughlin </PERSON> will take over the post Oct. 23, replacing <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenblatt </PERSON>, who resigned on Thursday night, said <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bushkin </PERSON>. Before their promotions Ms. <PERSON> McLoughlin </PERSON>, 44, was a senior editor at the magazine and <PERSON> Ruby </PERSON>, 47, was executive editor. <PERSON> Rosenblatt </PERSON> is resigning because the commute between the magazine's headquarters in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and his home in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> was disrupting his family life, Ms. <PERSON> Bushkin </PERSON> said. However, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Saturday editions that <PERSON> Rosenblatt </PERSON> was quitting because of a conflict with the magazine's publisher, <PERSON> Mortimer </PERSON> <PERSON> Zuckerman </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 0905EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Palme 1stLd-Writethru a0426 10-13 0483t Ld-Writethru,
eed Convict Has For Palme Widowruout to UPDATE with news conference, details.
</FIRST>
<SECOND>By CECILIA LOA man who was freed from prison ed his conviction
in the slayingls no bitterness widow, who testified against him.</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Christer </PERSON> <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON>, who hal record, was y after 10 month He told a news police protectiof identity. plans for me to w weeks. But I mrld at some point anyway,'' he said. A police spokesman said <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON> might be placed unde, a four-term pd a prominent inure active in sond nuclear disarmament, was shot Feb. 28, 1986 as he walked home from a movie with his wife, <PERSON> Lisbeth </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Palme </PERSON> testified she was certain she saw <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON> when she looked up from her northern Stockotebro several hours after the <ORGANIZATION> Svea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> threw out his July convictioncient evidence to convict him of the crime. <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON> maintained his innocence throughout his trial. Sentenced to life in prison in <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Court </LOCATION>, chiefly on the testimony of Mrs. <PERSON> Palme </PERSON>, he had beenhis arrest in De he said Thursdaply for her. Actof me and it wouture.'' There was no commensday from Mrs. <PERSON> Peportedly </PERSON> abroads ruling could d biggest setbackr investigation that critics havicted even though no obvious motive was established, no weapon was found and noerseasArrests Arrests
</TEXT>
<UNK></UNK>
<DATELINE>ity to Apprehend Fugitives on Fo LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has given the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> a go-ahead to arrentries without the nations' consent, it was repAssistant Attorney General <PERSON> Williority </PERSON> to seize fugitives in fore in such celebrated cases as terrorist attacks in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> efforrial in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> ing could draw protests from abroad that sovere within the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Barr </PERSON>, the attorney general's chief legal adviser as head ofLegal Counsel, r the office of legal counsel,'' e office ... provides legal advice throughout the administration and does it on a confidential basis.'' The Times reported that several other officials refused to discusty classification and the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> administration ruling was made public.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-EastGermany 1stLd-Writethru   10-13 0721</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-East Germany, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0434,0743</SECOND>
<HEAD>Official Document Rules Out Talks with Opposition</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Leads with 13 grafs to UPDATE with officials ruling out talks
with opposition. Pickup 12th pvs, `Party sources...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GIRARD C. STEICHEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> today ruled out talks with pro-democracy activists and labeled one growing opposition group `` enemies of the socialist order.'' The government had promised discussions to cope with rising unrest and to seek the causes of a refugee exodus, saying it would talk to representatives of `` all parts of society.'' But in an internal <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> position paper obtained by <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, party leaders warned that `` open and hidden enemies of the socialist order'' could create a mass movement at odds with the socialist government. `` Any association with such opposition groups would hurt the further development of socialism,'' the position paper said. The document was directed primarily at the opposition group <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forum </ORGANIZATION>, which has advocated free elections, greater openness in society and a free press. It said New Forum's platform was `` aimed at destroying the leadership role of the Socialist society'' and accused the group of being made up of `` enemies of the socialist order.'' On Thursday, the chief ideologue of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Hager </PERSON>, indicated the opposition movement would be excluded from any discussions about political reform. <PERSON> Hager </PERSON> promised during a visit to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> that the East German government will consider changes following the departure of tens of thousands of citizens to the West and the most widespread public demonstrations since 1953. But his reference to possible talks with public organizations, church groups and other social forces did not appear to include the opposition movement. He said those challenging the foundations of socialism would have no role in the talks. `` If they want to question our social order, then that's not a basis for discussions,'' said <PERSON> Hager </PERSON>, who was in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> for the opening of a cultural exhibition. The communist government here routinely has accused the major opposition groups of trying to undermine socialism. The future of hard-line leader <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>, meanwhile, remained a subject of widespread speculation. Party sources have said influential members of the ruling Politburo were upset over the way the 77-year-old <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> has responded to the unrest. Party sources said he had been asked to provide a report on the `` critical situation'' of the nation before the end of this week. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s mass-circulation <ORGANIZATION> Bild </ORGANIZATION> newspaper, quoting unidentified <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> sources, reported Thursday that <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> would be replaced on Oct. 18. Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> visited <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> over the weekend to help <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> celebrate its 40th anniversary and urged <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> to undertake reforms. Tens of thousands of East Germans demonstrated in several cities and demanded political and economic reform; many asked the reform-minded <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> for his help. <ORGANIZATION> Lutheran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> sources in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> said late Thursday that officials in <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION> were preparing to give amnesty to all those arrested in protests there since Sept. 11. The number was not immediately known, but up to 500 people are believed still to be in jail. The Politburo promised Wednesday to examine the causes of the protests and the recent exodus of tens of thousands of young, skilled East Germans to the West. Opposition leaders Thursday said they were skeptical about the government's professed willingness to enter into real dialogue with any social forces. <PERSON> Baerbel </PERSON> <PERSON> Bohley </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> painter and a co-founder of the opposition group New Forum, described the Politburo statement as a `` verbal shift that does not take into account real life.'' East German leaders have made it clear that any changes would occur only within the framework of the existing socialist system. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> welcomed the East German offer of a dialogue but said it `` should be meaningful and not just a tactical move to relieve domestic and international pressure.'' West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s chief of staff, <PERSON> Rudolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Seiters </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> was optimistic. `` This could be the first positive signal to the populace that the East German leadership has given,'' <PERSON> Seiters </PERSON> said of the Politburo statement. `` But we must wait to see what concrete measures it carries.'' The government in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> has rejected pro-democracy reforms like those taking place in the Soviet bloc countries of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1034EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w PM-FlagBurning 2ndLd-Writethru   10-13 0900</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Flag Burning, 2nd Ld-Writethru,900</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush to Allow Flag-Burning Ban to Become Law</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Combines pvs files a0524-a0529-a0532-a0417; recasts lead to
update with newer quote</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said today he will allow a newly approved ban on flag-burning to become law without his signature, but `` I do n't think it's enough.'' He vowed to continue pressing for a constitutional amendment. During an appearance in the White House briefing room, the president said he was withholding his signature from the congressional legislation `` to signal our belief that a constitutional amendment is the best way to provide lasting protection for the flag.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> commented on the flag legislation in a brief opening statement before responding to questions on other issues. When <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is in session, legislation can become law automatically if the president does not act on it within 10 working days of when it is sent to the White House. After <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has adjourned, a president can pocket-veto bills by refusing to sign them. `` I believe the American flag is a unique and special symbol of our nation and it should be protected from desecration, and our administration has proposed a constitutional amendment to protect the flag,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in his statement. He proposed the amendment after the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled last June that flag-burning was a constitutionally protected form of free speech. The court ruling brought a flood of calls for an amendment to the Constitution, but after the initial response many members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> including the Democratic leadership began looking for a way to deal with the problem through legislation rather than changing the Constitution. When asked if he were concerned about the political consequences of vetoing flag-burning legislation in the light of his attacks on Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in the 1988 presidential campaign, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> denied that was a consideration in his decision. During the campaign, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his supporters repeatedly attacked <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the governor of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, for vetoing legislation that would have required public schools teachers in the state to lead pupils in daily recitations of the Pledge of Allegiance. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the congressional vote was `` an overwhelming expression on the part of the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to do something about the protection of the flag. I do n't think it's enough.'' `` I can understand the rationale of those who voted for the legislation, but in my view, it is not the ultimate answer,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted 317-43 Thursday to complete congressional action on the bill. Supporting the bill were 154 Republicans and 217 Democrats, while it was opposed by 25 Democrats and 18 Republicans. The measure requires up to a year in jail and a $ 1,000 fine for anyone who `` knowingly mutilates, defaces, physically defiles, burns, maintains on the floor or ground, or tramples upon any flag of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' The lopsided approval margin reflected the power of the flag as a political symbol as demonstrated in last year's presidential campaign and by the outcry over the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s June decision overturning a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> flag-burning conviction. The court reversed the conviction of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> flag-burner <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> on grounds the law violated his right to freedom of speech. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> contends a constitutional amendment would settle the issue once and for all and could not be overturned by a court. Such a measure is set to come before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> next week. House Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ill </LOCATION>., told reporters that someone at the White House _ he did not recall the name _ told him the president might stress his dislike of the bill while bowing to its popularity by letting it become law without his signature Soon afterward, White House sources said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was likely to follow that course. He could do that by allowing the measure to sit untouched after it reached his desk for 10 days while <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> remained in session. The sources spoke on condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, traveling with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, declined to say what the president might do. `` We'll have to have a legal review take place'' when the bill arrives at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, he said. Congressional Democrats, declaring that constitutional amendments should be used only as a last resort, said their bill was so carefully worded that it probably could survive a court challenge. `` It is the act of harming the physical integrity of the flag rather than any action that the message might convey that is to be punished,'' said <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, D-Texas. He said the idea was to make flag defacement illegal regardless of whether it had anything to do with political protest and to make the statute `` content neutral.'' <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> scoffed at that notion, however, saying there was no way to draw up such a bill. `` To those who believe we can overturn a <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision at this time by statute, I can only repeat the immortal words of the farmer who, asked directions, said, ` You ca n't get there from here,''' <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. House Speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, D-Wash., said he hoped the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> would to block the proposed constitutional amendment next week `` I think the amendment would be extremely ill-advised,'' <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> said. `` I do n't believe we should rush into any action that would amend the First Amendment without the greatest care and obviously it would be, I think, reckless to do so, I think, at this point.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1034EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Lebanon-Kidnap 3rdLd-Writethru   10-13 0553</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon-Kidnap, 3rd Ld-Writethru,a0525,0569</SECOND>
<HEAD>Swiss Woman Reported Abducted In Lebanon</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: SUBS grafs 10-11, ``There is...of it' with 2 grafs to CORRECT
attribution of quote. Pickup 12th, `Switzerland asked...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MOHAMMED SALAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Armed civilians kidnapped a Swiss flight attendant in northern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> early this week and freed her today, security sources said. Police here could not confirm the abduction. In <LOCATION> Bern </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> on Thursday, <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Clemens </PERSON> <PERSON> Birrer </PERSON> said the woman, whom he refused to identify, was kidnapped by gunmen in northern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> on Sunday. A reliable <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> security source, speaking on condition of anonymity, identified the woman as <PERSON> Astrid </PERSON> <PERSON> Fischer </PERSON>, 31, and said she was was released in <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION> this afternoon. The source said gunmen kidnapped Ms. <PERSON> Fischer </PERSON> from a house in the village of <LOCATION> Koubbaa </LOCATION>, 31 miles north of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, on Sunday. <PERSON> Birrer </PERSON> had said the kidnapping occurred in <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION>, which is 50 miles north of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. The source refused to identify the kidnappers but said the woman, a flight attendant with <ORGANIZATION> Swissair </ORGANIZATION>, was `` interrogated in connection with her activities and stay in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>.'' He refused to elaborate. The abduction would be the third of a <LOCATION> Swiss </LOCATION> national in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> in a week. The two previous kidnappings were linked to the case of a Shiite Moslem militant serving a life sentence in <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> for hijacking a jet. When asked about the latest reported kidnapping, <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION> police chief Col. <PERSON> Nabil </PERSON> <PERSON> Zein </PERSON> said today: `` I have no information at all about this kidnapping. We have neither a notification nor a complaint about such a kidnapping.'' `` I read the report from <LOCATION> Bern </LOCATION> in the papers this morning,'' he told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> when contacted by telephone. <PERSON> Birrer </PERSON> said the woman's parents asked authorities not to publicize the case. He told reporters of the kidnapping after being asked about unattributed news reports of it. `` There is no sign of a political background to this kidnapping,'' he added. <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> asked <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, which controls much of northern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, to help find the woman, he said. In all, 19 Westerners are missing in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, including eight Americans. The longest held is <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, who was kidnapped March 16, 1985. Shiite Moslems loyal to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> are thought to be holding most of the hostages. On Oct. 6, two <ORGANIZATION> Swiss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> workers, <PERSON> Elio </PERSON> <PERSON> Erriquez </PERSON> and <PERSON> Emmanual </PERSON> <PERSON> Christen </PERSON>, were abducted in southern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. No group claimed responsibility for the kidnappings, and no demands have been made. Later that day, a <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> spokesman blamed radical Palestinian guerrillas led by terrorist mastermind <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Nidal </PERSON> for those abductions and linked them to a Shiite Moslem militant, <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Hariri </PERSON>. He is serving a life sentence in <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> for hijacking an Air Afrique jetliner in 1987 and killing a French passenger. Lebanese police also blamed <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Nidal </PERSON>'s group for the Oct. 6 abductions. The <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Nidal </PERSON> organization denied involvement. <PERSON> Birrer </PERSON> said he did not believe there was any connection between the kidnappings Oct. 6 and that reported Thursday. All Swiss <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> personnel were withdrawn from <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> following the kidnapping in November of <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Winkler </PERSON>, a relief worker in <LOCATION> Sidon </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Winkler </PERSON> was released a month later, and the Swiss contingent returned after receiving assurances from all sides in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> that humanitarian workers would not be targeted for kidnappings.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w PM-Abortion-Democrats 1stLd-Writethru a0442 10-13 0804</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion-Democrats, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0442,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Holds Out Hope for Compromise on Abortion Issue</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Top 11 grafs new with Bush, moves up Michel comment; picks up
10th graf pvs, It is part.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said today he opposes allowing Medicaid abortions for victims of rape and incest but held out hope a congressional compromise could be worked out that would `` avoid a veto on my part.'' At a morning news conference, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> repeatedly insisted he has not wavered in his opposition to a provision passed by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday, and earlier by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, that would drop a decade-long ban on federally funded abortions for poor women who are victims of rape or incest. But <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiators working out different versions of the broader legislation could produce `` room for flexibility.'' `` I'm not looking for any conflict over this. I'm not going to change my position any,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` But let's see how these negotiations come out, and we'll start discussing that today. But I have not changed my position.'' Asked if he was leaving open the question of whether he would veto the legislation as passed by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` Well, because I'm told that the conference language may be able to avoid a veto on my part.'' House Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> said Thursday that there might be room for a compromise if both sides could agree to a provision permitting Medicaid abortions when the rape or incest victim reported that act within 48 hours of its occurrence. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> commented a day after Democratic leaders in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> conceded they could not override a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> veto of the bill and pleaded with him to reconsider. `` The president has the power to deny an opportunity for poor women to make a choice in their tragic circumstances,'' said <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, D-Wash. `` The president's position is wrong,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION> `` It is harsh _ terribly harsh _ on the poorest, most vulnerable <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women.'' In an outcome that surprised even the victors, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted 216-206 to permit use of federal money to terminate pregnancies for poor women who are victims of rape or incest and who report it `` promptly'' to authorities. The provision would revise current law permitting Medicaid abortions only in cases where a woman's life was endangered by pregnancy and she could not afford to pay for an abortion. It is part of a $ 156.7 billion measure to finance labor, health and education programs for fiscal 1990 that has already been approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> but remains subject to final agreement on unrelated issues. `` Not only is this a reflection of the majority position of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION>, Democrat and Republican, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, but the American people as well,'' <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> said, joining <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> at a press conference to appeal to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` This is a plea to the president to reconsider,'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said. `` The votes are not there in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to override the veto. Therefore, he holds it in his power.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has been dogged by political controversy on the abortion issue for a decade, and some anti-abortion groups have questioned his commitment to their side. As a candidate for president in 1980, before becoming <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s running mate, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> took the view that there should be three circumstances permitting abortion _ rape, incest and the threatened life of the mother. He muted those views after joining <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s ticket. But once he started running for president again, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> made statements that suggested his position was shifting again. In an appearance Oct. 7, 1987, at an <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> high school, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told a student who questioned him that while he opposes abortion, `` I would make the exception ... rape, incest and the life of the mother.'' The provision passed by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> is narrowly drawn, permitting funding for abortions when the victims report the rape or incest `` promptly.'' Experts said the change might affect only a small number of cases, but it was widely viewed as a symbolic victory for supporters of abortion rights. It came as abortion rights forces were benefiting from an apparently shifting political climate on abortion since the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s ruling in July. That ruling allowed increased state regulation of abortions, and abortion rights forces say it politically energized those on their side of the issue. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote came on the same day abortion rights groups enjoyed a symbolic victory in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. The state legislature, in a special session called by Republican Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, rejected all the governor's proposed abortion restrictions. `` Certainly <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and the vote yesterday in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are reflective of a new political movement,'' said <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> <PERSON> Michelman </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abortion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>. `` The climate is changing.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1047EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-King-Abernathy 1stLd-Writethru a0477 10-13 0817</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-King-Abernathy, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0477,0833</SECOND>
<HEAD>Black Leaders Demand Abernathy Retract Account of King</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 5 grafs to RECAST, UPDATE with interviews published
today with Abernathy and a Memphis woman who contradicts part of his account.
Picks up 3rd graf, `Abernathy has....</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto AX1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SONYA ROSS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Civil rights leaders are demanding that the Rev. <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> retract implications in his new book that the Rev. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> had sexual encounters with women on the night before he was killed. A <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, woman said in an interview published today that she was with <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> and King that night, and she disputed part of the account in <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON>'s autobiography, `` And The Walls Came Tumbling Down.'' In his book, published this month, King's onetime top aide says <PERSON> King </PERSON> spent parts of the night before his death alone with two different women and physically fought with a third. <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> wrote that he awoke from a nap in a woman's living room after a late-night dinner to see King and the woman emerge from a bedroom. <PERSON> Adjua </PERSON> <PERSON> Abi </PERSON> <PERSON> Naantaanbuu </PERSON> told The Commercial Appeal in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> that she was host of the dinner and that she and her sister talked with King and another aide in the living room while <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON>, who `` had too many'' drinks, slept on her bed. In an interview published today in The <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> Journal-Constitution, <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> rejected suggestions by some of the civil rights leaders that two strokes and brain surgery might have impaired his memory. `` I am most surprised anybody would think I'm mentally incompetent,'' <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> said <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> has said that he did not include passages about King's extramarital affairs out of malice, but felt he needed to address the issue since it had been discussed in previous biographies of the Nobel Peace Prize winner `` I loved Martin Luther King more than a brother. I would never do it to injure him,'' <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> said. A coalition of black leaders including <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said Thursday they objected to the controversial passages and doubted that <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> wrote them. A spokesman for the book's publisher replied that the whole book was written solely by the <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> minister The group's statement concluded that `` the <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> section'' of <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON>'s book was so out of character with <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON>'s life and previous statements that it must have been `` put into your mouth by others who needed a sensational story to sell books and slander the name of your martyred brother.'' <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Sorrentino </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Harper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Row in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, said the allegations are untrue. `` The book is entirely <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON>'s words. There was no co-writer, no ghost writer,'' <PERSON> Sorrentino </PERSON> said. `` He stands by everything he says in the book. I wonder if all the people sitting back criticizing now have read the book. `` The book is not a sensationalized, ` put down <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>' book,'' <PERSON> Sorrentino </PERSON> said. `` He reveres <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> and takes two pages to address what everyone has talked about before. He wanted to address it and be honest about it.'' <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> _ appearing to promote the book Thursday in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, where King was slain April 4, 1968 _ said he was surprised by the uproar. `` I'm not <PERSON> Judas </PERSON>,'' he told reporters. `` I know who I am. I'm a Christian minister.'' <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, chairman of the board of The King Center in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, said a number of civil rights leaders including <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> chief <ORGANIZATION> Benjamin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hooks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON>, sent <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> a telegram Sunday calling on him to repudiate his writings. `` We take particular exception to your personal reconstruction of <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s last hours on this earth,'' said the telegram, read to reporters by <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> at a news conference in front of King's tomb at The King Center. `` The <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> we know and love would not have written this section. ... We deplore the fact that, for this account, if it is not repudiated, will rob you of your rightful place in history.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> issued a statement that the character of <PERSON> King </PERSON>'s work would stand `` when all the dust clears.'' `` Dr. King can not speak for himself,'' the statement said. `` Those of us who appreciate Dr. <PERSON> King </PERSON>'s work will stand with him through every challenge.'' Hooks, in a statement released from <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, said he had read the book and was `` deeply saddened and distressed'' that <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> `` would succumb to the temptation to desecrate'' King's memory. King Center officials said <PERSON> King </PERSON>'s widow, <PERSON> Coretta </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, president of the center, would have no statement other than to endorse that made by <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, the center's board chairman. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurst </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, an African <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> bishop, said <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, Hooks and former King aide <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, all of whom were in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> with <PERSON> King </PERSON> on his final days, have `` sharply different'' recollections of the events of those days.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w BC-BushText     10-13 0665</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text,600-up</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: Retransmits a0534 to include material cut off at end of last
answer.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a transcript of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s news conference Friday: I have a statement I'd like to make, and then _ some time constraints _ be glad to answer a few questions. I believe that the American flag is a unique and special symbol of our nation and it should be protected from desecration, and our administration has proposed a constitutional amendment to protect the flag because we believe that is the most _ the most lasting and legally correct means of protection, a constitutional amendment. And yesterday, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION> agreed to a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bill providing statutory protection for the flag, and when this measure comes to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, I will allow the bill to become law, but without my signature. And I am withholding that signature to signal our belief that a constitutional amendment is the best way to provide lasting protection for the flag. We will continue to work for such an amendment, and I can understand the rationale of those who voted for this legislation, but in my view it is not the ultimate answer, and therefore I will not put my signature on the legislation. I would now be glad to take questions, all of which, I am sure will be on the flag. Q. Sorry to disappoint you, Mr. President. You have said on several occasions that you knew everything at the time of the Panamanian coup, and you did n't feel that there were any really problems in retrospective. At the same time, there are many reports that you've changed the rules of procedure on handling _ on crisis management, and that you have asked the Hill for more authority to operate during a coup or plan a coup or whatever. Can you straighten this out for us? And ... A. Let me help you out. Q. Obviously there were glitches, or you would n't have spent two weeks trying to defend yourself _ I mean, the administration. A. Well, I'm not sure I agree to the last part. Q. You have spent two weeks trying to explain to the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people what you did. A. No, this is the first chance _ shot I've had at explaining. Q. Not you per se, but your administration. A. Oh, I see. No, I _ what was the first part of the question? Q. That you have changed the procedures on crisis management, and ... A. No, look, here's what _ it's coming back. Here is my position. I have not seen any fact in all the reports that have come out that would make me have done something different in terms of use of force. And I reiterate that. Now, in terms of procedures, I'll simply say, any time we can make improvements, so much the better. But there has not been an intelligence gap that would have made me act in a different way. And so _ and I repeat that. And there's been endless interviews and discussions and stories, many of which are false, that come out as to what we were asked to do or not to do. But I've seen no fact that would make me change my view. And I've seen allegations that we had _ if when I said I wanted <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to get out there, that implied use of force. I hope I would never be reckless enough as a commander-in-chief to make a blanket commitment to use of force if _ without knowing the facts regarding some coup attempt. We want to see Mr. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> out. I'll repeat that. I've been very heartened by the reports from various leaders in our hemisphere.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 about what <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> should do. So _ but I do n't see any serious disconnects at all. And if we can fine tune our crisis management system, so much the better. And I think that's what you're reading about now.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1100EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Syria     10-13 0663</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Syria,0685</SECOND>
<HEAD>Syrian Says He Flew `Into the Unknown' In Search of Freedom</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By G.G. LaBELLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TEL AVIV, Israel (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Syrian pilot who landed his plane in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> said today he defected because he wanted to live in a democracy and would refuse any offer by the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> to return him to <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> has denied the pilot was a defector and asked the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> to intervene. Maj. <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Bassam </PERSON> <PERSON> Adel </PERSON> refused to answer most political questions at a news conference arranged by the Israeli army, but he said <LOCATION> Syrian </LOCATION> pilots considered <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s air force superior to their own. He recounted how he flew across the border at high speed and as low as 30 yards off the ground, `` going into the unknown'' in search of freedom and a place to land. He said he made the decision to defect on his own for personal reasons and had no contact with anyone in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> before he piloted his Soviet-built MiG-23 over the <LOCATION> Golan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> on Wednesday. `` I decided to cross the border in electronic silence,'' he said. `` I was not in contact with anyone. Nobody was expecting me. `` It was a difficult mission. I did n't know where I was going to land. I did n't know if I would find a facility to land. I was going into the unknown,'' the 34-year-old flier told Israeli and foreign reporters. Much has been made in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> over how <PERSON> Adel </PERSON> crossed the border without being intercepted, although he reporedly was in Israeli air space for seven minutes before landing. `` The section I was crossing was spread all over with missiles,'' the short, wiry pilot said. `` I crossed at very low altitude and very high speed.'' When asked to be specific, <PERSON> Adel </PERSON> said he flew at 700 to 750 mph and `` below 50 meters -LRB- yards -RRB-, sometimes 30 meters, sometimes 40.'' <PERSON> Adel </PERSON>, who was dressed in an olive green flight suit, spoke in Arabic and his words were translated into English by Israeli officers. The news conference was held at a military base near <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION>. The pilot said he defected in search of freedom. `` I wanted to live in a democracy where people can express their views with freedom,'' he explained. Asked to comment on Syrian politics, he repeated his desire for freedom and added that `` by implication you can presume my thoughts about the political system in <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Adel </PERSON> was asked whether he would see a representative of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>, as <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> has requested. `` If the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> wants to meet me and take me back to <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, I would refuse this,'' he said. Asked if he hoped to remain in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, he said, `` I said I wanted to live in a democracy ... so you might conclude I want to live here.'' However, he said he had made no definite decisions about his future. <PERSON> Adel </PERSON> would say little about the MiG-23 he piloted across the <LOCATION> Golan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION> to a civilian airstrip near <LOCATION> Megiddo </LOCATION>, 57 miles north of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> in northern <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Nor would he compare it to other Syrian air force planes. He also refused to discuss his family and whether he was discriminated against because of his Sunni Moslem religion in a country where the president, <PERSON> Hafez </PERSON> <PERSON> Assad </PERSON>, and many military leaders belong to the minority Alawite sect. <PERSON> Adel </PERSON> said he received `` gentle'' treatment from the Israelis, was asked mainly about his reasons for defecting and had not yet been questioned about the Syrian air force. When asked if Syrian pilots felt they had gained superiority over <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, he replied: `` No one in the Syrian air force feels that they could defeat <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, that they are superior to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Adel </PERSON> said he was born in the Syrian town of <LOCATION> Aleppo </LOCATION> and was a graduate of <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>. He said he decided `` a long time ago'' to defect and had been planning it seriously for three to four months.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1100EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BostonFire 1stLd-Writethru a0480 10-13 0399</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Boston Fire, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0480,0404</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinatown Fire Ignites Fireworks, Destroys Building</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 3 grafs to UPDATE with fire still smoldering, work
continuing on gutted building; picks up 4th graf pvs: `The blaze...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JONATHAN YENKIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fire in a bustling <LOCATION> Chinatown </LOCATION> neighborhood detonated 2,000 pounds of illegally stored fireworks, destroyed one building and injured 17 people, officials said. The fire, which broke out about noon in a building that had a small grocery store on the ground floor, was controlled at 5 p.m., but pieces of the building continued to smolder this morning. Firefighters worked to finish tearing down the six-story brick building to prevent it from collapsing. The blaze spread to two adjoining buildings, igniting as many as 29 explosions in fireworks stored illegally in one of the buildings and forcing some of the 200 firefighters to evacuate, said Fire Commissioner <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> Stapleton </PERSON>. `` I'm very distrubed about that,'' <PERSON> Stapleton </PERSON> said. `` We could have lost a lot of firefighters there.'' Of the 17 people injured, 13 were were treated at the scene for minor injuries, three were treated at area hospitals and released, and one _ a firefighter _ was hospitalized in stable condition suffering from smoke inhalation, spokesmen said. The fire broke out just before noon in the compact and congested neighborhood of <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> restaurants, bakeries, apartments and small businesses, casting a pall of thick black and gray smoke over the city's skyline. The fire appeared to have started on the ground floor of the six-story building, where there were reports that workers might have been using welding equipment or cutting torches, <PERSON> Stapleton </PERSON> said. The cause remained under investigation, and preliminary estimates put the damage at $ 2 million, he said. Damage estimates for the two other buildings were incomplete early today. Within the last month city officials had ordered the stoppage of illegal construction work at the building where the fire started, said fire Lt. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonnell </PERSON>. Firefighters had trouble getting adequate pressure in their hoses, said Deputy Fire Chief <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Christian </PERSON>. He said he was unsure if more pressure might have saved the six-story building, but he said it might have enabled firefighters to keep the flames from spreading. Officials from the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sewer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> said two valves under the street had been closed, possibly by a contractor doing work in the area.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1101EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Norway     10-13 0403</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Norway,0417</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brundtland Steps Down as Norway's Prime Minister</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUG MELLGREN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OSLO, Norway (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Gro </PERSON> <PERSON> Harlem </PERSON> <PERSON> Brundtland </PERSON> resigned today, yielding the government to a three-party non-socialist coalition after 3 -LCB- tough years of minority rule. <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Syse </PERSON>, 58, will become prime minister on Monday. Mrs. <PERSON> Brundtland </PERSON> remains until then as caretaker. Mrs. <PERSON> Brundtland </PERSON>'s resignation followed a loss by her <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> of eight parliament seats in the Sept. 11 election. The party fell to 63 seats in the expanded 165-member Storting. The 50-year-old prime minister helped topple the same Conservative-led alliance in 1986, and some analysts predict her return to power within a year. Mrs. <PERSON> Brundtland </PERSON> presented her resignation to King Olav V today and referred the monarch to <PERSON> Syse </PERSON> about a new government. <PERSON> Syse </PERSON>, an attorney, will polish his coalition of the <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parties </ORGANIZATION> and assign Cabinet posts this weekend. `` I can assure you the government will be ready at the right time,'' <PERSON> Syse </PERSON> said after seeing the king. The new coalition controls 62 seats. It had the support of the extreme right 22-seat <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Progress </ORGANIZATION> in its threat to evict Labor in a no-confidence vote unless Mrs. <PERSON> Brundtland </PERSON> stepped down. Labor's ally, the <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Left </ORGANIZATION>, has 17 seats and there is one independent. Mrs. <PERSON> Brundtland </PERSON> is best known abroad as head of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on the Environment and Developement. In opposition, she is expected to chair parliament's Foreign Affairs Committee. The coalition's position is tenuous. The anti-tax <ORGANIZATION> Progress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> has said it wo n't guarantee support, since the coalition refused to make it a partner. `` They wo n't last more than a year,'' predicted <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Lafferty </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> political scientist who has lived in <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> for 22 years. <PERSON> Gunnar </PERSON> <PERSON> Vogt </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Syse </PERSON> may even turn to Labor to support some of his programs to avoid being held to ransom by the extremist parties. `` It's anyone's guess'' whether the coalition can last until elections in 1993, <PERSON> Vogt </PERSON> said in an interview. <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> has no mechanism for early elections, and if <PERSON> Syse </PERSON> ca n't hold his partnership together, Mrs. <PERSON> Brundtland </PERSON> probably would move back into the prime minister's office Mrs. <PERSON> Brundtland </PERSON> was credited for helping to cut inflation in half, turn a trade deficit into a surplus and slow consumer spending. But she left the country with postwar record unemployment of 5 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1102EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Trost-Soviets 1stLd-Writethru a0447 10-13 0487</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Trost-Soviets, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0447,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Navy Chief: Soviet Arms Control Proposals Present Undue Restrictions</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: CORRECTS first name in penultimate graf to Sergei sted Moisev</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> chief of naval operations says Soviet arms control proposals would place undue restrictions on the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s ability to protect American interests and `` deter aggression. Adm. <PERSON> Carlisle </PERSON> <PERSON> Trost </PERSON>, the first chief of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military service to visit the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, made the comments Thursday in a speech to the <ORGANIZATION> Leningrad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. A text of his remarks was made available to The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s top man noted with some amusement that he was spending today, the 214th anniversary of the founding of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, `` here in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, visiting ships in your fleet ... meeting officers and men in your <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. `` I think that my being here marks a milestone in the progress that our two countries have made in just the past few years toward improving bilateral relations and easing some of the tension that has characterized our dialogue for the past four decades,'' <PERSON> Trost </PERSON> said. But the admiral had few kind words to say about Soviet proposals to limit <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> naval power around the world. <PERSON> Trost </PERSON> mentioned proposals from the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact and others that would exclude anti-submarine forces from certain security zones; exclude all naval force activity from certain strategic straits and high density shipping lanes; limit naval exercises; or place restrictions on the movement of ships with nuclear-capable weapons. `` Any one of these would result in the inability of my <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> to protect the global interests of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> or to deter aggression. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> forces must be free to operate when and where deterrent presence is required, and operate unimpeded by restrictive sanctions,'' <PERSON> Trost </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Trost </PERSON> said he also opposed any restrictions on the use of sea-launched cruise missiles, calling compliance with any such limitations `` unverifiable without unacceptably intrusive inspections.'' The admiral contended the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is dependent upon overseas trade for its economic well-being, whereas `` seaborne trade for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is not a matter of national survival.'' `` When viewed from this perspective, I strongly feel that my country's reluctance to enter into naval arms reductions is justified by the facts and is a prudent and rational position,'' the admiral said. <PERSON> Trost </PERSON> also dismissed Soviet calls for limits on the 14 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aircraft carriers that ply the high seas, calling them the `` backbone'' of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and a useful tool for deterring `` would-be aggressors.'' <PERSON> Trost </PERSON> noted that when former Soviet military chief <PERSON> Sergei </PERSON> <PERSON> Akhromeyev </PERSON> visited the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, he said the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and its bases `` threaten the security of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.'' But <PERSON> Trost </PERSON> said, `` The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> strategy is not intended to threaten anyone.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military forces `` are only a threat to someone who would intend to threaten our interests or those of our allies,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1103EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Academy-Blacks     10-13 0345</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Academy-Blacks,0360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Board Members, Athletes Quit Over Private School Racial Issue</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WEST, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two school board members resigned and seven athletes quit an all-white private school's football team after it forfeited a game with a school that is fielding a black player. `` I just felt it was time I did n't serve on -LRB- the board -RRB- anymore,'' said <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> McClellan </PERSON>, a vice president at <ORGANIZATION> Holmes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> who has been a board member of the <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Holmes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> for two years. He did not elaborate. The resignations and walkout by the players followed confirmation by <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Holmes </ORGANIZATION> Headmaster <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Drake </PERSON> that the school would not play <ORGANIZATION> Columbus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>, which has the first black player in North Central AA Conference history. <PERSON> Drake </PERSON>, one of the school's founders, said earlier this week that race had nothing to do with the decision. He said the action involved something `` private'' that he could not discuss. But several questioned his decision. `` It's a racial thing, no question about it,'' said <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, whose son was a starting tackle and linebacker before quitting the team Wednesday. <PERSON> Drake </PERSON> refused Thursday to answer additional questions about the decision. A broadcaster also said Thursday in <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> that former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Football </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> player <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> was banned from broadcasting a game at <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Holmes </ORGANIZATION> because he is black. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said he and <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> were scheduled to broadcast the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> <PERSON> Academy-East </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> game on television on Aug. 25. <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, an ex-Mississippi State standout, was told he should not come, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said Thursday. <PERSON> Drake </PERSON> denied <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' charge. `` That was not the case,'' he said. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Janous </PERSON>, another <PERSON> East </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> school board member, said he sent a letter of resignation last Friday after serving on the governing panel for more than 10 years. Asked why he resigned, <PERSON> Janous </PERSON> said: `` I do n't want to say ... I think you probably know.'' Among the seven atheletes who quit were four starters in tonight's game against <ORGANIZATION> Grenada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kirk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>. East <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> has 17 players remaining on its roster. `` How do you function?'' asked <PERSON> East </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> coach <PERSON> Riley </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w BC-BushText 1stAdd   10-13 0775</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 1st Add,770</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> WASHINGTON </LOCATION>: about now. Q. Well, have you asked for greater authority from the intelligence committees to act in such cases? A. No, I have not, but we had a very good meeting with two leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, the other day, but I have not asked for that. We may _ we may _ Q. You're satisfied with the power you have? A. Well, I want as broad a power as possible, and I think under the Constitution a president has it, but I'll be working with the _ has broad powers, broader than some in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> or the House might think. I may have a difference with some on interpreting what the powers of the president might be, but I want to work cooperatively with these committees, and it was with that in mind that we invited <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> here, but I've not made specific requests of them. We might. We might do it. But we have not done it yet. Yeah, <PERSON> Terry </PERSON>? Q. Mr President, Democratic leaders in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are urging you not to veto legislation to remove the ban on federal financing of abortions for the poor. House Speaker <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> says your position is harsh, terribly harsh on the poorest, most vulnerable <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women. Will you let that legislation become law? A. My position is well known and well stated. And right now there is some negotiation and discussion going on. I have not read the conference language, and so we're going to be meeting with some of the various most interested congressional parties on this and see what can be resolved. I'm not looking for any conflict over this. I'm not going to change my position any. But let's see how those negotiations come out, and we'll start discussing that today. But I have not changed my position. Q. But you're leaving it open about whether or not you would veto this? A. Well, because I'm told, <PERSON> Terry </PERSON>, that the conference language may be able to avoid a veto on my part. Yeah, <PERSON> Lesley </PERSON>? Q. Mr. President, in other words, you are willing to negotiate or accept a compromise that in some way would allow federal funding for abortions in cases of rape or incest. A. No, I've already said what I'm willing to do _ discuss the conference language. Yeah, <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>? Q. Let me ask you specifically. Are you _ A. Is this a follow-up? Q. Yes. Are you willing to compromise? A. I'm not willing _ I've already told you my position Yeah? Q. Let me ask you a question about your position. Can you explain why you believe it's all right for women who can afford an abortion on their own, that in cases where they are raped or in cases of incest that it's permissible, but that for poor women who can not afford abortions, it is not permissible to help them get abortions in cases of rape and incest? <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>, the only answer I can give you on that is to go back to the original Hyde Amendment, and to the position that I took and will stay with And to some, there might be a contradiction there; to me, there is none. Yes, <PERSON> John </PERSON>? Q. If I may follow, sir, I mean, it's not a question of a contradiction. It seems that if you can pay it yourself, it's okay under those circumstances, but the message, it seems, is that if you ca n't afford it yourself, tough luck. And is n't that a moral conflict in your own position? A. There _ no, I do n't think it's a moral conflict in my own position. Yes, <PERSON> John </PERSON>? Q. Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, could I return to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> for an instant? A. Yes. Q. Would you _ what message are you sending _ you say you want <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> out _ what message are you sending the PDF then? Would you like them to attempt another coup, or is that out of the question? A. Well, I do n't think anything's out of the question I think that from what I've seen, and the reports I've heard out of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, things are more unsettled than before about the fate of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. I would simply reiterate that we have no problem with the PDF itself. I think this rather sophisticated argument that if you say you'd like to see <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> out, that implies a blanket open _ open carte blanche on the use of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> force. I do n't want to mislead somebody, and to me that's a _ you know _ a stupid argument that some very erudite people make.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w PM-Bush 2ndLd-Writethru a0543 10-13 0852</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0543,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Still Hopes for Noriega's Removal</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Inserts new 8th graf, While saying, with Bush willing to review
crisis management; minor editing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, reflecting on the failed coup against <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, said today he still hopes to see <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s leader ousted and brought to justice and added, `` I would n't mind using force if it could be done in a prudent manner.'' At a mid-morning news conference in the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he opposes House-passed legislation providing federal funds for abortions for poor women who are victims of incest or rape. But the president said he hoped compromise language would make it possible to avoid a veto of the politically charged legislation. On another controversial subject, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he would permit legislation banning flag burning to become law without his signature. He said the legislation was n't `` the ultimate answer,'' and urged a constitutional amendment to do the same thing. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> signaled his desire for flexibility on other issues, as well, including <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> calls for expanded individual retirement accounts and legislation to repeal catastrophic health care for the elderly. But there was no give on his defense of his much-criticized handling of the failed coup attempt in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> two weeks ago, when <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops stationed nearby were not directed to intervene on behalf the rebels. `` I would hope I would never be reckless enough as commander-in-chief to make a commitment to force without knowing the facts'' of a coup attempt. He said he'd seen no evidence of a crucial gap in intelligence. `` I would n't mind using force if it could be done in a prudent manner,'' he said in defending the decision not to take part in the coup. `` So I'm not ruling out the use of force for all time.'' While saying he would not change his decision against using force, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> acknowledged complaints about poor communication and other problems by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He said they were `` well worth looking into'' and that he was not opposed to `` fine-tuning'' his crisis-management system. He hinted broadly he might seek congressional approval for greater authority in dealing with situations like the coup in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. `` We may, we may,'' he said. `` I want as broad a power as possible and I think under the Constitution the president has it.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> continued his defense even as he was walking out of the briefing room. `` I can understand instant hawks appearing from where there used to be the feathers of a dove, because some of it is political and some of it is the frustration they feel because this man -LRB- <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> -RRB- is still in office,'' he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also urged <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to approve his plan for a cut in the capital gains tax, and said he would consider signing legislation that combined his plan with a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> proposal liberalizing individual retirement accounts. `` The mixing of IRAs and capital gains in this debate is troublesome to me,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` Whether there is room for compromise on that, I'd leave it to those who are negotiating.'' Most of the attention during the question-and-answer session was focused on <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. The Panamanian leader is under indictment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for drug trafficking, and the president said he's not willing to have the indictment dropped in exchange for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> giving up power. He blended his call for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s ouster with his defense of his own actions two weeks ago. `` I am not going to give carte blanche support for an operation, particularly when they do n't ask for that support,'' he said. `` I have to reserve that right, I have at stake the lives of American kids.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> brushed aside critics who said he missed an opportunity to assist in <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s ouster in the failed coup. `` I've seen no fact that would make me change my view,'' he said. On the flag legislation, the president said: `` I will allow the bill to become law, but without my signature. I am withholding that signature to signal our belief that the constitutional amendment is the best way to provide protection for the flag.'' Asked about attempts in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to repeal catastrophic health care legislation for the elderly, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he was `` letting the congressional process hash this out.' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was asked repeatedly about the volatile abortion issue, and said he hoped he could avoid a veto of legislation that calls for Medicaid funding for abortions for poor women who are victims of rape and incest. `` I'm not looking for any conflict over this,'' he said. `` My position is well known and well stated and right now there is some negotiations and discussion going on,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Aides have suggested <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would likely veto the bill if the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> version is embraced in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. He said he wanted to see if there is `` room for flexibility.'' The House has passed the provision and sent it to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, which approved similar provision a year ago and is expected to do so again. `` The conference language may be able to avoid a veto on my part.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Pope     10-13 0423</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pope,0436</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pope Celebrates Final Mass of Visit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VICTOR L. SIMPSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEDAN, Indonesia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The pope today celebrated the final Mass of his Indonesian tour and urged Catholics here to be bold in proclaiming Christian values in this predominantly Moslem nation. The pontiff stressed themes of family and social teaching at his final stops but also acknowledged difficulties facing the church in <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> spokesman <PERSON> Joaquin </PERSON> <PERSON> Navarro </PERSON> gave a positive summation of the trip, saying no obstacles had been placed before the pope and that he spoke with `` absolute freedom.'' But the pontiff again used guarded language when referring to potential conflicts with the government or Moslem community. His last Mass here was attended by 100,000 people amid lush coffee and palm oil plantations in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sumatra </LOCATION>. In a speech to the country's 42 bishops later in <LOCATION> Jakarta </LOCATION>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> urged Catholics to be bold in proclaiming their Christian values. He acknowledged `` occasional difficulties'' facing his 5 million-member flock but reminded them that religious freedom is protected by the constitution. There are 157 million Moslems in <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>. `` Do not be afraid to encourage the Catholic people to -LRB- be -RRB- an ever more public witness to the truths and values of their faith, in keeping with their rightful place in the society of which they are worthy citizens,'' he told the bishops. Raising another delicate issue, the <PERSON> pope </PERSON> said `` You are sometimes painfully aware that certain traditional practices and other contemporary social influences bring about an obscuring of fundamental principles regarding family life and the responsible transmission of life.'' He did not elaborate but was apparently referring to polygamy and the government's aggressive birth control program. The church bars artificial birth control. The church as well as the government here is concerned about increasing pressure from Moslem extremists. The Moslem influence is reflected in two proposed laws before parliament. One would make Islamic religious teaching mandatory in all schools, including <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> ones, and the other would set up Islamic courts for marriages, wills and inheritances. The only trouble during the pope's stay occurred Thursday in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Timor </LOCATION>, when youths opposed to <LOCATION> Indonesian </LOCATION> rule of the former <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> colony clashed with police at the end of the papal mass. They held up banners greeting the pope in the name of an anti-Indonesian guerrilla group. <PERSON> Navarro </PERSON> said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> watched the incident calmly and made no mention of it afterward. The pope is scheduled to leave Saturday for the <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> island nation of <LOCATION> Mauritius </LOCATION>. He returns to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> on Monday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-StampAuction     10-13 0328</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stamp Auction,0338</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ninty-six Cents Worth of Stamps Gets Record $1.1 Million at Auction</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four 24-cent stamps printed in 1918 to inaugurate <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> air mail delivery fetched $ 1.1 million at an auction, the highest price ever paid for a stamp collectors' item, officials said. The airplane depicted on the stamps was inadvertently printed upside down. The stamps, considered the finest philatelic item in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, are called `` Curtiss Jenny'' because the airplane shown is a model <PERSON> Curtiss </PERSON> JN-6, which carried the first air mail deliveries, said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Trepel </PERSON> of <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s auction house. <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s, which handled the sale, identified the buyer at Thursday's auction only as `` an American broadcast executive.'' The stamps were uncanceled and included a border bearing the four-digit number of the plate used to print the stamps. Another block of four <PERSON> Curtiss </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenny </PERSON> stamps that did not include the plate number sold for $ 528,000. The original sheet bearing 100 <PERSON> Curtiss </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenny </PERSON> stamps was bought for $ 24 in 1918 in a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> post office by a private collector. The <PERSON> Curtiss </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenny </PERSON> stamps and other philatelic items sold at <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s were from the collection of <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Weill </PERSON>, 74, and his brother, <PERSON> Roger </PERSON>, 78, renowned stamp dealers who have run a stamp shop in the French Quarter of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> since 1932. The 342 lots auctioned went for a total of $ 4.29 million. Another big seller was a block of four <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> stamps bearing a picture of a car that inadvertently was printed upside down. The stamps, issued in 1901 to commemorate the opening of the Pan-American exposition in <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, sold for $ 203,500, <PERSON> Trepel </PERSON> said. Among the other items sold was a telegram cover with a Pony Express insignia, which went for $ 99,000. The telegram was sent in 1860 from the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, but since the telegraph line terminated in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joseph </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, the last leg of the journey between <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> was made by <ORGANIZATION> Pony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GMBiasSuit     10-13 0211</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-GM Bias Suit,0216</SECOND>
<HEAD>Appeal of GM Racial Discrimination Lawsuit Filed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Several black <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> workers are challenging a settlement of a racial descrimination lawsuit against the company, saying the payout is too small. Attorneys said the settlement could cost <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> $ 3 million immediately and up to $ 40 million over the next five years. An appeal filed Thursday with the 6th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> says the case was poorly handled and the settlement too small. Last month, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Feikens </PERSON> approved a settlement of the lawsuit originally filed by four employees in 1983. It became a class action suit three years later involving 10,000 black <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> workers in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. The black workers claimed an employee appraisal system, dropped by the automaker after the suit was filed, resulted in lower pay and fewer promotions for blacks between 1982 and 1986. <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> issued a statement Thursday saying the settlement was fair. <PERSON> Godfrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Dillard </PERSON>, an attorney who represents a group of black <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> employees challenging the settlement, said the appeal will stop implementation of the settlement. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON>, an attorney who negotiated the settlement for the plaintiffs, said the appeal would cost about $ 1 million a year in attorneys' fees.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Wedtech-Garcia     10-13 0445</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wedtech-Garcia,0462</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jury Begins Deliberations In Wedtech Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VERA HALLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal jury began deliberating today whether Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> and his wife extorted payoffs from the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a defunct defense contractor. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Sand </PERSON>, who instructed the jurors Thursday afternoon, told them to begin their discussions at 10:30 a.m. Also Thursday, the panel heard closing arguments from <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>'s lawyer, who said the prosecution did not prove the couple's guilt `` No one was paying off <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Morvillo </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> helped <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> get government contracts because he was a good public official, he said. The lawyer described <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> as a dedicated and honest politician who rose from the ghetto to represent his neighborhood in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> wants nothing more than to go back to the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> and serve his constituents,'' he said. <PERSON> Morvillo </PERSON> said the $ 76,000 that the government contends was funneled by <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> to Mrs. <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>'s consulting firm to pay for <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>'s political influence was for work unrelated to <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION>. A $ 20,000 loan <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> received from the company was `` a loan among friends,'' he said. He claimed <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> asked <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Moreno </PERSON>, the former <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> vice chairman, to make the loan to the congressman's sister, who passed the money on to Mrs. <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, because he knew it would n't look right to take a loan from a constituent. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> members are not required to report loans from family members on their financial disclosure forms, <PERSON> Morvillo </PERSON> said. He noted that the loan was promptly repaid. <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, a 56-year-old Democrat, and his wife, <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, are accused of conspiring to obtain $ 185,000 in checks and interest-free loans, and a diamond and emerald necklace for Mrs. <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, from officials of the now-defunct <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. The couple was charged in a seven-count indictment with conspiracy, extortion, bribery and receipt of illegal gratuities. If convicted of extortion, they face up to 20 years in prison. Their trial is the last of several to stem from the scandal at <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION>, the small <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> machine shop that grew into a multimillion-dollar defense contractor through various bribe schemes. The company collapsed in 1986 amid allegations of corruption. <PERSON> Morvillo </PERSON> attacked the credibility of <PERSON> Moreno </PERSON>, the government's key witness `` Did <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Moreno </PERSON> lie in this case? Yes,'' <PERSON> Morvillo </PERSON> said. `` He lied about everything that would incriminate these people.'' <PERSON> Moreno </PERSON> pleaded guilty to theft - and bribe-related charges in 1987 and testified at other <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> trials In the prosecution's rebuttal which followed <PERSON> Morvillo </PERSON>'s arguments, Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Little </PERSON> denied the defense's argument that the prosecution presented a one-witness case He said 27 other witnesses and 500 documents corroborated <PERSON> Moreno </PERSON>'s testimony.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w BC-BushText 3rdAdd   10-13 0725</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 3rd Add,720</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> WASHINGTON </LOCATION>: <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>, right? A. I'm not ruling out anything in that regard. I am ruling in capital gains. But, I'm not suggesting that by answering the question that way, that we go off on a _ that this is some instruction to our side in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to do something different on <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>. Yeah? Q. I want to go back to what you called your critics `` stupid argument'' about <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. A. That one argument is the one I _ not all the other critics _ Q. You've said since the beginning of the year that you thought <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> should go. A. Yes. Q, And you've said so loudly and publicly. But when push came to shove a few weeks ago, it was n't clear that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> did very much to lend a hand. A. Right. Q. So the question is, is it responsible or consistent to, on the one hand, call publicly for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s ouster, but then to do nothing? A. Yes. Absolutely. Totally consistent. I want to see him out of there and I want to see him brought to justice. And that should not imply that that automatically means, no matter what the plan is or no matter what the coup attempt is or what the effort is, diplomatically and anything else, that we give carte blanche support to that. Follow-on. Q. Some people would say you do n't have to give carte blanche support to all situations like that, but you have to lend a hand _ A To the support that we did n't, yeah. In other words, what they're trying to argue _ look, let's be fair with each other. What they're saying is _ and it's only a handful of critics _ `` You said you wanted <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> out. You say you have no argument with the PDF. An element tries to get him out. And you did n't support him.'' And I'm saying, yes, I want him out, and yes, we have no argument with the PDF. But I am not going to give carte blanche support to an operation, particularly when they do n't ask for the support.'' And I have to reserve that right. I have at stake the lives of American kids. And I am not going to easily thrust them into a battle unless I feel comfortable with it, unless those general officers in whom I have total confidence have _ feel comfortable. So, my argument is with the `` argument.'' My argument is with the argument that when I say, you know, I'd like to see <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> out, that that means carte blanche commitment on my part of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> force. I'm not going to do that. Yeah. These two. Q. Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> LA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> is reporting today that the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has given the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> the go ahead to arrest fugitives in foreign countries without the foreign country's consent. Now, this reverses the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> administration's policy. Can you tell us what led up to this event, and perhaps what _ A. No. I'm _ Q. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has to do with that, because he's a fugitive? The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> can go into <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> now. A. I'm embarrassed to say I do n't know what it is your _ I'll have to get back to you with the answer to your question <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON>, will you take care of that? <PERSON> MR. </PERSON> <PERSON> FITZWATER </PERSON>: I'm not sure that's happened. A. I do n't know what it _ I've not seen the <ORGANIZATION> LA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> report, so I'll just have to not comment until I do Q. Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, your explanation of why you did not back the coup seemed to imply that it would almost have to be an American operation and an American-planned operation before you would use American troops. Is that a misreading of what you've said? A. A little bit, yeah. A little bit. Q. Well, could you explain by what you _ I'm only a little bit off? A. Yeah, just a hair, because if the circumstances under this coup plan had been different, the requests had been different and the facts on the ground had been different in terms of what we knew, we might well have done something different. So I _ is that helpful? Q I'm not sure. I have one other question on <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, if I may. A. Have two, come on.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891013-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-13-89 1134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w BC-BushText 4thAdd   10-13 0715</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 4th Add,700</SECOND>
<TEXT>
