<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-EndangeredSturgeons     03-06 0388</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Endangered Sturgeons,0399</SECOND>
<HEAD>Large Dam Killing Off Chinese Sturgeons</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Chinese sturgeon, a 10-foot ocean fish, is in danger of extinction because a <LOCATION> Yangtze </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> dam is blocking it from the breeding grounds it has used for 300 million years, an official newspaper reported today. The <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> Daily said the number of mature Chinese sturgeons, known scientifically as <PERSON> Acipenser </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinensis </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, has fallen to 5,000 and at least 400 are being killed each year. There are even fewer of the smaller white sturgeon, it said. The fish, which weigh between 330 and 550 pounds when they lay eggs, are unable to reach their breeding grounds in the upper reaches of the Yangtze because of the newly completed <ORGANIZATION> Gezhouba </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dam </ORGANIZATION> in central <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Hubei </LOCATION> province. The dam, under construction since 1974 and partially operating since 1981, prevents the fish from reaching 19 of their 20 breeding grounds 1,800 miles upstream in the <LOCATION> Jinsha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> Yangtze </LOCATION> tributary. The dam builders originally agreed to put in a passageway for the fish around the dam, but abandoned the idea because of the expense. Every year, about 30 dead sturgeons are found at the base of the dam. The newspaper quoted <PERSON> Ke </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuen </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Yangtze </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> River </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aquatic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, as saying female sturgeons reach maturity at age 13 or 14, when they begin their 20-month journey into <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s largest river. Because the fish eat nothing while they are in the river, they are exhausted by the trip and are not ready to breed again for four or five years. An average sturgeon, he said, lays about 18 pounds of eggs, or about 450,000 fry. But 80 percent are eaten by other fish and most of the young sturgeon do not survive their six-month journey to the sea. <PERSON> Ke </PERSON> said about 370 sturgeon a year are caught at the mouth of the river by fishermen unaware the fish is now under state protection. Ke's institute, which has a budget of only $ 6,750 a year for sturgeon research, is now trying artificial breeding to save the fish from extinction. It has been putting about 350,000 sturgeon fry into the river a year. The dam, with a designed capacity of 2.7 million kilowatts, will supply 20 percent of the central <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> network's electricity when it is fully operating.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Africa-Film     03-06 0168</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Africa-Film,0173</SECOND>
<HEAD>English-Language Movie Wins For First Time</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OUAGADOUGOU, Burkina Faso (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An English-language movie won the grand prize in the Pan African Film Festival for the first time in the event's 20-year history. The filmmaker called on African governments to do more for the medium. The film, `` Heritage of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'' was made by <PERSON> Ghanaian </PERSON> <PERSON> Kwah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ansah </PERSON> and recounts the story of a Ghanaian civil servant who discovers while moving up in the administrative system the British set in place in <LOCATION> Ghana </LOCATION> that he has lost all cultural bearings. Previous winners of the film prize have been in African languages or French. The prize, awarded Saturday night, includes about $ 13,000, twice that given to the 1987 winner. The film also won the Organization of African Unity prize. <PERSON> Ansah </PERSON> said he will use the money to pay bills incurred in making the film, and added that it would be his last. `` It is about time African governments saw the importance of filmmaking and try to help filmmakers.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-CarnabyStreet     03-06 0881</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Carnaby Street,0905</SECOND>
<HEAD>London's Carnaby Street, Symbol Of Swinging Sixties, Goes Yuppie</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EDITH M. LEDERER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Carnaby Street, which soared to fame as the fashion pacesetter for Beatles generation of the Swinging Sixties, is seeking a new incarnation as a mecca for stylish yuppies of the 1980s. When <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Quant </PERSON>'s miniskirts and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON>'s bell-bottom hip-huggers clothed the flower children, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> became the fashion capital of the world and Carnaby Street the favorite haunt of the Mods and Rockers. For about a decade, young people from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION> flocked to boutiques called <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Cat </PERSON>, Take 6, and Lord <PERSON> John </PERSON> to buy the latest in hot pants, platform shoes, wide floral ties and psychedelic shirts. But as styles changed and rents soared in the early 1970s, <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> and other designers moved out and Carnaby Street took on a tacky down-market flavor. The street remains a microcosm of English fashion over the last 20 years: Shoppers can buy the'60s Mod look,'70s hippie and ethnic fashions and'80s punk leather and sado-masochistic gear including studded leather belts, Sex Pistols T-shirts and neo-fascist and Nazi-symbol buttons. Now the <ORGANIZATION> Peachey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Property </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, the private real estate company that owns about three-quarters of <LOCATION> Carnaby </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>, wants to restore some fashion magnetism to the two-block thoroughfare tucked behind <ORGANIZATION> Regent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> in the heart of central <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. `` We're not trying to revive the'60s,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Bourne </PERSON>, <PERSON> Peachey </PERSON>'s surveyor for Carnaby Street. `` What we are aiming to do in <LOCATION> Carnaby </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION> is cater to the better-off young market, the 15-30 age group who, like the young kids in the'60s, had no shops catering to them, especially in central <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>.'' Over the last two years, <PERSON> Peachey </PERSON> has replaced about half of the shops that sold this fashion mish-mash with branches of pricier, fashion chains like <ORGANIZATION> Benetton </ORGANIZATION>, Supreme, <LOCATION> Capricorn </LOCATION>, Confetti and Midas. The Nazi-insignia merchants have proved such an embarrassment that the two main stores, on an alley off <LOCATION> Carnaby </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>, are being forced out of business under pressure from <PERSON> Peachey </PERSON>, Westminster borough authorities and anti-fascist campaigners. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Quant </PERSON>, who worked out of the King's <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Chelsea </LOCATION> in the 1960s, has opened her first shop on Carnaby Street, selling makeup and accessories. She said she was lured by the revival of the surrounding <LOCATION> Soho </LOCATION> area as a center for young people and young industries. <PERSON> Bourne </PERSON> hopes the whole street eventually will be yuppified with wine bars, restaurants and art galleries. `` It does take a long time to move a whole area around,'' he said in an interview. `` Not only do we have to change tenents, but we have to tell the world this area has changed.'' Last June, <PERSON> Peachey </PERSON> relaunched Carnaby Street with balloons, 20,000 leaflets and the message that it was now `` synonymous with chic and stylish <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>.'' This year, it hopes to start regular street theater and entertainment and stage fashion and art shows. Knitwear designer <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> Foale </PERSON>, who moved into <LOCATION> Carnaby </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION> in the early 1960s and did clothes for the Beatles, remembers when it was a quaint backwater where you could get a saddle mended. `` Now, it's beginning to come up again,'' she said. `` But it's always different ... The next Carnaby Street will have its own incarnation.'' But many shoppers, designers and storekeepers mourn the Carnaby Street they say is gone forever. `` It's an interesting historic relic. It's where it all started,'' said Los Angeles-born Giffi Fields, who started selling hand-painted, made-to-measure men's clothes to Carnaby Street shops in the late 1960s. `` Carnaby Street was a one-off -LRB- one-of-a-kind area -RRB- at its time because it was a street devoted to youth culture,'' he said. `` Every major city in the world today does n't have only one street, but many streets devoted to youth culture. So you just do n't get the uniqueness anymore and you wo n't get the uniqueness.'' At <LOCATION> Inderwick </LOCATION>'s pipe shop, a Carnaby Street landmark for at least 70 years and the only store left from the 1960s, owner <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> doubted <PERSON> Peachey </PERSON> would succeed because the street is getting the same stores as dozens of other shopping areas in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. `` Most shops are multiple or franchises. Not one shop has individual character except The Great Frog, because they make their own jewelry,'' said the 64-year-old businessman. `` I ca n't see it ever becoming what they're aiming for. It's still a street without any character. Shopkeepers at both ends of the market are unhappy with Carnaby Street's current clientele. Those at the top said the street was still attracting the same customers it did in 1975 _ young people looking for cheap clothes. But those at the bottom complained that the punks, Mods, skinheads and hippies had gone and the street was attracting too many straight people in suits. Potential shoppers wandering along the street recently were also unimpressed. `` It's just like a pedestrian walkway with tacky shops on either side,'' complained <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sawkins </PERSON>, 30, a student and motorcycle courier. `` It's just a tourist trap. Most people from <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> would n't come here.'' <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>, 20, a student from <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION>, said: `` It's gone downhill. It's too respectable now. The businessmen have taken over. It tries to be anarchic and anti-establishment, but it does it all commercially so it's not unique.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0010EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-BRF--LiquorDeaths 2ndLd-Writethru a0706 03-06 0384</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Liquor Deaths, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0706,0388</SECOND>
<HEAD>100 Die After Drinking Homemade Liquor</HEAD>
<UNK>Eds: UPDATES thruout with at least 100 people reported dead, 200 fighting
for their lives. No pickup.</UNK>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At least 100 people, most of them poor laborers, died and more than 200 others were battling for their lives after drinking homemade liquor in the western city of <LOCATION> Baroda </LOCATION>, news reports said Monday. Press Trust of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and said at least 100 of the 251 people hospitalized after drinking the illicit brew Saturday were in critical condition. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> said survival chances were bleak for virtually all the patients. Both news agencies said the death toll was at least 100 and was expected to rise. The mass poisoning in <LOCATION> Gujarat </LOCATION>, the only Indian state where sale of alcohol is banned, was the country's worst known liquor poisoning case, the news agencies said. Many victims are likely to go blind if they live, doctors treating the patients said, according to <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION>. Press Trust quoted doctors as saying some of the victims could have been saved if they had sought treatment earlier. It said many victims became dizzy and fell into stupors after drinking the illegal brew in the city 560 miles southwest of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> said police arrested three people who had supplied the liquor. A son of one supplier and the son of a prominent local politician were among those killed by the poisonous brew, it said. <LOCATION> Gujarat </LOCATION>'s chief minister, <PERSON> Amarsinh </PERSON> <PERSON> Chaudhary </PERSON>, ordered an investigation and promised `` drastic action'' against the police officials who failed to avert the tragedy, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> reported. The newspaper said most of the victims were poor laborers who bought the liquor Saturday morning after receiving their monthly wages. The first deaths were reported about midnight Saturday, it added. As news of the first deaths emerged, police fanned out across <LOCATION> Baroda </LOCATION> with loudspeakers blaring warnings that anyone who had consumed the liquor should seek medical help immediately. The liquor, known locally as `` lattha,'' is made from industrial spirits and methyl alcohol. About 300 people have died in about seven illicit liquor tragedies in <LOCATION> Gujarat </LOCATION> during the last decade, <ORGANIZATION> UNI </ORGANIZATION> said. Two of the previous cases occurred in <LOCATION> Baroda </LOCATION>, with others reported in <LOCATION> Ahmedabad </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Surat </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0257EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-RushdieDebate     03-06 0731</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rushdie Debate,0753</SECOND>
<HEAD>Second Thoughts And Gritted Teeth On `The Satanic Verses'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BARR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 No one in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> outside of the Moslem community has endorsed the Iranian death sentence against <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>, but some are supporting the author of `` The Satanic Verses'' through gritted teeth. `` An insidious outbreak of ` yes-but' has entered the public debate on the rights and rightness of his case,'' the Observer newspaper said in an editorial Sunday. The debate even popped up at a Writers' Day conference organized by British Pen, the association of poets, essayist and novelists. Most wrote supportive greetings to <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> in a book that was left open for messages, but one entry said: `` Personal freedom is constrained by personal responsibility. You are shown to be wanting in the latter.'' Below it, another writer asserted: `` Freedom is freedom. It does not imply restraint.'' The liberal Observer said it was disturbed by statements by Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> and Foreign Secretary Sir <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> last week that the book was offensive, and by the opinion of Lord <PERSON> Jakobovits </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s chief rabbi, that such books should be banned. They are not alone in their criticisms. `` Mr. <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>'s life has to be defended at all costs, but not necessarily his book,'' The <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION>, a conservative newspaper, said in an editorial last week. A cartoon in The Sunday Express showed <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> dressed like <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, with a flowing beard of pound notes labeled `` my royalties,'' and threatening the foreign secretary. `` Blasphemy, Sir <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON>,'' the caption said. `` I shall call upon the authors of the world to spear you with their pens.'' <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> has been in hiding since Feb. 14, when <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> sentenced him to death. Iranian clergymen have offered a bounty of as much as $ 5.2 million. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said Saturday that <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> still insists <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> repudiate the death sentence before diplomatic relations can be normalized. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> has withdrawn its diplomats from <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>. The Majlis, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s legislature, has set Tuesday as a deadline for breaking diplomatic relations unless <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> `` clarifies'' its position on the book. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s official news agency said Sunday that `` the withdrawal of all copies of ` The Satanic Verses' and banning of its reprinting by the <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> government would certainly bring <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> closer to the implementation of the Iranian conditions.'' Many of those in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> who criticize the book stop short of calling for it to be banned. <PERSON> Hartley </PERSON> <PERSON> Shawcross </PERSON>, a prominent attorney and a former chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, wrote to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> had committed `` a deplorable abuse of the freedom which he shares with the rest of us, but which we must nonetheless defend.'' `` The <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> book has done incalculable harm to the interests of all people, not with any intention of contribution to scholarship but in order to sensationalize a novel in the hope of securing its better sale,'' <PERSON> Shawcross </PERSON> wrote. In its editorial, The Telegraph said that `` free speech to some degree depends on responsibility in exercising it.'' `` A civilized society is unwise to insist that all abuses of freedom of expression within the law, regardless of the damage done, form part of the ark of the covenant and so are sacrosanct,'' the newspaper said. <PERSON> Auberon </PERSON> <PERSON> Waugh </PERSON>, fuming over <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>'s past criticisms of British imperialism and racial prejudice, wrote in The Spectator magazine: `` Perhaps the real debate is not so much whether <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> should be executed ... but just how much we should exert ourselves, as deeply stained white imperialists, to protect him from his own people.'' `` I really do not think it unreasonable in the circumstance of <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>'s having made several million pounds through insulting <ORGANIZATION> Islam </ORGANIZATION>, to suggest that he should pay for any police protection he may judge advisable,'' said <PERSON> Waugh </PERSON>, a columnist for The Spectator and The Sunday Telegraph. A letter to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> from <PERSON> Jeremy </PERSON> <PERSON> Treglown </PERSON>, editor of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Literary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supplement </ORGANIZATION>, argued that <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>'s critics might want a broader revision of the literary canon. `` <PERSON> Milton </PERSON>'s pamphlets and <PERSON> Dryden </PERSON>'s and Pope's satires, which caused deep and violent feeling in those they attacked, should obviously have been toned down. Many readers have been made uncomfortable by the moral insights of <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Austen </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Dickens </LOCATION> _ clear cases for sensitive editing,'' <PERSON> Treglown </PERSON> wrote. `` Would n't we be easier in our minds if there were no books at all?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0205EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-No1City     03-06 1170</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-No 1 City,1203</SECOND>
<HEAD>City Ratings Inspire Elation, Indignation And Fascination</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LISA LEVITT RYCKMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP National Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Alphabetically speaking, <LOCATION> Yuba </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, was used to being last on lists. But catching the caboose in Rand McNally's `` Places Rated Almanac'' four years ago insulted residents right down to their toes. At first, they fumed, they raged, they stamped their collective civic feet. Then they got smart. City leaders decided `` there are only two places to be on the list: the top _ and the bottom,'' said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Knapp </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Yuba-Sutter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> executive vice president. `` It depends what you make of both of them.'' What <LOCATION> Yuba </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Citians </LOCATION> made from last place was a heap of first-rate public relations hay. In the 50 years since one <PERSON> E.L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thorndike </PERSON> created his `` goodness index'' for <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> cities, academicians, special interest groups, magazines and the federal government have cranked out a plethora of rankings identifying the best of all possible towns. Stressed out? Live in <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, says one survey; <ORGANIZATION> Cedar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rapids </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, says another. Best place for a hip, contemporary career woman? <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, Savvy magazine says. Easiest place to make friends? <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Forbes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION> says. No. 1 overall? It's <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, says one survey; <LOCATION> Danbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, says another. In a nation where everybody loves the underdog but nobody wants to be one, where everyone says it does n't matter what other people think but no one believes it, city ratings have become a source of indignation, elation, frustration and, always, fascination. Now, it's almost time for another edition of `` Places Rated,'' the most objective and carefully researched of the bunch. Like the presidential election, it appears every four years _ and a lot of people do n't like the results. The fallout has included threatened lawsuits, map and magazine burnings and, on a number of occasions, campaigns for civic improvements. But ask researchers, city officials and municipal groups what city rankings mean, and how seriously to take them, and the answers seem to be not much, and not very. `` There's no best city, just like there's no best work of art,'' said <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Sperling </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, computer researcher who, despite that opinion, created software that rates cities. `` Who's to say <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON>'s ` Sunflower' is better than -LRB- da <PERSON> Vinci </PERSON>'s -RRB- ` The Last Supper'?'' And who's to say there are 328 better places to live than <LOCATION> Yuba </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>? Why, `` Places Rated'' authors <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Savageau </PERSON> and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyer </PERSON>, that's who. When <LOCATION> Yuba </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> leaders reflected on how to make the best out of being the worst, they decided to lighten up. `` If you screamed and ranted and raved, you made a fool of yourself,'' <PERSON> Knapp </PERSON> said. `` We decided to make a fun thing of it.'' First, 1,000 residents burned hundreds of Rand McNally maps at a community pep rally, packaged the ashes in a walnut box and had a local mortician present them to a Rand <PERSON> McNally </PERSON> vice president, who flew out from <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> just for the occasion. Then the city helped a radio station in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> _ rated No. 1 in the same survey _ award an all-expense paid trip to <LOCATION> Yuba </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> as a contest prize. The happy winners toured the city by limousine and rode a float in the 105th Annual Bok-Kai Festival. A good time was had by all. And at year's end, when <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION> wrapped up 1985, it was <LOCATION> Yuba </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, not <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, that received a full page. `` And they spelled the name right,'' <PERSON> Knapp </PERSON> mused, a little amazed. It took `` Places Rated'' to not only rocket <LOCATION> Yuba </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> out of obscurity but to propel the metro ratings game onto the best-seller list. The idea sprang from the authors' desire to move out of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and their discovery that there was no single source for good, solid data on life in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cities. They decided to compile a comprehensive American cities reference guide, and sold Rand <PERSON> McNally </PERSON> on the idea in 1978. The first edition, with <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> at the top and <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, in the cellar, came out in 1981. More than 300,000 book sales later, <PERSON> Savageau </PERSON> says he's a bit disappointed that the book is considered more the topic of cocktail party chitchat than the serious reference tool the authors intended, and he acknowledges its popularity still baffles him. `` I would n't go out and buy a book that said <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> was the best place in the country,'' he said, taking a rare break from his computer and the latest edition of `` Places Rated,'' due out this fall from <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Schuster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which acquired the series last year from Rand McNally. When the statistics laid the exalted mantel of extreme livability on <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, a city once known as `` hell with the lid off,'' even <PERSON> Rand </PERSON> <PERSON> McNally </PERSON> did n't believe it at first. The crowning of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> illustrates the key difference between `` Places Rated'' and other city rankings. The Savageau-Boyer study gives equal weight to climate, housing, crime, transportation, health care, recreation, education, the arts and economics. That might tend to give an edge to larger cities, which have more amenities, and does n't take into account which factors people think are most important. Other studies tend to focus on one aspect of life, such relief from stress _ which the advocacy group Zero Population Growth found in <LOCATION> Cedar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rapids </LOCATION> and a study in Psychology Today magazine found in State College. Or they consider the preferences of a specific group of people, as Money magazine does, polling 251 subscribers. In its 1987 survey, <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> was 43rd; <LOCATION> Nashua </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>, was No. 1. Last year, <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> moved to No. 20; <LOCATION> Danbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, was top of the heap. A change from one year to the next in what the subscribers consider most important _ say, education over leisure, or transportation over weather _ plus even a small shift in a city's vital statistics can account for a wild fluctuation, said <PERSON> Sperling </PERSON>, whose company, <ORGANIZATION> Fast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forward </ORGANIZATION>, has created a computer program called `` Places U.S.A.'' used by Money `` Some of the cities that have been disappointingly rated have used it to say, ` Oh, yeah?,' and show they have a strong community support base,'' said <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Arndt </PERSON>, spokesman for the National League of Cities. `` It depends on the resourcefulness of the city.'' The league would n't dream of ranking its 1,400 members. `` I do n't know who these surveys benefit, except the authors Everybody does n't live in the perfect place, but it's home to us,'' <PERSON> Arndt </PERSON> said. `` Whether you live in <LOCATION> Scarsdale </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Saginaw </LOCATION>, life is what you make of it.'' The same can be said of city ratings. In the next `` Places Rated,'' <PERSON> Savageau </PERSON> and <PERSON> Boyer </PERSON> plan a section designed to make everyone happy by showing how under certain conditions, using factors in the book, any burg can be a <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. `` For instance, if the only thing you're interested in are cities in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> with a moderate climate and low cost of living,'' <PERSON> Savageau </PERSON> said, `` <LOCATION> Yuba </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> would be the best place in the whole country.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AssaultWeapons     03-06 0779</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Assault Weapons,0802</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gun Lobby Fights Legislative Assaults On Semiautomatic Rifles</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID FOSTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Outrage over a schoolyard massacre led five <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> cities to ban semiautomatic rifles, but legislative attacks on so-called assault weapons elsewhere in the nation are facing stiff opposition from gun advocates. Bills to ban or restrict military-style assault rifles have surfaced or are planned for introduction in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, 11 states and at least a dozen cities following the Jan. 17 shooting spree at an elementary school in <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. Five children died, and 29 others and a teacher were injured, when drifter <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> opened fire with an AK-47 assault rifle on a crowded playground He fired 106 bullets in two minutes, and then killed himself. The shock and anger that erupted, combined with concerns over the mounting use of assault weapons by drug gangs, prompted bans in the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> cities of <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Compton </LOCATION>. Outside <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> has banned the weapons. But elsewhere, the outrage seems to be losing some of its persuasive power. Bills to ban or restrict assault weapons have died in the <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> legislatures; in <LOCATION> Hutchinson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Summit </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. In <PERSON> Hutchinson </PERSON>, city commissioners rejected a ban on assault rifles after facing an angry crowd of 150, only one of whom spoke in favor of the ban. The issue has revived familiar gun-control arguments. One side says the bloodshed must stop, while the other says <LOCATION> Americans </LOCATION> have a constitutional right to own guns. `` We think <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is tired of picking up the newspaper or watching TV and seeing kids and police officers lying in pools of blood,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Scutt </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriffs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. `` We share the grief of the tragedy in <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>,'' said <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> lobbyist <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>. `` But the answer does not lie in restricting the rights of law-abiding citizens. The answer lies in getting the criminal off the street.'' The <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> has challenged the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> cities' bans in court, arguing that only the Legislature has the power to regulate firearms in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. The biggest legislative battles are still to come. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is considering four bills to ban or restrict assault weapons. Bills are pending or expected to be introduced in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. Debate on all the bills focuses on how to define assault rifles. An automatic weapon, or machine gun, fires bullets as long as the trigger is pulled. A federal permit is needed to own one. Semiautomatic rifles, which can be bought over the counter in nearly all states, fire one bullet for each pull of the trigger but do not need to be cocked or loaded between pulls. Most states allow such rifles in hunting but usually limit the size of the ammunition magazine, or clip. Distinguishing assault rifles such as the Soviet-designed AK-47 from semiautomatic hunting rifles can be difficult. `` They all function the same way,'' said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alcohol </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tobacco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Firearms </ORGANIZATION>. `` All that changes is you take off the wood stock and put on a plastic or metal folding stock, or you put on a banana clip, rather than a small hunting clip, or you put on a bayonet.'' Some legislation would ban specific brands of guns, but the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> argues that is useless. `` The AK-47 this year will be the AR-48 next year, and they'd be out from under the regulation,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. While the debate bogs down in detail, the issue remains clear to <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Geng </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Stockton </PERSON> teacher whose leg has a hole `` the size of a grapefruit'' from <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON>'s shooting spree. `` These people against a ban _ I'd like to have had them standing out there next to me,'' she said. `` I do n't believe there is any reason for that type of weapon to exist in our society.'' <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> said imports of AK-47s, which at $ 250 to $ 350 are among the cheapest assault rifles, have increased tenfold in the past four years. More than 40,000 were imported during the 14 months ending Nov. 30, he said. If anything, <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> said, debate over banning assault rifles has boosted sales. Demand is reported especially high in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. And when a store in <LOCATION> Menomonee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, ran a `` get'em - before-you-ca n't'' sale on AK-47s, it sold out and had to order 150 In <PERSON> Stockton </PERSON>, meanwhile, police are relying on the honesty of gun owners to turn in their now illegal semiautomatic rifles. They've received seven
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> is the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> regional reporter, based in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-USMoslems     03-06 0924</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US Moslems,0947</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Moslems Struggle To Break Into American Religious Mainstream</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRIGGS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Islam may surpass <ORGANIZATION> Judaism </ORGANIZATION> as the nation's largest minority religion by the turn of the century, but American Moslems still are struggling to find their place in a nation that has long defined itself as `` Protestant, Catholic, Jewish.'' The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> publication of <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>'s `` The Satanic Verses'' _ a novel some consider blasphemous _ is to many of the nation's estimated 3.5 million Moslems only the latest example of how acceptable anti-Moslem prejudice has become in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> `` The eight years they lived under <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> were not easy years. The enemy moved from being the ` evil empire' of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to <ORGANIZATION> Islam </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> Yvonne </PERSON> <PERSON> Haddad </PERSON>, a professor of Islamic history at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Amherst </LOCATION>. `` I've seen the prejudice. It's almost American to bash Islam.'' Nor has their exclusion from the American religious landscape ended with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s departure, according to Moslem leaders. There were neither Moslem participants nor any mention of Islam at an interfaith <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prayer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> after President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s inauguration `` We felt a bit insulted but blamed it on their ignorance rather than discourtesies,'' said <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Mehdi </PERSON>, a co-chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interfaith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> and secretary general of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> on Islamic Affairs. The service was organized by a National Day of Prayer and Thanksgiving committee. Ever since interfaith support was drummed up for World War I, with <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Jewish </PERSON> leaders showing unprecedented cooperation, the portrait of the nation as consisting of three basic faiths has been implanted in the public mind. Moslems have settled in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> since the 19th century, but tremendous growth did not take place until the 1960s and 1970s when relaxed immigration rules and a jump in Islamic students related to the oil boom coincided with a movement by blacks to <ORGANIZATION> Islam </ORGANIZATION>. No one knows how many Moslems there are in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> _ estimates range from 2 million to 10 million _ but many scholars and religious leaders say <PERSON> Haddad </PERSON>'s estimate of between 3 million and 4 million is the most reliable. If that estimate is correct, there are more Moslems in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> than two of the nation's most influential denominations, the 3 million-member Presbyterian Church -LRB- U.S.A. -RRB- and the 2.5 million-member <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. Because of higher rates of immigration, births and conversions among Moslems, there also is substantial agreement with <PERSON> Haddad </PERSON>'s assessment that if current demographic trends continue the nation's Moslem population will be larger than the Jewish population `` possibly by 2000, definitely by 2015 The nation's Jewish population is estimated at 5.9 million. But growing numbers have not meant growing respect for Moslems, who still must contend with public perceptions of them ranging from `` camel jockeys'' to more dangerous stereotypes fostered by American anger over <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. `` The amazing thing about it is that they persist so perversely,'' said <PERSON> Marston </PERSON> <PERSON> Speight </PERSON>, director of the Office of Christian-Moslem Relations for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Churches </ORGANIZATION>. `` Everywhere I go, no matter what I say, people always come up with the stereotype of Islam being a fanatically aggressive type of religion.'' <PERSON> Speight </PERSON> said the ethical principles of peace and mercy in the Koran, the sacred book of Moslems, `` simply belie the negative, militant, violent image.'' He said violent acts committed in the name of <ORGANIZATION> Islam </ORGANIZATION> have parallels in Christian history, but `` morally and ethically, Islam and Christianity and Judaism are on common ground.'' Many religious groups have made improved relations with Moslems a priority. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Borrelli </PERSON>, executive secretary of the Office for Interreligious Relations of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>, said Catholic-Moslem dialogue is going on in cities such as <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and he expects more meetings and discussions nationally. Rabbi <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudin </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jewish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> said the `` the test of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> religion in the 21st century'' will be its ability to integrate other religious groups such as Moslems. `` If we fail, if we can not have a mutually respectful society, then we can end up with religious, sectarian strife, and <PERSON> God </PERSON> forbid,'' he said, adding that his organization has increased efforts to have contacts with Moslems. <PERSON> Mehdi </PERSON> said that with the exception of unofficial, isolated letters from Christian fundamentalists who label Moslems `` heathens,'' the `` overwhelming number of established religions have been supportive.'' But discrimination persists, he and others contend. <PERSON> Haddad </PERSON> said since 1985, mosques have been bombed in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>, and others have been desecrated. The publication of `` The Satanic Verses'' `` showed Moslems are not perceived as being part and parcel of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> society, and are misunderstood,'' said <PERSON> Brother </PERSON> <PERSON> Ihsan </PERSON> <PERSON> Babgy </PERSON>, education director for the <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Plainfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> has said the book is a work of fiction that was not intended to offend anyone. Viking Penguin, the book's <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> publisher, has said its position is `` freedom of speech, freedom to publish and freedom to read must be guaranteed internationally.'' But the turmoil caused by the book may have long-term benefits for American Moslems, according to officials here. `` The atmosphere has changed remarkably in recent times. This whole issue of ` Satanic Verses' is pushing us together more,'' <PERSON> Babgy </PERSON> said. `` I think there is a clear and dramatic unification of Moslems in this country.'' Since the controversy developed, <PERSON> Mehdi </PERSON> said, his office has received about 20 calls from people who used obscene language to express their point of view, and four times as many calls from people wanting to find out more about Islam.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-History 1stLd-Writethru b0233 03-06 0581</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-History, 1st Ld - Writethru, b0233,0598</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: In BC-History, sent in advance as b0233 for use today, CORRECTS
graf starting `In 1983, in a case,' four sted two convicted.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Today In History</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Today is Monday, March 6, the 65th day of 1989. There are 300 days left in the year. Today's Highlight in History: On March 6, 1836, the <LOCATION> Alamo </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, fell to Mexican forces after a 13-day siege. All 187 defenders of the mission compound _ including <PERSON> Davy </PERSON> <PERSON> Crockett </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowie </PERSON> _ were killed. On this date: In 1806, poet <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> <PERSON> Browning </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Durham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. In 1834, the city of <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Upper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> was incorporated as <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>. In 1853, <PERSON> Verdi </PERSON>'s opera `` La Traviata'' premiered in <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. In 1857, in its `` Dred Scott'' decision, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> held that <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, a slave, could not sue for his freedom in a federal court. In 1933, a nationwide bank holiday declared by President <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> went into effect. In 1935, retired <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> died in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. In 1944, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bombers staged a daylight raid against <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> during World War II. In 1957, the former British African colonies of the <ORGANIZATION> Gold </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Togoland </LOCATION> became the independent state of <LOCATION> Ghana </LOCATION>. In 1967, the daughter of <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Svetlana </PERSON> <PERSON> Alliluyeva </PERSON>, appeared at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and announced her intention to defect to the West. In 1981, <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON> signed off for the last time as anchorman of `` The CBS Evening News.'' In 1982, author-philosopher Ayn Rand died in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> at age 77. In 1983, in a case that drew much notoriety, a woman in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, said she had been gang-raped atop a pool table in a tavern called Big Dan's. Four men were later convicted in connection with the case. In 1983, the pro-environment, anti-nuclear `` Greens'' party won seats in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s lower house of parliament for the first time. In 1987, 189 people died when water rushed through the open bow doors of the `` Herald of Free Enterprise,'' causing the British ferry to capsize off the Belgian port of <LOCATION> Zeebrugge </LOCATION>. Ten years ago: A jury was empaneled in <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> in the case of nuclear plant worker <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Silkwood </PERSON>, who was contaminated with plutonium through what <PERSON> Silkwood </PERSON>'s family charged was the negligence of her employer, <ORGANIZATION> Kerr-McGee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, shortly before her death in a 1974 car crash. Although the jury ruled against <ORGANIZATION> Kerr-McGee </ORGANIZATION>, an appeals court in 1985 ordered a re-trial. Five years ago: Democratic presidential hopeful <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> won <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>'s preference vote by a wide margin over <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>, following victories over <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary and <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> caucuses. One year ago: The board of trustees at <ORGANIZATION> Gallaudet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, the world's only liberal arts college for the deaf, chose a hearing woman, <PERSON> Elisabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Zinser </PERSON>, school president over two deaf candidates. Outraged students shut down the campus, forcing <PERSON> Zinser </PERSON>'s ouster and the selection of a deaf president in her place. Today's Birthdays: TV personality <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> McMahon </PERSON> is 66. Conductor <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Caldwell </PERSON> is 65. <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> is 65. The chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON>, is 63. The first woman in space, Soviet cosmonaut <PERSON> Valentina </PERSON> <PERSON> Tereshkova </PERSON>, is 52. Actor <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> is 47. Opera singer <PERSON> Dame </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiri </PERSON> <PERSON> Te </PERSON> <PERSON> Kanawa </PERSON> is 45. Actor-director <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Reiner </PERSON> is 42. Thought for Today: `` Caveat actor.'' Let the doer beware. _ Latin proverb.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0223EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-AfghanDrugs Bjt   03-06 0596</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Afghan Drugs, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officials View Afghan Drug Situation With Concern</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials are concerned that <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, already a principal opium producer, could become an even greater source of illicit narcotics in the wake of the Soviet troop withdrawal. `` <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> ... worries everyone who is interested in this issue,'' said <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Wrobleski </PERSON>, the assistant secretary of state for narcotics affairs. Ms. <PERSON> Wrobleski </PERSON>, in discussing the department's annual narcotics control report, said the problem is likely to be aggravated when the estimated 3 million to 5 million Afghan refugees return to their homeland. In the wake of the destruction caused by the nine-year war against the Soviet occupiers, traditional agriculture has been made nearly impossible in many regions. `` As we see refugees moving back into a war-torn country where there is no strong central government, we see them returning to a fairly easy, quick, profitable means of supporting themselves,'' Ms. <PERSON> Wrobleski </PERSON> said. `` Therefore, the prediction is that output of opium will increase out of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, which then leads to a chain reaction of increased heroin moving through <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>,'' she added. Throughout the opium-producing region that also includes <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION>, `` prospects are not good'' for any reduction in the opium trade in the coming year, Ms. <PERSON> Wrobleski </PERSON> said. With some 700-800 metric tons produced last year, <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> is second only to <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> in opium production in <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, the report said. `` Compounding <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government frustration at increasing worldwide opium supplies is the fact that about 90 percent of the world's opium production takes place in areas in which the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has little or no access _ such as <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>,'' the report said The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> long warned the <ORGANIZATION> Mujahedeen </ORGANIZATION> rebels against producing and smuggling drugs to support their war effort against the Soviets. With the Soviets gone, the rebels are now attempting to overthrow the communist regime of strongman <PERSON> Najibullah </PERSON>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials are concerned that amid a possible struggle among the various rebel factions, narcotics control might not be given a high priority. `` Current agricultural production is roughly half of the prewar level, insufficient to support the existing population, let along the large numbers of returning refugees,'' says <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, a senior policy analyst at the conservative <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> think tank, the <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>. `` Drug production could be a major problem,'' he said in an interview. `` But perhaps I'm just more pessimistic than others.'' Another State Department Afghan expert, who spoke on condition he not be identified by name, said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> must wait for a central government to be formed to start any kind of comprehensive drug eradication or crop substitution program. But he took a more positive approach to the post-Soviet era. The <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> has been involved in a pilot program near the city of <LOCATION> Jalabad </LOCATION>, encouraging farmers to switch from poppy growing to wheat and vegetable production, he said. `` We're pleased with it,'' he said, claiming a `` quite impressive'' success with the local farmers and expressing hopes the pilot program could be used elsewhere once calm is restored. At present, however, cooperation can only be obtained in certain areas where rebel leaders are in control and sympathetic to such an approach, the official said. `` My sense is, the resistance leaders we work with are exceptionally sensitive to this, aware that it is a domestic issue in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' added the official. He predicted that fundamentalist rebel leaders intend `` to apply the rigid tenets of Islam'' and police drug production if they gain control.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CopCount     03-06 0575</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cop Count,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nearly Half of Police Forces Have Fewer than 10 Officers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Law enforcement is a lonesome job in nearly a thousand <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> communities with one-officer police departments, according to a government study. Although some big cities and counties boast thousands of officers, nearly half of all police and sheriff's departments have fewer than 10 officers, the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> reported on Sunday. Law enforcement agencies ranged in size from 34 police departments and 12 sheriff's offices with more than 1,000 officers apiece to the 987 departments with just one, according to the study, the first detailed statistical analysis of local law enforcement staffing. All state police agencies, 99 percent of sheriff's offices and 97 percent of local police agencies with 135 or more officers require at least a high school diploma, the 1987 study found. A separate analysis of police standards in 1967 found only 70 percent required such a diploma. In fact, the new study found, about 10 percent of the larger police departments and 6 percent of sheriff's operations are now requiring prospective officers to have at least some college education. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report said that overall the nation has 11,989 local police departments, 3,080 sheriff's departments and 49 state police agencies. <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> has no state police, even though such a department was once featured in the television show `` <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> Five-0.'' Nationally, law enforcement agencies had 757,508 employees including 555,364 sworn officers. Of those agencies 52.6 percent of local police departments have fewer than 10 officers and 79 percent have under 25, the report found. Among sheriff's offices, 33.6 percent had under 10 deputies and 67.3 percent had fewer than 25. Thus, of the 15,057 local police and sheriff's agencies, 48.7 percent had fewer than 10 officers. Sheriff's departments led the way in employing women, at 12.5 percent of their sworn deputies, the report found. Women constituted 7.6 percent of local police officers and only 4.2 percent of state troopers. Blacks were more strongly represented on local police departments, making up 9.3 percent of the officers. Sheriff's offices reported 8.3 percent black deputies and state police lagged with 6.5 percent Average annual starting salaries for police officers ranged from $ 13,768 in the smallest departments to $ 23,000 in cities of a million people or more. Local police chiefs were paid salaries of between $ 18,503 and $ 87,044. Salaries and wages accounted for six of every seven dollars spent on police work by governments. Total police spending was $ 28.3 billion. Two-thirds of the departments that have 135 or more officers said they allow collective bargaining. Nationwide, 31.7 percent of police agencies and 28.3 percent of sheriff's departments said they participated in the 911 emergency telephone system. The highest rate was 88 percent for police in cities of between 250,000 and 500,000 people. Sheriff's offices serving communities of under 10,000 reported that only 15.7 percent had the 911 system in use. The responsibilities of the law enforcement agencies vary from place to place in addition to regular peacekeeping functions. Nearly half of the departments are also responsible for animal control in their communities, for example, and one in four handles emergency medical services. Other special functions include court security, handled by 22 percent of the departments; civil defense, 21 percent; civil process serving, 18 percent; jail operation, 12 percent; training academy, 6 percent; drug testing, 4 percent; and ballistics testing, 2 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Homicides-Transplants     03-06 0639</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Homicides-Transplants,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Organs of Homicide Victims Spur Transplants</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LISA M. HAMM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The burgeoning homicide toll in the nation's capital is providing doctors with a new source of organs for transplant `` There's always going to be tragedy and there are going to be fatalities with young people,'' says Dr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Macoviak </PERSON>, medical director of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Regional Transplant Consortium. `` And the one and only clear-cut benefit to society of that, which did n't exist until recently, is the fact that other lives can be saved as the result of these people that lose their lives prematurely.'' The District of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> and neighboring <LOCATION> Prince </LOCATION> <LOCATION> George </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Fairfax </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, each had record homicide rates in 1988. In the district alone, more than 90 people have been killed thus far this year. That is far above the 1988 rate. In the district and Prince <PERSON> George </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, many of the homicides are attributed to drugs. The record homicide rates are `` absolutely'' increasing the number of available organs and tissue for transplant, said <PERSON> Macoviak </PERSON>, who performs heart transplants at the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, the city's largest and most active trauma facility. `` I would say that probably about twice the number of donors are being procured this year as were being procured last year,'' he said. Last August, the consortium received 14 referrals for organ donations. Six months later, the number had risen to 27. In addition to the record homicide rates, the availability of organs for transplants also has been assisted by a <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> law passed in January 1988 requiring that families be asked to donate organs. Victims felled by a single gunshot wound to the head are the most likely candidates for donation because their organs are n't damaged, said <PERSON> Macoviak </PERSON>. When they can, doctors keep gunshot victims alive on a ventilator. But if it's certain the person is brain-dead, hospital and consortium officials ask the bereaved family to donate the victim's organs. `` I'd say the families of drug victims are very supportive as a rule,'' he said. `` They want to donate the organs.'' `` It's solace,'' concurred <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bardi </PERSON>, a consortium executive committee member and assistant administrator at <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's the way they deal with their grief, to know the individual is alive in someone else, to know they've touched someone else. When dealing with homicide victims, hospital staff also must cooperate with homicide detectives and the medical examiner, and these delays sometimes make it impossible to perform transplants, said <PERSON> Macoviak </PERSON>. Tests are run to ensure that the potential donor meets rigid criteria. If there are signs of intravenous drug use or a history of promiscuous homosexuality, transplants are ruled out because of the AIDS risk to potential recipients, doctors said. When doctors are finished removing organs and tissue, the respirator which has kept the victim alive is quietly turned off. As many as 16 people can benefit from a single person's death, receiving the heart, lungs, kidneys, liver and assorted tissue such as bones, eyes and skin, said <PERSON> Macoviak </PERSON>. Recipients for the various organs are chosen from waiting lists and summoned to the hospital within eight hours. About 20 people in this region are waiting for new hearts and are likely to die in less than a year without transplants, said <PERSON> Macoviak </PERSON>. Ninety percent of organs procured in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> area are used for people on waiting lists here. Only those organs for which there's no local match are sent elsewhere. The <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Regional Transplant Consortium was created by six area hospitals in 1986 to pool resources for heart transplantation. It coordinates organ procurement in the metropolitan area and last year was authorized to perform liver transplants. `` It's unfortunate that someone has to die to save another life, but that's the way it is,'' said <PERSON> Bardi </PERSON>. `` It's a cycle.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Dante'sThreat 1stLd-Writethru a0772 03-06 0303</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dante's Threat, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0772,0305</SECOND>
<HEAD>Group Threatens Medieval Poet's Monument For Islam Slight</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf to CORRECT mayor's name</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RAVENNA, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group has threatened to blow up a monument to <PERSON> Dante </PERSON> <PERSON> Alighieri </PERSON> because the medieval poet's famed `` Divine Comedy'' places the prophet <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> in hell, officials said Sunday. Mayor <PERSON> Mauro </PERSON> <PERSON> Dragone </PERSON> said he ordered increased security around the monument to the poet, who died in <LOCATION> Ravenna </LOCATION> in 1321, after receiving a threatening letter from a group calling itself `` Guardians of the Revolution.'' `` It is an initiative taken in a prudent way because I am more inclined to think that the letter, which also was sent to a local newspaper, is a joke orchestrated in bad taste or a provocation,'' <PERSON> Dragone </PERSON> was quoted as saying by the Italian news agency <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION>. However, the mayor said he warned police and demanded stepped up security because he believes the potential danger from such threats should not be underestimated. He said the letter also demanded that he repudiate `` the false poet <PERSON> Dante </PERSON>'' and declare publicly `` that <PERSON> Dante </PERSON> lied and that these verses can no longer be read or studied.'' The `` Divine Comedy'' is considered a literary masterpiece that established the Tuscan dialect as the literary language of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. The work, a poem of more than 14,000 lines in 100 cantos, recounts a poet's journey through hell, purgatory and heaven. It places <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> in the ninth pit of hell. It comes in the midst of the controversy over `` The Satanic Verses'' by author <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>, a native Indian now living in Briton. Iranian clerics have offered a $ 5.2 million reward for <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>'s death because they say the book blasphemes <ORGANIZATION> Islam </ORGANIZATION> by portraying <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON>'s wives as prostitutes and suggesting that <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON>, not God, was the source for the Koran, <ORGANIZATION> Islam </ORGANIZATION>'s holy book.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0252EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Technology-Commerce     03-06 0728</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Technology-Commerce,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Critical of Bush Technology Delay</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARTON REPPERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are voicing concern over the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's delay in naming an official to head a newly reorganized drive to assist <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> industry with high-technology innovation. In addition to the absence of a permanent appointee to the new post of <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> undersecretary for technology, the effort also is being hampered by lack of money for a key program at the department's <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION>. `` I'm deeply concerned about it,'' said Rep. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>., who closely follows technology issues on Capitol Hill `` I would say that at this point the administration has not got their act together: first, in terms of making the key appointments that would be involved in policy in this area; and, of course, establishing the policy framework necessary to be able to go ahead.'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> is a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> science, research and technology subcommittee, which is set to hear testimony Tuesday by <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Ambler </PERSON>, who last December was named acting undersecretary for technology but is planning to retire at the end of March. At his confirmation hearing in January, <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> said the role of the undersecretary for technology `` is an extremely high priority'' and that he was concerned about <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> capability in high technology. So far, however, <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> has been unable find a willing candidate for the undersecretary job, which pays $ 82,500 a year. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said a number of people _ including <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Good </PERSON>, chairwoman of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, which oversees the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> _ had been offered the post but had turned it down. Rep. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Ritter </PERSON>, R-Pa., said the failure to implement a pay raise for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the judiciary and top federal executives apparently figured in the decisions by several people who would have had to take a substantial cut from their private-sector incomes Under a reorganization plan approved by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> late last year, <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>'s new <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> includes: _ The Office of Technology Policy, a policy analysis and development organization; _ The <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commercial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>, which promote cooperative joint ventures with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> industry in areas of research and technology development; _ The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> NIST </ORGANIZATION>, which works in areas ranging from automated manufacturing, electronics and materials research to computer science and technology, building and fire research, and biotechnology; _ The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecommunications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, responsible for developing federal telecommunications technology policies; _ The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, which disseminates the <PERSON> Ambler </PERSON> said in a speech last month that the office of the undersecretary for technology `` is a catalyst, a friend, a forum, a listening post and a voice in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for technology-based industry.'' At the same time, he emphasized that `` it is the job of the private sector to develop and sell goods and services. Government has never been successful in showing industry how to do its job, and there is absolutely no reason to think that will change in the future.'' Legislation passed last fall also established within <ORGANIZATION> NIST </ORGANIZATION> an Advanced Technology Program, intended to be a civilian counterpart of the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s highly touted <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advanced </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Projects </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. The program is designed to coordinate development of emerging-technologies and manufacturing-research consortia; foster industry, government and university partnerships, and monitor cooperation between federal and regional agencies. However, so far the program has no funding either for this fiscal year or in the fiscal 1990 budget. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said that in the absence of leadership by the administration on issues related to civilian technology, `` we may go ahead with proposed legislation which would compel them to start focusing on this.'' `` What we also need are some short-term decisions having to do with selecting targets of opportunity and providing some funding for civilian advanced technology projects this fiscal year,'' the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Democrat said. <PERSON> Ritter </PERSON>, who serves along with <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> on the science, research and technology subcommittee, said that after a meeting last Wednesday with <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON>, he is optimistic about the longer-range prospects for developing the <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> into an effective agency. `` I think that given the feelings of the secretary of commerce, it's going to be an important new feature on the landscape,'' the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> Republican said. `` I think he's committed to it. He just has to get people to work for him.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0217EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MilitaryAdoptions     03-06 0380</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Military Adoptions,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon Helping Support Adoptions by Service Members</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, in a test program ordered by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, has begun reimbursing some of the expenses of active-duty servicemen who adopt children. The unusual program, which provides up to $ 2,000 to offset the expenses of legally adopting a child, is set to last through the end of the current fiscal year _ or until Sept. 30 _ unless <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> votes to make the benefit permanent. The adoption reimbursement program was formally launched by the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s personnel chief, <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, last September and as of Dec. 31, the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> had processed 69 claims. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> lagged behind the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> in publishing their regulations and are only now handling claims. The test was ordered in the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s fiscal 1988 budget bill and was championed by Rep. <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Colo </LOCATION>. It was proposed not only as a morale-building benefit that might play a role in keeping men and women in the military, but also as a benefit for adoptive parents that parallels the cost of health care provided to women bearing babies in military hospitals. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> nonetheless opposed the program, arguing <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> was n't providing any extra money for the payments and it could n't afford to tap other accounts. `` In the current fiscal climate, this program might negatively affect the other personnel and family initiatives that benefit a greater percentage of the military population,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> argued unsuccessfully. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has not requested any funding for the program in the fiscal 1990 budget pending before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, but promised it would `` look at the results of the test program to determine further action.'' The reimbursement payments are available to anyone on active duty `` who initiates adoption proceedings after Sept. 30, 1987, and before Oct. 1, 1989,'' the Pentagon regulation states. `` Benefits paid under the test program may be paid only after the adoption is final. The adoption of stepchildren does not qualify for reimbursement under this program.'' Service members who adopt more than one child can claim a maximum $ 5,000 per year, the regulation adds. According to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Adoption </ORGANIZATION>, a group headquartered in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the average agency adoption fee was about $ 6,000 in 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Sweden-Welfare Bjt   03-06 0862</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sweden-Welfare, Bjt,0888</SECOND>
<HEAD>Swedish Reformer Touches off Ideological ``War of the Roses''</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EVA JANZON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A wiry-haired socialist with free market notions has touched off a battle of ideas in the party that created <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s welfare state _ challenging some of its basic principles. Finance Minister <PERSON> Kjell-Olof </PERSON> <PERSON> Feldt </PERSON>, a five-foot-six dynamo, is at the center of a reform movement in his <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which has governed for all but six of the last 56 years. Since the Social Democrats were re-elected in September, they have loosened foreign currency exchange rules, outlined tax reforms, reduced farm subsidies and warned the troubled textile industry that government help is tapering off. By fighting entrenched interests in order to give socialism the new direction he thinks it requires, the 57-year-old <PERSON> Feldt </PERSON> has alarmed party stalwarts and the unions. The internal debate he has set off is known as `` the war of the roses,'' after the party's red rose election symbol. `` We must stop slandering the market economy, defined as decentralized economic decision-making, competition on free markets and a free choice of consumer goods,'' <PERSON> Feldt </PERSON> wrote in a recent edition of <LOCATION> Tiden </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> magazine. `` On the global level, it is known that market economy in this form has won a complete victory over its only known alternative, the planned economy.'' <PERSON> Feldt </PERSON> said a tax policy which takes half the wages of the average worker _ as does <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s _ has made `` a historical contribution but should now come to an end.'' Although as finance minister he collects some of the highest taxes in the world _ 72 percent as a maximum on high incomes _ <PERSON> Feldt </PERSON> consistently ranks near the top in popularity polls. A quarterly survey published by <ORGANIZATION> PK </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banken </ORGANIZATION>, a state-owned bank, said <PERSON> Feldt </PERSON>'s proposals amount to `` the introduction of a new economic policy regime in <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>.'' In the draft budget presented last month, <PERSON> Feldt </PERSON> announced measures to cool the overheated economy by stimulating supply rather than lessening demand. Among the proposals were lowering trade barriers and taxes. The debate he is stirring comes as the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, in its 100th year, reviews its platform. A party committee charged with the task is to offer a new draft program by August. Although the Social Democrats espouse undiluted socialism, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> is far from being socialist. About 90 percent of production is in private hands, and big businesses like <ORGANIZATION> Volvo </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Ericsson </ORGANIZATION> telecommunications group play by capitalist rules. While a few big companies drive <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s economy, the government controls transportation, communications, health care and other services. Advocates say the system gives <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> one of the world's highest living standards, with basic necessities provided for everyone. Critics say that while the country may seem rich, the individual Swede, after paying taxes and high living costs, often has little money left over to spend as he chooses. <PERSON> Feldt </PERSON> has said he wants to change the pervasiveness of the public sector, which employs about half the work force and which he says has grown fat and inefficient. An opening salvo in the ideological debate was fired in January by <PERSON> Feldt </PERSON>'s treasury officials, who drafted a working paper for a closed meeting of the Scandinavian Labor Movement. It suggested citizens be allowed to choose private alternatives to public institutions such as day care centers and hospitals. The report met with such fierce opposition that the meeting tried to suppress it. When it leaked last month, it created a furor among traditionalists in the party. Foreign Minister <PERSON> Sten </PERSON> <PERSON> Andersson </PERSON> led a counterattack against what he saw as a threat to the party's underpinnings. He likened the reformists among his colleagues to rivals in the non-socialist opposition. `` That the Liberals and Conservatives want to undermine the general welfare is not so strange,'' <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> wrote in the socialist daily Arbetet. `` But now this has gained a foothold within the workers' movement, disquieting me and others.'' Prime Minister <PERSON> Ingvar </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlsson </PERSON> was compelled to defend <PERSON> Feldt </PERSON> and reassure his party. `` The general welfare policy will not move,'' <PERSON> Carlsson </PERSON> said in a television interview. `` We managed to retain it during the difficult years, and we're not abandoning it now.'' He denied that a battle was being waged between <PERSON> Feldt </PERSON>'s pragmatists and socialist orthodoxy `` In the government there is no right wing. There is just the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> government, and that is to the left,'' he said. However, <PERSON> Feldt </PERSON>'s article attacked the argument that a free market inevitably leads to social gaps and impoverishment of the worker. `` It is definitely misleading to describe capitalism _ not to speak about the market economy _ as the source of all misery and injustice, whereas the public sector is described as a perfectly working idyll,'' he wrote in <LOCATION> Tiden </LOCATION>. The conservative newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Svenska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dagbladet </ORGANIZATION> called the article `` one of the most remarkable political pieces of recent years'' and said <PERSON> Feldt </PERSON> `` has decided to start the fight for a modernization of Swedish social democracy.'' Aftonbladet, the popular tabloid owned by the blue-collar union LO, accused <PERSON> Feldt </PERSON> of trying to throw the `` basic ideals on the garbage heap of history and attack the soul of the party.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0228EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     03-06 0936</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0975</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sir <PERSON> Yehudi </PERSON> <PERSON> Menuhin </PERSON>, honored for promoting German-Jewish reconciliation, made a plea for dialogue between <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and Palestinians. `` The chances for positive change are closer than we believe,'' the 72-year-old virtuoso violinist said Sunday during an address to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s Societies for Christian-Jewish Cooperation. Earlier, <PERSON> Menuhin </PERSON> was awarded the Buber-Rosenzweig medal for his outspoken efforts to promote dialogue between Jews and Christians. The award, established in 1968, commemorates the Jewish philosophers <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Buber </PERSON> and <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenzweig </PERSON>. The award cited his performances in <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> immediately after World War II, including giving concerts for fellow Jews and others who survived the Nazi Holocaust. <PERSON> Menuhin </PERSON> said he hoped talks between Arabs and Jews could produce agreement on one state for both peoples. `` It may be the modest and lonely view of one man, but I believe there are only two possibilities: either two independent states, and that means a divided <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, or a united <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> that would mean at the very least a united, bi-national state. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> must follow this second path if it wants to survive
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>KEWANEE, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President and <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> top this year's list of the nation's best mannered people, but their predecessors _ the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> _ have been left off it for the first time The Bushes `` exemplify the new age of kinder and gentler manners that will prevail in the 1990s,'' said <PERSON> Marjabelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, who speaks and writes about etiquette. Mrs. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> said nominations for the fifth-annual best-mannered list came from journalists, television crew members, make-up artists, chauffeurs, maitre d's and others. This year's list includes <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletics </ORGANIZATION> pitcher <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Eckersley </PERSON>, who demonstrates `` good sportsmanship on and off the field and is a fine example to the youth of our nation,'' she said. Others were <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> newsman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuralt </PERSON>; Dr. <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> of Children's Square <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> in Council Bluffs, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, who started an etiquette program at the orphanage; <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Today'' show weatherman <PERSON> Willard </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>; talk-show host <ORGANIZATION> Arsenio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION>, and Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>. Former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>, dropped off the list after topping it for the past four years. `` It's not that they are not beautifully mannered,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>. She said they are no longer as highly visible as they were when they were in the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, adding, `` Is n't life fickle?''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Isabelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Adjani </PERSON> read from `` The Satanic Verses'' in an acceptance speech at <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s 14th annual <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> film awards in a gesture of support for novelist <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Adjani </PERSON> received the best actress award Saturday night for playing the title role in `` <PERSON> Camille </PERSON> <PERSON> Claudel </PERSON>,'' the sculptress and lover of sculptor <PERSON> Auguste </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodin </PERSON>. It was her third best actress <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s Oscar. `` You should know what I have suffered. ... In the artist's condition there is something extreme,'' she read from the novel in her speech `` Angels are easy to calm. Human beings ... can doubt everything.'' <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> has been in hiding in <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> since <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> called for his death for the novel, saying it blasphemes Islam. There was little overt reaction from the audience to the recitation. `` <PERSON> Camille </PERSON> <PERSON> Claudel </PERSON>'' received five Cesars, including best film, photography, decor and costumes. <PERSON> Jean-Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Belmondo </PERSON>, who said in advance he would refuse an award, was named best actor for his role in `` Itineraire d'un Enfant Gate'' -LRB- Itinerary of a Spoiled Child -RRB-. <PERSON> Belmondo </PERSON>, 55, has said the audience reaction to his work was enough reward. The West German film `` <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cafe </LOCATION>,'' directed by <PERSON> Percy </PERSON> <PERSON> Adlon </PERSON>, was voted best foreign film.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Empress <PERSON> Dowager </PERSON> <PERSON> Nagako </PERSON>, widow of Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>, celebrated her 86th birthday today with only a family luncheon scheduled because of the mourning period for her husband, the Togu Palace said. Those attending the luncheon were her eldest son, Emperor <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> and his wife, Empress <PERSON> Michiko </PERSON>; and the empress dowager's younger son, <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitachi </PERSON> and his wife, Princess <PERSON> Hanako </PERSON>, according to a palace official who spoke on condition of anonymity. The imperial family is observing a year of mourning for <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>, who died of cancer Jan. 7 at age 87, the official said. The official declined to discuss the health of the empress dowager, who has used a wheelchair and has made few public appearances in recent years. She did not attend her husband's funeral last month Quoting the <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said the empress dowager is suffering from pains in the back and knees, but her condition has remained stable and her appetite is good. <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> said she spends her days watching television and reading, apart from observing prayers for her late husband twice a day.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Entertainers including <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wynette </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pia </PERSON> <PERSON> Zadora </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> helped stir up pledges of more than $ 37 million to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Easter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> during its 18th annual telethon. `` We found that the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> public was very supportive. We had an even stronger turnout than we expected,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON>, head of the non-profit organization. This year's pledges exceeded the goal of $ 36 million and last year's mark of $ 35 million, he said. The 20-hour telethon was broadcast live on local television stations nationwide over the weekend. Singer <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Boone </PERSON> was host for the ninth year and was joined by his daughter <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> in singing a medley of their hits. The star of the show was 10-year-old Joy Hall, the National Easter Seal child. Joy, who was born with cerebral palsy, has already appeared on the `` Today'' show and will be a guest star on the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> series `` Amen'' later this year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0258EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congressmen-Shooting     03-06 0537</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congressmen-Shooting,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Once Pages Together, Congressmen Are Linked By Memory Of 1954 Shooting</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Once congressional pages together, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kanjorski </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Emerson </PERSON> both realized their dream of being elected to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. As if that were not unusual enough, both also were witnesses to the rarest of events: an attack by gunmen on the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kanjorski </PERSON>, D-Pa., and <PERSON> Emerson </PERSON>, R-Mo., stood together on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor last Wednesday to mark the 35th anniversary of an event they said will always seem fresh in their The two were 16-year-old pages and roommates on March 1, 1954, the day that four neatly dressed Puerto Ricans walked into the public galleries, unfurled a flag, shouted `` Free Puerto Rico!'' and began shooting randomly from large automatic pistols. House Speaker <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> _ who had been counting heads in a quorum call on a bill dealing with migrant laborers _ banged the gavel. A few congressmen fell, bleeding. Some raced for the doors. Some hid under the tables. `` As one who has never been particularly age-conscious, I stand in awe of the fact that this event occurred 35 years ago, and I remember it as though it were yesterday,'' <PERSON> Emerson </PERSON> said last week. <PERSON> Kanjorski </PERSON> had just gotten out of his seat on the Democratic side in the rear of the chamber when the shooting started. `` When the shots started to be fired, they sounded like firecrackers going off,'' <PERSON> Kanjorski </PERSON> said last week. `` There were a lot of them and they were different-sounding because there were several weapons that were being used. The only thing that made it clear they were n't firecrackers is that I got sprinkled with some of the marble that flaked off.'' <PERSON> Emerson </PERSON> thought the noise was firecrackers, too, `` but when I looked up, I could see fire coming out of the end of the barrels of those guns.'' Wounded were Reps. <PERSON> Alvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentley </PERSON>, R-Mich.; <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Jensen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>; <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Fallon </PERSON>, D-Md; <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, D-Ala.; and <PERSON> Clifford </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, D-Tenn. All Before it was over, a photographer snapped a picture of <LOCATION> Kanjorski </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Emerson </PERSON> carrying one of them off on a stretcher. As bad as the moment was, the news photo gave <PERSON> Kanjorski </PERSON> and <PERSON> Emerson </PERSON> temporary celebrity status among their peers, and linked them together in time. `` All through our lives we have been very close friends,'' <PERSON> Kanjorski </PERSON> said. He classified the odds of both becoming congressmen as `` remote,'' even though he said both dreamed about the possibility. One of the attackers died in 1979, and the other three were given presidential clemency the same year after 25 years in prison. <PERSON> Emerson </PERSON> was elected to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1980, <PERSON> Kanjorski </PERSON> four years later. `` I might say it was a great pleasure for me personally when my friend <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kanjorski </PERSON> joined us here two terms ago,'' <PERSON> Emerson </PERSON> said. `` He and I were roommates and colleagues of that era, and it was great to see an old buddy come back to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` I have often thought it -LRB- the shooting -RRB- was a terrible thing to have happened, but since it did, I was glad I was here to observe that little anecdote in American history,'' <PERSON> Emerson </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890306-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-06-89 0301EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BushandTower     03-06 0796</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush and Tower,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Even Republicans Say Tower Nomination Handled Poorly</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
