<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 2349EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ReaganinHistory 2Takes   01-02 1031</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan in History, 2 Takes,1053</SECOND>
<HEAD>Historians' First Rough Draft On Rating Reagan: Fair To Medium</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The jury is still out on <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, but history is likely to regard him as an average to good president, according to some scholars of the presidency. With little time left in <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s final term, The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> interviewed eight presidential scholars including specialists in history, political science and social psychology. Their tentative verdict: <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will get high marks for his use of the White House pulpit to unite the country and will get credit for improving East-West relations even though Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> may have been more responsible for it than he. `` My view is that he will be viewed by the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people as an above-average president,'' said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronin </PERSON>, a historian of the presidency at <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> who calls himself a moderate Democrat. `` I think the historians and biographers will treat him a little bit more harshly, still ranking him at least an average president but not as high as the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people now do or will.'' But <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON>, a professor of political science at <ORGANIZATION> Colgate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> who is critical of many <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> policies, said, `` I think, in the historical sense, somewhere down the road, that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will be considered as a somewhat worse than average president because of the problems that he has left us.'' If the economy turns sour in the wake of his administration's record budget and trade deficits, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> may go down in history like <PERSON> Calvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Coolidge </PERSON> as a president who failed to take action to stave off coming disaster Some scholars said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s reputation will also suffer from scandals in his administration and from his failure to deal effectively with such social ills as the plight of the homeless. `` I think probably in the short range reaction in the next five or 10 years, even liberal and radical historians will find something good to say about him and that will be that he somehow represented a kind of quality of Americanism and a sense of national unity and he projected that from the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> <PERSON> Belz </PERSON>, a neo-conservative historian at the University of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>. `` Whether or not in the long run our relations with the Soviets will be so good that people will always say it started in the fall of 1988 under <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> I do n't know, but it would certainly look that way,'' said <PERSON> Vaughn </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> <PERSON> Bornet </PERSON>, professor emeritus of history at <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and a self-described moderate Republican. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chester </PERSON>, a conservative historian at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION>, said it is too early to evaluate <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. But, echoing many of his academic colleagues, he said, `` The deficit does bother me. The deficit does bother me.'' `` I think we can say history will probably look most kindly upon him not necessarily for any substantive policy changes that he brought about but for the tone that he brought to the office and for a renewed sense of national pride,'' said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> congressional aide who teaches political science at <ORGANIZATION> Clemson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and has written widely on the presidency. <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ranney </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Political </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, said, `` On just the externalities of it, I think <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s presidency, with one huge ` if,' will probably go down as one of the most successful ones certainly in this century and maybe ever.'' However, comparing <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> with one of the predecessors the president most admires, <PERSON> Ranney </PERSON> also said that `` <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> may go down in history pretty much the way <PERSON> Coolidge </PERSON> did'' if some economists' predictions of economic collapse come true `` Coolidge is not seen now as a successful president followed by <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON>, a bum, but as a president whose do-nothing policies led to the huge crash of the early'30s that <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> was the victim of,'' he said. Dean <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Simonton </PERSON>, a professor of psychology at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> who has devised a formula for predicting how history will rate presidents, said, `` When you put all the pros and all the cons in the equation, <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> comes out as a slightly above average president.'' One of the `` pro'' factors for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Simonton </PERSON>, is the improvement in U.S.-Soviet relations that he and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> have forged. `` He gets nice points for that in foreign policy when actually he did n't take the initiative for that,'' <PERSON> Simonton </PERSON> said. `` In all fairness, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> deserves more credit than he does,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Cronin </PERSON>. `` Still,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Bornet </PERSON>, `` <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> stepped forward as usual and managed to pin it on himself and that's going to be hard to erase, I'll tell you.'' <ORGANIZATION> Clemson </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, similarly, argued, `` A good leader also must seize the opportunity, and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> offered an opportunity to play for high stakes in the international arena. He seized that; he was not frozen in place by rigid ideology, and thus I think one has to give him credit.'' From <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Ranny </PERSON> said the relaxation of East-West tensions was the most important of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s accomplishments in foreign policy. `` Now you might say that's because he got lucky and had <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> there, and I would n't quarrel with that,'' he said. `` Nevertheless, it did happen. And I think when historians look back at that, they will say that he was in terms of foreign policy one of the most successful postwar presidents that we have had.'' Psychologist <PERSON> Simonton </PERSON> said one big factor working in <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s favor is the simple fact that he was the first president since <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> to serve eight years `` The longer you serve the more events happen that can be credited to you, whether or not you are responsible for them,'' he said. `` You make a thick chapter in the history of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> under your name.'' Although <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> recently pictured himself as the adversary of a `` <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> colony'' protecting special interests at the expense of ordinary citizens, some scholars argued that one of his own chief shortcomings is his failure to be an advocate for those on the outside.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 2350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ReaganinHistory-1stAdd     01-02 0569</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan in History - 1st Add,0577</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON: the outside.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` There will be a feeling that he was largely indifferent to those without voice in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, that he responded much more to upper middle class and middle class <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Cronin </PERSON>. `` The presidency ought to be a place which raises its voice on behalf of those who do n't have the powerful lobbies.'' <PERSON> Cronin </PERSON> is self-described as a Democrat with a liberal viewpoint compared with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s, but the more conservative <PERSON> Chester </PERSON> agreed, `` I also think <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> could perhaps have done more for the homeless.'' The Iran-Contra affair and the investigations and indictments that have marked <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s administration also will cast their shadow, the scholars said. `` The people will forget that quickly; the historians wo n't,'' said <PERSON> Cronin </PERSON>. `` The historians will have chapters on the sleaze stuff and they'll call it as bad or equal to the Watergate mess.'' Some who praised <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> highly on other grounds conceded he was not as attentive as he should have been to his duties. `` He did n't keep his ear to the ground enough and he did n't have enough interest in political life, the warp and woof of it, to do as good a job as he could have,'' said the neo-conservative <PERSON> Belz </PERSON>. In strikingly similar language, <PERSON> Ranny </PERSON> said, `` I imagine he loses a few points because of the large number of scandals and indictments and things like that,'' and <PERSON> Simonton </PERSON> said that `` he is probably going to get some negative points'' because of such troubles. In comparing <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> with past presidents, scholars cited the names ranging from <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> to <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. `` Personality and character issues for 20 years have overwhelmed evaluation of <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> as president and if that's any precedent, then maybe for several decades it will be difficult to get down to serious business with <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Bornet </PERSON>, who has written extensively on <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, he said, `` is still the crude, cornpone president, and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is going to continue to be for a long time this image people watched on TV and this person the press correctly portrayed as essentially a lazy president.'' As for <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>, he has undergone a re-evaluation in recent years, with scholars believing him a much more activist president than first believed. <PERSON> Ranney </PERSON> said, `` If future scholarship finds out that behind the scenes and when the truth is known <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> himself was also a much more hands-on active president than we now believe _ and incidentally it is unlikely that they will find that _ he might undergo the same kind of upgrading.'' <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, however, said, `` Definitely a comparison of <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is in order. <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> had a very subtle style of leadership that evidently caused him to lead more effectively than most people thought he was leading. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s leadership I do n't think will come off as that kind of subtle hidden hand leadership so much as it has been leadership through orchestration of symbols and movement of the public mind.'' On the other hand, the <ORGANIZATION> Clemson </ORGANIZATION> political scientist said, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> may also be in for the kind of scaling down of his reputation that <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> has suffered as the force of his personality recedes. `` There is no longer the Camelot mystique to <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>; a lot of that has worn off,'' he said. `` I suspect that with <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> there will be a little bit of wearing off of the mystique that surrounds him.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AbortionActivist     01-02 1132</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion Activist,1169</SECOND>
<HEAD>Operation Rescue Head: Create `Social Tension' To Change Laws</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BAUDER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BINGHAMTON, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Where most people list their job experiences, <ORGANIZATION> Operation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION> founder <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> Terry </PERSON>'s resume brags, `` Arrested 26 times in seven cities.'' <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> complains it's out-of-date. `` It might be closer to 30 right now,'' the 29-year-old activist said during an interview at the unmarked storefront office in upstate <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> where the latest protests against abortion are being planned. Since its national debut at the Democratic National Convention in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> last summer, Operation Rescue has made abortion a high-profile issue again. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> and his followers have blocked women from entering abortion clinics throughout the country, lying in front of doors until police carry or drag them away under the watchful eye of television cameras. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> says he is trying to produce the `` social tension'' necessary to change abortion laws by using the non-violent 1960s civil rights protest as a model. `` He's the <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> of a movement,'' said <PERSON> Dominick </PERSON> <PERSON> Brignola </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION> lawyer and footsoldier in the anti-abortion drive. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON>'s critics claim Operation Rescue, so named because followers try to `` rescue'' the unborn, is an assault on women's rights `` The civil rights movement was trying to gain rights for people. They're trying to take away the rights of living, breathing human beings,'' said <PERSON> Molly </PERSON> <PERSON> Yard </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION>. More than 450 anti-abortion demonstrators clogged <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> jails during the five-day Democratic convention. Since then, demonstrations have spread to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and still more cities. The activists want the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> to overturn <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON>, its 1973 decision that allows women to have abortions. An estimated 1.6 million women have abortions each year in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Standing at the forefront of Operation Rescue is a used car salesman who once wanted to be a rock star. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Cindy </PERSON>, began their crusade in 1984 by standing in front of abortion clinics, trying to talk women out of entering. Friends soon joined them, and the couple opened an office that offered women free pregnancy tests and hand-me-down baby clothes. `` God clicked a light on in my head and said it was n't enough to just be against child-killing, that I had to do something about it,'' said <PERSON> Terry </PERSON>, who's selling his auto dealership because he is too busy with Operation Rescue. Critics concede <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> has a mesmerizing personality. He even tries to convert relatives at family reunions, said <PERSON> Dawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION>, his aunt. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> was reared in a low-key Protestant environment but quit high school at 17, dreaming of a career in music, said <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON>, who is communications director for the <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION> chapter of Planned Parenthood, a medical service that anti-abortion pickets frequently target. She stressed that she does not speak for the organization about her nephew. `` He went away and he flipped out,'' she said about <PERSON> Terry </PERSON>'s transformation into a born-again Christian `` He came back a totally changed personality. It was more like a cult reaction than a spiritual quest.'' Marriage and his highly public role as Operation Rescue spokesman have calmed him somewhat, she said. The Terrys have one child and three foster children. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> dismisses his aunt's comments _ including her assessment that `` he's an egomaniac,'' lapping up news media attention. To <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, administrator at <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tier </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Binghamton </LOCATION>, Operation Rescue is nothing new She said anti-abortion activists have spread nails in the parking lot and glued the clinic's door shut four or five times. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON>'s first arrest came in January 1986 when he chained himself to a sink at the clinic, which performs abortions. He was jailed for 22 days for refusing to pay a $ 60 fine. `` It does n't matter what you say to him. There is no reason involved,'' <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> said. `` He does n't care about women. I think he really hates women.'' Iron pipes now prevent cars from blocking the entrance to the <LOCATION> Binghamton </LOCATION> clinic. A court order keeps the nearly ever-present demonstrators at shouting distance. `` They really want to make it personal,'' <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> said. Even when she has run into him on a Saturday in the post office, <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> said <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> has shouted at her, `` How many babies did you murder today?'' <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> criticizes the anti-abortion movement as being `` too nice'' during the 1980s, pacified by the presence of an ideological friend like President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> into not working hard for its goal. `` We cry that abortion is murder, it's child-killing, and yet we carry a picket once or twice a year and write a few letters,'' he said. `` That's not an adequate response to murder. A logical response to murder is physical intervention on behalf of the victim.'' The lean, bushy-haired <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> expects and even hopes his demonstrators will be arrested. He claims Operation Rescue was responsible for 11,000 arrests in 1988 and predicts 500,000 will be arrested in 1989. There are no situations, he said, when abortions are justified. `` In most areas of life it's OK for people to follow their own beliefs, but not when it comes to having innocent children murdered,'' he said. `` That's like saying, ` Why ca n't a white man follow his own conscience concerning owning a black slave? Why ca n't a German follow his own conscience if he decides he wants to shoot Jews?''' <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> has attracted some prominent supporters, including former presidential candidate <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, who said he backs `` any means short of violence'' to stop abortion. If anti-abortion demonstrators set their minds to it, <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> said, they could change abortion laws in six months because the political system is not built to deal with mass protests. Yard dismisses <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> as a `` puppet'' groomed for the role of point man in the latest anti-abortion offensive. `` Women are really outraged by the whole thing,'' she said. `` The reason they have been passive seemingly in the light of bombings -LRB- of abortion clinics -RRB- and Operation Rescue is that people do n't believe <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> can be overturned. ... I'm not so sanguine. All I know is we have to make the biggest outcry we possibly can.'' At Operation Rescue's office, a competing outcry is being plotted. Pinned to the wall is a large map of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, with `` abortion mills'' dotted in red. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> distractedly complains to a staff member about a plane flight later that afternoon that will take him to a television appearance. As a photographer snaps pictures, he removes his foot from his desk, saying `` that's too casual for someone trying to change world history.'' He adds, chuckling: `` It's comical, really. I think God has a sense of humor. Do n't you think it's rather funny that a former used car salesman is heading such a movement?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 2353EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AIDSBrigade     01-02 0805</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS Brigade,0828</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ex-Junkie Takes AIDS Prevention To The Streets</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHELLE LOCKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Faced with the choice of trying to kick heroin or going back to jail, <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> fought his way 14 years ago from the murky world of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>'s shooting galleries to the academic heights of <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. Now he's back on the streets. He again faces a possible jail term, but this time he's charged with illegally handing out clean needles to people he used to run with _ many of whom already have contracted AIDS by sharing dirty needles. <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, 33, said he does n't want to go to jail, but he's willing to risk it to try to change the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> requirement for a prescription to buy a hypodermic syringe. `` People look down on addicts, but it's through them that AIDS is going to spread to the heterosexual community,'' he says. `` People are going to have to realize that.'' <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> is founder of a 50-member organization called the AIDS Brigade, which includes <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> graduate students as well as former addicts and convicts. It was formed about four years ago and distributes AIDS education materials, bleach and needles in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Haven </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. Critics say he's a renegade, too far from mainstream efforts to curb the spread of AIDS, most often transmitted through homosexual contact and shared needles. `` I think clean needles clearly is one way of addressing the problem for addicts. It would be nice if they were available, but they're not, so we do what we can through other aspects,'' said <PERSON> Brianne </PERSON> <PERSON> Comella </PERSON>, director of Project Trust, supported by city and state funds. Project Trust volunteers distribute bottles of bleach and show addicts how to sterilize needles. `` I think that there is an absolute need for fringe groups such as the AIDS Brigade to push the system. Unfortunately, I think that they could be more effective if they worked with existing programs rather than as Lone Rangers,'' Ms. <PERSON> Commella </PERSON> said. State health officials estimate there are about 40,000 addicts in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, and about one-third are believed to be carrying the AIDS virus. Mayor <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON> backed a needle exchange program, but it was rejected by the City Council. Dr. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamb </PERSON>, first deputy commissioner for the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> and Hospitals, supported the attempt at a needle exchange program and said he will testify at <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>'s trial, which he hopes will revive interest in the program. Addicts meet AIDS Brigade workers in dingy restaurants and on street corners to get their sets of needles, known as `` the works.'' <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> makes rounds of the neighborhoods where the people he tries to help live, such as <PERSON> Jenny </PERSON>, who used to shoot dope with <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> 18 years ago, but now is trying to stay clean. A thin, pale woman in her 30s with dark circles under her eyes, <PERSON> Jenny </PERSON> spoke at her apartment on condition her last name was n't used. She tested positive for the AIDS virus last summer, and she's sure she contracted the disease through sharing dirty needles. `` The works are hard to get,'' <PERSON> Jenny </PERSON> says. <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> was arrested this summer and charged with illegal possession of hypodermic syringes, which he buys legally in <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>. The charge is a misdemeanor, but <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> requested a jury trial, which will probably take place this spring. `` I want to show that this is the logical answer to stop the spread of AIDS,'' <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> said. His attorney, <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Abelow </PERSON>, plans a `` necessity defense,'' saying that illegally handing out the needles is justified by the need to curb AIDS. But prosecutors say having a reason for doing something does n't excuse an offense `` We're only kidding ourselves to think -LRB- addicts -RRB- are going to go out and only use the needle once,'' said First Assistant Attorney <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Leary </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Suffolk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> District Attorney's office. <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> says his personal history makes him a better judge of how addicts are likely to respond. He shot heroin as a teen-ager and robbed drug stores for money and supplies. At 17, he served more than two years time, earning his high school equivalency diploma in jail. A month after his release, in 1974, he was caught violating parole and given the choice of checking into a drug rehabilitation center or going back to jail. He chose reform. Since then, <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> has worked a variety of jobs, including driving a cab and a few bouts as a local boxer, to get money to help pay his way through <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Amherst </LOCATION>, where he studied biology, and then to <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Epidemiology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION>, where he is completing work on a masters degree in public health. He says he wants other addicts to have the same chance he did.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 0008EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador-Killings     01-02 0909</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador-Killings,0940</SECOND>
<HEAD>Killings Illustrate Surge Of Violence In Salvador</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PIEDRA LUNA, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Uniformed men beat up <PERSON> Cecilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Aguilar </PERSON> beneath an avocado tree, marched him and two friends down a wooded path and pounded them to death with rifle butts, witnesses say. Leftist guerrillas captured <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> as he was searching for three wayward cows, took him away and shot him. The killings are examples of the growing toll of politically motivated slayings in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> in 1988 as both sides in a 9-year-old civil war grow frustrated with a stalemate. The <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>'s Legal Aid office has counted 181 summary killings in the first 11 months of 1988, compared with 129 in all of 1987. Catholic Archbishop <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> <PERSON> Damas </PERSON> said during his homily Sunday that altogether 1,369 civilians, soldiers or leftist rebels were killed last year in military clashes, rightist death squad operations and car bombings or other terrorist acts. The war has claimed an estimated 65,000 lives since it began. `` It is so hard to see any sort of light,'' said a church worker who has spent nearly two decades in <LOCATION> Morazan </LOCATION>, an eastern province divided between guerrillas and government forces. `` It's so disheartening because you had the feeling things were getting better. And now you feel them going backward, getting worse,'' the worker said on condition he not be identified. When the uniformed men had finished killing <PERSON> Cecilio </PERSON>, they went back to his house to demand food and his weapon. His mother could give them only tortillas. `` They said he was a guerrilla. But my son had no weapon, only a machete,'' said <PERSON> Dominga </PERSON> <PERSON> Aguilar </PERSON>. In her one-room mud brick home, she recounted through sobs the events of Nov. 12, when men she described as government soldiers swept into this hamlet. <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> was the former mayor of another small town, <LOCATION> Lolotique </LOCATION>, 12 miles from <PERSON> Piedra </PERSON> <PERSON> Luna </PERSON>. He was searching for cows with his brother Dec. 6 when leftist guerrillas captured him, his wife said. They killed him for what they said was his complicity in a U.S.-imposed counterinsurgency plan. The cases in <LOCATION> Lolotique </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Piedra </PERSON> <PERSON> Luna </PERSON>, a village of a dozen households 90 miles east of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, are not unique. Respect for human rights improved steadily from 1984 until 1988. The early 1980s were a time of slaughter when soldiers and rightist death squads were blamed for the slayings of about 30,000 people. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which has provided more than $ 3 billion in aid this decade, told Salvadoran authorities in 1983 that support would dry up if the rights situation did not improve. Salvadoran authorities say the government no longer has any ties with right-wing death squads. The leftist guerrillas have killed eight mayors and 32 other civilians in 1988 for allegedly collaborating with the army. The Catholic Legal Aid office blames the army for 90 summary executions of suspected guerrilla collaborators. Death squads are blamed for 51 murders. The slayings of <PERSON> Aguilar </PERSON>, 17, <PERSON> Hernan </PERSON> <PERSON> Benitez </PERSON>, 18 and <PERSON> Dolores </PERSON> <PERSON> Pineda </PERSON>, 24, devastated their families, the community council they all sat on and the village soccer team. <PERSON> Benitez </PERSON> was the goalie, <PERSON> Aguilar </PERSON> a fullback and <PERSON> Pineda </PERSON> a midfielder. <PERSON> Benitez </PERSON> died with his soccer shoes on. `` I wo n't play ever again,'' his mother, <PERSON> Amalia </PERSON>, quoted him as saying as he laced up the cleats before being taken away. `` He knew. He lifted the dog's front paws and danced with him. He kissed the baby and said, ` This is it, <PERSON> Ma </PERSON>. I'm saying goodbye,''' she said. Those who took them away were government soldiers, six witnesses said. <PERSON> Hernan </PERSON>'s mother said the officer in charge repeatedly accused the family of setting corn aside for the guerrillas. <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> <PERSON> Damas </PERSON>, archbishop of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, also has blamed army troops for the <PERSON> Piedra </PERSON> <PERSON> Luna </PERSON> killings and called for an investigation. Lt. Col. <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Linares </PERSON> denied army responsibility. He blamed the guerrillas, claiming they wanted to discredit the armed forces. He said army records show no troops near <LOCATION> Piedra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Luna </LOCATION> on Nov. 12. He denied a request to see the records, saying they were classified. He said the case is closed. <PERSON> Aguilar </PERSON>'s 15-year-old brother has been a guerrilla for a year, Mrs. <PERSON> Aguilar </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Benitez </PERSON>'s father was detained for four days in October, and _ according to his family _ he was severely beaten and accused of guerrilla sympathies. The three young men, though perhaps not outright collaborators, maintained friendly relations with rebels who pass through regularly, villagers said. The community council they sat on functions with tacit guerrilla approval. When the guerrillas kill civilians, they usually announce it on their clandestine Radio Venceremos. The radio announced Dec. 9 that <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON>, the former mayor, was found guilty of `` crimes against the people.'' He was the secretary-general of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Lolotique </LOCATION>. He had been kidnapped by the guerrillas for five months in 1985. `` We explained to him how mayors are tools for the implementation of the counterinsurgency plan ... but he did not obey, and continued implementing the plan in <LOCATION> Lolotique </LOCATION>,'' said the broadcast. `` He helped whomever he could,'' said his widow, <PERSON> Blanca </PERSON>, in their home. The room where she sat contained a sort of shrine _ a crucifix and her husband's photograph surrounded by flowers in coffee cans. `` Maybe they killed him for helping the community,'' she said, a tear tracking down her cheek.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 0010EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Sweden-Policy     01-02 0764</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sweden-Policy,0788</SECOND>
<HEAD>Swedish Foreign Policy Scores Success With PLO-US Dialogue</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ARTHUR MAX</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador sat down with a <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> delegation for the first official meeting in 13 years, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> scored a triumph for a foreign policy variously described as magnanimous or meddlesome. For a small country, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> is engaged in other people's troubles to a surprising degree. `` Some people call it international meddling or giving unsolicited advice,'' said <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Schori </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> secretary who is the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>'s No. 2 official. But <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> sees its foreign diplomacy as central to its own well-being. `` Our security has not only to do with our borders. It also is affected by the international climate,'' <PERSON> Schori </PERSON> said. Increasingly, neutral <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> is being used as a communications channel for parties who ca n't talk to each other. On Dec. 16, the same day the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ended its formal boycott of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s ambassador to <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Rolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Gauffin </PERSON>, was instrumental in mediating the release of <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Winkler </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> delegate who was kidnapped Nov. 17 by a Palestinian faction in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s approach to world affairs, sometimes criticized as moralistic and preaching, has created some ill feeling, particularly in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> but also in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The late Prime Minister <PERSON> Olof </PERSON> <PERSON> Palme </PERSON> was blacklisted from the White House for his outspoken opposition to the Vietnam War after he marched through <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION> with North Vietnamese leaders. `` We believe strongly in human rights, international law and the resolution of conflicts,'' <PERSON> Schori </PERSON> said in an interview in his vaulted 18th century office. `` Our actions are motivated by a combination of self-interest and solidarity.'' The U.S.-PLO dialogue was a personal victory for Foreign Minister <PERSON> Sten </PERSON> <PERSON> Andersson </PERSON>, who worked in secret for nine months to nudge <ORGANIZATION> Palestinian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> to meet <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> conditions for ending its ban on contacts with his organization. `` The <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> success was the climax of a long process,'' <PERSON> Schori </PERSON> said. `` But the positions were blocked, and what was needed was a midwife. Somebody had to take the initiative. <PERSON> Sten </PERSON> <PERSON> Andersson </PERSON> saw that.'' <PERSON> Andersson </PERSON>, a wily politician with little foreign experience, came to the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> in 1985 after nearly 20 years as secretary of the dominant <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and three years as health minister. He brought with him the typically Swedish approach that any problem is solvable by discussion among reasonable men. <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, which allocates 1 percent of its gross national product to foreign aid, also has provided a pool of experienced diplomats for international service. <PERSON> Bernt </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlsson </PERSON> was <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner for <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. He died in Dec. 21 <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> plane crash in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> while on his way to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to observe the signing of an agreement for Namibian independence from South African rule. <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Eliasson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> ambassador, was tapped by Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> on Sept. 1 to lead Iran-Iraq peace negotiations. In less public roles, Swedish diplomats have been conduits for contacts between rival factions in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, among others, <PERSON> Schori </PERSON> said. Last year the Swedes persuaded <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> to allow the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> to visit prisoners in Cuban jails. <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s international activity goes back a long way. Prime Minister <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Branting </PERSON> won the 1921 Nobel Peace Prize for his work with the League of Nations. It has contributed 55,000 men to <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeeping forces, which were created by the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Secretary-General <PERSON> Dag </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammarskjold </PERSON>, a Swede. Count <PERSON> Folke </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernadotte </PERSON>, a member of <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s royal family, was the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION>'s first martyr. He was assassinated by Jewish extremists in pre-independence <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION> in 1948. Four years earlier, diplomat <PERSON> Raoul </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallenberg </PERSON> distributed Swedish passports to Hungarian Jews threatened with deportation to Nazi death camps. He was credited with saving 100,000 lives before Soviet forces arrested him at the close of the war and he disappeared. The Soviets say he died in prison in 1947, but his family is convinced he is still alive. <PERSON> Gunnar </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarring </PERSON>, appointed special <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> emissary to the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> after the 1967 Six-Day War, earned a footnote in history as the inventor of shuttle diplomacy, though the credit went later to former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>. Jarring's mission ended in failure. <PERSON> Schori </PERSON> said the relaxation of U.S.-Soviet tension may usher in a less active period for <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>. `` There's been a need for bridge-building. Now it's changing,'' he said. `` We have no ambition to be mediators. Where we have a contribution to make, we do all we can. But I see this role declining in an era of detente.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 0022EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;LRescues Bjt   01-02 0718</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;L Rescues, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Flurry of Thrift Bailouts Leaves Bush With Budget Puzzle</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal regulators rescued a post-Depression record 217 savings institutions in 1988, leaving <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to figure out the best way to pay the $ 38 billion bill. Theoretically, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, which regulates the S & amp; L industry, expects enough income over the next 30 years _ $ 45 billion to $ 50 billion _ to cover the cost. But analysts and many members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> say regulators have run up such a huge bill that turning to the taxpayer is inevitable. `` We still do n't know the magnitude of the S & amp; L crisis,'' <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> said Sunday. `` We're not even certain what the regulators have been doing the past week, running up a tab of some $ 40 billion.'' Even with a last-minute spending spree of nearly $ 6 billion to rescue 22 institutions in the final 48 hours of 1988, regulators still have about 350 more insolvency cases to handle. And, as of last Sept. 30, another 150 savings institutions were sliding toward insolvency with capital levels below 1.5 percent. Estimates of the total cost of paying for the mess run as high as $ 112 billion, a figure reported last month by the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' auditing agency. <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials are considering a variety of plans for the incoming administration. Most attempt to spread out the burden over time and keep as much as possible from adding to the federal budget deficit. But <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, in an interview on <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION>'s `` This Week With <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Brinkley </PERSON>,'' said, `` Somebody's going to have to pay. ... We ca n't hide it by putting it off budget or smoke and mirrors. This year's failure and rescue total _ 217 of the 3,100 <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls operating at the start of the year _ is more than quadruple last year's total of 48. It is the highest total since a record 277 failures and rescues in the Depression year of 1938. According to the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deposit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which insures the nation's 13,500 commercial banks, 221 banks failed or required government assistance. That is also a post-Depression record, topping the previous record of 203 in 1987. Both the <ORGANIZATION> FDIC </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> draw their funds from an assessment on member institutions. But the <ORGANIZATION> FDIC </ORGANIZATION> depends on the much-larger banking industry, which as a whole is in much better shape, and enters 1989 in relatively good shape with more than $ 15 billion in reserves. <ORGANIZATION> FSLIC </ORGANIZATION>, however, is technically insolvent. So, regulators have been patching together rescue deals with as little cash as possible. Most of the aid takes the form of various commitments secured by revenue that regulators do n't have now and in some case wo n't have for as long as 30 years. Moreover, the revenue projections depend on charging S & amp; Ls a special assessment, originally intended to be phased out in a few years, over the next three decades. Industry officials say that would drive even more S & amp; Ls into the red. The biggest rescue on the last day of 1988 was for the <ORGANIZATION> Beverly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hills </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, a giant <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> institution whose financial problems had plagued regulators for years. The package called for the government to provide $ 983 million in assistance in the sale of <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> to <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a bank holding company in <LOCATION> Farmington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, that is putting $ 52 million into the deal. Also on Saturday, the bank board pledged: _ $ 243.3 million in aid to Home Federal Savings and Loan, a <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diego </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L putting up $ 25 million to acquire three institutions in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> area. They are: <ORGANIZATION> Columbus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> and Loan, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rafael </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Cal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> and Loan, <LOCATION> Walnut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION>, and First Security, <LOCATION> Pleasant </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. _ $ 151.1 million in aid to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Savings and Loan of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, which agreed to put up $ 20.4 million into the insolvent <ORGANIZATION> Broward </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sunrise </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> _ $ 29.9 million in aid to <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION>, which agreed to pay $ 1.25 million for the insolvent <ORGANIZATION> Tahoe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> and Loan of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tahoe </LOCATION>. _ $ 8 million to Home Federal Savings and Loan of <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, which is purchasing <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aberdeen </ORGANIZATION>, S.D.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 0024EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DCCrime     01-02 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-DC Crime,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Last Year Was Bloodiest In DC History: 371 Murders</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's capital also may be the nation's murder capital In 1988, 371 people were killed in the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, far surpassing the previous high of 287, set in 1969. Police say drugs are mostly to blame. Final population and homicide figures have yet to be compared, but <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> had the two highest per-capita murder rates in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> in 1988. Thus, the nation's capital, where the federal government's war on drugs is mapped out, could earn the dubious distinction of being the murder capital as well. The District of <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>'s drug problems dramatize the two different Washingtons _ the Capitol, the White House and other sites visited by millions of tourists each year, and the squalid neighborhoods tucked away from the traditional seats of power. There, a more vicious power struggle is contested among teens drawn to the status and money that come from selling drugs. Police say drugs _ particularly the arrival of crack cocaine _ are to blame for about 60 percent of the slayings. As recently as 1986, drug-related killings accounted for just one-third of the city's homicide total. The absence of organized crime in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> may be a factor in the city's murder rate, officials say. Law enforcement officials say that in cities where organized crime factions control the drug market, there are fewer drug-related slayings. `` What you have here is a lot of young entrepreneurs fighting among themselves for drug turf,'' said Police Chief <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>. `` They are just working for themselves.'' Stemming the city's drug tide has become an increasingly tough battle for <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> and his 3,800 officers. Earlier this year, police decided they will switch to .9 mm semiautomatic handguns out of fear that weapons commonly found on the street were outclassing the standard .38 - caliber six-shot revolver officers have The new weapons, which allow officers to fire an extra 10 shots before reloading, were ordered after drug raids frequently resulted in the seizure of Uzi submachine guns and other sophisticated weaponry. Surveying the weapons at a March news conference, <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> called the district's streets `` something out of the wild, wild West.'' Officers will have their new guns by 1990. And police have learned that simply arresting more drug suspects has n't dulled the city's appetite for narcotics. A highly-touted anti-drug program, Operation Clean Sweep, has produced more than 46,000 arrests since it began in August, 1986. However, <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> has complained that the program, which sends swarms of officers through drug-infested neighborhoods to make arrests, has done little more than further clog the city's already overcrowded jail and court systems. For each drug dealer arrested, another springs forward, according to <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>. `` A lot of these kids are high school dropouts with few skills,'' <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> said. `` They can make up to a $ 1 million a year selling drugs. What would you do?'' <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney for the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, who can prosecute both local and federal crimes, announced in December that he is assigning five senior prosecutors to work solely on drug-related killings in the district. Turner also has called on city officials to spend more money on drug education, prevention and treatment programs. Currently, a three-week wait is common for people wanting to enroll in the city's treatment centers As for the future, police believe that as markets are more firmly established for crack, a highly-addictive cocaine derivative, the murder rate will decrease. `` This is one of the last major cities in this country to have an infusion of crack,'' <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> said. `` When crack arrived in other cities, like <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, murder rates went up there, too.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 0026EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NewLaws Bjt   01-02 1134</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-New Laws, Bjt,1131</SECOND>
<HEAD>Medicare, Pensions Among Changes To Take Effect With New Year</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ringing in the new year are dozens of changes in federal laws and regulations, many of them aimed at quenching Americans' thirst for security and a few that will make life a little more expensive. Among the most significant of the Jan. 1 changes are a vast expansion of Medicare to cover catastrophic illnesses, faster pension fund vesting that will benefit millions, particularly women, and tax changes reducing the government's subsidizing of purchases on credit. Others that occurred just before the end of 1988 or are scheduled early in 1989 include a ban on lie detector tests by private employers, 60 days advance notice of plant closings and large layoffs and a new law prohibiting landlords from discriminating against the handicapped and families with children. A few of the changes are a little more esoteric but their impact eventually may be felt by the entire population. For example, <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> regulations implementing the 46-nation ozone treaty took effect Jan. 1. The regulations do n't require chemical companies to actually do anything until next July, but then they must cut their production of chloroflourocarbon or <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> compounds by an estiamted 20 percent back to 1986 levels. The treaty is aimed at halting the depletion of the ozone layer 15 to 25 miles up protecting the earth's surface from ultraviolet rays. <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> compounds also contribute to the `` greenhouse'' effect that is warming the planet. As a result of the regulations, consumers may notice fewer plastic food containers from fast-food outlets, thicker insulating panels and possibly even slightly harder seat cushions. The biggest of the immediate changes is the Jan 1. expansion of Medicare coverage for 32 million <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> beneficiaries to include catastrophic health care costs Prior to passage of the measure last summer by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> _ the first major expansion of <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> in its 22-year history _ the program paid full hospital bills for no more than 59 days a year. With the changes that took effect Sunday, the beneficiary still will have to pay the first-day deductible of $ 560. But that charge will be assessed no more than once a year no matter how many times the patient has to be hospitalized. The other 364 days are fully paid. That fundamental change in the hospital benefit was the cornerstone of the Medicare expansion set in motion by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in his 1986 State of the Union message. `` Let us remove a financial specter facing our older <LOCATION> Ameicans </LOCATION> _ the fear of an illness so expensive that it can result in having to make an intolerable choice between bankruptcy and death,'' he said then. <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> enrollees will pay for the new benefits through a flat increase in the premium deducted from their monthly Social Security checks and an additional sliding scale premium for approximately 40 percent of the elderly who pay federal income tax. The flat increase will be $ 4 a month effective immediately, climbing to $ 10.20 monthly in 1993. The sliding scale premium is projected to rise from a maximum of 15 percent of regular income tax liability in 1989 to about 28 percent in 1993. Many of the Jan. 1 changes grow out of the 1986 Tax Reform Act. The biggest new benefit from that law is faster vesting in pension plans. The maximum waiting period for employees to become fully invested in a pension is being cut in half from 10 years to five years. However, employers can adopt an option that denies full vesting until seven years. To do so, they have to offer 20 percent vesting after three years and an additional 20 percent vesting annually until the seventh year, when it reaches 100 percent. The <ORGANIZATION> Employee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Benefit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> estimates that the pension changes will provide a retirement stake to 2 million more workers a year. `` We'll especially see more women being vested than in the past because they tend to be in the workforce or with the same employer for shorter periods,'' said <PERSON> Stephanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Poe </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the institute. Another tax change is that only 20 percent of personal interest payments on everything from car and student loans to credit card charges will be deductible in 1989, compared with 40 percent last year. And while the government is now raising tax brackets, exemptions and standard deductions to keep cost-of-living raises from bumping people into higher brackets, it also is taking more Social Security taxes. The 7.51 percent Social Security tax took a maximum $ 3,380 out of employee paychecks in 1988. This year the maximum amount of income subject to the tax rises from $ 45,000 to $ 48,000, raising the maximum Social Security tax that can be collected from an individual employee to $ 3,605. The latest change came about just last Thursday, when the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> ordered airlines, effective Jan. 1, to either inspect by hand or X-ray all luggage checked aboard <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airline flights from western <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. The new inspections, prompted by the bombing of a <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> jet over <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> on Dec. 21, are expected to delay passenger check-ins by about an hour. Other changes taking effect slightly before or after New Year's Day include: _ The use of polygraph or lie detector tests by private employers to screen job applicants was outlawed, with some exceptions, effective last Tuesday The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> estimates the law will effectively eliminate about 80 percent of the 2 million polygraph exams now administered annually. _ A 47-year-old ban on homework in five apparel trades is being removed on Jan. 8, unless unions which support the prohibitions win a court stay first. Affected are an estimated 50,000 to 75,000 workers in fields such as mittens and gloves, embroideries, buttons and buckles, handkerchiefs and some jewelry trades. They will be able to work legally at home for the first time if their employers obtain a certficate from the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> after pledging to abide by minimum wage and other federal labor standards. _ A law requiring employers to provide 60 days advance notice of plant closings or layoffs affecting 50 or more people officially takes effect Feb. 4. However, there are different interpretations on whether companies are required to have provided 60 days notice beforehand if they close a plant on that date. The <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> advised in early December that, to avoid potential liability, they should. _ Regulations implementing a law passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last summer forbidding landlords from discriminating against the handicapped or families with children take effect March 12. Violators can be fined up to $ 10,000 for a first offense, $ 25,000 for a second violation in a five-year period and $ 50,000 for two or more violations within a seven-year period.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 0024EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Chile-Volcano     01-02 0307</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chile-Volcano,0315</SECOND>
<HEAD>Volcano Eruption In Southern Chile May Last Two Months</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTIAGO, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Christmas Day eruption of the snow-capped <LOCATION> Lonquimay </LOCATION> volcano in southern <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> is gaining in force and seismologists say they expect it to continue for at least another two months. Authorities have issued masks to residents who are remaining in the area to protect them from a thick cloud of ash spewed by the volcano over a sparsely populated area of about 12 square miles. And scientists estimate that 525 million cubic feet of lava have oozed out of the 8,400-foot volcano, toward an uninhabited valley, since the eruption began. Lonquimay, a peak in the Andes foothills about 400 miles south of <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION>, had been dormant for a century when it erupted on Christmas Day. Authorities say the eruption poses no danger for two nearby villages, <LOCATION> Lolco </LOCATION> and Malacahuello. Residents of both towns quickly evacuated after the eruption, and some later returned home. But many remain lodged at schools and municipal buildings in <LOCATION> Curacautin </LOCATION>, a city 50 miles away. Authorities on Saturday issued masks to the few residents who had returned to their homes. Researchers, soldiers and police officers also in the area were also wearing the white masks. On Sunday, the volcano continued to spew smoke and lava through a 300-foot-wide crater. The volcano initially showed three separate smaller fissures, but a series of explosions joined them into a single crater, authorities said. Seismologists from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Frontera </ORGANIZATION>, in <LOCATION> Temuco </LOCATION>, the largest city in the region, said a 1,200-foot-wide, 30-foot-high mass of lava is slowly slipping down the volcano. They said the route followed by the lava is the same as the one in the Lonquimay's previous eruption, in 1889, and poses no danger for the population. Livestock in the area were removed to safer zones, police said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 0027EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-McLaughlin Bjt   01-02 0797</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-McLaughlin, Bjt,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>McLaughlin Says Successor Belongs on Bush Economic Team</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Outgoing Labor Secretary <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> says her successor needs to carve out a place on President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s team of top economic advisers to help solve the nation's competitiveness Mrs. <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON>, the only woman in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Cabinet, said in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, `` On occasion I've felt that we were spending too much time looking backward instead of preparing a human resource policy for the future.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> recently named former <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> as the next labor secretary and _ so far _ the only woman in his Cabinet. But he did not give her what Mrs. <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> thinks the labor secretary needs: a designated spot on his top economic team right alongside the heads of the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> departments and the White House budget office and <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisers </ORGANIZATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON>, during her 14-month Cabinet stint, sought to heighten business awareness of employee needs such as job retraining, flexible hours and child-care assistance, and emphasized the links between education and competitiveness. `` I see the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> as an economic arm,'' she said. `` I think <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is headed there. The question is how do we get to the next step.'' `` The name of the game is going to be competitiveness and unless the incoming labor secretary moves in there and ties the human resource issues with the equation ... we're going to have a skills shortage,'' she said. Mrs. <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON>, in what she calls her holistic approach to workplace issues, has often complained that too many people in government, labor and business are looking backward and constantly fighting over turf. During her brief tenure, Mrs. <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> spent a good part of her time in those skirmishes, fighting her way into them on occasion and sometimes finding herself on the sidelines. It was on her watch that the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> won its first major legislative victories in a decade: a ban on the use of polygraphs or lie detectors by private employers to screen job applicants and mandatory advance notices of plant closings and large layoffs once vetoed by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. With Sens. <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., forming an uncharacteristic but also unstoppable alliance on the first, Mrs. <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> helped persuade the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to acquiesce to the polygraph ban rather than continue opposing it on behalf of some business groups She was relegated to the sidelines on the second, with then-Treasury Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> using the plant closing notices as the primary reason for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to veto legislation overhauling the nation's trade laws. When Republican moderates from northern and midwestern states with large blue-collar constituencies wanted to cut a deal last spring in which labor would get advance notices of plant closings but not other layoffs, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said no. Four months later, with polls showing that more than 80 percent of voters favored advance layoff warnings, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, then <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign chief, persuaded <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to let the notices for both layoffs and plant closings become law without his signature `` Plant closing was bigger than all of us,'' Mrs. <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> said. `` There was never a time when the plant closing situation was really thought through. If I'm remiss, I suppose I should have hollered louder.'' As the former No. 2 official in the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> relished playing the broker, mediating disputes between environmentalists and oil companies and cutting deals on Alaskan and offshore drilling. She tried the same approach at <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION>, finding that while union leaders and business executives spoke glowingly of cooperation, they were often unyielding in practice. `` Organized labor is not there yet in its role of what it can do for itself and this country with regard to training, a quality work force and all the issues of the workplace as we move into the 21st Century,'' she said. `` And they wo n't be there, in my view, if they continue just to back mandated legislation piecemeal to address workers' needs. `` On the other hand, business is n't there yet either. It will hold the line on legislation, just like labor will push it, instead of finding out what's driving these things,'' she said. Mrs. <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> said she will keep speaking out on child care, flextime, education, drugs _ the human resource issues that she says will determine the nation's economic health in the 1990s. She claimed she is not surprised not to have a role in the new administration, although she had declared her availability early. `` I expected <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to find his team, his people,'' she said. `` It's time to leave because I leave on a high. I join a prestigious group of people who were here only a year or two years.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 0018EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-RetirementHomeSlayings     01-02 0241</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Retirement Home Slayings,0248</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Killed, Four Hurt In Retirement Home Attack</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DADE CITY, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two residents of a retirement home were beaten to death and four were injured in an attack early New Year's Day, and police detained an 88-year-old man for questioning, authorities said The man being questioned was regarded as a key witness and was taken into custody Sunday night, said Police Chief <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>. The man has not been ruled out as a suspect, but no charges have been filed, <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. The two killed in the attack in this central <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> city were <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Nickbarge </PERSON>, 90, and <PERSON> Myrtle </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 73. The man in custody shared a room at the house with <PERSON> Nickbarge </PERSON> and with <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Tear </PERSON> <PERSON> Sr. </PERSON>, 89, who suffered a fractured skull and was listed in critical but stable condition Sunday night at <ORGANIZATION> Tampa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, authorities said. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Tear </PERSON> <PERSON> Sr. </PERSON> is the father-in-law of <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Tear </PERSON>, who owns the Reflections I retirement home, where the attacks occurred. The man who was taken into custody was missing when the bodies were found Sunday morning by two nurses, <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. One of the nurses slept through the attacks, which took place between midnight Saturday and 8 a.m. Sunday, <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Esther </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>, 67, was in guarded condition Sunday night following surgery at a hospital here, <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, 85, and <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Godfrey </PERSON>, 71, were in fair condition at a hospital in <LOCATION> Zephyrhills </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     01-02 0668</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0694</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Bochco </PERSON> is developing a TV series about a teen-age doctor, <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> is tailoring his comedy show for Britons and <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> is preparing to make <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Robards </PERSON> and <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> into a father-and-son team. <PERSON> Bochco </PERSON>, one of 36 artists who told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> about their plans for the 1989, said he got some inspiration from his father, who was an accomplished violinist by age 7 or 8. He plans a half-hour series to begin on <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> in September about a 16-year-old doctor. `` It's interesting to think that a 16-year-old kid ca n't buy a six-pack of beer, but he could write you a prescription for morphine,'' said the writer-producer of `` <LOCATION> L.A </LOCATION>. Law.'' <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, whose one-man show `` The World According to Me'' was a hit on Broadway, said he is writing new material about the differences in lifestyles between <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> for the debut of his show in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> in February. `` In <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, politeness is the accent of the whole culture,'' he said. `` I swear if a guy was drowning, he'd be ashamed to holler ` help.''' <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>, whose movie credits include `` Cocoon,'' plans to start filming `` a comedy-drama about several phases of parenthood'' later this month. <PERSON> Robards </PERSON> will play <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s father, <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Moranis </PERSON> will play <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s brother-in-law and <PERSON> Dianne </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiest </PERSON> will play a single mother, he said. `` When you get them all in a room, they actually look like a family,'' <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> <PERSON> Fish </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, who was recently re-elected to his 11th term in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, married <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Tinklepaugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Knauss </PERSON>, a deputy assistant secretary of commerce for intergovernmental affairs. The couple were married Saturday at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Philip </ORGANIZATION>'s Episcopal Church-in-the-Highlands in Garrison. It was the third marriage for Fish, a 62-year-old Republican who represents <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s 21st District. His previous two wives died. The new Mrs. Fish, a longtime <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> activist, directed the 1980 Reagan-Bush campaign in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>. Her previous marriage ended in divorce. The wedding was the second for a Hamilton Fish this year. Fish's father, <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> <PERSON> Sr. </PERSON>, the oldest living former member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> who turned 100 last month, married his live-in housekeeper in September
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tenor <PERSON> Luciano </PERSON> <PERSON> Pavarotti </PERSON> will lead a group of stars in performing with the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Opera </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orchestra </LOCATION> in a benefit for <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. Also appearing in the Jan. 9 gala will be <PERSON> Mariella </PERSON> <PERSON> Devia </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kallen </PERSON> <PERSON> Esperian </PERSON>, <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Verrett </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pietro </PERSON> <PERSON> Ballo </PERSON>, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hampson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sherrill </PERSON> <PERSON> Milnes </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ruggero </PERSON> <PERSON> Raimondi </PERSON>. The artists will perform operatic arias, duets and ensembles with the orchestra. Afterward, they will join guests for a supper party on the promenade of <PERSON> Avery </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, which will be decorated as a Renaissance garden of an Italian palazzo with troubadours in medieval costumes. Proceeds of the black-tie event will benefit the center's Great Performers Series.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HOUSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Bears' <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Ditka </PERSON>, who refused to be sidelined earlier this season by a heart attack, is the most charismatic coach in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Football </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, according to an informal survey. `` He hurls gum, he's back a couple of weeks after a heart attack, he says outrageous things, he mocks opposing fans and stadiums,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Serby </PERSON>, one of 11 writers and broadcasters surveyed by The <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. `` What more do you want?'' The Bears came out as the most charismatic team overall, finishing first in three of the eight other categories in the survey: stadium, unique characters and fans. <ORGANIZATION> Orange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Register </ORGANIZATION> columnist <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Whicker </PERSON> said he would `` love to have a few drinks with the Bears _ and watch them fight.'' The runners-up for the charisma title were <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Falcons </ORGANIZATION> were the most woesome in the charisma leagues, finishing last in seven categories, including the worst uniforms. That vote was n't unanimous, though. <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> columnist <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Kornheiser </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Tampa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bay </ORGANIZATION>'s uniforms are so bad, their players `` look like clerks at Disney World.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     01-02 0459</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0476</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ants, ants and more ants are marching into <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area homes, crawling up Christmas trees and making themselves a nuisance in unprecedented numbers because of winter's sudden onset `` They give me the heebie-jeebies. Last night I came back to find the bathtub black with ants,'' said <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Darling </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Menlo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>. The ants, lured by early December's sun and mild temperatures, were n't ready for the recent wet and cold weather. When the weather changed, they went scurrying inside houses, said <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Neitzel </PERSON>, manager of <ORGANIZATION> Rose </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exterminator </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> `` I ca n't remember when it's been this bad. We're being flooded by calls, absolutely flooded,'' said <PERSON> Neitzel </PERSON>. The insects also were lured inside by Christmas trees, which drip sap and are adorned with candy canes, both of which they find irresistible, exterminators said. `` We spray ... everywhere, but it's only a Band-Aid solution. They always come back,'' said Ms. Darling. Exterminators say the Argentine ants _ the <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area's most common variety _ are hard to get rid of. You may control them for a few weeks, or even months, but the ants will come marching back. `` They were on this planet before us, and they'll definitely outlive all of us,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Pereira </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Jackson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Novato </LOCATION>. `` For people like me, that's what you call job security.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 While others were at home nursing hangovers, the <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>'s icy waters were apparently just what the doctor ordered for those who braved an annual New Year's Day swim. `` It was great!'' said <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Tobin </PERSON> after her first winter swim. `` I said I was going to do it and I did it.'' Forty-nine men and women took to the 29-degree water Sunday morning to celebrate the L Street Brownies swimming club's 85th anniversary. Before they ran down the beach into the water, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Levenson </PERSON>, the club's president, apologized to onlookers for `` the mild weather over which we have no control.'' It was 25 degrees. `` Not bad,'' said <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Binari </PERSON>, 55, as he left the water. Many of the swimmers are longtime members of the swimming club headquartered at the L Street Bathhouse in south <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. Some, like <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Graney </PERSON>, 75, <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, 82, and <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Alecks </PERSON>, 77, have been swimming in the harbor year-round for decades. `` We do it for health reasons,'' said <PERSON> Graney </PERSON>. `` It's a discipline. We do it every day, like joggers. Some days we have to chop the ice away before we go in.'' <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jurzynski </PERSON>, 37, scoffed at questions about the cleanliness of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>, which was an issue in last year's presidential campaign. `` The yuppies go to the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>; we have the crystal clear waters of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Jurzynski </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 2354EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Czechoslovakia-Defection     01-02 0238</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Czechoslovakia-Defection,0247</SECOND>
<HEAD>Czechoslovak Hockey Star In Custody Of Canadian Immigration</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CALGARY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 17-year-old Czechoslovakian hockey star who wants to play in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hockey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> was in the custody of Canadian immigration officials when his teammates flew back home Monday, tournament officials said. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Nedved </PERSON> had disappeared from his billet's residence early Monday morning. `` He is currently in the hand of the immigration people,'' said <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Mac </ORGANIZATION>'s Midget Hockey Tournament. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said he does n't know whether the 6-foot-2, 165-pound forward has asked to stay in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Nedved </PERSON> said in a weekend interview he wanted to return to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> as a visitor but would `` prefer to play here.'' He led the tournament in scoring and his club, <PERSON> Litvinov </PERSON>, won the event. Spokesmen for the <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> could not be reached, and a spokesman for the External Affairs Department in <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION> said he had no information about <PERSON> Nedved </PERSON>. His father played on <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s national team alongside his current coach <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Beranek </PERSON>. An older brother also played before being drafted into the army. That fate would await <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>. `` I should have a better chance to play for the national team, every boy hopes to play for it,'' he said through an interpreter. His dream also includes the <ORGANIZATION> NHL </ORGANIZATION>. `` I do n't plan that far ahead,'' he said with a smile. `` But I'll be able to give you a better answer in five years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PoliceDeaths     01-02 0212</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Police Deaths,190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Deaths of Police Officers Down Slightly In 1988</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The number of police officers who died in the line of duty in 1988 fell slightly to 153, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday. The national total was 155 the year before. Eight women officers were included in the 1988 total; three women officers died the year before. In 1988, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> led the nation with a loss of 23 officers, followed by 21 in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, where five died in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> alone, and 13 in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>, president of the association, said many police killers were on alcohol or drugs. Of the officers killed, 75 died of gun shot wounds, 58 in traffic chases and accidents and the rest in plane crashes, stabbings, drownings and other causes in the line of duty. Their average age was 27. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Arenberg </PERSON>, a spokesman for the association, said the 153 deaths included a broad range of law enforcement officials from county sheriff deputies and local police to <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and corrections officers. The association has maintained an <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fame </ORGANIZATION> listing all officers killed since 1960 when 55 died. In 1988, one office died every 57 hours. On average, 157 are wounded or injured every day.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Rehnquist     01-02 0408</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rehnquist,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chief Justice Backs 51 Percent Pay Raise For Jurists</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Chief Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> has strongly endorsed a proposal to raise federal judges' salaries by 51 percent to $ 135,000 a year. In his 1988 year-end report on the federal judiciary, <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> threw his weight behind a presidential commission's recommendation of big pay raises for judges and about 2,000 other top federal officials. Besides calling for the pay raise for trial judges, who now make $ 89,500, the commission recommended boosting salaries of federal appeals court judges from $ 95,000 to $ 140,000, a 47 percent jump; of <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> associate justices from $ 110,000 to $ 165,000, a 50 percent increase; and of the chief justice from $ 115,000 to $ 175,000, a 52 percent increase. The recommendations are pending before President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who can accept or modify the figures before sending his fiscal 1990 budget to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Jan. 9. Under the law, whatever pay increases the president endorses will take effect 30 days later unless both the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> vote to set them aside. `` Over the past two decades, the purchasing power of federal judicial salaries has been seriously eroded by inflation,'' <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> said. The buying power of an appeals court judge's salary has dropped 30 percent in the past 20 years, said the chief justice, adding, `` While the salary of the median household has increased approximately 200 percent to keep pace with inflation since 1969, the salaries of federal -LRB- trial -RRB- judges rose by little more than half that amount.'' <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> cited a recent <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> survey in which 30 percent of the federal judges who responded said they planned to resign before retirement unless `` a significant increase in compensation'' is provided. `` Dozens of federal judges have resigned from the bench during the past 15 years, far more than ever before, due in large part to financial reasons,'' <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> said. `` And the problem appears to be growing worse.'' He said judicial salaries are directly linked to `` the quality of American justice.'' Comparing justice and medical care, <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> said, `` We are interested in receiving the best medical care available. If the quality of medical treatment is poor, it is little consolation that the cost may be low.'' He added: `` The right to one's day in court is meaningless if the judge who hears the case lacks the talent, experience and temperament that will enable him to protect imperiled rights and to render a fair decision.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FerretHalfwayHouse     01-02 0424</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ferret Halfway House,0440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Unwanted Ferrets Find Shelter at Halfway House</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto CX8</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Deep in the basement of a suburban family home, 220 ferrets from all around the country frolic with toy balls, crawl tubes and other ferret-phernalia in a makeshift halfway house for the weasel-like creatures. The ferrets, unwanted by their owners or between homes, are the pride and joy of <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dahm </PERSON>, who keeps 14 of her own upstairs. It started 18 months ago when a group of concerned Chicago-area ferret-lovers formed the <ORGANIZATION> Greater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ferret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dahm </PERSON>, the only founding officer with a basement, was asked to run the association's shelter. She agreed. So when a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> woman recently asked her veterinarian what to do with two ferrets her older son had outgrown, she was told to head for the <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dahm </PERSON> home. There, the ferrets live in cages until a new owner is found. `` We've gotten ferrets from all over the country,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dahm </PERSON>, who prefers to keep the location of her home a secret so as not to disturb the neighbors. Some were transported from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. A batch from <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> arrived after animal-welfare officials seized 19 ferrets from a <LOCATION> Louisville-area </LOCATION> woman who kept them in a cramped back-yard shed. Others come from disenchanted owners. `` It was not what I expected,'' one woman said, complaining that her ferret did not like to sit in her lap to be stroked like a cat. `` They are more exotic than dogs or cats,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dahm </PERSON> said. `` They are good for apartment dwellers because they are small and can be kept in cages most of the time. `` They also have a bit of a wild look, and they do n't provoke allergies,'' she said. Of the nation's estimated 5 million pet ferrets, about 10,000 live in the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> area, said <PERSON> Janice </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Greater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ferret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> based in suburban <LOCATION> Westchester </LOCATION>. She said the association was formed because `` so much was unknown'' about ferrets. `` We wanted to say, ` Hey, these little guys are n't so bad.'' Ferret lovers say the animal's reputation as a sometimes vicious biter is unfounded. They are often mistakenly considered rodents but related to weasels and mink. Like cats, they can be trained to use litter boxes and will eat cat food. `` They have a strong will to survive,'' said <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Westchester </LOCATION> veterinarian and another association member. `` They are easy to work with. I'm seldom bitten. In fact, I'm bitten far more often by iguanas and birds.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890102-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-02-89 0108EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Hungary-Parliament Bjt   01-02 0726</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hungary-Parliament, Bjt,0750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hungary's Parliament No Longer Just A Rubber Stamp</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TEDDIE WEYR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
