<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 2327EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-EastGermany-Trial     11-24 0168</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-East Germany-Trial,0171</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former East German Policeman Jailed For Hurting Protester</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EAST BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former East German policeman was sentenced to 14 months in prison Friday for injuring a protester detained during a pro-democracy mass demonstration last month, the state news agency <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> said. An <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> court also ordered the man, identified by ADN only as <PERSON> Horst </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON>, to pay damages to be set later. Police attending the sentencing shouted their complaints, calling out `` Corrupt!'' and `` Now you have your show trial!,'' ADN said. The policeman was found guilty of causing bodily harm when he pushed the man down stairs at a police station after taking him into custody during a demonstration Oct. 7. The ruling said the act was not deliberate, <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> said. Demonstrations in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> and other cities led to the ouster of hard-line <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>. The agency said the defendant was 41 and referred to him as a `` former policeman,'' indicating he was dismissed from the force.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 2337EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Czechoslovakia 9thLd-Writethru a0736 11-24 1178</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Czechoslovakia, 9th Ld - Writethru, a0736,1206</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hard-line Communist Leaders Resign; Dubcek in Triumphant Return</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Inserts 4 grafs after 8th pvs bgng: Later, when he... with editor
saying doubts Dubcek could rejoin the party, no immediate comment from
student leaders, ADDS background on planned strike Monday. Strike plans
uncertain. Pickup 9th graf: Urbanek, 48....</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALISON SMALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PRAGUE, Czechoslovakia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The hard-line <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief and ruling <ORGANIZATION> Politburo </ORGANIZATION> resigned Friday, forced from power by a week of massive pro-democracy protests that surpassed even the `` <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> Spring'' of 1968. <PERSON> Milos </PERSON> <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON> became the third Soviet bloc leader to be swept out of office in a stunning five-week wave of political upheaval that has washed over the Communist world in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. The party <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> elected little-known <PERSON> Karel </PERSON> <PERSON> Urbanek </PERSON>, member of the party's Politburo only since October 1988, to replace <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON> who resigned along with the rest of the 13-man Politburo and Secretariat. At the end of a 16-hour closed-door session that lasted until early Saturday the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> reshuffled the Politburo, shrinking it to nine members. It elected <PERSON> Urbanek </PERSON> and five holdovers along with three new men, <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Cizek </PERSON>, <PERSON> Miroslav </PERSON> <PERSON> Huscava </PERSON> and <PERSON> Miroslav </PERSON> <PERSON> Zajic </PERSON>. Premier <PERSON> Ladislav </PERSON> <PERSON> Adamec </PERSON>, who broke with years of policy this week by meeting opposition activists, was among those Politburo members who lost their seats, meaning a new premier will likely be named soon. Thousands of people poured into <LOCATION> Wenceslas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> Friday night, dancing, singing and popping champagne corks at the news of the resignations. The celebration _ one week after police clubbed peaceful protesters _ capped a day in which 300,000 people jammed the square for the triumphant return of <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON>, the bold reformer ousted in 1968. `` An old wise man said, ` If there once was light, why should there be darkness again?' Let us act in such a way to bring the light back again,'' <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON> had told the jubilant crowd. Later, when he heard the news of the resignations, <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON> and top dissidents at a news conference jumped to their feet, shouted `` Hooray!'' and hugged each other joyously. After the Soviet-led <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact invasion of <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> in August 1968 <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON> was ousted from the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in disgrace. <PERSON> Zdenek </PERSON> <PERSON> Horeni </PERSON>, editor in chief of the party newspaper Rude Pravo, held a news conference early Saturday after the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> meeting ended and he was asked about <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON>'s future. He said <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON> `` was expelled because he completely failed as party and state representative. I personally doubt that <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON> could possibly be readmitted to the Czechslovak party.'' There was no immediate response to the resignations from student and intellectual leaders who had called for a general strike on Monday to force <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON> to step down. <PERSON> Urbanek </PERSON>, 48, is the former party leader of the Czech republic. He was a surprise choice to replace <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON> and represented a break with the rigid policies in place since the invasion. His selection, on a vote of 136-7, seemed designed to boost the party's flagging standing after a week of nationwide calls for its reform-resistant leaders to resign. <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON> said the party had not instituted reforms quickly enough and had underestimated the effect of the pro-democracy movement sweeping <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said it hoped <PERSON> Urbanek </PERSON> `` will act swiftly to address the long-awaited desires of the <LOCATION> Czechoslovakian </LOCATION> people for civil liberties, political freedom and basic human rights.'' British Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, also in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said: `` We have great hopes that <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> will also become a democracy.'' In a terse dispatch, the official news agency <ORGANIZATION> CTK </ORGANIZATION> announced: `` The general secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Czechoslovak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Milos </PERSON> <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON>, and all other members of the Politburo and Secretariat submitted their resignations so that a new leadership of the party could be elected. <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON> said he hoped the newly elected organs of the party will contribute to a more resolute implementation of the process of restructuring and democratization.'' Restructuring and democratization have been key terms used by Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, who has inspired the reforms that have swept through his own nation, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s leaders, who were installed after the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact invasion, had resisted most of the reforms adopted by their formerly hard-line <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> allies. Earlier this year, however, they allowed thousands of East German refugees to pass through <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> on their way to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Since Nov. 17, hundreds of thousands of people have filled the streets of <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> and other cities demanding democratic reforms and the end of the Communists' monopoly on power. They have been the largest demonstrations in the nation's history. `` For a week, our capital lives in a feverish atmosphere accompanied by large demonstrations,'' <ORGANIZATION> CTK </ORGANIZATION> quoted <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON> as saying. `` The tension is gradually spreading to other places in the republic. We must openly say that our country is at a fateful crossroads.'' `` We have underestimated completely the processes taking place in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and especially recently in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and their effect and influence on our society,'' said <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON>, who was responsible for the expulsion from the party of half a million Communists, including <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON>. In December 1987, <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON> was named <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief to succeed <PERSON> Gustav </PERSON> <PERSON> Husak </PERSON>, who came to power in April 1969, eight months after the invasion. <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON>, 67, was seen as a bureaucrat and party functionary whose speeches and personality have made little or no public impact despite his long years in high office. <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON>, 67, made his first public appearance in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> since the party purge in June 1970. Since his ouster, he has worked as a low-level employee of the state forestry services and has lived in virtual seclusion. `` Dubcek, <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON>!'' and `` Long live <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON>!'' the flag-waving crowd yelled as he appeared in <LOCATION> Wenceslas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, the site of repeated pro-democracy demonstrations. He urged them to unite to improve the country. `` The ideal of socialism with a human face is living in the conditions of a new generation,'' <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON> said. `` We must unify to raise our country to a higher level.'' Pro-democracy demonstrations also were held in the cities of <LOCATION> Bratislava </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brno </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kosice </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ostrava </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Usti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> nad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labem </ORGANIZATION>, according to state-run media. <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON> threw his support behind the Civil Forum, an opposition group formed Sunday to guide <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s pro-democracy movement. He appealed to police, militia and the army `` to stand by the people's side,'' and not to destroy the search for democracy. `` Do not act against the people. Remember, you are from the people,'' <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON> said. He also told demonstrators to `` avoid extremist trends.'' Riot police beat hundreds of peaceful demonstrators in the square on Nov. 17, sparking a week of growing protests. Police have kept a generally low profile since then. Playwright <PERSON> Vaclav </PERSON> <PERSON> Havel </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s most prominent dissident, then spoke to the crowd and told them that Civic Forum `` is ready to negotiate with the authorities elsewhere than on the streets.'' `` But it's not up to us, but to them, whether democracy will arise from the excited atmosphere on the square. It is their turn to move, not ours,'' <PERSON> Havel </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0015EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Philippines-Drugs     11-24 0754</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Philippines-Drugs,0777</SECOND>
<HEAD>Filipinos Concerned About Growing Drug Trade</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CLARO CORTES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A growing drug trade has led to concern that the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> is in danger of becoming the <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> of the <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. Calls are going out for tougher laws and the death penalty for drug dealers. Police say the illegal drug trade has become a $ 41 million-a-year business in recent years. The three largest drug syndicates employ about 15,000 people fulltime, according to police estimates. The trade comes nowhere near that of <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s multibillion-dollar drug cartels, but experts here say most of the narcotics produced in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> are used locally But Filipino and foreign experts fear the country could become a major regional drug center because of a favorable climate for growing marijuana, corruption and inefficiency within the police and established trade and communications links to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and other markets. In October, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agents in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> seized two tons of Philippine-grown marijuana worth $ 14 million in what was believed to be an attempt to establish a pipeline between <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Two Americans of Filipino ancestry were arrested recently in <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> for allegedly trying to smuggle in two pounds of the drug crystal methamphetamine, a widely abused drug known in <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> as `` shabu'' and said by officials and drug experts to be more addictive than crack. Philippine-grown marijuana and other drugs also have turned up, albeit in modest amounts, in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> and some <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> countries, police say. Foreign and Filipino narcotics officials say syndicates have been bringing in foreigners, mostly Europeans, to teach growers here how to grow better quality marijuana. Last year, police uprooted 15 million marijuana plants and seized 7.5 tons of marijuana packed for shipment abroad. `` If we do not do something about this, there might come a time when we will see the spectacle of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> becoming like <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, where drug lords even have armies, helicopters, planes and even tanks,'' Sen. <PERSON> Alberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Romulo </PERSON> said at a recent Philippine <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> hearing. Public concern over the problem began to grow in October after Sen. <PERSON> Ernesto </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrera </PERSON> charged that at least 17 police and military members, including a brigadier general, were protecting drug lords. According to the police, the drug trade is flourishing because of the potential for huge profits in a country where the annual per capita income is only about $ 600. Marijuana can be bought in remote mountain plantations for 200 pesos -LRB- $ 9 -RRB- a kilo -LRB- 2.2 pounds -RRB- and sold in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> for 10 times as much. <PERSON> Shabu </PERSON>, the crystaline drug, can be purchased in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> for about $ 2,270 a kilo and sold in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> for the equivalent of $ 45,450. Sources say some shabu also is being made locally. Corruption among police and customs officials is said to compound the enforcement problem. Col. <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON>, chief of the national police <ORGANIZATION> Narcotics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, said his unit is riddled with corruption because poorly paid policemen find it difficult to turn down bribes from drug syndicates. He said at least 40 of his officers and men had been removed in an attempt to combat corruption. <PERSON> David </PERSON> and others say stronger laws and greater police powers are needed in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. `` In <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, if you go there and the police doubt your papers, they can just detain you,'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> said. `` That is the same case in <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>. They have stronger laws that empower the police to arrest anybody based only on strong suspicion that they are a violators of the law. We must have the same kind of laws here.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> said the military has urged <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to revive the death penalty for drug dealers. The Constitution, ratified in 1987, abolished capital punishment but allows <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to revive it for `` heinous'' crimes. He also said the government should establish special courts to handle only drug offenses to speed up trials, which often drag on here for years. Because of legal obstacles in enforcing the laws, critics say, police often simply execute big-time dealers and then report that they were killed in a `` shootout.'' In the <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> area alone, at least 22 drug pushers have been killed in `` shootouts'' with police since <PERSON> Herrera </PERSON> made his charges about the police and military in October. Sen. <PERSON> Neptali </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, a former justice secretary, said the killings should persuade drug dealers to turn themselves in and seek government protection. `` Otherwise, they may soon find themselves targets of elimination,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0016EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WonderChemical     11-24 1177</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wonder Chemical,1208</SECOND>
<HEAD>Industry Seeks to Define Life Absent CFCs</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> is trying to stuff a bigger air conditioner into its cars, while <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> is revising decades-old assembly line practices. The changes come as industry, under pressure from government and environmentalists, seeks to eliminate the use of chlorofluorocarbons, the one-time wonder chemical that has been destroying the Earth's ozone layer. But the task is more complicated than simply replacing an old chemical with a new one, government and industry experts say. `` The transition is going to take time ... We're talking about retrofitting not one industry, but several industries,'' says F.A. `` Tony'' <PERSON> Vogelsberg </PERSON>, environmental manager for the Freon Division at <ORGANIZATION> Du </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pont </ORGANIZATION>, a major producers of CFCs. CFCs, discovered in 1928, help cool houses in the summer and keep them warm in the winter. They are used to make the foam cushions on couches, in pillows _ even in stuffed toys. Without them, refrigerators would not cool as well; radios, televisions, stereos or home computers might not work as well, and items from coaxial cables to mailed Christmas gifts might not have as much packaging protection. But CFCs also have a dark side: When they float 10 to 30 miles above the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> to the stratosphere, their chlorine component eats away at the ozone shield that protects against the sun's cancer-causing ultraviolet rays Industrial nations want to ban all CFC production within the next decade. But while a half-dozen or more replacements are under study, they all have some drawbacks and no single substitute is expected to be found. `` I do n't think there's going to be a substitute that is going to be given an A-plus on all -LRB- areas of concern -RRB-,'' said <PERSON> Eileen </PERSON> <PERSON> Claussen </PERSON>, director of atmospheric and indoor air programs at the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. `` We're going to have to make some tradeoffs.'' The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> is examining the array of substitutes, mainly a family of chemicals called HCFCs, to determine whether they are toxic or pose other health concerns and how significantly they harm the environment. The HCFCs also deplete ozone but much less severely. `` We clearly do not want to blunder along and create a new health or environmental problem while solving the ones that we targeted,'' said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Elkins </PERSON>, whose EPA office is reviewing the potential toxicity of some <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> substitutes. Every year more than 2 billion pounds of CFCs are produced worldwide, a third of them in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> banned use of the chemical in aerosol cans in 1978, four years after the first concerns about the ozone layer were raised. Still, the operation of more than $ 135 billion worth of equipment nationwide is dependent on CFCs. Industry turned to CFCs because they do not burn or corrode metal, pose no direct health hazards to workers and hold heat and cold, making them ideal insulators. That was before their threat to the ozone layer was understood. Half of the ozone over <LOCATION> Antarctica </LOCATION> was destroyed during September and October 1987, causing a hole in the Earth's protective shield that closes and reappears with the seasons. Severe destruction of the ozone layer is believed to be occurring over the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pole </LOCATION> again this year, according to scientists. They say the conditions for ozone destruction are present over the <LOCATION> Arctic </LOCATION>, although no massive loss of ozone has been observed there. Several large corporations have announced plans to end their reliance on CFCs, some by the early 1990s. These include such giants as <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T, <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION>. `` We have used <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> solvents and cleaners for so long they're almost ingrained in the manufacturing process,'' says <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Chittick </PERSON>, vice president for environment and safety at AT & amp; T. Nevertheless, <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T hopes to end all uses of CFCs by 1994 The major automakers are developing substitutes and are designing new air conditioning units to accommodate the changeover, probably in the mid-1990s. But the new air conditioners will be less energy efficient and require larger compressors, experts say. `` We feel we can do it without any dramatic effects on the look or design of the car. It's going to be difficult though,'' says <PERSON> Toni </PERSON> <PERSON> Simonetti </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is considering legislation calling for the elimination of CFCs by the year 2000 and at least 20 states are reviewing proposals aimed at curbing <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> pollution. <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> has banned the use of CFCs in auto air conditioners after 1994. <PERSON> Du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> has spent more than $ 100 million on research for <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> substitutes and estimates it will spend as much as $ 1 billion to build production plants and to cover other costs during a 10-year transition period. <ORGANIZATION> ICI </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Americas </ORGANIZATION>, another major manufacturer, also has spent $ 100 million in <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> replacement research and recently announced plans to begin production of a substitute cooling agent by 1992 at a new <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> plant. But developing substitute chemicals will not be enough. As much as 30 percent of today's <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> demand will have to be eliminated by conservation and recycling, government and industry experts say. Major appliance manufacturers as well as automakers recently have supplied their repair shops with equipment to capture CFCs rather than let the old coolant vent into the air. But EPA and industry officials acknowledge that routine venting of old CFCs is still widespread. Shifts to new manufacturing procedures or altogether new technology could account for a 30 percent reduction in <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> demand, especially in the electronics industry, the experts say. But some critics say that industry is slow to accept new technology. `` What we're facing is inertia,'' says <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Crynodynamics </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey-based </LOCATION> company that is producing a refrigeration system using helium as a cooling agent. The system is being marketed primarily for commercial uses. The major automakers have expressed little interest. Companies such as <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T and <ORGANIZATION> Northern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecom </ORGANIZATION> are turning to new manufacturing procedures such as using low-solid fluxes to reduce leftover residues and eliminate the need for CFCs as a solvent for cleaning circuit boards after soldering. `` This -LRB- CFC problem -RRB- has caused a whole new review of the way we do business,'' says <PERSON> A.D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>, director of environmental affairs at <ORGANIZATION> Northern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecom </ORGANIZATION>, a Canadian-based manufacturer of telephone equipment. The thorniest problems have emerged in the area of refrigeration and air conditioning because all substitutes under consideration pose energy and environmental tradeoffs, particularly in the area of global warming. A bill putting a time limit on use of HCFCs as substitutes for chlorofluorocarbons has been approved by a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> environmental subcommittee, but its prospects in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are uncertain. Environmentalists say, meanwhile, that even the less potent HCFCs would be a dangerous threat to ozone depletion if the amount used worldwide is dramatically increased over the next century. The <ORGANIZATION> HCFC </ORGANIZATION> family of substitutes should be looked at only as a `` bridge'' solution and industry should not be allowed to `` sit back and be happy once they made the one-step transition,'' says <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Doniger </PERSON>, an attorney for the <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0017EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-PerezEsquivel     11-24 0771</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Perez Esquivel,0794</SECOND>
<HEAD>Human Rights Activist Says Effort Continues to `Silence' His Work</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED McCULLOUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Arriving at work one recent morning, <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Esquivel </PERSON>, winner of the 1980 Nobel Peace Prize, found his office had been vandalized. An interior door was smashed open, and thieves took a computer, files and typewriters from his workplace in a dilapidated building in a run-down neighborhood. `` They were n't common criminals, but ... the forces of national insecurity,'' the human rights advocate said in an interview. `` They stole everything and the police did absolutely nothing.'' <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Esquivel </PERSON>, 59, recounted the incident matter-of-factly, convinced the break-in stemmed from his vocal opposition to an Oct. 7 presidential pardon of soldiers accused of human rights abuses, and his efforts to call attention to society's downtrodden. `` The Nobel Prize opened a lot of doors and possibilities, except in my own country, where ... an effort continues to permanently silence our work,'' he said. The mild mannered, slightly built son of a Spanish fisherman taught architecture at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plata </ORGANIZATION> until he became enmeshed in human rights causes during <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>'s turbulent 1970s. While leftists with guns and bombs tried to bring down the elected government of President <PERSON> Isabel </PERSON> <PERSON> Peron </PERSON> and the military regime that succeeded it, <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Esquivel </PERSON> preached social change through non-violence. In 1973, he founded the <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, which has branches in 11 Latin American countries. Two years later, he helped set up the <ORGANIZATION> Permanent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION>. Both organizations protested the arrests and presumed killings of thousands of alleged leftists who `` disappeared'' during the 1976-83 dictatorship. Despite the work of his organizations and his detention without charges for 15 months in 1977 and 1978, <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Esquivel </PERSON> was little known even in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> when the Nobel Committee announced his name in October 1980. Since then, <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Esquivel </PERSON> has achieved a certain international stature, although nothing like that of other Nobel laureates such as <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON>, <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> or Archbishop <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON>. These days, <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Esquivel </PERSON> puts together proposals to raise funds from churches and agencies in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, travels and writes. He and a small staff, mostly volunteers, help poor people get legal title to land on which they work or live, set up shelters for abandoned children, organize soup kitchens and clothing drives for the needy. Most any rally in support of democracy, civil rights or social welfare can count on his presence, his signature on petitions, his voice. `` He genuinely feels his ideals,'' said the director of the human rights group <ORGANIZATION> Legal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Emilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Mignone </PERSON>, a friend for 15 years. `` He is a very simple man ... ethical, generous.'' <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Esquivel </PERSON> also can be disorganized and quixotic, however, and that, colleagues say, has hampered his effectiveness. His Peace and <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> is neither the biggest nor most prestigious human rights group in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>. Leaders of other groups _ who also protested, at personal risk, the atrocities of the `` dirty war'' against leftist subversion _ hoped <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Esquivel </PERSON>'s distinction would make it easier to influence popular opinion and public policy. That has not happened. The government treats <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Esquivel </PERSON> as a gadfly, and his Peace and <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> lacks the staff and the clout to deliver people to rallies or push an idea in the public consciousness. `` He's more important internationally'' than in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Hebe </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonafini </PERSON>, a founder another human rights group, the Mothers of the Plaza de Mayo. `` I think he could have done more things. ... Before, he had more impact than now.'' <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Esquivel </PERSON>'s politics are openly left of center. Companies and natural resources should be kept in state hands even if they lose money or the government has no ability to exploit them, he says, criticizing plans to privatize them. The foreign debt is unpayable, he says, workers should receive higher salaries, businesses should be compelled to be more productive, the government should insist that capital flight cease, weapons manufacturers should be convinced to make non-lethal products. And the servicemen who committed human rights abuses should be tried by elected President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Menem </PERSON>'s government, he says, despite open resistence from sectors of the armed forces. Despite the seriousness of his causes, his maintains a cheerful disposition and says he bears no hatred to those who imprisoned him or threatened him, his wife or his three children. `` I'm optimistic by nature,'' he said. `` I try to contribute, to make things a little better. ... I hope my life has been useful.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0019EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MessyEaters     11-24 0272</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Messy Eaters,0280</SECOND>
<HEAD>Table Manners 101: Remove the Tables</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BIRMINGHAM, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An assistant principal who got fed up with his students' sloppy habits tried to teach them a lesson in table manners by taking away the cafeteria tables. Teens in two of the three lunch periods at <ORGANIZATION> Erwin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> ate on the floor Wednesday after Assistant Principal <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> ordered the tables taken down. `` What we did today we did to get their attention,'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said. `` I hope we got it.'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said school administrators had warned students for two weeks to clean up after themselves or risk losing their tables. `` The problem has been that we've had some pigs eating in the cafeteria _ at least you might call them that from the look of the place after they finish,'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said. But some students and their parents found the tactic severe. `` The floor is something people walk on, not eat on. It's nasty,'' said <PERSON> Mandy </PERSON> <PERSON> DeWitt </PERSON>, a junior who left school rather than dine on the linoleum `` They are punishing all of us for the actions of a few and that's not right.'' Her mother, <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> DeWitt </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> punished a `` lot of kids who did nothing wrong and I think, they forgot they were dealing with children, not prisoners in a war camp.'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> responded: `` The students were not kept from eating. What we were trying to teach them is that there are consequences for their actions.'' <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON>, another junior who left school at lunchtime, said the action was ill-timed as well as unfair, because she and other students had donated blood that day.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Afghan-Soviet     11-24 0948</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghan-Soviet,0978</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Carry Out Huge Aid Program for Afghanistan</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is conducting one of the largest aid programs in its history to support the government in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, transporting billions of dollars in weapons, food and fuel to the war-torn nation. Beginning at least one year before the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> withdrew in February 1989, the operation has brought hundreds of thousands of tons of commodities to <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, the state-run press has reported. Another $ 3 billion in military aid, including advanced weapons, is supplied annually, Eastern European diplomats said. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> gives the anti-government guerrillas an estimated $ 500 million worth of arms a year. `` If we did n't have food from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, we would starve,'' says <PERSON> Massuma </PERSON> <PERSON> Esmaty </PERSON> <PERSON> Wardak </PERSON>, president of the <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> Women's Council. `` We have no one else to turn to.'' The massive operation indicates the commitment <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> has made to the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government, which came to power in a bloody Communist coup in 1978. Soviet troops arrived the following year to prop up the faltering Marxist regime. After the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> ended its decade-long military intervention in February, Western diplomats predicted a quick victory for the guerrillas. But <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> did n't fall. The rebels failed to unite, and Soviet aid gave the government the firepower and food it needed. `` The West underestimated the Soviet commitment. Everyone thought the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> was retreating and had lost the war,'' said one diplomat, who has been counting transport planes and trucks for the past nine months. `` Only now do we know how serious the Russians really were.'' For their aid, the Soviets get a pliant government on its southern border that helps offset neighboring <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s Islamic fundamentalism and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s pro-Americanism. In late October, the Daily <PERSON> Payam </PERSON>, official organ of the ruling <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Afghanistan </ORGANIZATION>, published an unusually detailed account of Soviet aid. From February to August, it said, 266,543 metric tons of Soviet goods crossed through the border town of <LOCATION> Hayratan </LOCATION>. Among the goods, more than 40,000 tons of fuel, 82,000 tons of wheat, 1,000 tons of cooking oil, 900 tons of sugar and 540 tons of flour rolled into <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> on more than 21,000 Soviet trucks, the newspaper said. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> says another 220,000 tons of Soviet-supplied flour, some of it purchased from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, is in the pipeline. Also since February, 168,750 tons of goods have arrived in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> aboard 6,750 Soviet transport planes, diplomats said. Diplomats estimated that until recently the airlift contained 75 percent weapons and 25 percent food. But Afghan officials reportedly have asked that the food portion be raised to 40 percent in view of the coming winter and the country's serious transportation problems, caused by war, bad roads and harsh weather. To help with this problem, the Soviets recently gave <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> 2,200 heavy duty trucks, the state-run <ORGANIZATION> Bakhtar </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported last month. Tens of thousands of vehicles had already been left behind by the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> when it pulled out. Diplomats said the duration and size of the operation make it one of the biggest aid programs in Soviet history, rivaled only by Soviet aid to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. `` The costs are tremendous and we believe that not even <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> knows how much it is paying,'' said one high-ranking <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> diplomat whose country is friendly with both <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. In the military sphere, diplomats in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> say that since 1988, about $ 200 million to $ 300 million in weapons have been crossing the Soviet border each month. Diplomats from two Eastern European countries who provided the $ 3 billion annual estimate said <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> has promised to provide <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> with two advanced weapons: the Scud-500, an updated version of the medium-range missiles already supplied to <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, and the MiG-29, an advanced combat jet. The Soviets already have given <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> more than 150 planes for its air force, mostly MiG-21 fighters. <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> also has received air defense rockets, according to the April 29 edition of the state-run <ORGANIZATION> Kabul </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, which carried a photograph of the weapons on its front page. Some diplomats challenged attempts to estimate the value of Soviet military aid because accounting methods vary from country to country. Diplomats in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> say <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> has fired 1,000 Scud missiles in the past year at the rebels. Each rocket costs about $ 1 million on the arms market, bringing the Scuds' total cost to $ 1 billion. But they contend the missiles are valueless because <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> probably would have destroyed the weapons, which were orginally built to carry nuclear warheads and use 1960s technology. In addition to aid, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> occupies a commanding position in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s economy. Soviet economic ties account for 60 percent of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s state budget and 75 percent of its industrial output, the Daily <PERSON> Payam </PERSON> said in November Soviet assistance is used in the production of 100 percent of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s natural gas, 100 percent of its chemical fertilizer and 60 percent of its electricity, the <PERSON> Payam </PERSON> said. Since the 1954 signing of the first Afghan-Soviet long term credit agreement, <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> has had close economic ties with <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. Soviet aid built housing, roads and bridges, and generated power. In 1956, the two nations signed an agreement for the training and modernization of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s armed forces. The military led the Communist revolution in 1978. Since the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> intervention, <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> has become increasingly isolated economically. The U.S.-backed rebels have cut the road to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, which carried flour and cooking oil. Trade with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> is minimal. Among the industrialized nations only <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, which exports about $ 100 million a year, has substantial economic ties.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0022EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-UkrainianCardinal     11-24 0797</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ukrainian Cardinal,0820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cardinal Hopes Gorbachev-Pope Meeting Will Lead To Legalization</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEPHEN R. WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` I am numb from all those years of waiting, waiting in vain,'' says Cardinal <PERSON> Myroslav </PERSON> <PERSON> Lubachivsky </PERSON>. But the wait is nearly over. Few perhaps have more riding on Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>'s meeting Dec. 1 with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> than <PERSON> Lubachivsky </PERSON>, head of the Ukrainian <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. The historic encounter holds out the prospect that the Ukrainian church will be legalized after 43 years of suppression, and <PERSON> Lubachivsky </PERSON> will be able to return to his homeland for the first time in 51 years. `` We're optimistic about it, yes,'' the 75-year-old former metropolitan-archbishop of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> said in an interview. `` But to have too much hope, too much trust is not good. There is a Polish proverb: ` Hope is mother of the stupid people.' So it's better just to be practical and wait to see what happens. Still, <PERSON> Lubachivsky </PERSON> sees concrete signs the pope's talks with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will pave the way for legalization of the Ukrainian church in the next two months. He said information coming from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> indicates the government has already approved the basis of a new law on religion, which would give all churches the same legal status under the Constitution. `` We expect this will become law around the middle or end of January,'' <PERSON> Lubachivsky </PERSON> said. He says Soviet authorities have adopted a much more tolerant attitude toward the Ukrainian Catholics in the past few months, allowing them to celebrate Mass in public, import Bibles and communicate by fax with church groups in the West. It is in <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s interests to legalize the church of more than 4 million followers in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s second largest republic, the cardinal said. `` If Mr. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> would like to have the moral support of the Holy Father, this is the condition that he could get it,'' <PERSON> Lubachivsky </PERSON> said. `` He needs this. He'll also have the support from the Western countries. He needs the money from the West.'' Legalizing the Ukrainian church could also lead to the first papal visit to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> frequently has expressed the wish to travel to the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>. `` We would invite him as soon as we are free,'' <PERSON> Lubachivsky </PERSON> said. `` I think he would not refuse.'' <PERSON> Lubachivsky </PERSON> credits the Polish-born <PERSON> pope </PERSON>, a fellow Slav, for helping bring the Ukrainian church out of the catacombs and to the brink of legalization. `` He is the greatest friend of ours and he has always assured me he would be staying fast for the legalization of our church,'' he said. Ukrainian Catholics practice the Byzantine, or Eastern, rite but look to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> for guidance and recognize the authority of the pope. The Ukrainian church, which traces its history to the introduction of Christianity in the region 1,000 years ago, was suppressed in 1946 by Soviet dictator <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>. It was forcibly merged with the Russian Orthodox Church and its clergy were arrested, deported or shot. The church continued to flourish underground, however, with priests and bishops ordained and consecrated in secret. Encouraged by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s glasnost policies, church officials and faithful have come out in the open in the past two years to demand official recognition. Church officials in the West estimate there are 12 <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> bishops, 1,000 priests and 1,200 monks and nuns in the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Lubachivsky </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Dolyna </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION>, in 1914. He left in 1937 when the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION> was under Polish occupation to study in <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. He moved to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1947 and became an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> citizen. The pope appointed <PERSON> Lubachivsky </PERSON> as metropolitan-archbishop of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> in 1979 and made him cardinal six years later. He replaced Cardinal <PERSON> Josyf </PERSON> <PERSON> Slipyj </PERSON>, who died in 1984, as leader of Ukrainian Catholics. If the church is legalized, <PERSON> Lubachivsky </PERSON> said, he would return to the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION> if permitted by Soviet authorities and organize the hierarchy. `` I would like to see how the country looks because for 50 years I have n't seen anything,'' he said. `` I would like to see for myself how the people are living. Most of my family has died, but I would like to see if there are any relatives left.'' A major stumbling block to legalization has been the opposition of the Russian Orthodox Church, which stands to lose some 450 churches it took over from the Catholics after 1946. `` Up until now the people were worshiping in forests, in the streets, in private houses,'' <PERSON> Lubachivsky </PERSON> said. `` That's not the way to worship God.'' <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> officials have held periodic negotiations with the Russian Orthodox Church, but <PERSON> Lubachivsky </PERSON> contends only the Soviet government can resolve the dispute by giving the churches back.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0024EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lebanon-Analysis     11-24 0773</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon-Analysis,0796</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lebanon Back on Brink After President Slain</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Analysis</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Lebanon</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED BLANCHE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The assassination of President <PERSON> Rene </PERSON> <PERSON> Mouawad </PERSON> leaves <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> staring into the abyss, as it has so often since a seemingly endless civil war began 14 years ago. <PERSON> Mouawad </PERSON> was trying to assemble a government that could end the war. His death Wednesday, after only 17 days as president, raised the possibility of more fighting between the 40,000 Syrian soldiers in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and Gen. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>, the Christian army commander. The assassination underlined the dangers of trying to achieve peace in a deeply divided land that has become a proxy battleground for rival powers in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. One clear motive for killing <PERSON> Mouawad </PERSON> was to undermine the peace agreement reached by <LOCATION> Lebanese </LOCATION> legislators Oct. 24 in <LOCATION> Taif </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>, after weeks of negotiations mediated by the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>. Many earlier attempts to end the war, which has cost more than 150,000 lives since 1975, have been wrecked by one or more of the many factions involved. <PERSON> Amin </PERSON> <PERSON> Gemayel </PERSON>, who was <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s last president and left office last fall, scuttled a Syrian-arranged peace treaty signed in December 1985 by leaders of the main Moslem and Christian militias. He contended it stripped Maronite Catholics of the power they have held since independence from <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> in 1943. <PERSON> Mouawad </PERSON> also was a Maronite, the main Christian sect in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, as <LOCATION> Lebanese </LOCATION> presidents traditionally have been. If supporters of the Taif accord hope to save it, they must move swiftly to elect another president acceptable both to <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, the main power broker in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, and the Moslem and Christian factions. More than a score of people were killed with <PERSON> Mouawad </PERSON>, an advocate of reconciliation, when a remote-controlled bomb containing an estimated 550 pounds of explosives went off in a crowded street as his motorcade passed. There was no claim of responsibility, but the murky world of Lebanese and <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> politics contains no shortage of suspects. <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, which supports the Taif accord, quickly pointed the finger at <LOCATION> Aoun </LOCATION>, the main Christian opponent of the plan. President <PERSON> Hafez </PERSON> <PERSON> Assad </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> clearly referred to the general when he called the assassination `` a new impulse to double the support for <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> so that it can destroy the evil in its nest and in order for the Lebanese to avenge themselves against those ... who wanted with their crime to hit <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s unity and prolong the suffering of the Lebanese.'' <PERSON> Assad </PERSON> did not elaborate, but his remarks indicated <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> might use the slaying to justify a move against <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s chief of staff, Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Shomron </PERSON>, said in <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> the Syrians probably would attack <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>, who commands about 20,000 men in Christian units of the Lebanese army. <PERSON> Yossi </PERSON> <PERSON> Olmert </PERSON>, an Israeli government official, said: `` The losers are the Syrians, and those who gained are all those who think that an elected president in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> would be bad for their interests.'' An Arab analyst said privately the gainers include <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. `` A unified Lebanese government would be able to ask the Syrians to leave, which the Syrians do n't want to do,'' he said. `` If the Syrians went, then the Israelis would have to get out of the border enclave they occupy in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> has said the Taif agreement is a betrayal because it does not provide for speedy withdrawal of the 40,000 Syrian soldiers, who are in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> under an <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> peacekeeping mandate issued in 1976. He fought an artillery `` war of liberation'' against the <ORGANIZATION> Syrians </ORGANIZATION> that lasted six months until the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> arranged a truce Sept. 22. More than 900 people were killed and nearly 3,000 wounded, most of them civilians. The fundamentalist Shiite Moslem militia <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, and its Iranian sponsors, also oppose the peace accord. <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> says it ignores the demands of the 1.2 million Shiites, the largest sect in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, for more political power. Druse Moslem chief <PERSON> Walid </PERSON> <PERSON> Jumblatt </PERSON> has gone along with the agreement, albeit grudgingly, to please his <LOCATION> Syrian </LOCATION> allies, but has made clear he does not feel it goes far enough in curbing Maronite privilege. Some Lebanese see the hand of <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s archrival in the Arab world and <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s main supporter, in the assassination of <LOCATION> Mouawad </LOCATION>. President <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, a sworn enemy of <PERSON> Assad </PERSON>, went along with the Taif accord only after <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> threatened to cut off aid.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanche </PERSON> is <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> news editor of The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, formerly based in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, and has covered the region since 1985.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0026EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-Courts     11-24 0468</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Courts,0480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japanese Trials Are Tough on Defendants</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TETSUO JIMBO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s judicial set-up may appear similar to systems in the West, but in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> strip searches are routine, lengthy delays occur in setting bail, and the odds of being found innocent are 1-in-15 ,000, an expert says `` There are many peculiar traditions,'' said <PERSON> Hiroshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Itakura </PERSON>, professor of criminal law at <ORGANIZATION> Nippon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. The traditions and customs, which play a strong role at all levels of Japanese society, may pose other hurdles for the 12 politicians, bureaucrats or business executives charged with bribery in the influence-peddling scandal known as the Recruit affair. The first of five separate trials begins Friday. `` The Japanese judiciary system may look similar to that of ordinary Western democratic countries on the surface, but it differs a great deal in substance,'' <PERSON> Itakura </PERSON> said. In a typical criminal case, suspects are required to undergo a physical examination completely naked at the beginning of police investigation following arrest. Police can question suspects for up to 48 hours before sending them to prosecutors, who have 20 days to interrogate them before filing formal charges with the court. The suspect is permitted to have a lawyer present during interrogation. An arrested person has no chance of being released on bail until prosecutors complete their investigation. <PERSON> Hiromasa </PERSON> <PERSON> Ezoe </PERSON>, the central figure in the Recruit bribery case, was arrested Feb. 13 and held until June 6, when he was released on $ 1.4 million bail. He was charged with seven counts of bribery of politicians and public officials. Defendants do not enter a formal plea until their trials start, and there is no plea bargaining beforehand. There is no chance to sway a jury _ trials are decided by a single judge at the district court level _ and judges hardly ever give innocent verdicts. `` The chance that the court will find a suspect innocent is only one out of 15,000,'' said <PERSON> Itakura </PERSON>. `` I think it reflects a homogeneous society where judges, prosecutors and defense attorneys all share a similar sense of justice and fairness.'' If <PERSON> Ezoe </PERSON>'s trial goes by the usual pattern in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, his 18 defense lawyers will try to draw the case out and reduce the penalty after the virtually inevitable guilty verdict. Since there is no plea bargaining, a defendant may want to plead innocent, but a judge may take that as a sign of a lack of repentance and impose a stiffer sentence. `` Once you are arrested for wrongdoing, it is hard to expect fairness of the Western standard in this country,'' said <PERSON> Itakura </PERSON>. `` I guess it depends on how you define fairness, but in general, the Japanese judiciary system is made in such a way that tends to be quite cruel to criminals.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MirageJackpot     11-24 0274</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mirage Jackpot,0286</SECOND>
<HEAD>$4.6 Million Jackpot Winner Borrowed $20 From Ex-Wife to Hit Big
One</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT MACY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A retiree who borrowed $ 20 from his ex-wife to play a slot machine in the city's newest resort won a $ 4.6 million jackpot. <PERSON> Elmer </PERSON> <PERSON> Sherwin </PERSON>, 76, of <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, hedged when a reporter asked him during a Thanksgiving Day news conference if his newfound fortune would reunite the couple. `` She wo n't have me,'' <PERSON> Sherwin </PERSON> said. `` He said that, not me,'' piped up his ex-wife, <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION>, who said the two are `` still buddies'' 13 years after divorce ended their 25-year marriage. <PERSON> Sherwin </PERSON> spent 90 minutes playing $ 80 of his own money Wednesday night at the new Mirage hotel-casino on the <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> strip. Then, nine hours after the casino opened and shortly after borrowing the money, he hit the winner. The jackpot _ on the Megabucks system linking slot machins in dozens of casinos _ was the largest payoff in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> history but did n't surpass the <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> record of $ 6.8 million won in <PERSON> Reno </PERSON>. `` Then I started taking Tums and I've been taking them ever since,'' he said. <PERSON> Florence </PERSON> <PERSON> Sherwin </PERSON> said she was n't surprised when her ex-husband put the touch on her for $ 20. `` He has a habit of not carrying enough money,'' she said. <PERSON> Sherwin </PERSON>, a former engineer from <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> who moved to <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> two years ago after touring the country in a mobile home, said he planned to give some of the winnings to a son and others. And the former Mrs. <PERSON> Sherwin </PERSON>? `` Of course,'' he responded. `` I told her I would fix her up.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-EasternEurope 1stLd-Writethru a0416 11-24 0701</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Eastern Europe, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0416,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: When Might German Reunification Come?</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Subs 19th graf to complete reference to Bush.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For former Secretary of State <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>, the reunification of West and <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> will be a reality when the long-divided German nation fields a single Olympic athletic team. Former Secretary of State <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> thinks reunification will come much sooner, perhaps within five years. Former Secretary of State Dean <PERSON> Rusk </PERSON>, who marvels at the changes being wrought in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, believes it is far too early to even discuss reunification and that doing so before events sort themselves out is `` folly.'' All three men had long experience sitting across the table from tough Soviet leaders in grimmer times when the Cold War was truly cold and the Iron Curtain truly iron. All three have varying ideas about the events transforming <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> now. <PERSON> Rusk </PERSON>, who was secretary of state in the <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> administration when the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wall </LOCATION> was built, said in an interview that any discussion of reunification is decidedly premature. `` I never thought I would live to see the day these things would happen in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Rusk </PERSON> said, speaking of the reform program of Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, the rise of democratic movements in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, the opening of the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall, and unprecedented protest demonstrations in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION>. `` These are dramatic and important changes,'' <PERSON> Rusk </PERSON> said. `` It's too soon to tell if they are permanent But I'm inclined to think <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and the other leaders have set in motion forces that are irresistible.'' <PERSON> Rusk </PERSON> noted that 20 Soviet divisions remain in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> with others in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. `` If <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> were to be replaced we could return to the Cold War rather quickly,'' <PERSON> Rusk </PERSON> said. In light of the uncertainties, he said, `` I deplore the premature discussion of German reunification. In a situation moving so fast, it's folly to do that.'' <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> believes German reunification is `` unavoidable.'' `` I do n't believe that unification is decades away,'' <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday. `` I really believe it will happen within the next decade, and maybe even within the next five years.'' But <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> disagrees, saying, `` whatever develops will develop more slowly than people think.'' `` I'd like to make a wager on when <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> will have just one team in the Olympic Games,'' he said in an interview, noting the rivalry that has existed between the two Germanys in the past. During the 40 years in which the two Germanys have existed side by side, united by a common tongue and culture, divided by ideology and walls, `` a lot of nationalism has developed,'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said. The East Germans, he said, are relatively well and inexpensively housed, and have a reasonable chance at a good education. `` I think there will be cooperative ventures between East and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said. `` But as to reunification, I'd be surprised if there was a single German team before two -LRB- four-year -RRB- Olympic cycles are gone through. That would be an indication that reunification had been completed.'' <PERSON> Rusk </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> reject complaints by congressional Democrats that when it comes to exploiting the opportunities presented by the rush of events in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is `` overly timid.'' `` My view is that we are doing the right thing,'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said, `` Because events and developments are changing so rapidly it makes no sense to announce a hard and firm policy until we see the results and know where things are going. `` I think it's unwise for the government to make strong statements of policy now,'' he said. `` Being very aggressive in foreign policy is often just a formula for spending more money.'' <PERSON> Rusk </PERSON> appeared to agree with that. `` I'm inclined to think this is a pretty good time for the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to remain silent,'' he said. `` I realize they find that difficult. But they also find it difficult to be subtle and sophisticated and tend to see things in black and white.'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> was asked if he had any advice for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as his December summit with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> approaches. `` Keep on doing what he's doing,'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> replied. `` I think he's doing great.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lite     11-24 0193</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lite,0201</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BIGFORK, Mont. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Robocker </PERSON> has some real turkeys for neighbors, but things could be worse. They occasionally drop by for snacks and sit in her trees, but they go to bed early and do n't make much noise. In fact, they've been so nice that she's decided she wo n't eat them These turkeys are a flock of wild ones _ a flock that's grown to about 1,000 birds foraging along the banks of the <LOCATION> Flathead </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Bigfork </LOCATION>. The birds troop through her yard, pausing to peck at grain she throws to them. But they're still wild turkeys. They do n't respond to calls, and if they are n't hungry, they wo n't show up for dinner, she says. `` They are not dumb like people think, and that's the reason they have survived well,'' she says. <PERSON> Robocker </PERSON> is familiar with the birds' likes and dislikes, but visitors seem to scare the birds away. <PERSON> Robocker </PERSON> says she maintains the neighborly relationship with the turkeys by using a point of animal etiquette she learned from the deer that also frequent her yard. She never looks the animals in the eye.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0055EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Navy-Colombia     11-24 0380</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Navy-Colombia,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. May Put Anti-Drug Flotilla Off Colombia's Coast</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Pentagon says <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> is considering a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> proposal to aid the anti-drug war by posting a flotilla off <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s coast. The proposal is among a range of ideas outlined by the heads of the various military branches, but <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said Thursday no decisions have been made on whether to accept any of them. In September, <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> had asked the military leaders for ideas on how to take a more active role in the international drug battle. The Los Angeles Times, citing anonymous sources, reported Thursday that <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> was `` pretty positive'' toward a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> proposal to put an aircraft carrier battle group or a marine amphibious task force off the Colombian coast. `` It's a done deal,'' according to one administration official quoted by the newspaper. But <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, when asked about the report, said, `` It's not a done deal.'' <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION> this fall asked the military leaders to keep working on their proposals because of legal questions and issues of coordination among the different service branches, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said. An administration official, who was asked about the scope of the flotilla proposal as outlined by the Times, said the report was `` not out of the realm of the things the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has proposed.'' This official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> has been busy preparing the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s five-year budget plan and has not concentrated in recent weeks on the various services' anti-drug proposals <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said it is not clear yet when the administration will formally announce the specific steps the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> plans to take in support of a broad, government-wide anti-drug effort. Under the plan reported in the Times, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> would operate an aircraft carrier battle group or a marine amphibious task force off <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. Each group would be in position for one or two months, similar to training deployments. It was unclear whether the aircraft, their carriers or assigned amphibious assault ships would be allowed to chase suspected drug traffickers into Colombian territory. It also was unclear whether one or both Colombian coasts would be involved. The country has two coasts, one on the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> and one on the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>, with the Isthmus of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> between them.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0056EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BushThanksgiving     11-24 0162</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush Thanksgiving,160</SECOND>
<HEAD>Traditional Holiday for Bush</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAMP DAVID, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s Thanksgiving at the Camp David retreat included a traditional dinner as well as several games of horseshoes, the White House says. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> won two matches pitching horseshoes, defeating one of his guests, <PERSON> Willard </PERSON> <PERSON> Heminway </PERSON>, two games out of three, and then defeating two of his staff by the same score, said spokesman <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Allison </PERSON>. Dinner, served early Thursday afternoon, included roast turkey with stuffing and cranberry sauce, sweet potatoes topped with marshmallows, green beans, salad and pumpkin and pecan pies. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> chaplain Capt. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothermel </PERSON> conducted Thanksgiving Day services for the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> party and the Camp David staff. President and Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> were joined by their daughter, <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> LeBlond </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Willard </PERSON>, <PERSON> Betsy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Alexandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Heminway </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>; Lud, <PERSON> Cathy </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> and <PERSON> Meredith </PERSON> <PERSON> Ashley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucey </PERSON>; <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Sadruddin </PERSON> <PERSON> Aga </PERSON> <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON>, Princess <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> and their son, <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Sursock </PERSON>; and <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Steel </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0058EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Navy-Accidents     11-24 0393</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Navy-Accidents,370</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Helicopter Crash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This week's accident that left two Marines presumed killed in the western <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> was the latest in a string that prompted the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> to order an unprecedented two-day stand-down to review safety procedures earlier this month. The two Marines believed killed during exercises from the helicopter carrier USS Iwo Jima were the 12th and 13th fatalities in the series. This fall's string of accidents began with another on board the Iwo Jima six weeks ago. Here is a rundown of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s known accidents since then: _ Oct 11, an officer aboard the Iwo Jima was killed and a crewman injured when struck by shrapnel from a shell fired by the neighboring cargo ship <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION> during an exercise in the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>. _ Oct 11, a sailor was lost overboard from the frigate USS Downes 300 miles off <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. _ Oct 29, a jet fighter pilot making his first carrier landing crashed on the deck of the training aircraft carrier <ORGANIZATION> USS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lexington </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, killing himself and four others. _ Oct 30, the pilot of an F-A-18 attack jet accidentally dropped a 500-pound bomb on the cruiser USS Reeves in the <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>, slightly injuring five sailors. _ Oct 30, a sailor from the aircraft carrier USS <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Vinson </PERSON> was lost overboard in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> 620 miles north of <LOCATION> Wake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. _ Nov 1, three sailors and $ 4 million worth of aircraft missiles were swept overboard from the carrier <ORGANIZATION> USS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eisenhower </ORGANIZATION> off <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>; two were rescued and one sailor was declared dead. _ Nov 1, nine sailors were injured in a boiler fire aboard the USS Monongahela 500 miles west of <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION>. _ Nov 9, a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> pilot flying an A-7E attack jet crashed into an apartment complex in <LOCATION> Smyrna </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, killing two civilians and wounding two other people, including himself. _ Nov 11, one man was killed when the destroyer USS Kinkaid collided with a freighter off the coast of <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>. _ Nov 14, an F-14 crashed into the Gulf of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> 60 miles northwest of Key West. The two-man crew was not seriously injured. _ Nov 14, fire aboard the amphibious assault ship USS <ORGANIZATION> Inchon </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> VA. </LOCATION>, injured 31 people, eight of them civilians. _ Nov 14, a technician at the Naval Surface Weapons Testing Center in <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oak </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, was slightly injured in a small lab explosion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SantaScholar     11-24 0451</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Santa Scholar,0464</SECOND>
<HEAD>Santa Scholar Says Learning the Truth is Harder on Parents than Kids</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EVAN RAMSTAD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Kids give up <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION> more easily than their parents, says one Santa who ought to know. For seven years, <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> has taken a break from his counseling practice to play <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION>. And this <PERSON> Kriss </PERSON> <PERSON> Kringle </PERSON> earned a Ph.D. studying how children decide to stop believing in him. Wide-eyed children this week watched as <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, 36, inspected the elaborate North Pole set at <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>' <ORGANIZATION> NorthPark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, where he will spend the next month. <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION>, he said, teaches children an early lesson about giving, even though they are the recipients. But when it's time to give up the belief in a jolly old elf who travels to every house in the world on one magic night, children usually are ready, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said. Children `` told us that more often they felt proud and happy and good, basically because they felt more adultlike,'' said <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, who in his research at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> three years ago interviewed 75 9 - to 12-year-olds and their parents The parents react differently. `` They feel like their baby is growing up and it's all going by too fast,'' he said. Children reported that, as early as age 5, they begin doubting <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said. By age 9, most have decided they do n't believe in him `` Most kids reported at least going through two or three Christmases of increasing doubt before they decided for themselves to no longer believe,'' he said. `` So the first time they heard on the schoolyard somebody say ` <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION>'s not real,' it did n't necessarily crush them at all. The biggest surprise of his research, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said, was that children understood <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> as `` something that linked generations, something that you go through initially as a child and participate in one way and then later on you go through it again as a parent from the other side.'' Older children often adopt a parental role by professing to believe in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> to younger siblings, he said. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said there is no single way for children to learn <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> is a myth. He tells parents to try to find out what the child believes. To children who declare <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> is <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION>, he gives a <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION> business card, a response that keeps him from having to tell a lie. `` Often they'll give you an indication of what they're looking for,'' <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said. `` They may be looking for permission to continue to believe. They may be wanting to say ` Look, I'm old enough now. Let's put the cards on the table and get straight with this.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HelicopterCrash     11-24 0401</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Helicopter Crash,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kentucky, Illinois Marines Killed in Copter Crash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Marine investigators are seeking the cause of a helicopter crash that killed the craft's pilot and co-pilot this week during carrier-based exercises in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>. The two crew members were declared dead Thursday following a 20-hour search by the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>, officials said. The AH-IT Cobra helicopter crashed and sank in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> during a night exercise. The search for the helicopter and its pilot and co-pilot was called off at 10 a.m. EST Thursday, said Capt. <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerstens </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman. `` They had been searching for almost a day at that point and decided there was no hope of finding them,'' Capt. <PERSON> Kerstens </PERSON> said. `` The pilots have been declared dead and their remains are unrecovered.'' The aircraft was operating from the helicopter carrier USS Iwo Jima in the western <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> off the coast of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> when the crash occurred at 2:21 p.m. EST Wednesday, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>. Capt. <PERSON> Kerstens </PERSON> said the cause of the crash was not immediately known but that an investigation has been started. The pilot was identified as Capt. <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Travis </PERSON>, 29, of <LOCATION> Glasgow </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>; and the co-pilot-gunner as Capt. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vidusek </PERSON>, 28, of <LOCATION> Naperville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Travis </PERSON> had been in the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> five years and 10 months and <LOCATION> Vidusek </LOCATION> and been in the service six and one-half years The two officers were participating in a night carrier qualification and instrument refresher training exercise when the helicopter went down within sight of the ship, Capt. <PERSON> Kerstens </PERSON> said. She said <PERSON> Travis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Vidusek </PERSON> were not using night vision goggles as a part of the exercise. Alleged defects in night vision goggles and a high rate of military helicopter accidents involving their use have prompted several recent congressional inquiries and hearings. Capt. <PERSON> Kerstens </PERSON> said both pilots and the Iwo Jima had participated in a 48-hour <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> `` safety stand-down'' two weeks ago, during which almost all routine training was suspended for reviews of safety procedures. The unprecedented stand-down was ordered following a string of 10 accidents in less than a month. The pilots were assigned to <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medium </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Helicopter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Squadron </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> 365 </ORGANIZATION>, which is based at the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Station </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, and is part of the 24th Marine Expedition Unit currently deployed with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sixth Fleet. The Iwo Jima is based at <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpaceShuttle Bjt   11-24 0359</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Shuttle, Bjt,0368</SECOND>
<HEAD>Astronauts Deploy Spy Satellite, Set Sunday Landing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURA TOLLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SPACE CENTER, Houston (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Discovery's astronauts set their sights on a Sunday landing for a secret military space shuttle mission that sources said included deployment of a spy satellite. Silence has surrounded most of the classified flight, but <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> did interrupt the quiet briefly on Thanksgiving Day to announce that the shuttle was scheduled to land at 7:02 p.m. PST Sunday at <ORGANIZATION> Edwards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> `` The crew is doing well and the orbiter continues to perform satisfactorily,'' <ORGANIZATION> Mission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> commentator <PERSON> Billie </PERSON> <PERSON> Deason </PERSON> said in the brief status report Thursday evening. According to sources close to the project, a 2 -LCB- - ton, $ 300 million payload was released from the shuttle's cargo bay early Thursday morning about 10 hours into the flight It was a satellite capable of monitoring Soviet missile tests and eavesdropping on military and diplomatic communications in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and other countries, said the sources, who spoke on condition of anonymity. The satellite was to be maneuvered into a stationary orbit 22,300 miles above the equator, on a line of sight to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and all of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. The sources were unable to provide information on how the satellite was operating. A similar satellite was launched by a shuttle crew in 1985. They were expected to tend experiments for the `` Star Wars'' missile defense system and other military projects. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has said the news blackout is necessary to try to keep the Soviets from finding out about what the astronauts are doing. Discovery is commanded by <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Col. <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON>. His four-person crew: <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Col. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Blaha </PERSON>, the pilot, and the three mission specialists, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Capt. <PERSON> Manley </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Story </PERSON> <PERSON> Musgrave </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kathryn </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornton </PERSON>. The flight, the fifth dedicated to the military, began Wednesday night with a spectacular nighttime liftoff that brightened the sky over the central <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> coast. The launch time was dictated by the secret cargo and its mission. On Thanksgiving Day, the astronauts dined on irradiated turkey, freeze-dried vegetables and cranberry sauce.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     11-24 0024</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0024</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nikkei Up</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 36,484.47, up 197.55 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Friday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador-Press     11-24 0649</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador-Press,0678</SECOND>
<HEAD>Censorship During Rebel Offensive Was Dangerous, Journalists Say</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Salvador, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government's crackdown on the news media has kept Salvadorans in the dark about the most dramatic fighting of the civil war and may even have cost some lives, journalists and others say. On Nov. 12, the day after leftist rebels launched their biggest offensive of the 10-year-old struggle, the rightist government of President <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> imposed a state of siege. The measure suspended rights guaranteed by the constitution, including freedom of expression. <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> said Thursday the suspension will last a month. Since it began, the population has been able to cull only vague or mistaken perceptions of the battles. In the days after the offensive was launched, all radio and television stations were forced to join the `` cadena nacional'' _ the national network. The programming of <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cuscatlan </ORGANIZATION>, the military station, became the only source of broadcast information and opinion. Early in the first week of fighting, the cadena dedicated periodic segments to telephone callers, but it screened out leftists. Several callers denounced the Jesuit priests who ran the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> outside <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. They called the priests subversive ideologues and suggested they be expelled or otherwise punished. On Nov. 16, they were indeed punished. A group of men broke into the campus residence where six of them were sleeping. They roused the priests, their housekeeper and her 15-year-old daughter and killed them all. Jesuit authorities say two witnesses saw men in army uniforms enter the house before the killings. In his homily at the priests' funeral, <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> <PERSON> Damas </PERSON>, archbishop of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, cited `` the climate of hate fostered by the national network'' as a factor in the slayings. The government has installed censors at all television and radio stations. They make sure viewers and listeners find out only what the government believes strengthens its hand in the fighting. Predictably, the guerrillas are portrayed as murderous demons, while the armed forces are presented as the epitome of virtue. In order to downplay the magnitude of the rebel offensive, the simple facts _ even where the fighting was taking place _ were often withheld. `` The radio says everything is getting back to normal, and everything is under control of the armed forces and the government. But look for yourself,'' said one passer-by in the <LOCATION> Soyapango </LOCATION> district of the capital late last week. He pointed down the road. Fire from assault rifles and machine guns resounded less than a hundred yards away, where several barricaded guerrillas defended an intersection from army troops trying to advance. Some journalists have publicly made known their objections to the government interference. On Nov. 22, editors and reporters of the country's principal evening news program _ Channel 12's <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dia </LOCATION> _ stood together before the camera at the show's opening as the anchor read an anti-censorship message. They then signed off indefinitely. `` For ethical reasons, it is impossible for us to continue our broadcasts,'' said a solemn <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Mineros </PERSON>. `` We can not be what we are not.'' Others are willing only to speak privately. `` Because people did n't know what was going on beyond what they could see or hear in their own neighborhood, they did n't know what places were dangerous and what places were safe. The lack of information undoubtedly killed people,'' said a prominent local radio and print newsman who spoke on condition of anonymity. `` A real fear exists that they could kill you for what you say. Even if what you say is not against the government _ just for describing objectively what's going on,'' he said. Some opposition groups have also raised their voices. `` Freedom of expression has been reduced to zero, making it tremendously difficult for the democratic opposition to fulfill its function,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> in a statement Thursday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891124-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-24-89 0205EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-UnderreportingAIDS 1stLd-Writethru a0440 11-24 0556</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Underreporting AIDS, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0440,0568</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Finds 40 Percent of AIDS Cases Not Reported in South Carolina</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf, `The national ...' to CORRECT Centers, sted Center
for Disease Control.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
