<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 2347EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-WeaponsImports     03-16 0241</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Weapons Imports,240</SECOND>
<HEAD>Post: NRA Blocks Gun Halt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A complaint by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> stopped the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alcohol </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tobacco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Firearms </ORGANIZATION> from banning the importation of 25 more models of semiautomatic weapons Thursday, a newspaper reported. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, in its Friday editions, said the bureau was ordered to hold off by <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials after the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> raised objections. The newspaper said senior <ORGANIZATION> BATF </ORGANIZATION> officials decided at a meeting Thursday morning to announce the restrictions on the additional models later in the day, according to an official familiar with the events. But then they were instructed by the parent <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> not to proceed, according to the official. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, a senior <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> official, said the group learned on Wednesday night that other weapons might be added to the list of five types of assault weapons which drug czar <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> temporarily banned on Tuesday and contacted <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> officials who said there would not be any new restrictions, the newspaper said. The ban announced by <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> included the Chinese-made AK47 and the Israeli <PERSON> Uzi </PERSON>, and covered about 80 percent of total imports of semiautomatic weapons. <ORGANIZATION> ATF </ORGANIZATION> then sought to close the door on the semiautomatic weapons not covered by the initial ban, fearing that these firearms would fill the void, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said. In addition, <ORGANIZATION> BATF </ORGANIZATION> officials worried that manufacturers affected by the import ban would complain they were unfairly singled out.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0311EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Suicide     03-16 0381</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Suicide,0396</SECOND>
<HEAD>Suicide Kills 140,000 Chinese A Year</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 140,000 Chinese take their own lives every year _ most of them women _ and suicide has become a particularly serious problem among rural women, a Chinese sociologist says. <PERSON> Shan </PERSON> <PERSON> Guangnai </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> said suicide is the leading cause of abnormal deaths in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, and 70 percent of all victims are female, the official <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> reported today. `` It used to be a taboo in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> to study suicide. Yet in recent years we are increasingly haunted by the rising problem,'' the paper quoted her as saying. A survey of 10 million people taken by the <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Preventive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> found the suicide rate for urban women to be 10.2 per 100,000, and for urban men 7.23 per 100,000. In rural areas, the suicide rate was 23.34 for women and 18.6 for men. In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the suicide rate is about 12 per 100,000. <PERSON> Shan </PERSON> said half the suicides among women are caused by family disputes and marital problems. He noted factors such as the breakup of the traditional extended family and lengthy separations as rural people stream into cities looking for work. Rural women are still treated as dependents and men dominate in the family, <PERSON> Shan </PERSON> said, adding that the psychological and emotional needs of women are largely ignored. He said women also appear to have more difficulty adapting to rapid changes in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s social values and moral standards brought about by industrialization and improving living standards. Rural women who migrate to the cities looking for work often find `` the sharp contrast is too much for them,'' <PERSON> Shan </PERSON> said. Those who return to their villages have difficulty adjusting again to rural poverty. Tens of thousands of Chinese committed suicide as a result of persecution during the ultra-leftist 1966-76 Cultural Revolution. The more recent phenomenon of suicide, linked to changing social conditions, has only recently begun to be a subject for study. In January 1988 the southern city of <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION> opened the nation's first suicide prevention and treatment center In the first year it received about 140 phone calls, 600 letters and dozens of visitors asking for help, the <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> said. <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> also opened a suicide prevention center last September.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0311EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BerlinCabinet     03-16 0274</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Berlin Cabinet,0283</SECOND>
<HEAD>Women Dominate Cabinet Nominated to Govern West Berlin</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The leftist coalition that is to run <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> has agreed on a new administration that gives women their first-ever majority in a West German state governing body. The agreement signed Wednesday by the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> party </ORGANIZATION> and the Alternative List gives women eight posts in the 13-member Cabinet administering the city-state of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. `` Women capture <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>,'' read a front-page headline in the leftist Frankfurter Rundschau newspaper. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> has the status of a state in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s federal system and its government is formally known as the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The government was scheduled to be formally ratified when the newly elected legislature meets for the first time today. The leftist coalition between the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> and the Alternative List _ the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> equivalent of the environmentalist <ORGANIZATION> Greens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> _ was formed after voters on Jan. 29 stripped the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> of its dominant position in legislature. The Christian Democrat's Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s center-right party, suffered heavy losses in the elections and the party's mayor, <PERSON> Eberhard </PERSON> <PERSON> Diepgen </PERSON>, was forced to give up his post. <PERSON> Diepgen </PERSON> will be replaced by <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Momper </PERSON>, a Social Democrat. The vote left the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> and the Social Democrats with 55 seats each in the legislature, while the Alternative List won 17. The far-right Republicans took 11 seats. With neither mainstream party able to muster a majority, the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> entered into a power-sharing agreement with the Alternative List. The Alternative List got three government posts under the agreement and gave all three to women. The Social Democrats named five more.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0311EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-RoyalOpera     03-16 0195</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Royal Opera,0199</SECOND>
<HEAD>Expensive Night At The Opera</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The price of the best seats at the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opera </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, Covent Garden, will rise to about $ 170 each when <PERSON> Luciano </PERSON> <PERSON> Pavarotti </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Placido </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Domingo </ORGANIZATION> sing there next season, general director <PERSON> Jeremy </PERSON> <PERSON> Isaacs </PERSON> says. `` We either charge these prices or we go out of business,'' <PERSON> Isaacs </PERSON> told a news conference Wednesday. He said performance standards at one of the world's leading opera houses need to be improved at a time of falling government subisidy. Next year's subsidy is $ 23.6 million _ 40 percent of the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opera </ORGANIZATION>'s income and down from 60 percent five years ago. <PERSON> Isaacs </PERSON> hopes that Spanish-born tenor <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> will return in January to repeat his title role in <PERSON> Giuseppe </PERSON> <PERSON> Verdi </PERSON>'s `` Otello,'' and that Italian tenor <PERSON> Pavarotti </PERSON> will star in <PERSON> Gaetano </PERSON> <PERSON> Donizetti </PERSON>'s `` L'elisir d'amore'' in February `` We expect no falling off at the box office,'' <PERSON> Isaacs </PERSON> said. The director also announced an 11 percent overall rise on seats for other than special performances. The best seats will be $ 140. Seats at the very top of the house, where only a corner of the stage can be seen, remain at $ 4.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0311EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BerlinDeathPenalty     03-16 0190</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Berlin Death Penalty,0194</SECOND>
<HEAD>Allies Abolish 44-Year-Old Death Penalty In West Berlin</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The three Allied military powers in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> have abolished a law allowing them to pronounce the death penalty, erasing a controversial regulation adopted 44 years ago, officials say. No one has ever been executed under the now-defunct law, said a <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> military spokesman who requested anonymity. But the continued existence of the regulation has irritated many West Berliners. `` The Allies are conscious of many Berliners' objections'' to the law, said a statement issued by French military authorities on Wednesday. `` Beginning today ... no person can be sentenced to death because of violations against the Allies.'' <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> officially control <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> under post-war treaties which left the Soviets in charge of communist <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. The French military spokesman said the three Allies were abolishing the death penalty in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> to `` bring their regulations into accordance with German law.'' <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> has no death penalty. The spokesman said the law was aimed at preventing attacks against Allied soldiers and officials in the years immediately after <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s 1945 defeat.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0310EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PigeonBurial     03-16 0540</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pigeon Burial,0556</SECOND>
<UNK>City Halts Mass Pigeon Burials</UNK>
<DATELINE>LEXINGTON, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The practice of disposing of pigeons by burying them alive was suspended after an official of the <ORGANIZATION> Humane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> contacted the mayor's office. <PERSON> Guy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodge </PERSON>, of the society's <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> headquarters, said he offered to travel to <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> and provide a `` blueprint'' for urban pigeon control that would include alternatives to burying the birds alive in the county landfill. <PERSON> Hodge </PERSON> said Tuesday that the society might challenge the practice of burying live birds. `` I would say certainly it violates the spirit, if not the letter, of the anti-cruelty law'' protecting animals in <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hodge </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hodge </PERSON> said he knew of no other place in the nation where pigeons were buried alive. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hadidian </PERSON>, an urban wildlife biologist with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, also said he'd never heard of such a practice elsewhere. <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Scotty </PERSON> <PERSON> Baesler </PERSON>, who was in a meeting Wednesday afternoon, issued a statement that the burials were suspended. He said he was unaware of the practice until it was reported Wednesday in the <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> Herald-Leader. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>, of the <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> Humane society, said he was not aware the birds were being buried alive. `` Of course, we see problems with that,'' he said. The city had a year-round trapping program and caught about 125 birds a week, said <PERSON> Gayle </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, an aide in the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Works </ORGANIZATION>. He said the pigeons congregate on public buildings and leave smelly droppings. They were removed by city sanitation workers, tied in burlap bags and taken to the landfill, where the bags were buried. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said the method combined `` reasonable humaneness and convenience.'' The method was inexpensive, but that was not the deciding factor, he said. <PERSON> Hodge </PERSON> said there is no evidence that killing pigeons eliminates the problem in the long run. Instead, the <ORGANIZATION> Humane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> advocates taking measures to limit roosting spots, `` pigeon-proofing'' buildings by placing sharp spikes on roosting areas, frightening the birds with noisemakers and passing laws to limit the food supply from citizens, restaurants and other sources. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said it was expensive to pigeon-proof buildings and that pigeons were smart birds that soon learned to ignore noisemakers and predator decoys. The only solution is to kill the birds, he said Tuesday. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said that despite the apparent success of a pigeon shoot Sunday in downtown <LOCATION> Somerset </LOCATION> in southeast <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION>'s pigeon problem was not bad enough to warrant blocking off downtown and shooting the birds `` I think the problem would have to be much more serious before we'd close the downtown and let -LRB- hunters -RRB- cut loose on them,'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> <PERSON> Estes </PERSON>, community development director in <LOCATION> Somerset </LOCATION>, said 500 to 600 birds, about half the pigeon population there, were killed in Sunday's shoot, and he expected half that many to be killed in a shoot scheduled Saturday. <PERSON> Hodge </PERSON> said he had been trying Wednesday to contact <LOCATION> Somerset </LOCATION> officials to offer them a similar plan for pigeon control but had been unsuccessful. <PERSON> Estes </PERSON>, who said he planned no further shoots after Saturday because of `` the media aggravating you to death,'' said he considered the method more humane than live burial. `` I'm not out here choking ours to death,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0250EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hostages-Chronology     03-16 0858</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hostages-Chronology,0902</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chronology of Terry Anderson's Captivity</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
<NOTE>1985</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 MARCH 16 _ <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> abducted on <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> street. Telephone caller says Islamic Jihad kidnapped him as part of `` continuing operations against <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and its agents.'' MAY 16 _ First photograph of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> in captivity released. Islamic Jihad warns of `` catastrophic consequences'' if <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> does not free alleged terrorists. SEPT. 9 _ The Rev. <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Weir </PERSON>, another Islamic Jihad captive, freed after 16 months in captivity. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> says he `` will not be satisified'' until remaining Americans also are released. OCT. 29 _ <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> TV stations broadcast videotaped birthday message from relatives and friends to <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>. NOV. 8 _ In an open letter, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and three other American captives held by Islamic Jihad call on <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to negotiate with kidnappers. All four hostages are allowed to write to their families. Another letter to the Archbishop of <LOCATION> Canterbury </LOCATION> appeals for <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Waite </PERSON> to mediate with Islamic Jihad.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>1986</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 FEB. 15 _ <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s father, <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, dies of cancer at age 69. JUNE 7 _ <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s 46-year-old brother, <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, dies of cancer four days after making a videotape from his bed appealing to <PERSON> Terry </PERSON>'s captors. JULY 26 _ The Rev. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenco </PERSON>, freed after almost 19 months as hostage, says he was held with <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and two other hostages for a year. OCT. 3 _ In a videotaped appeal, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobsen </PERSON> call on the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration to work as hard for their release as it did to secure the release of journalist <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniloff </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. OCT. 31 _ <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> TV stations broadcast videotape showing <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s 16-month-old daughter, whom he has never seen. NOV. 2 _ <PERSON> Jacobsen </PERSON>, freed after 17 months in captivity, says hostages `` are in hell.'' NOV. 15 _ Islamic Jihad releases new picture of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>. DEC. 28 _ Fourth picture of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> sent by captors to Western news agency in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>1987</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 JAN. 16 _ Islamic Jihad distributes another picture of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>. JUNE 7 _ <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s daughter is shown on Lebanese television on her second birthday saying, `` Our hearts are broken. Where is daddy?'' AUG. 2 _ Sixth photo of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> released by Islamic Jihad. OCT. 21 _ Islamic Jihad releases another photo of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>. OCT. 27 _ <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> turns 40. Friends and family gather in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> staff in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> goes to his vacant office to mark the day. NOV. 26 _ <PERSON> Jacobsen </PERSON> says he learned from sources in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government and the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> that <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> is being held again in chains and blindfolded 24 hours a day. DEC. 10 _ <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> passes his 1,000 th day as a hostage DEC. 24 _ Islamic Jihad release a videotape of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>. Appearing to read from a text, he criticizes the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration for failing to secure the release of himself and other Americans and warns `` there's a limit how long we can last.'' DEC. 30 _ A <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> newspaper reports that a <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> analysis of the tape indicated <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> may be held in <LOCATION> Basta </LOCATION> prison in west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> with missing <ORGANIZATION> Anglican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> envoy <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Waite </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>1988</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 MARCH 16 _ <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> begins his fourth year in captivity. APRIL 10 _ Islamic Jihad threatens in a statement, accompanied by a photo of <LOCATION> Anderson </LOCATION>, that it will kill its captives if any attempt is made to storm a <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> jetliner hijacked by Shiite extremists. MAY 4 _ Islamic Jihad frees three <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> hostages. MAY 9 _ Freed French hostage <PERSON> Marcel </PERSON> <PERSON> Fontaine </PERSON>, also held by Islamic Jihad, says <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s greatest fear is that the Americans will launch a commando raid to free him, an action he believes would mean his certain death. AUG. 18 _ Islamic Jihad issues a photo of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> with a statement saying he and another <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hostage wo n't be freed soon, squelching speculation they would be released following the Iran-Iraq cease-fire. It also contains new demands: <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> withdrawal from south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and compensation for the reconstruction of south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and south <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. OCT. 3 _ <PERSON> Mithileshwar </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, and Indian national and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> resident alien, is freed. OCT. 21 _ <LOCATION> Islamic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jihad </LOCATION> threatens to `` punish'' its captives in retaliation for Israeli air raids in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. A photo of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> accompanies the statement. OCT. 23 _ Islamic Jihad threatens in a statement, accompanied by a photo of <LOCATION> Anderson </LOCATION>, that its American hostages will a price that `` will reflect adversely'' on them if the group's demands are not met. OCT. 24 _ <LOCATION> Islamic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jihad </LOCATION> denies any connection with a Lebanese woman arrested in <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> with a photo of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and another <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hostage. OCT. 27 _ <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> is 41, his fourth birthday in captivity. Islamic Jihad issues a photo of him to authenticate a statement again denying any connection with the women held in <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION>. OCT. 31 _ Islamic Jihad issues a videotape of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> to mark his 41st birthday. He says the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government is impeding his release and adds: `` I find it difficult to keep my hope and courage high.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>1989</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 MARCH 16 _ <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> begins his fifth year in captivity.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0249EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hostages-Profiles     03-16 0690</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hostages-Profiles,0705</SECOND>
<HEAD>Profiles of Foreign Hostages in Lebanon</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Sketches of nine Americans and other foreign kidnap victims missing in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>: _ <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, 41, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, kidnapped March 16, 1985. He was born in <LOCATION> Lorain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, reared in <LOCATION> Batavia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, and graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. He worked at AP bureaus in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> before <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. _ <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutherland </PERSON>, 57, acting dean of agriculture at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION>, abducted June 9, 1985. A Scottish-born American who studied agriculture at <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, he was on leave from the faculty of <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and had worked in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> for two years. His wife, <PERSON> Jean </PERSON>, also taught at <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. _ <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON>, 56, the American director of the <ORGANIZATION> Lebanese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, kidnapped Sept. 9, 1986. From Malden, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, he had spent nine years in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and was a convert to Islam. His wife is Syrian. _ <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON>, 58, acting comptroller at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, kidnapped Sept. 12, 1986. He spent most of his life in <LOCATION> Norristown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa </LOCATION>. He moved to <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> in 1984, and in 1985 converted to Islam and married a Lebanese woman, a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> secretary. _ <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON>, 58, west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> resident and self-described writer. <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> claimed on Oct. 21, 1986, to have abducted him. A native of <LOCATION> Rutland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vt. </LOCATION>, he had traveled and lived around the world most of his adult life and was divorced from a West German woman. _ <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Polhill </PERSON>, 54, originally of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, an accountant and a lecturer in accounting at <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> since February 1986, kidnapped Jan. 24, 1987. A <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> graduate, he formerly worked as an accountant in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. He is married to a Lebanese woman. _ <PERSON> Alann </PERSON> <PERSON> Steen </PERSON>, 49, a communications instructor at <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, kidnapped Jan. 24, 1987. A <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> native, <PERSON> Steen </PERSON> graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Humboldt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Arcata </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. His wife, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> A <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, is a fine arts professor at <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. _ <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, 41, a visiting professor of mathematics and computer science at <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, kidnapped Jan. 24, 1987. A native of <LOCATION> Boise </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, he holds degrees from <ORGANIZATION> Boise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Idaho </ORGANIZATION>. His wife is Lebanese. _ <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> Lt. Col. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>, 44, head of observer group attached to <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeeping force in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, kidnapped Feb. 17, 1988. Born in <LOCATION> Danville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, the decorated <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veteran is married to Marine Maj. <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON> and has a 17-year-old daughter. <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON> graduated from high school in <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, and from <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, on an ROTC scholarship in 1967. He earned a master's degrees in human resources management at <ORGANIZATION> Pepperdine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Univiversity </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and in political science at <LOCATION> Auburn </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>. _ <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Waite </PERSON>, 49, British envoy of the <ORGANIZATION> Anglican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> who has been seeking the release of foreign hostages, disappeared Jan. 20, 1987. He reportedly is being held by pro-Iranian kidnappers, although no group has claimed responsibility for his abduction. _ <PERSON> Alec </PERSON> <PERSON> Collett </PERSON>, 67, British. A New York-based journalist on assignment for the U.N. Relief and <ORGANIZATION> Works </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, he was kidnapped March 25, 1985, while traveling south of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. On April 23, 1986, the <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Moslems </ORGANIZATION> said it killed <PERSON> Collett </PERSON> in retaliation for British complicity in the April 15 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> air attack on <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>. A videotape purporting to show <PERSON> Collett </PERSON> hanged was made public. _ <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, 32, British television journalist. He was kidnapped April 17, 1986, en route to the <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> airport. _ Italian businessman <PERSON> Alberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Molinari </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> resident. He was kidnapped Sept. 11, 1985, on the city's dividing Green Line. _ <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Keenan </PERSON>, 38, an Irish teacher of English at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION>. He was kidnapped April 11, 1986, in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. _ Jan Cools, a 32-year-old Belgian physician, disappeared May 21, 1988, after leaving his residence in <LOCATION> Rashidiyeh </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> refugee camp in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. On Dec. 16, a previously unknown group, the <ORGANIZATION> Soldiers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>, claimed it kidnapped him and accused him of being a spy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0301EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     03-16 0049</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0051</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Wednesday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 06; 07; 19; 22; 23; 31.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 05; 13; 27; 32; 41; 52. Supplementary 37.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 9-4-7; 1-2-4-8; 7-8-5-0-5; 8-3-3-3-0-6.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AIDSIncubation     03-16 0515</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS Incubation,0528</SECOND>
<HEAD>Half of AIDS-Infected Men May Stay Disease-Free 10 Years, Study Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A gay man who becomes infected with the AIDS virus stands a 50-50 chance of going nearly 10 years without developing the disease, suggests a study reported today. The virus may incubate at least 9.8 years in half the gay men it infects, some two years longer than other recent studies suggested, according to the analysis of AIDS among gay men in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. If infected people are given AZT or an aerosol form of the drug pentamidine to stave off development of AIDS, the interval may run longer, said researcher <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Moss </PERSON>. He and colleague <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Bacchetti </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> present the work in today's issue of the British journal Nature. The study represents a new approach to estimating AIDS incubation time, and `` it's good work,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kalbfleisch </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Waterloo </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, said Wednesday. <PERSON> Kalbfleisch </PERSON>, a statistics professor who has done similar research, said incubation estimates are uncertain because too little time has passed since the earliest AIDS infections to give a clearer picture. For the new work, researchers compared infection rates among <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> gay men since 1978 to monthly totals of new cases of acquired immune deficiency syndrome. The analysis estimated incubation times that would be consistent with the two sets of data. It was not designed to determine the fraction of infected men who would eventually get AIDS, <PERSON> Moss </PERSON> said. He said he believed incubation periods seen among people who were infected by transfusions will eventually approach the 9.8-year figure. The work suggests that the number of new AIDS cases among <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> gay men will decline after this year, <PERSON> Moss </PERSON> said. Other studies suggest the number of new infections started to decline after 1982, he said. Several teams of researchers had previously estimated AIDS incubation times. Last year, <PERSON> Kalbfleisch </PERSON> and colleague J.F. Lawless suggested that half of adults infected by tainted blood transfusions may still be free of AIDS 7.3 years after infection. Also last year, researchers at the <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> estimated an average incubation of 7.8 years among 84 gay men. A British economist suggested a 15-year average incubation period in a 1987 analysis of blood transfusion data, but his study has since been criticized by other scientists, <PERSON> Kalbfleisch </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bacchetti </PERSON> said. Another transfusion study that year estimated an eight-year average. A report by the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> estimated that 25 percent to 50 percent of infected people will develop AIDS in five to 10 years. AIDS has struck 87,188 Americans and killed 49,976 since June 1981, according to the most recent <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> figures. Sixty-one percent of cases have occurred in gay or bisexual males. The AIDS virus is called human immunodeficiency virus, or HIV. It is spread most often through sexual contact, needles or syringes shared by drug abusers, infected blood or blood products, and from pregnant women to their offspring.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MuscularDystrophy     03-16 0195</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Muscular Dystrophy,0201</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scientists Isolate Muscle Protein That Prevents Muscular Dystrophy</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Studies of a protein that prevents the most common kind of muscular dystrophy should be aided by today's report of a way to isolate the substance from muscle tissue, researchers say. Scientists do not yet know what the protein does in muscle tissue. But its absence causes <PERSON> Duchenne </PERSON> muscular dystrophy, the most common and severe kind of dystrophy. Isolation of the protein from rabbit muscle is reported in today's issue of the British journal Nature by <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Kahl </PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. They said the isolation method should help research into the protein, called dystrophin. The new study found dystrophin was tightly bound to a second protein. The results suggest the combination of the two proteins may be important for normal muscle structure or function, the researchers said. Duchenne dystrophy is a genetic disorder that strikes boys almost exclusively, appearing in about one in every 3,500 male births in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. It causes a progressive weakening and wasting of voluntary muscles. Most patients die in their early 20s.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WalterMears     03-16 0791</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Walter Mears,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Week Later, Only Ripples Left from Tower Defeat</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WALTER R. MEARS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> has fallen, but the sky has not. For all the forecasts of dire results if the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> blocked Tower's path to the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, business is proceeding as usual. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the case was closed and accepted Democratic assurances of future cooperation. That does n't undo the resentment among some of Tower's more ardent Republican allies in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and in some corners of the White House. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> lieutenants claimed they had heard what sounded like assurances of support from a dozen <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democrats. They ended up with only three Democrats in the close-to-party-line vote against Tower. Nevertheless, a week after the former <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> senator was denied confirmation as secretary of defens, the waters have closed. There will be ripples, and some of them could be wave-sized. The good-behavior rules set in the debate over Tower's drinking habits and his lucrative defense consulting business are certain to be invoked as precedents whenever Republicans spot a Democratic target. `` We've established what will be known as the Tower standards,'' said Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>. That argument will be used by <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Republicans challenging the financial conduct of House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> But it will be a debating point, not a turning point, in a <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> controversy that was ordained long before the Tower episode. While President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was unwavering in his support of Tower, he burned no bridges to congressional Democrats. He insisted that Tower was the best man for the job and he spoke out repeatedly for his choice, even after it was clear that the nomination was doomed. But he did n't get nasty about it, saying there was no point in escalating the fight. `` That's over,'' he said 24 hours after the Tower defeat. `` That's history. And now we are going to go forward.'' The 53-47 vote against Tower was a setback to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the sense that it always is a defeat when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> denies a president something he wants. But this denial did not cost <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a program, or a major campaign pledge, or the support of voters. Indeed, it could turn out that the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> did the president a favor by sending Tower back to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> instead of to the Pentagon. It was a break <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> could not make with a political ally who had been after the Pentagon job since <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was elected president. Tower had not been a Reagan man _ he had supported <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for the 1980 nomination. And the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> White House went to some lengths to rule the senator out of the job he sought, declaring that the new president would not be nominating any <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republican for any Cabinet post. After Tower's long wait, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> displayed his own loyalty, all the way to a losing vote when the standard, somewhat safer course would have been to withdraw the nominee. Tower not only shunned withdrawal; he offered conditions that had to be humiliating, if only the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> would let him have the job. Tower promised to quit drinking, taking the pledge on national television. And when that did n't work, he offered to become the first-ever probationary Cabinet member. Republicans proposed that he get the job for a six-month trial and then return for reconfirmation, a gimmick that would have changed the system and could have haunted the presidency. No deal. So Tower became the ninth Cabinet nominee ever to be rejected, the first who was a former senator. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he had been fighting for the right of a president to appoint his own Cabinet, but he avoided language that would have raised the political stakes. Tower did not restrain himself. Battling for the job, he said withdrawal would damage <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and rejection would be `` damning the president's judgment.'' He said his nomination had been turned into a vehicle for a major presidential defeat. Tower's advocates on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor said grave constitutional issues were at stake, that the authority of the presidency was on the line, that the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will come to rue the rules it wrote in the Tower decision. But <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said all along that the outcome, either way, would not hurt on other issues. Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and the pivotal figure in the Tower defeat, agreed. He told his <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> constituents that the Tower rejection would not hurt <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s leadership `` In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, ` triumphs' and ` setbacks' are short-lived,'' <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> said, `` and that's particularly true of the president.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WeatherService Bjt   03-16 0820</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Weather Service, Bjt,840</SECOND>
<HEAD>Plan to Close More Than 100 Local Offices Announced</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> is promising better forecasts and fewer false alarms when it completes a reorganization program officials say will close more than 100 local offices. A giant supercomputer, an array of new high-tech radar and automated data collection systems will allow the agency to operate with 800 fewer workers and 115 local offices rather than the approximately 250 now open, says <ORGANIZATION> NWS </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> Elbert </PERSON> W. Friday. Friday said the agency hopes to complete the modernization program by 1995, but promised that no local office will be closed until officials are convinced they can do so without hurting local forecast and warning services. Staff cuts will be handled through normal attrition, Friday said, with no current workers expected to lose their jobs. The program is expected to reduce the overall staff from 4,700 people to about 3,900 when it is completed. Despite the <ORGANIZATION> NWS </ORGANIZATION> assurances on Wednesday, the plan is likely to provoke criticism from some members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Reports earlier this month that some <ORGANIZATION> NWS </ORGANIZATION> offices might be closed led to quick complaints from senators and representatives anxious to preserve jobs and facilities in their home states. Friday said a list of the 115 communities expected to retain offices would be made public. However, <ORGANIZATION> NWS </ORGANIZATION> spokesmen later told reporters that the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> had nixed that plan and the list would not be released. Friday said the improved technology, some of which is being tested in <LOCATION> Norman </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>, is expected to improve forecasting of severe storms from 60 percent accuracy to 80 percent. That should reduce false alarms an equal amount, he said. He said the automated data collection and processing system will first be installed in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and will be expanded to the remainder of the country once it is proven effective. Major components of the new system will be: _ The Next Generation Weather Radar, which will provide more detailed analysis of storms than current radar, which was installed in the 1960s The new radar can detect wind direction, improving the ability to see tornadoes before they touch the ground, Friday said. _ The Automated Surface Observing System, which will replace many current weather service offices with computerized stations that continually measure temperature, humidity, rainfall, cloud height, wind and visibility These stations will send data now collected by people to central offices for use in writing forecasts. _ A supercomputer will be installed at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Meteorological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, to provide detailed forecasts twice a day to weather service offices for use in preparing local forecasts _ The Advance Weather Interactive Processing System, an upgraded computer forecasting system to be installed in all 115 local offices The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employees </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, however, was critical of the plan, saying the new equipment has n't been proven effective. While <ORGANIZATION> NWS </ORGANIZATION> officials declined to provide either a list of weather offices to be closed or those to be kept open, an unofficial map was obtained indicating 113 sites in the 48 contiguous states expected to retain weather forecasting offices. Some locations are approximate, with final decisions yet to be made. The preliminary list includes: <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION> and Mobile. <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Flagstaff </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Yuma </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joaquin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area, <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Eureka </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, Grand Junction and <LOCATION> Pueblo </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Melbourne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area, <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and Key West. <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Boise </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pocatello </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Des </PERSON> <PERSON> Moines </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Quad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cities </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Goodland </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Dodge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Topeka </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wichita </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Paducah </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Shreveport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Charles </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Marquette </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Alpena </LOCATION>, Grand Rapids and <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Duluth </LOCATION> and Minneapolis-St. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Missoula </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Glasgow </LOCATION> and Billings. <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Platte </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Elko </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Reno </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Binghamton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Raleigh-Durham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Morehead </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> _ Bismarck, <LOCATION> Fargo-Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Forks </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Cincinnati-Dayton </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Pendleton </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Medford </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Aberdeen </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Rapid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Knoxville-Tri-City </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Amarillo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lubbock </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Midland-Odessa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angelo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Austin-San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Dallas-Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, Houston-Galveston, <PERSON> Corpus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christi </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Burlington </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Roanoke </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Richmond-Norfolk </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Crosse </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cedar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Riverton </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cheyenne </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0229EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NuclearSecurity     03-16 0490</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuclear Security,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Watkins Seeks Tighter Air Security Over Defense Reactors</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Energy Department is urging aviation authorities to restrict flights over its military nuclear reactors to make them more secure against potential terrorist attack. `` We've got a lot to do in that area,'' Energy Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> told a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee Wednesday. `` It's going to be some time before we get this completely closed.'' The issue was raised by Sen. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Exon </PERSON>, D-Neb., during a hearing in which <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> pledged to give top priority to modernizing and cleaning up the department's nuclear weapons complex, which includes 16 major facilities in 12 states <PERSON> Exon </PERSON> said he was stunned to read a recent report that there are no effective restrictions on airplane flights over the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> plant near <LOCATION> Aiken </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, whose reactors are the nation's only source of a gas used in nuclear warheads. Those reactors currently are not operating because of safety problems. `` If there is one place where we have fallen down on what is A, B, C in security, it is in this area,'' <PERSON> Exon </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> also includes an Energy Department research laboratory, a plant that makes naval reactor fuel material, two chemical separation plants and a facility that produces weapon-grade plutonium. The only nuclear weapons plant that now has prohibited airspace is the Pantex plant near <LOCATION> Amarillo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, which is the final weapons assembly point. The Charlotte Observer reported in last Sunday's editions that classified security reports obtained by the newspaper in a Freedom of Information Act request showed <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> officials had repeatedly urged the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> to ban low-altitude flights over the 300-square-mile facility. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> had failed to justify the need for the restrictions, which the aviation agency views as excessive. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said he was personally involved in trying to establish the air restrictions, not only at <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> but also at other sensitive weapons plants. `` We've got to take a look all around,'' he said, to find ways of better protecting the weapons complex from possible air attacks by terrorists or damage from a crash. `` I believe with the new secretary of transportation and with my personal friend coming into the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>, I do n't see any problem getting it reestablished,'' <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said. Although he was not more specific, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, a retired admiral, apparently was referring to recent reports that Adm. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Busey </PERSON> IV, commander of naval forces in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> since March 1987, would be named <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> administrator. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration had not yet nominated anyone for the job. The Observer report said that last September, the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> dropped its 1983 request to prohibit flights below 14,000 feet for <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> and eight other weapons sites. The agency settled for a 2,000-foot minimum limit at <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. That restriction, however, is voluntary and not enforceable, the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0230EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Baker-MiddleEast     03-16 0594</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Baker-Middle East,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baker Plays Down Suggestion that Israel and PLO Talk</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Amid Israeli complaints, Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> is playing down his suggestion that direct talks between <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> may be needed if alternate peace efforts fail. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations subcommittee on foreign operations Wednesday that an Israeli-PLO dialogue was difficult to foresee but should not `` categorically'' be ruled out. This represented a shift in tone from Tuesday when he told a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee that if talks between <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and non-PLO Palestinians do not prosper, `` I suppose we would then have to see negotiations between Israelis and representatives of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s remark triggered a telephone call from <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Foreign Minister <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Arens </PERSON>, who told the secretary that the statement was `` damaging'' to the prospects for a dialogue between <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and non-PLO Palestinians. <PERSON> Arens </PERSON>, here for official talks, disclosed the phone call to Israeli reporters. At Wednesday's hearing, Sen. <PERSON> Arlen </PERSON> <PERSON> Specter </PERSON>, R-Pa., said <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s statement was an `` open invitation'' for the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> to engage in terrorist activities against Palestinians who choose to bargain with <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> replied that he only meant to say in his earlier remarks that an Israeli-PLO dialogue should not be `` categorically, absolutely, totally and completely'' ruled out `` under any and all circumstances,'' because it might help the peace process. The comment did not repudiate what he had said Tuesday but there was a clear change in emphasis. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has steadfastly refused to talk to the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> and says the dialogue the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> opened with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> last December has strengthened the group's hand. <PERSON> Arens </PERSON> accused the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday of committing the `` worst atrocities we've ever seen since World War II.'' In his remarks Wednesday, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> seemed to hold out little hope that an international conference on the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, advocated by many <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> states, could make a significant contribution to peace. What is needed instead, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said, are `` mutually reciprocal and reinforcing steps'' by both <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> to build confidence. `` Both sides have to take steps,'' he said. The mood at the hearing was generally friendly but there were some hints that President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> may encounter some resistance, especially on Central American policy. Subcommittee Chairman <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt., said the only aid package he could support for the Nicaraguan Contra rebels would be one leading to their resettlement in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> or elsewhere from the base camps where they now are housed in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said he believes the Contras should remain intact at least until national elections are held in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> next February. He implied that the rebels could then be reintegrated into <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> if the elections are fair. The administration is expected to seek a humanitarian aid package for the Contras in the $ 40 million to $ 50 million range in the next few days. On <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON> said that if the rightist ARENA party wins presidential elections there on Sunday, future <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to that country should carry strict conditions because of the ties he said ARENA has with death squad activities. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> replied that it would be a mistake to exaggerate the size of the death squad problem, contending that politically motivated murders averaged 800 per month in 1981 and 1982 compared with 280 per year at present. He added, however, that the administration is aware of continuing human rights problems in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, recalling that Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> raised that issue with Salvadoran officials during a visit there six weeks ago.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0231EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PollClosing     03-16 0538</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poll Closing,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Committee Approves Uniform Poll Closing Bill</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LES BLUMENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The sponsor of legislation that would establish a uniform closing time for polls in 48 of the 50 states says he expects full <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approval of the bill as early as next month. On Wednesday, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> approved the measure on a voice vote. Rep. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Swift </PERSON>, sponsor of the bill, said he expects the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to approve the measure in early April, but <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> has indicated passage could come before the Easter recess which begins March 24. Election officials in the West have charged that the early projection of the winner in the presidential race discourages people from voting in their states and the drop in turnout had affected the outcomes of close local races. Swift, D-Wash., has said previously that studies have shown voter turnout can drop by as much as 2 percent in states where the polls are still open but the winner in a presidential contest is known `` With passage of this legislation we will be one step closer to preserving the integrity of election day not only in the West, but across the country,'' said <PERSON> Swift </PERSON>. <PERSON> Swift </PERSON>'s bill was similar to ones approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> twice before, but both times the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> failed to act. A different version of a uniform poll closing bill is before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rules </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. Under <PERSON> Swift </PERSON>'s bill, polls would close simultaneously across the country at 9 p.m. EST on election day. In the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> time zone, daylight-saving time would be extended for a maximum of two weeks in presidential election years. The extension would allow polls in that time zone to close at 7 p.m. PDT. <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> are exempt from the legislation, but could change their poll closing times if desired. <PERSON> Swift </PERSON> said the need for a uniform closing time became apparent with the 1980 election when television networks projected the results based on exit polling hours before the polls on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> closed. The networks have since agreed not to project election results in a state where the polls have n't closed, but in 1988 the problem was different as President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> rolled up a large electoral college majority before Western polls closed. <PERSON> Swift </PERSON> said his uniform poll closing bill `` will ensure that voters in all regions of the country will be able to cast their ballots without being told who won the election. `` The networks held to their part of the bargain last November, now it is up to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to send this legislation to the president.'' While a version of a poll closing bill cleared the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rules </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commitee </ORGANIZATION> late last year, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> adjourned before the the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> had an opportunity to act. Sen. <PERSON> Brock </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, D-Wash., has introduced legislation that avoids a change in daylight-saving time and simply calls for the polls to close at 7 p.m. Pacific time, 8 p.m. Mountain time, 9 p.m. Central time and 10 p.m. Eastern time <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, an <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> spokeswoman, said the chairman of the rules committee, Sen. <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, D-Ky., has indicated he expects <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' bill to clear the panel in early April
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Hungary Bjt   03-16 0543</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hungary, Bjt,0559</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hungarians Mourn Past, Celebrate Future In Unprecedented Rallies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TEDDIE WEYR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of people, some chanting `` Russians go home,'' marched in twilight across the <LOCATION> Danube </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> to demand <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s full independence and celebrate its first small steps toward democracy. An estimated 100,000 people took to the streets of the capital on Wednesday to mark <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s 1848 revolt against Austrian rule, an anniversary that has become a symbol for reformers demanding greater freedoms. Unlike in previous years, when authorities cracked down on celebrations, the anniversary this year was declared a public holiday and both government and opposition rallies took place peacefully across the nation. In <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION>, thousands of people sporting national emblems marched, listened to poetry and folk songs and chanted slogans during rallies and other events held throughout the day. Crowds applauded calls for an independent <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, the withdrawal of Soviet troops, free elections and a multi-party system and expressed solidarity with jailed activists in neighboring <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc countries. A five-hour march through the capital to symbolic sites of the 1848 revolution, which <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> crushed in 1849 with the help of Russian troops, was followed in the evening by a candlelight procession across a <LOCATION> Danube </LOCATION> bridge and up a steep road to the <LOCATION> Castle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. Police made no move all day to interfere with the marchers. Pro-democracy activist <PERSON> Sandor </PERSON> <PERSON> Szilagyi </PERSON>, one of the organizers of Wednesday's mass march through the capital, said this was a sign the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> was sincere about taking steps toward democracy. In past years, large numbers of police escorted demonstrators at unofficial gatherings or forcibly dispersed them and detained protest leaders. In 1986, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> protested violent a police crackdown on a March 15 rally. In a further sign of <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s recent reforms and greater independence from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, no Soviet-style red flags hung anywhere in the capital for the first time on any national holiday in three decades. The day amounted to one of the biggest outpourings of nationalist pride since another unsuccessful Hungarian revolt, the anti-Soviet uprising of 1956, was crushed by Russian tanks. <PERSON> Miklos </PERSON> <PERSON> Tamas-Gaspar </PERSON>, a leader of the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, told the crowd gathered before the candlelight march that March 15 was not only a celebration of 1848, but also of 1956. `` The aim is the same,'' he said. `` Constitutional democracy and national independence.'' Wednesday night, a crowd estimated by Western reporters and independent activists to be about 80,000 to 100,000 marched across the river to the castle, with some chanting `` Russians go home.'' Themes of democracy and independence marked events throughout the day, as Hungarians celebrated the newly recognized holiday and recent reforms endorsed by Parliament that could usher in a bona fide multi-party system. <PERSON> Denes </PERSON> <PERSON> Csengey </PERSON>, a popular leader of one of the largest independent groups, the Hungarian Democratic Forum, told a cheering crowd that March 15 should not be the only day of freedom. He spoke in front of the television headquarters where children stood underneath a banner which read `` Free Hungarian Television.'' Referring to a decision by independent groups not to accept an invitation by <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> leaders to celebrate jointly, <PERSON> Csengey </PERSON> said the separate celebrations did not mean `` we do n't wish to work toward national unity.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0246EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-OldestEclipse     03-16 0386</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Oldest Eclipse,0397</SECOND>
<HEAD>Oldest Known Record of Total Eclipse Is Younger Than Thought, Study
Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Scientists missed by 150 years in dating the oldest known reliable record of a total solar eclipse, a clay tablet that also reflects fear among the ancient observers, researchers said today. Scientists had concluded about 20 years ago that the eclipse, recorded on a clay tablet found in <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, occurred on May 3, 1375 B.C. But in today's issue of the British journal Nature, two Dutch scientists report their analysis shows the eclipse really happened about 150 years later, on March 5, 1223 B.C. The tablet was found in 1948 in the ruins of <LOCATION> Ugarit </LOCATION>, an ancient city near <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> coast. One side appears to tell of a solar eclipse, and the reverse side reads, `` Two livers were examined: danger.'' `` Apparently the anxiety caused by the eclipse of the Sun and the sudden appearance of Mars had to be resolved by an explanation through liver divination,'' wrote the researchers from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amsterdam </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Leiden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. They concluded that the earlier text analysis of the tablet misidentified the time of year in which the eclipse occurred. The new study indicated the eclipse really happened in late February or early March. In addition, the text apparently indicates that Mars was visible at the time of the eclipse, the Dutch researchers said. They compared those criteria and the likely age range for the tablet to a list of possible total solar eclipses visible from <LOCATION> Ugarit </LOCATION>. Only the event in 1223 B.C. fills the bill, the researchers said. In an accompanying editorial, <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> B.F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Museum </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> cautioned that their conclusion `` can best be regarded as a plausible hypothesis.'' The translation of the tablet's text is not certain, and the study assumes that citizens of <LOCATION> Ugarit </LOCATION> followed an Egyptian-style calendar, for which no supporting evidence is available, he said. Even if the tablet is 150 years younger than previously believed, it would remain the oldest known reliable record of a total solar eclipse, <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Krupp </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Griffith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observatory </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, said in a telephone interview. The next-oldest record was made in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> Eighth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Century </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> B.C. </ORGANIZATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> Krupp </ORGANIZATION>, a researcher in ancient astronomy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     03-16 0929</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0973</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Angela </PERSON> <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON> says she has relied on cosmetic surgery for more than 20 years to help her remain a leading lady. The most recent operation was a 1986 neck tuck, she said in April's <PERSON> McCall </PERSON>'s magazine. This, along with losing 20 pounds, enabled the 63-year-old actress to spruce up <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Fletcher </PERSON>, the mystery writer she portrays in the `` Murder, She Wrote'' television series. She said she had a facelift before opening in 1966 in `` Mame,'' the role for which she won the first of her four <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> awards. The next surgery was in 1969 `` to get rid of the little puffy bags that I'd always had under my eyes,'' she said. She said she had her neck and chin redone in 1976. She said she wanted to talk openly about the operations because `` cosmetic surgery should n't be just the secret of actresses and socialites now that it's available to anyone who wants it and can afford it.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ABU DHABI, United Arab Emirates (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> and Princess <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> spent the second day of their visit taking in <LOCATION> Arabian </LOCATION> customs, including camel racing, sword dancing and an open-air lamb roast. The royal couple also did some touring Wednesday. Their hosts were <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Tahnoun </PERSON> <PERSON> Bin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON>, the U.A.E. ruler's representative in the <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Region </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Nahyan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Nahyan </PERSON>, chancellor of <ORGANIZATION> UAE </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> The couple was scheduled to visit the town of <LOCATION> Dubai </LOCATION> next, where <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> was to play in a polo tournament.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Dustin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> has postponed his British stage debut in `` The Merchant of <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION>'' to stay with his 81-year-old father, who is in a coma in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Rehearsals were to start Wednesday in the southwest <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> city of Bath, but <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> flew to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Gottsegen </PERSON>, a spokesman for the family. The play was to have a two-week run in May before moving to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> End </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> Dustin </PERSON> is by his father's bedside. He is taking things day by day at the moment. We do not know what is going to happen next,'' <PERSON> Gottsegen </PERSON> said. The actor's father, <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>, suffered a stroke two weeks ago, the spokesman said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Shelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON>, mother of a 4-year-old daughter, says she was adamant when she first told her husband that she would n't have children. `` In fact, it was the source of one of our first big arguments,'' <PERSON> Long </PERSON> said in April's <PERSON> McCall </PERSON>'s magazine. `` I said, ` Look, I've wanted to have a career all my life. And now that it's taken off, I'm not going to give it up to have a baby.''' <PERSON> Long </PERSON> said she and <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> `` made a contract that he would consider not having children and marrying me anyhow ... and that I would consider having children. `` I do n't think <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> ever kept his part of the deal. But you know what? I'm really glad he did n't. <PERSON> Juliana </PERSON>, she's the very best,'' <PERSON> Long </PERSON> said of her daughter.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SANTA BARBARA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> visited his mountaintop ranch for the first time since leaving the White House and went for a trail ride atop a gift horse, a spokesman said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>, arrived at their 635-acre Rancho del Cielo on Tuesday and were to stay through Friday, said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON>, spokesman for the ex-president. Upon their arrival, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was presented with a black thoroughbred measuring 16.2 hands, a gift from the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canadian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mounted </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON> said. The horse was given to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to acknowledge `` the close friendship'' the <LOCATION> Canadian </LOCATION> government feels toward the 40th president, <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON> said. `` He rode it for the first time on Wednesday and he enjoyed it very much,'' the spokesman said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Journalist <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellerbee </PERSON>, who won an Emmy for her work on an <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> news program, is joining <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> as a regular commentator. She will contribute essays three times a week, <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday. Terms of the contract, which calls for <PERSON> Ellerbee </PERSON> to begin March 20, were not disclosed. <PERSON> Ellerbee </PERSON> was a guest commentator last year during <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION>'s coverage of the national political conventions and on election night. `` I found I like being on <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION>. I'm glad they want me as a regular,'' <PERSON> Ellerbee </PERSON> said. From 1975 to 1986, <PERSON> Ellerbee </PERSON> was at <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, where she anchored and wrote the news magazine `` Weekend'' and `` Summer Sunday-USA,'' plus several documentaries. In 1986, she moved to <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and won the Emmy for her writing on the `` Our World'' historical series. She left <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> the following year to form her own company.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former ballet dancer who says she is <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurt </PERSON>'s common-law wife wants `` equitable distribution'' of the actor's multimillion-dollar holdings, her lawyer said. Hurt is worth about $ 10 million, said <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Golub </PERSON>, attorney for <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> said she and Hurt's 5-year-old son are living in near poverty. She had been asking $ 16,000 a month alimony and child support but now wants what a wife would be entitled to, <PERSON> Golub </PERSON> said. Ms. <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> said she and Hurt lived together for months in <LOCATION> Beaufort </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, during the filming of `` The Big Chill'' in 1982. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> does not recognize common-law marriages but <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> does. Hurt married <PERSON> Heidi </PERSON> <PERSON> Henderson </PERSON>, daughter of band leader <PERSON> Skitch </PERSON> <PERSON> Henderson </PERSON>, two weeks ago. Hurt reportedly had been giving Ms. <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> about $ 60,000 a year. Hurt's lawyer, <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Papernack </PERSON>, could not be reached for comment; calls to his office were not answered.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0254EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Mauldin-Vets     03-16 0727</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mauldin-Vets,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cartoonist, Guest of Administration, Tweaks New Department, Quayle</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As his only non-family, non-official guest on becoming secretary of veterans affairs, <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> chose World War II cartoonist <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Mauldin </PERSON>, who says the new department `` sounds like the same old bureaucracy under a different name.'' <PERSON> Mauldin </PERSON>, winner of the Pulitzer Prize, created the bedraggled dogfaces <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> and <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> for the soldier's newspaper `` Stars and Stripes.'' `` <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> and <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> told the truth of the war, World War II, and the fatigue, sadness, anxiety and humor of the period,'' <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> said in his remarks on the White House South Lawn, with <PERSON> Mauldin </PERSON> close to him on the podium. <PERSON> Mauldin </PERSON>, 67, was a constituent when <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> represented the South Side of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> during 12 terms in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. During an interview before Wednesday's ceremony, <PERSON> Mauldin </PERSON> said he knew <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> only slightly, and did not know whose idea it was to make him a prominent part of the day's events. <PERSON> Mauldin </PERSON> carries a few more pounds and gray hairs than he did in slogging his way up the <LOCATION> Italian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> peninsula </LOCATION> in 1943-1944, where he collected a minor shoulder wound from a German mortar round that inspired one of his best panels _ Soldier, standing, to medic, seated at a table with boxes of medals before him: `` Just gim me the aspirin. I already got a purple heart.'' He told two reporters, one from Stars and Stripes, `` I ca n't help thinking <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> knows my attitude'' as an opponent of the large, main-line veterans groups and of what he saw as their grasping attitude. `` We were against the special philosophy, if you're a veteran you're a special case,'' he said. `` Just by virtue of being a veteran, I do n't think that entitles a guy to a gravy-train ride for the rest of his life.'' <PERSON> Mauldin </PERSON> belonged to the tiny <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, serving two terms as chairman, and has not used any veterans benefits. `` We backed the GI bill, but our slogan was, ` Citizens First, Veterans Second,''' he said. `` I have n't paid dues for years, but they still send me mail. `` There are millions of guys for whom the military experience was the one great experience of their lives. I do n't blame them for wanting to sit around on a Saturday night with their friends and tell lies about their experience.'' <PERSON> Mauldin </PERSON> said he had not paid close attention to veterans affairs recently, so his opinions had to be tentative. _ Agent Orange: Veterans are being forced to try to prove illnesses are connected to exposure to that defoliant, but `` the burden of proof ought to be on the government Those kids ought to have it made up to them. I'm very much in favor of a liberal hand'' in compensation. _ A <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> department replacing the old Veterans Administration: `` It sounds like the same bureaucracy under a different name ... maybe it will be entirely different.'' He was not at all tentative on universal service. `` I think it's great, the idea of putting two or three years of a young man's -LRB- or woman's -RRB- life into public service,'' he said. `` If you're not inclined to the military, then CCC-type work.'' The CCC was the <ORGANIZATION> Civilian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>, a depression-era agency tha provided jobs, clothes and food for young men in camps working on conservation projects. `` I think everyone owes his country a few years out of his life, just a short period, two years, maybe three.'' The point of this, he said, is to `` make better citizens out of them.. bond them to their country. Though many proponents of universal service have said the ending of the draft in 1973 ended valuable lessons in democracy through the military's mixing of classes, races and viewpoints, <PERSON> Mauldin </PERSON> said he thought `` the sociology is obviously a side benefit.'' <PERSON> Mauldin </PERSON> himself enlisted in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mexico </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> in 1940, more than a year before the entry of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> into World War II, because, `` I had some friends in the unit I wanted to be with. ... I wanted to get into something, not out of something.'' Which started his cartoonist juices flowing: `` I do n't want to pick on <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Boy </PERSON>,'' he said with a grin, recalling cartoons of last fall's campaign lambasting the Vietam-era plunge into the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> of Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0259EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChurchProtest     03-16 0590</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Church Protest,0612</SECOND>
<HEAD>Troubled Church Reopens Without Incident; Priest Suspended</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRENT LAYMON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BRIDGEPORT, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Roman Catholic church where parishioners rebelled over the removal of a Polish priest has reopened, but church authorities revealed that the priest has been suspended by his superiors. Police have guarded St. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> the Archangel church since it was closed Feb. 18 by <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Egan </PERSON> after a weeklong sit-in by about 200 dissidents upset over the sudden, unexplained ouster of the Rev. Roman Palaszewski. There were relatively few worshipers Wednesday at four early morning Masses, two celebrated in English and two in Polish, said the Rev. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Smyka </PERSON>, associate pastor. `` It was very, very emotional,'' <PERSON> Smyka </PERSON> said. `` The 6:30 Mass _ I think I cried through half of it. It was just so good to be back in the church. I mean, that's what our business is as priests.'' Some parishioners said they were overjoyed by the church's reopening Some said they heard about it by word-of-mouth, or by making daily drives by the church since the announcement that it would reopen. Monsignor <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Grieco </PERSON>, a spokesman for <PERSON> Egan </PERSON>, said Wednesday that <PERSON> Palaszewski </PERSON> was suspended indefinitely for defying orders from his Franciscan superiors in <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, to return to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> last month. `` He's still ordained, but he can not function as a priest because he did n't obey his superior who commanded him, under obedience, to return to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Grieco </PERSON> said `` He would not be able to say Mass or administer the sacraments.'' <PERSON> Palaszewski </PERSON>, who spent three years at the church under an agreement between his superiors in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and Franciscan officials in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, has been in seclusion in the <LOCATION> Bridgeport </LOCATION> area since his removal in December. About 50 worshipers attended a Lenten prayer service Wednesday evening. They entered the church under the watchful eye of a police officer sitting in a van parked discreetly across the street. Four or five dissidents watched quietly from across the street Wednesday evening as worshipers entered the church. They then gathered at a Polish club a block from the church to plan a demonstration outside the church this weekend on Palm Sunday, the start of the holiest week in the church year. `` They did n't heal our wounds _ everything is the same,'' said <PERSON> Genevieve </PERSON> <PERSON> Kozlowski </PERSON>, a parishioner for 25 years and one of the protest leaders. She was unaware of Wednesday's opening, but said she and many other protesters plan to boycott services because they do n't believe their complaints have been addressed, <PERSON> Kozlowski </PERSON> said. The dissidents are demanding <PERSON> Palaszewski </PERSON>'s return to the parish and the removal of the church's pastor, the Rev. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bambol </PERSON>, who they claim engineered <PERSON> Palaszewski </PERSON>'s removal because of his popularity among recent immigrants. They also question <PERSON> Bambol </PERSON>'s commitment to maintaining the church's <LOCATION> Polis </LOCATION> traditions. <PERSON> Bambol </PERSON>'s supporters have said <PERSON> Palaszewski </PERSON> paid scant attention to parishioners who were not recent immigrants. A weeklong sit-in by about 200 dissidents who occupied the church in shifts ended early Feb. 18 when church authorities summoned police to expel them. Two who refused to leave voluntarily were charged with trespassing. <PERSON> Egan </PERSON> suspended Masses indefinitely the same day. <PERSON> Bambol </PERSON> said after the prayer service that the dissidents are welcome to return as long as they `` abide by the rules of the church.'' He said he was `` very joyful, very happy'' that the church had reopened. `` After all we were all suffering for so long unjustifiably ... we are happy to be back in harness, so to speak,'' he said. `` This is a period of reconciliation.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     03-16 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0025</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Down In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 32,098.24, down 2.24 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Thursday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890316-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-89 0313EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Semiautomatics     03-16 0775</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Semiautomatics,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Manufacturer Halts Sales of Semiautomatic Weapon</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Colt Industries Inc, no period, is cq</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
