<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 2327EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Egypt-Libya     05-31 0332</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Egypt-Libya,0344</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mubarak Meets Libyan Emissary</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAIRO, Egypt (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> and high-ranking <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> official <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaddaf </PERSON> <PERSON> Dam </PERSON> met on Wednesday to discuss improving relations between their two countries, the state-run <ORGANIZATION> Middle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported. It said the meeting is a continuation of conciliatory talks that started between <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> leader Col. <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> at last week's <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> summit at <LOCATION> Casablanca </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gaddaf </PERSON> <PERSON> Dam </PERSON> is a cousin of <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>'s intelligence chief. He came to <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> Tuesday. The agency gave no details on the meeting or elaborate on the duration of the visit. The summit was <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>'s first since 1976. <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION>'s relations with the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> plummeted in 1977 with the late President <PERSON> Anwar </PERSON> <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON>'s visit to <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>'s league membership was suspended and most Arab states cut diplomatic ties in 1979, after <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON> signed a peace treaty with the Jewish state. <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> is among the last to soften its attitude toward <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> told Egyptian journalists before Wednesday's meeting that Egyptian-Libyan relations `` are on the threshold of a new era based on a right foundation of frankness.'' On Monday, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> reopened its borders with <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> for the first time in more than a decade. The land route is used mainly by thousands of Egyptians working in <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>. During the years the border was closed, Egyptian workers had to travel between the two countries by way of <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> or some other point. Negotiations are under way between a Libyan civil aviation delegation and Egyptian authorities for restoring direct air service between <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> capital <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION>. Egyptian-Libyan relations had been strained since 1972, when <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON> rejected a bid by <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> ffor an immediate merger of the two countries. They fought a brief border war in 1977. <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>'s government has charged <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> with several atttempts to assassinate Libyan dissidents in Egyptian exile. It suspected <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> of laying mines in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Suez </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Red </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> that damaged 20 ships in the summer of 1984.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 2341EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-NuclearSabotage 3rdLd-Writethru a0844 05-31 0578</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nuclear Sabotage, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0844,0591</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Environmentalists Arrested on Nuclear Sabotage Charges</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES throughout with founder of radical group among those
arrested, background on group, quotes, other details. Adds byline. No pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MEL REISNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A radical environmental group's founder and three other people were arrested Wednesday on charges they conspired to sabotage two nuclear power plants and an <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> bomb factory in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> said. Two men were arrested early Wednesday while trying to use a propane torch to cut down a utility-line pole leading from an electrical substation in <LOCATION> Wenden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> officials in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> said. A woman was arrested in <LOCATION> Prescott </LOCATION>, nearly 80 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Wenden </LOCATION>, in the alleged plot, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> said. A third man was arrested in <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> on charges of conspiring with th others to sabotage commercial nuclear power plants at <LOCATION> Wintersburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, and near <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Luis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Obispo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, as well as the federal government's Rocky Flats Nuclear Weapons Plant near <LOCATION> Golden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo </LOCATION><LOCATION> . </LOCATION> The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> said the defendants were members of a radical environmentalist group calling itself the <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> Eco-Terrorist International Conspiracy. The organization, which took its name from the former <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> governor who was impeached last year, has sent communiques to news organizations in the <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION> claiming responsibility for criminal acts, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> said. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> said the arrests resulted from a three-year undercover investigation that began after vandals cut power lines at the Palo Verde Nuclear Generating Station in <LOCATION> Wintersburg </LOCATION>, 50 miles west of <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>, in May 1986. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Foreman </PERSON>, 42, who founded Earth First! _ the exclamation point is part of the name _ in 1979, was arrested in <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> on a charge of conspiracy. He appeared before a federal magistrate there and was ordered held without bond. The other three appeared in <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> and also were ordered held for an appearance Friday in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, 39, and <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, 37, both of <PERSON> Prescott </PERSON>, were charged with conspiracy to sabotage a nuclear facility as well as destruction of an energy facility, destruction of property used in interstate commerce and destruction of government property. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> said they were arrested while trying to cut down a utility pole supporting a power line that links an electrical substation with two irrigation pumping stations of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Project </ORGANIZATION>, a multibillion-dollar canal system bringing <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> water to <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> `` Peggy'' <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Millett </PERSON>, 35, of <PERSON> Prescott </PERSON>, was arrested and charged with the same crimes, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> said. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> also investigated acts of vandalism against ski-lift equipment at a <LOCATION> Flagstaff </LOCATION> ski resort and the cutting of power-line poles at three uranium mines last year in northern <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, the bureau said. <PERSON> Foreman </PERSON> is a co-founder of Earth First!, said <PERSON> Rod </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondt </PERSON>, a spokesman in the <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> office of the group's journal. The loosely organized group, which has no officers or formal membership, did n't plan the attack, <PERSON> Mondt </PERSON> said, but added: `` Some of us support the right to do those kinds of things.'' Earth First! was inspired in part by `` The Monkey Wrench Gang,'' a novel by the late <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Abbey </PERSON> about a trio of environmentalalists who try to blow up the <LOCATION> Glen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canyon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dam </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mondt </PERSON> said he was unaware of an organization called the <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Meacham </PERSON> Eco-Terrorist International Conspiracy, but noted that the organization's acronym would be EMETIC, a word defined as a medicine or other substance that causes vomiting.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0019EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-HongKong-Vietnamese     05-31 0305</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hong Kong-Vietnamese,0315</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hong Kong Moves 109 Vietnamese Boat People to Remote Island</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government, enforcing its policies to discourage Vietnamese refugees from coming to this British colony, on Tuesday towed a boat with 109 Vietnamese to a remote island, officials reported. They said boats carrying 745 refugees entered <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> waters Tuesday and a vessel with 109 people was towed to <LOCATION> Tai </LOCATION> <LOCATION> A </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chau </LOCATION>, an island 20 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, because other facilities were filled. <PERSON> Tai </PERSON> <PERSON> A </PERSON> <PERSON> Chau </PERSON> has virtually no shelter. `` We have had more than 2,300 arrivals over the past three days. Our accomodation resources have simply been overwhelmed,'' said <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> refugee coordinator <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON>. He said the people taken to <LOCATION> Tai </LOCATION> <LOCATION> A </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chau </LOCATION> would have to stay aboard the boat or on the dock. `` There is one school building which some people may be able to use, but I think most will not be able to have covered accomodations,'' he added. The refugees will remain on the island until the government can find a place for them and then process them, <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON> said. He said he did not know how long that might take. <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> received hundreds of thousands of Indochinese boat people after communist forces defeated the U.S.-backed governments in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in April 1975. But thousands of Vietnamese are still fleeing their homeland. A year ago <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> adopted a screening policy that treats all Indochinese refugees as illegal immigrants subject to repatriation unless they can prove they fled political persecution. But that has not curbed the influx. For the first five months of this year 13,182 boat people have arrived in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> has agreed to attend an international conference on Indochinese refugees that is to be held in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> June 13-14.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0019EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BuyingFriends     05-31 0189</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Buying Friends,0194</SECOND>
<HEAD>Elementary Student Gives Away $3,000 To Buy Friends</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KNOXVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 10-year-old elementary school student, apparently feeling he needed more friends, decided to buy them with thousands of dollars of his father's money. No one is exactly sure how much money the youngster spread around the school in his pursuit of friendship, although officials have recovered $ 3,000 from classmates and their parents. `` He was handing out $ 5, $ 10, $ 20 and $ 100 bills,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Scruggs </PERSON>, the school system's security officer. `` The boy apparently got into his father's stash.'' The money-for-friendship enterprise was uncovered by <ORGANIZATION> Ritta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Principal </ORGANIZATION> J.W. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> last week when a student asked him to break a $ 10 bill. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> asked where the student had gotten the money, and was told the fourth-grader was giving it away. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said no disciplinary action was taken against the spendthrift youngster. Officials checked to make sure no coercion was involved in the payments, but the gifts apparently were made freely, <PERSON> Scruggs </PERSON> said. And with some success; the boy `` was making friends real well,'' said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Shumpert </PERSON>, assistant superintendent of the <LOCATION> Knox </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> school system.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0022EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AsteroidApproach     05-31 0342</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Asteroid Approach,0351</SECOND>
<HEAD>Experts: Another Asteroid Will Pass Close, But No Danger</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GAINESVILLE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An asteroid will pass by Earth just a little more than 8 million miles away this Saturday, the closest approach since a `` near miss'' in March, but presents no danger to the planet, astronomers say. The asteroid, estimated to be one to two miles across, may be visible as a faint star, and will grow brighter as it approaches at 20 miles per second, astronomer <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON> said in a release Tuesday from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION>. On March 23, an asteroid came within 450,000 miles of <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, which was considered a near miss in astronomical terms. <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Marsden </PERSON>, associate director of the <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Astrophysics </ORGANIZATION>, said Tuesday that the asteroid due Saturday is the sixth relatively close approach this year. He called the number a `` statistical fluke.'' <PERSON> Marsden </PERSON> said no one should worry about this or any other known asteroid _ the one that hits probably wo n't be spotted until it's too late to do anything `` It's not a question of if an asteroid will hit us, but when,'' <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON> said. `` And it will make earthquakes, volcanic eruptions and other natural disasters pale in comparison to its destructive force.'' Some astronomers believe an asteroid larger than a quarter mile across hits the Earth once about every 50,000 years. The last crater formed by an asteroid occurred in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> about 50,000 years ago, <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON> said. An asteroid that struck the Earth 65 million years ago may have wiped out the last of the dinosaurs, some scientists believe. Such a strike today would have effects similar to nuclear war without the radiation. It would level buildings for several hundred miles and would create giant tidal waves, <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON> said. Scientists in the 1960s and 1970s thought asteroids that pass by <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> were rare; today they believe there may be hundreds and possibly thousands of them. It is unclear if there are more asteroids or if astronomers have simply become better at finding them, <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0023EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Homeless-Amnesty     05-31 0310</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Homeless-Amnesty,0320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Homeless Featured in Anti-Death Penalty Commercial</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HORN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new public service announcement against capital punishment features an unusual cast of characters: the homeless. The <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> television commercial, to be offered soon for international broadcasts, uses 50 homeless people. `` I did n't want people that were well-fed, happy human beings, to try to pull off the roles of people all over the world who have been imprisoned for long periods of time,'' said commercial director <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Bill </PERSON>, who co-produced `` The Sting'' and directed `` My Bodyguard.'' `` The homeless are disenfranchised people, and they are people who are, in effect, oppressed,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON>, who like others donated work for the project. The black-and-white ads cast the homeless as prisoners facing execution, their heads covered in bags before an imaginary killing. The 30 - and 60-second commercials conclude with the shot of a falling guillotine blade <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> said the faces of the homeless, unlike those of professional actors, naturally are filled with hopelessness and defeat. `` I think by seeing them on the screen, your attention is drawn to them,'' <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> said. `` We're talking about a larger issue. The homeless people sort of represent people in prison.'' <PERSON> Bill </PERSON>, who runs the <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION> restaurant, selected his cast from the crowds of people who gather for a free meal the restaurant provides every Tuesday. Those cast were paid $ 40 for the one-day commercial shooting and given lunch. `` The saddest thing was to see them leave at the end of the shoot,'' said producer <PERSON> Clare </PERSON> <PERSON> Baren </PERSON> of Riverrun Films. `` It was horrible to think where they were going back to. They were just really terrific people.'' The commercial's makers hope television stations across the country and around the globe will broadcast the spot. It also will be shown at the commercial competition at <LOCATION> Cannes </LOCATION> starting June 19.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0031EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-IntelligenceCenter     05-31 0778</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Intelligence Center,0802</SECOND>
<HEAD>El Paso Intelligence Center Serves as Drug Agencies' Eyes, Ears</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOLDEN LEWIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> EL </LOCATION> <LOCATION> PASO </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> _ Subject: <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paso </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. Mission: Collect and share with law enforcement agencies information on drug -, weapon - and Number of arrests: None. `` Our first task is tactical intelligence _ that which the field agents can use to cause an arrest or seizure,'' says <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Norsworthy </PERSON>, director of the center at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bliss </LOCATION> that publishes its phone number but reveals little else. EPIC might tell the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> where to find a specific marijuana-laden ship off the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> coast. Or it might tell the <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> who a certain smuggler hangs around with. But it looks farther downrange, too. `` What's going to happen two years from now in what part of the world? We try to figure that out,'' said <PERSON> Norsworthy </PERSON>. At EPIC, representatives of 10 federal agencies gather evidence and piece together a criminological jigsaw puzzle that displays drug smugglers and other criminal organizations. The law enforcement consortium does n't make seizures or arrests and does n't take credit for the arrests it produces `` They are our primary source of intelligence,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON>, senior tactical coordinator for <ORGANIZATION> Operation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION>, an El Paso-based union of federal agencies that chases and arrests drug smugglers along the U.S.-Mexican border. He declined to recount specific cases in which EPIC information resulted in large-scale busts. EPIC started out in 1974 as the <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Border </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, with 35 employees from the <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> and the Immigration and <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> working in cramped quarters. Four years later it had a congressional mandate, a new name, 106 employees from six federal agencies and 16,000 square feet of space in central <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>. Now the 15-year-old intelligence network occupies a brand-new, 57,000-square-foot building on <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bliss </LOCATION>, where 200 employees of the <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Marshals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alcohol </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tobacco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Firearms </ORGANIZATION> labor 24 hours a day. Some of those agencies have been known for fierce turf battles, but <PERSON> Norsworthy </PERSON> said that's rare at EPIC. `` It's pretty unique in that we all get along good. After 90 to 120 days, agents lose their agency identity and become part of EPIC.'' EPIC gives <ORGANIZATION> Operation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> `` threat assessments'' _ dossiers on illegal organizations, along with when and where they are expected to operate next. It prepares similar assessments for the Miami-based <ORGANIZATION> Lightning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, which tries to keep drug shipments out of southern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. Other information goes to the agencies making up EPIC, the lead law enforcement agencies in 50 states, the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Guam </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Samoa </LOCATION>. It gets upwards of 300,000 inquiries a year. Usually, when police ask for information, EPIC asks why. `` Something made someone make that call _ either he saw or heard something,'' <PERSON> Norsworthy </PERSON> said. `` We ask for that information, and we build on that. We look for patterns and trends all the time.'' Bits of information can be assembled like a puzzle: an ID number on the tail of a plane, a series of large cash bank deposits and the sighting of a suspect could start an investigation ending in an arrest and seizure. Sometimes it turns out that different police agencies are investigating the same organization but are n't aware of each other. In those cases, EPIC brings the agencies together and helps plot investigation strategies. Some of the information comes from those cases. Other times, member federal agencies contribute. Some data come from <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> offices abroad. Each agent working at EPIC is limited to the investigative methods his or her agency is permitted under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> law; a wiretap, for example, would require a court order. If there's any criticism of EPIC among law enforcement agencies, it's that the center's computer system needs to be upgraded. `` Just bring them up to the state of the art,'' <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, represents the district where EPIC resides. A few years ago, he helped fight off a proposal to move it to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Now he would like to improve its computers. `` My goal is to make it the absolute state-of-the-art intelligence-gathering center in the country,'' he said. Just how advanced the computer and communications systems are is a secret. <PERSON> Norsworthy </PERSON> is n't telling, but he said a police agency calling EPIC probably will find the information it wants on a suspect. `` If he's ever been the subject of an investigation or an associate of someone who's been the subject of an investigation,'' he said, `` chances are pretty good.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lebanon-Blockade     05-31 0785</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon-Blockade,0814</SECOND>
<HEAD>Blockade Runners Carry Food, Ammo For Besieged Christians</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 The bombardment of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> and the blockade of its ports has produced an anonymous armada of small craft bringing in food, ammunition and even whisky to the 1 million trapped Christians. Here is a report on how it stays afloat.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By DONNA ABU-NASR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OQAIBEH, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Most nights, a dozen small cargo ships zigzag through shellfire for ports along <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> coast to deliver food and ammunition to Christians besieged by <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and its Moslem allies. Others dart in during daylight, often as shells and rockets explode around them and knots of people stand on shore and cheer. The ships' cargoes have become the lifeline for the estimated 1 million Christians trapped in their enclave north of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. `` This is why there are no serious shortages,'' said a police spokesman, who can not be identified under standing regulations. `` The ships bring in vegetables, canned fruit and cattle as well as ammunition.'' Not all the provisions are essentials. An east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> businessman said one company recently received 11 containers of whisky. The police spokesman said at least 12 ships a day make it through the Syrian blockade. They dock mainly at <LOCATION> Jounieh </LOCATION>, 12 miles north of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, and the ancient port of <LOCATION> Byblos </LOCATION>, 10 miles farther north, and at smaller harbors in between. <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, said two or three ships out of every 15 carry weapons and ammunition from <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s main Arab rival and the Christians' only ally in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. The latest round of fighting in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s 14-year-old civil war began on March 8 when <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> commander Gen. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> ordered his troops, most of whom are Christians, to blockade ports run by Moslem militias. Fierce artillery battles followed and the Syrians blockaded Christian ports. Despite a cease-fire called by the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> on May 11, the Syrians shell the Christians' coastal strip daily to try to prevent supplies from reaching <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s forces. In recent days, the <ORGANIZATION> Syrians </ORGANIZATION> have deployed navy gunboats to tighten the blockade, and some cargo ships have been turned back. Yet some Christians believe the Syrians are not tightening the noose as much as they might. `` With the firepower the Syrians have they could be doing a lot more,'' one source said. `` We do n't know why there is this restraint, except possibly because they're not yet prepared to go all the way.'' The danger zone is about six miles off the coast. <PERSON> Boutros </PERSON> <PERSON> Sassine </PERSON>, 23, was a crewman aboard the 1,000-ton Lebanese freighter <PERSON> Paula </PERSON>, which took several hits on May 18 as it approached <PERSON> Oqaibeh </PERSON>, five miles north of <LOCATION> Jounieh </LOCATION>, with a cargo of food. He and three other crewmen were wounded when a Syrian 130mm shell hit the mast. Lying in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> George </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> <LOCATION> in </LOCATION> <LOCATION> east </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, his head heavily bandaged, <PERSON> Boutros </PERSON> said the freighter was about five miles off <PERSON> Oqaibeh </PERSON> `` when the shells started falling all around us.'' `` Some of them were hitting only a few feet away, sending cascades of water over us. Then we were hit. I saw my brother <PERSON> Boulos </PERSON> and the others fall,'' he said. `` A fishing boat which was in the vicinity came through the shelling and took us ashore,'' <PERSON> Boutros </PERSON> said. A Christian source said that most of the ship captains come from the <LOCATION> Oqaibeh </LOCATION> area. `` Their agency pays them about $ 5,000 a trip,'' he said. `` The seamen who used to earn $ 200 a month now get $ 200 a trip, which usually lasts between 24 and 48 hours.'' The ships sail mainly between the Christian enclave and <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, 100 miles to the northeast. But Christian sources reported that some also pick up cargoes of fruit and vegetables from the southern ports of <LOCATION> Sidon </LOCATION> and Tyre, both run by Moslem militias. A police spokesman in <LOCATION> Sidon </LOCATION> said merchants charter boats to take produce to the Christian enclave. `` They do n't want to waste their produce,'' he said. `` They're ready to sell to the devil. The Shiite Moslem Amal militia, which controls Tyre, tried to stop merchants there from sending goods to east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. But sources said the businessmen, who pay hefty fees to Amal, told the militia they would stop only if the militia bought all their produce. The traffic is not all one-way. About 15,000 Christians have fled the enclave aboard ferries from <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>. The vessels anchor offshore, and passengers must take a nerve-jangling ride in small boats in darkness _ and often under shellfre _ to reach the ferries. Hundreds more have evacuated aboard a Norwegian Hovercraft, the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Maria </LOCATION>, which slips into <LOCATION> Jounieh </LOCATION> and other ports at night.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--LegislativeIntrusion     05-31 0120</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Legislative Intrusion,0121</SECOND>
<HEAD>Masked Intruders Disrupt Parliament Session</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COPENHAGEN, Denmark (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This country's parliament has a tradition of free public access, so it was n't much trouble for about 50 masked intruders to barge into the chamber and rip up documents as legislators looked on. The intruders, said by police to be members of a radical squatter's organization, fought briefly with unarmed parliament guards during Tuesday's raid. Police said they arrested about 30, but the rest escaped. It was the first time demonstrators had disturbed a session of the Folketinget, or parliament, police said <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>'s chairman, <PERSON> Erik </PERSON> <PERSON> Ninn-Hansen </PERSON>, said afterward that the intruders would be prosecuted and that security in Christiansborg Palace, which houses the parliament, would be reviewed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Sweden-SkinCancer     05-31 0254</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sweden-Skin Cancer,0260</SECOND>
<HEAD>Comprehensive Study Show Skin Cancer Galloping</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 29-year study of cancer in <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> shows the rate of cases increased faster among women than men, especially skin cancer caused by too much sun. Malignant melanoma caused by overexposure to ultraviolet rays was increasing by 6.6 percent a year and ine 1987 represented 3.5 percent of all cancer cases, said <PERSON> Jerzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Einhorn </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Karolinska </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>. A law requiring doctors to report all cancer cases to a national registrar since 1958 has yielded `` a unique foundation'' for health care and planning, since it covers 100 percent of the population in specific areas, <PERSON> Einhorn </PERSON> said. The study, released Tuesday by the hospital, covered <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gotland </LOCATION>, a large rural island in the Baltic. <PERSON> Sven </PERSON> <PERSON> Tornqvist </PERSON>, who was in charge of the register, said the rate of all forms of cancer increased by 29 percent for women and 15 percent for men in the Swedish capital from 1958 to 1987. The figures were higher in <LOCATION> Gotland </LOCATION>. Malignant melanoma `` could become the major form of cancer in the next century'' because many people who have damaged their skin have not yet developed the disease, <PERSON> Einhorn </PERSON> said. He attributed the increase among Swedes to their more frequent holiday trips to warmer countries and their penchant for sunbathing. One reason for the general rising incidence of cancers is that people are living longer, <PERSON> Einhorn </PERSON> said. Lung cancer was the most common cancer, but it decreased among men along with a decline in smoking.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--UnusualStrike     05-31 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Unusual Strike,0185</SECOND>
<HEAD>Italian Strikers Give Tourists a Break</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tourists got an after-hours look at the Roman Forum and free tours of the ancient ruins, the <LOCATION> Palatine </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> and the Coliseum because of an unusal work protest by the caretakers. The Forum is normally closed on Tuesday afternoon, but the caretakers chose instead to work overtime and give away free tickets as a way of protesting work conditions and `` Cultural Ministry bureaucracy.'' The workers said they want more money and they want the ministry to train them and offer guided tours of the Forum. They also want the ministry to hire more people and to keep the site open for more hours. Tourists in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> often miss the chance to see archeological sites and musems because of limited visiting hours and recurrent strikes. The unusual protest was designed to gain public support, said a woman employee who asked not to be identified. `` If we stopped work, we would just get a bad press. This way we can show people that we are also interested in them,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-India-USTrade     05-31 0737</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-India-US Trade,0763</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government, Business Baffled By US Trade Warning</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RAJU GOPALAKRISHNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 By accusing <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> of unfair trade practices, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> may have dealt a major setback to Prime Minister <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s cautious efforts to open the vast Indian market to foreign goods. In a nation that has long aspired to self-sufficiency and thrown up a bewildering and costly barricade of red tape to foreign investment, the few <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> brand names to reach consumers have achieved overnight popularity. Wrangler jeans, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> music cassettes and <LOCATION> Chesterfield </LOCATION> cigarettes are among American goods that entered <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> after <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s government started easing the protectionist policies of his mother and predecessor, <PERSON> Indira </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> <ORGANIZATION> Pepsi </ORGANIZATION> is poised to follow. All are manufactured in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> under license and in association with local partners, with the foreign share limited to 40 percent. The opening of Indian markets started in 1985, a few months after <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> took office. But observers say last week's citing of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> under the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Omnibus Trade Act could hurt the process. `` The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> perception seems to be that it can open up Indian markets with a crowbar,'' said industrialist <PERSON> Hari </PERSON> <PERSON> Shankar </PERSON> <PERSON> Singhania </PERSON>. `` From the logical point of view, it is better to use goodwill.'' `` Maybe they got impatient. I doubt whether the intended results will follow _ and maybe contrary reactions will set in,'' he added. In an editorial entitled `` A Super Folly,'' the pro-government <ORGANIZATION> Hindustan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said: `` By branding <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> as an unfair trade partner at a time when the country is attempting to move towards more open trade, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> runs the risk of reversing the tide of opinion building up in favor of liberalization.'' A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> official acknowledged <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> had eased its trade restrictions but said much remains to be done. `` There has definitely been some liberalization, but there is a considerable distance to go,'' he said, speaking on condition he not be identified further. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> accused <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> of violating the 1988 trade act by impeding direct foreign investment and closing its insurance market to foreign companies. The law allows the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to impose tariffs of 100 percent on goods from <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> if negotiations fail to remove the barriers within 18 months. Despite its tentative reforms, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> still levies customs duties in excess of 200 percent on some foreign goods and industrial components. The government has yet to respond to the American invitation for negotiations. Its only comments have been that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> action is unfair and irrational. `` Negotiations can not be held under threat. How can you expect any self-respecting country to do it?'' said <PERSON> Singhania </PERSON>, who led a delegation to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> earlier this month to try to ward off the citing of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> under the Omnibus Trade Act. A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> delegation also came to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> earlier this month for discussions with Indian government officials. `` We justified our restrictions because of our balance of payments constraints,'' said <PERSON> Anwarul </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoda </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> official who took part in the talks. `` But even while offering justifications, we are liberalizing. Our trade has never been so liberal.'' <PERSON> Hoda </PERSON> and <PERSON> Singhania </PERSON> noted that <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s trade surplus with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has been declining, from $ 1 billion in 1987 to $ 700 million in 1988. They said <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s tough measures were unjustified since <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> was responsible for less than 1 percent of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' overall trade deficit <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, which also was cited, is responsible for 44 percent. Only one other nation was singled out _ <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>. Both <PERSON> Hoda </PERSON> and <PERSON> Singhania </PERSON> acknowledged the tremendous appeal of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> goods and services for <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 880 million people. `` <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> brands, techniques and marketing systems are the best in the world,'' said <PERSON> Singhania </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> J.K. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, which makes synthetic fabrics, paints and cosmetics. Among consumer items, U.S.-franchised stereo cassettes hold a virtual monopoly in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s Western music market. `` CBS cassettes sell very well,'' said <PERSON> Kishore </PERSON>, a salesman at a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> music shop who declined to give his last name. `` Since they came in the market, <ORGANIZATION> Music </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- the major local company -RRB- has dropped.'' Another indicator of the appeal of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> goods is the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>'s semiannual sale of obsolete equipment. A weekly news magazine, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> Today, said recently that buyers bid feverishly for 10-year-old air conditioners, sometimes offering more than the price of a new Indian model, because `` of the strong mystique of the foreign brand.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0058EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Secchia     05-31 0694</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Secchia,0720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Controversial Ambassador Nominee Is Respected in Hometown</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Note contents grafs 8-11.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LISA PERLMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GRAND RAPIDS, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 People at <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign rallies in southwestern <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> last year heard first from his foremost cheerleader, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON>. The outspoken and sometimes abrasive state <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> party leader positioned himself at the podium for more than an hour before <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s arrival and led thousands of supporters in songs taunting Democratic presidential nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. As <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>'s national committeeman since 1980, <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON> never has been at a loss for words. Until now. After months of tireless work on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s behalf, <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON> was rewarded with a nomination as ambassador to <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. It initially appeared the 52-year-old Italian-American lumber magnate would sail through <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation, but <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON>'s propensity for coarse humor and off-color remarks have haunted him For example: _ A few days after <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s selection of <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> to run as vice president, <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON> defended <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> amid rumors linking him romantically to a former female lobbyist. `` If that's the only thing you can say about a 41-year-old man _ that he danced close with a good-looking woman _ then I think he'll make one hell of a vice president.'' _ <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON> does n't deny he made an offensive hand gesture to a political foe in the basement of a bar, but after it was reported called it good-natured political sparring. _ A January 1988 <PERSON> Harper </PERSON>'s magazine article about the <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> GOP portrayed <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON> as a sexist and quoted him as making vulgar remarks about the size of a woman's breasts. <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON> says he was misquoted. _ In August 1988, <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON> said of his political adversaries, `` I know what sodomy is because that's what Democrats are always doing to me.'' <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON> complains his comments have been misinterpreted, and that some of the people now judging him in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> do n't understand his humor There's been grumbling in Italian newspapers over <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s selection of an ambassador who is an expert fund-raiser with a sharp tongue but little foreign policy experience In the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON>'s confirmation vote was stalled until at least Wednesday because of concerns of Sen. <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallop </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wyo </LOCATION>. The delay caused <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON>, the grandson of <LOCATION> Italian </LOCATION> immigrants, to miss <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s visit to <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> last week. `` He's certainly not pleased ... with reports that the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> wants to make him twist in the wind as punishment for so-called past sins,'' said <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Secchia </LOCATION> employee fielding media calls. <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON> has declined all requests for interviews since his confirmation was stalled two weeks ago. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> approved <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON>'s nomination, but Chairman <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, warned that <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON> might be an embarrassment At home in Grand Rapids, those who know <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON> well see him primarily as a generous, hard-working, good-hearted community leader _ who just happens to put his foot in his mouth occasionally. `` He's a street fighter,'' said businessman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Yob </PERSON>, a close friend and political associate. `` When he wants something, he goes for it.'' Even his political foes acknowledge <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON> has been a driving force in the state <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. As chairman and chief executive officer of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cos. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the father of four has turned the Grand Rapids business into a $ 400 million lumber, restaurant and real estate empire, the fourth-largest building products distributor in the country He has vowed to tone down his rhetoric when he takes on his new job in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. But some of his political adversaries are dubious. `` I never suspected I would hear the name <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Secchia </PERSON> in the same sentence with the word diplomat,'' said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Lansing </LOCATION> attorney and deputy state director of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' campaign. `` His mouth works faster than his mind. ... I do n't think it'll be long before he'll put his foot in his mouth when he gets over to <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> said But others believe <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> will be disarmed. `` I get the feeling that he is moving on to a different phase of his life, where he going to learn and practice the art of diplomacy. But I know it probably wo n't come easy,'' national <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> Committeewoman <PERSON> Ronna </PERSON> <PERSON> Romney </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0100EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ReadingLists     05-31 0257</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reading Lists,0292</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Required Reading Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the most widely assigned literary works at public, <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> and private high schools, according to a survey by the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Learning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Teaching of Literature at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>. Included are the percentages of schools assigning each work.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Public Schools:</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 1. `` Romeo and <PERSON> Juliet </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>, 84 percent. 2. `` Macbeth,'' <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>, 81 percent. 3. `` Huckleberry Finn,'' <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Twain </PERSON>, 70 percent. 4. `` <PERSON> Julius </PERSON> <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>, 70 percent. 5. `` To Kill a Mockingbird,'' <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, 69 percent. 6. `` The Scarlet Letter,'' <PERSON> Nathaniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawthorne </PERSON>, 62 percent. 7. `` Of Mice and Men,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinbeck </PERSON>, 56 percent. 8. `` Hamlet,'' <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>, 55 percent. 9. `` The Great Gatsby,'' <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>, 54 percent. 10. `` Lord of the Flies,'' <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Golding </PERSON>, 54 percent.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Catholic Schools:</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 1. `` Huckleberry Finn,'' 76 percent. 2. `` The Scarlet Letter,'' 70 percent. 3. `` Macbeth,'' 70 percent. 4. `` To Kill a Mockingbird,'' 67 percent. 5. `` The Great Gatsby,'' 64 percent. 6. `` Romeo and <PERSON> Juliet </PERSON>,'' _ 63 percent. 7. `` Hamlet,'' 60 percent. 8. `` Of Mice and Men,'' 56 percent. 9. `` <PERSON> Julius </PERSON> <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON>,'' 54 percent. 10. `` Lord of the Flies,'' 52 percent.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Private Schools:</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 1. `` Macbeth,'' 74 percent. 2. `` Romeo and <PERSON> Juliet </PERSON>,'' 66 percent. 3. `` Huckleberry Finn,'' 56 percent. 4. `` The Scarlet Letter,'' 52 percent. 5. `` Hamlet,'' 51 percent. 6. `` The Great Gatsby,'' 49 percent. 7. `` To Kill a Mockingbird,'' 47 percent. 8. `` <PERSON> Julius </PERSON> <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON>,'' 42 percent. 9. `` The Odyssey,'' Homer, 39 percent. 10. `` Lord of the Flies,'' 34 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0110EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RequiredReading Bjt   05-31 0614</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Required Reading, Bjt,0633</SECOND>
<HEAD>Required High School Reading Lists Stress Shakespeare</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserGraphic NY9</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE MITGANG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 High schools are requiring students to read almost exactly what they did 25 years ago: heavy on Shakespeare but light on works by female and minority authors, according to a survey. Eighty-four percent of public high schools assign students `` Romeo and <PERSON> Juliet </PERSON>,'' the tearful Shakespearean play that tops the list of required works, according to the nationwide survey by the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Learning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Teaching of Literature at <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>. But only one of the top 10 most frequently assigned works was by a female author _ `` To Kill A Mockingbird,'' by <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>. No works were by minorities, according to the survey of 322 public schools, 80 <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> schools and 86 private schools conducted last spring. `` I think the survey shows schools are still very much concerned with emphasizing good literature. They continue to assign classics complemented with modern and accessible works,'' said the survey's author, <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Applebee </PERSON> `` At the same time, it's disturbing that there are essentially no books by minority authors working their way into the canons, and little representation of women.'' Following `` <PERSON> Romeo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Juliet </PERSON>,'' 81 percent of public high schools required `` Macbeth.'' `` Huckleberry Finn,'' the classic <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Twain </PERSON> novel, was the third most assigned work, with 70 percent requiring it. The rest of the top 10 were, in order, `` <PERSON> Julius </PERSON> <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON>,'' by <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>, `` To Kill A Mockingbird,'' `` The Scarlet Letter,'' by <PERSON> Nathaniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawthorne </PERSON>, `` Of Mice and Men,'' by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinbeck </PERSON>, <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>'s `` Hamlet,'' `` The Great Gatsby,'' by <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>, and `` Lord of the Flies,'' by <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Golding </PERSON>. The most frequently assigned books by minority authors are <PERSON> Lorrainne </PERSON> <PERSON> Hansberry </PERSON>'s `` A Raisin in the Sun,'' required in 19 percent of schools, and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s `` Black Boy,'' required by 7 percent, the survey found. <PERSON> Applebee </PERSON> added, however, that commonly used high school literature anthologies frequently include works by minority and female authors. The survey appeared to answer conservative critics who have lately accused schools of watering down curricula and retreating from the classics. Such charges gained currency in the recent best-sellers `` The Closing of the American Mind'' by <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON>, and `` Cultural Literacy,'' by E.D. <PERSON> Hirsch </PERSON>. The study also showed, surprisingly, that public, private and <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> high schools are assigning nearly identical books, said <PERSON> Applebee </PERSON>. At the 80 <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> schools surveyed, the top-10 list included the same books as public schools, but in different order. `` Huckleberry Finn'' ranked first, followed by `` The Scarlet Letter'' and `` Macbeth.'' `` Macbeth'' topped the list at 86 private schools surveyed. Unlike public and <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> schools, that top-10 list included <PERSON> Homer </PERSON>'s epic poem, `` The Odyssey,'' but omitted `` Of Mice and Men.'' The report replicated a similar survey 25 years ago by the <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Testing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON> dominated the list, as he does now. `` Romeo and <PERSON> Juliet </PERSON>'' replaced `` Macbeth'' in first place, apparently boosted by the popularity of the film version. `` <PERSON> Silas </PERSON> <PERSON> Marner </PERSON>,'' by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Eliot </PERSON>, was the only book showing a dramatic change in popularity. The 19th century novel about an old miser who turns to a more human life through his love of a little girl ranked third 25 years ago, but dropped off the top-10 list in the latest survey. The survey had a margin of error of 3 points. The Center for the Learning and Teaching of Literature is a research center funded by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endowment </ORGANIZATION> for the Arts.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Copies of the report are available from the center for $ 7, payable to the <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> SUNY </ORGANIZATION>, 1400 <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> 12222.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RestaurateurRetiring     05-31 0498</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Restaurateur Retiring,0513</SECOND>
<HEAD>Duke of (</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto CX1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By F.N. D'ALESSIO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a city where pork bellies have made commodity traders rich, it took a European, Chef <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Szathmary </PERSON>, to master the art of turning goose livers into gold. After 26 years, <LOCATION> Chef </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> next month is closing his <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Side </ORGANIZATION> restaurant called the Bakery. `` I grossed more than $ 1,300,000 a year for 26 years, and that's only five dinners a week _ no lunch, no bar and no ` early birds,''' <PERSON> Szathmary </PERSON> said `` Some restaurants give a discount for diners who arrive before 5 p.m., but I never did that because my meat supplier could n't guarantee quality that early. The income estimate is even more remarkable in that the Bakery has never seated more than 170 people at one time, and all of its five-course dinners had a fixed price: from $ 5 in 1962 to $ 25 this year. When <PERSON> Szathmary </PERSON> opened the Bakery, it was one of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s first restaurants outside of the downtown area to feature classic French cuisine. Resembling an unpretentious European inn, it also was one of the first where the food got top billing over the decor. It was also a place to sit down and listen to <PERSON> Szathmary </PERSON> philosophize about food. Every night he was in town, he visited each table, talking with patrons as he doled out his fresh country pate. `` We have every day fresh flowers, and sometimes the silver matches, but the important thing is the food on the plate,'' he said. And the food on the plate often is beef <LOCATION> Wellington </LOCATION>. It may be a haute cuisine cliche now, but <PERSON> Szathmary </PERSON> made his first hit by smearing beef with goose liver pate and baking it in a pastry shell. `` The food writers joke about beef <LOCATION> Wellington </LOCATION> now, but they all raved about it once, and I know 50 percent of our sales after 26 years is still beef <LOCATION> Wellington </LOCATION>.'' Other popular items at the Bakery have included pork loin stuffed with Hungarian sausage and roast duck served with cherry sauce. On his retirement at age 70, <PERSON> Szathmary </PERSON> is giving his 24,000-volume cookbook library to the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION>. Other items in the collection will go to <ORGANIZATION> Johnson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Wales </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION> `` Some of my cookbooks go back to the late 1400s and they may be important in teaching the history of food,'' he said. Some of his more modern works, though, were written by <PERSON> Szathmary </PERSON> himself, who is the author of `` The Chef's Secret Cookbook,'' `` American Gastronomy,'' `` The Chef's New Secret Cookbook,'' `` The Bakery Restaurant Cookbook'' and the 15-volume `` Cookery Americana.'' A native of <LOCATION> Transylvania </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Szathmary </PERSON> came to this country in 1951, and spent 11 years in food research before becoming a restaurateur. `` I could not do it now,'' he said. `` The restaurant business has changed too much. ... `` One thing I am proud of, though,'' he added. `` I never served one kiwi fruit.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-HouseLeadership 8thLd-Writethru a0410 05-31 1148</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-House Leadership, 8th Ld-Writethru, a0410,1100</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wright Not Saying Yet If He'll Resign; Colleagues Assume He Will</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS graf 5 to restore first reference to The Washington Post</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> declared Tuesday, `` I think I know what I should do,'' but did n't say whether that meant he'd resign over ethics charges. Colleagues assumed he would quit and were even beginning to push. Meanwhile, sources confirmed Tuesday night that the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> is conducting a preliminary inquiry into allegations of payroll padding on the staff of Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> Democrat who is seeking a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leadership post. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, who is seeking the majority whip position in anticipation of the expected resignation of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, confirmed earlier in the day that he had been approached by two Philadelphia-based <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents on Monday. But <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> denounced as an `` outrageous lie'' a televised report that he was under criminal investigation. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> quoted unidentified sources as saying the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> was launching a preliminary criminal investigation of <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> sources have previously said the department was monitoring ethics proceedings against <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and had not decided whether to look into his financial dealings. The <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> also quoted a source as saying <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> planned to announce his resignation either Wednesday or Thursday, but delay its effective date so the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee could rule on whether he accepted gifts from a business partner with a direct interest in legislation. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, after returning from a weekend getaway in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Blue </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>, told reporters, `` I do n't have a statement right now I expect to have one before the week's out.'' `` I think I know what I believe to be in my best interests and the interests of the institution,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> told reporters as he returned to the Capitol. `` I want to be fair to myself, my family, my reputation, and I want to be fair to this institution that I've served for 34 years. While the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Democrat held his cards close, fellow Democrats were openly angling for leadership posts in what they expected to be a major shakeup in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> hierarchy. A handful of senior lawmakers were pushing for the No. 2 and No. 3 jobs of majority leader and majority whip. That assumes, as most in th House do, that <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> will soon resign and the current majority leader, Rep. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, will be elevated to the speakership. The current whip, Rep. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, had been expected to fight for the No. 2 job, but he said Friday he would resign in the face of separate ethics questions about a bond investment he made. He said a congressional investigation of that issue could harm the party. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> said he had been told by <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents that he was neither a target nor a subject of a criminal investigation. But government sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, confirmed a CBS News report that the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> was conducting a preliminary inquiry into allegations regarding personnel and expenditures in the congressman's office. One source said there were allegations of a no-show employee being kept on <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>'s payroll. The source stressed, however, that the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s inquiry was at this point preliminary and agents did not know whether it would lead to a full-scale criminal investigation. Though <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> denied that he was a target or subject, under the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s definition of a preliminary inquiry, no one is a subject or target of such a probe. Some Democrats were making clear they were running out of patience, and one lawmaker pointedly referred to <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>'s announcement as an example for <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> to follow in deciding what to do about the ethics committee's allegations of financial impropriety `` He has to take a hard look at how <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> conducted himself,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Slattery </PERSON>, D-Kan., calling the Californian's gesture `` courageous and selfless. `` It is in the best interests of the institution and the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> to get this mess behind us,'' <PERSON> Slattery </PERSON> said. `` Regrettably, that involves the resignation of the speaker.'' Last week, sources close to <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said he had all but reached a decision to resign his leadership post and was leaving for the weekend to draft a statement, defending himself, that could be delivered along with the announcement of his resignation as early as Wednesday. But they also cautioned that <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> was torn between such a move and fighting the ethics charges to some legal conclusion. Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, said Tuesday, `` I hear that he's going to resign. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, who is a close ally of the speaker but said he had not talked to him this week, added, `` My personal opinion is that he'll do it Wednesday or Thursday.'' One source close to <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said he did not expect an announcement until at least Thursday. Another source said the death Tuesday of Rep. <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., could cause <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> to delay as <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members would be involved with attending services for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' oldest member <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> alluded to his legal fight and to a motion to dismiss the most serious charges against him, telling reporters, `` I'm convinced our motions are legally well grounded. The ethics committee is due to take up the motion to dismiss charges at a meeting on Thursday, and it was seen as likely to reject the defense effort. Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, the senior Republican on the ethics committee, said in answer to a question that the panel also might expand its action to other ethics allegations against <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, a reference to <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s investment in a gas well drilling venture and a deal involving a nursing home company. `` It's possible we could vote for a preliminary inquiry on those two issues,'' <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> said, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> has been formally charged with 69 instances of violating House rules, including charges he circumvented limits on outside income through bulk sales of a book he wrote and charges he improperly accepted $ 145,000 in gifts from a <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, businessman with a direct interest in legislation. Should <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> be promoted into <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s job, Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Mo </LOCATION>., remains the favorite to succeed him, although Rep. <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>, D-Ga., also has expressed interest in the The most ferocious contest is expected for <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>'s whip post. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, Reps. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, D-Mich., and <PERSON> Beryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>., are running, and Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>., also has been mentioned as <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, already running full-speed, said Tuesday he's telling colleagues his middle-class constituency makes him the best candidate. The suburban <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrat </ORGANIZATION> claimed 60 solid commitments of support, slightly less than half the 130 he said he needed to win. <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON> said the demographics of his district _ a blue-collar industrial area seasoned with middle-level managers _ `` is contrasted, of course, to the constituencies on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>, Mr. <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, and the inner-city constituency of Mr. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0043EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CollegeDesegregation     05-31 0668</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-College Desegregation,0690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Official Issues Final Recommendations in Louisiana Desegregation
Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN SAYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BATON ROUGE, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A special official appointed to draft an integration plan for <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s higher education system recommended Tuesday that no universities be closed or merged and that they be governed by a powerful unified board. The final recommendation by <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Verkuil </PERSON>, who was appointed by a three-judge federal panel, contained few changes compared to his preliminary proposal April 18, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, an attorney with Gov. <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>'s administration. `` I do n't think this is a cosmetic plan,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said at a news briefing Tuesday night. `` I think you will look on the landscape of higher education in five years and it will not be the same. The changes will be fundamental _ quality and desegregation.'' The court will have the final say on the plan. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said he did not know if the judges would hear further comment from the parties in the case _ including the predominantly black <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> System </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Grambling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s alumni association _ before deciding whether to approve it. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>, who had pushed for a single board with authority to implement desegregation plans, was pleased by <PERSON> Verkuil </PERSON>'s recommendation. `` The single board is the linchpin of this whole thing,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said. State Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, an attorney for the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> System </ORGANIZATION>, said he had not seen the recommendation and declined to comment immediately. Other parties were not available for immediate comment. <PERSON> Verkuil </PERSON> was appointed to draw up a new plan after the court ruled last year that a 1981 desegregation agreement between the state and the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> had failed. The plan called primarily for spending millions of dollars to upgrade faculty, programs and facilities at Southern and <LOCATION> Grambling </LOCATION>. The dispute began 15 years ago when the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> filed a lawsuit against the state accusing it of operating a dual system of higher education for blacks and whites. Under the plan recommended Tuesday by <PERSON> Verkuil </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> William </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>: _ The single governing board would consist of 17 members, including at least seven blacks. <PERSON> Verkuil </PERSON> said the board should show a geographic balance, represent all schools and include a student. Board members would be appointed by the governor and confirmed by the state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. Members would not have to come from existing boards. Black leaders had said a unified board would be insensitive to the needs of historically black <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Grambling </LOCATION>. _ All current university systems would be abolished in favor of one system under the unified board. A new president for higher education would be selected and an interim president would be appointed during the search. _ <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> would be the state's flagship institution with the greatest number of graduate programs and the toughest admission standards. Currently, all <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> colleges have an open-admissions policy. _ A second tier of schools _ <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tech </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> at </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> _ would also offer graduate programs, but fewer than LSU. Those schools would have less stringent admissions standards. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said <PERSON> Verkuil </PERSON>'s recommendation would allow the new board to add other schools to the second tier. Other four-year colleges would have still less restrictive admissions and limited graduate degree programs. _ Two-year community colleges would offer open admissions and be responsible for most remedial education. _ The state must continue to spend money to enhance Southern and <LOCATION> Grambling </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Verkuil </PERSON> did not recommend a dollar amount. Previous agreements between <LOCATION> Grambling </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tech </ORGANIZATION> to end program duplication should be carried out, while the <ORGANIZATION> LSU </ORGANIZATION> and Southern law schools in <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION> should agree to let students at one school take courses at the other, <PERSON> Verkuil </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said <PERSON> Verkuil </PERSON> recognized the state's financial difficulties, including a projected deficit of more than $ 700 million for the next fiscal year and possible cuts to higher education.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BroadwaySeason     05-31 0445</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Broadway Season,0455</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Record for Broadway</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL KUCHWARA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Drama Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Higher ticket prices, strong long-running musicals, several acclaimed new plays helped Broadway end its season with a record box-office take. Theaters took in $ 262 million, up 4 percent over the 1988-89 season's total of $ 253 million, according to figures released Tuesday. The League of American Theaters and Producers also said attendance was 8 million, off slightly from last season's record 8.1 million but still higher than the 7 million of two years ago. `` It was a good season. It had strong box-office dollars and solid attendance,'' said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Wachtel </PERSON>, the league's director of research. `` There were fewer musicals but there were more plays. Over the last four years, it was one of the best seasons, attendance-wise.'' Much of the box-office strength came from long-running musicals particularly `` The Phantom of the Opera'' and `` Les Miserables,'' each grossing more than $ 500,000 a week, and other veteran hits like `` Cats'' and `` Me and My Girl.'' The only new musical to demonstrate much box-office muscle is `` <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Robbins </PERSON>' Broadway,'' which has been running at slightly under capacity since it opened in January. The compilation of dance numbers from some of the choreographer's biggest hits has been grossing about $ 520,000 a week. It also has a top ticket price of $ 55. The average ticket price rose from $ 31.10 to $ 33.90, up 6 percent from last year, the league said. Much of the rise, <PERSON> Wachtel </PERSON> said, was because theatergoers were paying full price for tickets to hot shows like `` Phantom'' and `` Les Miserables,'' which are not available at half-price discount. Only seven musicals _ including a revival of `` Ai n't Misbehavin''' _ opened on Broadway during the 1988-89 season, compared with 15 the previous year They included such flops as `` Legs Diamond,'' `` Chu Chem'' and `` Welcome to the Club,'' as well as such still-running shows as `` Black and Blue'' and `` Starmites.'' `` For a variety of reasons, it's becoming increasingly difficult to mount a large musical,'' <PERSON> Wachtel </PERSON> said. `` But I do look to the fact that there were two seasons fairly recently when there was as many as 20 musicals. You have to be optimistic to be in this business and we are.'' Twenty-one plays, including nine revivals, opened on Broadway during the 1988-89 season. Among the biggest successes were <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'s farce, `` Rumors,'' and <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wasserstein </PERSON>'s `` The Heidi Chronicles,'' which is the favorite to win the best play <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> on June 4. Box-office receipts also climbed for touring productions in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, jumping to a record $ 255 million. It was a 14 percent increase from the previous season's $ 223 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Revolution     05-31 0595</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Revolution,0612</SECOND>
<HEAD>Authorities Use Memories of Cultural Revolution to Fight Students
^Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN BIERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In their gloves-off campaign to end the pro-democracy movement, authorities are tapping the painful memories of the chaotic Cultural Revolution to turn public opinion against the students. But students reject any comparison of their campaign with the ultra-leftist 1966-76 movement, during which the nation was plunged into turmoil by young Red Guards unleashed by <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse-tung </PERSON> in a power struggle. Conservative leaders including Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> and senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> in recent days have increased pressure on students to stop their 6-week-old protests. The <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> newspaper, the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION>, on Tuesday published a letter from seven unidentified intellectuals who chillingly warned of a new Cultural Revolution if the protests did not cease. `` Our middle-aged generation who walked away from the Cultural Revolution purgatory still can painfully and clearly remember the lawlessness and turmoil of those 10 years,'' they wrote. `` The national economy was on the verge of ruin ... there was no peace in the party, the country or anywhere.'' `` We ask all comrades who in those 10 years of catastrophic terror lost loved ones, wasted their youth and suffered hardship to call on their sense of responsibility to history and society,'' the letter said. `` Warn your sons and loved ones not to allow a repeat of this tragedy of history.'' Chinese in their 30s and older have vivid memories of communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s darkest decade, when <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> mobilized millions of youth to save his revolution from entrenched bureaucrats. His Red Guards ruled the streets for two years before the army was called in to restore order. Gangs of youths tore down temples and churches, burned books, seized government ministries, ransacked homes and persecuted intellectuals. Estimates of deaths from political turmoil during the decade are as high as 1 million. Millions more were persecuted and their lives destroyed. Students who have joined this spring's protests are quick to point that their approach is different. This year's demonstrations have been peaceful. Students have gone out of their way to ensure their marches and sit-ins are orderly. <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s citizens have reacted not with fear but with heartfelt support, donating money and food to the protesting students. `` We have been calm and orderly,'' said a 22-year-old senior from <ORGANIZATION> Nanjing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Polytechnic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. `` If there's turmoil, you can say it's created by the government.'' The government cracked down on the protests by declaring martial law on May 20, but leadership divisions over how to deal with the students created a bitter power struggle. The conservatives appear to have toppled moderate <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziyang </PERSON>, who reportedly is under house arrest. A diplomatic source says party documents accuse <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> of helping incite demonstrations and of using the student movement in a bid to seize power. The student protesters reject comparison to the Red Guards, who were called to the streets by <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> as his followers. `` I think that up to now, our student movement has not been exploited by anyone,'' said a senior from <ORGANIZATION> Puyang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Anhui </LOCATION> province. He and other students argue their movement is of the masses, not of a government faction. Although all Chinese share horrific memories of the Cultural Revolution, not all share the concern that history is poised to repeat itself. `` This time the people want democracy,'' said a 41-year-old mathematics professor from <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Normal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> who was in <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> to support the students. `` A second Cultural Revolution ca n't come. I am not afraid.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PipelineExplosion     05-31 0351</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pipeline Explosion,0361</SECOND>
<HEAD>City Loses Bid to Block Resumption of Pipeline Operation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN BERNARDINO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge Tuesday rejected a request by city officials that he prohibit a pipeline company from resuming operation of a fuel line that blew up in a deadly fireball last week. City Attorney <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Penman </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bernardino </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Kayashima </PERSON>'s decision had been expected. <PERSON> Penman </PERSON> attorney has unsuccessfully sought to block the <ORGANIZATION> Calnev </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pipe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> from resuming pipeline operations or to persuade <PERSON> Calnev </PERSON> executives to relocate the 14-inch diameter fuel line away from city residents. The devastating explosion, fueled by unleaded gasoline being pumped through the line, killed two people and injured dozens more last Thursday. A federal investigation into the cause has focused on the possibility that the pipe was damaged by the wreck of a <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> freight train, which derailed in the same area May 12. Calnev attorney <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Diamond </PERSON> said the federal government, not local government, has sole authority to regulate interstate commerce, including products shipped by pipeline. <PERSON> Calnev </PERSON> has moved aggressively to establish federal jurisdiction in the case. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Manning </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, another Calnev attorney, told <PERSON> Kayashima </PERSON> that the fuel company had every intention of abiding by regulations set by the federal Office of Pipeline Safety. The company will not open the pipeline without OPS approval, <PERSON> Manning </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Penman </PERSON> complained, `` We're having a very difficult time trying to get Calnev to comply with federal laws and to get OPS to comply with federal laws.'' But in issuing his decision, the judge said the 1979 Hazardous Pipeline Safety Act of 1979 gives the Office of Pipeline Safety authority to determine pipeline safety. In a related development in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Calnev </PERSON> sought a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> order that would effectively force the city to allow the company to reopen the pipeline in accordance with federal regulations. Over the weekend, <PERSON> Calnev </PERSON> obtained a similar federal order prohibiting city officials from interfering with the repair and replacement of the damaged 14-inch diameter pipeline. <PERSON> Penman </PERSON> vowed to continue the fight, but conceded the city faces an uphill battle.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BlahBlah Bjt   05-31 0648</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Blah Blah, Bjt,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Washington Today: Bush On The Upbeat</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WALTER R. MEARS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Granted, it was a less-than-elegant paraphrase of the solemn pronouncement of the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. Sixteen heads of state in summit conference assembled, and President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> summarizes a line of their communique as `` blah, blah.'' But no offense intended. He was just skipping over words, hurrying to get to the heavy stuff. And nobody cared more about the heavy stuff than <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. It gave <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, by his account, a double hit. He did keep reminding himself, out loud, that this was good for the alliance, not only the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Or <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, president thereof. After weeks of taking flak while Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> took bows for his arms-control offensive, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had his own, dramatic proposal in place, with the blessings of the <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> summit. His euphoria was showing. At a <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> news conference, the president was asked why his arms offer did n't seek to eliminate nuclear weapons. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said repeatedly that the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> proposes to reduce nuclear weaponry, not go to zero. `` Well,'' he said, `` the communique addresses itself to where nuclear forces are concerned'' _ and stopped reading the text. `` Blah, blah,'' he abbreviated. `` Land, sea, air-based systems, including ground-based missiles _ in the present circumstances as far as can be foreseen, they'll be needed in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>.'' And when will the alliance get rolling with a specific negotiating offer on the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plan? The president lapsed into NATO-speak: `` <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> is tasked to be back on September 7th, with our internals to be farther along. `` ... We all remember September 7th, do n't we?'' he asked, and laughed. That's the day the campaigning <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> pronounced to be Pearl Harbor Day, three months ahead of the real one on December 7. He also laughed when asked whether his attitude toward the critics is now `` I told you so.'' `` Not really,'' he said. `` Not really. No, listen, I'm not going to get into that game with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, or anyone else.'' But it was n't the only game in town, <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was so enthusiastic he even waived his rule against talking to reporters at photo-taking sessions, briefly, on Tuesday. `` We'll make an exception ... just to say, yes, I'm very pleased ... It was a united alliance; plenty of credit for everybody there.'' That was at the headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, where <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s exit was briefly delayed when he tried to make his way through the middle of a brown curtain that had no opening in it. He flailed briefly, then went around end. At the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>, he rated the summit `` marvelous.'' At the Chancellery in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>, he said it had been good for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, good for <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>, good for <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, and could be good for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, too. Was the president feeling up? `` Have you ever seen him down?'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as they flew to <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>. `` You are a friend among friends,'' West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> told the president in welcome. He'd been in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>, too, and got back shortly before the ceremony. Never mind the weeks of friction between <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> over German demands for quick negotiations seeking cutbacks in short-range nuclear missiles. `` I told him that I do n't believe German-American relations have ever been better,'' the president said. The short-range missile compromise may yet come back to haunt <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> politically, although he said Tuesday the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> visit would be a boost in the 1990 West German elections. Maybe <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s upbeat mood about the <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> summit was catching. `` There are only winners,'' said <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, who, if he was one, certainly did n't win much.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890531-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-89 0153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Soviet-Military Bjt   05-31 0770</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Soviet-Military, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Experts Say Soviets Still Understate Military Spending</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
