<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 2344EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-QuakeAnniversary     12-04 1060</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quake Anniversary,1096</SECOND>
<HEAD>One Year After Quake, Leninakan Mired in Mud and Memories</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANN IMSE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LENINAKAN, U.S.S.R. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A year after an earthquake smashed northwestern <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> into rubble, the city of <LOCATION> Leninakan </LOCATION> is a shantytown of mud and memories. The Garapetyans do laundry by boiling their clothes in a bucket on a tiny wood stove. The stove also heats a makeshift cabin they built from remains of their former apartment building next door. Far above, rain lashes the wallpaper of their old living room on the fourth floor, which was exposed when the side of the building sheared off. `` We're afraid of living in a large building again,'' <PERSON> Meruzhan </PERSON> <PERSON> Garapetyan </PERSON> said. Popular songs speak of the disaster of Dec. 7, 1988, when an earthquake measuring 6.9 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale killed at least 25,000 people and destroyed the homes of 500,000 more. `` Oh earthquake, what have you done?'' one asks. `` Why did you leave so many parents without their children? ... You covered them with stones and dirt and left their parents in tears.'' The Armenian relief agency Search says 20,000 people still are missing, 2,000 of them children. Daily life is slogging through mud, relying on relatives and wondering when normality will return. A quake of 7.1 magnitude in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> area on Oct. 17 killed only 66 people. Damage was estimated at $ 7 billion, but much of the destruction was cleared and service restored within weeks. In <LOCATION> Leninakan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>'s second-largest city, <PERSON> Vartan </PERSON> <PERSON> Oganisyan </PERSON> and his family of five live in a shack made from bits of sheet metal, wood scraps, tar paper and salvaged window frames. Other families crowd into half-shattered buildings, construction huts, army tents, round Mongolian yurts, abandoned railway cars and even gasoline tanks fitted with doors and windows. A few open cooking fires can be seen in the twilight. Electrical power is intermittent as <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> enters the bitter Soviet winter. Children bundle up for classes in temporary, unheated buildings. They wake up crying at night and run from classrooms in fright at the slightest noise. After school they play `` earthquake,'' recreating the disaster in the muddy streets. Hundreds of people go to the huge city cemetery after work. Many graves are marked only by the flowers relatives leave. <PERSON> Sofik </PERSON> <PERSON> Torunyan </PERSON>, who lost both children, was there on what would have been her daughter's 20th birthday, with a cake fashioned from carnations. `` Oh, my young daughter! Oh, my love!'' she wailed, holding onto a friend. `` Why did n't I die, too, so I would not have to live without you?'' People struggle on, helping each other. Hospitality and pride remain. A dozen families share the only bathroom on their block that still works. A boy paints the window frame in his family's shack. Visitors are offered coffee and sweets, but often there is no electricity to boil water. <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Tumanyan </PERSON>, who lives in the ground floor of a severely cracked five-story building, insists that `` we're making great progress.'' She concentrates on the vast stretches cleared of broken concrete and twisted metal, not the rubble remaining. The town of <LOCATION> Spitak </LOCATION> was leveled. Kirovakan and 300 villages were shattered. In <LOCATION> Leninakan </LOCATION>, which had 235,000 residents, the quake destroyed 99 nine-story apartment buildings, 10 schools and every factory, officials said. Reconstruction has lagged badly. <PERSON> Nikolai </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryzhkov </PERSON>, the Soviet premier, said in November that the crash program to rebuild in two years already was a year behind schedule, meaning virtually nothing had been accomplished. Residents blame disorganization, central planning's failure to supply enough building materials and a two-month blockade of <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> by ethnic enemies in neighboring <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION>. Many foreigners building schools and hospitals went home because supply shipments were held up on rail lines in <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION>. By early November, only three new buildings had been completed, all by the army for the army. <PERSON> Karlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ambartsumyan </PERSON>, chairman of the city <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> committee, still hopes to move 4,000 families into a vast new suburb before year's end, but even that would be only one-fifth as many as planned. For now, <PERSON> Ambartsumyan </PERSON> is concentrating on getting the remaining homeless among the 190,000 people now living in <LOCATION> Leninakan </LOCATION> into construction huts and other temporary housing, and getting heat for them before winter. <PERSON> Svetlana </PERSON> <PERSON> Asaturyan </PERSON> lives in one such hut, generously called a `` little house'' in Russian but in reality a two-room insulated packing crate. She and her family of five must haul water from a block away, use nearby bushes as a toilet and travel to a relative's place for showers. Her washing flaps over a sea of mud. Mrs. <PERSON> Asaturyan </PERSON> is grateful, however, because they used to be in the remains of the towel factory where she once worked, and where 30 of her co-workers were killed. Her `` little house,'' like thousands of others, showed up without a door, window glass, heater, wiring or furniture. It was vandalized en route, apparently by <PERSON> Azerbaijanis </PERSON>, whom the Armenians accuse of stealing or destroying relief supplies. When asked about the Soviet leadership's promise to rebuild in two years, Mrs. <PERSON> Asaturyan </PERSON> said: `` I'll be glad if I get a home within five years.'' About 20,000 of the homeless are scheduled to receive apartments in the new suburb as sections are completed over 18 months. A forest of 129 cranes towers over the site, and buildings faced with local salmon-colored stone gleam in the sun. Because nine-story apartment blocks shoddily built of pre-formed concrete panels collapsed in the quake, the new buildings are made by assembling vault-like precast rooms, foreman <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> Pogosov </PERSON> said. None is more than four stories high. In May, a commission of the ruling Politburo blamed most of the deaths on shoddy construction and gave its findings to prosecutors. No charges have been filed, said <PERSON> Haik </PERSON> <PERSON> Minasyan </PERSON>, an Armenian government spokesman. Only a few projects are under way in the city itself. On the central square, a statue of <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON> looks over a scene of devastation: a ruined school, department store, government building, post office, shops and a sock factory. Cafes and movie theaters are gone. So are most food stores, and shopping sometimes amounts to picking over piles of cabbages and potatoes at what remains of the bus station. <PERSON> Ambartsumyan </PERSON> said experts had ruled out reconstruction on half the original city lots because the ground is too unstable.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 2342EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Philippines 6thLd-Writethru a0779 12-04 1083</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0779,1113</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fighting Intensifies in Manila Area Where Foreigners Are Trapped</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS lede to CORRECT that foreigners trapped for four days,
not five. To UPDATE with heavy firing delaying evacuation, SUB 23rd graf,
`But shortly ... was made.' Picks up 24th, `U.S. Embassy ...' ^LaserPhotos
MLA1,2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN GUERRERO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fighting intensified Tuesday between rebels and loyal forces in the <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION> <LOCATION> financial </LOCATION> <LOCATION> district </LOCATION>, where about 2,000 foreigners, including more than 200 Americans, have been trapped in hotels for four days. Efforts to evacuate foreigners held by the rebels appeared to have stalled early Tuesday. A 60mm mortar round slammed into a squatter settlement near the <ORGANIZATION> Makati </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> about 6 a.m. -LRB- 5 p.m. EST Monday -RRB-. Ten people were taken to the hospital, including a 6-year-old girl who died. Two bombs exploded in the capital late Monday, wounding two people. It was unclear if they were related to the coup attempt, which began Friday and has killed at least 71 people and wounded more than 500. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> recommended Tuesday morning that Americans living in <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION> remain in their homes but avoid upper floors, lest they become targets for snipers. At least three people were killed in <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION> on Monday and 15, including one American, were wounded by sniper fire and shells. Troops loyal to the government of President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, backed by three armored personnel carriers, began moving under cover of fire toward the hotel district where the foreigners are. `` Are we going to win?'' a colonel asked his men at the end of a briefing. `` Yes, sir!'' they shouted. He told his men not to fire unless they had a rebel in their sights. The Japanese Embassy recommended that Japanese citizens living in parts of the posh <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION> district not under rebel control leave for safer areas of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. It estimated 500 Japanese remained in <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION>, including about 300 trapped in the hotels. A statement telephoned to news organizations from a rebel spokesman, Capt. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Yen </PERSON>, said the insurgents would release the foreigners to dispel suspicions they were being held hostage. The statement said the foreigners would be free to leave the hotels at 10 a.m. Tuesday and would be taken to <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>'s airport aboard shuttle buses. Yen said the move did not indicate the rebels were about to end their bid to oust Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>. `` That's the farthest thing that we could do,'' he said. `` We pledged our lives to this cause. We will hold the line to the last drop of our blood.'' About 400 mutineers from the elite <ORGANIZATION> Scout </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rangers </ORGANIZATION> were holding 22 buildings in the <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION> <LOCATION> district </LOCATION>, where many foreign embassies and residences of foreign diplomats and businessmen lie. About 400 rebels continued to occupy <LOCATION> Mactan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Base </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Cebu </LOCATION>, 350 miles south of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. Their leader refused to surrender and threatened to blow up the base's planes. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> called Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> on arriving back in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> from the <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> superpower summit and following a visit with <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> allies in <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION> to express concern for the lives of Americans in the <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION> hotels. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> quoted <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as telling Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>: `` ` I understand some Americans are in the hotels... Can we get those people out? I'm very concerned about their lives and their safety.''' `` She assured him they were doing everything possible to protect <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> lives,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. `` Then the president ended the conversation by saying, ` I appreciate your concern for the civilians. We're proud of you for standing up with great courage. We want to see you succeed.''' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> provided fresh military supplies to the Aquino government and promised $ 25,000 in help for civilian hospitals, said <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON>. The Japanese are planning to send three tons of emergency aid, including food, water and medicine to its embassy, said a foreign ministry official in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. Filipino Tourism Undersecretary <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Alunan </PERSON> prepared about 20 buses to go into the battle zone and evacuate tourists to the airport. <PERSON> Alunan </PERSON> broadcast a statement over <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> radio stations telling the rebels the routes the buses would take and that each would carry a white flag. As the first buses prepared to enter the area, heavy firing broke out. Officials stopped the buses in order to contact rebel leaders by telephone to make sure the deal was still on. Officials planned first to evacuate guests from the Intercontinental Hotel and if the operation was successful to clear out other buildings. <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Huchel </PERSON> said 215 Americans were believed in three hotels in <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION>. Hospital sources identified the American wounded Monday as <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Weissburg </PERSON>. They said he was hit in the arm by glass when a bullet shattered the window of his room at the Peninsula Hotel. They did not know his hometown. The <ORGANIZATION> Manila </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chronicle </ORGANIZATION> quoted military reports as saying nine <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> servicemen from <LOCATION> Clark </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Base </LOCATION>, 50 miles north of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, were among the trapped Americans. Loyal forces said the rebels were contained in 22 buildings in <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION>. Snipers exchanged fire through the night. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Julich </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> businesswoman trapped in the Intercontinental Hotel, was contacted by telephone and said, `` Literally, we're in the middle. -LRB- We're -RRB- now low on food. There are babies in the building, and there is no baby food, and the mothers are hysterical.'' The city's international airport reopened Monday but domestic air service was indefinitely postponed. Schools were closed but government employees were ordered to return to work except in the <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION> area. Officials reported shortages of food and fuel. An explosion Monday rocked the compound of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, the equivalent of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION>. There were no injuries. A second bomb went off in the <LOCATION> Ermita </LOCATION> entertainment district, damaging an unoccupied minibus and shattering windows. Two women were injured by flying glass. Monday morning, the estimated 390 rebel holdouts in <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION> _ members of the army's <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scout </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ranger </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regiment </ORGANIZATION> _ refused appeals to surrender and fired at soldiers and civilians who approached their strongholds. The mutinous soldiers claim Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, swept to power in a 1986 military-civilian uprising that toppled President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, has failed to deal effectively with the country's Communist insurgency and economic problems. This is the sixth and most serious attempt to overthrow her. One of the coup leaders is <PERSON> Gregorio </PERSON> `` Gringo'' <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON>, a cashiered lieutenant colonel who once supported Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> but later led an August 1987 attempt to overthrow her. He remained at large.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 2346EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Quake-Missing     12-04 0512</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quake-Missing,0528</SECOND>
<HEAD>Family Still Searches for Boy Lost in Last Year's Quake</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Quake Anniversary</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANN IMSE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LENINAKAN, U.S.S.R. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 His family has n't seen <PERSON> Araik </PERSON> <PERSON> Sukasyan </PERSON> since the earthquake destroyed his school a year ago, but they speak of him celebrating his 13th birthday soon and hope a <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> psychic can tell them where. `` We wait to find him alive,'' said his mother, <PERSON> Galine </PERSON>, weeping as she pulled out <PERSON> Araik </PERSON>'s school portrait. She hopes publicity will bring word from someone who has taken him in, if that happened. The fourth grader vanished in the rubble of School No. 9 along with more than 500 other people when the earthquake hit <LOCATION> Leninakan </LOCATION> during school hours Dec. 7, 1988. Authorities say it killed 25,000 people, but the Armenian relief agency Search says 20,000 more still are missing, including 2,000 children. `` They are not counted on the list of the dead or on the list of those evacuated,'' said <PERSON> Ashot </PERSON> <PERSON> Georgyan </PERSON>, director of the Search office in <LOCATION> Yerevan </LOCATION>, capital of <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>. He said he had no way of knowing how many of the 20,000 were dead and how many were just separated from their families. `` We are now continuing the search for children, particularly orphans, who were sent in groups to various points in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and are still there in sanatoriums and resorts,'' <PERSON> Georgyan </PERSON> said. Many parents, like the Sukasyans, believe officials may have lost track of some evacuees. <PERSON> Larissa </PERSON> <PERSON> Vagashakovna </PERSON>, head of the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> office of Search, said she had asked in vain for state television to show pictures of the missing children. `` It's impossible to forget the faces of these parents,'' she said. `` They have n't found the corpse and they have n't found the child. Where have they disappeared to?'' <PERSON> Araik </PERSON>'s sister, <PERSON> Narina </PERSON>, also was in School No. 9 when it crumpled. She escaped, and when her mother came running from home, <PERSON> Narina </PERSON> cried: `` Momma, I am alive, but I ca n't find my brother!'' For a month after the earthquake, the <PERSON> Sukasyan </PERSON> family watched workers claw through the concrete and dust that had been School No. 9. Searchers found the bodies, or identifiable parts of bodies, of 420 students and 26 teachers. There was no sign of 100 others, including <PERSON> Araik </PERSON>. `` There were people where they found only one leg, and identified the shoe or the skirt, and they buried that,'' said <PERSON> Lida </PERSON> <PERSON> Grigoryan </PERSON>, a teacher at another school and a friend of the family. The Sukasyans searched hospitals, opened every one of thousands of coffins at the cemetery and telephoned relief agencies in <LOCATION> Yerevan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. They found no sign of their son and cling to the hope that someone took him away. `` In <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, there is a woman who can see where someone is by looking at his picture. We hope she can help,'' <PERSON> Araik </PERSON>'s mother said. Then she was worried again, because reports say the psychic's powers only work with an original photograph `` This is a copy,'' she said, staring at her son's young, serious face.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 2346EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LawSchoolToys     12-04 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Law School Toys,0433</SECOND>
<HEAD>Play Doh and Marbles Take Place Alongside Law Books</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOE McDONALD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 How do hard-working, mature <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION> law students relax after a hard day of studying for final exams? `` The favorite is Play-Doh,'' law library secretary <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said Monday. `` We go through a lot of Play-Doh. They say it's really relaxing. The colorful modeling clay is in the law library's toy room, an area stocked with marbles, puzzles, board games and Far Side cartoon books, as well as coffee and food. It began three years ago and re-opened Wednesday in the library's <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morgan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> room for the school's 2 -LCB- - week final examination period `` It's just really to relieve tension and stress,'' Ms. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said. `` It's a chance to do something besides study and hit the law books.'' Playing Battleship or marbles in the toy room was often the only relief for students who studied as much as 20 hours a day for final exams, said <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Holling </PERSON>, who graduated from the law school last year. `` After you study all day, there's just a point where you ca n't study any more and ca n't absorb any more,'' she said `` This sounds pretty childish, but we did those things.'' The toy room was the idea of law librarian <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitchett </PERSON>, who started similar toy rooms at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Tulane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, Ms. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said. `` She said to me the second year she was here, ` I think we should have a play room for the students,' and I said, ` Just what am I supposed to do?''' Ms. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said. `` She said we should get some puzzles and coloring books, and I said, ` Are you serious?''' Ms. <PERSON> Fitchett </PERSON> was out of town Monday and unavailable for comment. Ms. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said the library has n't heard any complaints about the toy room. But she said one problem can be how the Play-Doh is used. She said the colorful modeling clay was used after the <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bengals </ORGANIZATION>' victory over the <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Browns </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday to modify a statue of President <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Taft </PERSON>, a graduate of the school. `` I came into the library this morning and he had on a <ORGANIZATION> Bengals </ORGANIZATION>' helmet, and I said, ` Oh, no,''' she said Ms. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said the library plans to keep the toy room open only during test periods, despite students' pleas. `` They'd like us to have it all year long, but it's too much of a mess,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 2349EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NerdSociety     12-04 0626</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nerd Society,0642</SECOND>
<HEAD>Society for Nerds and Geeks Forms at Harvard</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEPHANIE SCHOROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's the laugh. That obnoxious giggle that ends in a full-fledged snort. That's the mark of true nerd. <PERSON> Jeremy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON> has it. Naturally. He is the founder, president and ideological spokesman for the newly formed <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nerds </ORGANIZATION> and Geeks _ or SONG _ at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. If `` Veritas'' -LRB- truth -RRB- is the motto of <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> and `` Vanitas'' is the motto of the <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lampoon </ORGANIZATION>, then the slogan of SONG is `` Veritas is more important than Vanitas,'' explained <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON>, 20, a junior majoring in math. `` The kind of people we're looking for are very interested in what they're studying. Not as worried about _ like _ what other people think about them,'' said <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON> who punctuates his sentences with `` like'' a lot. `` Truth is more important than to look good,'' he added. Everyone knows or has known a nerd or a geek. A nerd was that brainy math major in college, the one with the thick glasses, the perpetual pocket calculator and plaid shirt. The geek is the guy _ or gal _ who wore mismatched socks or strange color combinations and walked to the beat of a drummer no one else heard. Nerds, however, go on to invent amazing new machines and make millions on the patents. Geeks go on to found new companies and become the CEO featured on Fortune's cover for maverick style. Nerds and geeks always have the last laugh. Will nerds inherit the earth? No, but they might just save it, according to <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON>. The first step, he says, is to help take the stigma off students who live to study, not party. SONG, organized in mid-October by <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON>, aims to do that with meetings, speakers and other activities. `` Basically it's putting academics ahead of social life.'' With about 35 members, SONG meets weekly and fosters discussions on how to study better and improve academic standings. `` We talk about _ like _ why grades are important to us or how we see relationships, which may seem strange for nerds and geeks to talk about,'' said <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON>. And he laughed that nerdy laugh. Future plans for SONG include lectures, off-beat dances for those slightly out of step and a special `` procrastination hot line.'' This would involve a `` kind, caring and generous counselor'' to talk with students who simply ca n't get down to work. `` I think students procrastinate more than anyone else. It's amazing how much time I spend procrastinating,'' <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON> said A hot line could get students `` on the road to recovery. In 10 minutes they'd be sitting down and getting to work.'' <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON> had been thinking about organizing some kind of club since he entered <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>. `` Freshman year I found myself very isolated. For the first time in my life I could not concentrate on studies. No organization that would, like, help me concentrate on studies.'' So he thought up the name <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nerds </ORGANIZATION> and Geeks, registered it with the proper <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> authorities and began having meetings. Most members are math majors, but other disciplines are represented as well, such as Sanskrit. The club's graduate student adviser <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> Fridman </PERSON> has written a `` Nerd Manifesto'' about the dangers of anti-intellectualism. Yet the alumni adviser is the assistant coach of the <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> wrestling team, demonstrating that nerds and jocks are n't necessarily mutually exclusive. `` The role of women in SONG is n't any different from that of men. We are equal opportunity nerds,'' said freshman <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> <PERSON> Tulenko </PERSON>, an 18-year-old biochemistry major. There's a funny saying going around <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>, `` Blessed are the nerds and geeks for they will become trendsetters,'' <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON> said. And then he laughed like nerd.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ConfessionControversy     12-04 0667</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Confession Controversy,0686</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man at Center of Church-State Debate Pleads Guilty</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RAY FORMANEK Jr.</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BERKELEY SPRINGS, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A showdown between three Pentecostal ministers and a prosecutor over the confidentiality of a burglary suspect's confession in church ended when the man pleaded guilty to grand larceny. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Yost </PERSON>, who was to have gone on trial today, entered the plea Monday under an agreement reached at a hearing before <ORGANIZATION> Morgan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Steptoe </PERSON>. <PERSON> Yost </PERSON>, 35, had been charged with the more serious crime of breaking and entering. `` It's over with,'' said a jubilant Rev. <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Hiles </PERSON>. `` We do n't have to testify, nor do we have to refuse to testify.'' <PERSON> Yost </PERSON>'s hearing came after <PERSON> Steptoe </PERSON> refused for the second time to excuse Mrs. <PERSON> Hiles </PERSON>, 51; her husband, the Rev. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Hiles </PERSON>, the 58-year-old founder and pastor of the <ORGANIZATION> Word </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deliverance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>; and the Rev. <PERSON> Wilda </PERSON> <PERSON> Maconaughey </PERSON> from subpoenas issued by county Prosecutor <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> IV. <PERSON> Yost </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> carpenter who has been held at the Eastern Regional Jail in lieu of $ 15,000 bond since January, was sentenced to a year in the county jail, with credit for time served. `` I'm happy, the whole church is happy,'' <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> said in a telephone interview from jail. `` I did n't want to see the ministers go to jail. And I should be out in a month if everything goes right.'' Last December, a sobbing <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> interrupted a service at the church, confessing that he did n't try to stop the break-in at his uncle's building supply store. The ministers had said <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> wanted them to testify at <PERSON> Yost </PERSON>'s trial, and maintained authorities had crossed the boundary between God's work and their own <PERSON> Steptoe </PERSON> first refused to block the subpoenas Nov. 15, ruling that state law does not protect confessions made to clergy. The state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> last week refused to hear the ministers' challenge <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> are the only states that do not protect confessions made to ministers or priests in criminal cases, said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gay </PERSON>, the ministers' lawyer. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, however, does allow statements made to clergy about divorce proceedings to be kept secret, <PERSON> Gay </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> said earlier that just before Christmas he told the congregation that he watched and did nothing as another man broke into his uncle's store last December. He denied having a role in the robbery. `` It was such a burden on my heart, I just had to go to my church and get it off my chest,'' <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> said. Gay said another attorney has contacted him about drafting legislation to protect clergy and penitents in similar situations. `` I was disappointed the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> did n't take this opportunity to examine the issue,'' he said. `` It's a fundamental issue that cries out to be heard.'' The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Constitution provides for freedom of religion. Gay also argued that the state constitution prohibits anyone from being subpoenaed, jailed or arrested based upon a religious belief. The importance of protecting confessions made to clergy has been recognized since the days of the Roman Empire, according to the Rev. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Burtchaell </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> professor of theology at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Notre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dame </ORGANIZATION>. `` Society has said that it is of paramount importance that people be able to confide in clergymen or attorneys or their doctors without fear of it being disclosed,'' said <PERSON> Burtchaell </PERSON>, who has taught a course preparing seminarians to hear confessions. However, <PERSON> Burtchaell </PERSON> added that the ministers' case may have been weakened because <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> gave his confession publicly. Public confession of sins is a basic tenet of the Pentacostal church. `` <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> never took anyone aside and had them confess their sins in private,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Hiles </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hiles </PERSON> said the church's jail ministry had been hurt since inmates heard of the subpoenas. `` They do n't know if they can trust us anymore,'' <PERSON> Hiles </PERSON> said. `` They're saying ` Why should I tell you anything? If I do, they might force you to say it in court.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 2352EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Eliana-Funeral     12-04 0500</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Eliana-Funeral,0517</SECOND>
<HEAD>Young AIDS Victim Laid to Rest</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto TP5</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAT LEISNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TAMPA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An 8-year-old girl whose life was cut short by AIDS was laid to rest Monday with balloons, songs and a procession past the federal courthouse where she won her fight go to school. In a 90-minute service at a funeral home, <PERSON> Eliana </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> was eulogized as a frail, innocent child barely 3 feet tall who never learned to speak but taught adults the language of love. `` <PERSON> Eliana </PERSON> taught us to hug and to kiss,'' said her mother, <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON>. `` She takes a part of me with her.'' At <LOCATION> Myrtle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cemetery </LOCATION>, the mentally disabled girl's small, white casket was opened and Mrs. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> kissed her adopted daughter goodbye. Mourners released balloons into the air, and the casket was lowered into the ground. Friends were invited to throw of colored beads into the grave along with the traditional handfuls of dirt. Strands of the colorful glass beads which <PERSON> Eliana </PERSON> liked had been placed around her neck, and her Raggedy Ann doll laid on her chest. She was in a white dress with blue ribbons. The funeral home was decorated with small balloons. Larger red and purple balloons adorned the four white limousines that carried relatives and friends on the 15-mile procession to the cemetery, passing <PERSON> Eliana </PERSON>'s school, school board offices and the courthouse. More than 125 people who gathered at the funeral home watched a slide show that showed the wide-eyed smiling girl at home, the beach, school, the county fair _ and the hospital. Playing in the background was `` Everybody's Child,'' a song composed by family friend <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Castellano </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> told mourners that <PERSON> Eliana </PERSON> was `` a little girl with a gigantic heart -LRB- who -RRB- taught us so many things _ love, respect.'' Speech therapist <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> McClowrey </PERSON> said <PERSON> Eliana </PERSON> did not learn to speak, but `` spoke so loud to all those who were willing to hear.'' `` She showed me that loving is all there is,'' he said, his voice breaking. `` It was interesting to meet someone who turned the tables on me.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> adopted <PERSON> Eliana </PERSON>, who died a week ago, when she was 11 months old after hearing a radio appeal for a sickly child abandoned in a hospital in <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>. Four years later, the family learned that <PERSON> Eliana </PERSON> had acquired immune deficiency syndrome. By the time she was four months old, <PERSON> Eliana </PERSON> had received 38 transfusions, and doctors believed she received tainted blood. Education officials tried to restrict <PERSON> Eliana </PERSON>'s instruction to her home, fearing she might transmit AIDS to other pupils. Mrs. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> sued, saying the child needed contact with other children to develop. A federal judge said the child could attend classes only if she sat inside a specially-built glass booth until she was toilet trained and stopped sucking her fingers. Mrs. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> appealed and won after a two-year battle. <PERSON> Eliana </PERSON> went to school this year, but became too ill to continue after three weeks in class.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;Ls-Silverado Bjt   12-04 0559</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;Ls-Silverado, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Panel May Probe S&amp;L Case Linked to Bush's Son</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, having aired the collapse of <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, is considering probing an even more politically touchy case linked to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s family. Among the institutions that could be spotlighted next by the committee are <ORGANIZATION> Silverado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION>, declared insolvent by regulators in December 1988. <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the president's son, served on <PERSON> Silverado </PERSON>'s board of directors, resigning just after his father won the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> nomination in 1988 and only four months before the <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L's seizure. In a drive to oust top thrift regulator <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Wall </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> conducted six public hearings this fall focusing on regulators' delay in acting against the <LOCATION> Irvine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, - based <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION>, which is expected to become the nation's largest S & amp; L failure at a cost to taxpayers of $ 2 At the last hearing just before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> recessed for Thanksgiving, <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, vowed to continue the probe when legislators return in January, expanding it to include other notorious examples of abuse. `` We had scores ... of Lincolns and we're going to look into them. <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> is just the first because it was the biggest,'' he said. In response to a question from a reporter, <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> said <PERSON> Silverado </PERSON> could be among the failures highlighted at a future hearing. Committee aides have been gathering material on the case. <PERSON> Silverado </PERSON> was declared insolvent by thrift regulators on Dec. 9, 1988, and taxpayer costs could run as high as $ 500 million. The Federal Savings and <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, now part of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deposit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, attributed the failure to `` substantial dissipation of assets due to alleged violations of laws, rules and regulations.'' According to government sources, who spoke on condition of anonymity, regulators are investigating to determine whether to file a civil suit against <PERSON> Silverado </PERSON>'s former officers and directors, which would include <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. A new investigative book on the S & amp; L crisis, `` Inside Job'' by <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Pizzo </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Fricker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Muolo </PERSON>, cites links between <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, a director from 1985 until August 1988, and a major customer of Silverado. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s oil and gas company, <ORGANIZATION> JNB </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exploration </ORGANIZATION>, had a $ 1 million line of credit at <ORGANIZATION> Cherry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Creek </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, which was owned by <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Walters </PERSON>, who received more than $ 40 million in loans from <LOCATION> Silverado </LOCATION>, according to the book. <PERSON> Silverado </PERSON> also had business ties to <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mizel </PERSON>, a prominent Republican who raised $ 1 million for <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s 1984 campaign. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Moroney </PERSON>, a former analyst for the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Topeka </ORGANIZATION>, alleges that regulators held off action against <PERSON> Silverado </PERSON> because of its political connections, the book says. Aides to <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> said no decision has been made about whether to air the <PERSON> Silverado </PERSON> case in public hearings. The Lincoln sessions _ even though they targeted Wall, a Republican _ proved more embarrassing for Democrats because they highlighted the efforts of five senators, four of them senior Democrats, to intervene with regulators on <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>'s behalf. The president thus far has praised <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> for his bipartisan conduct of the hearings and said he has `` not closed the door'' on ousting Wall. Aides to Wall speculate that <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> may be holding out the possibility of <PERSON> Silverado </PERSON> hearings as part of his bid to get rid of the regulator.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ElvisSighting Bjt   12-04 0546</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Elvis Sighting, Bjt,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tacky Lawn Sculpture: `It's So Bad It's Good'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ARLINGTON, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It is n't any noisy, late-night parties at bachelor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Shumate </PERSON>'s home that have his neighbors whispering. It's what he keeps in his front yard. Like the life-size <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON> bust with purple pompadour, bolted atop a tall pedestal guarded by a grinning, red-bearded gnome holding a sign reading `` Long Live the King.'' Or that plastic palm tree festooned with blinking blue lights that decorated <PERSON> Shumate </PERSON>'s front porch last Christmas, opposite a plastic <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION> whose fat belly was illuminated with a flashing light bulb. Passersby also are transfixed by the concrete <PERSON> Venus </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Milo </PERSON> and pink flamingo, the plastic madonna blessing the concrete rabbit, squirrel and penguin. And the little concrete toddler, shyly clutching a teddy bear and sucking on its fingers while its diapers fall down. It's one of <PERSON> Shumate </PERSON>'s favorites. `` It's the most horrifying thing I've ever seen,'' he says with a chuckle. `` It's just awful.'' <PERSON> Shumate </PERSON>, a 42-year-old architect and avid collector of lawn ornaments, delights in adorning the yard of his modest bungalow in this <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> suburb with the sort of truly tasteless schlock that makes urban sophisticates wince. `` I saw this stuff when I was a kid growing up in the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> suburbs,'' he said. `` It was humorous to me even then. What's interesting about the 50s was the junky stuff _ the cars, the lawn sculptures, the furniture. It's so bad it's good.'' <PERSON> Shumate </PERSON> had only a few pink flamingos when he bought his <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION> house three years ago. Perhaps it was the house, with its original pink aluminum siding from the 1950s, that inspired <PERSON> Shumate </PERSON> to begin collecting in earnest. His favorite haunt is <PERSON> Harper </PERSON>'s Lawn Ornaments, a two-acre mecca for kitsch hunters in rural <LOCATION> Harrisonburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>. It was there that he found his $ 32 <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> bust among the tons of concrete birdbaths, <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> figures, antlered stags and naked ladies. `` Things were relatively quiet around here until I put up <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Shumate </PERSON> said. `` It became a landmark overnight. At first my neighbors did n't know what to think, but they finally figured out my sense of humor and now they enjoy it.'' <PERSON> Shumate </PERSON> is a Cadillac freak, too. He's owned six of them. The latest, parked in his driveway, is a monstrous 1975 model Fleetwood. Original avocado green paint, wide white sidewalls, license plates that read `` Gross XS'' -LRB- for Gross Excess -RRB- and a `` Caution: I Brake For Elvis'' bumper sticker. `` I consider that to be one of my lawn sculptures,'' he says. Down in his basement, <PERSON> Shumate </PERSON> keeps the trashy stuff he has n't decided where to display in the proper mock-serious style, including a concrete cherub with a large fish draped over its shoulder and `` your generic babe with a bunch of grapes'' sprayed with gilt paint On a shelf are air-brushed wall squirrels, a pink coffee mug with pelican-shaped handle, a blue plastic shark that <PERSON> Shumate </PERSON> once hung from the rear-view mirror of his old powder-blue Caddy. `` This is what yuppies put in their kitchen window as a joke,'' he said disdainfully. `` They have no real commitment to lawn ornaments. If everyone thinks it's a joke, it does n't count. It's not really fun.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 0042EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SummitWrapup Bjt   12-04 0798</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit Wrapup, Bjt,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush, Gorbachev Leave Summit Offering Visions of Cold War's End</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHARLES CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MARSAXLOKK BAY, Malta (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> left their weatherblown summit talks offering visions of a dawning era of lasting peace, with the remnants of the Cold War giving way to a better world. They announced no breakthroughs Sunday on issues that divide their countries, such as <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and naval disarmament, but said that was not the point of their open-agenda dockside encounters. In their parting remarks, both chose to emphasize mutual aspirations. `` We sought the answer to the question where we stand now,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> told reporters. `` Many things that were characteristic of the Cold War should be abandoned ... the arms race, mistrust, psychological and ideological struggle and all that. All that should be things of the past.'' Trading relaxed banter at the first-ever joint news conference of <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> presidents, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> repeatedly echoed each other's words as they described their talks and their hopes for the future. `` I could n't have asked for a better result out of this non-summit summit,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` It was a no-agenda meeting and yet it was a meeting where were discussed, as the chairman said, many, many subjects. So I think if a meeting can improve relations, I think this one has.'' The next chance comes in June, when a full-scale Bush-Gorbachev summit is scheduled for <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The fireworks missing in the superpower talks were supplied Sunday night in a loud and colorful display over the <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valletta </LOCATION>, the capital of this Mediterranean island nation. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, meanwhile, headed for <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to meet with his <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION> allies while <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> traveled to <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> to brief the <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> allies. `` Tonight we stand at the crossroads of history on our way to a <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> made whole and free,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said when he arrived in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>. `` Today as the sun broke through the clouds there at <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>, we could see both a new world taking shape, a new world of freedom,'' he said. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said he was `` encouraged and inspired'' by the reforms sweeping Stalin-style communism from <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. He said the changes stem from `` the desire of these peoples to ennoble their societies, to make them more democratic, humanitarian, to open up the rest of the world.'' And in a post-summit interview broadcast on Soviet television, he had praise for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` I must say I'm glad I found a lot of realism in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s attitude and I felt his desire, his effort to understand the processes under way, exchange opinions, to work out approaches,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said `` The dialogue actually surpassed my expectations.'' The weather in <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> was less congenial. What was planned as an offshore summit alternating between <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet warships never came off. Saturday afternoon's session was canceled when <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> could not get off the guided-missile cruiser USS Belknap because of 60 mph winds and high seas. The two rounds of talks that did take place were both moved to the Soviet cruise liner Maxim Gorky, docked at <LOCATION> Marsaxlokk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> several hundred yards from the naval vessels. Neither leader ever made it to the missile cruiser <PERSON> Slava </PERSON>, intended to be the Soviet summit site. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> suggested cutting naval forces on the two sides, but <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, whose large-ship navy predominates, said he was `` disinclined to think that this is an area where we will have immediate progress.'' The leaders also restated their positions on <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> complained about Nicaraguan and Cuban supplies of Soviet-bloc weapons to rebels fighting the right-wing government in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, while <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said the Sandinista government in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> had given assurances such shipments had stopped. `` I do n't believe that the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> have told the truth to our Soviet friends,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> could benefit from cuts in tariffs on Soviet exports to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> support for its participation in the 97-nation General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade in exchange for relaxing emigration restrictions on Soviet Jews. The leaders also ordered their officials to speed up negotiations on treaties to cut conventional arms in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and long-range nuclear weapons in hopes of signing both next year. An unprecedented joint news conference at the conclusion of the summit was not part of the initial plans. It developed when both leaders stayed to respond to questions after making their statements, and unfolded in a relaxed, almost teasing atmosphere. While the two were discussing the possible reunification of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said he and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had exchanged messages on the question. `` The president wrote in English and I do n't read English. I answered him in Russian and he does n't read Russian. But, we agreed,'' said <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. `` No matter what it said,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> added.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-Gorbachev     12-04 0582</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Gorbachev,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gorbachev Challenge: To Lead Way to New Political Alliance</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL PUTZEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MARSAXLOKK BAY, Malta (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> sets out from his first superpower summit meeting with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to lead his <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact alliance into a new era of cooperation with the West _ or risk being left behind and alone. As he and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> parted after two days in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> headed home for a meeting with a dramatically different and more Westward-looking <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION> leadership than when members last convened in July. The communist bloc alliance has become less communist and less a bloc, presenting <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> with the challenge of leading the transition he described from a Kremlin-dominated military alliance to a new political association guiding <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in its rush to erase the lines that have divided East and West for 45 years. Culturally and geographically, <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION> partners are closer to the West than the vast <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> straddling <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. And as they turn away from the Kremlin to face the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> may find it increasingly difficult to drive his stubbornly backward society at a quick enough pace to catch up. At his joint news conference with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> closing their first summit meeting, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> declared himself `` encouraged and inspired'' by the changes that have swept hardline communists from power in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION>. The changes, he said, show `` the desire of these peoples to ennoble their societies, to make them more democratic and humanitarian and to open up to the rest of the world.'' But they also dramatically alter the <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION>'s once dominant and domineering role in the alliance. For the first time since the pact was signed in the Polish capital in 1955 in response to the formation of the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION>, one of the leaders present _ Polish Prime Minister <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> _ will be a non-communist. <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON>, a leader of the independent Solidarity labor movement suppressed with Soviet support in 1981, was elected in August to head <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s first non-communist government in four decades. And on the eve of the summit, the leadership of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, at the heart of the strategic alliance, was wrenched by its second spasm in recent weeks as communist leader <PERSON> Egon </PERSON> <PERSON> Krenz </PERSON> and the party's entire top echelon abdicated to a 25-member panel of reformers in a desperate effort to salvage some measure of support for the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Krenz </ORGANIZATION> relinquished the party post he had held less than six weeks, and although he retained the largely ceremonial title of president, it was not immediately clear who would represent <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> at the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> meeting. Several other East European leaders, including <PERSON> Petar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mladenov </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Karel </PERSON> <PERSON> Urbanek </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, are attending their first <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact leadership meeting. And for the first time since the alliance was formed, the head of the <ORGANIZATION> Polish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, now out of power, apparently was n't invited at all <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>, who continues to rule <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> with the iron hand once rewarded by <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, is the only <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc leader who rejects the democratically inspired reform movement. With the recent fall of orthodox communist leaders like <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Milos </PERSON> <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, he is likely to find himself more isolated than ever as he sits down with the new generation of East European leaders.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Putzel </PERSON> heads the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> bureau.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 0058EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-Malta     12-04 0534</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Malta,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Summit Offers Cure for Country With Identity Crisis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRY LEONARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VALLETTA, Malta (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Before the dockside summit, this tiny island nation suffered from an identity crisis. Maltese passports even included a map to show doubtful foreigners that the country exists. But that was before President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> came to <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> and put this rocky <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> archipelago back on everyone's map. The passports will be changed shortly after the first of the year, said a slightly embarrassed <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Cachia </PERSON> <PERSON> Caruana </PERSON>, the aide to the prime minister who was in charge of organizing <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>'s part in the summit. `` That was a lack of self-confidence by the previous government,'' he said, shaking his head. `` It's degrading.'' Any lingering doubts by the Maltese about their country's identity seemed to have been dispelled by the superpower summit, by the words and images beamed abroad by about 2,500 journalists covering the <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush-Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> talks `` For <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> itself, the summit has been very positive. It has shown <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> can cope even with the necessary organization for a summit like this,'' Prime Minister <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Fenech </PERSON> <PERSON> Adami </PERSON> said in an interview after the summit closed Sunday. `` Some people were skeptical that <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> could do it. I think we proved ourselves,'' he added. Not even the fierce December gale that drove the summit at sea to the side of a pier could dampen the enthusiasm of the prime minister. `` Well, I do n't mind the weather at all. If anything, it has proved I was correct when I suggested that the meetings should not be held in <LOCATION> Marsaxlokk </LOCATION> but in some other bay, such as <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>, which is more protected than <PERSON> Marsaxlokk </PERSON> <PERSON> Bay </PERSON>,'' he said. <PERSON> Cachia </PERSON> <PERSON> Caruana </PERSON> said the Soviets and Americans first planned to hold the summit at sea, perhaps in Maltese territorial waters, but that the prime minister had convinced them of the hazards of December. `` Within 24 hours we made the point that this is December and that these things can happen,'' he said. Still, he acknowledges the images of thunderous waves crashing against the rocks below the 16th Century fortifications of the capital <LOCATION> Valletta </LOCATION> wo n't help the island's winter tourism. `` In terms of what we had hoped to achieve overall, the tourism objectives probably will not be met,'' said <PERSON> Cachia </PERSON> <PERSON> Caruana </PERSON>. `` But our principal objective, especially in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, was name identification. `` Just being at the center of the world stage for two days in a way helped give us that anyway.'' <PERSON> Cachia </PERSON> <PERSON> Caruana </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> wants to base its growth on business, not just tourism, and that's why the summit will help. `` Our greatest objective is dragging the economy into the last decade of the 20th Century,'' he said. Still, in those first few hours after the departure of the leaders of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the chief Maltese organizer of the summit was relieved that it was over. `` It's been a hell of an experience. We had a situation here where the journalists outnumbered the army by two-to-one,'' said <PERSON> Cachia </PERSON> <PERSON> Caruana </PERSON>. `` It's back to business as usual tomorrow. We will assume it was a dream and forget all about it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 0058EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-Glance     12-04 0245</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Glance,240</SECOND>
<DATELINE>MARSAXLOKK BAY, Malta (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here, at a glance, is a look at the shipboard summit between President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>THE MEETINGS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 _ <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> met for about eight hours over two days aboard the Soviet cruise ship <PERSON> Maxim </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorky </PERSON> Plans to hold the talks on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet warships were scrapped because of rough weather.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>AGREEMENTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 _ No accords were reached and no joint communique was issued
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>ARMS CONTROL</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 _ Both presidents expressed hope that a long-range strategic arms treaty could be signed at a June summit in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and that differences could be settled to reduce conventional forces in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and eliminate chemical weapons <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> played down chances for a quick resolution of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s desire for naval reductions.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>CENTRAL AMERICA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 _ <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> stood by his assertion that Soviet-made weapons continue to flow to leftist rebels resisting the government of President <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said the Soviets were n't shipping them there.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>EASTERN EUROPE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 _ <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said he was `` encouraged and inspired'' by the changes in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, while <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is laying to rest previous doctrines, including the <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON> doctrine, under which the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> had asserted its right to intervene militarily in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>WHAT'S NEXT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 _ <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> briefs <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> allies in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> today, while <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> holds a similar session with leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION>
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEXT SUMMIT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 _ In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in the second half of June
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ManhattanOwners Bjt   12-04 0704</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Manhattan Owners, Bjt,0723</SECOND>
<HEAD>Despite High-Profile Buys, New York Isn't `Little Japan'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICK HAMPSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Recent Japanese purchases in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> have made some people nervous, despite a foreign-buyer tradition that started when Dutch settlers snapped up the island for $ 24 worth of knives, fabric and trinkets. Officials say a majority of <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>'s buildings still are owned by Americans, and Japanese are not even the largest foreign landlords. Some find the alarm over Japanese purchases puzzling. `` I do n't know what's behind this xenophobia,'' said <PERSON> Rosemary </PERSON> <PERSON> Scanlon </PERSON>, an economist for the <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. `` Everyone seems to have been jolted awake to find we're not the only large economy in the world. Several organizations have tried to estimate foreign holdings in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> commercial real estate, but no one really knows the figure, said <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, head of the real estate firm that bears his name. `` When a foreigner buys a piece of property, he does n't declare, ` I'm a foreigner,''' said <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, a researcher for the <ORGANIZATION> Real </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION>. `` The owner's name may be <ORGANIZATION> Piccadilly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Properties </ORGANIZATION>, but there's no legislation requiring them to sign in as British.'' Foreign investments often are made through part ownerships, joint ventures and convertible mortgages, which can further cloud an owner's identity. `` On a mortgage the address might simply say, ` Return to <LOCATION> Curacao </LOCATION>''' said Ms. <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>. When <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> announced in October it was spending $ 846 million for a controlling interest in the company that owns <ORGANIZATION> Rockefeller </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, local wits said sumo wrestlers would soon take over the center's ice skating rink. On a more gloomy note, Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Lieberman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., said of the Christmas tree-lighting ceremony at the center in <LOCATION> midtown </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, `` that great national celebration is actually occurring on Japanese property. But, noted Ms. <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, `` the <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> and the Dutch have been buying in this country for a long, long time,'' and it seems safe to say that worries about foreigners buying up <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> are exaggerated. `` For all the publicity, the amount of foreign-owned real estate here is still pretty modest,'' said <PERSON> Scanlon </PERSON>. `` It's not such a big deal.'' According to the <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION>, during the past 15 years foreigners have acquired about 64 million of <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>'s 335 million square feet of prime office space, or 19 percent. This includes Canadians -LRB- 7.3 percent -RRB-, Japanese -LRB- 5.4 percent -RRB-, British -LRB- 2.7 percent -RRB- and Dutch -LRB- 1.4 percent -RRB-. Other foreigners have bought more than 2 percent. The city's largest single foreign landowner is <ORGANIZATION> Olympia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; York of <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>, which shrewdly began buying in the depressed market of the mid-1970s and now owns about 25 million square feet of office space worth billion of dollars. Since 1986, Japanese investors have jumped into commercial real estate, snapping up the <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Citicorp </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Mobil </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Paine </PERSON> <PERSON> Webber </PERSON> buildings. They also bought hotels, including the Algonquin, the Stanhope, the Inter-Continental and the <ORGANIZATION> Essex </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. But they have been even more active elsewhere. In 1988, when Japanese investors bought $ 8.3 billion in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> real estate, twice as much of that was in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> as in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> state. More than half the office buildings in downtown <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> are foreign owned, according to the real estate firm of <ORGANIZATION> Cushman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <LOCATION> Wakefield </LOCATION>. Even in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, a city that was never a magnet for foreign investment, 12 percent of the office space is owned by foreigners, and some experts say that could rise to 50 percent by the year 2000. Foreign investment in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> office space will surely increase _ Swedes and <LOCATION> Koreans </LOCATION> are said to be next in line for some prime buildings _ but business executives, at least, are n't worried. In a survey released earlier this year, 55 percent of corporate executives said foreign investment helped the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy, and 31 percent said it was little cause for alarm. Only 10 percent of real estate executives said foreign investment severely threatened the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy. In fact, foreign investment is crucial to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, said Ms. <PERSON> Scanlon </PERSON>, noting that foreign money helped the city rebound from its fiscal crisis a decade ago. `` It's important for the city's economy that investment come in,'' she said. `` It's not so important where it comes from.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-GorbachevText     12-04 0791</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Gorbachev Text,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Text of Gorbachev Post-Summit Statement</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Summit Wrapup, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MARSAXLOKK BAY, Malta (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the text of Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s statement Sunday at the conclusion of his two-day summit meeting with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: There are many symbolic things about this meeting and one of them _ it has never been in history that the leaders of our two countries hold a joint press conference. This is also an important symbol. I share the view voiced by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> that we are satisfied in general with the results of the meeting. We regard this informal meeting _ the idea of it was an informal meeting and the idea belongs to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, and I supported it _ that we would have this informal meeting without restricting it to any formal agenda, to have a free exchange of views, because the time makes great demands to our countries, and this increases the responsibility and the role of our two countries. And I can assure you that in all our discussions _ and our discussions lasted for eight hours, in general _ this responsibility on both sides was present. Our meeting was characterized by openness, by a full scope of the exchange of views. Today, it is even difficult and perhaps there is no sense to explain the entire range of issues that we have discussed. I wish to say right away, nevertheless, that on all the major issues, we attempted in a frank manner, using each side's arguments, to explain our own positions, both with regard to the assessment of the situation and the current changes in the world, in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, and as regards disarmament issues We addressed the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> negotiating process, the <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> process, and also negotiations on the elaboration of the chemical weapons ban. All those questions were considered thoroughly. The president and I, myself, also thought it necessary to exchange views on our perception, both from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, of the `` hot'' places on our planet. And this exchange of views was very significant and thorough. We reaffirmed our former positions that all those issues, acute issues, must be resolved by political methods. And I consider that this was a very important statement of fact. We not only discussed problems and explained our positions, I think that both sides had many elements which, if they are taken into account in our future activities, activities of both governments, then we can count on progress. This concerns the subject of the reduction of strategic offensive arms by 50 percent. And we have an optimistic assessment of the possibility to move even next year to the conclusion of the <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> treaty. We both are in favor _ and this is our position. Naturally, we can be responsible only for our position. We are in favor of signing this document at the summit meeting. This time we discussed much bilateral relations. And I, on my part, would like to note many positive elements and points which were contained in statements and words by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Thus, I would say that in all directions of the political dialogue of our discussion, including bilateral relations, we not only confirmed the consistency of our political course, the continuity of our political course _ and I should say, although we had an informal meeting, we met only for the first time with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in his capacity, and the confirmation of the continuity of the course is an important element. What is also important is that during this informal meeting, we have laid the foundation for increasing this. And I believe that in the first place, it serves the interest of our both countries and also the interests of the entire world community. Well, we have made our contact a good contact. The atmosphere was friendly, straightforward, open. And this enabled us to make good work. In our position, the most dangerous thing is to exaggerate _ and that is always that we should preserve elements of cautiousness _ and I use the favorite word by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. -LRB- Laughter. -RRB- Our world and our relations are at a crucial juncture. We should be highly responsible to face up to the challenges of today's world And the leaders of our two countries can not act as a fire brigade, although fire brigades are very useful. We have to keep it in mind also. This element was also present. I would like once again to thank the president for the idea of holding this meeting with which we are satisfied, I hope. And I would like to thank the people and the government of <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>, and to express the words of appreciation and gratitude for their hospitality. Thank you, Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, for your cooperation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-BushText     12-04 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Bush Text,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Text of Bush Post-Summit Statement</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Summit Wrapup, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MARSAXLOKK BAY, Malta (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the text of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s statement at the conclusion of his two-day summit meeting with Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>: Ladies and gentlemen, President <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has graciously suggested I go first. And I do n't think anyone can say that the saltwater get-together was anything other than adventure, at least out in the harbor here. First, I want to thank Prime Minister -LRB- <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Fenech </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Adami </PERSON> and the people of <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> and others for their warm and gracious hospitality. I want to thank the captain and crew of -LRB- the USS -RRB- <PERSON> Belknap </PERSON> for the great support that they've given us _ I think they were wondering if I was about to become a permanent guest _ and a special thanks to the captain and crew of -LRB- the Soviet cruise ship Maxim -RRB- <PERSON> Gorky </PERSON> for their hospitality, and also thanks to the captain and crew of -LRB- the Soviet naval cruiser -RRB- <PERSON> Slava </PERSON> who had been so hospitable to many on the American side. I first approached Chairman <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> about an informal meeting of this kind after my trip to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> last July. The amazing changes that I witnessed in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, hopeful changes, led me to believe that it was time to sit down with Chairman <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, face to face, to see what he and I could do to seize the opportunities before us to move this relationship forward. He agreed with that concept of a meeting, and so we got rapid agreement. And I think that the extraordinary ... developments in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> since the time that the meeting was proposed only reinforced the importance of our getting together. So I'm especially glad we had this meeting, and we did gain a deeper understanding of each other's views. We set the stage for progress across a broad range of issues. And while it is not for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to design the future for Europeans or for any other people, I am convinced that a cooperative U.S.-Soviet relationship can indeed make the future safer and brighter. And there is virtually no problem in the world, and certainly no problem in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, that improvement in the U.S.-Soviet relationship will not help to ameliorate. A better U.S.-Soviet relationship is to be valued in and of itself, but it also should be an instrument of positive change for the world. For 40 years the Western alliances stood together in the cause of freedom. And now, with reform under way in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, we stand at the threshold of a brand-new era of U.S.-Soviet relations. And it is within our grasp to contribute, each in our own way, to overcoming the division of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, and ending the military confrontation there. We've got to do more to ameliorate the violence and suffering that afflict so many regions in the world and to remove common threats to our future. The deterioration of the environment, the spread of nuclear and chemical weapons, ballistic missile technology, the narcotics trade, and our discussions here will give greater impetus to make real progress in these areas. There's also a great potential to develop common opportunities. For example, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> now seeks greater engagement with the international market economy, a step that certainly I'm prepared to encourage in every way I can As I leave <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> and a meeting with our <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> allies, I am optimistic that, as the West works patiently together and increasingly cooperates with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, we can realize a lasting peace and transform the East-West relationship to one of enduring cooperation. And that is a future that is worthy of our peoples, and that's the future that I want to help in creating, and that's the future that Chairman <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and I began right here in <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>. -LRB- To <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> -RRB- Thank you, sir, for your hospitality.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     12-04 0561</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Aquaculture a Growing US Industry</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Catfish farming has had some flip-flops over the years but <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> experts say it looks good over the long pull. For that matter, fish farming in general _ aquaculture is the fancy name _ is expanding and shows promise if growers and processors can hone their marketing skills. Catfish are the main items in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aquaculture output, but trout, salmon, crawfish and other species are also growing, according to <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. But there are problems. For example, catfish farmers have boosted production so rapidly that sometimes the demand lags supplies. In October, for example, production was estimated at 31.7 million pounds, live weight. That was up 21 percent from 26.2 million pounds a year earlier. Prices received by growers averaged 64 cents per pound, down 19 percent from 79 cents in October 1988. <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> said aquaculture in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is still `` a young and growing industry'' that is still going through adjustments that may become even more important in the 1990s. A number of forces will contribute to the continued growth of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aquaculture, <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> told last week's <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> outlook conference. `` First, the interaction of worldwide population growth and the biological limits of what our oceans can supply should increase the demand for farm-raised fish,'' he said. `` As the capture-fisheries industry approaches maximum harvest rates for more and more species, added pressure will be placed on aquaculture to become a major source of seafood production.'' <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> said one sign of the pressure on commercial fishing _ the `` capture'' fisheries _ is the growing number of harvesting restrictions being placed on species around the world. Another factor is the growing public concern about pollution of ocean and fresh water resources. This `` should strengthen aquaculture's position as an alternate source of seafood'' produced under closely watched conditions, he said. `` However, aquaculturists must make the public aware of how their products differ from those of the capture-fisheries industry,'' <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> said. `` To avoid consumer resistance to their products due to pollution concerns, producers must maintain high quality standards, be sensitive to consumer fears about contaminated products, and be able to document the safety of their products.'' The ongoing emphasis on nutrition also should help boost seafood consumption, he said. Other factors that may influence <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> seafood consumption include the general aging of Americans and the rising percentage of non-whites. `` Both these groups, older people and non-whites, in the past have consumed seafood at higher rates than the general population,'' <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> said. `` One -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- study combining changes in age, race and income estimated that seafood expenditures for fish products would increase 27.4 percent between 1980 and 2005, well above the projected increases for beef, pork or poultry.'' <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> said if legislation is passed to require federal inspection of seafood products it would boost consumer confidence in the safety of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> seafood but would probably add some expense to processing and marketing. `` The basic technologies are now in place for the expansion of the domestic aquaculture industry, but producers will have to successfully deal with a variety of issues that may impact future growth,'' he said. `` The rate of growth for most aquacultural species may depend on the industry's success at marketing its products to a larger group of consumers.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-LandInventory     12-04 0269</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Land Inventory,240</SECOND>
<HEAD>Embargoed for release 10 a.m. EST; time set by source</HEAD>
<HEAD>Wind Damage to Cropland Increases</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soil erosion from water runoff declined between 1982 and 1987, but wind damage to the nation's cropland increased slightly, an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report said today. The latest National Resources Inventory released by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Soil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said `` sheet and rill'' erosion by water dropped to an average of 3.8 tons per acre annually from 4.3 tons during the five-year period. Wind erosion, however, increased 0.1 ton per acre to 3.3 tons per acre annually. Most wind erosion of cropland is concentrated in the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> states. Total sheet-and-rill erosion of cropland was reported at 1.6 billion tons per year and wind erosion at nearly 1.4 billion tons annually. The national summary of the <ORGANIZATION> NRI </ORGANIZATION> _ a benchmark reference used widely by government and private conservationists and others _ will be followed next year by a complete report, officials said. Wilson Scaling, chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Soil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said the report includes information on erosion, cropland use, irrigation, tillage and conservation needs. The area of rural non-federal land totals 1.4 billion acres, the report said. Of this, 422.8 million acres are cropland; 401.7 million rangeland; 394.5 million forestland; and 59.9 million in `` minor land uses.'' From 1982 to 1987, it said, 4 million acres of rural non-federal land were converted to urban and transportation uses, which include roads and airports. Cropland increased 1.4 million acres in the five years to 422.8 million from 421.4 million, while pastureland declined 2.3 million acres and rangeland dropped 6 million acres.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Summit-TV     12-04 0468</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-TV,0483</SECOND>
<HEAD>Storm-Lashed Network Crews Leave Malta</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Bush-NATO, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAY SHARBUTT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Weary network crews trudged home today after following their anchormen from <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>, where they covered a summit whose storms threatened to upstage the superpowers. At one point Saturday night, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> anchor <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rather </PERSON> warned that `` if the weather does n't improve, this thing's going to be a wreck.'' But from the TV standpoint, the only thing wrecked at the summit was a small studio <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> had built near <LOCATION> Marsaxlokk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, overlooking the harbor site of the shipboard meetings of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. A <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said the structure was demolished by Saturday's storm, which forced the cancellation of the day's second planned meeting of the two leaders and sent network staffs scurrying to reshape their coverage <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> anchor <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> had to remain with the other anchors in the city of <LOCATION> Valetta </LOCATION>, six miles away. But that was only one of <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION>'s problems Saturday's 60 mph winds blew down and damaged a <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> satellite dish, knocking out <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION>'s signal for eight hours. But a spokesman said no transmissions had been planned during the period of the blackout, which began at 9 p.m. EST. The storm also briefly affected <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. Rain shorted out an electrical connection at the start of anchor <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenning </PERSON>'s live summit report from <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> during the first of two `` World News Tonight'' broadcasts that <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> sends its affiliates each night. But the Maltese connection was quickly restored. <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> came back on with his report eight minutes later. The storm did n't much affect <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> coverage of Saturday's summit, to which the four <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> networks brought a total of nearly 200 staff members On Sunday, the weather was much better. But an electronic problem caused a translation problem for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> during the live telecast of the superpower leaders' joint news conference aboard the safely docked Soviet luxury liner Maxim Gorky. The Soviets provided the TV pool feed for broadcasters and an audio channel offering a simultaneous English translations of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s remarks. However, during the last half hour of the session, an electronic glitch knocked out the English-language channel. CBS and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> had translators standing by, so viewers did n't miss anything. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> hastily summoned a Soviet official on <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>, but missed eight minutes of translation. <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> went the long way for help. After 13 minutes in which <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> recapped summit news while <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was speaking, an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> woman's voice was heard translating the Soviet leader's comments. She was <PERSON> Siobahn </PERSON> <PERSON> Darrow </PERSON>, translating from <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman said. The summit capped a busy week for the networks, during which their anchors were based in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, and in the case of <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891204-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-04-89 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Right-to-Die-Cruzans Bjt   12-04 0688</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Right-to-Die-Cruzans, Bjt,0709</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cruzan Says Daughter Wants to Die: `It Is The Right Decision For
Us'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL MANNING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JEFFERSON CITY, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
