<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ShootingTrek     03-18 0396</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Shooting Trek,0408</SECOND>
<HEAD>Paterson Man Turns Himself In After Being Sought For Shooting Wife</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PATERSON, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man who fled the shooting of his wife crashed his car, took over two other vehicles at gunpoint and left an abducted family beside a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> highway before surrendering Friday, police said. <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Otero </PERSON>, 39, was wanted for the Thursday night shooting of his estranged wife, <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> <PERSON> Otero </PERSON>, 34. She was in critical condition Friday night at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joseph </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said a nursing superviser. <PERSON> Otero </PERSON> turned himself in to <LOCATION> Paterson </LOCATION> police about 5 p.m. Friday and was arrested on charges of attempted murder, kidnapping, armed robbery and unlawful possession of a weapon, said police Sgt. <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Perrone </PERSON>. <PERSON> Otero </PERSON> was held in the city jail pending arraignment Saturday. Police said the shooting began an interstate trek across the <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> and a manhunt that involved police from <LOCATION> Paterson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nassau </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Otero </PERSON> shot his wife several times about 10:15 p.m. Thursday and fled in his own car only to get into an accident with other cars a few blocks away. Witnesses told police <PERSON> Otero </PERSON> pulled a revolver and forced <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Vazquez </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Paterson </LOCATION> to drive him to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Vazquez </PERSON> dropped <PERSON> Otero </PERSON> off near the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> end of the <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tunnel </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, police said. There, <PERSON> Otero </PERSON> approached a car stopped at a pay phone and forced five members of a <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> family to drive him to <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, said Officer <PERSON> Janice </PERSON> <PERSON> Swinney </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> police spokeswoman. A male family member was at a pay phone when <PERSON> Otero </PERSON> allegedly forced him back into the car and made them drive to <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. `` I thought he was going to kill us for sure,'' said <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Gee </PERSON>, whose husband, daughter, son, and grandson were held at gunpoint during the two-hour ordeal. `` We started to pray out loud as soon as he got into the car,'' Mrs. Gee said. `` He told us to shut up.'' The gunman forced the family, which was in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to attend a funeral service, out of the car on the Long Island Expressway near <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Westbury </LOCATION>, police said. <PERSON> Perrone </PERSON> said there were no reports of injuries to the family or <PERSON> Vazquez </PERSON>. <PERSON> Otero </PERSON> then fled on foot. He contacted his relatives while on the run and was talked into giving himself up, <PERSON> Perrone </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GlobalWarming Bjt   03-18 0603</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Global Warming, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>EPA Urges Conservation Measures for Cars, Homes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Conservation techniques that were urged during the energy shortages of the 70s should be adopted to combat global warming caused by pollution, the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> says. The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, in a report Friday, outlined actions such as development of fuel-efficient cars, energy-saving homes and solar technology, needed by the end of the century to curtail global warming. They say such warming will occur unless air pollution is reduced. In its report to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on environmental protection, the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said most scientists agree that without action to reduce pollution, the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> can be expected to warm by 4 to 11 degrees Fahrenheit over the next 100 years. `` There's no doubt there is a consensus that the greenhouse phenomenon is very real,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Baucus </PERSON>, D-Mont., the subcommittee chairman after hearing <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON> summarize the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> report Scientists believe that a variety of pollutants are causing a `` greenhouse effect'' that traps the sun's infrared radiation, instead of allowing it to go back into space, resulting in increased warming. The gases most responsible for the warming are carbon dioxide, chlorofluorocarbons, methane and nitrous oxides. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> report said `` no single technology or policy can have significant impact in mitigating the accumulation of greenhouse gases'' because of their wide use. Instead, it said, that only by dealing with the problem broadly can there be significant reductions. The recommendations outlined in the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> report will be used by both the administration and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to assess what kinds of regulatory action or legislation might be needed on global warming. One focus, the agency said, must be aimed at reducing the use of fossil fuels, which produce carbon dioxide, by far the largest single contributor to global warming. Last decade, the high cost of such fuels and the easy shutoff of foreign sources prompted conservation moves. To curtail energy use, the report proposed: _ Increasing average automobile fuel economy levels to 40 miles per gallon by the year 2000 This is in sharp contrast to the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, which in recent years has urged elimination of federal fuel economy standards and accommodated auto industry requests not to set fleetwide standards above 26.5 mpg. _ Taking measures to make new single family homes more energy efficient so that on average they will use 50 percent less fuel heat in the year 2000 than the average in 1980 _ Setting fees of 7 percent to 20 percent on carbon emissions from natural gas, oil and coal to encourage less use of those fossil fuels The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> also suggested increasing research into solar technology so it competes with oil and gas and pushing to get all industrial countries to require catalytic converters similar to those required in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> automobiles. But the report emphasized that increased energy efficiency will not in itself provide the total answer. It said efforts must be made to: _ Stop the loss of forests around the world by beginning in 1990 a program aimed at planting at least as many trees as are cut down or destroyed Trees absorb carbon dioxide as they grow, keeping the gas from getting into the atmosphere. _ End the use of chlorofluorocarbons by all industrialized countries over the next 14 years and take action to sharply curtail the chemical's use by developing countries The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration and the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> countries recently agreed to phase out use of such gases, which contribute to depletion of the world's ozone layer and are believed to be a major contributor to global warming.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bennett-NRA Bjt   03-18 0617</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bennett-NRA, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>NRA's Alleged Threats Anger Bennett</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Colt Industries Inc, no period, is cq</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> is denying an accusation that it indirectly sent messages to national drug director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> threatening his political future. `` The allegations are absolutely ridiculous,'' said <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> LaPierre </PERSON>, executive director of <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION>. An administration source said Friday that the warnings to <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> through third parties threaten that `` if he has thoughts of a political future, he can forget them if he does n't respect the power of the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> has frequently been mentioned as a candidate for elected office. The source, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> is `` very angry at the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>'' and that while he's `` not looking for a fight with the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>, he wo n't walk away from it'' and may battle them in public if need be. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said Friday through spokesman <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>: `` There have been a lot of phone calls, a lot of pressure. Let's cool off.'' The issue arose Tuesday when, at <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>'s urging, <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> immediately suspended import permits for more than 110,000 assault-style rifles such as the semiautomatic versions of AK-47s and Uzi carbines. <ORGANIZATION> Colt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION> subsequently decided on its own to suspend sales of its AR-15, the most popular U.S.-made semiautomatic assault rifle. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had told <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> a week earlier to develop a policy on the rifles. Calls for a ban have been prompted by scores of drug-related shootings and the recent killing of five <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> schoolchildren by a man wielding such a weapon. Publicly, the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> has reacted calmly to the decision, saying it would relieve the `` media hysteria'' over the guns and `` should provide an atmosphere for a reasoned and sensible debate on this issue.'' But privately, the source alleged, the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> has been relaying warnings via `` private people'' who are not in government. During an interview earlier in the day, <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said he believed most members of the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> do not support an `` anything goes'' attitude toward gun ownership and said he had spoken with friends of his who are hunters. `` These people have no use or interest in assault rifles,'' he said. `` The ` anything goes' idea _ let's just get our hands on any kind of weapon _ I think that's a view of the world that's not shared by most Americans, by most members of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, and I think an awful lot of people out there are concerned about the kind of firepower that we're seeing used in our streets,'' he said. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said he was not surprised that sales of semiautomatic assault rifles have taken off since the import suspension and <PERSON> Colt </PERSON>'s action this week, but, he said: `` If people are doing this because they think that this could mean the end of guns, that no more guns would be available, then they're mistaken `` The tradition in this country of a law-abiding citizen having guns, using them for lawful purposes, teaching their kids how to hunt, target shooting, is as old as this republic itself, and it's not something anybody wants to disturb. Echoing the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>'s words, <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said: `` Everybody knows ultimately the problem is n't the gun, the problem is the gun in the wrong hands. `` But it seems to me reasonable measures can be found and taken in this effort which do n't deprive or interfere with that good and decent practice of people enjoying their firearms in lawful ways and yet respond and speak appropriately to this escalation, this arms race in the cities that police have spoken about so eloquently. Clearly there's a large middle ground there.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Cheney Bjt   03-18 0612</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cheney, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cheney Goes to Work as Defense Secretary</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> congressman <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> was sworn in as the nation's 17th secretary of defense after a unanimous <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> endorsement that one Republican complained may have been too swift. <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> won <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation Friday on a 92-0 vote, just one day after the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> gave him its unanimous blessing. Shortly after Friday's vote, <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> resigned as <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>'s sole congressmen and then was sworn in as defense chief during a private ceremony in his Capitol Hill office. A large, formal oath-taking ceremony was scheduled for next Tuesday. Later in the afternoon Friday, <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> traveled to his new Pentagon office where he met with <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwood </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> executive who has been nominated to become deputy defense secretary, and with several <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration holdovers for briefings. Officials said <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> would probably work at least part of the weekend trying to get settled in. <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>'s elevation to the defense post finally completed formation of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s Cabinet, a process slowed by the bruising fight over the president's first choice for <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> secretary, former <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON>. Tower was rejected by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, 53-47, on March 9 after weeks of controversy over his personal life, drinking habits and consulting work for large defense contractors. <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> was sworn into office by <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON>, director of administration and management in the office of <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> secretary. Present were his wife, <PERSON> Lynne </PERSON>, their two daughters, <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>, and his parents, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> and <PERSON> Marge </PERSON>. `` I am proud to have the opportunity to serve the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the nation as secretary of defense,'' <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> said. `` But at the same time, I will miss the House. And more than anything, I regret that I must step down after representing the state of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> for 10 years.'' The rancor surrounding the Tower nomination was largely absent when the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> moved quickly this week on <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION>, although some bitterness remained. Sen. <PERSON> Arlen </PERSON> <PERSON> Specter </PERSON>, R-Pa., complained the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> had `` rushed to judgment'' on <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION> after the dispute over Tower and with a two-week recess looming `` There's hardly been a chance for people to find out about Congressman <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>'s nomination in the press, media, to sit down and write a letter and have it delivered,'' <PERSON> Specter </PERSON> said. `` I think we're correct and I'm prepared to vote for Congressman <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>, but I do think this timetable ought not set a precedent.'' Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, top Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, denied <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> was put on a fast track, noting that because he was a congressman, his financial records were already on file. In addition, <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> said, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> expedited its background check. Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., the committee chairman, later responded more pointedly, saying: `` I gather what he -LRB- Specter -RRB- wanted us to do was to wait for the rumor and innuendo to come in. <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> led the fight to kill the Tower nomination and came under harsh criticism for his handling of the proceedings. The <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> Democrat used his time on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor to defend the committee's process <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said he and Sen. <PERSON> Malcom </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallop </PERSON>, both Republicans, felt a mixture of pride and sadness because their state's congressional delegation was losing a man of `` distinction and honor and rare political savvy.'' A special election will be held in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> to fill the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> seat vacated by <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>. Senators not present for the vote on <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION> were <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>, R-Colo.; <PERSON> Rudy </PERSON> <PERSON> Boschwitz </PERSON>, R-Minn.; <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> <PERSON> Garn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON>, R-Pa.; <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON>, R-Vt.; <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanford </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.C. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> James </PERSON>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0231EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChildDeath     03-18 0264</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Child Death,0271</SECOND>
<HEAD>11-Year-Old Confesses To Killing Baby Brother, Resented Caring For
Him</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WILTON MANORS, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An 11-year-old girl who confessed killing her 2-year-old half-brother and trying to kill her 15-month-old half-sister apparently resented caring for them, police said. `` Apparently the mother had to work a lot of double shifts and -LRB- the 11-year-old -RRB- was in charge of feeding the baby, clothing them, taking care of them as an adult would and she's only 11 years old,'' said police Sgt. <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Wierzbicki </PERSON>. `` We worked with a lot of investigators on this case, and no one can remember a person that young committing such a crime,'' he added. The girl, whose name was not disclosed because of her age, was being held at the <ORGANIZATION> Broward </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Juvenile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> on one count of first-degree murder and one of attempted first-degree murder, police said. <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> figures show three children younger than 10 were arrested in 1986 for murder. In 1987, one child that age was arrested. The children's mother, <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> <PERSON> Butterfield </PERSON>, discovered <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON> dead and <ORGANIZATION> Tiffany </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caesar </ORGANIZATION> unconscious in their beds Tuesday morning. Police said there were no signs of abuse, and tests were done to see if the children had been poisoned. But after the medical examiner determined Thursday night that <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> had been strangled, his half-sister admitted killing the boy and choking <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON> and hitting her on the head, <PERSON> Wierzbicki </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON> was listed in critical condition Friday at <ORGANIZATION> Hollywood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Wierzbicki </PERSON> said the case will be turned over the the <LOCATION> Broward </LOCATION> state attorney's office next week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0231EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SteelImports     03-18 0448</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Steel Imports,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senators Call for End to Quotas</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Twenty-one senators have lined up against their steel-state colleagues and called on President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to end steel import quotas covering 19 nations and the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>. The senators said in a letter Friday to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> that the restraints have driven up steel prices and caused product shortages. They said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> needed `` a sensible steel policy'' that considered not just steelmakers, but other producers, too. The senators, 18 of them <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION>, face stiff opposition. Fifty-five other senators, many of them from steel-producing states, have signed onto a bill empowering the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration to extend the import curbs beyond their Sept. 30 expiration. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration negotiated five-year, product-by-product `` voluntary restraint agreements'' in 1984 with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> and other nations to limit the flow of foreign steel into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Three days before last November's election, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> pledged to continue the restraints in some form. But with the steel industry newly profitable, opponents of the curbs _ led by a coalition of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> manufacturers _ believe they can make a case for ending the program, or at least narrowing its scope. Manufacturers of home appliances, construction and farm machinery, industrial equipment, auto parts and other products all rely on steel as a raw material, said the letter to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` In the experience of many of these manufacturers, steel voluntary restraint agreements have caused higher prices and shortages of some steel products, and are undermining their ability to compete in international markets,'' the letter said. `` It is important that steel trade be considered from the perspective of all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> manufacturers, not just the steel industry alone,'' it said. The senators invited <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to work with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to end the `` burden'' of the quotas. But Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON>, R-Pa., a leading advocate of continued restraints, said through a spokesman Friday that the conditions that compelled steel firms to seek government aid in 1984 remain `` There are still some senators who keep their heads in the sand when it comes to the fact that countries have not discontinued their unfair trading practices of dumping and subsidies,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryers </PERSON>, legislative director for <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON>. Signing the letter to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> were Sens. <PERSON> Brock </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, D-Wash.; <PERSON> Rudy </PERSON> <PERSON> Boschwitz </PERSON>, R-Minn.; <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>,; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-R.I. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Thad </PERSON> <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON>, R-Miss.; <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, D-Calif.; <PERSON> Slade </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorton </PERSON>, R-Wash.; <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, R-Ore.; <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kassebaum </PERSON>, R-Kan.; <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON>, R-Wis.; <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, D-Wis.; <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Fla </LOCATION>.; <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McClure </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Idaho </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON>, R-Ore.; <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Pressler </PERSON>,; <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Symms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Idaho </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallop </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wyo </LOCATION>.; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>.; and <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, R-Calif
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Eastern-Congress     03-18 0493</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Eastern-Congress,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bills Aiding Striking Eastern Workers Bogged Down</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Leaders of <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airline </ORGANIZATION>'s striking unions are shrugging off their inability to prompt <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to quickly produce legislation aimed at helping the thousands of picketers. The two bills that the carrier's workers are pinning their hopes on both bogged down on Friday _ at least temporarily _ as the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> began its two-week Easter recess. Union leaders said the delay would not be overly harmful to strikers, who began their third week of picketing today. Labor leaders said they are relying more heavily on two other strategies: working in the bankruptcy courts, and seeking a buyer for the grounded airline. `` We never indicated to any of our members that these bills were a panacea, they would be passed quickly, or anything like that,'' <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Winpisinger </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION>, said in an interview. `` We told our pilots up front that things in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> would go quickly but the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> would be an uphill fight,'' said <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Duffy </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. The Eastern strike began when the airline's 8,500 machinists walked off their jobs in a wage and benefit dispute and were followed by the carrier's pilots and flight attendants. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democrats scheduled a vote for April 5 _ the chamber's second post-Easter day of business _ on whether to allow consideration of a bill that would hand the government a role in ending the walkout Republicans have so far blocked action on the measure, which would compel President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to name a special board to recommend a way to end the strike. At the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, officials of <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s parent company, <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, voiced opposition to a measure that would up the ante for management. The bill, introduced by Sen. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, would allow <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s creditors access to the assets of <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION>, which also owns <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>. Eastern filed for protection from its creditors under the federal bankruptcy code on March 9. <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION>'s associate general counsel, <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Seiden </PERSON>, told the panel that the bill would be `` unfair, oppressive and unconstitutional'' and would have dangerous repercussions throughout the airline industry. `` In the future, no corporation could or would consider acquiring a troubled airline, or starting a new airline ... because the risk of failing could not be confined to the new venture itself,'' <PERSON> Seiden </PERSON> told the senators. Both bills are considered long shots for enactment into law. Administration officials have threatened a veto of the emergency board bill. The bankruptcy revision measure has been questioned by several lawmakers, including Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, D-Del., chairman of the judiciary panel, who said Friday that he wants to study how the proposal would effect other airlines Union leaders and their <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> supporters have sought action on the bills anyway, arguing that their efforts would at the very least be good for strikers' morale.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0234EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-EnergySecurity     03-18 0560</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Energy Security,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Says Loss of Oil Imports Would Cause no Shortage</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> energy system could handling a sudden and sustained loss of oil imports without suffering shortages of gasoline and other refined oil products, although prices might jump, a government-sponsored study has concluded. The study by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, an advisory group to the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, said the key to managing an import cutoff is quick action by the government to tap into the <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION>'s underground oil stocks. In the event of a loss of oil imports equal to 3 million barrels a day _ representing about 40 percent of last year's average import rate _ the strategic reserves in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> could be used to meet most of the shortfall, according to a draft of the study provided Friday to The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The study assumed the imported oil would be cut off for three months. The strategic reserves currently hold about 555 million barrels of crude oil. The system was created by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1975 in response to the Arab oil embargo that year. The study made no firm predictions about price increases resulting from a supply emergency, but <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lichtblau </PERSON>, a private energy expert who helped compile the draft report, said in an interview that prices would be expected to rise sharply even if the oil transport system succeeded in averting shortages. `` The possibility of a price explosion as an instant reaction in such a volatile situation is highly likely,'' said <PERSON> Lichtblau </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>. He said it was impossible to predict how high prices would go. Energy industry officials and many on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> have voiced increasing alarm in recent weeks at a trend toward rapidly growing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dependence on foreign oil. Imports last year equaled 42 percent of supply, up from 31 percent in 1985. This trend is linked to a drop in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> oil output and rising consumption. The concern has fueled an oil industry drive to win congressional approval to drill for oil in the <ORGANIZATION> Arctic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refugee </ORGANIZATION> in northern <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and off the shores of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, where prospects for discoveries are considered good. Some energy executives also have cited the import trend as a reason for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to approve an import fee on oil and for providing new tax breaks for oil drillers. The study on how the nation's oil transportation system would respond to supply emergencies was requested by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> in February 1987 while he was energy secretary. Final conclusions are to be presented to Energy Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> in mid-April, said <PERSON> Carla </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, a petroleum council spokeswoman. The draft report cites three main reasons why even a severe disruption of oil supplies would not cause a shortage of petroleum products: the large amounts of oil in transit on ocean tankers, barges and in pipelines; a more flexible and efficient oil refining and transport system; and the availability of strategic reserves. The study also said the energy system could cope with a shutdown of the Trans-Alaska Pipeline System for 30 days without causing shortages of gasoline or other products. The pipeline carries oil from the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Slope </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> to the port of <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION> for shipment to the lower 48 states, <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0235EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-ForeignAgents     03-18 0566</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Foreign Agents,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senators Keep PAC Money They Claim is Tainted</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD L. VERNACI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> senators say they'll keep $ 8,000 in campaign contributions from an imported-car dealers' group, even though both complained the organization is a foreign agent forbidden to make such payments. Although the <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dealers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drivers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> PAC </ORGANIZATION> gave $ 5,000 to Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and $ 3,000 to Sen. <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Reid </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> last year, it also spent nearly $ 1 million to defeat them and Sen. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Nev </LOCATION>. Those three senators, along with Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., signed a letter to the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> asking it to investigate whether the PAC ought to be registered as a foreign If the organization were found to be a foreign agent operating with foreign funds, spending that money to influence an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> election would be illegal. Nevertheless, neither <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Reid </PERSON> plan to give the money back unless the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> tells them to do so, their spokesmen said. `` I mean these guys are hypocrites,'' <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Nemet </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> PAC </ORGANIZATION>, said Friday. `` They asked us for money to support them.'' <PERSON> Nemet </PERSON> and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Glacken </PERSON>, the imported-auto dealer <ORGANIZATION> PAC </ORGANIZATION>'s executive director, deny they're working for foreigners. The PAC spent nearly $ 2.6 million last year on <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> elections. Of that total, about 83 percent was spent to help Republican candidates, according to figures compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Nemet </PERSON> and <PERSON> Glacken </PERSON> said in a telephone interview from their office in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> that <PERSON> Reid </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> are trying to get even because the group spent large amounts of money against them. <PERSON> Nemet </PERSON> and <PERSON> Glacken </PERSON> said the organization's funding comes entirely from American citizens. <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Neal </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON>, acknowledged that <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> was `` not thrilled'' that the PAC spent more than half a million dollars against him. <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>, a spokesman for <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, said the Senator would wait to see what the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> decides. <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Varoga </PERSON>, spokesman for <PERSON> Reid </PERSON>, said only that the senator does not plan to give back any money. <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, who has neither been opposed by nor accepted money from the group, signed the letter because his colleagues asked him to and because he is opposed to the role political action committees in general are playing in American politics, said spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Deeken </PERSON>. Under federal law, individuals or firms representing foreign governments, people or companies have to register with the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> as foreign agents and report what activities they have carried out for their clients. While foreign agents could still give money to political campaigns as individual <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> citizens, the law does not permit them to make such contributions in their role as foreign agents. The PAC also paid out big money to help <PERSON> Trent </PERSON> <PERSON> Lott </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallop </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. All three of those Republicans won their <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> elections. <PERSON> Lott </PERSON> had $ 319,126 spent on his behalf by the <ORGANIZATION> PAC </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> received a $ 10,000 contribution and had another $ 326,050 spent for him, and Wallop got a $ 4,000 contribution with $ 88,862 spent on his behalf, according to the <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION>. The PAC also spent money independently on two <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> races, and the beneficiaries there were Democrats. Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> had $ 80,000 spent independently for him, and Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> got $ 45,000 spent independently on his behalf.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0235EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-CrumblingMonuments     03-18 0564</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crumbling Monuments,0577</SECOND>
<HEAD>Italian Monuments Endangered By Modern Ills And Old Age</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VICTOR L. SIMPSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Pavia tower toppled, the Tower of <LOCATION> Pisa </LOCATION> is leaning further than ever and dozens of other artworks have been shrouded in scaffolding or turned over to restorers. Modern day damage from traffic and pollution and simple old age are exacting a heavy toll on some of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s most famous monuments. The collapse on Friday of the 255-foot medieval tower in the northern city of <LOCATION> Pavia </LOCATION> was one of the most dramatic blows to <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s historic patrimony since a bell tower in <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION> toppled 87 years ago But experts say is it symptomatic of the problems afflicting art works in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. `` There has been inadequate regular maintenance and we have reached the absurd, where if an -LRB- art -RRB- superintendent wants to send a letter he's forced to pay for the stamps,'' <PERSON> Franco </PERSON> <PERSON> Piacenti </PERSON>, head of the art section of the government's <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, told a convention on protecting artworks in <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION> Friday. He commented after word of the Pavia collapse reached the experts. Two people were killed and 15 injured when the tower collapsed in <LOCATION> Pavia </LOCATION>, a city founded in 568 by the Longobards, a Germanic tribe, and later home of the Lombard rulers. The tower was 900 years old and possibly suffered damage from heavy rains last August. The architect in charge of monument preservation, however, said the cause was probably the natural decay of the mortar cementing the bricks. `` It's something due to age, which can not be predicted. It's typical of ancient towers,'' said <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonietta </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrate </PERSON> `` It also happened to the bell tower of <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION>.'' In 1902, the 1,000-year-old St. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tower </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION> toppled without warning. A worldwide subscription raised money to build an exact reproduction, which was completed in 1912. <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s most famous tower, the Leaning Tower of <LOCATION> Pisa </LOCATION>, has been judged in danger of collapsing although not in the immediate future. The 800-year-old tower continued to increase its lean last year, according to the annual report recently issued by the group charged with preservation of the marble monument. But <PERSON> Giuseppe </PERSON> <PERSON> Toniolo </PERSON>, head of the group, said he expected it to stand for as long as another two centuries at its current rate of lean. `` The tower is closely watched, very closely watched,'' said <PERSON> Toniolo </PERSON> in a telephone interview. `` Just because one tower falls does n't mean another will.'' The 180-foot marble monument, begun in 1173, began to lean when it was only 34 feet high when the soil underneath it began to give way. Experts have been studying projects to support the tower, while keeping its famous tilt, but no work has begun yet. <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> is the depository of some of the world's greatest artworks but has also had to battle some of the biggest problems caused by the exhaust fumes and the rumbles from the 1.8 million cars in the Italian capital. Experts recently reunited <PERSON> Marcus </PERSON> <PERSON> Aurelius </PERSON> with his horse after an 8-year-long restoration project but have n't decided yet whether to risk new damage by returning it to its place on the Campidoglio Square. The Trevi Fountain sits behind plexiglass, with its waters turned off, as it undergoes cleaning and restoration. But over the past year, other monuments and columns have been reappearing from behind scaffolding as restoration work is completed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0243EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Fruit-Cyanide Bjt   03-18 0693</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fruit-Cyanide, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chilean Fruit to Return to Market under Tougher Inspections</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Chilean fruit could be back in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> stores next week under an intensified inspection plan designed to assure the safety of the produce after traces of cyanide were found in two grapes last week. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration cleared the way Friday for new shipments of Chilean fruit with announcement of an inspection plan that officials said will provide `` maximum feasible safety'' of the fruit and end a week-long health scare. Under the plan, fruit held by importers, wholesalers and retailers in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> `` that can not be practically inspected'' will be destroyed, while fruit at the docks, on ships or awaiting export in <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> will be subjected to heightened inspections, officials said. `` This is a plan that deals with safety and what is maximumly feasible,'' said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, commissioner of the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. Responsibility to see that fruit already in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is destroyed lies with state health departments, <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said. Neither <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> nor representatives of Chilean exporters could give figures on the value of the fruit to be destroyed. <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said questions about who would bear the cost of the lost fruit are also not his to consider. `` I've got to look at safety, I've got to look at the scientific data and I ca n't allow economics or politics to move into those decisions,'' the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> commissioner said. A third poisoning threat was telephoned to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION> on Friday, sometime before the plan was announced in the early afternoon Friday, <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said officials believe the caller may have been the same Spanish-speaking man who made the two earlier threats that prompted the inspections that found the tainted grapes. But, he said, the latest threat raises no more or less concern than the first two. `` We designed this thing with -LRB- the probability of more -RRB- threats in mind,'' he said. About 5 percent of Chilean fruit at <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> docks or in transit to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will be visually inspected, and all suspicious-looking fruit will be subjected to laboratory tests before it is released for sale. In <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>, fruit to be exported will be subject to increased security, inspections and lab tests. The Chilean government and exporters will be responsible for the program there, but an <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> team will be sent to <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> soon to assist and observe their procedures, <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said. He said the plan is `` based on the assumptions of the type of sampling that would be required to have a high confidence of detecting anything if something is there.'' `` It is impossible to assure 100 percent safety,'' without checking every piece of fruit, he said. Chilean grapes, which make up the bulk of grapes on sale this time of year, and other fruit could be back on the shelves of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> stores in five to nine days, he said. Young said grapes _ which constitute about 70 percent of <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>'s sales in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> _ raspberries, blueberries, blackberries and strawberries will be the first fruit released because cyanide contamination of them is the easiest to spot since the fruit discolors quickly and becomes mushy But, he cautioned, that `` consumers should inspect all products, regardless of country of origin.'' He said buyers should look for needle marks, any unusual appearance or discoloration or a chemical or ` burned almond' smell. <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said he could not estimate the time for return of the other Chilean fruit exports, including melons, cantaloupes, pears, apples, nectarines, plums and peaches. These larger fruits, if injected with cyanide, could carry higher levels of the poison than the smaller fruits can. <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said the inspections of 13,000 crates of fruit since small amounts of cyanide were found in two seedless red grapes last weekend turned up no additional evidence of contamination. After the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> plan was unveiled, the military government in <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION> announced a package of economic measures to counter the extensive damage to the Chilean fruit industry. Chilean Foreign Minister <PERSON> Hernan </PERSON> <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON> <PERSON> Errazuriz </PERSON>, who met in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Friday with Vice President <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, called the plan a `` workable solution.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0304EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Flight103-Skinner     03-18 0608</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Flight 103-Skinner,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Skinner Sending Aides to Europe for Flight 103 Probe</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Flight 103 Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Transportation Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> says he is sending top aides to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> this weekend to look into the safety of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airlines and new allegations about warnings of terrorist attack before the bombing of Flight 103. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> said Friday his action was prompted by a meeting with relatives of some of the 270 people killed in the Dec. 21 disaster over <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> and by the controversy erupting in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> over specific threats before the bombing. In addition to dispatching members of his personal staff, <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> said he planned to visit <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> himself next month in an effort to get a united approach to the threat of sky terrorism and find out more about the bombing and the warnings. The secretary said in a speech that his meeting with relatives of some of the people killed in the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> explosion convinced him he must get directly involved in issues surrounding the bombing. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> said the relatives introduced themselves one by one, using the names of loved ones killed in the crash. `` It was one of the most moving meetings I think I have ever had ... You were literally speechless,'' he said. <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Ammerman </PERSON>, a victim's relative who attended the meeting, praised <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> for meeting with about 20 families but said he is angry that the government has done so little to prevent further terrorist attacks or warn passengers. He said neither former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> nor President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has sent even a note of condolence to any of the families, while at least two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> victims' families received sympathy notes from <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>. `` If we'd won the Super Bowl, we'd have been in the Rose Garden. But if you get people blown out of the air, that's not important enough,'' said <PERSON> Ammerman </PERSON>, whose brother was killed in the bombing. A group of Flight 103 victims' relatives proposes that the government set up a telephone number passengers can call to see if there are threats against a flight they are planning to take. Officials in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> disclosed that a bomb warning, including a photograph of a radio-cassette bomb of the type investigators believe was used, was dated two days before the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> 747 was destroyed but did not reach the airlines until several days later. Both British authorities and the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> had described such a bomb in security warnings a month earlier, airline and government officials said. The West German intelligence agency said it sent a memo about the possibility of such a bomb to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airlines even earlier, on Nov. 10. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> said he was trying to get more details on the warning and how they were handled. `` Let me tell you I do n't know everything,'' he said. `` Yesterday I learned some things for the first time, and I think the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> did, about some disclosures in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> as well as some possible disclosures to <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION> airlines.'' Meanwhile, Sen. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, chairman of a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> transportation subcommittee, introduced a resolution urging <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to appoint a commission to investigate the bombing. `` The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> specifically warned that the explosive device might evade detection by X-ray machines,'' <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON> said in a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> speech. `` We need to know what <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> and other airlines did, if anything, in response to these warnings.'' <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON> attempted to get floor passage of his resolution, but Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, the deputy Republican leader, said it should go through the committee hearing process first.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0305EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DC-Curfew     03-18 0352</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-DC-Curfew,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Barry Says ACLU ``Out of Touch'' in Curfew Opposition</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD KEIL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A lawsuit by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> challenging an emergency curfew for teen-agers in the nation's capital shows the organization has lost touch with the reality of drugs and violence, Mayor <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> says <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> commented Friday after the local <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> chapter asked a federal court to declare the <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>'s 90-day law unconstitutional and issue an injunction blocking enforcement. Backers say the law is intended to help fight drugs in the nation's capital by keeping people under 18 off city streets late at night and early in the morning and thus away from the often violent open-air drug markets. The class-action suit, filed in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on behalf of the parents of five teen-agers, a 12-year-old boy and three other people, says the curfew violates constitutional protection of freedom of speech and association. The law also is flawed because it forces young adults to carry adequate identification and display it to police on request, and discriminates `` irrationally'' between people under and over age 18. But <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> countered: `` The <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> lawyers do n't live in these neighborhoods where you ca n't sleep at night because gunshots, killings are going on. They do n't live in communities where drugs are being used or sold. They're out of touch with reality.'' The emergency law went into effect Thursday. Enforcement will start on Monday, the mayor said. The measure generally requires people under age 18 to be off the streets by 11 p.m. during the week and by midnight on weekends. The curfew ends daily at 6 a.m. The suit said one of the plaintiffs is a 17-year-old girl, <PERSON> Simbi </PERSON> <PERSON> Waters </PERSON>, an actress attending art school who would need to be out after midnight if she gets the part in a play for which she is now auditioning. Another plaintiff, 17-year-old <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Dranitzke </PERSON>, is a student council president who attends senior class dinners at night about twice a month and who says the senior prom this spring will last well past midnight.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CivilRights-Apache     03-18 0433</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Civil Rights-Apache,0442</SECOND>
<HEAD>Commissioner Rebuked Over Visit to Indian Reservation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> demanded Friday that its chairman apologize for his actions on an Indian reservation in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> last month, according to a published report. The chairman, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, went to the White Mountain Apache Reservation on Feb. 7 to look into a custody dispute involving a 14-year-old girl. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, a psychologist and a television crew interviewed the girl, outraging tribal authorities who called the incident an invasion of sovereignty. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Saturday editions that the commission rebuked <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> during a closed meeting Friday, and ordered him to write letters of apology to all involved. One member of the commission who attended the meeting said <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> acknowledged he had exercised bad judgment, The Times reported. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> has said he went to the reservation because he wanted first-hand knowledge of whether the girl, <PERSON> Lalita </PERSON> <PERSON> Altaha </PERSON>, had had a chance to express her own wishes in the custody dispute. The girl was adopted as an infant by a white couple, <PERSON> Nadine </PERSON> and <PERSON> Normand </PERSON> <PERSON> Desrochers </PERSON>, but last year a court ordered that she be returned to her natural mother, <PERSON> Thurza </PERSON> <PERSON> Altaha </PERSON>, who lives on the White Mountain reservation. According to The Times' account, <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> learned of the case from psychologist <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodfield </PERSON>, who is a consultant to the commission and who also had advised the <PERSON> Desrochers </PERSON> family. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> told the commission he went to the reservation with Goodfield, two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> marshals and a camera crew which was making a documentary on Indian adoption cases. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> told the commissioners that they approached a school bus on which <PERSON> Lalita </PERSON> was riding and asked for her, and that she agreed to speak with them. They spoke with the girl for about 30 minutes, then drove her in <LOCATION> Goodfield </LOCATION>'s car to her home, where they had a `` tense'' exchange with Mrs. <PERSON> Altaha </PERSON>, <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said. As <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, <PERSON> Goodfield </PERSON> and the others were driving away from the reservation, they were stopped by <LOCATION> Gila </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's deputies at the request of tribal police and deteined for questioning. They were released four or five hours later, said Sheriff <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>. Tribal chairman <PERSON> Reno </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> later called the incident `` an incursion that ... clearly violates the sovereignity'' of the tribe. At the commission's meeting Friday, <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> defended his actions as an attempt to determine how tribal courts handle custody cases. The commission then went into private session and demanded he write letters of apology indicating that his activities were not approved by the commission or condoned by its members, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0236EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     03-18 0947</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0983</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, who is pulling out of <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Webber </PERSON>'s new musical `` Aspects of Love,'' will be replaced by his understudy for the part. <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Colson </PERSON>, an Australian who recently starred in the musical `` Chess,'' will take over <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>'s role and the show will open as planned April 12 at the Prince of <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION> theater, said a spokesman for the production. <PERSON> Colson </PERSON> had been scheduled to take over the <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> part _ the dashing <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Dillingham </PERSON> _ in October. The part of <PERSON> Dillingham </PERSON> is the third-largest in the musical after those of two young romantic leads. But <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, 61, who's probably most famous for his <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> role in the movies, said earlier this week he was having `` terrible nightmares'' about it and felt he lacked musical expertise. His departure came six weeks into rehearsals for the show, which is sold out through December. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Webber </PERSON>'s most recent musical was `` Phantom of the Opera.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BANNING, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Bernie </PERSON> <PERSON> Kopell </PERSON>, who played wise and winsome `` Doc'' <PERSON> Bricker </PERSON> on <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Love Boat,'' suffered minor injuries in a hit-and-run freeway crash. <PERSON> Kopell </PERSON>, 55, and his wife were heading east on Interstate 10, about 25 miles west of <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, when their car tangled with another vehicle, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Highway Patrol Officer <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kopell </PERSON>'s car struck the center divider and flipped. The other car kept going, she said. The actor was taken to <LOCATION> Desert </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> where he was treated and released, a spokeswoman said. <PERSON> Kopell </PERSON>'s wife refused treatment at the crash site, Ms. <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kopell </PERSON> started his acting career with a two-line part in the movie `` The Oregon Trail.'' In 1963, he was signed for the role of <PERSON> Siegfried </PERSON> in `` Get Smart.'' He became <PERSON> Marlo </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>' neighbor on `` That Girl'' and spent three years on `` The Doris Day Show.'' In 1977, <PERSON> Kopell </PERSON> caught `` The Love Boat'' for a television cruise that lasted about a decade.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PROVIDENCE, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, who followed family tradition by entering politics, did it again with a St. Patrick's Day speech to <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>'s Friendly Sons of <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> dinner <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s 21-year-old son who won a seat in the <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> House </LOCATION> last year, invoked his ancestry in both joking and serious ways Friday. He reminded the crowd that his great-grandfather, the legendary <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> `` </PERSON> <PERSON> Honey </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitz </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>, had addressed them in 1910 and that his uncle, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, then a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> senator, had done so in 1959. `` So some of you have probably heard this speech before. Perhaps even twice before,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said that by starting his own career in politics he hoped to rededicate his generation to the ideals of his uncle and great-grandfather. He said he is `` tired of hearing that my generation is the ` me' generation I do not accept that serving others is out of fashion, or that the problems confronting the government are too great.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>AIKEN, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soul singer <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> will not serve a longer jail term despite having drugs in his system during a probation check in December. Circuit Judge <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Peeples </PERSON> revoked a probationary sentence <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> received last July 24 following his conviction for resisting arrest and carrying a pistol. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> could have been ordered to serve a one-year jail term. But <PERSON> Peeples </PERSON> dismissed six months of that sentence and ordered the `` Godfather of Soul'' to serve the remaining time concurrently with a six-year prison term <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> began serving Dec. 29 following his conviction on charges stemming from a Sept. 24 car chase with police from two states. Friday's hearing was ordered after <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, 55, tested positive for marijuana and PCP in violation of his probation for the July case.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mankiewicz </PERSON>, the 80-year-old filmmaker who won four Academy Awards by 1950, is disillusioned with today's <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>. `` And I know _ and I'm very sad _ that <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> film has become, in my opinion, the major motivation for the American being as detested as he is throughout the world,'' <PERSON> Mankiewicz </PERSON> said. `` All they see in American movies is variations on obscenity, boozing and -LRB- sex -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Mankiewicz </PERSON> told reporters Wednesday. On Thursday, <PERSON> Mankiewicz </PERSON> received the 1989 <PERSON> Akira </PERSON> <PERSON> Kurosawa </PERSON> Award for Lifetime Achievement from the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Festival </ORGANIZATION>. He was the fourth recipient, and the first American. <PERSON> Mankiewicz </PERSON> produced `` The <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> Story'' and `` Woman of the Year.'' He won his two Academy Awards _ for best direction and best screenplay _ in 1949 for `` A Letter To Three Wives.'' In 1950, he won the same two Oscars for `` All About Eve.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Version of this item moved on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the president's son, and the group he is leading will buy the <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rangers </ORGANIZATION> baseball team. `` It's very important that the team stays in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has agreed to keep it here in the <ORGANIZATION> Metroplex </ORGANIZATION>,'' said team owner <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON>, who agreed Friday to sell his 58 percent interest in the major-league team Friday. Baseball Commissioner <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Ueberroth </PERSON> helped assemble the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> group last month in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>. The group includes <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> `` Rusty'' Rose of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Rainwater </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> DeWitte </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON>, who declined to give the purchase price, said he chose the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> group because he wanted local ownership and `` because they were the first to come up with an offer that I thought was good.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 42, is an energy consultant for <ORGANIZATION> Harken </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. He is the largest individual stockholder of the company, based in <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> suburb.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0316EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Quayle-Architect     03-18 0223</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle-Architect,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Arrested for Phony Credentials Worked On VP Residence</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> businessman who had been asked by <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> to design renovations for the vice presidential residence was arrested on felony charges of misrepresenting himself as a certified architect. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, 36, was charged after he allegedly fabricated the architect's seal on blueprints for renovation of restrooms in <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, parks, said county police detective <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowell </PERSON>. Police said <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, who was arrested Tuesday, was not a licensed architect but that he allegedly had fake District of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> architect's seals. <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, owner of <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Architects </ORGANIZATION>, refused to comment on Friday, according to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. His attorney, <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Berman </PERSON>, told the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> she would not comment on <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>' arrest or his business dealings <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> has not yet entered a plea in court. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Beckwith </PERSON>, a spokesman for Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> and a former employee met with <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> twice in the weeks before <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> moved into the official vice president's residence. <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> toured the mansion and later submitted applications for the $ 200,000 remodeling plan, said <PERSON> Beckwith </PERSON>. But he was never paid the $ 5,000 fee he was due after submitting blueprints and plans because the <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> found `` problems'' in his security application and seized the plans.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0316EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-RainForests     03-18 0290</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rain Forests,0297</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rock, Jazz Stars, Indians Record Song To Save Rain Forests</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Joni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ringo </PERSON> <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> and <PERSON> Belinda </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlisle </PERSON> have joined a dozen rock stars in recording a song to benefit the world's rain forests, organizers said. The song `` Spirit of the Forest'' is to be released in May and proceeds from its sales will go to rain forest preservation groups, said a statement Friday from <LOCATION> K.A </LOCATION>. Publicity of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. `` A palpable sense of urgency surrounds the ` Spirit of the Forest' campaign,'' said the statement. `` As Third World nations like <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> continue to burn, harvest and plow under the forests for short-term human and corporate gain, the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> faces increasing danger from global greenhouse warming and desertification,'' it said. The global warming trend called the `` greenhouse effect'' is thought to be caused in part by a surfeit of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere. Rain forests absorb carbon dioxide and produce oxygen. The statement said the song was originally written by an environmentalist English band, Gentlemen Without Weapons, for a fund-raising gala last autumn organized by Friends of the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> U.K. </LOCATION> Two recording sessions _ in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> _ have been completed and three others _ in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Janeiro </LOCATION> and in an <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> rain forest _ are scheduled in April, the statement said. Joining <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> of the Beach Boys, ex-Beatle <PERSON> Starr </PERSON>, Ms. <PERSON> Carlisle </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> will be <PERSON> Mick </PERSON> <PERSON> Fleetwood </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Fleetwood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mac </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilmour </PERSON> of <PERSON> Pink </PERSON> <PERSON> Floyd </PERSON>, Was Not Was and <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Dolby </PERSON>. As well, <ORGANIZATION> Amazon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION> from the <LOCATION> Tukano </LOCATION> tribe, <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION> from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, and Japanese and Soviet musicians would join in the singing. It did not name the Japanese or Soviet participants.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0317EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtoninBrief     03-18 0525</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington in Brief,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Fails to Extend AZT Program</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has failed to extend a program that provides the drug AZT to victims of AIDS who can not afford the costly treatment, virtually assuring that the program will expire March 31. A bill sponsored by Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., sought to redirect $ 5 million in federal AIDS research funds to the AZT program for use through September But three senators objected to <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s request on Friday that the measure be acted on without debate or consideration of amendments. The three critics were not identified. Due to the two-week Easter recess, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will not be back in session for the rest of the month. Currently, some 6,000 to 7,000 AIDS victims are receiving AZT under the program.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>Child Safety Seats Recalled</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 1.5 million <ORGANIZATION> Fisher-Price </ORGANIZATION> car safety seats for children are being recalled by the manufacturer because they do not meet federal flammability standards. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Traffic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> said on Friday that the company's own tests prompted the recall of the seats, which are Models 9100 and 9101 manufactured from 1985 to 1989. The company discovered the foam seat pad used in the two models burns faster than federal standards permit, <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> said. Since the pad cover does meet standards, motorists should continue to use the seats until they get replacement pads, and should not return them to stores, the agency said. Owners of the affected seats may call a <ORGANIZATION> Fisher-Price </ORGANIZATION> hotline, 800-334-5439, for instructions.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>Senate Confirms Eagleburger for State Department Post</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has confirmed President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s selection of <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> for deputy secretary of state <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s nomination of <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> for the No. 2 post at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> was approved by voice vote on Friday shortly after the senators confirmed <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> for secretary of defense. The choice of <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> had been approved a day earlier by the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, 19-0. That tally even included the vote of Sen. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>, who spent two days questioning the nominee's business relations with former Secretary of State <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>Honeybee Quarantine Imposed to Combat Mite</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is imposing a federal quarantine affecting 19 states and other areas to help stop the spread of tiny parasitic mites that threaten the honeybee industry. Officials said the proposed quarantine would also be effective in the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> and 15 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> territories or other possessions known or believed to be infested with the <LOCATION> Varroa </LOCATION> mite. `` We are proposing to quarantine all ` states' where Varroa mites are known to occur,'' <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Strating </PERSON>, acting administrator of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inspection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said Friday. States listed in the proposal, which was announced on Thursday, include: <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. Other areas include: <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Samoa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Baker </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Guam </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Howland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jarvis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> <PERSON> Atoll </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Kingman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reef </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Midway </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Navassa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mariana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Palmyra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Atoll </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palau </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0320EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Thailand-Accident     03-18 0112</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Thailand-Accident,0115</SECOND>
<HEAD>10 Killed In Road Collision Outside Bangkok</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A pickup truck carrying tourists collided with a truck about 120 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>, killing 10 people, police said today. The accident occurred Friday as the passengers in the pickup truck were returning from a sightseeing trip in <LOCATION> Rayong </LOCATION> on the Gulf of <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, said Sub. Lt. <PERSON> Pumin </PERSON> <PERSON> Singhasut </PERSON>. <PERSON> Pumin </PERSON> said nine of the dead were in the pickup truck and that the 10th victim was a woman who was buying goods near the scene of the crash. Cause of the crash was not immediately known. <PERSON> Pumin </PERSON> said the driver of the 10-wheel truck fled the scene.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0254EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EnolaGay Bjt   03-18 0610</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Enola Gay, Bjt,0627</SECOND>
<HEAD>Museum Effort For World War II Bomber Under Way</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto XSIL1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEB RIECHMANN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SILVER HILL, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Enola Gay, the steel-gray bomber that effectively ended World War II, today sits in a warehouse without wings or engines, belying its fame as the B-29 that carried the first atomic weapon. Restoration experts are taking the plane apart bolt by bolt in a nine-year project to turn the grimy aircraft into a shiny relic for the <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> and Space Museum. When the plane is displayed in 1994, the exhibit likely will renew debate about <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s use of the atomic bomb. It was early in the morning on Aug. 6, 1945, when the first atomic bomb was released over <LOCATION> Hiroshima </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, killing and injuring 160,000 people. A second bomb was later dropped over <LOCATION> Nagasaki </LOCATION>. `` Any time you even bring up the name Enola Gay it rekindles debate,'' said <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON>, a navigator on the historic mission. `` I guess the discussion is always going to be around. It's been 40 some years and there still is n't any conclusion. <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON>, now 68, saw the plane in 1985 when rehabilitation work began at the <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Paul </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> E. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Garber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Preservation </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Restoration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Storage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Facility </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Silver </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, just outside <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. He retired three years ago from <ORGANIZATION> DuPont </ORGANIZATION> and lives in <LOCATION> Novato </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. The Enola Gay's 98-foot-long body sits severed in half at the warehouse. The two pieces sit side by side with various other historical planes and spacecraft. `` We have some -LRB- visitors -RRB- who tell us that this plane saved their life or their uncle's life because it ended the war,'' shop foreman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Horigan </PERSON> said recently. It took nearly three years for <PERSON> Horigan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON> to restore the front section. Earlier this year, technicians began work on the rear section and wings of the plane, which Cmdr. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tibbets </PERSON> named after his mother. Each part is dipped, sprayed or painted with preservatives and waxes, <PERSON> Horigan </PERSON> said. Using photographs, old technical manuals and history books as their guides, the restoration experts plan to remove all markings and decals that were not on the plane the day after the mission. The names and dates of scores of unknown people will be buffed from the plane's aluminum exterior. `` There's lots of graffiti,'' <PERSON> Horigan </PERSON> said. `` Most of it was ` Joe Blow 1950' _ that kind of thing.'' <PERSON> Tibbets </PERSON>' name will be repainted in stenciled military lettering instead of the script-style print added sometime after the flight. `` Enola Gay'' was painted in black, block letters under a cockpit window just hours before the mission. The name will remain, but extra brush strokes on the `` E'' and `` G,'' from a touch-up paint job done later, will be removed, <PERSON> Horigan </PERSON> said. During the restoration work, <PERSON> Horigan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON> found a chisel that had been lost inside the plane when it was being manufactured. They also found an atomic bomb arming pin behind the radio operator's table. The pin apparently was an extra not used on the weapon. A replica of the <LOCATION> Hiroshima </LOCATION> bomb sits in front of the plane. `` There's no evidence of the blast whatsoever -LRB- on the plane -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Horigan </PERSON> said. `` I think they were 10 to 15 miles away when the blast went off.'' After the war, in November 1945, the plane was modified. It returned to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1946 and went into storage for three years in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, then was ferried by <PERSON> Tibbets </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, a storage site for the Smithsonian. It made its last flight Dec. 2, 1953, when it was flown to <ORGANIZATION> Andrews </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0334EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-NewZealand-DrRuth     03-18 0170</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-New Zealand-Dr Ruth,0174</SECOND>
<HEAD>Customs Seizes Books By Dr. Ruth Westheimer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WELLINGTON, New Zealand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Customs officials today seized 4,500 copies of a book by popular American sex therapist Dr. <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Westheimer </PERSON>, saying they may be pornographic. Customs Department spokesman <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Dare </PERSON> said the copies of `` Guide To Sex'' were being held in <LOCATION> Auckland </LOCATION> until the <ORGANIZATION> Indecent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribunal </ORGANIZATION> rules on its acceptability. Dr. <PERSON> Westheimer </PERSON>, host of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> television show and frequent guest on radio programs, is due to visit <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> next week to promote the book, which has sold well in neighboring <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. Known more commonly as `` Dr. <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON>,'' she was stunned by the seizure of the book, said her publicity manager, <PERSON> Jacqui </PERSON> <PERSON> Dimes </PERSON> said. `` She is a really nice person and really cares about what she does,'' Ms. Dimes said, adding that the book is `` far from being pornographic.'' She said publicity about the seizure would help sales if the book is approved. It was not known when the tribunal would make a decision.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0336EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     03-18 0336</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0351</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some graduates wore silly hats and carried balloons to <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s 307th commencement, and one student brought his teddy bear. <PERSON> Reginald </PERSON> <PERSON> Fennell </PERSON> and his fuzzy companion sat in the front row at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arena </ORGANIZATION> Friday, flanked by 1,269 other graduates. `` Today I feel like a little kid,'' said <PERSON> Fennell </PERSON>, an associate professor of health education at <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> as well as a doctoral candidate. <PERSON> Fennell </PERSON> said he never tells anybody his age. He said he carries the bear with him when he teaches. `` My philosophy is to show people how to have a good time without abusing alcohol or drugs,'' he said. `` I'm going to be a kid all my life.'' <PERSON> Fennell </PERSON> credited his former professors with teaching him the importance of combining education with levity. `` Learning has to be fun,'' he said. `` It gets boring by the time you get to college.'' He left the bear on the seat, however, when he went to the podium to receive his diploma.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>JACKSONVILLE BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When police got a call that an otter had been sighted on First Street, they were surprised to find just how weaselly the critter could be. Officer <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Pomeroy </PERSON> and two other officers quickly cornered the furry, bucktoothed animal near City Hall Thursday night and began trying to herd it toward the police garage. But the 3-foot-long, 25-pound otter had a mind of its own. `` He saw the fountain -LRB- at City Hall -RRB- and was in it in no time,'' <PERSON> Pomeroy </PERSON> said. That's when the Police Department called <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Brimm </PERSON>, a wildlife officer with the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Game </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fresh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Brimm </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pomeroy </PERSON> took off their shoes and splashed around in the fountain until they caught the otter. `` They're actually very playful animals,'' <PERSON> Brimm </PERSON> said, `` but they have good-sized teeth.'' The officers put the otter in the Police Department's pet carrier and <PERSON> Brimm </PERSON> took it to the <ORGANIZATION> Intracoastal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Waterway </ORGANIZATION> and set it free.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0337EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Flight103-Families     03-18 0474</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Flight 103-Families,0488</SECOND>
<HEAD>Families of Flight 103 Victims Demand Federal Investigation</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Flight 103, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN LUMSDEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NORTH ADAMS, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The parents of five people killed when a bomb exploded aboard a <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> flight over <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> are demanding that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government investigate the bombing. `` There is an enormous amount of anger and outrage at the way we've been treated by this country's government,'' said <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Primeau </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, mother of 20-year-old twins, <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> and <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Coker </PERSON>, who were among the 270 people killed in the Dec. 21 crash of Flight 103 in <LOCATION> Lockerbie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Primeau </PERSON> joined two families of victims from upstate <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and another family from <PERSON> North </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> at a news conference on Friday. The petition drive was launched in this northwest <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> city because residents have shown concern at the slow progress of the crash investigation, the families said. `` Terrorism and tragedy such as this have never touched this community before,'' said Mayor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, the first to sign the petition. The drive was organized by <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Wrend </PERSON>, who was among the 1,000 mourners at the church service for <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> student on her way home from <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> for Christmas when the plane blew up. `` I'd like to see an outcry from the people so loud that the government ca n't forget this,'' said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> in his first statement since the death of his 23-year-old daughter. The petitions will be distributed throughout the Northeast. Organizers said they hope to get 20,000 signatures by the time they stage a vigil outside the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on April 3. Ms. <PERSON> Primeau </PERSON> and other family members said they suspect the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> knew about the bomb threats but that it remained on the sidelines before and after the crash. `` We're not an investigatory agency,'' <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Consular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said Friday. `` British authorities are investigating the crash and the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> is assisting them.'' `` The investigation is a very lengthy, complicated process. And it's frustrating, which is very difficult for the families. It's understandable,'' she added `` I wish there was something we could do to make things come together more quickly.'' Ms. <PERSON> Primeau </PERSON> said the anger of the families was heightened Friday by a British newspaper report that authorities knew who had bombed the flight. The report from the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION>, dismissed by investigators, has increased their suspicion that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government is withholding information about the bombing, she said. <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> confirmed it had been warned by the West German government Nov. 10 about the kind of radio-cassette player bomb involved. Politicians of the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> accused <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Channon </PERSON> with bungling a warning dated two days before the disaster but not mailed until several days later.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890318-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-18-89 0353EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LongDay'sJourney     03-18 0180</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Long Day's Journey,0184</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yale Press Sells Millionth Copy of Its O'Neill Bestseller</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: RETRANSMITTING to fix cycle designator</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW HAVEN, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
