<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0229EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ImpeachmentAmendment     09-23 0489</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Impeachment Amendment,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senator Wants Supreme Court to Take Over Impeachment Trials</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lawmakers who have been tied up by the impeachment trials of three federal judges in as many years are calling for a change in the Constitution to hand such trials to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. Sen. <PERSON> Wyche </PERSON> <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON>, D-Ga., chairman of the 12-member trial committee that heard the case of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> earlier this month, said Friday that he would propose a constitutional amendment to relieve <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> of its impeachment duties `` They ought to be the ultimate triers of fact,'' <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON> said of the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> justices. `` They are the most qualified. They have the constitutional perspective on both the protections and sensitivity of federal judgeships,'' he said. He said the justices also have more time for the lengthy process required to remove judges from the federal bench. The amendment would pertain only to the federal judiciary, leaving the trial of other public officials impeached by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON>, who said he would sponsor the proposal with Sen. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Moynihan </PERSON>, D-N.Y. An impeachment voted by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> serves as an indictment for trial before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. A two-thirds vote of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is required to then remove an official from office and disqualify the person from holding other federal office. There only have been 15 impeachments by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> sent to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> for trial in the 200-year history of the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, but three of them have been in the last three years and all of the last three were federal judges. <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON> said he spent all of August studying the <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> case prior to the four-day trial before his special 12-member committee earlier this month. The full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is expected to take no less than two days to hear the case, debate and vote. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> hearings in the impeachment case against <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Alcee </PERSON> <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> took four weeks last summer and are awaiting action by the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The impeachment and trial of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> in 1986 took the committee 10 days to hear and the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> 18 hours to consider before voting to remove <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> from office. According to Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan., who was majority leader at the time, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor proceedings took more time than all but a handful of major issues before the 98th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> Under the Constitution, the federal judges are appointed for life and can be removed from office only by voluntary resignation, death or trial by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON>'s plan for a constitutional amendment is not the first call for a change in the discipline of federal judges. Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kastenmeier </PERSON>, D-Wis., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on courts, intellectual property and the administration of justice, has proposed strengthening federal laws governing the judges and setting up a commission to study the impeachment process
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0229EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Crack     09-23 0519</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Crack,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Defends Arranged Crack Sale for Drug Speech</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says it does n't really matter that a drug dealer was coaxed into selling crack cocaine near the White House _ just so the president could tell the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people that's where the sale took place. `` The man went there and sold drugs in front of the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, did n't he?'' the president told reporters in <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> on Friday. `` That's the bottom line. That's what the man did.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s press secretary, <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, and the <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> concede the drug dealer was maneuvered into making a previously arranged sale in <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, across the street from the White House. The president displayed the cocaine in a see-through plastic bag in his nationally televised drug strategy speech on Sept. 5. He told the audience the crack had been `` seized a few days ago in a park across the street from the White House.'' A Democratic senator from <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Breaux </PERSON>, criticized the president's use of the prop as `` staged.'' `` Is this really a drug war, or is this theatrics and screenplay?'' he asked. `` We do n't need the president to lure drug pushers to <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> for photo opportunities.'' And a reporter suggested to the president that the transaction would n't have taken place in the park had the cocaine not been needed for the speech. `` The message I get out of it -LRB- is -RRB- a man was busted in front of the White House and I can not feel sorry for him,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` He ought not to be out peddling these insidious drugs. It's ruining the children of this country.'' The president said he'd asked for a drug sample `` from that vicinity to show it can happen anywhere ... and that's what they gave me. And they told me where they caught this guy.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spoke as if the suspected dealer, a teenager, had been arrested. Although the transaction with an undercover <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> agent was photographed, the dealer was not taken into custody, agents said, because they hoped he would sell a larger amount later and identify his organization. A planned arrest earlier this week fell through when the suspect did not show up, and agents hope to obtain indictments against him. Asked if the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people were manipulated into thinking drugs were being sold near the White House, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> replied: `` What do you mean it did n't really -LRB- happen -RRB-? The guy was arrested or grabbed for selling drugs in front of the White House. It did n't exist? It did n't happen?'' On every drug bust, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` You bring somebody someplace.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> became irritated with reporters' questions, gesturing toward the press at one point and saying, `` I do n't understand. Are these advocates here for this drug guy?'' But while <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> defended the arrangement, another senior <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> official suggested the <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> had been `` a little overzealous.'' `` We told them that if a buy could be made near the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, so much the better. They took us literally,'' said the official, asking not to be identified.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0254EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Frank     09-23 0437</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Frank,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congressman Apologizes for Dealing With Prostitute</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> is offering an apology to political supporters and assuring them that `` my judgment has improved'' since his involvement with a male prostitute. `` I made some serious mistakes in judgment several years ago. What I did was wrong,'' the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Democrat, said in a letter mailed Friday to home-state supporters and volunteers in his previous campaigns for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` It did not affect my public decisions or any public business,'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> wrote. `` But I regret that some of my past personal actions are troubling to people who placed their confidence in me.'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> also drew some Republican support Friday for his decision not to resign while awaiting an inquiry by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee into his 18-month relationship with <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON>. `` He deserves a fair hearing,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Newt </PERSON> <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, the House Republican whip. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, who is under investigation by the ethics committee over his personal finances in a book deal, told reporters it was appropriate for <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> to await the panel's findings. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> is a five-term congressman and outspoken liberal who was re-elected overwhelmingly in 1988 after disclosing the year before that he is homosexual. <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> has charged he operated a prostitution ring out of <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s Capitol Hill apartment <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> has acknowledged paying <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> for sex and then hiring him as a personal assistant and driver, but says he threw <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> out when he learned of the prostitution operation. That was shortly before <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> publicly disclosed he is homosexual. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, in his letter, said the pressure of hiding his homosexuality while maintaining a political life led him to deal with the prostitute. `` Dealing with being gay, while continuing to meet my public obligations, created tremendous internal pressures,'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> wrote. `` Those pressures ended when I spoke publicly about my own personal identity. Not coincidentally, my judgment has improved since then.'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said that as a result of being in public life, `` I can not be surprised that my mistakes in personal judgment of several years ago have now become public knowledge.'' But he said that `` some highly sensationalized stories'' about the matter have included `` substantial untruths.'' `` It was to end any question about what is the truth that I asked the ethics committee of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to consider this entire matter,'' he wrote. `` I need hardly tell you that this committee will have my full cooperation. Meanwhile, I hope you will accept my apology.'' Aides to <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said the letter was widely distributed to veteran supporters, and was not mailed at government expense.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0255EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ArtsNominee     09-23 0323</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Arts Nominee,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Endowment Nominee Opposes Helms Amendment</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s choice to lead the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endowment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> says a measure by Sen. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> to stop federal funding of sexually explicit or blasphemous art would cripple the government's role in promoting artistic excellence. `` Making unfettered artistic judgments would be most difficult under the <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> amendment,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Frohnmayer </PERSON> told a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committee considering his nomination. `` I think we need freedom ... and tolerance ... for art to flourish,'' the <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, lawyer told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Friday. The arts agency is at the center of a political storm resulting from the use of federal money in exhibits that included works by artists <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mapplethorpe </PERSON> and <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Serrano </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mapplethorpe </PERSON>'s photographs depict explicit homosexual acts and <PERSON> Serrano </PERSON> displayed a work showing a crucifix submerged in a jar of urine The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in July adopted an amendment by <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>, that would prohibit the agency from using any of its $ 170 million in annual appropriations to promote, distribute or produce `` obscene and indecent materials'' or art that denigrates the beliefs of any religion. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted against <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>' measure 264-153 last week after endowment defenders complained it would establish a broad pattern of censorship that would destroy the agency's credibility in the arts community. The endowment uses panels of experts to award subsidies each year to artists. `` I do not believe in funding obscene art,'' <PERSON> Frohnmayer </PERSON> said. But, he added, `` I would certainly hate to see the whole structure change because of some grants which are controversial.'' A one-time divinity student with a graduate degree in Christian ethics from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Frohnmayer </PERSON> encountered no opposition to his confirmation from members of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committee. If approved by the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, he would replace <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Southern </PERSON>, who has been named general manager of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Metropolitan Opera.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0256EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SleepingDrug     09-23 0597</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sleeping Drug,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>FDA Panel Suggests Stronger Warnings on Sleep-Drug Side Effects</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal advisory committee says the world's leading sleep medication, Halcion, may put users at greater risk of temporary amnesia than other drugs of its kind <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> panel recommended Friday that the warning be added to Halcion's label and that stronger warnings be given to consumers and doctors about all possible side effects for this drug and other sedative-hypnotics, which are sold only by prescription. The <ORGANIZATION> Psychopharmacological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drugs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> asked the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> to work out the language of the warnings. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Leber </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION>'s division of neuropharmacological drug products, said it would be at least six months before the agency would complete work on the warnings. `` There's no sense of urgency on this,'' he said. <PERSON> Godfrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Upjohn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which makes Halcion, said the committee's review should put to rest many concerns that have been raised about the drug. The recommendations resulted from the committee's review of a `` relatively high'' number of reports about side effects associated with the use of Halcion compared with other sedative-hypnotics. These included amnesia, anxiety, aggression and hallucinations, all of which are included in the warning label for Halcion. Panel members said the high number of reactions reported may be overstated, since incomplete data on incidents was collected and it can be used only as a broad indicator. `` Given the limitations of the information, we did not sense there was a special problem'' of side effects with Halcion, said Dr. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>, panel chairman and chief of psychiatric research and psychopharmacology at the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>. Halcion was approved for sale in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1983 and about 43 million prescriptions of the drug have been written since then The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> has received 1,693 reports of adverse side effects possibly associated with its use, ranging from amnesia to death, said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Anello </PERSON>, deputy director of the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION>'s office of epidemiology and biostatistics. By comparison, 35 million prescriptions have been written for Restoril, a sedative-hypnotic made by <ORGANIZATION> Sandoz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pharmaceuticals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, since 1981 and the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> has received 266 reports of unwanted side effects, he said. Officials of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Upjohn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which makes Halcion, said the greater number of Halcion reports could be the result of a number of things, including media reports about the drug. These include reports about a <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> woman shot her mother last year after taking Halcion. Charges against the woman were dismissed. <ORGANIZATION> Upjohn </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> said the company was `` pleased the advisory committee has essentially come to the conclusion that there are few if any concerns that need to be addressed.'' Besides agreeing to recommend relabeling for Halcion for temporary amnesia, the panel decided to address concerns for the entire class of sleeping pills. Three drugs are included in this class _ Halcion, Restoril and Dalmane. Panel members asked the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> to `` provide material to consumers to alert them to the possibility of side effects'' of the drugs so the consumers could discuss them with their doctors. Committee members said they were concerned about `` traveler's amnesia'' _ a temporary syndrome that can affect travelers who take one of the drugs They can function normally after awakening but later wo n't recall their activities during this period, such as going through Customs at the airport. The labels for these drugs already warn of amnesia as a possible side effect, but the committee recommended the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> consider adding `` traveler's amnesia'' to the labels.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0257EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Hugo-Pentagon     09-23 0448</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hugo-Pentagon,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Navy Cleaning Up ``Catastrophic'' Hurricane Damage</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Hugo Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> crews are beginning to clean up `` catastrophic levels of damage'' at the <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> and sweep wreckage at other bases and military ships that were caught in the path of Hurricane Hugo. No serious injuries were reported at several bases along the eastern seaboard, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said Friday, but two firefighters at the <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> base sustained minor injuries. A nuclear attack submarine was knocked from its moorings in the <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> harbor and a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> destroyer was sideswiped by a barge tossed in the waves whipped by the hurricane's winds. <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> treated the military installations no differently from the rest of the ravaged <LOCATION> Carolinas </LOCATION>, ripping apart poles with power lines and wiping out power and communications at facilities. The information from the <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> base, one of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s main installations on the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>, was sketchy. `` Many roofs off, many windows out, ... most trees down,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> statement said. `` Preliminary reports of catastrophic levels of damage'' had been received. A few airplane hangar doors were knocked off during the storm but the aircraft inside were not damaged, the statement said. The base is the home of the <ORGANIZATION> 437th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlift </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wing </ORGANIZATION>, and the <ORGANIZATION> 315th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlift </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION>. The USS Narwhal, a nuclear attack submarine that was tied up at the <ORGANIZATION> Charleston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> shipyard, broke loose from its moorings, said a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Lundquist </PERSON>. The crew submerged the sub as a safety precaution, he said, and later returned to the surface without incident. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> statement said the USS Dewey, a guided missile destroyer, was damaged by a barge that broke free and scraped the side of the ship, and several small boats assigned to a submarine squadron were sunk at the pier. `` Widespread flooding'' occurred and electricity has been disrupted at the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> base, but emergency power has been made available at `` vital installations.'' Limited telephone service was restored Friday, the statement said. The Naval Hospital was reported operating and providing assistance to local residents, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said. <ORGANIZATION> Shaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, reported `` major damage'' to its housing area with `` many trees and power lines'' down. No injuries occurred at the base, where the wall of the commissary caved in, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> statement said. At <ORGANIZATION> Myrtle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beach </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, moderate structural damage occurred to some buildings, and only emergency generators were providing power. The Army reported a `` widespread power outage and minor flooding'' at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, which was directly in the path of the hurricane. Minor damage occurred to one of the barracks, the statement said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-USAirCrash 6thLd-Writethru a0402 09-23 1201</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-USAir Crash, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0402,1234</SECOND>
<HEAD>Co-pilot Pushed Wrong Button, Says NTSB</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 8 grafs to CLARIFY sequence of events in cockpit,
ages of cockpit crew; picks up 8th graf pvs: `The co-pilot, meanwhile,
...; SUBS INSERTS 1 graf after 19th pvs, `Both men .. ., with Kohlstad
comment on cockpit crew leaving the scene; INSERTS 1 graf after 28th, ``When
he ..., with USAir contradicting ALPA account of pilot's whereabouts; DELETES
outdated grafs 30-35, `The NTSB said ...; picks up 36th graf: `The New
York ...; Kleissaf is CQ.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The co-pilot of the <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> jet that crashed into the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, killing two people, inadvertently pushed a button that caused the 737-400 to decelerate, federal officials said Friday after interviewing the cockpit crew. The pilot tried to increase the throttle manually, the plane began to veer to the left and the pilot, feeling a vibration, aborted the takeoff, said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohlstad </PERSON>, acting administrator of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Kohlstad </PERSON> did not specify a precise cause for Wednesday's 11:29 p.m. crash, when Flight 5050, bound for <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, skidded off the runway into the waters off <LOCATION> LaGuardia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. `` He initiated the abort because of the drift,'' <PERSON> Kohlstad </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kohlstad </PERSON> said the plane has automatic throttles that are programmed prior to takeoff by the flight crew. The button that the co-pilot, <PERSON> Constantine </PERSON> <PERSON> Kleissaf </PERSON>, 29, should have pushed would have automatically accelerated the plane to a preset speed for takeoff, he said. But <PERSON> Kleissaf </PERSON> inadvertently hit the disengage button, he said. As the plane continued down the runway, pilot <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, 36, jumped in to try to increase the throttle manually. The plane started drifting to the left and `` the pilot felt and heard a vibration which concerned him,'' <PERSON> Kohlstad </PERSON> said. A senior flight attendant and a passenger also reported feeling the vibration, he said. As the plane accelerated down the runway, <PERSON> Kohlstad </PERSON> said, the flight crew did not call out the jet's speed to each other as is mandatory. `` It was clearly a lack of proper procedure being followed in the cockpit,'' <PERSON> Kohlstad </PERSON> said. The co-pilot, meanwhile, told investigators he was looking out the front window when he realized the captain was going to abort the flight, <PERSON> Kohlstad </PERSON> said. The pilot, referring to an earlier flight that day, told officials `` the co-pilot's performance suggested that he was obviously new,'' <PERSON> Kohlstad </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kohlstad </PERSON> said it was the co-pilot's first operational takeoff on a 737-400 following completion of flight training. After the crash, the pilot and co-pilot helped passengers get out of the plane, <PERSON> Kohlstad </PERSON> said. The pilot took a rescue boat to the airport and then a taxi to the <LOCATION> Marriott </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hotel </LOCATION>, where he called his union representative, he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> earlier Friday suspended the flight licenses of the pilot and co-pilot because both men left the scene after the accident and could not be questioned by investigators, said <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Busey </PERSON>. `` For these two pilots to have been sequestered for more than 36 hours after an accident that took two lives and to do so with no explanation is highly questionable,'' <PERSON> Busey </PERSON> said in a statement issued in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` There are many questions that only they can answer relating to public safety.'' Both men may appeal the suspension but would need to go through a recertification procedure to get their licenses back. Interviews with the flight crew indicated that the pilot `` was not exhibiting any abnormal behavior'' before the takeoff, <PERSON> Kohlstad </PERSON> said at a news conference Friday evening. <PERSON> Kohlstad </PERSON> said the co-pilot, <LOCATION> Kleissaf </LOCATION>, apologized for having said the pilot, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, was incoherent before the takeoff. <PERSON> Kleissaf </PERSON> had reportedly said <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> had been acting irrationally just before he ordered the plane's takeoff aborted. `` I regret that I put that in those words,'' <PERSON> Kohlstad </PERSON> said <PERSON> Kleissaf </PERSON> told the investigators. Both men have submitted to urine tests but the results were not yet available, <PERSON> Kohlstad </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kohlstad </PERSON> said <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kleissaf </PERSON> were not required to remain at the accident scene. `` They had gone through a very traumatic experience,'' he said. `` They had helped the passengers, they wanted to leave the scene.'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s whereabouts were unknown the day after the crash, but <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopatkiewicz </PERSON> said that was not unusual in plane crash investigations. <PERSON> Kohlstad </PERSON> said both pilots went to a hospital for treatment Thursday, which he said partially explains their absence. `` I do n't feel they've hampered the investigation,'' he said `` It is difficult for me to say they were stonewalling us.'' Investigators arranged Thursday through the pilots' union and the airline to interview the pilots, who had been subpoenaed by the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> but appeared before investigators voluntarily, authorities said. The senior flight attendant on the plane, at an emotional news conference with three of his co-workers from Flight 5050, said both pilots assisted in rescue efforts after the crash. But the attendant, <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON>, 34, of <LOCATION> Chesapeake </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, refused to comment on the captain's behavior except to say, `` He was assisting me in any way he could.'' Also Friday, the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> issued a statement in response to what it called `` a number of erroneous news reports and inappropriate speculations'' about the crash and <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s alleged irrational behavior `` There was nothing unusual in the crew's performance, no federal rules were broken and the crew has cooperated completely with the investigation,'' the pilots' union said. <ORGANIZATION> ALPA </ORGANIZATION> also denied that <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> disappeared after the crash. A <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> representative contacted <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> after the crash and told him to check into a <ORGANIZATION> Marriott </ORGANIZATION> hotel and stay there, the union said. `` When he was unable to obtain a room at the <ORGANIZATION> Marriott </ORGANIZATION>, he went to the home of another pilot to rest and recuperate,'' the union's statement said `` There he remained in contact with the company, which knew his whereabouts at all times.'' <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON> denied that <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> had been in contact with any airline official. `` He did not contact us and we did not tell him to go to the hotel,'' <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON> said. In another effort to determine what caused the crash, investigators began removing pieces of the plane from the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> on Friday morning, said <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>. The 11:29 p.m. crash Wednesday cracked the plane into three pieces, which were partly submerged. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported that according to airline industry officials, the captain had flown 737s for only two months and the first officer was in a 737 cockpit crew for the first time. <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> records show <PERSON> Kleissaf </PERSON> received his commercial pilot's license in October 1987 and an instructor's license six months later. His <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> record is completely clean, said <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoppers </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla </LOCATION>. Killed in the crash were passengers <PERSON> Betsy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brogan </PERSON>, 37, of <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, a nurse and mother of a 5-year-old boy, and her mother-in-law, <PERSON> Alyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Brogan </PERSON>, 69, of <LOCATION> Vixton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>. The deaths were <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION>'s first in 17 years. The plane was delivered in January and had no history of mechanical problems, said airline spokeswoman <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Vaughan </PERSON>. In June, the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> ordered most <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737-400s grounded because of two incidents in which engines failed. Airlines were ordered to replace certain engine parts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BlessingFlap     09-23 0277</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Blessing Flap,0285</SECOND>
<HEAD>Condo Resident Ordered to Dump `Bless This Home' Sign</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HALLANDALE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Reiter </PERSON> ca n't figure out what's offensive about the heart-shaped `` God bless this house'' sign on the front door of her apartment, but her condominium board says it has to go Ms. <PERSON> Reiter </PERSON>, who has lived at the <LOCATION> Fairways </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Riviera </LOCATION> complex for 17 years, says she's been told to remove the sign by Monday. `` She is not supposed to put anything strange on her door,'' condo board member <PERSON> Theo </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeelander </PERSON> said Thursday. Ms. <PERSON> Reiter </PERSON> ca n't see what's wrong with her sign because other residents decorate their doors with mezuzas _ Biblical inscriptions in <LOCATION> Hebrew </LOCATION> meant to be hung on doorposts. `` Are we in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>? I have every right to have that sign on my door,'' Ms. <PERSON> Reiter </PERSON> said. `` I am a Christian. This is my religious symbol asking God to bless my home.'' Condo President <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> would n't explain why the association found the sign offensive, but said it has to go. `` If the sign was somewhere else on another front door hidden from view, it would n't matter, but her door is very close to the condo's meeting room. A lot of people have to pass by her door, and it's offensive to everyone,'' he said. <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> has sent a letter telling Ms. <PERSON> Reiter </PERSON> the condo association would remove the sign if she does not. He said she was in violation of a condo regulation that prohibits residents from decorating their front doors. Ms. <PERSON> Reiter </PERSON> said she has called a lawyer and is ready to go to court. `` If they pull down that sign, there will be trouble,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ElevatorExplosion     09-23 0174</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Elevator Explosion,0179</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Killed, Three Hurt In Grain Elevator Blast</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BINGHAM LAKE, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A grain elevator explosion in this southwestern <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> town Friday killed two people and injured three others, authorities said. The bodies of two employees of <ORGANIZATION> Cargill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which owns the elevator, were recovered about two hours after the 2:30 p.m. explosion, said to a dispatcher for the <ORGANIZATION> Cottonwood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> The dead were identified as <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Gahler </PERSON>, 39, and <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunkelberger </PERSON>, 51, both of <LOCATION> Bingham </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>. Rescue workers had to empty the 75,000-bushel bin to recover the bodies, the sheriff's department said. Three people were hospitalized at <LOCATION> Windom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> with minor injuries suffered in the explosion, said nursing supervisor <PERSON> Carla </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>. All three were in stable condition and remained under observation Friday night, she said. The cause of the explosion was not immediately known, <ORGANIZATION> Cargill </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Garland </PERSON> <PERSON> West </PERSON> said. He said there was no fire, although some materials were smoldering after the explosion. The sheriff's department said the entire elevator complex sustained extensive structural damage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0219EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-LastTemptation     09-23 0333</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Last Temptation,0340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cable Company Offers to Blackout ``Last Temptation of Christ''</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BISMARCK, N.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A cable television company is asking its <ORGANIZATION> Cinemax </ORGANIZATION> subscribers whether they want the cable company to blackout the scheduled showing next month of the movie `` The Last Temptation of Christ.'' When the movie was released last year, many fundamentalist religious groups objected, with mass demonstrations and picketing of theaters where it was shown. In <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, the movie was only shown in <LOCATION> Fargo </LOCATION>. Because of that controversy, Bismarck-Mandan Cable TV sent its 1,800 <ORGANIZATION> Cinemax </ORGANIZATION> subscribers a letter saying it is considering blacking out the five showings of the film in October. The company also sent subscribers a card with two boxes to check _ a box in favor of the blackout and a box against it. `` As we examined it, we said it looks like a no-win situation,'' said <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> O </PERSON>. `` Jot'' <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, manager of the cable company. `` If we aired the movie there will probably be a lot of protests like last year in the theaters. And if we censor the movie or blackout there would be a lot of protests from people saying you should n't do that.'' <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> said he will have an announce the results of the balloting on Wednesday. A spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Box </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, parent company of <PERSON> Cinemax </PERSON>, who asked not to be identified said he did n't want to comment on the movie but said the company's general policy is that <ORGANIZATION> HBO </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Cinemax </ORGANIZATION> have the final say over programming. Local cable operators do not have the right to blackout the movies, he said. <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> said Bismarck-Mandan Cable TV's contract allows it. `` We do have a clause in there which says that we can make a decision if there's some programming we feel is not proper to community standards, we would have the right to black it out,'' he said. <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> said that clause is used only as a last resort and added the cable company has never exercised that option.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0220EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     09-23 0712</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names ,0755</SECOND>
<BYLINE>Names in the News</BYLINE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SYRACUSE, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Rolling Stones may not seem like publicity-shy types, but they banned reporters and photographers from a newspaper whose shutterbug snapped a few unauthorized shots during a concert. The photographer from the <ORGANIZATION> Herald-Journal </ORGANIZATION> sneaked back into the group's performance in <LOCATION> Syracuse </LOCATION> Thursday night and took photos after a two-song time limit. So the photographers were banned from Friday's concert, and Stones aide <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> said they would n't be allowed back unless the newspaper's managing editor met with him Managing Editor <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Atseff </PERSON> took the ban in stride. `` Wild horses could n't keep us from doing our job, and neither will the promoters,'' <PERSON> Asteff </PERSON> said. `` Do n't they know you ca n't always get what you want Come on, <PERSON> Mick </PERSON>, what's the big deal? It's only rock' n' roll And our readers like it, too.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ASBURY PARK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON> at 40 has n't lost his appeal for female fans, and the presents he received for his birthday today included a rock' n' roll G-string _ a guitar string with a dangling leaf. `` I figured if it gave <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> a chuckle, that's fun,'' said the garment's creator, <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Russoniello </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tinton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>. She won a `` Bruce Card'' contest sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> Asbury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. Runner-up was 14-year-old <PERSON> Kerrie </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, who sent a card with `` please'' written inside 37,000 times. The paper promised to forward all 145 cards and gifts entered in the contest to <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON> through his agent.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WEST SPRINGFIELD, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, a frequent target of radio talk show hosts, took to the airwaves with a live call-in show of his own. Broadcasting Friday from the Big E, a state fair in western <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, the one-time presidential candidate fielded questions about his unpopular budget cuts and a variety of social issues. `` You're on the air, this is Gov. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>,'' the Democrat said in the first installment of a regular show on station WSPR-AM. In the off-the-wall category, one caller asked him to intercede in the case of political extremist <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>. When a caller accused him of lying about plans for a state prison, the unflappable governor responded, `` You're wrong sir. I'm sorry.'' It was n't his first broadcast experience. In the 1970s <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> hosted a public television show called `` The Advocates'' that featured roundtable discussions of controversial issues.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>JEFFERSON CITY, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Roots'' author <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Haley </PERSON> is working on another book, and it may include a story about losing a childhood friendship with a white boy who said <PERSON> Haley </PERSON> would one day have to call him `` Mister.'' The Pulitzer-Prize winning author told students and faculty at <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> Friday about his boyhood friend <PERSON> Kermit </PERSON>. <PERSON> Haley </PERSON> said he remembers spending time with <PERSON> Kermit </PERSON> climbing a persimmon tree in <LOCATION> Henning </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, and talking about the future. <PERSON> Haley </PERSON> said he pulled away from the friendship when the two boys were about 10 because <PERSON> Kermit </PERSON> told <PERSON> Haley </PERSON>, `` Pretty soon you'll have to start calling me ` Mister.''' Both boys knew the statement was true in the 1930s, <PERSON> Haley </PERSON> said, but it made him so uncomfortable that in a month the friendship was over. <PERSON> Haley </PERSON> said he hopes to find <PERSON> Kermit </PERSON> someday and renew the friendship.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ST. LOUIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffa </PERSON>'s daughter says she doubts a magazine article describing the alleged murder and dismemberment of her long-missing father is true because the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> has never given the family such information. `` It's terribly gory. It's terribly upsetting to the entire family,'' <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Crancer </PERSON> said this week after reading an advance of the article in Playboy. `` It's a shame we had to read it in a Playboy-type magazine.'' A federally protected witness, <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> `` Tony the Greek'' Frankos, told <ORGANIZATION> Playboy </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Hoffa </PERSON>, the former Teamster leader who disappeared July 30, 1975, in suburban <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, was shot, dismembered and buried in concrete at Giants Stadium in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rutherford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Crancer </PERSON> said she assumed the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> would have notified her family if the agency had information such as that given to Playboy by <PERSON> Frankos </PERSON>. <PERSON> Crancer </PERSON>, who is an administrative law judge for the <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Division </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Compensation </ORGANIZATION>, has sued the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> for release of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s file on her father. No trial date has been set.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0100EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Britain-Blast Bjt   09-23 0782</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Blast, Bjt,0808</SECOND>
<HEAD>IRA Attack Stirs Security Controversy</HEAD>
<HEAD>By MAUREEN JOHNSON</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DEAL, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> bombing that killed 10 men and blew apart a building at the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Music </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> outraged Britons and stirred recriminations over safety standards at the school. A huge explosion in a barracks staff room Friday morning leveled the three-story building as bandsmen took a coffee break between practice sessions on the school's parade ground. Twelve of the 22 people injured were hospitalized, eight of them in serious condition, police said. They said nine of the dead were bandsmen and one other man was not immediately identified. Dozens of neighboring homes in the quiet southeastern English seaside town of Deal were damaged. Although trainees at the school range in age from 16 to 20, Col. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ware </PERSON>, principal director of music, said the slain bandsmen all were trained, adult musicians. They held military ranks but none had been trained as a fighting soldier. The outlawed <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, engaged in a 20-year-old campaign to drive the British from the province of <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, claimed responsibility in a telephone call to <ORGANIZATION> Ireland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION> news agency. Residents of the area adjoining the <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION> school said Friday that despite government calls for stepped-up public alertness against terrorists, security at the school had eased noticeably. `` Anyone in Deal will tell you how easy it is to get into the base,'' said <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Verge </PERSON>, a 70-year-old army veteran. Local people laid wreaths and bouquets of flowers at the entrance to the barracks. `` There is a great sense of anger'' in the community, <LOCATION> Kent </LOCATION> police Chief Constable <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Condon </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Music </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> is one of 30 military establishments in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> that use private security firms, <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> figures show. Unidentified defense sources quoted by the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> newspaper today said the civilian guards were backed up by armed Marines who patrolled regularly inside the perimeter. Defense Secretary <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> promised a security review and said new measures had already been taken at the base. He did not elaborate. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON>, the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s spokesman on defense, said on Friday: `` Serious questions must be asked about the penny-pinching policy of the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION>, which may well put our armed services at dreadful risk.'' <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON> later told <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> television the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> was `` prepared to take out anybody. The cowardly nature of their attacks is such that every military establishment is under threat.'' He said private security firms were assigned to areas considered low risks for attacks. `` If we designate places as being low-risk categories, then it is likely they will be attacked, given the way that the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> is forced to operate,'' <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON> added. `` The big prizes are no longer available to them, so they're picking off the ones which they regard vulnerable.'' Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> received news of the bombing while aboard a jet over <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION> en route from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. She called it a `` deeply serious outrage.'' King visited the scene soon after the explosion. `` I know that the people who committed it, the godfathers who sent them, actually know in their hearts that it is not going to make any difference; that it is just killing for the sake of killing,'' he said. The defense minister, anger clearly written on his face, said that rather than erode the will of the security forces, the attack `` redoubles their determination to ensure that terrorism can not win.'' Prime Minister <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Haughey </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> condemned the attack and sent Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> a message of sympathy at `` this outrage ... which has caused severe and tragic loss of life and many injuries.'' The mainly Roman Catholic IRA claim gave no details of the operation, but said it was a response to a `` message of war'' delivered by Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> when she visited <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> nine days ago. It was an apparent reference to her speech praising the locally recruited <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regiment </ORGANIZATION> as `` a very, very brave group of men'' who have lost 179 members in <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> attacks since 1970. The mainly Protestant UDR is regarded by many <PERSON> Catholics </PERSON> as a sectarian force, and is at present under a cloud over allegations that some recruits leaked names, addresses and photos of <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> suspects to <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> assassins. British military installations are a frequent target of the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> campaign. Friday's attack was the worst since July 1982 when 11 servicemen were fatally wounded in two bombings in central <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. The music school trains young recruits for the seven Royal Marines bands. Up to 250 young men, most ages 16 to 20, undergo military and musical training there, working with older, professional bandsmen.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0249EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Hugo-Bicycles     09-23 0427</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hugo-Bicycles,0444</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bicycles Prove Useful in Battered City</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Hugo, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELLIOTT MINOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Many residents of this hurricane-ravaged city mounted bicycles to check on their homes and friends, dodging toppled trees, wind-sheared roofs, broken gas lights and other debris. Hurricane Hugo's torrential rains and 135 mph winds caused an estimated $ 1 billion in damages in historic <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>. Mayor <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Riley </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> imposed a 7 p.m. curfew Friday to deter looting, and 1,400 National Guardsmen joined police in patrolling the streets early today. Among those pushing pedals were Dr. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Sadler </PERSON>, his wife and two daughters. Their golden retriever, `` Snickers,'' maneuvered around the debris on foot. `` We did n't know which streets would be under water,'' said <PERSON> Sadler </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Sadlers </ORGANIZATION> spent Thursday night in <LOCATION> Summerville </LOCATION>, about 25 miles inland, when it became clear <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> would get the brunt of Hugo. The family returned to the battered city Friday morning to check on damage, finding streets littered with planks, window frames, shards of glass and other debris. Many of the city's historic homes were damaged and its big oak trees topped by the force of the storm. `` I could n't imagine it being as bad as they were saying,'' said <PERSON> Sadler </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Francie </PERSON>. `` I did n't want to believe it. I cried when I came back into town.'' Attorney <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tisdale </PERSON> said he decided to use his 10-speed bicycle because his car was low on gasoline and because some streets were impassable in cars. `` Given the problems with the streets, it's easier and faster in many cases to get around on bicycles,'' he said. In the luggage rack of his bicycle, <PERSON> Tisdale </PERSON> carried a folded blue tarp that had covered his desk during the storm. <PERSON> Tisdale </PERSON> said his office was not damaged, but a friend's roof was gone. <PERSON> Tisdale </PERSON> planned to give the tarp to his friend to cover the gaping hole. Another bicyclist, <PERSON> Beth </PERSON> <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON>, stopped for a break at a street corner across the street from City Hall, whose metal roof was blown off. `` It's the only way to get around,'' she said. `` I came out to look at family homes. One's water damaged. One's roof is damaged. One's OK, except we'd like to take a bath.'' Ms. <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON> said she did n't think <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> would cause such extensive damage. `` Lots of trees are down,'' she said. <PERSON> Katie </PERSON> <PERSON> Crouch </PERSON> peddled along Meeting Street, past damaged motels and shops, to check the homes of friends who had evacuated. `` Everything is in shock right now,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Crouch </PERSON>, a high school junior.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0304EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-IRA-Glance     09-23 0261</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-IRA-Glance,0268</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Look at Attacks Claimed by the IRA</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Britain-Blast, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are some of the major <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> attacks of recent years on targets in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and continental <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>: July 20, 1982: A bomb exploded under the British army's bandstand in Regent's Park, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, killing seven band members and injuring 28. On the same day, another bomb in the capital's <LOCATION> Hyde </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> killed four soldiers. Dec. 17, 1983: A car bomb exploded outside <PERSON> Harrod </PERSON>'s department store on a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> street packed with Christmas shoppers. Six people were killed and 90 injured. Oct. 12, 1984: Five people were killed and 24 injured when an <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> bomb exploded at the hotel in the southern English seaside town of <LOCATION> Brighton </LOCATION>, where Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> was staying during her Conservative Party's convention. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>'s declared target, was unhurt May 1, 1988: Three British airmen stationed in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> were killed in <LOCATION> Nieuwbergen </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION>. One was fatally shot and two died an hour later when a bomb went off in a discotheque frequented by British troops. It was one of a series of <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> attacks on British military personnel in continental <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> during the year. Aug. 1, 1988: A bomb in the dormitory at <ORGANIZATION> Inglis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Barracks </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> killed one soldier and injured nine. Sept. 7, 1989: The wife of a British soldier, <PERSON> Heidi </PERSON> <PERSON> Hazell </PERSON>, 25, was shot and killed near her home outside <LOCATION> Dortmund </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Sept. 22, 1989: An explosion at the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> of Music in Deal killed 10 people and injured 22.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0252EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-`Strangler'Weds     09-23 0228</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-`Strangler' Weds,0234</SECOND>
<HEAD>Defendant in `Hillside Strangler' Case Weds in Prison</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WALLA WALLA, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Hillside Strangler'' inmate <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Bianchi </PERSON> has married a woman he met through the mail. <PERSON> Bianchi </PERSON>, 38, and his pen pal, <PERSON> Shirlee </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. Book, 36, of <LOCATION> Monterey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, were married in a 30-minute ceremony in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penitentiary </LOCATION> chapel, prison spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bauer </PERSON> said Friday. The couple have corresponded by mail and telephone since 1986 but did n't meet face to face until Wednesday, the day before the wedding, <PERSON> Bauer </PERSON> said. A marriage license was issued Monday by the <ORGANIZATION> Walla </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Walla </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auditor </ORGANIZATION>'s Office. <PERSON> Bianchi </PERSON> is serving two life sentences for the slayings of two <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> women in January 1979. He pleaded guilty to first-degree murder in five of the 10 `` Hillside Strangler'' slayings in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, in which young women were raped and strangled and their bodies dumped on hillsides around <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> in 1977 and 1978. His cousin, <PERSON> Angelo </PERSON> <PERSON> Buono </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, is imprisoned in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> for nine of the killings. The newlyweds wo n't get a conjugal visit for two to three months, <PERSON> Bauer </PERSON> said. Then they'll get to spend time together in a trailer on the prison grounds. <PERSON> Bianchi </PERSON> and his bride each were allowed one attendant, but neither the attendants' names nor the minister's will be released, <PERSON> Bauer </PERSON> said. The spokesman did n't know if Book would move to <PERSON> Walla </PERSON> <PERSON> Walla </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0306EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites SUB a0427 09-23 0053</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites, SUB, a0427,0053</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 1st graf, second item to CORRECT spelling to disc sted
disk.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BURLEY, Idaho (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Disc jockey <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitton </PERSON> broadcast for 103 hours straight, and claimed to have accomplished the feat without the aid of coffee or any other stimulant, even chocolate. `` We wanted, 2nd graf
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0316EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-Drugs 1stLd-Writethru a0409 09-23 0638</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Drugs, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0409,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drug War Negotiations Fizzle Out in Senate</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 4th graf pvs, Republicans were, to CORRECT billion to million;
picks up 5th graf, The parties; Note, PM-Congress-Drugs should have carried
a bjt designator</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s war on drugs is caught in a partisan battle in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, with Democrats trying to add prevention and treatment money and Republicans arguing the revision would weaken the defense budget. `` If we're not willing to spend $ 150 million more, this is no war,'' Sen. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>, said Friday after a week of closed-door efforts to reach a compromise failed. The talks broke off Friday and no new negotiations were scheduled. Republicans were proposing to add $ 850 million to the $ 7.9 billion program <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> announced two weeks ago and Democrats were holding out for an additional $ 1 billion, with no further talks scheduled. The parties also were at odds over how to distribute cuts in programs for money to go to the anti-drug effort. The breakdown threatened to create a logjam of money bills in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> just before the Oct. 1 start of the fiscal year when the funds ordinarily would be needed. Lawmakers said they might pass a stopgap measure to keep federal workers on the job and benefit checks flowing. The chief Republican negotiator, Sen. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, R-Ore., said the two sides were actually fairly close and said he hoped the parties would take `` a clear-eyed, Monday morning view'' and resume bargaining `` We have to wage this war and the sooner we get at it the better it's going to be,'' <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON> said. Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, the chief <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> negotiator, said the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> had been `` a shadow participant'' in the negotiations and that its reluctance to compromise was the key `` There comes a time when you have to fish or cut bait,'' said <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. Republican lawmakers said they were frequently on the phone to White House chief of staff <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> on Thursday when a marathon bargaining session ended at midnight. <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> was in the office of Senate Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> Friday morning for a strategy session with <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> senators, national drug policy director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> and budget director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>. Of the $ 1 billion Democrats would add, $ 800 million would be aimed at stemming demand for drugs through education and prevention programs and through treatment. The rest would go to local law enforcement. Democrats would finance their program with an across-the-board cut of 0.3 percent in federal spending plus selected cuts to be determined by congressional subcommittees. Republicans were offering to add $ 850 million to the program, including $ 750 million for the so-called demand side programs of treatment and prevention and the rest for local law enforcement. They would get additional money through a 0.4 percent across-the-board cut in spending, <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON> said. But Republicans were holding out for additional flexibility to protect defense procurement from the full brunt of across-the-board cuts. Since the bargaining began, <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> cut their proposed increase by more than half to compromise with Republicans. <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> senators said <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>'s initial plan, with its across-the-board reduction of more than 0.5 percent, would have been too hard on defense. And inclusion of selected cuts also represented a partial concession to Republican demands. <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> told a news conference that Republicans asked for concessions `` and we said, <LOCATION> OK </LOCATION>, we'll do that, but lets beef up that treatment side, that prevention side.'' He and other <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> lawmakers dismissed the notion that their proposal would weaken defense. `` The administration was unwilling to let a $ 300 billion defense budget bear a less than one-half of one percent cut to beef up the war on drugs,'' Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>, D-Tenn., told reporters
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0316EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Martinez-Abortion     09-23 0405</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Martinez-Abortion,0417</SECOND>
<HEAD>Governor Orders Clinic Closed, Seeks New Rules</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> is seeking emergency rules to protect women at private abortion clinics in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> after ordering a <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> clinic closed because of reports of botched abortions. `` This is a pure pro-health issue,'' <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> said at a Friday news conference. `` This is for the health of individuals irregardless of philosophy on the substance of the abortion issue.'' <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rehabilitative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Coler </PERSON> to `` take all steps necessary to remove the license of this clinic.'' The action comes after reports of improper abortions by unlicensed physicians resulting in ruptured uteri and hysterectomies at the <ORGANIZATION> Dadeland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, now doing business as the Women's Service Center `` There is no legal reason, no health reason, for this order,'' responded <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>, director of the center. `` We've done nothing against the law. We've helped thousands of women. I see this as totally ludicrous.'' <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunbar </PERSON>, the governor's general counsel, said any emergency regulations drawn up by HRS for abortion clinics would be in effect for 90 days. After that, the new rules would be subject to public hearings and HRS board approval to become permanent. By that time, the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> will have decided whether to go along with <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>'s proposals to further restrict access to abortions. The session is scheduled for Oct. 10-13. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> has denied he was trying to bypass the Legislature by using the <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> situation to enact emergency regulations. Yet in his letter to <PERSON> Coler </PERSON>, the governor said conditions at the <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> clinic `` are precisely why I have called for increased regulation of abortion clinics to protect the health of women.'' The new rules, <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> said, will not be as strict as his proposal for the special session to make private abortion clinics adhere to the same standards as ambulatory care clinics. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> said HRS should not be blamed for the problems at the <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> clinic, saying the agency does n't have the power at present to uncover them. He said he does n't know whether abortion clinics throughout the state have similar practices. <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON>, the governor's chief of operations, said veterinary clinics have more stringent regulations than abortion centers. Neither <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Dunbar </PERSON> would be specific about the kinds of regulations being sought, but both said they would be designed to protect the health of women seeking abortions _ not to restrict their access to an abortion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0319EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Pope-Gorbachev     09-23 0179</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Pope-Gorbachev,0185</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vatican Official Discusses Possible Pope-Gorbachev Meeting</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VATICAN CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> has confirmed that a <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> official met with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> to discuss a possible meeting between Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> II and President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. Such a meeting would be the first between the leader of the world's 850 million Roman Catholics and the head of the officially atheist <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Joaquin </PERSON> <PERSON> Navarro </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> spokesman, Friday confirmed a newspaper report that Archbishop <PERSON> Angelo </PERSON> <PERSON> Sodano </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>'s Secretariat of State had gone to the Soviet Embassy in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> about 10 days earlier to meet Ambassador <PERSON> Nikolai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lunkov </PERSON> The spokesman told reporters the meeting involved `` preparation for a possible visit by President <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to the Vatican.'' <PERSON> Navarro </PERSON> gave no dates for such a meeting. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is expected to visit <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> sometime in November, however. The spokesman did not comment on another part of the report in the <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> daily <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Repubblica </ORGANIZATION> that said <PERSON> Sodano </PERSON> told <PERSON> Lunkov </PERSON> the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> was ready to consider establishing diplomatic relations with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0321EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Norway-Extremist     09-23 0167</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Norway-Extremist,0170</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anti-Immigration Leader Convicted For Bomb Plot</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ARENDAL, Norway (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A founder of an anti-immigration group was convicted of plotting to bomb a refugee center and sentenced to one year in prison, news reports said. <PERSON> Arne </PERSON> <PERSON> Myrdal </PERSON>, 53, called his conviction on Friday `` absurd'' and `` a political judgment,'' according to the Norwegian news agency <ORGANIZATION> NTB </ORGANIZATION>. He was expected to appeal. The Agder Country Court said evidence, including dynamite and a hand-drawn map of a new refugee reception center near this southern <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> town, proved that <PERSON> Myrdal </PERSON> intended to bomb the center, <ORGANIZATION> NTB </ORGANIZATION> reported. <PERSON> Myrdal </PERSON> helped found the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Against </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> in October 1987, after the annual number of asylum seekers in <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> increased tenfold in two years to about 8,600 people. A second defendant in the case, <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Skauen </PERSON>, 34, was convicted of conspiracy and threatening to kill a police informer who acted as a prosecution witness, the news report said. He was sentenced to eight months in prison, according to the report.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0322EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Berlin-Appreciation     09-23 0558</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Berlin-Appreciation,0569</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Man Who Created the American Popular Song</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Obit-Berlin, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL KUCHWARA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Drama Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> <PERSON> Berlin </PERSON> created the American popular song. Until <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> began writing after the turn of the century, American music was dominated by <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> _ English music hall, <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, Viennese operetta and Italian opera. <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> took native American sounds, such as ragtime, and turned them into huge popular hits like `` Alexander's Ragtime Band'' and `` Everybody's Doin' It Now. When <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> <PERSON> Berlin </PERSON> wrote, <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> listened _ for more than 50 years. `` He caught the voices of the people early in this century and held them for longer than anyone else,'' <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kimball </PERSON>, musical theater historian, said Friday. From his first song, `` Marie of <LOCATION> Sunny </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>,'' in 1907 to his last Broadway show, `` Mr. President,'' in 1962, <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s presence was felt on the music scene in this country. No one today can look to such a long period of domination. And <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> was a winner in every medium he tried. He found success not only in Tin Pan Alley but on Broadway with musicals like `` Annie Get Your Gun,'' `` Call Me Madam'' and his Music Box revues, and in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> where he wrote the scores for <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Astaire-Ginger </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> movies like `` Top Hat'' and `` Follow the Fleet'' and other films like `` Holiday Inn'' and `` Easter Parade.'' His colleagues thought he was the best, particularly contemporaries like <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Kern </PERSON>. He had an enormous influence on the Broadway composers who followed him, especially <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Gershwin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Arlen </PERSON> who relished his inventive way with rhythm. <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> also had an incredible versatility, a great intelligence and perspective about the world. He could write any kind of song _ a stirring, patriotic anthem like `` God Bless <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' a seasonal standard like `` White Christmas,'' a comic theater ditty like `` Doin' What Comes Natur ` lly,'' an unbashedly sentimental favorite like `` Always'' or a complex love song like `` Let's Face the Music and Dance `` He was a folk singer and he was able to absorb whatever was happening in the street and bring it out, even more than <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Jablonski </PERSON>, a good friend of <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s and the author of several books on American theater composers. `` He was an ordinary man who was able to write songs. That's why he appealed so much to people. `` But he also made a point of not being a well-educated musician. He was a born musician, which is a hard thing to be. So he could be more sophisticated that he ever thought he was.'' <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> also was a shrewd businessman. He was a charter member and served on the first board of directors for <ORGANIZATION> ASCAP </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Composers </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Authors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishers </ORGANIZATION>, which collects songwriting royalties. Before 1920, he had formed his own music publishing company which published all of his music. And at the time of his death, he was still co-owner of the Music Box Theater, a Broadway theater he built in 1921. As late as two years ago, he would call up the box office at the Music Box to see how the grosses were going. But it will be for his music that he will be remembered. `` I would think <LOCATION> Irving </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> is the most admired songwriter <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> has produced in this century _ and maybe ever,'' <PERSON> Kimball </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0322EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--China-Waste     09-23 0158</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China-Waste,0164</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Officials Seize New Luxury Office Building From Ministry</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Waste watchers in the Chinese government have seized a new luxury office building from a ministry accused of ignoring state orders to avoid extravagance, according to an official report today. The <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> newspaper quoted He <PERSON> Yong </PERSON>, vice minister of supervision, as saying, `` This violates the state's regulations on construction standards for executive office buildings as well as the present austerity drive.'' The central government has demanded for the past year that all public offices sharply reduce spending as part of a policy to counter inflation, rising budget deficits and excessive economic growth. The six-story building on <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s main Changan Avenue contains marble walls and floors, central air conditioning and other luxuries for top officials. It cost $ 31 million, 3 -LCB- times the amount planned. He <PERSON> Yong </PERSON> said the building, completed last year, will be turned over to the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Offices </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0323EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Obit-Berlin-List     09-23 0292</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Berlin-List,0339</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Songs Written by Irving Berlin</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Obit-Berlin, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a list of some of the songs written by <LOCATION> Irving </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>: `` Marie of Sunny <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'' -LRB- 1907 -RRB- lyrics only, music by <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicholson </PERSON> `` <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>'s Ragtime Band'' -LRB- 1911 -RRB- `` I Want to Go Back to <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>'' -LRB- 1913 -RRB- `` When I Discovered You'' -LRB- 1914 -RRB- `` Play a Simple Melody'' -LRB- 1914 -RRB- `` I Love a Piano'' -LRB- 1915 -RRB- `` The Girl on the Magazine Cover'' -LRB- 1915 -RRB- `` I Can Always Find a Little Sunshine in the YMCA'' -LRB- 1918 -RRB- `` Oh, How I Hate to Get Up in the Morning'' -LRB- 1918 -RRB- `` Mandy'' -LRB- 1918 -RRB- `` A Pretty Girl is Like a Melody'' -LRB- 1919 -RRB- `` Say It With Music'' -LRB- 1921 -RRB- `` What'll I Do'' -LRB- 1923 -RRB- `` Always'' -LRB- 1924 -RRB- `` Remember'' -LRB- 1924 -RRB- `` All Alone'' -LRB- 1925 -RRB- `` Blue Skies'' -LRB- 1926 -RRB- `` How Many Times'' -LRB- 1926 -RRB- `` Russian Lullaby'' -LRB- 1928 -RRB- `` Puttin' on the Ritz'' -LRB- 1929 -RRB- `` Let Me Sing and I'm Happy'' -LRB- 1930 -RRB- `` Let's Have Another Cup of Coffee'' -LRB- 1932 -RRB- `` How Deep is the Ocean'' -LRB- 1932 -RRB- `` Say It Is n't So'' -LRB- 1932 -RRB- `` Easter Parade'' -LRB- 1933 -RRB- `` Heat Wave'' -LRB- 1933 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> on My Mind'' -LRB- 1933 -RRB- `` Supper Time'' -LRB- 1933 -RRB- `` Cheek to Cheek'' -LRB- 1935 -RRB- `` Top Hat, White Tie and Tails'' -LRB- 1935 -RRB- `` The Piccolino'' -LRB- 1935 -RRB- `` Is n't It A Lovely Day'' -LRB- 1935 -RRB- `` Let's Face the Music and Dance'' -LRB- 1936 -RRB- `` I've Got My Love to Keep Me Warm'' -LRB- 1937 -RRB- `` God Bless America'' -LRB- 1938 -RRB- `` White Christmas'' -LRB- 1942 -RRB- `` This is the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, Mr. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>'' -LRB- 1942 -RRB- `` Doin' What Comes Natur ` lly'' -LRB- 1946 -RRB- `` The Girl That I Marry'' -LRB- 1946 -RRB- `` There's No Business Like Show Business'' -LRB- 1946 -RRB- `` Anything You Can Do I Can Do Better'' -LRB- 1946 -RRB- `` I Got the Sun in the Morning'' -LRB- 1946 -RRB- `` They Say It's Wonderful'' -LRB- 1946 -RRB- `` You Ca n't Get a Man With a Gun'' -LRB- 1946 -RRB- `` Let's Take An Old-Fashioned Walk -LRB- 1949 -RRB- `` You're Just in Love'' -LRB- 1950 -RRB- `` It's a Lovely Day'' -LRB-
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0324EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Berlin-ShowsandFilms     09-23 0183</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Berlin-Shows and Films,0211</SECOND>
<UNK>The Films and Musicals of Irving Berlin</UNK>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a list of some of the Broadway musicals and revues written by <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> <PERSON> Berlin </PERSON>. Before 1914, he contributed individual songs to more than 20 other shows. `` Watch Your Step,'' 1914 `` Stop! Look! Listen!,'' 1915 `` <PERSON> Yip </PERSON>, <PERSON> Yip </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Yaphank </LOCATION>,'' 1918 `` Ziegfeld Follies of 1911, 1919 and 1920,'' contributed some of the songs `` Music Box Revues of 1921, 1922, 1923 and 1924'' `` The Cocoanuts,'' 1925 `` Ziegfeld Follies of 1927'' `` Face the Music,'' 1932 `` As Thousands Cheer,'' 1933 `` <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Purchase </LOCATION>,'' 1940 `` This is the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>,'' 1942 `` Annie Get Your Gun, 1946 `` Miss Liberty,'' 1949 `` Call Me Madam,'' 1950 `` Mr. President,'' 1962 Here is a list of some of the films that had songs by <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>: `` Puttin' on the Ritz,'' 1930 `` Top Hat,'' 1935 `` Follow the Fleet,'' 1936 `` On the Avenue,'' 1937 `` Carefree,'' 1938 `` <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>'s Ragtime Band,'' 1938 `` Second Fiddle,'' 1939 `` Holiday Inn,'' 1942 `` Blue Skies,'' 1946 `` Easter Parade,'' 1948 `` Annie Get Your Gun,'' 1950 `` Call Me Madam,'' 1953 `` White Christmas,'' 1954 `` There's No Business Like Show Business,'' 1954
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0317EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SoldiersofFortune Bjt   09-23 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soldiers of Fortune, Bjt,0667</SECOND>
<HEAD>Would-Be Rambos at Las Vegas Convention</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT MACY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Platoons of would-be Rambos are shopping for exotic weaponry and fighting fashions, taking tutorials on world terrorism and swapping war stories at the 10th annual Soldiers of Fortune convention. At the start of the three-day gathering Friday, conventioneers decked out in berets, flak jackets and camouflage pants sat around the pool of the Sahara Hotel amid bikini-clad sunbathers. Others rubbed shoulders with civilian gamblers at the bars and slot machines. An estimated 10,000 delegates could choose from seminars on such hot spots as <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, manufacturers' displays and a shooting competition at a desert range As usual, the big hit was the annual display of weapons and apparel designed especially for those spoiling for a fight. `` It features a lot of things your mother probably did n't want you to play with when you were growing up,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, exhibition director at the convention, which is put on by Soldier of Fortune magazine of <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Colo </PERSON>. The show, he said, is keyed to the interests of the `` professional adventurer.'' Elsewhere in the country, people are campaigning to rid the civilian populace of semiautomatic weapons. But in the hotel's main exhibition hall, convention-goers trooped to booths featuring the latest in rapid-fire armament. Street Sweeper Sales of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> touted a line of automatic weapons with a banner picturing an ominous looking weapon. `` The Street Sweeper _ Delivers 12 rounds in less than 3 Seconds,'' the sign said. `` Buy American _ It matters.'' Salesman <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON> <PERSON> Yarborough </PERSON> said the featured firearm is used mainly for police work and by <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> law agencies against drug smugglers and dealers. Some Street Sweepers are used for `` self protection,'' <PERSON> Yarborough </PERSON> said, adding it's `` like any gun. Each person has a different use for them.'' <PERSON> Yarborough </PERSON> said his company sells only to licensed gun dealers. Several booths, including one set up by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, urged attendees to fight efforts at gun control. Posters, T-shirts and bumper stickers carried a similar theme. One poster pictured a man with a cache of guns and a message: `` Make all the laws you want _ you ai n't taking mine!'' Nearby was a stack of bumper stickers reading `` WAR _ <LOCATION> Mankind </LOCATION>'s oldest contact sport. Camouflage was the uniform of the day. Several booths offered `` camo'' clothing including pants, jackets, hats _ even bikini swimsuits and women's lingerie. Outside, a motor home sported a camouflage paint job. T-shirt slogans ran along the lines of `` Kill a Commie for Mommy,'' and `` I do n't dial 911'' next to a picture of a gun. One booth bristled with dozens of official-looking laminated ID cards, including Police, Press, <PERSON> Swat </PERSON> <PERSON> Team </PERSON>, Security and Ordained Minister. A sign read `` America is at Peace because the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> is at War.'' Among the hundreds of books offered were a manual on the care and operation of the AK-47 assault rifle and a volume entitled, `` Armed and Female: 12 million <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women own guns. Should you?'' Some exhibitors were reluctant to talk to reporters. A salesman for Miami-based <ORGANIZATION> Intratec </ORGANIZATION> referred questions to his home office when asked about the company's .22 - caliber Scorpion automatic CEP, Inc. of <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, was hawking videos on such subjects as terrorist weapons and making various explosives. <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON>'s Gun Shop of <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, showcased a new bullet with enhanced destructive power. The promotional literature described it: `` On impact, a pre-cut, precision forged metal projectile opens into whirlpool-creating, chopping blades.'' Airpower Sabot Cannons of <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, demonstrated an air-powered gun that's fired while resting on a person's shoulder. Potential ammunition included steel or lead balls, steel projectiles, bean bags, paint balls and water balloons. `` Kill it, capture it, mark it, rescue it, scare it, intimidate it, supress it, sink it,'' read the brochure.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890923-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-23-89 0214EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-US-Soviet 8thLd-Writethru   09-23 1257</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Soviet, 8th Ld-Writethru,a0435,1,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Superpowers Hammer Out Arms Accords In Rocky Mountains Talks</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS one graf after 24th pvs with Soviet response; picks
up, In another</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JACKSON HOLE, Wyo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
