<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SatanicVerses-US 1stLd-Writethru a0824 02-24 0772</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Satanic Verses-US, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0824,0789</SECOND>
<HEAD>Waldenbooks Defends Position; Moslems Seek Sensitivity</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS lead to CORRECT tense shift; SUBS yth graf, `The third
. .., to UPDATE with full-page Times ad; INSERTS 2 grafs after 11th graf,
`The chain's ..., to UPDATE with Times report of demand among independent
booksellers.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Rusdie, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 A bookstore chain caught up in the controversy of `` The Satanic Verses'' went on the offensive Thursday, with writers and booksellers decrying death threats against its author and <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> groups seeking compassion for their faith. `` Let's not be stampeded by this kind of intellectual terrorism. Let's vote with our wallets. Buy the book,'' said poet and novelist <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Anania </PERSON> at a rally at the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION>'s Cultural Center. Writers nationwide have rallied in support of <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>, whose novel has enraged Moslems and brought a death sentence from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> and offers of a $ 5.2 million bounty. Moslem leaders in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, while denouncing the death sentence and threats of violence against bookstores, said the book was intolerable to followers of Islam and called for withdrawal of `` this slanderous work.'' `` We simply expect the media to accord Muslims the same rights that have been generally extended to other religious minorities,'' said <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> <PERSON> Zaki </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammad </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Plainfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind </LOCATION>. `` It is regrettable that <ORGANIZATION> Viking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Penquin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the -LRB- <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> -RRB- publishers, has shown insensitivity to the concerns of Muslims.'' Three <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bookstore chains had yanked the book off shelves, but <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Barnes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Noble bookstores, which are under common ownership, decided Wednesday to stock the book. The third chain, Waldenbooks, the nation's largest with 1,200 stores, placed full-page advertisements in Friday's editions of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> and eight other newspapers, saying it will continue to sell the book despite `` many threats of violence.'' In the text of the ad, Waldenbooks complained that it was subjected to `` unfair castigation'' for telling its outlets to remove the book from their shelves for security reasons. Waldenbooks noted that it continued to sell the book while not displaying it until its supply ran out. Also, late last week it gave store managers permission to display the book at their discretion. `` We will continue to sell the book when it comes back in stock at the publisher,'' Waldenbooks said. `` We will continue to use discretion in displaying the book.'' The chain's president, <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>, has said it has received about 60 bomb threats. The Times reported in Friday's editions that demand for `` The Satanic Verses'' has been strong among independent booksellers, who report taking orders for nearly 200,000 copies of the book. Yet all of the more than 300 independent booksellers surveyed by the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said they did not have copies of the book for sale. Protests also came from groups in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` The ayatollah has n't only taken out a contract on <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>: he has taken out a contract on our <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> freedoms to read, to write, and to express ourselves as we choose,'' said <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kropp </PERSON>, president of People for the American Way. The 275,000-member organization has opposed efforts by American fundamentalists to censor textbook and school reading lists. An ad hoc group calling itself the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> for Free Expression also issued a statement in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> decrying <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s threats against the British author. `` We can not and will not tolerate a threat to assassinate a writer for his ideas or others for disseminating those ideas,'' declared the committee, which includes the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Booksellers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. At the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> rally, 300 writers and supporters heard Pulitzer Prize-winning author <PERSON> Studs </PERSON> <PERSON> Terkel </PERSON> compare <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> to <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Scopes </PERSON>, who was tried for teaching Darwinism, and author <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinbeck </PERSON>, criticized for his `` Grapes of Wrath.'' <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>, a British citizen born in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> into a Moslem family, went into hiding in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> because of the death threats. The president of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Muslim </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaiseruddin </PERSON>, said after the writers' speeches that he objects to the death sentence, but does n't believe such `` very strong, profane passages about people Moslems respect the most'' should be tolerated by society. A writer in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> was organizing a public reading of <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>'s work for March 9, the day he was supposed to give a reading during a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> promotional tour that was canceled At a public reading Wednesday night at <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>, those who read the passages said their intent was not to offend Islam but to protest censorship. `` We are here to confirm our right as Americans to read whatever we want,'' said graduate student <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0707EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AIDS-Stats     02-24 0222</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Stats,0245</SECOND>
<HEAD>CDC Statistics On U.S. AIDS Cases</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest statistics on acquired immune deficiency syndrome in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, as reported this week by the national Centers for Disease Control:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Number of Cases</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Total cases reported since June 1981: 87,188. Cases, year to date: 4,443. Total deaths: 49,976, or 57 percent of all cases.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Transmission Categories</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Homosexual or bisexual males: 52,758, or 61 percent. Intravenous drug abusers: 17,226, or 20 percent. Homosexual male and drug abusers: 6,140, or 7 percent. Heterosexual cases: 3,792, or 4 percent. Transfusion or blood cases: 2,312, or 3 percent. Hemophilia patients: 916, or 1 percent. Children of parents with AIDS or at risk: 1,119, or 1 percent. Undetermined transmission cause: 2,925, or 3 percent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Age and Race</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Childhood cases -LRB- under age 13 -RRB-: 1,432, or 2 percent. Cases among whites: 49,945, or 57 percent. Cases among blacks: 23,290, or 27 percent. Cases among Hispanics: 13,154, or 15 percent. Cases among Asians or Pacific Islanders: 507, or 1 percent. Cases among American Indians or Alaskan natives: 97, or 0 percent. -LRB- NOTE: These statistics are through Feb. 20 and have been rounded to the nearest whole percent. Cumulative totals are for AIDS cases reported since June 1981, and include 75 cases subsequently found to have occurred prior to that date. -RRB-
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hirohito-Name     02-24 0410</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hirohito-Name,0419</SECOND>
<HEAD>To The Japanese, Hirohito Has Become Emperor Showa</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Hirohito Funeral, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 To the rest of the world, he was known as Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>, but in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> his given name was seldom used. In Japanese he was simply called <PERSON> Tenno </PERSON> <PERSON> Heika </PERSON>, meaning His Majesty The Emperor. The foreign habit of using his name rankled some Japanese, who found it impolite, and unnecessary since to them there is only one emperor. Some Japanese complained that after his death it even became inaccurate to call him <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> because he has been given the posthumous name <PERSON> Showa </PERSON>. In Japanese histories, he will be recorded as Emperor <PERSON> Showa </PERSON>, the name he chose for his reign soon after he became emperor in 1926. It means Enlightened Peace, and has been succeeded by <LOCATION> Heisei </LOCATION>, or Achieving Peace, the name the government chose for the reign of <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s son <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> a few hours after the emperor died Jan. 7. But for the convenience of the rest of the world, which is not so able to keep track of the person behind the changed name, even official agencies have used the name <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> in English-language publications. The obituary issued in English by the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, which is supported by the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>, was headed `` His late Majesty The Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>.'' English-language newspapers published in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> quickly began using the name <PERSON> Showa </PERSON> for <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> after his death, but it did not become truly official until Jan. 31, when Emperor <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> conducted a ceremony in which <PERSON> Showa </PERSON> became the late emperor's posthumous name. A stone tablet placed in his tomb is engraved only with the posthumous name and the dates of his death and burial. The custom of renaming emperors after the completion of their reigns began after the death in 1912 of Emperor <PERSON> Meiji </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s grandfather In <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, years are numbered according to the emperor's tenure on the throne. Thus 1926 became Showa 1 as Crown Prince <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> ascended to the throne on Dec. 25 when his father, Emperor <PERSON> Taisho </PERSON>, died. The year 1927 was Showa 2, and 1989 was <ORGANIZATION> Showa </ORGANIZATION> 64 until <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s death on Jan. 7. Now this year is <ORGANIZATION> Heisei </ORGANIZATION> 1. The Japanese custom of changing imperial names is not unique among world royalty, where an individual may have a variety of names and titles in a royal career. In <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> became the Duke of York upon his marriage in 1986.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0710EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DiamondSamaritan     02-24 0349</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Diamond Samaritan,0360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jewels Returned to Idaho Farmer</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HERBERT G. McCANN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> businessman who lost $ 125,000 in uncut diamonds during his return from <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> got them back from a good Samaritan who found them on an airport sidewalk. <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Cacioppo </PERSON>, a 53-year-old office worker, received a $ 7,500 reward from <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> <PERSON> Von </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> of <PERSON> Rigby </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, for his good deed. <PERSON> Cacioppo </PERSON> returned the diamonds Thursday to a Walker business associate, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON>, during a meeting at the office of <PERSON> Cacioppo </PERSON>'s lawyer. `` Mr. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> was certainly pleased,'' <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON> said. `` We were a little surprised that they had n't been turned in earlier.'' He said they were virtually worthless uncut. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, 62, lost the diamonds at <LOCATION> O'Hare </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> on Friday, when he flew in from <LOCATION> Amsterdam </LOCATION>. He had returned from his travels with 76 uncut stones, worth about $ 220,000, which he had mined and purchased in <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION>. He carried them in two envelopes pinned inside his pants pockets. But when <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> reached the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> desk at <LOCATION> O'Hare </LOCATION>, one envelope was missing. He reported the loss Saturday. <PERSON> Cacioppo </PERSON>, of suburban Mount Prospect, was on the same <ORGANIZATION> KLM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> flight and said he found the envelope of diamonds on the sidewalk outside a terminal. `` I picked it up and put it in a pocket without looking in it because I was n't feeling too swift,'' he said. Because of his illness, <PERSON> Cacioppo </PERSON> said he stayed in bed Saturday and finally got up on Sunday to eat something. Then his wife asked about the package. `` I opened it and was n't sure what they were,'' he said. `` I took them to a friend, who told me he thought they were real diamonds.'' <PERSON> Cacioppo </PERSON> said he was excited and pretty nervous about the discovery, and at the insistence of a friend, contacted attorney <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Clifford </PERSON> for advice. <PERSON> Clifford </PERSON> phoned <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> police, who provided <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>'s telephone number. <PERSON> Cacioppo </PERSON>, who plans to use the money to finance his son's college education, said he did not regret giving up the diamonds. `` It was the right thing to do.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0712EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SnowballFight     02-24 0391</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Snowball Fight,0400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Amherst College, UMass Leaders Condemn Annual Fight</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AMHERST, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The heads of <ORGANIZATION> Amherst </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> have joined forces to condemn an annual snowball fight that nearly blinded a student in one eye this winter. The two school leaders released a statement Thursday blasting the Dec. 14 fight as <ORGANIZATION> Amherst </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> prepared a lawsuit against its neighbor, <ORGANIZATION> UMass </ORGANIZATION>, for building damages and medical costs incurred by the injured student, <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonya </PERSON>, 19, of <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. `` The freshman student had to undergo emergency surgery to save an eye. In light of this incident it has become clear to us that we can no longer tolerate the continuation of this ` tradition,''' <LOCATION> Amherst </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pouncey </PERSON> and UMass Chancellor <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Duffey </PERSON> said in the statement. <PERSON> Pouncey </PERSON> estimated damage to the school at more than $ 10,000 in the last several years. The two school leaders promised `` to educate our students about the dangers of this event and ... plan other measures to deter students from participating.'' <LOCATION> Amherst </LOCATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said it was unclear what further measures the schools will take. She said police have been unable to identify <PERSON> Gonya </PERSON>'s assailants from videotapes of the snowball fight. The fights usually take place on the first significant snowfall of the year. University students march to the <LOCATION> Amherst </LOCATION> campus a mile away and engage in battle. <ORGANIZATION> Amherst </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> will seek a preliminary injunction to allow campus and town police to arrest anyone found instigating a snowball fight at the school, said school spokesman <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>. The complaint against <ORGANIZATION> UMass </ORGANIZATION> is expected to be filed with <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in the next few days, according to <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Duffey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pouncey </PERSON> contended that the violence has escalated as students have begun packing snowballs with rocks that have broken several dormitory windows. <PERSON> Gonya </PERSON>, who may have been hit with a snow-covered rock, spent five days in hospitals in <LOCATION> Northampton </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. Doctors say his vision is blurry, but he will regain sight in a few months. In 1987, <ORGANIZATION> UMass </ORGANIZATION> paid more than $ 3,000 to <ORGANIZATION> Amherst </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> for damages from that year's snowball fight. The college claims UMass still owes $ 1,788 from last year's bombardment. `` I do n't think this university as an institution is liable for the behavior of its students once they leave the campus,'' <PERSON> Duffey </PERSON> has said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-JapanToday     02-24 0840</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan Today,0859</SECOND>
<HEAD>Today's Headlines Show Japan A Conqueror, Despite Wartime Defeat</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY THORSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Newspaper headlines show a vastly different <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> from the nation that <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> fought five decades ago in World War II. _ `` <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> Launches Scientific Satellite.'' A routine matter; EXOS-D is <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s 12th spacecraft to go into orbit to study the Earth. _ `` Japanese Airline Announces Multibillion-Dollar Airliner Purchase.'' Also routine; <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION>'s biggest customer is <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION>, and Wednesday's order by its competitor, <ORGANIZATION> All </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nippon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION>, could make ANA the biggest buyer of <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION>'s new 747-400s and hack $ 7 billion off the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade deficit. _ `` Funeral Diplomacy in Full Swing as World Leaders Arrive.'' Not routine; <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> buries Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> on Friday, the first imperial funeral in 62 years. Despite memories of aggression committed in <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s name in World War II, his funeral has brought dignitaries from more than 160 countries to <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> political science professor <PERSON> Seizaburo </PERSON> <PERSON> Sato </PERSON> said there were two reasons for so many countries to come: `` One is the increasing interdependence of the countries throughout the world. And the second is the increasing importance of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> in the world community.'' <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is rich. It is exerting international influence through financial power while its military strength is held in check by a postwar constitution that rejects force as a way of dealing with international disputes. In many ways, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is about as up to date as you can get. Its industrial prowess has made its automakers into global operators who produce more motor vehicles than <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> competitors. In high technology, the Japanese are at the forefront of superconductivity research and computer developments. The robust economy is propelled by the renowned diligence and managerial skill of the Japanese. At the government's urging, the economy is being restructured to depend more on domestic consumption than on the export drives that led to trade imbalances and friction with other countries. One problem is politics, which is widely held to have been corrupted by the tide of cash that has accompanied <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s rise to economic superpower. A headline in Thursday's <ORGANIZATION> Mainichi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shimbun </ORGANIZATION>: `` Questioning of Political Figures Looms.'' The story said that prosecutors investigating suspected bribery are on the verge of deciding whether to question 17 politicians about ethically dubious share transactions that benefitted them or their aides. Among those politicians is Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>, the chairman of the committee organizing <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s funeral and playing host to the presidents, kings, prime ministers and other foreign officials now in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. Also on the list are <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>'s predecessor, <PERSON> Yasuhiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakasone </PERSON>, and other leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> All have denied any wrongdoing. But some Japanese media are speculating that <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> will not last long, despite his announced intention to clean up political ethics starting right away. Still looming are those prosecutors, who arrested eight businessmen and bureaucrats in the last two weeks for questioning on suspicion of bribery or securities law violations but have n't touched the politicians yet The conservative party has governed since World War II with the exception of 10 months of socialist Cabinets in 1947-48. It holds fat majorities in both houses of the Diet, or Parliament _ 297 of 512 seats in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION> and 143 of 252 in the upper House of Councillors. In July, however, elections will be held for half the upper-house seats, and the ruling party is worried. A setback would probably send <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> to the back benches of the Diet, and the Recruit scandal has tainted so many leaders of his party that it's hard to guess who would succeed him. Another of Thursday's headlines: `` <ORGANIZATION> LDP </ORGANIZATION>'s Man Quits Race for Governor Over Recruit Funds.'' <ORGANIZATION> Recruit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> is the conglomerate at the center of the stock-trading scandal threatening the ruling party, and it has become anathema to have received its donations. The news story says that <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> persuaded his candidate, <PERSON> Kazuo </PERSON> <PERSON> Aichi </PERSON>, to withdraw from the <PERSON> Miyagi </PERSON> prefecture gubernatorial race because <LOCATION> Aichi </LOCATION> had received $ 60,000 in donations from Recruit since 1975. The conservatives' long grasp on power has both stultified politics and encouraged corruption, analysts say. It's also widely held that the conservatives' pro-business policies helped make <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> the peaceful economic giant it has become after being laid waste in the war. This conundrum of money politics linked with economic strength is making the Japanese especially thoughtful as they close a long chapter of history in burying their emperor of 62 years. A headline from Thursday evening's television news: `` Prosecutors Question Former NTT Head.'' <ORGANIZATION> NTT </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> Nippon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, is the most valuable company in the world in terms of stock market capitalization. Its former chairman, <PERSON> Hisashi </PERSON> <PERSON> Shinto </PERSON>, had a reputation as an exponent of clean business and politics until he resigned last year in disgrace after it was shown he had profited in the Recruit scandal's shady stock transactions.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Thorson </PERSON> is <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> news editor for The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CastrationBill     02-24 0264</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Castration Bill,0270</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Committee Approves Castration Bill</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Note contents</HEAD>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> committee has approved a bill that would permit a jail sentence to be suspended for a convicted rapist, criminal deviate or child molester who undergoes surgical castration. Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Worden </PERSON>, an investigator for the public defender in <LOCATION> Allen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> and a former constable, said he introduced the bill out of frustration that current criminal sanctions against rapists and child molesters do n't deter criminals from committing those acts again. `` You take the part away from the man that starts the process in the first place,'' said <PERSON> Worden </PERSON>, a Republican. The crimes now carry prison sentences of six to 50 years, depending on the circumstances. The bill, which the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Township </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> approved by a 5-3 vote on Thursday, calls for a convicted rapist, child molester or criminal deviate to be set free if after sentencing the person volunteers for surgical castration. The measure now goes to the full House. An opponent of the bill, Democratic Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON>, pointed out that many child molestation cases do n't involve intercourse. Offenders castrated after those crimes might still commit child molestation again, he said. `` I do n't think we ought to be setting our policy in <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> to follow Islamic countries,'' said <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON>. Another opponent, <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, argued that rape often is a crime of violence, not one motivated by sexual drives. Under <PERSON> Worden </PERSON>'s proposal, she said, a convicted rapist who had been castrated could go free to commit other violent acts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CDC--Cancer-Tanneries     02-24 0308</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CDC--Cancer-Tanneries,0316</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Report Cites `Elevated Risk' Of Cancer In Tannery Workers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal health officials have reported for the first time that some leather tannery workers exposed on the job to a controversial solvent are at increased risk for testicular cancer. An estimated 90,000 or more <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> workers are exposed to the chemical solvent dimethlyformamide, or DMF. The national <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday that while tannery workers exposed to the solvent are at `` elevated risk,'' DMF can not currently be shown as a `` definitive'' cause, and the exact risks require further evaluation. DMF is also used in the aircraft industry. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Occupational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> believes that about 94,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> workers are potentially exposed to the solvent. Three cases of testicular cancer were diagnosed in workers at a leather tannery in upstate <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Fulton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> between 1982 and 1984, triggering a state and federal investigation. The tannery had used DMF to help dyes seep into the leather being processed there. Three such cases among 80 workers on the plant's finishing line between 1975-87 is 41 times greater than would be expected statistically, which `` indicates an elevated risk for testicular cancer among finishing line workers,'' the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> said. Further, a survey of medical records found seven additional cases of testicular cancer in <LOCATION> Fulton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> males aged 20-54 between 1974 and 1987. `` Five of the 10 case-patients ... had been employed in leather-related occupations,'' the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> said in its report Thursday, prepared with <ORGANIZATION> NIOSH </ORGANIZATION>. Two of those five patients were from tanneries other than the original investigation site, <PERSON> Calvert </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> report noted that the tannery, identified in news reports as the Pan American tannery of <LOCATION> Gloversville </LOCATION>, had withdrawn its DMF dyes and replaced them with other materials, and other nearby facilities have done the same or are considering it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Sullivan Bjt   02-24 0769</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sullivan, Bjt,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sullivan Wins Endorsement, Sympathy from Senate Panel</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats and Republicans alike say they are concerned that the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> forced <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> Secretary-designate <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> to forgo nearly $ 300,000 he was entitled to from his medical school job. `` I feel what is being asked of you has not been asked of others in the past,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which endorsed <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> on a 19-0 vote Thursday. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON>, R-Mo., agreed, saying, `` It is grossly unfair to him ... My hope is we can reopen this issue with the White House.'' The issue of <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>'s severance pay from the <ORGANIZATION> Morehouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> came to light earlier this month when President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was trying to fend off ethical questions about several of his other top appointees. Committee members said they think the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> overreacted and forced <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> to give up the severance pay even though he was entitled to the money and accepting it would not have violated any ethical rules. At the time, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was on the defensive on ethics issues, with questions being raised about Defense Secretary-designate <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON>'s relationships with defense contractors, <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics chief <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyden </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>'s links to a communications corporation, Housing and Urban Development Secretary <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s acceptance of speaking fees exceeding <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> limits, and <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>'s acceptance of a lavish reception from a tobacco company. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said during his confirmation hearing Wednesday that he decided to forgo the severance pay because conflict-of-interest questions were raised in news reports about the arrangement. He said such questions could hamper his effectiveness and damage the image of <LOCATION> Morehouse </LOCATION>. `` I felt it was more important to clear up those questions by the action I took,'' he said. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, deputy director of the Office of Government Ethics, has said the office concluded that <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> was entitled to take the severance pay, but that he surrendered it before the opinion could be written. The White House did not return calls for comment on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s concerns Thursday <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said after the hearing that it appeared the nominee's decision to forfeit the money `` has been pressed on him,'' adding that <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> `` is not in any kind of position to make that kind of sacrifice. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> suggested that the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> might look into the matter and, if appropriate, clarify that ethics rules were not intended to apply to the kind of contractual arrangement <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> had with <ORGANIZATION> Morehouse </ORGANIZATION>. The severance pay generated more interest among committee members than <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>'s position on abortion, which had produced the most public controversy over <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s only black Cabinet nominee. In his opening statement to the committee, <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said he holds the same views on the issue as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: `` I am opposed to abortion, except when the life of the mother is threatened, or cases of rape or incest.'' He also said he supports an anti-abortion amendment to the Constitution with the same exceptions and would like to see the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> overturn its 1973 <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> ruling that legalized abortion. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> apologized to Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON>, R-Ore., for having `` misspoken'' his position on abortion in a private meeting with the senator when he reportedly said he favored retaining <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> He did not address remarks he made in an <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> newspaper that he supported abortion rights. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON>, acting president of <ORGANIZATION> Planned </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parenthood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, said following the committee vote that he was `` deeply troubled'' by <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>'s testimony. `` It is obvious that much political maneuvering has gone on in the weeks since Dr. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>'s appointment was first announced,'' <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON> said. The National Right to <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which was riled by <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>'s earlier remarks, welcomed the secretary-designate's statements opposing abortion However, <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, legislative director of the anti-abortion group, said he was disappointed that <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> refused to say whether he would extend a moratorium barring federal funding of medical research involving the transplant of fetal tissue. Questioned by Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>, R-Colo., <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said: `` I certainly would not want to do anything that would encourage abortion to be done in order to get fetal tissue. However, <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said he would not venture further on the issue until he reviews the recommendations of an advisory committee and consults with others about when, if ever, it might be appropriate to use fetal tissue for medical research. <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> said he was disappointed in <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>'s reply and, when the time came to vote on <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>'s confirmation, the senator simply voted `` present.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CampaignMoney Bjt   02-24 0876</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Campaign Money, Bjt,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrats Outspend GOP for Congress</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD L. VERNACI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats who control <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> now dominate the means of getting there, having spent more money, raised more and received more from special interests than the Republicans. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> put the price tag for electing the 101st <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last year at $ 458 million, not appreciably higher than it was to finance the campaigns of the 100th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> two years earlier. However, the commission, in a report issued Thursday, found that the Democrats now have surpassed the Republicans in raising money for <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> campaigns from political action committees. In the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the Democrats have widened the lead they held previously. One result is that Republicans suddenly are sounding like threadbare populists, while Democrats say they have made peace with the captains of industry who once regarded them with suspicion. `` All of the Democrats' expressions of concerns about the Republicans being the party of moneyed interests are shown up by these figures to be absolutely false,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which provides money and other help for GOP House candidates. However, <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senatorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said her party was able to recruit stronger candidates and they, in turn, were able to attract greater contributions. In the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, Democratic candidates got almost $ 24.9 million from political action committees, or PACs, while Republicans received $ 21.5 million, according to the <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> report. Until last year, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republicans had raised more money from PACs than did Democrats. In 1986 the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> raised $ 4.9 million more than Democrats from PACs, and in 1984 the margin was $ 1.6 million. The differences were far more pronounced in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, where the Democrats' control is more lopsided. House Democratic candidates received more than $ 66.9 million from PACs while Republicans got barely half that amount, $ 34.9 million. The gap between Democrats and Republicans in 1986 was $ 22 million and in 1984 it was $ 17 million. `` I think that PACs take a look at races and they take a look at candidates and I think, frankly, we just had better candidates,'' Ms. <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> said. `` They are not perceived as hostile to the business community, as they are n't. `` I think this is a party that realizes that certainly business is important to this country.'' Overall, the Democrats raised $ 107.4 million for <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> campaigns and spent almost $ 107.5 million in 1987 and 1988, the two-year period the election commission uses for compiling figures on the most recent election. The Republicans raised $ 91.3 million and spent $ 93.2 million. In the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> raised $ 159.8 million and spent $ 145.1 million while the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> received $ 116.6 million and spent $ 110.5 million. Another $ 1.3 million was spent by the 264 candidates who ran for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> as independents or on minor-party tickets. Republicans in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> have called for reform of the campaign finance system, saying it gives an unfair advantage to incumbents _ most of whom are Democrats. But while backing some means of limiting spending, the Republicans are against any reform that would involve public financing of congressional campaigns, as is now the case with presidential candidates. Ms. <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> said Republicans have become recent converts to the idea of finance reform. `` The Republicans did n't complain about the PAC system in 1986, when they controlled the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and their incumbents outspent our challengers 2-1 or 2 -LCB- -1,'' Ms. <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> said. Among Senate candidates, Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, R-Calif., spent far more than anyone else to keep his job _ nearly $ 13 million <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>'s Democratic opponent, <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, spent almost $ 7 million That was considerably less than in the 1986 campaign, when <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>'s colleague from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, Democratic Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, spent nearly $ 10.8 million to fend off Republican <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Zschau </PERSON>, who spent some $ 11.3 million. `` It's just because it's so damned expensive to run in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Royster </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>. `` The media market in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> is so massive and so expensive it virtually compels a candidate for statewide office there to raise more money than some would think is humanly possible.'' Ms. <PERSON> Royster </PERSON> said <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> accepts fund-raising as something he has to do to be in politics, but it `` drives him crazy.'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> raised $ 1.8 million from PACs, second only to Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, who raised more than $ 2.3 million. `` He says while he does not believe there is a conflict of interest involved in accepting <ORGANIZATION> PAC </ORGANIZATION> contributions, as long as there is a public perception that it is creating a conflict of interest, the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has a responsibility to do something about reform,'' Ms. <PERSON> Royster </PERSON> said. In the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, two Democrats who unsuccessfully sought an open seat in a <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> special election topped the spending list. <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Eskind </PERSON> spent nearly $ 2.6 million while <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Bredesen </PERSON> spent almost $ 1.9 million. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Clement </PERSON>, who beat them, spent just $ 938,492, but that brings the total spent on that one seat in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to nearly $ 5.4 million. <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> Democrat <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> won a seat in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and a distinction in the 1988 campaign. He spent nearly $ 7.4 million on his campaign and some $ 6.1 million of that was his own money, a record for the year. Much of the remainder was borrowed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0208EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PolicyReview Bjt   02-24 0676</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Policy Review, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Still no Word on How Bush Administration Plans
to Proceed</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than a month after taking office, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is still marking time on major foreign policy issues while the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> takes the initiative in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and nuclear weapons reduction talks remain on hold. The funeral diplomacy President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is conducting in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> _ 20-minute meetings with world leaders assembled for Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s rites _ is being described in some press accounts as `` mini-summitry,'' but the sessions are so brief they can only scratch the surface of difficult problems. In the meantime, Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> is winding up a whirlwind swing through the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> in which he offered <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> a resumption of diplomatic ties in exchange for attending a peace conference with the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. Apart from that proposal, the <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> trip is important because it marks a new initiative by President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to work with <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> moderates instead of the radical forces that are only on the periphery of events. That could make the Soviets an important player _ especially if <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> restores ties with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> after a lapse of more than 21 years. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s remark this week before his departure for <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> that the Soviets would _ and should _ play only a limited role in <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> diplomacy drew a light-hearted rebuke Thursday in <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> from <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>. `` That is sad,'' the foreign minister said. `` It injects a meaning of rivalry. If the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> can single-handedly resolve all the issues in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> we would welcome that. But they ca n't. There must be a collective effort to defuse the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> crisis.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he would not be rushed or stampeded by Soviet moves, but the pressure for a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> initiative is coming not only from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. Touring <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> capitals last week, Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> was urged by the British, <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION>, Dutch, Greek and French to seize on what they contend is growing Palestinian moderation and to get involved in peace-making. But <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> told them it would be a mistake to move too quickly or to aim too high if the situation did not call for it. And he was still cautious after <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> met in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> with <LOCATION> Egyptian </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>, King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> and President <PERSON> Chaim </PERSON> <PERSON> Herzog </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said there were `` perhaps some opportunities out there with respect to the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace process that have n't existed before.'' At the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, there was no word on when the policy review would be completed. Spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said `` policies are being looked at in a broad sense.'' He said experts were examining the issues and that policy-makers would get involved `` at the appropriate time.'' The review of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms control policy also is in low gear. Negotiations with the Soviets to reduce long-range nuclear weapons were to resume last week. The talks have been postponed indefinitely, although <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact will open separate negotiations on non-nuclear forces in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> on March 7. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration was aiming at a 50 percent reduction in strategic nuclear missiles, bombers and submarines. The two main obstacles to completing a treaty were the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Strategic Defense Initiative and finding ways to verify compliance with the accord. Policy-makers in the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration may be less committed to the search for a space-based defense against ballistic missiles. That could point to a compromise with the Soviets, who are determined to slow down the `` Star Wars'' program. On the other hand, <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON>, the assistant to the President for national security affairs, might push for development of a new mobile missile. That could complicate the verification problem, as well as require a re-calculation of some tentative weapons ceilings set during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. And completing the START treaty could be delayed even further.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schweid </PERSON> heads the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> staff.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0722EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MilitaryRecruiting     02-24 0453</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Military Recruiting,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Services Stretching to Meet Recruiting Goals</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A long-predicted downturn in military recruiting has begun, with <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> recruiters missing their quotas for the first time this decade, the Pentagon says. The other three military services managed to hit their enlistment quotas for the first quarter of fiscal 1989, but also are showing signs of distress, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday. The downturn has been predicted for more than a year, primarily because of the strong economy and a dwindling pool of 18-year-olds. `` But we need to act now to head off future recruiting problems,'' said <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, the assistant <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> secretary for force management and personnel. `` The first step is to work with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on military pay and to restore the value of recruiting incentives, advertising resources and education benefits,'' he said. `` Otherwise, we could begin the chain of events that led to the serious military manpower problems of the last decade.'' The latest manpower report covers the period from last Oct. 1 to Dec. 31. During those three months, the four services had a combined quota of 61,900 people. The services signed up 61,700 _ or just 200 shy of their goal. But breaking the statistics down by individual service, the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> fell short of its goal of 24,143 by 475 men and women _ the first such decline since 1980. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> managed to exceed its quarterly goal of 18,900 by signing up 19,200 men and women. But it did so by calling up, earlier than expected, volunteers who had joined the Delayed Entry Program to put off their military service by a few months. The <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> also had to increase the percentage of `` Category 4'' volunteers _ or low scorers on the military entrance test _ that they accepted, the report shows. The <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> had to accept almost 11 percent of its recruits from Category 4, more than double the 4 percent level maintained for the past three years. The <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> matched its recruiting goal during the quarter by bringing in 7,100 men and women, and the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> also matched its objective of 11,800. `` But the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> have reported they are working harder to meet their recruiting objectives,'' <PERSON> Green </PERSON> said. `` While the department still considers this recruiting performance to be good, environmental factors can not be ignored,'' <PERSON> Green </PERSON> said Thursday. `` Unemployment is at a 14-year low; the youth population will continue to decline through fiscal 1996, and budgetary pressures remain a concern.'' According to <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> projections, the pool of 18-year-olds in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has been declining for some years and wo n't begin increasing again until at least 1996
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0723EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Conservatives     02-24 0535</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Conservatives,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Conservative Conference Skeptical About Bush</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 While President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is half a world away, his supporters are trying to convince skeptical conservatives he is a worthy successor to their longtime hero <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> started the revolution,'' former Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> told Thursday's opening session of the <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Political </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>. `` I'll bet you right here and now today that <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, will consolidate it, strengthen it, broaden it, broaden its appeal.'' Long a conservative favorite, <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> now is housing secretary in the <ORGANIZATION> Bush </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s hand-picked chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, cited his involvement in three <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> presidential campaigns and then said, `` Another hero of mine is <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.'' Confronted by an openly critical delegate from <ORGANIZATION> Young </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Americans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> said that `` there is something to criticize about any president'' but conservatives were `` not going to get a better conservative elected the rest of this century than <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.'' YAF delegates from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> issued a `` report card'' on the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> presidency and said he `` has walked away from his conservative campaign promises that won him the election.'' The group gave <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> an `` F'' on aid to the Nicaraguan Contra rebels. `` It is well known that the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration will refuse to seek military aid to the freedom fighters,'' they said. When <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, the chairman of the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> YAF chapter, confronted the party chairman after the speech, <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> said, `` There's nobody who feels stronger about freedom fighters across this globe than <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.'' `` I would not judge things quite this early if I were you and I would n't be too harsh on him until you see what happens,'' said <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>. `` I have to judge him, sorry,'' said <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. `` I'm sorry, too,'' said <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is used to criticism from delegates to this annual meeting. Two years ago, as the fight for the 1988 Republican presidential nomination was heating up, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> outraged many conservatives by declining an invitation to address C-PAC. His six rivals appeared at the conference. Despite opposition from many conservative activists, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> easily won the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> nomination and a little more than a month ago succeeded <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in the White House. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was a regular participant at C-PAC meetings, and his retirement cast a long shadow on the current one. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Keene </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, one of the principal sponsors of the conference, noted that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had participated in 13 of the 16 C-PAC meetings, including all those held while he was president. `` His absence this year really is symbolic of another change within the movement, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> era, for all of its importance ... has ended,'' said <PERSON> Keene </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sergio </PERSON> <PERSON> Picchio </PERSON>, national chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Young </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Americans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION>, said the retirement of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> meant `` we do n't really have a leader that unifies the whole movement.'' When he and <PERSON> Keene </PERSON> were asked to identify likely successors to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as the leader of the conservative movement, the names they cited included <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, Sens. <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Trent </PERSON> <PERSON> Lott </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, and columnist and former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchanan </PERSON>. No one suggested <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> might succeed <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as the conservative hero.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-IndianInvestigation     02-24 0331</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Indian Investigation,330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senators Ask Bush to Take Initiative on Indian Reforms</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> should begin correcting `` the deplorable conditions on most Indian reservations'' by putting a someone in the White House in charge of issues affecting native Americans, say three senators who have been investigating those conditions. `` We urge you to consider our call for active and coordinated policy-making at all levels of the government, most notably at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>, and the departments of <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> and Justice,'' said Sens. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ariz </LOCATION>., <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>., and <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Daschle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.D. </LOCATION>, in a letter Thursday to By putting someone at the White House in charge of Indian issues, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would `` send a signal throughout the Indian communities of your dedication to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s first inhabitants,'' they said. The senators are members of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Indian Affairs and have been conducting special investigative hearings on a wide range of problems on reservations and within government agencies doing business with them. They said they wanted to meet as soon as possible with whomever <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> designates. The senators said their hearings will likely produce legislative proposals for correcting longtime deficiencies in government policies toward Indians. The White House could, in the meantime, get reform started, they said. In their letter, the senators said testimony before their committee casts doubt on whether the federal government is meeting its responsibility to protecting the rights of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION> to their land, water, forest, hunting, fishing and mineral resources. `` As we are sure you will agree, legal representation is at the very core of the federal government's trust responsibility to <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION>,'' they said. `` The inherent conflicts facing the federal trustee arise not only in legal matters, but also in policy decisions.'' The president was in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> Thursday for the funeral of the late Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>. There was no immediate response to the senators' letter from the White House
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0723EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Principals'Salaries     02-24 0366</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Principals' Salaries,0377</SECOND>
<HEAD>Top Principal Pay Exceeds $86,000</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE MITGANG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 High school principals enjoyed a 4.9 percent salary boost to an average of $ 52,987 this school year, reflecting what one official called a recognition that they are `` key players'' in the drive for better education. The lowest salary scale among senior high principals nationwide was $ 30,497, paid in one of the largest districts surveyed with at least 25,000 students, according to the survey by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Secondary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Principals </ORGANIZATION>. The report was released Thursday at the principal group's annual meeting being held this week in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. Data on more than 1,000 school districts around the country was collected by the <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, a private, nonprofit research arm created in 1973 by the principals' association and several other education groups. Pay increases exceeded the 4.1 percent overall inflation rate for 1988, but were not as steep as the 6-7 percent salary increases of the preceeding four years. `` I think it represents the fact that principals are being recognized as key players in the drive for better schools,'' said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hersey </PERSON>, the association's director of professional assistance. <PERSON> Hersey </PERSON> pointed out that more school districts are trying `` school based management,'' where individual schools are freed to try different strategies with less outside interference. That kind of reform `` requires highly skilled leaders who are paid well,'' <PERSON> Hersey </PERSON> said. The survey calculated average salaries by school district size, but did not identify individual school districts, nor did it give state-by-state averages. Average pay for high school principals was $ 52,987, up from $ 50,512 a year ago. But the averages ranged from $ 55,991 in districts of 25,000 students or more to $ 47,612 in districts with enrollments of 300 to 2,499. <PERSON> Hersey </PERSON> said in an interview that the highest salary found in the survey was $ 86,500 for a senior high school principal in a district in the <LOCATION> Northeast </LOCATION> with enrollment between 2,500 and 9,999 pupils. The survey also found that junior high and middle school principals averaged $ 49,427, up 5 percent from last year's $ 47,078. Elementary school principals' average pay rose 5.1 percent to $ 45,909 compared with $ 43,664 in 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0214EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Japan-AircraftTechnology     02-24 0509</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Aircraft Technology,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>FSX Deal Prompts Call for Putting Commerce Secretary in NSC</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARTON REPPERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The handling of a controversial aircraft technology deal with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> has prompted a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> congressman to call for making the secretary of commerce a statutory member of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. `` I strongly feel the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> must give more weight to long-term commercial interests in its national security decision-making,'' Democrat <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON> told a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel Thursday, explaining why he plans to introduce legislation next week. Critics of the deal involving <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s proposed <ORGANIZATION> FSX </ORGANIZATION> warplane _ to be built using technology developed for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> F-16 fighter _ contend it was negotiated by State and <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> department officials without participation by the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Trade Representative and other agencies. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, faced with mounting concern on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, has asked the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to review the strategic, commercial and technological aspects of the project and submit a combined report to the <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION> by March 10. <PERSON> Levine </PERSON> testified at a hearing of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on commerce, consumer protection and competitiveness. The panel's chairman, Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Florio </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, voiced serious concern over the <ORGANIZATION> FSX </ORGANIZATION> deal, under which <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Louis-based </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dynamics </ORGANIZATION> would join forces with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heavy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> to co-develop and co-produce the next-generation fighter. `` While this proposal may sound innocent, it could be troubling as far as our long-range national security is concerned,'' he said. `` Today, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, paying his respects on the death of of the emperor,'' he said. `` That is something he should do. But making massive amounts of sophisticated aircraft technology available to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, or anyone, is something that, quite possibly, the president should not do.'' Under current law, the <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION>'s permanent membership comprises the president, vice president, secretary of <ORGANIZATION> state </ORGANIZATION> and secretary of defense. Frequently, however, presidents designate other people as temporary members to participate in meetings on particular issues. Two former <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials, testifying before the panel, took differing positions on the advisability of going forward with the FSX deal. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Auer </PERSON>, now director of the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> and Cooperation at <ORGANIZATION> Vanderbilt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, argued that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> needs technologically superior fighters to help offset the threat posed by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> force of 2,000 aircraft. <PERSON> Auer </PERSON>, who in 1979-88 served in the office of the assistant secretary of <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> for international security affairs, also said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> stands to benefit from the FSX because `` state-of-the-art Japanese technology may well make the F-16 a better aircraft.'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaffney </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, director of the Center for Security Policy, a Washington-based think tank, said he saw no new Japanese technology from which the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should benefit. `` I, for one, am not persuaded that the co-cured composite wings and phased array radar technologies identified for ` flow-back' to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> under the <ORGANIZATION> FSX </ORGANIZATION> deal meet that test,'' said <PERSON> Gaffney </PERSON>, former deputy assistant secretary of <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> for nuclear forces and arms control policy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0214EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Budget     02-24 0655</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tax Panel Rejects Bush Proposals on Medicare, Capital Gains</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Press</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> quickly turned down President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposals to trim <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> costs by $ 5 billion and halve the capital gains tax rate. The panel, which has jurisdiction over tax and entitlement legislation, on Thursday approved a report by voice vote which said it has no intention of approving either of those requests from the new president. `` While the committee will work diligently in this area, it is not reasonable to expect providers or beneficiaries to absorb the level of reductions proposed by the administration in the <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> program for fiscal year 1990,'' the committee report said. The report did not mention the capital gains tax directly, but nonetheless made clear the committee backed the position of Chairman <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, D-Ill., that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposal would violate the spirit of fairness in the income tax overhaul <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> approved in 1986 `` While it may be appropriate for the committee to examine selective income tax issues in the 101st <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the committee does not anticipate consideration of major income tax changes or re-opening of any fundamental feature of the 1986 Tax Reform Act,'' Thursday's report said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has proposed cutting the tax rate on capital gains about in half, to 15 percent, contending the government would actually take in more money at the lower rate because of increased economic activity. Democrats and many economists say the proposal would be a revenue loser and a giveaway to the rich. Congressional analysts released a new estimate Thursday showing that after an initial jump in revenue next year, cutting the capital gains tax would reduce tax collections and cost the government $ 24.2 billion over the next six years. `` After an initial, and illusory, revenue gain, the president's proposal is shown for what it is, a tax break for the wealthy that will significantly increase the deficit,'' said <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, in a statement calling for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to withdraw the proposal `` It's a bad idea and should be discarded,'' he said. The administration and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> agree the cost of <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> has been soaring as the elderly population increases and medical fees grow faster than the general rate of inflation. Without restraints, the program would grow from $ 84.5 billion this year to $ 97.5 billion next year, according to White House estimates. In an effort to contain costs, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in his $ 1.16 trillion budget proposed holding <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> spending to $ 92.5 billion next year by imposing limits on payments to hospitals and doctors who treat <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> patients, and by cutting back the program's extra payments to teaching hospitals. `` If these modest reforms are adopted, the growth in Medicare payments between 1989 and 1990 will be reduced by $ 5 billion,'' the budget said. The committee, however, said it was not reasonable to expect either providers or recipients of Medicare to absorb the level of reductions proposed by the president, totalling $ 23.5 billion over three years. The new estimate on the capital gains tax, made by the staff of the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taxation </ORGANIZATION>, differs sharply from <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> estimates that the president's proposal would increase revenues by $ 9.3 billion during the 1989-94 period. `` Who's right?'' said Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, in a statement Thursday. `` That's the first thing we'll have to determine when the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> takes this matter up.'' Unlike <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, who opposes any change in the rate, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> has indicated he could live with a reduction in the capital-gains rate if the upper-income taxpayers who would benefit most were made to pay elsewhere for the cut. Capital gains are profits from the sale property such as stocks and real estate. Before the 1986 law, they had preferential treatment in the tax code but now they are taxed the same as other income at rates of 15 percent, 28 percent or 33 percent, depending on total income.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0215EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NuclearLicensing     02-24 0526</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuclear Licensing,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Proposed Rule Change Would Speed Nuclear Plant Licensing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A rule change being considered by the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> could help electric utilities get approval for new nuclear plants in half the time it currently takes, <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Lando </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> said in an interview. <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> said the proposed change could be approved by the commission as early as next month. The licensing reform idea is strongly supported by the utility industry, which blames regulatory barriers for its current financial problems. Environmental groups oppose the change, saying it would limit their ability to challenge applications for construction permits and operating licenses. `` This would be a giant step forward,'' <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> said in an interview in his <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> office. He declined to speculate on whether the four other commissioners would vote for the rule change, which he said does not require congressional approval. The commisioners were briefed on the inch-thick document by their staff on Wednesday. <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> said he had not yet studied the document in enough detail to be sure he would support the plan, but he repeatedly expressed enthusiasm for such changes. The plan would make three major changes in the licensing process: _ Allow utilities to get federal approval for a plant site long before committing themselves to actually building on it _ Encourage manufacturers to develop standardized reactor designs This would allow utilities to choose a design already certified by the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> and not requiring the current lengthy process of gaining design approval during the licensing process. _ Permitting utilities to get their plant construction permit at the same time as their operating license Currently this is a two-step process, and in some cases completed plants have stood idle because of failure to get an operating permit. `` The most important thing about this whole endeavor is to do as much up front in the whole licensing process as possible so you do n't have big major decisions for after the plant's been built,'' <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> said. He said utilities would be able to get plants built and licensed within six years, and possibly sooner, compared with the recent average of 13 years. The utility industry contends that long delays in obtaining <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> licenses is one reason that no new nuclear plants have been ordered since the mid-1970s. <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> said that with the rule change, some orders might be placed in the early 1990s. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's designated energy secretary, told his confirmation hearing Wednesday that streamlining the nuclear plant licensing process `` could get things moving, could relieve the kind of constipation we have in the process now.'' Environmental groups, however, have been critical of the regulatory reform proposals. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Mariotte </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resource </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, which is strongly critical of the industry and the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>, said the rule changes would unfairly limit the public's right to fight a plant licensing. He said the main purpose of the changes was to aid the nuclear industry. `` For them there is no future without'' the streamlined process, <PERSON> Mariotte </PERSON> said in a recent interview, adding that his group might challenge the plan in court.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0217EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;Ls     02-24 0801</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;Ls,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush S&amp;L Plan Facing Stiff Opposition</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s plan to close or merge insolvent savings and loan institutions over the next 30 years at a cost of $ 265 billion is encountering stiff opposition in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. After reading the 333-page bill submitted this week, both Democrats and Republicans who support a separate S & amp; L industry devoted primarily to home mortgages doubt it can survive under <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposal. `` There are too many officials within the administration who would just as soon see the home mortgage lending industry done away with,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Annunzio </PERSON>, D-Ill., and chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s financial institutions subcommittee <PERSON> Annunzio </PERSON> predicted that interest rates on home loans will rise dramatically if federally chartered S & amp; Ls are allowed to disappear, because the remaining financial institutions will not give such loans a high priority. That concern was bolstered Thursday by <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON>, who said his board is making it easier for bank holding companies to buy troubled <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls and questioned `` whether specialized fixed-rate residential lending institutions are needed today.'' <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON>, testifying before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said that whatever survives will not be the traditional S & amp; L that relied on short-term deposits from savers to finance long-term, fixed-rate mortgages. `` My own judgment is that, at the end of the day, thrifts will look a lot more like banks than they do now, but there will still be thrifts,'' he said. `` Ultimately it's going to be the markets that are going to determine the banking structure in this country.'' Treasury Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, testifying Thursday before the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, defended that `` market approach'' and said the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration will stoutly resist congressional efforts to re-regulate S & amp; Ls by further restricting their lending activities. The failure of many S & amp; Ls has been blamed on imprudent and sometimes fraudulent loans for shopping centers, office buildings and other high-risk ventures after <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> deregulated the industry in the early 1980s. <PERSON> Annunzio </PERSON>, with the backing of the industry, said he will try to amend <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposal to restrict 80 percent of future <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L lending to family housing within a 50-mile radius of each institution. He complained that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s plan requiring S & amp; L owners to put up more of their own capital to cover losses for non-residential lending `` does n't stop the crooks, it just makes them pay more to do business.'' <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> said <PERSON> Annunzio </PERSON>'s proposal would put <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls `` back into the same box that we took them out of'' through deregulation when they had to pay more interest on deposits than they were receiving on home mortgages. He predicted that more of them would go bankrupt as a result, even while acknowledging that the healthiest third of the industry contains precisely those S & amp; Ls that have maintained their emphasis on home mortgages. The administration's plan would require S & amp; Ls with less than 60 percent of their loans in residential housing to become banks eventually. It also would place them under the control of federal banking regulators for the first time, require them to meet the 6 percent capital-to-asset requirements of banks within two years, and open the way for banks to take over failed <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls immediately and healthy ones after two years. `` Rather than heal wounds, your plan may actually put it -LRB- the S & amp; L industry -RRB- out of its misery,'' Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>., told <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> `` The banking regulators are going to make S & amp; Ls look more like banks and I'm concerned about the effect of that on housing.'' <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> denied any `` intention on our part to deliver up the S & amp; L industry to the banking industry'' after contending earlier that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s plan `` assures the emergence of a healthy and strong S & amp; L industry.'' Meanwhile, <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION>, as the nation's lender of last resort, has entered into a support arrangement with the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> system, which lends to S & amp; Ls `` We stand ready to make certain the liquidity needs of the thrift institutions are met,'' <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> said, referring to the record $ 15 billion in deposits that were withdrawn from them in November and December. <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> also said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s financing proposal for protecting <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L depositors against losses `` should be adequate'' but conceded `` it's conceivable that there would be the need for a minor mid-course correction in a year or two. According to figures released Thursday by the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s plan calls for spending $ 265 billion through 2018: _ $ 52.2 billion to meet commitments made last year to rescue 205 institutions and prop up 17 others. _ $ 50 billion to shut down 350 more insolvent but still open S & amp; Ls through 1991. _ $ 89.2 billion through 2018 to pay the government's share of the interest on bonds sold to borrow the $ 50 billion. _ $ 73.4 billion to take care of additional S & amp; Ls likely to slip into insolvency between 1991 and 2018.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0220EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-FarEast     02-24 0433</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Far East,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Bush Rdp</HEAD>
<HEAD>Lawmakers Say Japanese Should Pay More</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s trip to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is leading to renewed calls in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for the island nation to share more of the burden for regional defense in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>. `` Our defense effort is 9.2 times greater than the Japanese effort, based upon the share of our respective gross national products we devote to defense,'' Sen. <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, said Thursday. `` The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> taxpayer is wondering whether this division of effort is fair any longer.'' <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> figures showed that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> spent $ 3.7 billion to maintain forces in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> in fiscal year 1985, and $ 5 billion the following. Those figures were the latest available, though costs have undoubtedly risen, he said. While the Japanese have announced their 1989 defense budget will increase by $ 1.56 billion to $ 31.6 billion over the previous year, <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON> said expenditures are actually declining as a proportion of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s GNP. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> for the funeral of Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> on Thursday. He has stepped gingerly when addressing the military spending issue, saying that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is making adequate contributions to regional defense but that any moves to do more will be welcomed by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Adm. <PERSON> Huntington </PERSON> <PERSON> Hardisty </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, said the Japanese are `` well on their way'' to building up a force capable of defending the sea lanes out to 1,000 miles. But <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>'s military is no match for the Soviets, who `` operate literally in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s back yard,'' he said. Although the Japanese have done much to increase defense spending, `` I believe they can and should do more,'' he said. Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McClure </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Idaho </LOCATION>, was more outspoken. `` I'm getting sick of everyone trying to soak Uncle <PERSON> Sam </PERSON>,'' he said, describing the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as `` guarantor of stability throughout the world.'' <PERSON> McClure </PERSON> said the American military presence is vital to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s security, yet <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> bears many additional expenses in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> including those of maintaining 44,000 troops in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and military bases in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> <PERSON> McClure </PERSON> said he thinks the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should be given space for overseas bases rent-free so long as <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> provides the troops and supplies. Sen. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, D-La., questioned the need to keep <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, hinting that some might be withdrawn if the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> faces tough budget choices `` I have n't figured out what the 44,000 troops are there for,'' he said. But <PERSON> Hardisty </PERSON> said a reduction of troops `` at this time would be premature'' in light of the continued threat from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890224-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-89 0235EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Tower-Debate     02-24 0735</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tower-Debate,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Committee Members Debate Perception, Process in Wake of Tower Defeat</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Tower Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
