<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 2327EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FiresRdp 2ndLd-Writethru a0702 07-09 0934</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fires Rdp, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0702,0955</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fires Rage in 10 Western States</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf to UPDATE with Alaskan fires almost out; SUBS
10th graf, `Nebraska Gov. ...,' with 2 grafs to CLARIFY that Orr's declaration
released state money; picks up 11th graf, `The 6-mile-wide ...' SUBS grafs
15-21, `But higher ...,' with 7 grafs to UPDATE size of New Mexico, California
fires, UPDATE with evacuated residents allowed to return home; picks up
22nd graf, `In Colorado ...' Should stand for AMs</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto SCO1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROGER PETTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Fires tore through brush and trees across the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> on Sunday, with one threatening an old cavalry fort where Sioux Chief Crazy Horse was killed, but lower temperatures and higher humidity were helping firefighters. Fires burned out of control in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. A fire in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> was contained. Light rain and lower temperatures all but extinguished three large wildfires in interior <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, including one that charred 24,000 acres. The federal <ORGANIZATION> Boise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interagency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> said about 31,000 fires had been reported through Sunday, and about 1.5 million acres have burned this year, according to information officer <PERSON> Milt </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. By the same time last year, 55,000 fires had been reported and 765,000 acres blackened. The center was coordinating the efforts of 10,000 firefighters, he said. It also had 50 air tankers in use, up from 42 on Saturday. `` We're having some storm activity bringing some relief in the <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION>, but when it moves east, it's creating more fires due to lightning in eastern <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said. The biggest fire in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> was the <ORGANIZATION> Diamond </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Creek </ORGANIZATION> fire, at 12,500 acres, in eastern <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, but it was 80 percent contained by Sunday morning, said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Plumb </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Moab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> District </LOCATION>. Efforts were focused on keeping it out of a 50,000-acre state roadless area, similar to a federal wilderness zone, she said. `` It's real wild, rugged country, real heavy timber,'' Plumb said. `` We dont want it to get in there.'' Several other fires in the state were nearing containment by fire lines, officials said. A lightning-sparked fire burned along a 20-mile front in northwestern <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, threatening the community of <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON> and forcing the evacuation of more than 629 people from a hospital, nursing home and <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Robinson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> issued an emergency declaration, making state money available, and ordered <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> troops to help fight the fire. The blaze was within a half-mile of the old <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Robinson </LOCATION>, where Crazy Horse was killed by guards in 1877, and fire burned to within 1 -LCB- miles of <LOCATION> Crawford </LOCATION>, a city of 1,300, authorities said. The 6-mile-wide blaze scorched 50,000 to 100,000 acres, said deputy state fire marshal <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Larson </PERSON>. `` We could see whole lines of trees exploding,'' said <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON>, a state game and parks commissioner who flew over the fire. A mushroom cloud of smoke was visible about 90 miles away. The fire burned 10,000 to 12,000 acres of trees, scrub and grassland in the 22,000-acre park's rugged canyons, estimated Park Superintendent <PERSON> Vince </PERSON> <PERSON> Rotherham </PERSON>. It also charred part of a wildlife refuge and private land. Temperatures around 90 degrees and variable wind complicated firefighting efforts, officials said. But higher humidity and less wind Sunday helped firefighters get the upper hand on the 10,025-acre Divide Fire in the <ORGANIZATION> Gila </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> in southwestern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Ness </PERSON> said conditions Sunday were favorable to containing the blaze, started by lightning June 30. Higher humidity, lower temperatures and less wind in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> also helped crews fighting fires that had burned more than 40,000 acres of forest, range and brush and most were more than 50 percent contained. Thunderstorms were reported overnight. A 1,000-acre fire in the Grand Canyon briefly threatened President <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>'s hunting cabin, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON>. In northeastern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, a wind-fanned fire had destroyed 3,500 acres of remote brush land and seven buildings by Sunday, and firefighters constructed a firebreak as wide as an eight-lane highway across its southern path. A separate 2,800-acre brush blaze blamed on arson threatened the <LOCATION> Ventana </LOCATION> wilderness in Big Sur. Between 30 and 50 families evacuated Saturday night from two sparsely populated areas in the 3,500-acre fire's path were allowed to return to their homes Sunday, officials said. The fire, on the eastern slopes of the <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, had destroyed three homes, a garage, three barns and numerous sheds and other small structures, officials said. The Butte fire five miles east of <LOCATION> Oroville </LOCATION>, north of <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION>, was brought under control Sunday morning after destroying four homes and six outbuildings, said D.J. <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON>, a state forestry department spokeswoman. A brush fire burned 2,000 acres in the <LOCATION> Laguna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> about 40 miles east of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, sweeping through a campground and the Cuyapaipe Indian Reservation. People were asked to evacuate the campground, and firefighters protected buildings on the reservation. In <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, a 100-acre fire destroyed at least five homes and forced the evacuation of five subdivisions near <LOCATION> Sugarloaf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> about 25 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, officials said. Archaeologists from around the <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION> were called to help firefighters at <LOCATION> Mesa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Verde </LOCATION> <LOCATION> National </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> in southwestern <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> protect ancient Indian relics from a 700-acre blaze. Numerous lightning-started fires were reported elsewhere around the state. <PERSON> Ann </PERSON>'s fire in the <ORGANIZATION> Bridger-Teton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> of western <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> slowed over the weekend, thanks partly to cooler weather, fire officials say. It was about 60 percent contained Sunday after having burned at least 3,477 acres in five days, according to forest spokesman <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Christian </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 2350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Argentina 3rdLead-Writethru a0729 07-09 0613</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Argentina, 3rd Lead-Writethru, a0729,0628</SECOND>
<HEAD>Menem Warns of `Surgery Without Anesthesia' to Break Ruinous Inflation</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: LEADS with 2 grafs to restore reference to inflation nearing
1 million percent a year; pickup 3rd graf pvs, `We have...' ^By ED McCULLOUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The new government Sunday announced economic austerity measures that included a 53 percent devaluation of the currency and massive utility rate increases in an all-out effort to halt soaring inflation. Earlier Sunday, President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> said Argentines must brace for `` a very tough period'' as the government tries to halt inflation approaching 1 million percent a year. `` We have to conduct major surgery without anesthesia,'' <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> said as he arrived at Government House the morning after he was sworn in. `` If not, <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> has no future.'' In a televised speech, Economy Minister <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> Roig </PERSON> said that beginning Monday the austral will sell for 655 per $ 1. He also announced that natural gas rates will rise by 650 percent for industrial users and 200 percent for homeowners. Natural gas is the principal source of energy for home heating in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>. State-set rates for electricity, public transportation and other public services will also increase substantially, <PERSON> Roig </PERSON> said in his 20-minute address. But he did not specify amounts or say when they would take effect. Public Works Minister <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Dromi </PERSON> said Saturday that gasoline prices would increase by 500 percent. To help Argentines cope with the increases, the government will roll back the price of bread and other basic foods and set price guidelines, <PERSON> Roig </PERSON> said. In addition, most workers next week will get a special one-time payment equivalent to about $ 13. Businesses raised the price of bread and milk by more than 150 percent on Thursday and Friday in anticipation of government price controls. <PERSON> Roig </PERSON> did not say how long the government price guidelines on a variety of supermarket items would be in effect. Argentines stocked up at supermarkets when they received monthly salaries at the end of June, and car owners lined up at gas stations all weekend to top off their tanks. <PERSON> Roig </PERSON> said the government utility rates were `` absurdly low,'' and that new rates would be `` very stiff.'' <PERSON> Menem </PERSON>, who attended a Mass Sunday morning at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cathedral </ORGANIZATION> and presided over a military parade, said <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> will have to `` endure a very tough period in order to emerge from this crisis.'' The inflation and the worst recession in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>'s 173-year history have severely hurt real wages in this <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> nation of 31 million. Low monetary reserves and a $ 60 billion foreign debt leave <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> little room for easy solutions. The 12-month cost-of-living increase based on June's inflation rate of 114.5 percent amounts to a staggering 948,597 percent. In his inauguration speech Saturday, <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> called for national unity. He has gone out of his way since he was elected May 14 to placate the military, smooth relations with the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, and coordinate plans with labor unions, business groups and rival political parties. It remains to be seen, however, how Argentines who have tightened belts for several months will react to the measures, and whether <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> will carry them out in the face of public resistance. Labor unions staged general strikes against former President <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> when he tried austerity measures last year. The measures triggered looting and rioting in several cities. The <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> is virtually without foreign reserves, except for an estimated $ 1 billion in gold, and tax revenue has shrunk. <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> will find it hard to borrow from abroad, as <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> did, because the country is about $ 4.5 billion behind in interest payments on the foreign debt.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MissingWomen 1stLd-Writethru a0604 07-09 0483</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Missing Women, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0604,0490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Suspect in Kansas Slaying Decides To Fight Extradition</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 7th graf, `He said...' with 3 grafs on Grissom's questioning;
picks up 8th graf pvs, `So far...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAY JORDEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An itinerant painter sought for questioning in the killing of a <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> woman and the disappearances of three other women has decided to fight extradition, authorities said Saturday. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Grissom </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 28, was captured Friday by police and <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents at <LOCATION> Dallas-Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, after an anonymous tipster told authorities <PERSON> Grissom </PERSON> would be meeting an arriving passenger. Police in the <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Overland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> said jewelry and other belongings of at least one of the missing women were recovered at the airport from a car stolen in <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> that <PERSON> Grissom </PERSON> allegedly drove to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Overland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> police began seeking <PERSON> Grissom </PERSON>, an avid bodybuilder, on June 27 in connection with the disappearance of 24-year-old <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON>, who was reported missing June 16. <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> investigators also said <PERSON> Grissom </PERSON> planned a date with <PERSON> Terri </PERSON> <PERSON> Maness </PERSON>, 25, of <LOCATION> Wichita </LOCATION> on June 7, the night she was strangled and stabbed repeatedly in her home. Police also want to question him about the disappearances of roommates <PERSON> Theresa </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> and <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rusch </PERSON>, both 22, of <LOCATION> Lenexa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Keller </PERSON> said. He was seen June 24 at a party given by the women, who were reported missing June 26. `` We found items linking the two women to him,'' <PERSON> Keller </PERSON> said. `` Credit cards and jewelry identified as belonging to one of the <LOCATION> Lenexa </LOCATION> women were found in his car.'' But authorities said <PERSON> Grissom </PERSON> was n't providing additional information about the three missing women. `` He talks a lot,'' and has admitted knowing the women, `` but he's just not giving you anything you can make a case on,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Wichita </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON>, who was in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> on personal business at the time of <PERSON> Grissom </PERSON>'s arrest. <PERSON> Keller </PERSON> said Ms. <PERSON> Rusch </PERSON> was last seen using a bank card machine near <LOCATION> Grandview </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>. `` We have photos of her from the -LRB- card -RRB- machine and she appeared injured,'' said <PERSON> Keller </PERSON>. She also made withdrawals totaling $ 2,900 to $ 3,200, he said. So far, <PERSON> Keller </PERSON> said, the three suburban <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> women have not been found and only the body of the <LOCATION> Wichita </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, woman has been recovered. <PERSON> Grissom </PERSON> has not been charged in the slaying or disappearances. <PERSON> Grissom </PERSON> is being held on <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> warrants for parole violation and felony theft. He initially agreed to return to <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> to face the charges, but decided Saturday to fight extradition, which can take 60 to 90 days, <PERSON> Keller </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Grissom </PERSON> was convicted at age 16 of fatally bludgeoning a 72-year-old <PERSON> Lansing </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, woman with a railroad spike. <PERSON> Keller </PERSON> said <PERSON> Grissom </PERSON> spoke with investigators Friday about unsolved murder cases in <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> but he had not admitted being involved in any crimes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 0225EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-BoyImpaled     07-09 0186</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Boy Impaled,0189</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boy Dangles From Fence When Spike Goes Through Neck</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY26</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A boy who was impaled by his neck on an iron spike after he lost his balance and slipped while climbing over a 6-foot-high fence was in serious condition Saturday at a hospital, officials said. The picket went up from under 15-year-old <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON>'s neck and out his mouth, police and fire officials said. Rescue workers were forced to prop him up with a ladder while they cut a section from the fence. `` The fence had to go with him to the emergency room,'' said Fire Department Capt. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>, who helped with the rescue. Once at the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> rescue workers scrubbed up and worked with the doctors to remove the spike from the boy's mouth, <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said. The spike just missed the boy's jugular vein. The accident occurred about 5:30 p.m. near the boy's apartment building in the borough of <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION>. The boy dangled from the fence for several minutes before rescue workers arrived. He was conscious through the ordeal, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 0218EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Earthquake 1stLd-Writethru a0608 07-09 0295</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Earthquake, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0608,0303</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Earthquakes Rock Tokyo</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with six grafs to UPDATE with 11 injured; pickup graf
six pvs `Trains on...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two strong earthquakes shook the <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> area within a minute of each other Sunday morning, swaying office buildings and knocking goods off shelves. Eleven people were reported injured. The first, more powerful earthquake at 11:09 a.m. registered 5.5 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, the <ORGANIZATION> Meteorological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said. The second quake was slightly weaker, but no Richter reading was immediately available. In <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, office buildings swayed. In the city of <PERSON> Ito </PERSON>, on the <LOCATION> Izu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> peninsula </LOCATION> about 80 miles to the southwest, parked motorcycles were knocked over, and canned goods fell from some store shelves. Some of the injuries, which were all blamed on the larger quake, occurred when furniture fell on people in their homes, police said. However, they said no one was reported hospitalized. About 4,000 people were without electricity in the town of <LOCATION> Usami </LOCATION>, police said. The bigger quake was centered in the ocean off the peninsula about 60 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, officials said. Trains on nearby land were delayed for about a half hour, a <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railways </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said it was still investigating damage. At least 17,760 small quakes, 380 of them strong enough to be felt by residents, have shaken the <LOCATION> Izu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> peninsula </LOCATION> since Tuesday, the <ORGANIZATION> Meteorological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said. The quakes have caused burst water pipes, gas lines leaks, and damages to roads and roofs. The open-ended <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale measures the magnitude of a quake at its epicenter. An increase of one unit means a tenfold increase in ground motion. A quake that measures 5 can cause considerable damage, and one that measures 6 can cause severe damage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 0942EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w BC-Bush-Europe 1stLd-Writethru a0612 07-09 0585</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush-Europe, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0612,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Promises Delicacy in Encouraging Changes in Poland, Hungary</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: To UPDATE with remarks to reporters, Ledes with new 6 grafs;
picks up 4th graf pvs: He also ....</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> set out Sunday on a journey to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, saying <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> `` now dreams of being whole and free'' after four decades of division put promising delicacy in fostering that movement. In a departure ceremony at <ORGANIZATION> Andrews </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` My visit underscores the growing importance our nation sees in the changing face of <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>.'' Trying to encourage political and economic freedom in communist <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was flying first to <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> for a two-day stop, where he will meet with government leaders and address the Parliament. In the wake of recent elections, nearly half of its lawmakers are members of the once-banned Solidarity union. Meeting with reporters, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> described the diplomatic situation `` as a little delicate.'' He said he wanted to avoid an appearance of trying to put Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> `` in a box by throwing strains on the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact.'' But, he added, `` I'm not going to back off my principles just because it might offend Mr. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. I will give my aspirations for a <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> whole and free. What we want to do is encourage them.'' Leaders of both the governments and democratic movements in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> `` do n't want overpromise,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. He declined to discuss an aid package for <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, but said some specifics would be offered. He also will visit the <LOCATION> Baltic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> city of <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> and deliver a speech outside the <LOCATION> Lenin </LOCATION> shipyard where the Solidarity labor movement was born. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will fly to <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> on Tuesday, becoming the first American president to visit <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. After two nights in <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will go on to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> for a bicentennial celebration of the French Revolution and the annual economic summit of the seven major industrialized countries. Concluding a 10-day trip, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will stop in the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> for one day, the first president ever to visit there. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said his journey `` underscores the tremendous changes, challenges and opportunities ahead of us.'' He described <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> as `` nations on the threshold of a new era, nations where the spirit of freedom is strong. `` In both countries,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` we're witnessing remarkable changes, welcome developments no one would have though possible even a year ago. `` New voices are shaping the course of national affairs and both countries are on the path towards economic rebirth and political pluralism,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. He said that `` <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> is at a turning point. `` A continent cruelly divided for more than four decades now dreams of being whole and free,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` Our task is clear: to see that we mend old divisions, that we fulfill the decades-old dream and that the new <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> emerges _ secure, prosperous, peaceful and free,'' the president said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said that <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> was in the midst of change, `` a time of unprecedented opportunity for peace, prosperity and freedom.'' At the summit in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will meet with the leaders of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. He said that in addition to economic problems, the leaders will grapple with environmental issues such as global warming, deforestation and ocean pollution. `` We know there are no easy solutions,'' the president said. `` But, provided we work together, I'm confident we can find common solutions to problems none of us can solve alone.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1121EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-ToiletCampaign     07-09 0332</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Toilet Campaign,0340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officials Want Cleaner Toilets to Lure Tourists</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tourism officials have started a campaign to clean up the nation's public bathrooms, setting up a phone hotline for complaints and even peering into toilet bowls. The officials are preparing for `` Visit Malaysia Year 1990.'' They are trying to address a common complaint of tourists, who say the country's public bathrooms are dirty, poorly maintained, and lacking such amenities as toilet paper and towels. Some have also complained about unflushed toilets. On Saturday, a 10-member team from the capital's <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, led by agency chief <PERSON> Zainol </PERSON> <PERSON> Arriffin </PERSON> <PERSON> Pawanchee </PERSON>, inspected bathrooms and kitchens in four hotels in <LOCATION> Kuala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lumpur </LOCATION>. The New Sunday Times said three hotels were cited for failing to keep their kitchens clean, while another was warned to keep its bathroom and kitchen tidy. The newspaper quoted <PERSON> Zainol </PERSON> as saying many public bathrooms, especially in shopping complexes, are dirty and missing hand dryers, towels and toilet paper. In most complexes, a small fee is charged to use the bathroom. To boost the campaign, the Minister of Culture and Tourism, <PERSON> Sabbaruddin </PERSON> <PERSON> Chik </PERSON>, on June 30 made a surprise check on public bathrooms in <LOCATION> Kuala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lumpur </LOCATION>. He took the press in tow. A picture in a local paper showed him gazing into a toilet bowl. The Ministry has also opened a `` Toilet Operations Room'' for the public to phone in complaints. On Saturday, it handled 30. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Straits </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> put the issue this way in an editorial July 2: `` Anyone who has ever had to hold his breath in a public toilet will agree that unbelievable as it may seem, there is a pressing need to educate Malaysians on how to use toilets and how to keep them clean.'' A similar toilet campaign also is under way in <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION>. Beginning July 1, anyone caught failing to flush a public toilet faced a fine of up to $ 77. Repeat offenders could be fined as much as $ 515.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Vietnam-Videos     07-09 0157</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Vietnam-Videos,0164</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vietnam Cracks Down on ``Reactionary'' Videos</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> has slapped a ban on rock videos and movie videotapes with `` reactionary and depraved'' contents. A <ORGANIZATION> Vietnam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> report, monitored Sunday in the Thai capital, said it was illegal to import, export or circulate such material. It did not specify what constituted `` reactionary and depraved'' contents. The announcement, made Friday in <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> by Minister of Culture <PERSON> Tran </PERSON> <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Phac </PERSON>, also banned the sale and showing of the videos. The agency said hotels catering to foreign tourists could be granted exemptions but must first submit the videotapes to government authorities for review. Hollywood movies on video and American rock cassettes have enjoyed growing popularity in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. Even films like `` Rambo: First Blood Part II'' have been widely circulated. In that movie, the American hero wipes out Vietnamese communists by the dozens as he searches for American prisoners of war in the country.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Israel-Films     07-09 0176</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Israel-Films,0181</SECOND>
<HEAD>Palestinian, Israeli Films Awarded Festival's First Prize</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Jewish Film Festival gave first prize to the first Israeli movie on the Palestinian uprising, and its best short film award went to one directed by a Palestinian refugee, a jury member said Sunday. An international jury awarded the $ 35,000 first prize to <PERSON> Isaac </PERSON> <PERSON> Zepel </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeshuron </PERSON>'s `` Green Fields,'' produced by <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Tur </PERSON>, said jury member and film critic <PERSON> Yehuda </PERSON> <PERSON> Stav </PERSON>. The movie portrays three generations of an Israeli family caught in the violence of the 19-month-old uprising. <PERSON> Yeshuron </PERSON>, a leading Israeli director, condemns his characters who accept violence as the only means of dealing with the revolt. `` The Shelter,'' by Palestinian director <PERSON> Rashid </PERSON> <PERSON> Mashrawi </PERSON>, which describes a day in the life of two <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> laborers in <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION>, was awarded the $ 10,000 prize for best short film. <PERSON> Mashrawi </PERSON> is from the Shati refugee camp in the occupied <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. The 10-day festival that ended Saturday featured more than 130 films from 40 countries, but competition is only among movies made in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-India     07-09 0216</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-India,0223</SECOND>
<HEAD>Explosions Rock Northern Town After Buddhist and Moslem Clashes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two explosions rocked a town in northern <LOCATION> Jammu-Kashmir </LOCATION> state Sunday, two days after clashes between Buddhists and Moslems injured at least 25 people, news reports said. No one was killed or injured in the pre-dawn blasts in Leh, according to <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> news agencies. `` The explosions occurred at deserted places during the night,'' <ORGANIZATION> PTI </ORGANIZATION> quoted Leh police chief G.J. <PERSON> Pandit </PERSON> as saying. Leh, a city of 100,000 people, is about 450 miles north of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>. Authorities on Friday imposed an indefinite curfew on the city after clashes between Buddhists and Moslems. Authorities said the brawls were sparked by an argument between two youths. Several shops were set on fire and taxi drivers were dragged from their vehicles and beaten, the news agencies said. The army was deployed to help restore order after police using tear gas and batons failed to stop the fighting, the agencies said. About 90 million Indians, or 11 percent of the country's 880 million people, are Moslem. <LOCATION> Jammu-Kashmir </LOCATION> is the only state where Moslems are in a majority. But in Leh, more than 90 percent of the people are <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION>. Only about 6 percent are Moslem.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Japan-Quakes     07-09 0303</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Quakes,0313</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Quakes Shake Tokyo Area, 18 Injured</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two strong earthquakes hit southwest of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> within a minute of each other Sunday, triggering landslides and injuring at least 18 people, police said. They were among thousands of tremors that have rocked the area in 10 days. The first quake, registering 5.5 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, occurred at 11:09 a.m., the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Meteorological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said. The second was slightly weaker, but its precise magnitude was not immediately known. The first quake was centered in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Atami </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> Izu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> peninsula </LOCATION>, about 60 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, officials said. It was the strongest among at least 19,363 tremors _ 433 of them strong enough to be felt by residents _ that have shaken the <LOCATION> Izu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> peninsula </LOCATION> since June 30, the agency said. Landslides occurred at 16 places and roads were cracked in 10 places in <LOCATION> Ito </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> Izu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> peninsula </LOCATION>, said a police official of <LOCATION> Shizuoka </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prefecture </LOCATION>, or state. Some of the injuries, all blamed on the larger quake, occurred when furniture fell on people in their homes, police said. Two people were burned from spattering oil in a kitchen, said the police official on condition of anonymity. The official said 2,600 households lost electricity for four hours. <PERSON> Masayoshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Abe </PERSON>, a railway official, said the region's high-speed commuter trains were stopped for up to 61 minutes, delaying about 20,000 people The agency gave no reason for the increased seismic activity. The Richter scale is a gauge of the energy released by an earthquake, as measured by the ground motion recorded on a seismograph. Every increase of one number means that the ground motion is 10 times greater. A quake of magnitude 5 can cause considerable damage in populated areas, while one measuring 6 can cause severe damage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-SecretaryofMeat Bjt   07-09 0976</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Secretary of Meat, Bjt,1000</SECOND>
<HEAD>Beef in Her Past, She's the Secretary for Meat</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> is a beef person. She grew up on it and remains a great fan of the standing rib roast. She was the first woman ever to head the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cattlemen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. She is a fifth-generation cattle raiser. Now she regulates the industry she once promoted. But she rejects the idea that as assistant secretary of agriculture for marketing and inspection services, she might someday have to choose between her loyalties to beef and her responsibilities to government. Meat has been Topic A all her life. Her husband, <PERSON> Cedric </PERSON>, also comes from a cattleman's heritage. Both she and her husband come from families that have raised cattle for generations. She is no stranger to blue jeans and hard work. While she had to separate herself from the operation to accept the $ 80,700 presidential appointment earlier this year, her husband and son still run a 500-head, 4,500-acre ranch near <LOCATION> Wacahoota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. She was an equal partner `` I always knew what <PERSON> Cedric </PERSON> was paying for corn,'' she once told an interviewer. She was a conservative Democrat _ she underscores the `` conservative'' _ until 1988, when she campaigned for President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. She ran twice for the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> as a Democrat, but lost both races. Then Mrs. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 50, became involved in beef politics as head of the <ORGANIZATION> Cattlemen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, one of the most powerful agricultural lobbies. She helped drag a reluctant industry toward feeding and breeding changes that produced leaner meat, but it was a struggle. `` We were very slow to respond,'' she says. `` You could see the train coming.'' `` I really do enjoy beef,'' she says and usually eats it once a day. `` I am not a great lover of fish-fish,'' she says. She has come to accept it but wo n't cook it: `` too messy.'' She'll eat it when <PERSON> Cedric </PERSON> cooks it, which, she says, he does well. Her new job puts her in the midst of a dozen arguments, including controversies over meat inspections _ the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration wanted the industry to do more, and the government less _ and over <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s consumption of red meat. The health side of government says Americans eat too much of it. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>, in a study that came out last March, concluded in the most comprehensive evaluation ever of the effects of diet on health that this country consumes too much fat and gets too much of it from meat. The study advised `` eating lean meat in smaller and fewer portions.'' `` No, I do n't think we consume too much,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said in an interview. She said the beef industry already has addressed the fat issue by putting leaner beef on the market. `` We're producing a product that does not have the fat -LRB- it once did -RRB-,'' she said. `` We recognized that it was the fat that was the culprit, not the product. And we have addressed that in genetics and breeding. You can buy lean meat.'' At the same time, Mrs. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> endorsed labeling the fat content of meat _ a position that could raise hackles among cattlemen. `` Labeling has certain strong advantages,'' she said. `` The consumer wants to know. The only way they're going to know is to be able to read something that -LRB- says -RRB- this is what the product has in it.'' It is a sensitive issue. <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Winslow </PERSON>, director of nutrition policy for Mrs. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>'s old organization, the 35,000-member <ORGANIZATION> Cattlemen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said it will be discussed at the group's meeting in <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, this month `` Proud producers might view the issue as a positive opportunity to highlight the nutritional density of the product, beef,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Winslow </PERSON>, adding that her own recommendation will be for labels that show how much fat remains after cooking _ after fat has been trimmed and drained away. She said the stress on fat has turned attention away from the high iron, zinc and vitamin B-12 contents of beef. Mrs. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>'s pro-label stand and her support for federal inspection of seafood _ an issue on which the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has yet to take a stand _ wins applause from the ever-vigilant consumer movement. `` For an industry person, she's more of an activist than you'd expect,'' says <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Haas </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> `` She has an understanding about what can be done. She has been out front on fish inspection.'' But on some other food issues in her domain, Mrs. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> tends toward caution. She is waiting for more study to be conducted before taking a stand on whether meat producers who give their cattle no hormones or other growth-enhancing drugs should be able to label their product `` organic'' or `` natural.'' Some cattlemen who have been using a `` natural'' label and who have found a market among health-conscious consumers say the government has been trying to get them to drop the label. Mrs. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said her discomfort with the label is that `` we have never defined ` natural.' Remember that every animal in order to be bred has hormone in it. The problem that has arisen is, does the consumer understand this. You want to know that your label is truthful.'' On veal issues, Mrs. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> dodged questions, saying she was n't familiar with them The Center for Science in the Public Interest and other consumer groups contend that the way some veal calves are raised _ kept in dark pens so small the calf ca n't turn around and fed only a liquid diet to keep the meat light-colored _ are inhumane. High residues of antibiotics have been found in veal, the center's <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Howell </PERSON> told a congressional subcommittee on June 6. Mrs. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said she knows nothing about raising veal calves and will have to do her homework on that.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Italy-Politics     07-09 0371</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Italy-Politics,0383</SECOND>
<HEAD>Andreotti Receives Mandate to Form Government</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY BETH SHERIDAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The president on Sunday gave Foreign Minister <PERSON> Giulio </PERSON> <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON> a mandate to create the nation's 49th postwar government, and it appeared the five-time premier would easily form a coalition. <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> has been without a government since May 19, when Premier <PERSON> Ciriaco </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Mita </PERSON> resigned following criticism of his leadership by the No. 2 party in the governing coalition, the Socialists. After President <PERSON> Francesco </PERSON> <PERSON> Cossiga </PERSON> summoned him Sunday morning to receive the mandate, <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON> said he would begin trying to form a government. However, he said his task might be delayed by preparations for this week's meeting of the seven major industrialized nations in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON>, like <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Mita </PERSON>, belongs to the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, who have dominated Italian politics since World War II. The <ORGANIZATION> De </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mita </ORGANIZATION> coalition apparently fell because of jockeying by the Socialists, led by popular former Premier <PERSON> Bettino </PERSON> <PERSON> Craxi </PERSON>. <PERSON> Craxi </PERSON> said he would not oppose <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON>, newspapers reported. <PERSON> Craxi </PERSON> and <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON> have worked closely in several governments. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Mita </PERSON>'s policies would likely continue in an <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON> government. The editor of the <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> daily <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Repubblica </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Eugenio </PERSON> <PERSON> Scalfari </PERSON>, noted in a front-page editorial that <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON> and the leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Arnaldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Forlani </PERSON>, now hold the same positions as they did 17 years ago. `` We are therefore about to turn back the clock of politics,'' he said. <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON> said he would work to revive the coalition of <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, Socialists, Republicans, Liberals and <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> that has governed in recent years. He said he was particularly concerned that <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> be ready for 1992, when <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> members are to eliminate all trade barriers among themselves. <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON> is considered to come from the `` conservative'' wing of the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, while <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Mita </PERSON> is a `` liberal.'' However, the labels can be misleading. For example, while <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON> is considered close to the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, the premier-designate also has very good relations with the Communists, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s second-largest party, which has been in the opposition for more than 40 years. <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON>, 70, has been prominent in Italian government since World War II, serving as premier twice in 1972-73 and three times successively in 1976-79.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Brites     07-09 0498</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brites,0519</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bright &amp; Brief</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A turtle who had the misfortune to be run over was at least lucky enough to be the victim of a veterinarian, who got a dentist to mend its broken shell. The vet, Dr. <PERSON> Joanna </PERSON> <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON>, said she injured the painted turtle with her car recently near the animal hospital where she works. Examining the turtle, she found its undershell broken into two pieces, but did n't know how to fix it. A dentist who by chance was at the hospital for a rare consultation on root canal work on a dog overheard Ms. <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON> discussing her problem. He stepped in and came to the rescue. `` That was just what he needed ... some dental acrylic,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Calabro </PERSON>. He splinted the shell and glued it back together with a baby-blue substance normally used for making dentures and repairing teeth. The turtle was up and about in no time and sent on its way. `` Getting hit by a car, going to the vet, going to the dentist _ that's a pretty scary day,'' <PERSON> Calabro </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>OAKLAND, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If eating two gallons of ice cream in one day is your idea of fun, you may have a treat in store. <PERSON> Dreyer </PERSON>'s Grand Ice Cream wants 20 adults and three children to help determine which flavors will fill freezers next year. Those who write the best entries will be flown to company headquarters in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> for the Sept. 15 event. Tasters are trained to rate flavor, texture and color. Then, spoon in hand, they visit 25 tasting stations, sampling as much as necessary to rate each new flavor on a 1-to-10 scale. `` Then we turn them loose to do some real eating,'' said <PERSON> Stacy </PERSON> <PERSON> Gammill </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Dreyer </PERSON>'s publicist. `` It's incredible what these people put away.'' The company's official taster, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, says he does n't feel threatened by the non-professionals, even though in the past couple of years they have picked several flavors `` that were big hits the minute they were introduced. Last year's bunch, chosen from among 15,000 applicants, consumed an average of two gallons of ice cream a day, he said. Along with a plane flight and hotel stay, winners will receive their weight in ice cream. But, said <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, `` we have n't decided whether to weigh them before or after.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SPEARFISH, S.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It was a big job for such a small place, but the 5,251 residents here pulled it off _ they're geared up and ready for the nearly 1,500 pitchers expected for the 1989 World Horseshoe Tournament. Organizers had to raise $ 40,000 toward cash prizes and trophies. Volunteer supporters held raffles, dances and even a chili cookoff to raise money. The Black Hills city spent about $ 30,000 adding 16 horseshoe pits, lighting and other improvements at the campground where the tournament will be held, said Finance Officer <PERSON> Beth </PERSON> <PERSON> Benning </PERSON>. The city already had 20 pits, but tournament regulations call for 36.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PolishDefectors     07-09 0736</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Polish Defectors,0761</SECOND>
<HEAD>Polish Sailors Who Jumped Ship Making Good in America</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SONNI EFRON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Six months after he defected to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> by jumping off a Polish ship, 42-year-old <PERSON> Wieslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Albinski </PERSON> is doing just fine in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, thanks. He's even got a new job at a computer company. `` In my wildest dreams I never anticipated having this kind of job,'' said <PERSON> Albinski </PERSON>, whose English is coming along but who spoke with the help of an interpreter. `` I had heard that there were opportunities here but I had no idea how much.'' <PERSON> Albinski </PERSON> was one of 48 sailors who fled from three different Polish vessels in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> over several days in January. All said they were members of the then-banned Solidarity union. <PERSON> Albinski </PERSON> and the 47 others have applied for but not yet received asylum in a political climate that is changing almost daily. President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> left Sunday for a trip to <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. It will include a two-day stop in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> where he was to address a newly elected <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, nearly half of whose members belong to Solidarity _ an outlaw just six short months ago. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> are `` nations on the threshold of a new era, nations where the spirit of freedom is strong,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Sunday before leaving from <ORGANIZATION> Andrews </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>. But <PERSON> Albinski </PERSON> says he likes it here. `` There is absolutely no question that I would defect again,'' he said during an interview last week at the <ORGANIZATION> Polish-American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, as he sat smoking Marlboros, wearing blue jeans, Reeboks and a T-shirt. He said he loves his new job testing computer modules at <ORGANIZATION> Teradyne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. But like the other sailors, he worries about his immigration status, and whether his wife and two children in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> will be permitted to join him. The 48 have almost all been interviewed by officials with the <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, but have yet to hear whether they'll be granted asylum, said <PERSON> Cathryn </PERSON> <PERSON> MacInnes </PERSON>, the city adviser on immigrant rights who handled the Poles' applications. Many of them have found jobs in the fishing industry in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, while others are working at hotels and factories in <LOCATION> Greater </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON>, the mayor's liaison to the Polish-American community. <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON> said the new arrivals got help from the community and a local church and had no trouble finding jobs. `` They went off to work right away. They refused any type of government assistance,'' <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON> said. At least five of the Polish sailors are working as machinists at <ORGANIZATION> Varian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION>, a vacuum products company in <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION>, making up to $ 9 an hour, production manager <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Grenon </PERSON> said. `` They have a terrific work ethic, the old-fashioned work ethic,'' said <PERSON> Grenon </PERSON>. `` The one problem is the language problem but we've provided them some English-as-a-second-language training and they're coming along.'' <PERSON> Albinski </PERSON> was a radio operator aboard the Kantar, which pulled into <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> just a few days after Polish sailors had jumped another ship. Nervous about the potential for more betrayals, the <PERSON> Kantar </PERSON>'s captain was ordered not to dock but to pump fuel aboard from another ship. <PERSON> Albinski </PERSON> and the others defected by jumping aboard the refueling ship. As the sailors prepared to leave, the captain stood in front of them and warned them of the ramifications, <PERSON> Albinski </PERSON> explained through <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON>. `` As I looked beyond him and saw the skyline of the city -LRB- I was -RRB- thinking about what my future would be,'' he said. He jumped. <PERSON> Albinski </PERSON> said his American co-workers are sympathetic and helpful, but can not conceive of how difficult life is in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. Most surprising, he said, is the absence of paranoia in the workplace. `` I come and go as I please ...,'' he said. `` I can speak freely to my co-workers. I can speak freely to you.'' And in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Albinski </PERSON> can let another secret off his chest: He took the shipboard job only for the money. `` I'm not a seaman,'' he said. `` And I'm really not partial to the sea.'' But the merchant seamen's fate depends on whether <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials believe they are freedom-seekers or mainly just interested in better economic opportunity. <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Whelan </PERSON>, deputy director of the <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, said at the time of the defections that officials would consider <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s political climate, as well as the lengths the sailors had to go to to leave their homeland.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1159EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ChemicalSpill     07-09 0399</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Chemical Spill,0412</SECOND>
<HEAD>Residents Return After Acid Spill</HEAD>
<DATELINE>POPLAR BLUFF, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 500 residents returned to their homes early Sunday after being evacuated for several hours when a nitric acid leak sent a vapor cloud over a wide area. The leak in a containment tank at a construction site in southern Poplar Bluff was discovered by a security guard at 8:45 p.m. Saturday. The evacuations were ordered when authorities feared wind might carry fumes from the acid to residents' homes. The leak was caused by a loose fitting in the 4,000-gallon tank at the site, where a factory is under construction, said <PERSON> Hercell </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> director. Workers put lime on the acid to neutralize it, and the evacuations were called off about 6 a.m. Sunday, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said. The tank had been filled Friday, and workers were transferring 1,500 gallons from the outside tank to another tank inside the plant when the leak occurred, a plant spokesman said. The guard who discovered the leak, <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>, 34, was in stable condition Sunday at Doctor's <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. No other injuries were reported. In an interview at the hospital, <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> said he was finishing his second round of the nearly completed factory when `` I noticed a steam coming out of the ground outside. It looked like something bubbling out of the concrete.'' <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> said the vapors smelled like battery acid. `` I got a pretty good hit, backed off and just fell down,'' <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> said. `` It burned my throat and I started coughing. I was OK until I lit a cigarette. That made me dizzy and got the dry heaves.'' <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheeley </PERSON>, an environmental emergency specialist with the <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION>, said that nitric acid is extremely corrosive. `` It's corrosive to the skin, and the fumes are noxious and can cause tissue damage,'' <PERSON> Sheeley </PERSON> said. `` It can react to other substances that burn. Most residents in the area left willingly and planned to stay with friends and relatives. But at the C & amp; W <ORGANIZATION> Corral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lounge </ORGANIZATION>, owner <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said, `` When we learned of the spill we called the police and they said for us to evacuate the bar. `` All of the customers left quickly except for two who wanted to be locked inside the bar. They finished their beers before leaving.'' <PERSON> Poplar </PERSON> <PERSON> Bluff </PERSON>, a city of about 20,000, is 160 miles south of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Cambodia     07-09 0561</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cambodia,0585</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nations Look Ahead to Peace in Cambodia Despite Major Barriers</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER ENG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BANDAR SERI BEGAWAN, Brunei (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For the first time in almost 11 years, <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> countries and major Western allies are seriously thinking about a world with <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> at peace. Though major barriers remain, last week's meeting of 12 foreign ministers here underlined that virtually all the major outside players are determined to bring about peace. They showed their commitment to finding a settlement despite differences among warring factions in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. They pinned high hopes on talks among the Cambodians starting July 24 in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and on an international peace conference starting in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> on July 30. In <LOCATION> Brunei </LOCATION>, Foreign Minister <PERSON> Wong </PERSON> <PERSON> Kan </PERSON> <PERSON> Seng </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> said the <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> conflict, which has preoccupied the region, was winding down. `` We have already begun to look beyond <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>'' to economic issues, he said after the conference ended Saturday. To examine new directions, Foreign Minister <PERSON> Siddhi </PERSON> <PERSON> Savetsila </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> proposed a summit of the group, the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Asian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, for next year. `` The important thing is that there has been a strong show of consensus of <ORGANIZATION> ASEAN </ORGANIZATION> and its dialogue partners on the need for a comprehensive settlement'' in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, said a senior <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official who spoke on condition of anonymity. The dialogue partners, or allies, included the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, and the 12-nation European Community. Nations at the <LOCATION> Brunei </LOCATION> conference said the pullout of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s troops from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> must be internationally supervised, the Cambodian factions must share power in a provisional government leading to elections, and an international body must also guarantee the peace <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> has pledged to withdraw all 60,000 to 70,000 troops by Sept. 30. Regional leaders are trying to avoid what they call `` an Afghanistan-type settlement.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> pulled its last soldiers from that country in February, but the Soviet-armed government is still fighting the U.S.-backed guerrillas. Vying for power in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> are the Vietnam-installed government of Prime Minister <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON> and the guerrilla coalition led by Prince <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>, which includes the communist <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>. The danger of prolonged civil war after a Vietnamese withdrawal is very real. <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON> refuses to allow the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> in even a provisional government. The <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, with up to 40,000 fighters, reportedly has stocked arms for a major assault after Vietnamese troops leave. The <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> killed hundreds of thousands of people when it ruled <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> from 1975 until <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s 1978 invasion ousted it from power. On Wednesday, <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> again refused <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON>'s calls to make a separate peace without the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON>'s side `` is very uncompromising, so there is no reason for us to be compromising,'' the prince said at his home in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. Still, outsiders feel guarded optimism because of the momentum of diplomatic initiatives over the past two years. Many of these were undertaken by Vietnamese reformers intent on rebuilding their own country's economy and ending its international isolation. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, which arms the rebels, has also grown more conciliatory on the issue in recent years, especially in toning down its backing for the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, which is <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s major ally, has told <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> it supports a major <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> role in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, even though <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> opposes it, according to Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1237EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Valdez-Pilot     07-09 0512</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Valdez-Pilot,0527</SECOND>
<HEAD>Environmentalist To Steer Exxon Valdez Into Port</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Exxon Valdez, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENNIS GEORGATOS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN DIEGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Exxon Valdez, responsible for polluting hundreds of miles of Alaskan shoreline, will have an environmentalist at the controls Tuesday when it enters <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> for repairs. Capt. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, the chief <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> harbor pilot who will steer the damaged tanker to a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipbuilding </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> dock, is a member of the sometimes militant environmental group <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> is a critic of many oil company maritime policies, but on Tuesday, his primary focus will be to bring the crippled <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> safely into port. The ship that caused the nation's worst oil spill was towed from <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> by tugs, but for greater maneuverability <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> will bring it through the bay under its own power. Exxon officials said they have no problems with <PERSON> Silva </PERSON>'s membership in <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> `` He's entitled to his opinion,'' said <PERSON> Carrie </PERSON> <PERSON> Chassin </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipping </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> `` There are people in Exxon who belong to the <ORGANIZATION> Sierra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>. I'm sure he'll drive that ship in as professionally as he knows how.'' <PERSON> Silva </PERSON>, a seaman for 42 years, said he comes from a family of mariners _ his grandfather and father also were sailors _ and his concern for the oceanic environment developed naturally. He believes the risk of oil spills has increased with crew reductions in recent years on the more sophisticated tankers. `` You can build the strongest ship in the world but if you do n't do the job right and you have an accident, you're going to have an oil spill, period,'' <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> said `` Where you're going to stop it is by making sure the people operating these ships are operating them safely and have enough people to do the job.'' The former captain of the Valdez has been accused of drinking on the job. <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> also said he believes the <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION> accident would never have occurred if a qualified pilot had been aboard to guide the ship through the sound. The pilot who had helped guide the ship through Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> had left it a few miles before the accident occurred March 24, as regulations allowed. `` I may be biased, but there should have been an Alaskan pilot on board,'' <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> said. `` They're more familiar with the area. I guarantee you if there had been one on, it would n't have happened.'' <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> will take him out to the <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION> by helicopter Monday so he can familiarize himself with the ship and its handling. `` Given that the ship is damaged, I'm not really sure how it's going to handle,'' he said `` Suppose there is a jagged piece of steel down there someplace I do n't know about? It could have an effect on how the ship steers.'' `` I'm doing it just to be absolutely certain in my own mind ... that the ship can handle OK,'' he said. `` There's no one more interested in trying to keep this area clean than I am, believe me.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1245EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-SoccerDisaster 1stLd-Writethru   07-09 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soccer Disaster, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0636,0727</SECOND>
<HEAD>Seven Years Late, Soviet Newspaper Discloses World's Worst Soccer
Tragedy</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: SUBS 4th graf, `A front-page...' to correct typo and add that
article also appeared Sunday. Pickup 5th graf, ``According to...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANDREW KATELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police trying to cram thousands of soccer fans into a section of <LOCATION> Lenin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION> in 1982 created a `` human mincer'' that killed as many as 340 people, a newspaper said in disclosing details of the world's worst soccer disaster. Sovietsky Sport, the official newspaper of the government's Sports Committee, accused authorities of covering up the disaster and said it was disclosing the tragedy now `` so as not to forget people who loved sports until the grave. The Oct. 20, 1982 incident had been reported before, but a death toll and other details were never released in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. A front-page investigative story in <LOCATION> Sovietsky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sport </LOCATION> on Saturday said parents believed there were as many as 340 deaths at <LOCATION> Lenin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s Luzhniki section. The newspaper repeated that figure Sunday in another article about the incident. `` According to our information _ and no other information has been provided to the public _ a human mincer at <LOCATION> Luzhniki </LOCATION> on that day pulverized 340 lives. In the twinkling of an eye, interior troops and police cordoned off the stadium, and also quickly surrounded the tragedy,'' the newspaper said. The account said that because only 10,000 tickets had been sold to the match between <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Spartak </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Haarlem </LOCATION> of the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> in the 100,000-seat stadium, management decided to cram all the fans into one section. Police ringed the section, and all but one staircase was locked `` to save trouble to the police, cleaners,'' the newspaper reported. Police pushed fans toward the exit a few minutes before the end of the game to prevent a jam at the nearby subway station, it said. But when the final _ and only _ goal was scored, some fans tried to return and collided with outgoing fans on stairs that had become covered with ice in the 14-degree weather. `` It was something terrible,'' <PERSON> Volodya </PERSON> <PERSON> Andreyev </PERSON>, who survived the accident, told the newspaper. `` We could n't move from where we were standing, and the crowd was pushing from above and below. It was no longer possible to control the people who had gone crazy.'' Sovietsky Sport said the parents of fans who failed to return home after the match received no information from police and had to search hospital morgues themselves. The bodies were not released for burial for 13 days, the newspaper reported. Five days after the disaster, The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> quoted semi-official Soviet sources as saying more than 20 people died and dozens were injured in a collision of fans on a ramp. A Soviet newspaper reported casualties at the time, but did not specify whether people were killed or injured and did not give a number. Sovietsky Sport reported on April 18 _ three days after 95 soccer fans were killed in a crush at <LOCATION> Hillsborough </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Sheffield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> _ that dozens of people were trampled to death in the 1982 <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> incident. The biggest loss of life previously reported at a soccer match was on May 24, 1964, when rioting left nearly 300 dead in <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, in a game between <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>. The worst single-incident sports disaster in modern history occurred when an estimated 604 people were killed after stands at the <ORGANIZATION> Hong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jockey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> racecourse collapsed and caught fire in February 1918. Sovietsky Sports said a minor stadium official was blamed for the 1982 tragedy and sentenced to 18 months of `` corrective work,'' but mostly the victims were blamed for alleged unruly behavior. Ever since the disaster, no soccer matches have been held in <LOCATION> Lenin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION> at the end of October because authorities are afraid survivors will place flowers on the field as a sign of protest. Readers suggested a committee be set up to investigate the tragedy and that a meeting be held at the site Oct. 20 to commemorate the tragedy, the newspaper said Sunday. The account was the latest disclosure by a Soviet media that has seized upon President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s policy of glasnost, or openness, to report long hushed-up Soviet disasters.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1313EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SwissUnrest     07-09 0209</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Swiss Unrest,0214</SECOND>
<HEAD>Housing Protest in Zurich Turns Violent</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ZURICH, Switzerland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police used tear gas and rubber bullets to disperse 150 people who erected barricades and smashed windows in a protest over housing shortages in <LOCATION> Zurich </LOCATION>, authorities said Sunday. The protest Saturday night caused $ 100,000 in damage, injured three officers and led to the arrests of 19 people, police said. A police statement said officers used tear gas and rubber bullets around midnight after demonstrators began smashing the shop windows in downtown <LOCATION> Zurich </LOCATION> and erecting barricades of garbage cans in the streets. The Swiss Journalists Union charged that police attacked journalists to prevent them from covering the violence. The union demanded an investigation. <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> photographer <PERSON> Klaus </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosza </PERSON> said he was covering the disturbances when police chased him into a restaurant. `` They threw tables to the ground and three of them beat me,'' he said. <PERSON> Rosza </PERSON>, who was treated for head and arm injuries, said a fourth policeman sprayed tear gas in his face. A police spokesman denied that authorities attacked the journalist. Demonstrations demanding a solution to <LOCATION> Zurich </LOCATION>'s acute housing shortage, especially of reasonably priced apartments, led to riots in March that police described as the most serious disturbances since the start of the decade.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1320EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Summit-Zeppelin     07-09 0188</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Summit-Zeppelin,0193</SECOND>
<HEAD>French Using Dirigible For Summit Security</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto PAR7</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities are using a zeppelin for surveillance when about 30 foreign leaders visit <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> for the 200th anniversary of the French Revolution. The 200-foot-long dirigible, estimated to cost $ 7 million, relays live television coverage from its two cameras simultaneously to several command centers on the ground. The aircraft went into service last week for the visit of Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, and was displayed Sunday for reporters at <LOCATION> Le </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bourget </LOCATION> airport north of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. It will be used for the celebrations of Bastille Day on July 14, the simultaneous summit of the world's seven richest countries, and the July 23 arrival of the Tour de <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> bicycle race in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. Designed by the British firm <ORGANIZATION> Airship </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION>, its envelope is manufactured in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, its 38-foot-long cabin in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, and its engines are made by Porsche of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. The cabin has room for a 10-man crew. Fourteen such airships have been built. They were used for security at the Olympic Games in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> and for the funeral of Japanese Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1324EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-France-US-Bicentennial     07-09 0330</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-France-US-Bicentennial,0340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Virginia Cadets Add American Marching Music To Bicentennial</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-French Revolution, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHARLES CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cadets from the <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, in gray tunics and dark blue plumed hats, are giving the French a taste of American marching music in this week's bicentennial festivities. The 45-member VMI band has been in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> since July 6 to represent the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> at several events marking the 200th anniversary of the French Revolution. On Saturday, the <ORGANIZATION> VMI </ORGANIZATION> cadets and other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> marching bands and majorettes wowed a crowd of several thousand at <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> City Hall with a display of jazzy music, fancy steps and spinning batons. French schools and universities have no marching bands, and the brassy art is considered quintessentially American. The account in Sunday's editions of the weekly <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Le </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> du </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dimanche </ORGANIZATION> noted that following the <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> Centennial Band in cowboy hats and blue jeans `` were the ringing tones, a bit more warlike, of the <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, whose representatives were sporting caps topped with blue plumes.'' Also participating in Saturday's display at City Hall were bands from <ORGANIZATION> James </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> B. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dudley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Greensboro </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION> -RRB- High School and <LOCATION> Lawrence </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- High School. The most exotic touch came from the <ORGANIZATION> Touch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kyle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Twirling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Kalamazoo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich </LOCATION>. The Journal du <PERSON> Dimanche </PERSON> tried to explain `` le twirling'' for its readers, describing it as `` manipulation of a baton, involving at once juggling, acrobatics and dance.'' Saturday's performance was part of a daylong <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> salute to the French bicentennial, which climaxes Friday on the 200th anniversary of the storming of the Bastille prison on July 14, 1789. VMI was founded 150 years ago on the model of the <ORGANIZATION> Ecole </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Polytechnique </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> military engineering academy _ established during the revolution _ whose graduates still dominate top jobs in French industry and technology. A tour of the Ecole Polytechnique was on the schedule for the visiting cadets.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1403EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People     07-09 1050</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People,1094</SECOND>
<HEAD>People in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY44</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was back home again in <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> on Sunday, and he said he was not about to change a tradition of personally taking his daughter to summer camp just because he's the vice president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The vice president arrived at the Columbus airport shortly before 9 a.m., landing away from the terminal and staying away from reporters. He left in a black limousine seven minutes later, planning to visit relatives before taking his 10-year-old daughter, <PERSON> Corrinne </PERSON>, to summer camp in nearby <LOCATION> Brown </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. The visit was described by <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> as strictly private. At <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON>, he spent about half-hour visiting his grandmother at a nursing home. As he left, he told a group of reporters waiting outside: `` It's good to be back home again. Things in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> are going well.'' He added, `` I've always taken my daughter to camp ... I'm not going to change that just because I'm in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, the 6-year-old son of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, is out of the hospital after an operation to examine nerve damage from an accident in April. `` The senator reports that <PERSON> Albert </PERSON>'s spirits are good and the prognosis is good,'' <PERSON> Marla </PERSON> <PERSON> Romash </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Democrat, said Saturday from his office in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The boy was seriously injured when he was hit by a car April 3 in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> after he let go of his father's hand and ran into the street. He entered <ORGANIZATION> Ochsner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> here Wednesday for an operation to examine what doctors called a stretch injury to a network of nerves in his right shoulder. The injury limits <PERSON> Albert </PERSON>'s ability to move his forearm, said hospital spokesman <PERSON> Reggie </PERSON> <PERSON> Moody </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> office said surgeons removed scar tissue but decided that the injured nerve had a better chance of growing back and restoring movement to the arm than a grafted nerve would have. The boy left the hospital Saturday with his parents.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Rev. <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> said Sunday he often receives death threats but pays no attention to them. `` I have no bodyguards and I do n't have anybody protecting me,'' the 70-year-old American evangelist told television interviewer <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Frost </PERSON> at the conclusion of his three-week British crusade. `` We get them quite often and I pay absolutely no attention to them. They're just put aside. I feel like I'm clothed in the armor of God and I'll go on as long as God wants me to and if he wants me killed, I'm happy to be killed.'' British news reports said <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> defied death threats from fundamentalist Protestants on Saturday night by appearing with <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> singer <PERSON> Dana </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>, at <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Wembley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> said he was not aware of those specific threats. Political and sectarian violence between <PERSON> Catholics </PERSON> and Protestants in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> has left more then 2,700 people dead over the last 20 years. He also told Frost he received a letter from <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>, the African National Congress Leader jailed in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, saying he had turned to Christianity. `` He invited me to come and see him,'' <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> said. `` He said that about three or four years ago he had received <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> into his heart, he was reading and studying the Bible.'' <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> did not say when he received the letter. <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> said 1.25 million people attended his 13 rallies in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, including 85,000 who braved heavy rains Saturday at <LOCATION> Wembley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>RENO, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Sferrazza </PERSON>, who shed her husband the mayor recently, plans to shed her clothes for the September issue of Playboy magazine. `` I wished her the best of success. What else can I say?'' Mayor <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Sferrazza </PERSON>, said last week when asked how he felt about the overexposure of his ex-wife. `` Playboy presented me with the option to do a very positive story on <PERSON> Reno </PERSON>,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Sferrazza </PERSON>, 25. She said she decided to approach Playboy in March after a friend said she looked like a model. In fact, she said, she had done some modeling previously. Playboy will be distributing 30,000 copies in the Reno area, five times the normal circulation here. The Sferrazzas' divorce was finalized late last month. It ended the couple's second marriage to each other; they were divorced once before, in December 1987.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Marriage has changed <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>, right down to his real estate. <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>, who married actress <PERSON> Loni </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> a year ago, is selling the Mediterranean-style house he bought as a bachelor pad in 1978. The 8,659-square-foot, two-story house featuring a pool, gym and wine cellar is being purchased by a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> couple for just under $ 5 million, the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> quoted unidentified real estate sources as saying. The house has been on the market for about a year. <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> decided to sell the house, which has two guest houses and a projection room, because he and Miss <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> have spent most of their time in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, said real estate agent <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aaroe </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MONROE, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> turned Mrs. as <PERSON> Kaye </PERSON> <PERSON> Lani </PERSON> <PERSON> Rae </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafko </PERSON> married <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> before a standing room crowd of about 850 people. Rafko, <LOCATION> Miss </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> of 1988, arrived in a white horse-drawn coach Saturday as spectators watched, some from folding chairs set up near the church. The nuptials followed a seven-month engagement and six-year courtship dating to when <PERSON> Rafko </PERSON>, 26, met <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, 25, at the strawberry farm where he had a summer job. Their wedding dessert included strawberries, a reference to their meeting. `` I had noticed him for about three years,'' <PERSON> Rafko </PERSON> said Friday. `` Every summer I'd go back there, but he did n't say anything to me. So I approached him.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The new music director of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>' Opera Bastille, <PERSON> Myung-Whun </PERSON> <PERSON> Chung </PERSON>, has won the <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Toscanini </PERSON> prize, Italian newspapers reported Sunday. The 36-year-old Korean-born conductor is to receive the award following his Wednesday concert in the northern Italian city of <LOCATION> Tavernelle </LOCATION>. The prize recognizes <PERSON> Chung </PERSON> as a maestro with `` a clear virtuosity typical of the great directors of the <PERSON> Toscanini </PERSON> school.'' <PERSON> Chung </PERSON> studied at <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s Juilliard School of Music. In 1978, he was named associate conductor of the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Philharmonic </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1415EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-China     07-09 0506</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China,0518</SECOND>
<HEAD>Official Gets Death Sentence, Others Expelled From Party</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A court sentenced a local <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> official to death for selling a fake name-brand liquor, a report said Sunday, dramatizing the party's determination to root out corruption that students recently protested. Six other officials were expelled from the party in separate corruption cases as the ruling party tried to clean up an image badly tarnished by nepotism, bribe-taking and black marketeering. The <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Daily said a court in the southeastern province of <LOCATION> Guizhou </LOCATION> gave <LOCATION> Tongren </LOCATION> district party secretary <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> <PERSON> Jingxing </PERSON> the death sentence for selling fake maotai, a fiery sorghum liquor. The paper said <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> earned `` staggering profits'' of $ 50,800. At least 26 people have been executed since the army cracked down on pro-democracy protesters, whose demands included an end to official corruption. <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> was the first party official to be sentenced to death under a new anti-corruption campaign announced after the crackdown. Other such campaigns in recent years have failed, partly because offenders usually were disciplined by the party rather than put on trial. The protests that shook <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> from April until June gave the party a strong incentive to try again. The student slogan that won the most sympathy from the public was `` Down with corruption,'' and the posters that were most copied were those detailing examples of nepotism among top leaders. The party newspaper, the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION>, said two party members were expelled in <LOCATION> Fujian </LOCATION> province and several others were put under supervision or criticized for arranging prostitutes for visiting businessmen. In another case, it said four men who had been party members for more than 40 years were expelled in <LOCATION> Heilongjiang </LOCATION> province for profiteering and bribe-taking. There were no new reports of arrests connected with the protests. According to a count by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, more than 2,000 arrests have been reported nationwide by the official media, but <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> sources said they believed that many had been arrested in the capital alone. The official media blasted Western suggestions that with time, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> will move away from socialism, and it lectured its citizens that the best way to improve their lives is by raising production. In a harsh half-page commentary, the People's Daily accused the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government-run <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> radio of supporting the protesters. `` This is yet another odious demonstration of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s crude interference in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s internal affairs,'' it said, `` and -LRB- of -RRB- the revival of the old dream of the American anti-communist monopoly capitalist class of promoting a peaceful evolution in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'' toward capitalism. Such venemous criticism of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was common during the 1960s, when revolutionary leader <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse-tung </PERSON> repeatedly claimed that <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> planned an attack, but it has not been seen in the Chinese media for years. Other political phrases from the 1960s also have reappeared. The People's Daily commentary said the protests showed that class struggle still exists in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. Other newspapers have urged students to learn from the workers, peasants and soldiers _ three `` good'' classes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890709-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-89 1422EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Poland-Changes Bjt   07-09 0744</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Poland-Changes, Bjt,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poland: A Nation Undergoing Tumultuous Change</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DRUSILLA MENAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
