<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 2332EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ThisNewHost     10-09 0851</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-This New Host,0873</SECOND>
<HEAD>`This Old House' Gets This New Host</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANA KENNEDY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CONCORD, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some might think a television show about home renovation would be as exciting as watching paint dry. But PBS' `` This Old House'' has long since proved that Americans love to watch other people fix up fixer-uppers. Now `` This Old House'' has this new host: <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, an eclectic blend of <PERSON> Thor </PERSON> <PERSON> Heyerdahl </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Waldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Emerson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Redford </PERSON>. PBS officials hope that <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, 36, an expert sailor, carpenter, world traveler and writer, will dispel the whiff of scandal that hovered over the show when its original host, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Vila </PERSON>, left over a conflict of interest. The popular <PERSON> Vila </PERSON> began as co-host of the show with master carpenter <PERSON> Norm </PERSON> <PERSON> Abram </PERSON> 11 years ago. He left after last season when an underwriter withdrew funding in a dispute over <PERSON> Vila </PERSON>'s commercial endorsements. The show is produced at <ORGANIZATION> WGBH-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and is broadcast more than 500 times a week by 315 PBS stations across the country, reaching 15 million viewers and standing as public television's highest-rated half-hour show The new season of `` This Old House'' premiered in some parts of the country last weekend, and will be seen in other places later this week. <PERSON> Vila </PERSON>'s departure prompted a flurry of more than 400 videotapes and resumes from people vying for the job. About half the applicants were television professionals. Others had little more than rudimentary carpentry credentials and a pickup truck. A concert pianist and a brain surgeon were among those interested. But the man who won the job never applied. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, who had almost no on-camera television experience, was in northwest <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> researching his new book on the Arctic during the search for <PERSON> Vila </PERSON>'s successor He had returned to the 1836 Colonial revival house he shares with his wife and 3-year-old son on <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Shore </LOCATION> and was in the middle of his own renovation project _ constructing skylights _ when he got a call from <ORGANIZATION> WGBH </ORGANIZATION> publicist <PERSON> Daphne </PERSON> <PERSON> Noyes </PERSON>. <PERSON> Noyes </PERSON> was calling about <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>' film `` The Last Navigator,'' which aired on PBS stations in July. But during the phone call, she mentioned that <PERSON> Vila </PERSON>'s job was open and suggested <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> apply for the job. Ten days and one screen test later, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> _ who combines <PERSON> Heyerdahl </PERSON>'s sailing zeal with <PERSON> Emerson </PERSON>'s philosophical self-reliance and <PERSON> Redford </PERSON>'s telegenic good looks _ had the job. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, the grandson of a missionary who worked with Eskimos in isolated Point Hope, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, appears to have inherited the hardy stock of his forebears. Since graduating from <ORGANIZATION> Evergreen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Olympia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> has built boats, worked construction, skippered ships across the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>, studied ancient celestial navigation with a master navigator, written a book and helped produce a PBS film. His latest project is a book about the <LOCATION> Arctic </LOCATION> region where his father was born called `` The Wilderness of Ice and Mind.'' But <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> is fairly modest about his accomplishments. `` Basically, I'm a bum,'' he said in a recent interview in <LOCATION> Concord </LOCATION>, where he and <PERSON> Abram </PERSON> will be dismantling an 1835 barn for most of this year's show, turning it into a single-family home. `` I've done a bunch of different stuff. There are those who would say I've never had a regular job.'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> has supported himself since college by avoiding the office and desk grind. He grew up in <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, where he learned to sail and surf early. He also learned home renovation firsthand from his father, who fixed up houses and sold them. After college, he sailed and raced extensively around the world. During a 1979 voyage between the <LOCATION> Galapagos </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Marquesas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> in the remote <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> without electronic navigation instruments, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> lost the nautical equivalent of an odometer and had to rely on his eyes to measure the speed of the boat. `` I found I could do it accurately,'' he recalled. `` I decided I wanted to become completely self-reliant.'' His desire to learn ancient navigation led him to a master navigator in <LOCATION> Micronesia </LOCATION> who spoke only Satawalese. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> learned the language enough to understand the navigator during a yearlong apprenticeship. He later wrote `` The Last Navigator'' about the experience. It became a segment for PBS' `` Adventure'' series. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said he spent a weekend considering the `` This Old House'' job _ and whether or not `` they'd even want me for it.'' Once he was hired, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said he stuck close to the show's creator and producer, <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Morash </PERSON>, and operated on `` fear and adrenaline. He has done eight shows so far and said he has grown more comfortable in front of the camera. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said <PERSON> Morash </PERSON> talked about a `` 10-year commitment and that sounded fine to me.'' He calls the job, with its July to March shooting schedule, ideal for a writer and craftsman. `` I have a tremendous respect and admiration for true craftsmanship, the way a person unites his craft with the rest of his life. It's pretty amazing you can communicate something you feel deeply about _ and that's part of this job.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FalseHero     10-09 0815</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-False Hero,0837</SECOND>
<HEAD>Navy Veteran Who Faked War Record Nearly Added to Vietnam Memorial</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VERN ANDERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SALT LAKE CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Fife </PERSON> never doubted her husband had been scarred in mind and body by his <ORGANIZATION> Viet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cong </ORGANIZATION> captors, that he was a tarnished and troubled war hero. The night nearly 20 years ago, when her sneakers seemed to drive <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Fife </PERSON> berserk, was all the proof she needed. <PERSON> Fife </PERSON> told her later that his captors used to wear sneakers when they came to his bamboo cage to beat him and urinate on him, and that the enemy soldier he strangled when he escaped also was wearing canvas shoes. Then there was the manuscript her husband left when he died this summer at the age of 46 of self-inflicted carbon monoxide poisoning _ 449 pages of vivid <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> experiences. But <PERSON> Fife </PERSON> had never been to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, let alone been a hero. Misled by <PERSON> Fife </PERSON>, his therapist, Dr. <PERSON> Corydon </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON>, had concluded that he suffered from post-traumatic stress syndrome and was `` very much a casualty of the Vietnam War.'' A letter <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> wrote after <PERSON> Fife </PERSON>'s death included a general account of what he believed was his patient's <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> war experience _ 15 days of torment as a prisoner of war after the USS Ranger-based F-4 fighter on which <PERSON> Fife </PERSON> was navigator was shot down in early 1966. `` He was clearly depressed, guilt-ridden, angry, alienated from people and viewed the world in a very negative manner as a result of his military service experiences, particularly as a prisoner of war,'' <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> wrote. But Fife's heroic identity was adopted to cover a lifetime of failure. His image, maintained through 23 years of marriage, was shattered only when his widow tried to have his name included on the state's Vietnam War memorial, using the letter from <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> as part of her evidence. The <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vietnam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Era </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> decided last month after some debate to place <PERSON> Fife </PERSON>'s name on the granite and marble structure, to be dedicated Saturday. <PERSON> Fife </PERSON>'s would have been the last of 390 names on the memorial. But while an artisan was preparing to engrave <PERSON> Fife </PERSON>'s name, an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reporter who had searched unsuccessfully for veterans who served with the dead hero told Mrs. <PERSON> Fife </PERSON> that her husband had lied. `` I feel like I've been raped,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Fife </PERSON> said after being told of the deception revealed by <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> records. After a great deal of anguish, she decided to tell the truth to her 21-year-old son and her 19-year-old daughter. `` Intellectually I know I have the right to be angry,'' she said, `` but even with all of this I first need to understand it all.'' <PERSON> Fife </PERSON> did n't usually talk much about <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, but his wife had accompanied him to his first session with <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> in 1986, when he used the old fiction to try to justify his life. <PERSON> Fife </PERSON> had acquired a certificate, purportedly from the <ORGANIZATION> USS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ranger </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, listing the medals he said he had burned at the time to protest bad treatment of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans. They included the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>, the service's highest award for valor. Lt. J.G. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fife </PERSON>, after 130 missions over enemy territory, was `` one of only four naval aviators to escape from enemy prison camps,'' according to the certificate, which appeared to be signed by Admiral <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Moorer </PERSON>, retired chief of naval operations. At the reporter's request, <PERSON> Jeannie </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s Awards and Special Projects Branch, tracked down <PERSON> Fife </PERSON>'s real <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> records They showed he enlisted in September 1965 and was discharged eight months later as medically unfit because of bones broken in his right foot during childhood that had n't mended properly. His only medal was the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> Award _ given to everyone. <PERSON> Fife </PERSON> wanted to be remembered as the hero in his manuscript, not as a man obsessed by the circumstances of his birth. <PERSON> Fife </PERSON> never knew his father and blamed his mother for making him `` a bastard,'' said a sister, <PERSON> Lynda </PERSON> <PERSON> Turcsanski </PERSON>. His wife, who met him in the months following his brief naval service, knew him as a pornography addict who spent hours alone with his erotic trove. Friends and relatives knew <PERSON> Fife </PERSON> as unreliable, angry, a dreamer, a failed businessman who gambled away $ 172,000 of a partner's money, a sometime truck driver, a would-be writer <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON>, co-director of the sex and marital therapy clinic at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION>, said he was not entirely surprised to learn <PERSON> Fife </PERSON> was no hero. Assuming the identity of a <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veteran was assuming a disability that would excuse his deficiencies and gain him sympathy and understanding, <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> said. `` He was what we call personality disorder, meaning very nonconforming, rebellious, somewhat anti-social,'' <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> said. `` I suspect the manuscript may have been a sort of last-ditch effort at salvaging a little bit of self-esteem.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AbortionistLegislator     10-09 0675</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortionist Legislator,0696</SECOND>
<HEAD>Doctor-Representative Draws Extra Attention for Florida Session</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: `Banjanin' in 18th graf is correct.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN SEWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A first-term state representative and physician is in the center of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s abortion storm this week because he's the only legislator who performs abortions, making him a lightning rod for protests. <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Graber </PERSON> even gets hate mail. `` They need something to marshal their forces around,'' he said of abortion opponents. The obstetrician-gynecologist's <LOCATION> Pompano </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> women's clinic drew a raucous demonstration Saturday, three days before the state <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> was to begin a special session on abortion called by Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>. `` They were frustrated by the -LRB- <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision. They decided to make me the target, an ideal situation with the legislative session coming up,'' <PERSON> Graber </PERSON> said Monday. The state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> last week cited the state privacy law to strike down a 1988 statute requiring minors to get parental consent for abortion, uphold a woman's unrestricted right to abortion in the first trimester, and emphasize individual privacy rights in abortion decision-making. The governor acted within weeks of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s July 3 ruling upholding <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> state restrictions on abortions, making <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> the first state since then to call a session devoted to abortion. At Saturday's demonstration, <PERSON> Graber </PERSON> said several of his patients, none there for abortions, were jostled by a 200-strong crowd and others were scared away. <PERSON> Graber </PERSON> says he performs two or three abortions a week and only as part of his practice. The Rev. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahoney </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> coordinator for <ORGANIZATION> Operation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION>, an anti-abortion group that demonstrates at clinics, was arrested and charged with assault on a police officer, obstructing justice without violence and trepassing. <PERSON> Graber </PERSON> called Operation Rescue `` a terrorist organization'' and said he will seek a restraining order against the group and damages. His office has been picketed before. But the latest protest was perhaps the most strident, he said. <PERSON> Graber </PERSON>, among many legislators who opposes holding the special session, said his mail has gone in recent weeks from evenly split to mostly anti-abortion. `` There have been more gory pictures -LRB- of fetuses -RRB- and more hate mail,'' said <PERSON> Graber </PERSON>, a German-born Jew offended by packets with pictures of <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> and fetuses that contend aborting fetuses is comparable to the Holocaust. `` Someone wrote: ` It's too bad <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> did n't finish off your family,''' he said. Thousands of activists on both sides of the abortion issue are flocking here this week but <PERSON> Graber </PERSON> is confident legislators will be protected by Capitol and local police, who have set up command posts and video monitors and trained a 40-member riot squad. Being in the middle of demonstrations is n't the role <PERSON> Graber </PERSON> wants to play. `` I'd like to be there to cut through the propaganda, be available to ask questions and answer questions, and make sure the facts come out in an intelligent manner,'' <PERSON> Graber </PERSON> said. Last month, he circulated `` A Legislator's Guide to Abortion Issues.'' <PERSON> Graber </PERSON> said his 27-page handbook has been positively received, although anti-abortion forces say he should n't necessarily be considered an expert Said state Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Banjanin </PERSON>: `` I think every member of the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> is very knowledgeable on this issue. I think abortions are the murder of unborn children.'' `` I question whether he can approach this issue objectively, considering that he has a profit motive involved in what can come out of this session,'' added <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, political director for <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Right </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> To </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Graber </PERSON>, 41, in practice for 12 years, said he initially opposed abortions, which were illegal when he entered medical school at <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. He said abortions are only a small part of his practice and that many are performed on older women whose health could be jeopardized by pregnancy. <PERSON> Graber </PERSON>, married father of daughters ages 18, 17 and 12 years, has proposed a statewide study panel. `` Everything's not black-and-white on this issue,'' he said. `` Now we're talking about a three-day session where we're going to solve all these complicated questions. It's unrealistic.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Copeland     10-09 0337</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Copeland,0345</SECOND>
<HEAD>Opera by Rock Drummer Opening in Cleveland</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KRISTI UMBREIT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opera </ORGANIZATION> opens its season today not with the works of <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON> or Puccini but with a tale of the Crusades written by <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> <PERSON> Copeland </PERSON>, former drummer for the rock group <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>. `` Holy Blood and Crescent Moon'' is bona fide opera, a love story with arias, choruses, grandiose sets and sweeping gestures, drawn from <PERSON> Copeland </PERSON>'s research and observations on Holy Land history and current situation in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Copeland </PERSON>, who spent six years with <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> before going on to score movies and television shows, said Monday he does n't put himself in the same league as the masters but did use the qualities found in traditional opera. `` The music is definitely very brooding,'' he said. `` It's very bombastic. I use the orchestra to its fullest.'' The opera, which took four years to write, is the result of <PERSON> Copeland </PERSON> making good on a flip remark during a 1984 press conference after he had written music for a ballet to <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>'s King <PERSON> Lear </PERSON> for the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ballet </LOCATION> When asked when he would write another ballet, he said it would be `` after I finish my opera.'' The son of Cleveland Opera General Manager <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bamberger </PERSON> heard that remark and urged his father to commission <PERSON> Copeland </PERSON>, who had ventured from rock music to write scores for the movie `` Rumblefish'' and the TV series `` The Equalizer.'' <PERSON> Copeland </PERSON>, 37, said he knew little about opera when he agreed to write one, and he had to learn to love the dissonant voices and grand drama. <PERSON> Copeland </PERSON>, whose father headed the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> office of the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> and who grew up in the region, said elements of the same story are in the war-wracked <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> of recent years It tells the tale of <PERSON> Edmund </PERSON>, prince of the Franks, and <PERSON> Dahlia </PERSON>, daughter of a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> ruler, who help each other despite the wars their people wage in the name of the land.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Confucius     10-09 0553</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Confucius,0569</SECOND>
<HEAD>Confucius Is Man Of The Hour On 2540th Birthday</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM ABRAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s Communist government is holding a big bash this year for the 2540th birthday of Confucius, the philosopher once reviled for his reactionary ideas. The old sage, while still taken to task as a father of Chinese feudalism, has now entered the party pantheon as a thinker who embodied such socialist virtues as harmony, stability and obedience. New Communist Party General Secretary <PERSON> Jiang </PERSON> <PERSON> Zemin </PERSON>, in a meeting with Confucian scholars Sunday, described Confucius -LRB- 551-479 B.C. -RRB- as a `` great ancient thinker of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>.'' The official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> quoted <PERSON> Jiang </PERSON> as adding, `` it is necessary to select the essence while discarding the dross from his thought. The good side of his thought, in particular, should be used to educate the younger generation in helping them inherit and carry forward fine national traditions.'' Some 300 scholars from 20 nations are holding a symposium on Confucian thought in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and Confucius' birthplace of <LOCATION> Qufu </LOCATION>, 300 miles to the south. It is being co-sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>, Science and Culture Organization. An exhibition on Confucius' life and work also opened at the Capital Museum, a former Confucian temple. Sacrificial rites were observed, the first time <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> has staged a large-scale ceremony in memory of Confucius since the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> takeover in 1949. <LOCATION> Qufu </LOCATION> is also holding its first Confucius Cultural Festival to mark the Sept. 28 birth of the sage whose ideas on filial piety and social order still wield considerable influence in such <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> countries as <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. Much of the hoopla has been part of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s efforts to revive its flagging tourist industry and develop <LOCATION> Qufu </LOCATION> as a tourist town. But it also reflects the new appraisal of the old thinker. The Confucian tenets of loyalty, stability, sacrificing oneself for the social good and obedience to one's masters have won favor from the current Communist government, which is now seeking to reassert control after crushing the pro-democracy movement this spring. Confucianism, which through Chinese history gained religious status with its own temples, was often been a target of Chinese progressives. Leaders of the May 4th Movement of 1919, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s first student-led campaign for democratic reform, said it represented agrarian feudal values, denigrated women and showed excessive respect for precedence, creating an obstacle to progress. <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse-tung </PERSON>'s revolutionaries, with their determination to overturn traditional class order, rejected Confucius while seizing the same `` mandate of heaven'' the scholar once bestowed on the imperial family. In 1973 the Cultural Revolution government launched a massive anti-Confucius, anti-Lin <PERSON> Biao </PERSON> campaign, linking <PERSON> Lin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mao </PERSON>'s heir-apparent who died in a plane crash after failing to assassinate <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> in 1971, to Confucius' reactionary ideology The movement assailed those trying to restore `` feudalism, capitalism and revisionism'' and accused Confucius of advocating the establishment of a slave society. After the 1966-76 Cultural Revolution ended, <PERSON> Confucius </PERSON> was rehabilitated. `` For centuries, people have either exalted and glorified him, or disparaged and belittled him,'' the official <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> said Monday in an article on the `` profound influence'' of Confucian ideas on contemporary <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. `` But none can add to or detract from his position in Chinese history as an outstanding thinker, statesman, educator and classicist, deserving to be called a cultural giant of the world.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 2347EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     10-09 0831</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0865</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Michael cq as woman's name in first item.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Bangles are breaking up after weeks of speculation about the all-female pop band's future, the lead singer says. `` We just did n't seem very happy anymore,'' <PERSON> Susanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffs </PERSON> said of the group whose hits included `` Walk Like an Egyptian,'' and `` Eternal Flame.'' `` The last few years were very emotionally draining. After nine years, we'd given so much to each other that it had become like a marriage _ a long marriage,'' she said of the band, whose latest album is `` Everything.'' `` It got to the point where we just did n't have that ` band' feeling anymore. At a meeting three weeks ago, Ms. <PERSON> Hoffs </PERSON>, bassist <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Steele </PERSON>, guitarist <PERSON> Vicki </PERSON> <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON> and drummer <PERSON> Debbi </PERSON> <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON>, agreed to go their seperate ways, at least for now, the lead singer said. Their last public performance was Sept. 2 at the <LOCATION> Redwood </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Amphitheatre </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clara </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>RADNOR, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Faye </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunaway </PERSON> feared she'd been forgotten, so the Oscar-winning actress is out to make a fresh impression by producing a cable TV movie, `` Cold Sassy Tree.'' Miss <PERSON> Dunaway </PERSON>, who plays a supporting part in the movie as well, said in the Oct. 14 issue of TV Guide the project began when her brother gave her the book `` Cold Sassy Tree,'' <PERSON> Olive </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>' novel about a young boy's relationship with his grandfather `` I finished it in one night and I thought, ` Why wo n't anyone send me a story like that?' I said to my brother, ` I'm going to do this myself. I do n't care what it takes.''' Miss <PERSON> Dunaway </PERSON>, 48, who won the best actress Oscar in 1976 for her role in `` Network,'' moved to <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> after marrying British photographer <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON>, but has since divorced.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than $ 1 million in contributions for victims of Hurricane Hugo has poured in since an on-the-scene appeal during `` The <PERSON> Oprah </PERSON> <PERSON> Winfrey </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> officials said. The Chicago-based Ms. <PERSON> Winfrey </PERSON> appealed for donations in a special show telecast Thursday from <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> By Monday, more than $ 1 million had been collected over the telephone in credit-card contributions, according to <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Chase </PERSON>, executive director of resources for the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. `` This is the quickest response from individuals that we have ever seen in a fund-raising effort,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Krueger </PERSON>, another <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> official.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>KANSAS CITY, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> is still trim at 64, but fans may notice he looks a little thickset in his new movie, `` Fat Man and Little Boy.'' The blue-eyed actor wore padding for the role of Gen. <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Groves </PERSON>, the man who brought together the scientists who developed the atomic bomb. At first <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> wore the padding just to appease director <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> <PERSON> Joffe </PERSON>. `` But as the filming went on I realized it was working,'' <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> told reporters after a <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> screening Sunday. `` They say the average powerhouse executive is over 6 feet tall and weighs about 180 pounds. I think size and heft contribute something to their ability to bulldoze things through, and that certainly was a quality in Groves.'' <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> said he was a gunner on a bomber off the coast of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> during World War II when he learned about the bomb. `` All I knew was that there had been a big explosion,'' he said. `` I was just a guy in a war, and I did n't have any idea of what it was all about, of what the implications were.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Blankets and earmuffs were nearly as common as <LOCATION> Italian </LOCATION> flags among the spectators, but <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spurned a coat when she led the Columbus Day parade. The first lady, accompanied by Democratic Mayor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> and other dignitaries, greeted well-wishers three-deep at the reviewing stand Monday. She apologized that President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had been unable to attend, but said it `` was a wonderful day for me to be here.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> is going all out to welcome <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> and other dignitaries due here for the <ORGANIZATION> Commonwealth </ORGANIZATION> summit. The queen will be given a specially wrought silver jewelery box with gold-plated trimmings as an official souvenir of her four-day visit, which begins Saturday. Her husband, Prince <PERSON> Philip </PERSON>, will be presented with a carved rattan `` tongkat'' or walking stick with a silver - and gold-plated hilt A team of 35 designers and craftsmen have been working since April on 3,200 presents for delegations from 46 nations and the 1,500 journalists expected at the meetings Oct. 18-24. The heads of government will each get a traditional gong, a pen holder and a rose bowl, all of silver, and their spouses will get silver music boxes. Seven tons of wood from rubber trees has been used to make the huge conference table and chairs for the heads of government, while bamboo and rattan furniture decorate the lounges where leaders and delegates will rest.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GasolinePrices     10-09 0203</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gasoline Prices,0208</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prices Steady as Crude Oil Supplies Rise</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An unusual autumn rise in retail gasoline prices has slowed nearly to a halt because of abundant oil supplies and volume discounts to sellers, an industry analyst said. The biweekly <ORGANIZATION> Lundberg </ORGANIZATION> Survey of 12,000 gasoline stations nationwide shows the average price, including taxes, for all grades of gasoline was $ 109.56 a gallon _ up 0.13 cent a gallon from two weeks earlier. The usual pattern of rising spring and summer prices, with fall reductions based on slower consumption, was turned on its head this year, analyst <PERSON> Trilby </PERSON> <PERSON> Lundberg </PERSON> said Sunday. `` They rose in spring, fell in summer and rose in the fall. At any rate, the situation seems to be returning to normal,'' she said. Rising insurance and other costs to retailers have made it important for them to sell in high volume, something oil companies are pushing by offering volume discounts, Ms. <PERSON> Lundberg </PERSON> said. At self-service stations, the latest <ORGANIZATION> Lundberg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Survey </ORGANIZATION> shows regular leaded at 96.87 cents a gallon, regular unleaded at 98.49 cents and premium unleaded at $ 1.16. At full-service pumps, regular unleaded was $ 1.26 a gallon, regular unleaded was $ 1.27 and premium unleaded was $ 1.40.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0153EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GreatPumpkin     10-09 0281</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Great Pumpkin,0289</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pumpkin Grower's Effort to Produce the Great Gourd Thwarted</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HARVARD, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Davidson </PERSON> lavished months of attention on one prickly vine in hopes of growing the Great Pumpkin, but was disappointed when plants he gave less water and manure produced greater gourds. `` I spend so much time pampering one plant and it does n't cooperate,'' grumbled the owner of <ORGANIZATION> Larry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Davidson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Sons Giant Pumpkins He had sheltered his favored seedling with a tent, warmed it with a space heater, encouraged it with a grow light, dumped 1,600 gallons of water on it and monitored it with a thermostat. The chosen seed turned into a 250-pound pumpkin, but others on <PERSON> Davidson </PERSON>'s eight-acre farm grew larger. <PERSON> Davidson </PERSON>, who claims to have the largest selection of giant pumpkins for sale in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>, says it's not the first time he's been thwarted in his efforts to nurture the biggest pumpkin in the world One year he paid $ 5 apiece for seeds from a whopper <LOCATION> Nova </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Scotia </LOCATION> parent weighing 644 pounds. But the offspring `` turned out to be some sort of mutants, and none of them was over 100 pounds.'' <PERSON> Davidson </PERSON>'s biggest pumpkin ever, which weighed 347 pounds, grew on its own one year where a cow yard drains manure and water. `` They're never in any place you'd expect them to grow,'' he said. The world record pumpkin was a 671-pound gourd raised by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gancarz </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Jacobstown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, in 1986. <PERSON> Davidson </PERSON> plans to travel to <LOCATION> Elk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grove </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, today for this year's World Pumpkin Weigh-Off, sponsored by the World Pumpkin Confederation. The event links points around the world by telephone conference call to find the biggest gourd.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0201EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names SUB a0426 10-09 0153</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names, SUB, a0426,0155</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS last item to CORRECT that Emory is in Atlanta sted Decatur.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Indigo Girls say their brand of folk-rock music is n't necessarily part of a return-to-roots movement among pop performers. `` I do n't know if we're big enough to be part of a trend,'' <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> said in a recent interview. `` I think once every 15 years acoustic music gets popular again. But we never thought of acoustic music not being popular.'' <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> and her partner, <PERSON> Emily </PERSON> <PERSON> Saliers </PERSON>, have been getting unaccustomed attention since their debut album, `` Indigo Girls,'' went gold two weeks ago. The childhood friends from <LOCATION> Decatur </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, began collaborating when they were in high school and became the Indigo Girls while students at <ORGANIZATION> Emory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> said her listening tastes lean more toward rock' n' roll, while <PERSON> Saliers </PERSON> favors the acoustic sound.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0223EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     10-09 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0026</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Up In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 35,376.35, up 167.00 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Monday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0229EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Columbus-Syphilis Bjt   10-09 0638</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Columbus-Syphilis, Bjt,0658</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study: Syphilis Traveled From New World To Old</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto BX3</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHELLE LOCKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AMHERST, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nearly five centuries after <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Columbus </PERSON> set sail, scientists still debate whether <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> explorers unleashed the scourge of syphilis on the <LOCATION> Americas </LOCATION>. A study says it might have been the other way around. Research by two <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> anthropologists cites studies of skeletal remains that they say show forms of syphilis existed in the New World before <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION> and his crew landed. In contrast, the researchers said studies from the pre-1492 Old World show almost no evidence of syphilis. Doctoral candidate <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> and Professor <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Armelagos </PERSON> base part of their conclusions on an apparent epidemic of syphilis in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in the 1500s. Their research was presented in an article, `` The Origin and Antiquity of Syphilis,'' which appeared in a recent issue of Current Anthropology. An opposing theory holds that venereal syphilis was present in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> before it was transported by the explorers to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, but at the time the disease was not distinguished from leprosy. Another theory suggests the disease has occurred independently in both continents. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> researchers cite one case of a skull showing signs of syphilis from a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> cemetery. But they note the cemetery was used between 1197 and 1537, and it is impossible to date the bone exactly. Another case from <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> could be pre-Columbian, the researchers note, raising the possibility that Norse explorers brought the disease back to their country. Explorers led by <PERSON> Leif </PERSON> <PERSON> Ericson </PERSON> are acknowledged to have landed in <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION> a little more than 500 years before <PERSON> Columbus </PERSON> crossed the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>. Syphilis is detected by such marks as lesions on bones and marks on skulls, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. It is usually transmitted sexually and, if untreated, it can lead to the degeneration of bones, heart and nerve tissue. Several skeletons marked by syphilis have been excavated in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> but the dating is uncertain, the study said. A handful of possibly pre-Columbian syphilitic bones have been found in southeast <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, but that is compared to hundreds of discoveries in the <LOCATION> Americas </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. Whether a European epidemic of syphilis occurred after the sailors' return is n't entirely clear. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Armelagos </PERSON> conclude it did after reviewing documents, studies of bones and numerous ordinances passed throughout <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in the late 1490s concerning the disease. Opposing theorists say the outbreak merely reflected the recognition that syphilis was distinct from leprosy. The various explanations of the origin of syphilis have fascinated scientists for two reasons _ sex and politics, says <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wesolowsky </PERSON>, managing editor of the Journal of Field Archeology at <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` First, syphilis is a venereal disease and so anything connected with sex often has an interest in and of its own,'' he said. The question also has political implications in light of a growing awareness that Native Americans see 1492 as an invasion that led to their exploitation and devastation by imported diseases such as smallpox and tuberculosis, he said. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Kimble </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York-based </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> on American Indian Affairs, said the disease could have been circulated from the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and from there to the <LOCATION> Americas </LOCATION>. But he professed little interest in the debate, and said his agency is working on the more pressing issue of halting excavation and public display of Native Americans' bones. <PERSON> Kimble </PERSON> said a bigger issue than the origin of syphilis is the way <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>' travels have been characterized. `` The conclusions of the Incan and pre-Incan civilizations, their importance and their sophistication has really been minimized,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Incas </ORGANIZATION> dominated in <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> until the Spanish conquest. <PERSON> Kimble </PERSON> said there were an estimated 30 million Indians in the <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION> in 1492, and just 400,000 in 1900. `` That's the story of <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0242EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Dollar-Yen     10-09 0029</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Dollar-Yen,0029</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dollar Down In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The dollar closed at 142.23 yen on the <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> Foreign Exchange Market Monday, down 0.22 yen from Friday's close.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0247EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-EGermany-Dissent     10-09 0572</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-EGermany-Dissent,0596</SECOND>
<HEAD>Public Support for Reform Swells Despite Crackdown</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-East Germany, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GIRARD C. STEICHEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Along a dimly lit <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> thoroughfare apartment dwellers wave sparklers, cheer and applaud from balconies, urging on thousands of people demonstrating for democratic reform. In a crowded, smoke-filled bar, a young man shouts `` Happy birthday police state'' and his companions assail the repressive policies of the hard-line Communist government. They jeer at weekend celebrations marking the state's 40th anniversary. In the most dramatic show of public dissatisfaction in more than three decades, East Germans have sent a clear message to the aging leadership: they want reform and momentum for change is growing. At least 50,000 East Germans gave up hope that the orthodox Communist government was capable of change and have fled West since mid-September in the largest such exodus since the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall was built in 1961. For many left behind, anger over the government's intolerance of change and dissent came into full force as authorities trumpeted four decades of achievements in elaborate ceremonies. Public discontent translated into massive street protests in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> and at least five provincial cities on a scale that had n't been seen since a 1953 workers' revolt was crushed by Soviet tanks. `` They -LRB- <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s leaders -RRB- have ignored and underestimated just how many people are fed up with this lousy system,'' said a 30-year-old East German woman who asked not to be identified because she feared reprisal. Hope for change has taken on new urgency as democratic reform sweeps the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. East Germans hope Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> can help bring change to this country of 16.6 million. But East German leaders have rejected the need for change and routinely suppress fledgling opposition groups. Prominent opposition activists are frequently expelled to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Open dissent has traditionally been suppressed swiftly and brutally by security forces, but the weekend crushing of street protests was the most violent in recent memory. `` The only people who are satisfied here are people who reap party privileges,'' one man said. The <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> controls most aspects of everyday life and although East Germans enjoy a higher standard of living than their East bloc neighbors, the atmosphere is clouded by gloom and a sense of powerlessness. Many complain of the severe restrictions imposed on travel to the West. Even within the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> was the only country East Germans could travel to freely. Then, last week, that border was closed. The mass emigration of East Germans that helped stir the recent protests is a principal topic of conversation in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. `` It's not easy to give up everything and leave friends and family behind,'' said a 24-year-old waitress. Others weigh the achievements in some spheres against life in a repressive state. `` Most East Germans would say that they are proud of many of the social benefits socialism has brought to the people,'' said a 27-year-old university student, referring to free day-care and medical treatment. `` But a joyless, restricted life is the price we're paying for it.'' Those who have decided to stay and work for change are buoyed by new opposition groups and the spontaneous support for the pro-democracy demonstrations. `` I still have hope,'' said a 35-year-old <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> man who said he was fired from an adminstrative job after openly defending a human rights group. `` This is only the beginning.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0254EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpaceShuttle     10-09 0618</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Shuttle,0637</SECOND>
<HEAD>Space Shuttle Countdown Set to Start</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Countdown set to start at 8 a.m. EDT. Lead planned.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOWARD BENEDICT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Aerospace Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> prepared to start the countdown for the space shuttle Atlantis today despite the promise of anti-nuclear activists to sit on the launch pad if necessary to block a payload that carries radioactive plutonium. Pending a federal judge's approval, <LOCATION> Atlantis </LOCATION> is to lift off at 1:29 p.m. Thursday with five astronauts who are to dispatch the nuclear-powered <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> spacecraft to explore the planet Jupiter. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> decided to begin the count on schedule this morning even though a decision is pending on a lawsuit by three citizens' groups seeking a temporary restraining order to halt the launch. The groups contend that an explosion on liftoff could spread cancer-causing plutonium particles over a large area of east-central <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> officials say the two nuclear-powered generators aboard <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> have been thoroughly tested and that flying them poses minimal health and environmental risks. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Gasch </PERSON> scheduled oral arguments on the suit for Tuesday in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. This is the first time anyone has gone to court to stop a space launch. The space agency said it could stop the countdown at the 11-hour mark for several days to await the judge's decision, if necessary. The activists have said that if they lose in court, they will attempt to block the flight by infiltrating the launch area Thursday. `` We are going to attempt to enter the launch area and sit on the launch pad,'' said <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Gagnon </PERSON>, coordinator for the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>, one of the groups that filed the suit. More than 200 security guards armed with M-16 assault rifles and semiautomatic 9mm pistols will patrol the <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> to stop any infiltrators, and the center also will be guarded by helicopters and boats. `` They indicated to us and to the press an intent to do some back-country-type activities to try to stop the launch,'' said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Wistrand </PERSON>, deputy director of the space center's security office. `` We are postured to try to prevent that.'' There is only a 10-minute launch period available on Thursday, and <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> is concerned the time could be consumed if protesters penetrate the launch danger zone with a boat, plane or on foot in the final minutes of the countdown. The astronauts who will fly the mission were to arrive here this afternoon from their training base in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. All five said they are not concerned about flying with plutonium. `` I have absolutely no qualms about the devices,'' said commander <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. The generators, each containing 24.7 pounds of radioactive plutonium-238 dioxide, were installed Sunday in the <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> probe stored in Atlantis' cargo bay. Officials said without nuclear power, spacecraft could not function at distant planets like <ORGANIZATION> Jupiter </ORGANIZATION> because they are too far away to draw energy from the sun. In a brief filed last week, the citizens' groups said the government underestimated or covered up the danger of plutonium contamination from any shuttle explosion like the one that destroyed the shuttle Challenger in 1986. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> responded that the organizations were spreading a `` tale of horrors,'' and that tests show the generators would survive a Challenger-like explosion. The agency said similar generators have flown on 22 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> space vehicles, including five manned Apollo moon missions, and that in three instances the well-protected devices survived severe accidents _ two rocket blowups and a fiery re-entry through Earth's atmosphere The probability of a release of plutonium in a launching accident is less than 1 in 2,500, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> said. The opponents put the odds at 1 in 430.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0307EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MirandaReconsidered     10-09 0617</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Miranda Reconsidered,0634</SECOND>
<HEAD>High Court to Weigh Modification of Miranda Ruling in Illinois Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENNIS CONRAD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SPRINGFIELD, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A case involving an unwitting jailhouse confession by a murder suspect could change the scope of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s Miranda ruling on the rights of criminal suspects. The high court last week agreed to review a ruling by an <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> appellate court. The state court said the confession should be suppressed because it was made before the suspect was advised of his right to remain silent and have an attorney, both guaranteed under the 1966 Miranda ruling. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>, 24, thought he was confiding in two inmates in a county jail in 1986 when he allegedly admitted to a drug-related slaying. But one of the `` inmates'' was an undercover police officer, planted in jail to quiz <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>. Prosecutors say the confession is the cornerstone of their murder case against <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>, who could face the death penalty if convicted. `` We ca n't win without it,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Baricevic </PERSON>, state's attorney in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clair </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> But the appellate court, in a 1988 ruling, declared that <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>' statements `` were not given through a knowing and intelligent waiver of his rights, but were in fact the questionable product of an intentional subversion of those rights.'' The court rejected the prosecutors' argument that <PERSON> Miranda </PERSON> applies only in those situations where a figure of authority directly interrogates a suspect. `` There is no authority in these circumstances for the police to do indirectly what they may not do directly,'' the court said. The <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> earlier this year refused to hear the case. Defense attorney <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Evers </PERSON> said he does n't think the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s ruling is likely to have a widespread impact. `` Nobody has ever tried to any great extent having undercover cops in jail,'' he said. But <PERSON> Baricevic </PERSON> said that could change with a favorable <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling. He said law-enforcement officials have tended to back away from such investigative techniques when they believe they already have a strong case against a defendant and do n't want to jeopardize it. <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clair </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> authorities had no suspects in the November 1984 killing of <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephenson </PERSON> until early 1986. Then <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON>, an inmate at the <ORGANIZATION> Graham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Facility </ORGANIZATION>, told police that <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> had admitted to killing someone in the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> area two years earlier. At the time, <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> was the prison on a theft charge. Authorities obtained a court order for <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON>'s release from prison to assist in their investigation. In 1986, police planted undercover officer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Parisi </PERSON> and <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON> in the <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jail </LOCATION> as escaped convicts; <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> was at that jail awaiting trial on an unrelated charge. <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON> renewed his acquaintance with <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> and introduced him to <PERSON> Parisi </PERSON>, and the three began plotting an escape, according to prosecutors. Police said <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> told <PERSON> Parisi </PERSON> that a man had paid him $ 5,000 to cripple <PERSON> Stephenson </PERSON> because <PERSON> Stephenson </PERSON> owed the man money for drugs and had been having an affair with the man's wife. Court documents did n't identify the man who allegedly hired <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>. Prosecutors say the confession should be allowed as evidence because <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> could not have thought he was undergoing coercive police questioning at the time. <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> is currently serving a 30-year sentence in the <ORGANIZATION> Menard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> on an unrelated aggravated battery conviction. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled in 1980 that law enforcement officials can not hire jailhouse informants to induce criminal defendants in custody to make incriminating statements. The justices in that ruling relied on their own 1964 decision _ handed down two years before <PERSON> Miranda </PERSON> _ that barred government agents from eliciting incriminating information from defendants entitled to a lawyer's help during interrogation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0321EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Hugo-Riley     10-09 0488</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hugo-Riley,0504</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mayor Praised for Organizing Relief Efforts After Hugo</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRUCE SMITH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mayor <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Riley </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> was somber as the 135-mph winds of Hurricane Hugo roared outside, wrenching the tin roof off <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>'s antebellum City Hall. `` All we can do now is pray,'' he said quietly to a handful of staff and reporters gathered in his candlelit office to ride out the storm. From that dark hour, the 46-year-old mayor emerged as a symbol of the determination with which residents are digging out from the Sept. 21 hurricane, the worst storm to hit <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> in a century. He organized a relief effort which brought tons of supplies and hundreds of thousands of dollars to <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, much of which was sent to storm-ravaged areas miles from the city. He also imposed a curfew to prevent looting and took quick steps to prevent price gouging. `` He was there the entire time. He was in the shelters and he was always there with the people,'' said <PERSON> Susie </PERSON> <PERSON> Crosby </PERSON>, a paralegal. <PERSON> Sara </PERSON> <PERSON> Joyner </PERSON>, an administrative secretary at a law firm, agreed. `` He was totally in charge,'' she said. <PERSON> Riley </PERSON> worked 18-hour days through the clean-up effort and fielded hundreds of questions daily from the media. He was sharply critical of the federal response to the disaster, blasting the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> for what he said was an inadequate response. <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> officials blasted <PERSON> Riley </PERSON> back, and <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON>, a spokesman for Gov. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, defended <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION>'s efforts. `` <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> is providing everything the state of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> needs. We're talking about one of the most devastating storms in recent history. It's being done,'' he said. That storm has mostly passed. Now, the mayor is spending much of his time urging tourists to return to the 319-year-old city. He said the city has bounced back. In an interview last week, he wore a T-shirt proclaiming `` <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, Going Strong.'' Scattered around room were cards and letters from people moved by <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>'s plight. <PERSON> Riley </PERSON>, who has served as mayor for more than a decade, had urged residents a day before <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> struck to evacuate low-lying areas. He directed his staff to contact mayors of cities hit by hurricanes in recent years to pick their minds about preparations. Hurricane Hugo toppled dozens of buildings in the city and damaged about 80 percent of the roofs. But <PERSON> Riley </PERSON> said the miracle is that so few lives were lost _ only one in the <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>. Seventeen other deaths across the state were attributed to the storm. `` This hurricane had blood on its mind,'' <PERSON> Riley </PERSON> said. Throughout the ordeal, <PERSON> Riley </PERSON> said his most enduring impression of the storm was the courage of his fellow Charlestonians. `` People who lost homes say they're lucky to be alive. People who lost a roof say they're lucky to have a house. The people are courageous, and thankful and spirited,'' the mayor said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0322EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-Climbers     10-09 0285</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Climbers,0292</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eight Alpinists Dead in Central Japan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Six climbers were found dead in the northern <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alps </LOCATION> today after the season's first snow and two others from the same group died later after being evacuated by helicopter, police said. The eight _ six men and two women _ were members of a 10-member party from western <LOCATION> Kyoto </LOCATION> and neighboring towns who started a climb Saturday and planned to return today, said <PERSON> Toyama </PERSON> Prefectural police. The climbers, who ranged in age from the late 40s to 60s, may have died of exposure after getting caught in a sudden snowstorm in light clothing, local press reports said. It was the most people killed in a mountaineering accident in <LOCATION> Japoan </LOCATION> since March 1982, when 12 climbers were killed in an avalanche in the central <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alps </LOCATION>. A local police officer said six climbers were found dead when rangers arrived this morning in mountains near <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Masago </LOCATION>, a 9,438-foot peak in western <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. Two others found wandering near a ridgeline were conscious when the rangers arrived but died at a hospital later after being evacuated by helicopter, said the officer, who spoke on condition of anonymity. He said rangers found two other members of the group wandering near <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Masago </LOCATION>. One was taken by a police helicopter to a hospital in <LOCATION> Toyama </LOCATION>, 160 miles west of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, and the other was under treatment at a nearby mountain hut. Their condition was not immediately known. The <ORGANIZATION> Asahi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shimbun </ORGANIZATION> newspaper quoted <PERSON> Kazuhiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Nomura </PERSON>, one of the two rescued, as saying one of the group's members fell ill Sunday afternoon during the hike to Mt. <PERSON> Masago </PERSON>. They were caught in season's first snow, the police officer said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0322EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Hugo     10-09 0333</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hugo,0344</SECOND>
<HEAD>Governor Promotes New Church Program To Help Hurricane Victims</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TRIP DuBARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Churches around the country can help <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> rebuild by adopting a family victimized by Hurricane Hugo, Gov. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> said. `` This long-term recovery process is going to take long-term support,'' <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> told about 300 members of the <ORGANIZATION> Citadel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Square </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in downtown <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> Sunday. `` Many families have lost everything. They are not going to bounce back from those circumstances,'' he said. In <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, 24 counties and 1.8 million people were affected as <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> rolled through the state Sept. 21, killing 18 and causing damage estimated at up to $ 5 billion. <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION> has held several news conferences since the storm, but Sunday was the first time he spoke about the storm in person to a formal gathering of <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> residents. Services at the 134-year-old church in downtown <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, which itself suffered some $ 250,000 in roof, window and other damage, were taped for broadcast on the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> System </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> used the opportunity to promote the Adopt-A-Family program announced last week as a means of linking individual congregations with families affected by the hurricane. He urged all willing churches to contact their <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> counterparts, which in turn would put them in touch with troubled families. The churches are needed, the Republican governor said, to provide `` spiritual, material and moral support `` for up to a year. <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION>'s wife, <PERSON> Iris </PERSON>, who conceived the plan, said church leaders are supportive. But she said many congregations would consider the program for the first time Sunday and it was too early to tell how many congregations will participate. `` We'll be back,'' <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> told his audience. `` With the spirit now in this state, with the help of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and with the help of God, we'll rebuild, and we'll reestablish and we will endure.'' Meanwhile, about 3,000 of <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Gas' 132,000 Charleston-area customers remained without power Sunday, said company spokesman <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Lide </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0321EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Markets     10-09 0273</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Markets,0283</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dollar Down, Stocks Up In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The dollar eased slightly against the Japanese yen Monday, while share prices on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> gained ground. The dollar closed at 142.23 yen, down 0.22 yen from Friday's close of 142.45 yen After opening at 141.60 yen, the currency moved in a range of 141.60-142 .28 yen On the stock market, the <ORGANIZATION> Nikkei </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Average </ORGANIZATION> of 225 selected issues, a 313.64-point loser Friday, won back 167.00 points, or 0.47 percent, to close at 35,376.35. Currency dealers said the dollar's slump followed a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report Friday that the nation's unemployment rate rose to 5.3 percent in Semptember from 5.2 percent in both July and August. `` The market now is a bit concerned about a possible move'' by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> to lower its federal fund rates, said a dealer with the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> on condition of anonymity. Another dealer at <ORGANIZATION> Daiichi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kangyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> said: `` Now that the incentive to buy the dollar is calming down it is uncertain whether the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> will continue to give upward pressure on interest rates. Either way, the dollar is expected to remain bullish'' in the long run. Securities dealers said investors were reacting favorably to the strengthening yen early Monday. `` The environment is sound, but with a national holiday the next day, we ca n't really expect much of market activities today,'' said a dealer at a major Japanese securities firm, requesting anonymity. Banks, government offices, foreign exchanges and stock markets and many businesses will be closed Tuesday, Oct. 10, for Sports Day, a national holiday in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0323EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Quotes     10-09 0166</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Quotes,0170</SECOND>
<HEAD>Current Quotations</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 `` After many talks I have the impression that the <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Democratic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>'s citizens, the veterans, the middle-aged and especially the young, have strong sympathy for our perestroika policy. ... These are fiery fans, there is strong support.'' _ Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> on pro-democracacy demonstrations by East German citizens that were violently repressed by police.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 `` And for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, with all of our strength and force and all of our belief in democracy, to stand by _ two miles away as the crow flies _ and do nothing, and allow these people to fail, personally I think is wrong.'' _ Sen <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., criticizing the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration for failing to help troops that rebelled against <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 `` I think the team could fly home on its own enthusiasm.'' _ <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletics </ORGANIZATION> Manager <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Russa </PERSON> after his team won the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> pennant by beating the <ORGANIZATION> Blue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jays </ORGANIZATION> 4-3 in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0325EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Harvard-AIDS     10-09 0144</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Harvard-AIDS,0148</SECOND>
<HEAD>Harvard Establishes AIDS Research Center</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> will establish a $ 38.6 million clearing house for AIDS research at the university's school for public health. The Statistical and Data Analysis Center for the AIDS Clinical Trials Group will compile information from and design proposals for research at 45 institutions and more than 100 clinics across the country. `` The center provides an essential link to getting data analyzed and reported as quickly as possible,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Marcia </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Testa </PERSON>, a lecturer at the school and director of one of the center's three divisions. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> will fund the center with a five-year grant, said <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Fink </PERSON>, a spokesperson for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Allergies </ORGANIZATION> and Infectious Diseases, the <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> division overseeing the project. <PERSON> Fink </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> chose <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> from a national competition, The <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crimson </ORGANIZATION> reported Saturday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Colombia     10-09 0549</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Colombia,0573</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Find Body Of Official; Justice Minister Takes Office</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STAN YARBRO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOGOTA, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police found the bullet-riddled body of the <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> army commander's private secretary stashed in a car just hours after the president swore in a new justice minister and two other Cabinet officers. <PERSON> Nury </PERSON> <PERSON> Velasquez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON> was kidnapped Friday in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s cocaine center, and her body was found Sunday 10 miles to the northwest, in <LOCATION> Marinilla </LOCATION>. No group claimed responsibility for the slaying. The <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> army brigade has been active in confiscating properties allegedly belonging to traffickers. The confiscations are part of the government's 2-month-old crackdown on the country's cocaine barons <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s new justice minister, <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Salazar </PERSON> <PERSON> Manrique </PERSON>, is the ninth to serve under President <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barco </PERSON>. He was sworn in along with Interior Minister <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Lemos </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmonds </PERSON> and Communications Minister <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Danies </PERSON> <PERSON> Rincones </PERSON>. <PERSON> Salazar </PERSON>, a graduate of <ORGANIZATION> Notre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dame </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, replaces <PERSON> Monica </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Greiff </PERSON>, 32, who resigned after death threats from drug traffickers during the 70 days she served in office. Shortly after taking office, <PERSON> Salazar </PERSON> told reporters he did not fear traffickers, who are thought to have killed former Justice Minister <PERSON> Rodrigo </PERSON> <PERSON> Lara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonilla </PERSON> in 1984. He reiterated his pledge to carry out `` firmly and fairly'' the extradition of Colombian drug suspects to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, where many face trafficking and money-laundering charges. In <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, drug barons have operated with relative impunity by paying off or intimidating judges. The new justice minister faces the difficult task of pushing forward the unprecedented government crackdown, which <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> declared a day after traffickers assassinated the leading presidential contender. In retaliation, traffickers declared war on the government. Since mid-August, 148 bombings and arson attacks have killed 10 people and injured 164 in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, the capital, and <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>. In commencing the crackdown, <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> issued emergency decrees allowing the extradition of cocaine barons and the seizure of their property. He has said he will not negotiate with traffickers, who want to hold talks with the government on its new extradition policy. But in newspaper interviews published Sunday, a former interior minister said he carried messages from the <ORGANIZATION> Medellin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cartel </ORGANIZATION> _ the world's largest drug trafficking organization _ to a top aide to <LOCATION> Barco </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tiempo </ORGANIZATION> newspaper quoted <PERSON> Joaquin </PERSON> <PERSON> Vallejo </PERSON> as saying that although there were no direct negotiations, the president's general secretary, <PERSON> German </PERSON> <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>, did not discourage indirect contacts with traffickers. <LOCATION> Vallejo </LOCATION> said <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>, who apparently acted on orders from <LOCATION> Barco </LOCATION>, was willing to consider negotiations if the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> agreed to participate. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government opposition made talks impossible, <LOCATION> Vallejo </LOCATION> said. In a communique, <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> said his decision to meet with <LOCATION> Vallejo </LOCATION> was a personal one and that he told the former interior minister a dialogue between the government and the cartel was impossible. Also Sunday, an explosion and fire killed seven people and injured eight on a <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> bus. Police initially said they thought it was caused by an incendiary bomb but later said that theory was in question. The radio network <ORGANIZATION> Caracol </ORGANIZATION> quoted a policeman at the scene as saying the fire originated from a five-gallon plastic container filled with gasoline that had been carried by a passenger. Three children were among the victims, who struggled in vain to climb out of the burning bus, police said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Elephants     10-09 0953</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Elephants,0985</SECOND>
<HEAD>Debate Begins on Saving the World's Elephants</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Iain in 5th graf is cq.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MORT ROSENBLUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAUSANNE, Switzerland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Wildlife specialists have squared off for a bitter fight over how to keep <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s endangered elephant population from vanishing forever into ivory piano keys and chess pieces. Delegates from more than 100 countries will meet through Oct. 20 at the biennial conference of the Convention on <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endangered </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Species </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fauna </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Flora </LOCATION>. There were strategy sessions Sunday, but the conference formally opens today. Although they will also consider the smooth-coated otter, the salmon-crested cockatoo and a Noah's Ark of other species, attention is focused on pachyderms and their valuable ivory. By some reckoning, the great lumbering African elephant, for many an unmatchable symbol of the wild, will survive mainly in zoos by the turn of the century. `` When we talk about halving the population in 10 years, we're talking about disaster,'' <PERSON> Iain </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas-Hamilton </PERSON>, a widely respected expert, said in an interview from <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Western </PERSON> of Wildlife Conservation International, who commissioned the last census, said: `` Numbers are dropping so fast elephants may be exterminated in most areas within 20 or 30 years.'' Overall, he said, just more than 600,000 remain in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, compared to estimates ranging from 1.3 million to 4 million a decade ago. Each year, poachers kill at least 70,000, often spraying gunfire at females and calves along with the few old tuskers left. In <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> alone, fewer than 17,000 are left of the 165,000 elephants counted in 1970. The convention's rulings become non-legally binding agreements that rely on international pressure for enforcement. A convention member may abstain from a resolution, but risks being branded an environmental bad guy. Delegates must find common ground between the East African demand for an ivory ban, backed by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, and southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s push for trade in culled tusks. <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Botswana </LOCATION> argue that careful management has increased their herds and that ivory finances anti-poaching measures. `` We have a very healthy elephant population that must be culled or it will simply destroy its own environment,'' <PERSON> Bosman </PERSON> <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON> of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> said in <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION> earns $ 9 million a year by selling ivory from herds estimated at 52,000. `` You do n't ban something valuable, you protect it,'' said <PERSON> Ingrid </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON> of the Save Endangered African Wildlife, which works in <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Nduku </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>'s director of parks and wildlife said, `` It's not fair to treat <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> as if it was a small country.'' But a broad coalition of experts and environmentalists, including <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Humane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, say that exceptions to a ban leave doors wide open to abuse. `` These arguments are based on a pack of lies: the numbers, the level of poaching and the ability to control trade,'' said <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Note </PERSON> of the Washington-based Monitor Consortium. Elephants and poachers ignore orders, experts say, and trade in wildlife products is as hard to control as drug trafficking. Documents are easy to falsify. For example, <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION> lost its last elephant, an old bull, years ago, but officials there have managed to export up to 100 tons per year of ivory. In 1986, the convention granted a blanket amnesty to 89 tons of ivory in <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION> as the start of an African quota system. Since then, convention officials admit another 87 tons of ivory _ the tusks of nearly 15,000 elephants _ have appeared in the nation. The ban lobby is countered by well-funded traders, mostly based in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, who fear an end to a billion-dollar industry in carvings, jewelry and personalized name stamps used widely in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. African elephants fall under the convention's Appendix Two for threatened species. Controlled trade is allowed in that category. Shifting them to Appendix One, endangered species, would mean a ban. <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Lapointe </PERSON>, secretary-general of the convention, has recommended a split-listing placing elephants on Appendix One but allowing those countries with controlled legal trade to continue. He said a total ban might force some member countries to declare reservations, allowing them to bypass convention guidelines. Western said he favors a ban but with accommodation for southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, under strict control. He is working on a method of tracing tusks based on genetic `` fingerprinting.'' But many specialists express concern that complex exceptions could lead to the end of elephants in the wild. Experts note the southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> group includes <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, where lingering civil wars have decimated wildlife. Mozambican rebels and Zambian poachers frequently penetrate Zambian reserves. <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Moss </PERSON>, author of `` Elephant Memories,'' said, `` <LOCATION> Zambia </LOCATION> is wearing blinders. They can not stop the poaching.'' Van Note testified before the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last year that poaching is rampant in parts of southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. A few recent incidents suggest serious problems. Last month, South African newspapers reported a plane that crashed on takeoff from an <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> rebel camp was overloaded with ivory. The Portuguese pilot, <PERSON> Joaquim </PERSON> <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON>, owned a truck found earlier in <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> with 7 tons of tusks. The plane was carrying three <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> legislators, including <PERSON> Joao </PERSON> <PERSON> Soares </PERSON>, son of President <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Soares </PERSON>, who had visited the headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> for the Total Independence of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Soares </PERSON> was badly injured. Last year, after <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> groups accused <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION> of helping <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> finance its rebellion by trafficking ivory, a South African board of inquiry denied any large-scale military involvement. But the board said the army did help <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> transport tusks from 1976 to 1979. Two South African army officers were among six people indicted last year in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> on charges of smuggling rhino horn, skins of endangered animals and assault rifles into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0419EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-LouisianaReferendum     10-09 0512</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Louisiana Referendum,0528</SECOND>
<HEAD>Voters Rejects Plans Intended to Increase More Black Judges</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN SAYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A plan designed to elect more black judges has failed in part because of voter concern over a grandfather clause that would have protected the jobs of mostly white incumbents, analysts said. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Quigley </PERSON>, an attorney for blacks who challenged the current election systems, said Sunday voters did n't support the proposals because `` there are ... people in the state not interested in providing equal opportunity to black candidates.'' `` In addition,'' he said, `` those ` no' votes were joined by people who are interested in giving opportunity to black candidates, but are not interested in giving special opportunities to white, male incumbents.'' Two proposed constitutional amendments _ one dealing with the <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> and another covering district and appellate judges _ were turned down overwhelmingly in every parish. The proposals received the most negative votes among 13 constitutional amendments decided Saturday. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> plan was rejected by 69 percent of the voters, while 70 percent opposed the other plan. In heavily black Orleans Parish, the propositions failed by 3-1 margins. The secretary of state said only 31 percent of the registered voters cast ballots. There were no major campaigns either for or against the propositions. A couple of other items on the ballot fared better. Voters overwhelmingly approved a 4-cent boost in gasoline taxes to finance a $ 1.4 billion highway improvement program; a special fund for coastal restoration projects; and a tough property confiscation measure aimed at drug dealers. The judicial propositions were drawn up by the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> in response to two suits alleging that the current election system for judges illegally dilutes black voting strength. Voter rejection probably will result in federal courts carving out new plans, <PERSON> Quigley </PERSON> said. Gov. <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> said Sunday he would meet with judges in hopes that the system can be revised without federal intervention. Currently, there are no black <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> justices. There is one black among the state's 52 appellate court judges and five black district judges out of 192. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Baton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> ordered a new system for district and appellate court judges. Although <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwartz </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> upheld the current <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> system, the decision is being appealed. Under the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>'s plan, additional district and appellate judgeships would have been carved from election districts. Although the judges would be elected on a subdistrict basis, they would have served the entire district. Also, 35 district and appellate judges who would be displaced by the new plans could opt for senior status, under which they would keep their jobs at full pay for eight to 10 years. `` I think the creation of senior judges was instrumental'' in the defeat, said <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Renwick </PERSON>, a veteran <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> political analyst. `` The people are n't going to fund that in an era where the funds are n't available -LRB- for -RRB- the basics.'' According to legislative estimates, the plans would have cost an additional $ 5.5 million over the next two years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0449EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GhostTownship     10-09 0460</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ghost Township,0473</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ballots Printed For Riveredge, But No One Lives There</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Voter turnout is n't likely to be very good in <LOCATION> Riveredge </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION> next month. Ballots will be printed and a polling place has been designated _ but no one lives there anymore. `` Unless we hear from the courts or some other governmental body that it no longer exists, we still maintain it as a voting place,'' said <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Cuyahoga </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elections </ORGANIZATION>. The township is adjacent to <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hopkins </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> and once was the site of a 256-home trailer park. The last resident left in 1986. `` I lived there, my parents lived there, and my grandparents lived there, but there is n't any town there anymore,'' said <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullrich </PERSON>, who now lives in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>. The ballot will have four spots _ three for township trustees and one for township clerk _ where the words `` No candidate filed for this position'' will be printed. Ms. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said election records showed the township has seven registered voters, all of whom either have died or moved away without notifying the board since 1985 _ the last time someone in Riveredge actually voted. `` It is bizzare, but we have to go through the motions,'' she told The -LRB- <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> -RRB- Plain Dealer. Ms. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said the cost of holding the election will be minimal. `` We've put the polling place in conjunction with a <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> precinct, so we do n't have to hire separate booth officials for Riveredge,'' she said. `` Provided anybody shows up, they will of course take care of the voters, but we kind of figure that <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> precinct can handle it.'' Although Riveredge is empty, it's far from a dead issue. <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> and the suburb of <LOCATION> Fairview </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> are battling in the courts to get control of the ghost township. <LOCATION> Fairview </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> would like to build a high-tech office park there. <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> hopes to extend a runway at Hopkins onto Riveredge's land Both sides would like the approximately $ 270,000 in income tax revenue generated at the <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lewis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, which rests within Riveredge's boundaries. Last week, the 8th <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> voided an annexation proceeding undertaken by <LOCATION> Fairview </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> last year, throwing the 6-year-old case back to <ORGANIZATION> Cuyahoga </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Common </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pleas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. Riveredge was little more than several scattered homes, a few small shops and the trailer park in 1983 when neighboring <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> announced plans to expand a runway at <LOCATION> Hopkins </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Fairview </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> opposed the plan, which would bring more air traffic over the western suburbs, and it offered annexation to <LOCATION> Riveredge </LOCATION>. But residents voted against that offer in 1984. Most residents began moving out after <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> bought the privately owned trailer park in May 1984 and offered residents money to relocate.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891009-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-09-89 0426EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Japan-Markets     10-09 0334</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Markets,0346</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dollar Down, Stocks Up In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
