<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0028EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HeathertonTrial     06-24 0279</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Heatherton Trial,0286</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jury: Joey Heatherton Did Not Assault Clerk</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SAMUEL MAULL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A jury ruled Friday that <PERSON> Joey </PERSON> <PERSON> Heatherton </PERSON> was negligent but did not assault or beat a passport clerk who claimed the entertainer attacked her in 1985, and both women said they were pleased with the verdict. The jury refused to award any money for pain and suffering, emotional distress or punitive damages, but it assessed Miss <PERSON> Heatherton </PERSON> $ 20,500 for the year's salary the clerk lost and her medical bills. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Polik </PERSON> sued <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Heatherton </PERSON>, 44, for $ 6 million, claiming that the entertainer ripped out her hair, slapped her and `` banged and bashed'' her head on a counter top after she told her she had the wrong photos for a passport and that she needed the $ 35 fee in exact change. `` I'm very happy,'' <PERSON> Heatherton </PERSON> said. `` I've been vindicated and I'm glad the situation has been resolved.'' `` Ms. <PERSON> Polik </PERSON> was looking for a $ 6 million gold mine and instead she's back to where she was in 1985 _ working for a living like everybody else,'' added <PERSON> Heatherton </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Kunstler </PERSON>. <PERSON> Polik </PERSON> also said she was pleased with the verdict. `` No human being has the right to beat up on another,'' she said. <PERSON> Polik </PERSON>'s lawyer, <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Ng </PERSON>, said she considered the verdict a victory for Polik. `` I am thrilled,'' she said. `` The jury found Ms. <PERSON> Heatherton </PERSON> negligent. They said that intentionally or unintentionally she did what she was accused of and ordered her to pay for medical expenses and loss of earnings.'' <PERSON> Polik </PERSON>, 27, said she suffered pinched neck nerves, headaches, dizziness and nausea following the July 8, 1985, attack.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0042EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Chile     06-24 0514</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chile,0531</SECOND>
<HEAD>Opposition Unites on Single Candidate for Presidential Election</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN NOBLET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTIAGO, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Socialist parties have agreed to back Christian Democrat <PERSON> Patricio </PERSON> <PERSON> Aylwin </PERSON> to form a united front for <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>'s opposition in presidential elections set for December. President <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, the general whose military government has ruled this <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> nation since a 1973 coup, has said he will not run for the presidency but will remain as commander of the army. The army on Friday threatened `` the use of legitimate force'' if needed to keep <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> as its commander after the elections. Leaders of the pro-socialist <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION> and two major factions of the divided <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> held ceremonies Friday to announce their support of <PERSON> Aylwin </PERSON>, 70. `` It's not just a president we are going to elect,'' said <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Lagos </PERSON>, head of the Party for Democracy. `` We are going to elect the man who will rebuild a democratic system trampled by a dictatorship.'' <PERSON> Aylwin </PERSON>, a lawyer and former <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> president, predicted victory in the Dec. 14 election. His centrist <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> form <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>'s largest political party. `` I'm sure we will triumph,'' he said in a speech accepting the socialists' support. `` I'm sure we will have a government of democratic reconstruction.'' <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> had been expected to run for president, but legal experts said the constitution, written by his military government, barred him because of a clause prohibiting a president from seeking re-election. Last Tuesday, <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> publicly declared he would not be a candidate, but he also said he would not relinquish command of the powerful army. Conservative and pro-Pinochet groups are split over possible candidates. The main contenders are <PERSON> Sergio </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarpa </PERSON>, leader of the center-right <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Renovation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, and former Finance Minister <PERSON> Hernan </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchi </PERSON>, who is <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>'s choice but has not agreed to run. The <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, Socialists and Party for Democragy are the major forces in a 17-party opposition coalition. A coalition leader, <PERSON> Claudio </PERSON> <PERSON> Vazquez </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Aylwin </PERSON> would be formally nominated on July 4. Leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and other far-left parties that are outside the coalition have said they will not present an opponent to <PERSON> Aylwin </PERSON> but will run their own candidates for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Coalition members have been negotiating on a single slate of candidates for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Aylwin </PERSON> said his platform will include the prosecution of those responsible for human rights violations during the years of military rule. He called rights abuses `` an open wound that will not heal until the truth is discovered.'' <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> scheduled the election after voters, in a referendum last October, overwhelmingly rejected a military proposal that the general remain in power until 1997. The elected government is to be installed March 11, 1990, with the president serving a four-year term. The constitution bars the new president from replacing any of the existing armed forces commanders for up to eight years. A statement by the army command in <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION> said Friday it has the `` mission of safeguarding the constitutional order, either through representations or, in their absence, through the use of legitimate force.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0043EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Army     06-24 0846</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Army,0868</SECOND>
<HEAD>Army to Continue Playing Key Role on Political Scene</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-China, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, which crushed <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s pro-democracy movement, is expected to play an increasingly important role in civilian politics. It was lack of army support that doomed Communist Party General Secretary <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziyang </PERSON> when he challenged senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>'s condemnation of student protesters for a freer society. Now that at least 150,000 soldiers are stationed in and around <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> to enforce martial law, cultivating the army will be a necessity for any replacement for <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> and prospective successor to the 84-year-old <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>. Which way the army will throw its support and whether it will stand united behind one candidate have become key questions, but most foreign diplomats and military experts say they can do little more than guess. One problem is that normal diplomatic and military contacts have been interrupted by the fighting in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. Outsiders have been reduced to watching which generals appear on television and reading between the lines in their speeches. Another is that the military stands outside the political dichotomy of liberals and conservatives defined by their stands on the speed of economic reform and degree of cultural freedom. The military has its own priorities, including stability and maintaining a political atmosphere in which the army has high status. Political initiatives are unlikely to come from the rank and file, many of whom are illiterate and subjected to heavy propaganda. Young officers with relatively liberal educations might support reformers such as <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> but have little power. The key players will be senior officers in their 50s and 60s who owe their positions to <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> and are desirous of promotion and national stability. By and large, the conservatives seem to meet their interests best right now, although long-term stability under a leadership that continues to repress the citizenry is dubious. In the latest move, army propaganda chief <PERSON> Shao </PERSON> <PERSON> Huaze </PERSON> took over as editor in chief of the party's official newspaper, the People's Daily The paper said today that <PERSON> Shao </PERSON> replaced <PERSON> Tan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wenrui </PERSON>, who resigned for health reasons. <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>'s problems with the military began well before weeks of student protests for which he expressed sympathy threw the party leadership into crisis. <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> was part of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s rising `` young'' generation of leaders in their 50s and 60s who, unlike <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> and those in their 80s, were not army officers in the pre-1949 civil war and World War II. Their rise was interpreted as part of a natural evolution from the heavily ideological politics of a revolutionary leadeship toward a more pragmatic and even technocratic government style. But the status and budget of the military eroded steadily under the new leaders as funds were shifted from defense to economic development. <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> approved the shift, but it appears <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> took the blame. <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s personal power base was in the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, in which he served as political commissar during the 1930s and 1940s when it fought the Nationalist government and Japanese invaders. He made <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> a vice chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, which he heads and which sets military policy. The army reportedly remained lukewarm toward <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>, who was more comfortable meeting diplomats and playing golf than visiting the troops. When <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> cast his vote against a crackdown on the protesters and publicly blamed the growing chaos on <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, not one army official rose to <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>'s support, according to foreign diplomats. There clearly was opposition to orders to shoot the crowd protecting the students. Some units sat on the sidelines throughout the battling and never joined in. There were reports, never confirmed, of individual soldiers or small groups firing on other soldiers who shot civilians. But there were no reports of units opposing the political shakeup or contemplating an anti-Deng coup. Clues in the official media indicate <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s candidate to succeed <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> is <PERSON> Qiao </PERSON> <PERSON> Shi </PERSON>, a member of the party's top decision-making group. He also lacks a military background, but he may have an alternative acceptable to the senior officers: he is believed in charge of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s internal secret service, and at one point was reported to oversee the people's armed police, which has links to the army. There are no indications the army is preparing to throw up its own candidate. The military has not put forward a political candidate since Marshal <PERSON> Lin </PERSON> <PERSON> Piao </PERSON> fell from grace as <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse-tung </PERSON>'s prospective heir in 1971 after allegedly plotting a coup One lesson may be drawn from the army's performance of the past few weeks. Even in the face of the hardest choice many soldiers probably have ever had to make _ to disobey orders or to shoot at people who had been giving them drinks and food for days as they sat parked in trucks around <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> _ discipline and unity prevailed. When it comes time to rally behind a successor to <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, the army likely will act as one.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilhelm </PERSON> has reported from <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> for The Associated Press for two years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-OverallFlap     06-24 0275</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Overall Flap,0282</SECOND>
<HEAD>Memo Stirs Flap over City Councilman's Overalls</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RICHWOOD, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A pair of worn, faded overalls has caused a flap at City Hall where the mayor wants a councilman to pay more attention to his appearance. After Councilman <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON> showed up recently at a <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> workshop in overalls, Mayor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Head </PERSON> issued a memo asking councilmen to dress properly when representing <LOCATION> Richwood </LOCATION>, a small town about 50 miles south of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. The memo mentions no names, but <PERSON> Head </PERSON> said it was directed at <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON>. His memo does not ban jeans but asks that they be clean and in good shape. `` While I'm sure that faded overalls and T-shirts are comfortable, I feel that they have no place in the council chambers,'' Head wrote. `` Hell will freeze over before I let anyone tell me how to dress,'' <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON> said. `` It's nobody's business how a person dresses. If someone wants to come down there in rags, that's his business.'' He intends to wear his overalls to the July 11 council meeting. <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON>, 54, said he has only worn overalls once since being elected in May, and that was because he did n't have time to change after taking care of some goats at his farm. But <PERSON> Head </PERSON> said <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON> has shown up at City Hall wearing T-shirts with holes around the neck, and cares little about his appearance when representing the city. <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON> lost an election to Head in 1988 but won a council post by a slim margin as a write-in candidate in May. Head, 50, stepped down from his council post to run unopposed for mayor in May.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-B-2Bomber Bjt   06-24 0512</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-B-2 Bomber, Bjt,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bomber Critics Shocked by New Cost Figures</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> leaders say newly declassified Pentagon figures on the cost of the B-2 stealth bomber bolster their argument against spending for the costly program. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> has produced a B-2 program that wo n't fly financially,'' Rep. <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>, D-Wis., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said Friday after the estimates were `` Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are balking at spending $ 4.1 billion this year for SDI -LRB- Strategic Defense Initiative -RRB-,'' he said. `` It is not realistic to think we can spend twice as much per year on a plane.'' According to the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, the radar-evading plane will cost about $ 24 billion over a three-year peak spending period. The estimated cost for the bomber in fiscal 1990 is $ 4.7 billion, including $ 2 billion in research, development, testing and evaluation and $ 2.7 billion in production. Estimated costs in fiscal 1991 total $ 5.3 billion with costs in peak years of fiscal 1992 at $ 7.8 billion, fiscal 1993 at $ 8.4 billion and fiscal 1994 at $ 7.7 billion. Recent estimates have shown the aircraft will cost between $ 500 million and $ 650 million a copy. The figures released Friday showed the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> has invested about $ 22.4 billion in the program and total cost to complete the project would be about $ 70 billion. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> plans to purchase 132 of the planes, including three in fiscal 1990, five in fiscal 1991, 10 in fiscal 1992, 21 in fiscal 1993 and 24 in fiscal 1994. Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel who had called for the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> to publicly release the cost figures on the aircraft, said publication of the figures means will make <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> take an even closer look `` I was shocked at the amount of money,'' <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said. `` This early on we will look at it with more care and more scrutiny.'' The full <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> meets Tuesday and will take up the 1990 National Defense Authorization Act. Opposition to the aircraft has grown in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> with lawmakers arguing that production should be suspended because the bomber has yet to undergo flight testing. In an appeal to <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>, Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, a former astronaut and test pilot, said pursuing production of the bomber violates the rule `` fly before buy.'' The bomber program has been `` buy it, and then we'll see how it flies,'' <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> said in a letter to <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION>. The defense secretary, at a hearing Thursday, indicated initial tests of the aircraft would be conducted by the end of the summer. In his fiscal 1990 budget, <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> had proposed pushing back production of the B-2 a year to 1993. In response to <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>'s criticism, <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said this week that <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> is `` thinks the B-2's long-range capabilities and its stealth capacities make it an important strategic asset to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' `` So, he plans to continue right on with that and he reaffirmed his strong support for the B-2 program,'' <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0100EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--DisgruntledCustomer     06-24 0152</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Disgruntled Customer,0156</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Crashed Through Dealership Doors, Police Say</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GLENSHAW, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A disgruntled customer has been accused of staging a one-man demolition derby at a suburban <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> car dealership. Police said <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> `` Pete'' <PERSON> Ruff </PERSON>, 72, drove a 1989 Toyota through the glass doors of <ORGANIZATION> Krebs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Toyota </ORGANIZATION>'s showroom in <LOCATION> Shaler </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION> on June 15 and crashed into five vehicles, including a police cruiser called to the scene. He caused about $ 5,000 damage, authorities said. The dispute was related to a car <PERSON> Ruff </PERSON> had leased from <PERSON> Krebs </PERSON>, according to <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Condie </PERSON>, District Justice <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON>'s secretary `` He apparently found out that he could have got a better deal by buying the car,'' she said after the retiree's arraignment Wednesday. <PERSON> Ruff </PERSON> has been charged with reckless endangerment, criminal mischief, simple assault, terroristic threats and resisting arrest. The criminal complaint against <PERSON> Ruff </PERSON> alleges he threatened dealership salesmen `` with bodily harm.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ChildCare Bjt   06-24 0626</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Child Care, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Passes Child Care Bill; Fight Shifts To House</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> passage of an unprecedented child-care package sends the debate to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, where Republicans and the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration promise to fight anew for a plan without the billion-dollar subsidies being pushed by Democrats. `` We've made a significant step toward providing affordable, safe care for <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> children and equal economic opportunity for <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women,'' <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, said Friday just before the measure passed on a voice vote. With $ 1.75 billion in direct subsidies for the fiscal year beginning Oct. 1 and more than $ 2 billion a year in tax credits, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> package represents the greatest government effort ever to address child-care needs of working parents and its first major effort since an emergency plan adopted during World War II. Action on child care is expected to accelerate in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> next week, and Republicans vowed to fight for legislation far different from the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s plan. `` This is just a first step and a very short step,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republican leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>. `` I'm going to encourage the administration not to view what happened in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> as final.'' With the White House raising the possibility of a veto, Democrats too said they hoped to strike a compromise, although they are not willing to abandon the subsidy approach. `` We are quite willing to hear the administration, to listen to their suggestions and their recommendations,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass. It appeared early Friday that partisan bickering would threaten a two-week <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> recess. But Republicans, after losing several attempts to significantly change the Democratic bill, relented and struck a deal with majority Democrats on a timetable to end the debate. Only a handful of senators remained when the measure passed. The leadership had agreed to the voice vote so those lawmakers who had to catch flights out of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> would not be recorded as absent for the vote. Democrats characterized the legislation as historic and a long-overdue effort to support low-income parents who must work but can not find affordable child care. `` The real winners, the children, are closer to a safer, more effective and affordable child-care program,'' said <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. The measure was the product of an unusual alliance between liberal Democrat <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> Republican <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, whose conservative credentials helped Democrats brush aside many <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> attacks on the plan. `` This is a monumental achievement,'' <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON> said. Despite changes designed to accommodate <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said the measure contained `` nothing for the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> added that despite the addition of provisions <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> favored, the bill remained `` a candidate for a veto.'' In addition to the $ 1.75 billion authorization for child-care subsidies, the measure includes three tax-relief provisions designed to help low - and moderate-income families pay for child care and health insurance for their children One would supplement the existing Earned Income Tax Credit to provide up to $ 750 more for parents whose annual incomes are less than $ 10,000 and have two or more children under age 5. Parents could receive a $ 500 credit for one eligible child. The second tax-related provision allows those who qualify for the existing Dependent Care Tax Credit to get 90 percent of their credit up front, a move designed to give cash to families who are eligible for the credit but can not take advantage of it because they do n't make enough to owe federal taxes The third provision, which Republicans vigorously opposed, would provide parents with annual incomes of less than $ 12,000 with a tax credit of to $ 500 to pay 50 percent of the cost of buying health insurance for their children.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HUD-Charities     06-24 0284</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-HUD-Charities,0291</SECOND>
<HEAD>Top HUD Officials Solicited Donations From Those They Regulated</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two top officials in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> regional office of the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> regularly solicited charitable donations from the people they regulated, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Saturday editions. Some of the builders, housing managers, architects, lawyers and local housing authority directors approached by <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Monticciolo </PERSON>, the previous <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> administrator, and <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> McGann </PERSON>, the current one, told the Times they felt that agreeing to requests to buy tickets or make donations would improve their chances when it came to securing <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> financing. `` Does it help you? I'd say yes,'' said <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>, a builder in <LOCATION> Hoboken </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, with several <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> projects who has given generously. `` It's perceived as the cost of doing business with <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> in the current political climate,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Large </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authorities </ORGANIZATION>. It is a violation of the federal ethics code to use `` public office or official title for private gain,'' even if the money goes to charity, according to <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Brunette </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>. No one has suggested that the money raised at the charity testimonials was misused. But <PERSON> Brunette </PERSON> said, `` <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> employees should not use their positions to solicit contributions, even for a charity, from the business and governmental community that they're working with.'' Violations can result in dismissal. <PERSON> Monticciolo </PERSON>, who ran the department's office that includes <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> from 1981 to 1988, and Mrs. <PERSON> McGann </PERSON>, the administrator since June 1988, did not respond to telephone messages left at their homes, the Times said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Dial-a-Porn Bjt   06-24 0671</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dial-a-Porn, Bjt,0703</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dial-a-Porn Stays Open for Indecent Business</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Erotic Department Store remains open for business today, its supposedly `` sizzling'' saleswomen talking sex by phone under no less an authority than the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. Their tape-recorded portrayals of sexual encounters _ part of a multibillion-dollar business known as dial-a-porn _ were ruled constitutional, within some restrictions, by a unanimous high court Friday. The decision, based on the First Amendment guarantee of free speech, rejected a federal law that sought to ban telephone pornography outright. Obscene messages can be banned, the court said, but simply `` indecent'' ones can not. `` It's fantastic. The First Amendment will not be put down,'' said <PERSON> Gloria </PERSON> <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON>, publisher of the <ORGANIZATION> sex </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> and a leading dial-a-porn entrepreneur. `` We feel very triumphant.'' But telephone pornography opponents claimed victory, too. `` Many, many of these messages are obscene,'' said <PERSON> Len </PERSON> <PERSON> Munsil </PERSON>, lawyer for the Children's Legal Campaign in <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>. As such, he said, they fall under the remaining ban. The debate began in 1983, when the court-ordered breakup of the telephone company gave independent companies the right to operate information services. Callers pay the fee, usually up to a few dollars, on their phone bill. In exchange, they can hear women, or men, make suggestive comments. The problem: Curious children were calling the numbers umpteen times, racking up enormous phone bills. Parents were not amused. Neither were organizations such as <PERSON> Munsil </PERSON>'s, which has been mounting lobbying and courtroom campaigns to have dial-a-porn banned as a corrupting influence on minors. `` There's no way to discriminate between adults and children in the listening audience,'' said <PERSON> Munsil </PERSON>. `` And it's quite clear that these messages are harmful to children.'' Beyond citing protections of free speech, Ms. <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> pointed to dial-a-porn's financial success as evidence that it meets community standards of acceptability. `` At its peak, a number of years ago, we were getting half a million calls a day,'' she said. While Ms. <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> said her business is off dramatically _ down to perhaps 5,000 calls a day _ she attributes that to a proliferation of competitors, not any lessened interest in sex talk. `` There are dozens if not hundreds of these numbers in every city,'' she said. `` This stuff has really taken off, on a mom-and-pop basis.'' But a source in the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> speaking on condition of anonymity said many of the dial-a-porn services appear to have corporate links. The opportunity for profit is great; all that's required is a contract with the local phone company for an information service number _ often given under the `` 976'' exchange _ a switchboard capable of handling many calls at once, and women and men willing to be recorded making suggestive words and noises. Some of the services provide live telephone contacts. Although complete figures have n't been compiled, court records say 180 million dial-a-porn calls were placed in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> in 1984. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> has 204 separate dial-a-porn services, making up 25 percent of its information service numbers. Nationwide, the industry did an estimated $ 2 billion in business last year. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> asked the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> to look into restricting dial-a-porn in 1983, and last year the federal lawmakers decided to ban the services outright. Although the court rejected the ban on messages that are only `` indecent,'' other restrictions are possible. <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Killory </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>'s general counsel, said the commission likely will revive a plan to require access codes, scrambled messages or credit card payment for dial-a-porn. The principle is that children, lacking the codes, unscramblers or credit cards, could not make the calls. Other steps are possible. In <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, for example, <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> will cut off 976 access to customers who request it, and 800,000 have done so. And the ban on obscene messages remains in effect, although the difference between obscenity and indecency can be a difficult one to draw. `` I do n't believe that what we do is obscene,'' Ms. <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> said. `` And if it is, it's yet to be proven.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-37CentRailway     06-24 0179</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-37 Cent Railway,0180</SECOND>
<HEAD>Foreigners Inquire about Sale of Railway for 37 Cents</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Malayan Railway is correct</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Inquiries about the sale of the Malayan Railway for 37 cents continue to pour in from abroad, the transport ministry said today. The minister, <PERSON> Ling </PERSON> <PERSON> Liong </PERSON> <PERSON> Sik </PERSON>, told reporters no decision has been made on a buyer of the railway because the government Economic Planning Unit was still evaluating recommendations by <ORGANIZATION> Bumiputra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Merchant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> on the privatization of the railway. There are no private railways in <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>. Officials said Japanese, Canadians and Americans were among those who were serious about buying the railway, which has about 1,000 miles of track and hundreds of millions of dollars worth of assets, including its rolling stock, land, buildings and trucks. It also has debts of about $ 407 million. Eighteen months ago, the government announced it planned to sell the <ORGANIZATION> Malayan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railway </ORGANIZATION> for one ringgit, or 37 cents, as part of plans to privatize many state companies, including <ORGANIZATION> Malaysia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Telecommuncations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, ports and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electricity </ORGANIZATION> board.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iran-ContraFiles Bjt   06-24 0476</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra Files, Bjt,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Investigators Find ``Chaos,'' Not White House Coverup</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 White House aides gave broad assurances <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> was receiving relevant documents in the Iran-Contra affair, even though the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> had little involvement in reviewing the material, says a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> report. The report issued Friday says lawyer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Nields </PERSON> did n't learn until August 1987 that <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> counsel had n't been involved in reviewing for relevancy the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> files of <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>. Instead, the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> counsel's office had relied entirely on the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>. ` He expressed his outrage at this, since he did not view this as sufficient compliance'' with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' requests, said the report. `` The <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> representatives repeated their contention that the Committees had, in fact, been given all the relevant documents in North' office.'' The 51-page study concludes that ` White House aides made repeated and broad assurances ... that they were receiving all White House documents that were relevant. ... The White House staff, in fact, had no way of knowing if other documents'' <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> needed were n't being selected The intelligence panel issued the report after looking into the handling of documents after six important memos were produced at the trial of North which the investigators had either not seen or seen in different versions. The process of getting documents was `` very, very haphazard'' and `` fairly chaotic,'' said Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Maine </LOCATION>. `` We have a situation where there's a lot of fault to go around on all sides,'' said <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Maine </LOCATION>, vice chairman of the intelligence committee. He was a member of the congressional panel which investigated the Iran-Contra scandal in 1987. The committee found no evidence to suggest that the documents, relating to an arrangement under which <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> would support the Nicaraguan Contras in exchange for expedited <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid, had been `` deliberately and systematically withheld by the White House.'' But <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, D-Okla., the committee chairman, said he could `` never rule out completely'' the possibility that someone could have removed documents from certain files to prevent finding them in any of several searches One key memo, a Feb. 19, 1985, message to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> from then-National Security Adviser <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> missed during document searches, turned up last month in a box of papers at the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> library in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. The memo recommends a letter be sent to Honduran President <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Suazo </PERSON> stating the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' `` deep conviction'' to support the Contras along with a promise to defend <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> against any incursion from <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> The memo strongly suggests the kind of `` quid pro quo'' arrangement with <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> that has been denied by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. It was not turned up during two searches of <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION> files, but was found in an informal `` heads of state'' file at the presidential library that has never been searched by investigators, the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ExxonValdez     06-24 0519</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Exxon Valdez,0538</SECOND>
<HEAD>Damaged Tanker Heads for California</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Oil Spill, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY5</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL JENKINS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VALDEZ, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The battered tanker <PERSON> Exxon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> was pulled cautiously toward <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> today, leaving behind stained shorelines and angry feelings from the nation's worst oil spill. `` I must say we're not sorry to see it go,'' Gov. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowper </PERSON> said at a news conference in <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION>. The 987-foot vessel was stopped briefly for a scheduled look at its hull, and video cameras were used to ensure that the punctured hull was sound before the damaged ship was towed into the often stormy Gulf of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> en route to a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> drydock and more than $ 25 million in repairs. The 2,500-mile trip is expected to take about 20 days. The Exxon Valdez rammed <LOCATION> Bligh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reef </LOCATION> on March 24, dumping almost 11 million gallons of heavy North Slope crude oil into the waters of Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>. After the accident, authorities pumped the remaining oil from the ship into other tankers. The spill killed thousands of birds and sea mammals and spoiled hundreds of miles of coastline. It also dealt a severe blow to <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s $ 2 billion fishing industry, forcing officials to ban, postpone or restrict fishing. The vessel unceremoniously lifted anchor Friday and came under tow behind two 7,000-horsepower ocean-going tugboats. A third tug was attached to the tanker's stern. A salvage boat trailed not far behind. Two escort vessels loaded with 9,000 feet of containment boom and each carrying an oil skimming vessel with 4,000 barrels' capacity brought up the rear. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Kapp </PERSON>, skipper of the Journeyman out of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, posted a hand-lettered sign on the side of his boat as he ushered the Exxon Valdez away. `` Thanks a lot Exxon,'' the sign said. Speaking by radio to a nearby media vessel, <PERSON> Kapp </PERSON> said fishing closures have hurt: `` It's disrupted my life; it's disrupted our industry.'' Progress initially was slow, and the tanker moved only about two miles in the first two hours, said <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Beathard </PERSON>. The speed is expected to increase to about 5 mph. <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Toledo </PERSON> said a light film of oil was reported on the water near the tanker as it got under way. The source of the sheen was unclear, she said, adding not much oil is necessary to make a sheen. `` We're talking pints, not gallons,'' she said. Seven Exxon officers and four salvage experts were aboard for the trip to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, officials said. The skeleton crew will monitor air pressure in the vessel's cargo tanks, conduct inspections and be ready to help with the ship's engines should the vessel run into trouble <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Alyeska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pipeline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> have been criticized for their slow handling of the spill during its first few days. Today, oil with a sludge-like consistency can be found 700 miles from the reef. The tanker's former captain, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>, has pleaded innocent to three felony counts of criminal mischief and misdemeanors, including negligent discharge of pollutants and operating a vessel while drunk. He is free on $ 50,000 bail.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0120EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HardyResigns Bjt   06-24 0662</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hardy Resigns, Bjt,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Outgoing Social Security Chief Says Public Confidence Restored</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dorcas </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> says she is stepping down as head of Social Security satisfied the agency she modernized and streamlined, sometimes in the face of sharp congressional criticism, is in good shape. But she warns that while overall public confidence in the program is justifiably high, policies using Social Security Trust Funds to underwrite other government programs and reduce the federal budget deficit are `` fueling a lack of confidence'' in the program by younger workers. `` Social Security continues to be misunderstood, by beneficiaries, taxpayers and elected officials alike, and most younger workers do not trust that the government will preserve Social Security for their ` Golden Years,''' she said in her letter of resignation to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Friday. <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> said she has confidence in the future of the Social Security program, `` but that's not to say everybody does.'' And, she said, many workers are `` discouraged'' by a provision covering the working elderly that withholds $ 1 for every $ 2 they earn over $ 8,880 a year, a provision she has worked to repeal. <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON>, 42, had sought to remain in the <LOCATION> Social </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Security </LOCATION> post she has held for three years, but told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration indicated to her she would be replaced. The administration is expected to nominate <PERSON> Gwendolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, a former legislative aide to Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON>, R-Pa., who later headed the office of Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> when he was governor of <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, according to sources who spoke on the condition of anonymity <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> said she will leave July 31, and plans to host a weekly, syndicated television program about finances and explore other options in the private sector. <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON>'s tenure was marked by efforts to streamline and modernize the agency despite declines in staffing, but critics on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> said service at the agency has deteriorated. Among the criticisms against her was that new services she introduced have been implemented poorly and resulted in worse service to the public. For example, a toll-free telephone service to provide information to individuals on their benefits has come under fire for a high rate of busy signals and inaccurate information is given to callers. A <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committee earlier this year asked whether Social Security was violating privacy rights through its practice, since halted, of verifying millions of Social Security numbers for private companies engaged in checking credit ratings. And a House Government Operations subcommittee in March began an inquiry into whether <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> combined business trips with vacations and political campaigning for members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, D-Ark., chairman of the Special <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Aging and one of <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON>'s harshest critics in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, said he hoped new leadership `` can recapture the original spirit of the agency to provide compassionate service to our most vulnerable citizens. But <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> said the agency now has a plan that will lead a solvent trust fund into the next century, and `` the vast majority of the public is very pleased with the service Social Security provides.'' A trust fund that was considered shaky before she took office now has enough money to pay benefits until at least the middle of the next century, according to a <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> report in April. She takes credit for modernizing the agency's massive computer operations, launching the 800 telephone service and providing to all workers Social Security benefit estimates upon request. `` All this has been accomplished despite an imposed 20 percent decrease in staffing,'' in which 63,000 jobs were eliminated through attrition, she said. When she was named to head Social Security by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in 1986, she became the first woman to head the agency. She worked for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on welfare issues when he was governor of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, and she was an assistant secretary at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> during his first presidential term before being named to the Social Security post.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Salvador     06-24 0476</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Salvador,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senators Suggest Withholding Salvador Aid</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some senators are impatient with what they see as slow progress toward peace in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and believe a cut in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid could promote a settlement with leftist guerrillas. But the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s top official for <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON>, says a sharp aid reduction would play into the hands of extremists and increase violence. <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON> testified Friday before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations subcommittee on foreign operations, making his congressional debut as assistant secretary of state for inter-American affairs. Most senators at the hearing expressed opposition to administration policy, asserting that $ 5 billion in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> in less than a decade had produced minimal progress. They noted the civil war in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> continues and argued the activities of rightist death squads are on the increase. Sens. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, R-Ore., and <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Iowa </LOCATION>, said they would seek legislation requiring that 50 percent of the $ 85 million military aid planned for <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> be withheld for six months The money will be released only if the administration certified the <LOCATION> Salvadoran </LOCATION> government is making progress toward a settlement with leftist guerrillas. <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON> said a number of Salvadorans identified with death squad activities who had lowered their profile for a time are now back in the `` good graces'' of the rightist ARENA party, which took over the government three weeks ago after its electoral victory in March. Subcommittee chairman <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt., described <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy toward <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> as a `` costly, bloody failure'' and said a new policy for <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> in particular is needed But <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON> warned against suspending aid to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> because it would cost the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> influence with the government. At least twice during the hearing he cited the precedent of <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, recalling that after <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military ties to that nation were suspended in 1977 under President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> there was a marked increase in the number of political killings. In the absence of a restraining <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> influence, he said, the Guatemalan military `` killed everybody in sight.'' <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON>, a Democrat with a conservative foreign policy outlook, was treated more respectfully by the subcommittee than his predecessor, <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON>, who alienated many lawmakers with his combative approach. But <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON> took strong exception to a statement by <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON> that the administration `` closes its eyes and ears to the threat from the right'' in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON> said admonitions to Salvadoran leaders for improvement in the protection of human rights are carried frequently by administration officials. He challenged assertions by Democrats on the panel that administration policy has produced no gains in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. He noted that despite the lack of a democratic tradition in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, five national elections have been held since 1982 and that politically motivated killings have dropped sharply over the years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CrashTests     06-24 0435</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crash Tests,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>NHTSA Releases New Crash-Test Results</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM BOVEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal engineers say crash tests of 19 cars show drivers of the Chevrolet Astro Van have the greatest chance of head injury in an accident. The van's manufacturer, <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, said the federal tests are n't a valid indicator of crash-worthiness. The Astro Van was among 12 vehicles listed in the third round of crash-test results released Friday by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Traffic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. The vehicles were tested under <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION>'s program to provide consumers a guide to the safety of 1989 vehicles Results of seven other vehicles had been released previously. <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> said the federal test results `` do not reflect the actual safety performance of these vehicles on the road'' because the test is done on only one vehicle. The vehicles were smashed at 35 mph into a fixed barrier, and the stresses that resulted were measured by sensors on human-shaped dummies protected by seat belts or other crash-protection devices. <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> engineers reported stresses on the head as an index called the head injury criterion. The higher the index, the greater the likelihood of injury. The Astro Van crash test produced a head injury criterion of 1,849 for the driver-side dummy in the Astro Van, <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> said. The figure was more than double the head injury criterion recorded in a test of the <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> van, the only other van tested this year. The <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> had a head injury criterion of 805, <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> said. Federal regulations require cars on the market to produce a head injury criterion no greater than 1,000 in tests conducted by the automakers. The public tests done by <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> and the mandatory tests to meet safety regulations are not considered comparable because the automakers' tests are done at 30 mph. Other new test results by weight class produced these driver head injury criteria: _ Subcompact cars: Mercury Tracer 4-door hatchback, 940 _ Compact cars: <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> Probe 2-door hatchback, 970 _ Large and mid-size cars: Chevrolet Caprice 4-door sedan, 1,328; <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> Fifth Avenue 4-door sedan, 786; Eagle Premier 4-door sedan, 877; <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> 4-door sedan, 863; and <ORGANIZATION> Plymouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Acclaim </ORGANIZATION> 4-door sedan, 663 _ Trucks, vans and multi-purpose vehicles: Chevrolet S-10 Blazer, 834; <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bronco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> II </ORGANIZATION>, 994; and Jeep Cherokee, 968 <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> said small differences in test results are n't considered significant. Previously released test results, by weight class, were: _ Subcompact: <LOCATION> Dodge </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Daytona </LOCATION> 2-door hatchback, 399; <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION> Civic CRX 2-door hatchback, 750; <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> Mirage 4-door sedan, 960 _ Compact: <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> Galant 4-door sedan, 971 _ Large and mid-size: <ORGANIZATION> Dodge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Spirit </ORGANIZATION> 4-door sedan, 1,421; Eagle Medallion 4-door sedan, 745; Ford Thunderbird 2-door, 541
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-China     06-24 0591</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-China,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Asks `Patience, Forbearance' on China</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-China Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Congressional leaders are pressing President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for tough action against <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> but the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> is appealing for patience, saying it will be a long time before <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> return to normal relations. White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, in a meeting with senators Friday, asked for `` their understanding that he was trying to do the best job possible to express the concerns of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> government, the outrage of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people in terms of what they had seen there, and at the same time, to preserve our relations as best we could.'' Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Del </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` asked for our patience and forbearance.'' Chinese authorities this week executed 27 people charged with taking part in pro-democracy demonstrations. On <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, calls continued for a stronger <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> response. Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said: `` I believe the president must take tough action and block trade with and new investments in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> right now He added that `` there are some values which take precedence over commerce.'' `` The stark barbarism of the communist regime is unforgivable to all civilized people,'' <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said. `` The dust has settled on the blood of peaceful demonstrators, and the regime wantonly spills fresh blood on top of old. It executes its young on the altar of old men's egos and fears. <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> can not possibly be in the position of rewarding, appearing to reward, or in any way countenance these acts,'' <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> added. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, who has called on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to be more forceful in denouncing the Chinese government's actions, attended the White House meeting but did not speak to reporters afterwards At the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did not suggest lawmakers should mute their criticism of his policy, and `` he made it very clear that he believed that it was appalling what was happening in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in terms of human rights.'' He quoted <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as saying `` there was a long road that was going to have to be traveled in that relationship and that we should n't move precipitously. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, in referring to `` a long road,'' was talking about `` the events that have taken place there, and the amount of time that anyone can foresee before we would have a return to a normalcy or anything like we had before.'' Unlike some of his congressional colleagues, <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> withheld criticism or suggestions about <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s policy. ` I do n't believe that we should suggest to the president precisely what he should do,'' <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> said. `` I think what we should do is make it clear to the president and make it clear to the Chinese that there is n't any option that is beyond consideration.'' Sen. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, said, `` I think the president was saying that it's very simple to take a precipitous action, break relations with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, but the long-range interests of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> require delicate, appropriate, judgmental handling of the situation.'' Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>, D-Mass., said the acts of the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> government against its own citizens `` must be met by an unrelenting and unmistakable willingness to change immediately and significantly the status quo of our relationship. `` The bullets aimed at pro-democracy students, workers and teachers are also aimed at us,'' <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> said. `` Each shot that takes a life, when met by silence, indifference or sense of impotence, also takes with it a piece of who we are and what we are supposed to stand for.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WesternMuseum Bjt   06-24 0597</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Western Museum, Bjt,0614</SECOND>
<HEAD>Museum of Western Art Makes a Home in Midwest</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NA1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JODI PERRAS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 12-foot bronze sculpture of a Blackfoot Indian chief with outstretched arms welcomes visitors to the <ORGANIZATION> Eiteljorg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> and Western Art. He carries no weapon, only a feather in his right hand. <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> <PERSON> Eiteljorg </PERSON> would not have it any other way. `` In this museum you will not see one battle scene,'' said <LOCATION> Eiteljorg </LOCATION>, whose voluminous private collection becomes public when the museum opens today. `` The Indians had a beautiful art or religion, whatever you want to call it. They worshiped the sun, the rain, their crops and fields. They never killed except for their own needs. I wanted the museum to show that. It has a romantic feeling about the western Indians and their life.'' The museum's collection of primarily 20th century paintings and bronzes chronicles the westward movement of American settlers and the <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION>' way of life. <LOCATION> Eiteljorg </LOCATION>'s collection is among the best displays of Southwestern art in the nation, said <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Krakel </PERSON>, former director of the <ORGANIZATION> Cowboy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fame </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. `` He bought early and he bought well, before the boom in prices,'' he said. The best of the <LOCATION> Eiteljorg </LOCATION> collection centers on the Taos Ten, a colony of artists founded by <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharp </PERSON> that settled in <LOCATION> Taos </LOCATION>, N.M. From Sharp's colorful oil `` Taos Indians'' to <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>' `` The Blue Shawl,'' each is a memento of <LOCATION> Eiteljorg </LOCATION>'s many visits to <LOCATION> Taos </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION> The collection also includes works by more well-known Western artists such as <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Frederic </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Remington </PERSON> and <PERSON> Georgia </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Keeffe </PERSON>. Other artists featured in the museum are <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Moran </PERSON>, whose watercolors were used to lobby <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to create Yellowstone National Park, and <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, the earliest known artist to paint the American fur traders during their heyday. <LOCATION> Eiteljorg </LOCATION>, who studied art at <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and whose German-born mother was an artist, married the daughter of a southern <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> coal company owner and later took over the business. The fortune he amassed in coal and real estate allowed him and his second wife, <PERSON> Sonja </PERSON>, to acquire their vast art holdings. It includes an impressive collection of African art and costumes, which will go on permanent display at the <ORGANIZATION> Indianapolis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> in 1990. His Western art, however, was too significant to place within another museum's walls. City and state leaders invited <LOCATION> Eiteljorg </LOCATION> four years ago to build a museum on the outskirts of <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> just west of downtown <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>. A $ 12.5 million grant from <ORGANIZATION> Lilly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endowment </ORGANIZATION> and $ 1.5 million from <LOCATION> Eiteljorg </LOCATION> financed its development and construction. The 25,000 square feet of gallery space house a rotating exhibit of <LOCATION> Eiteljorg </LOCATION>'s 240 Western paintings, 149 bronzes and 740 Indian artifacts, mostly from the <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION>, Plains and the Northwest Coast Indian cultures. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Duty </PERSON>, the museum's executive director, said his goals include developing the museum into a repository and research facility for <ORGANIZATION> Woodlands </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION>, who once roamed <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and surrounding states. `` We must also become spokespersons for trying to protect Indian burial sites, trying to afford them the kind of respect that I think they have not always gotten,'' he said. Perhaps the museum's most significant contribution is the respect it demands of Western paintings and sculptures, long considered the backwater of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> art, Duty said. `` Western imagery is so pervasive in advertising, movies and television that people find it hard not to get the two confused,'' he said. `` Western art has a real place in <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> art.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp     06-24 0600</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Says Congress Can't Hang Up Dial-a-Porn Industry</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Dial-a-Porn Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD CARELLI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has left separate messages for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and sexually oriented telephone services. To Congress: You ca n't kill dial-a-porn. To the multibillion-dollar industry: Clean up your act. The court's unanimous decision Friday said <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> went too far last year when it passed a law banning all sexually oriented phone message services. Only obscene messages, not messages that merely are `` indecent,'' may be outlawed, the court said. It said a blanket ban would violate free-speech rights. A phone conversation, like an explicit movie or centerfold in an adult magazine, may or may not be obscene. That's for a jury to decide, on a case-by-case basis. Material deemed to be indecent, rather than obscene, is protected under the Constitution. The court acknowledged that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has a legitimate interest in preventing children from being exposed to even indecent messages. But the justices said they are unpersuaded nothing less than a total ban will prevent kids from gaining access to such messages. In other decisions, the court: _ Ruled 5-4 in a <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> case that states are not obligated to provide free lawyers for death row inmates who lost an initial round of appeals _ Said, by an 8-1 vote, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has a legal obligation under the Freedom of Information Act to supply a weekly tax magazine with copies of all federal trial court opinions and orders in tax cases _ Made it more difficult, by a 7-2 vote in an <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> case, for older workers to prove their employers are guilty of illegal age bias in the handling of pensions and other fringe benefits In the dial-a-porn case, the court said the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>'s effort to use technology to restrict dial-a-porn messages to adults might work, resulting in `` only a few of the most enterprising and disobedient young people'' gaining access to such messages. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Maurer </PERSON>, a spokesman for the Cincinnati-based <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Against </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pornography </ORGANIZATION>, urged people to pressure telephone companies to drop dial-a-porn services. The ruling, <PERSON> Maurer </PERSON> said, `` gives citizens a chance to really speak out whether they want this stuff in their community.'' The ruling does not directly affect any state's regulation of the dial-a-porn business. But state laws deemed too similar to the federal law could be challenged on the same constitutional grounds. The court rejected industry arguments that the disputed law impermissibly imposes a national standard for what is obscene, based on `` the least tolerant community.'' The argument is that a phone message originating in a city such as <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, which tolerates numerous sexually explicit businesses, could be prosecuted and judged under the community standards of a small town in rural <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The court said that's a problem with which the dial-a-porn industry itself must wrestle. The court's three most liberal justices in freedom-of-expression cases _ <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Thurgood </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> _ voted to strike down the federal law even as it applies to obscene material. Dial-a-porn companies make their services available to callers through 976 exchanges. The telephone company typically charges callers according to per-call rates, retaining a portion of the charges and giving the rest to the dial-a-porn company. The same 976 exchanges also are used for other, non-controversial types of messages such as sports scores, time checks and weather reports. Born in 1983, the dial-a-porn industry matured quickly. By 1984, according to court records, some 180 million calls were placed by customers in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> alone. The industry reportedly topped $ 2 billion in income last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CivilRights-Anniversary     06-24 0479</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Civil Rights-Anniversary,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Activists Vow New Fight For Civil Rights Legislation</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENISE CABRERA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Activists commemorated the murders 25 years ago of three young civil rights workers by vowing to fight in their spirit to strengthen voter registration and reverse the effects of <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decisions on affirmative action. But relatives of the slain workers said they were disappointed President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did not commit himself to new civil rights legislation. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told family members of <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwerner </PERSON> and <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>, both white New Yorkers, and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Chaney </PERSON>, a black Mississippian, that the men killed by <PERSON> Ku </PERSON> <PERSON> Klux </PERSON> <PERSON> Klansmen </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, were `` heroes.'' `` We can erect no greater monument to their memory than to ensure that the arrogance and bigotry that took their lives never again exists in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in a statement released at the White House. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the president is waiting for a <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> review of the new <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> rulings before making any commitment to action. The families were on a bus caravan from <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to commemorate the June 21, 1964 disappearance of the men, who had been conducting a black voter registration drive in <LOCATION> Neshoba </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. Their bullet-riddled bodies were found buried in an earthen dam near <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, and the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> found that the <PERSON> Ku </PERSON> <PERSON> Klux </PERSON> <PERSON> Klan </PERSON> had killed them. <PERSON> Rita </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwerner-Bender </PERSON>, who was married to <PERSON> Schwerner </PERSON>, told reporters she was disappointed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was noncommittal when they asked him to back bipartisan legislation `` to deal with the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> cases that have so badly eroded civil rights in this country.'' At a ceremony at the Capitol, she charged the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> stand in the way of `` a suitable and fitting memorial'' to those who participated in the civil rights struggle. `` So long as the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> argues before the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> for a narrowing of the laws ... so long as the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the president fail to commit themselves to the needs of the poor, housing, education, medical assistance there is no honor shown to the civil rights participants,'' she said. <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Chaney </PERSON>, brother of the slain <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Chaney </PERSON>, told about 300 people in the Capitol's Statuary Hall, `` We have to remember they did n't volunteer to die.'' `` We need immediate passage of federal legislation that eliminates all the barriers to voting,'' <PERSON> Chaney </PERSON> said. `` This present majority on the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> is far more dangerous than <PERSON> Bull </PERSON> <PERSON> Connor </PERSON> with a fire hose,'' said <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hooks </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION>, referring to the <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, city official's actions against civil rights demonstrators. Hooks also vowed legislative remedies to reverse <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> rulings. Or, `` we'll have demonstrations that'll make what happen in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> look like child's play,'' he said, raising the threat of thousands of protestors converging on the capital.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     06-24 0659</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0686</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Sedg is cq</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON>, star of the movie `` She's Having A Baby,'' has a real-life baby of his own His wife had a healthy 8-pound, 5-ounce boy on Friday. Actress <PERSON> Kyra </PERSON> <PERSON> Sedgwick </PERSON> gave birth to <PERSON> Travis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sedg </PERSON> <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON> at 2 a.m. at an unidentified hospital, said <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON>'s spokeswoman, <PERSON> Heidi </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaeffer </PERSON>. <PERSON> Travis </PERSON> is the couple's first child. <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Sedgwick </PERSON> were married in September 1988 after meeting about a year earlier on the set of `` Lemon Sky,'' an American Playhouse production on PBS. Besides `` She's Having A Baby,'' Bacon stars in the recently released ` Criminal Law.'' He also appeared in `` Footloose'' and will be seen in `` The Big Picture,'' coming out in the fall.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Attorneys for actor <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowe </PERSON> will ask a federal judge Monday to dismiss a lawsuit stemming from a sexual videotape he allegedly made of a teen-age girl in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Lena </PERSON> <PERSON> Arlene </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> sued <PERSON> Lowe </PERSON>, contending he enticed her daughter, <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Parsons </PERSON>, then 16, into a videotaped encounter with another woman. The incident occurred last summer, when the Brat Pack star was in town for the Democratic National Convention. The lawsuit seeks unspecified damages. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Tidwell </PERSON> scheduled a hearing Monday on a motion by <PERSON> Lowe </PERSON>'s attorneys to dismiss the lawsuit. They also are seeking to recover court costs from Ms. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> and her attorney. A motion by <PERSON> Lowe </PERSON>'s attorneys denies that he `` has committed any wrongful acts giving rise to liability.'' According to published reports and court documents, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Parsons </PERSON> and a friend met <PERSON> Lowe </PERSON>, star of films including `` About Last Night'' and `` St. Elmo's Fire,'' at downtown <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>'s Rio nightclub during the convention last July. The reports say they returned to his hotel suite, where they had sex with him and each other as <PERSON> Lowe </PERSON> taped the encounter.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ST. MORITZ, Switzerland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Burghers are going to the polls this weekend to decide whether Dutch brewery tycoon <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Heineken </PERSON> can tear down a 70-year-old villa surrounding his multimillion-dollar pied-a-terre at this luxury resort. Results are expected Sunday. The yellow, 71-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Villa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boehler </ORGANIZATION> has been a thorn in <ORGANIZATION> Heineken </ORGANIZATION>'s side since he bought a hillside residence in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moritz </LOCATION> decades ago. He paid a reported $ 2.7 million in 1983 to buy the villa and its grounds. But a storm of protest erupted when he asked local authorities to allow him to tear down the villa and replace it with an annex to his own place. <ORGANIZATION> Heineken </ORGANIZATION> has said in various interviews that the villa, built for an Austrian industrialist by renowned German architect <PERSON> Heinrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Tessenow </PERSON> in 1917, is a `` bunker'' and a `` revolting yellow monstrosity.'' <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Rutishauser </PERSON>, chief curator of monuments of <LOCATION> Grisons </LOCATION>, the canton that includes <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moritz </LOCATION>, has said the villa is `` unique and original'' and should come under official protection.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joey </PERSON> <PERSON> Heatherton </PERSON> said she was `` vindicated'' by a jury ruling that she was negligent, but did not assault or beat a passport clerk who claimed the entertainer attacked her in 1985. The jury Friday assessed Miss <PERSON> Heatherton </PERSON> $ 20,500 for the year's salary the clerk lost and her medical bills The jury refused to award any money for pain and suffering, emotional distress or punitive damages. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Polik </PERSON> sued <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Heatherton </PERSON>, 44, for $ 6 million, claiming that the entertainer ripped out her hair, slapped her and `` banged and bashed'' her head on a counter top after she told her she had the wrong photos for a passport and that she needed the $ 35 fee in exact change. `` I'm very happy,'' <PERSON> Heatherton </PERSON> said. `` I've been vindicated and I'm glad the situation has been resolved.'' Polik, 27, also said she was pleased with the verdict. `` No human being has the right to beat up on another,'' she said. <PERSON> Polik </PERSON> said she suffered pinched neck nerves, headaches, dizziness and nausea following the July 8, 1985, attack.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-OilSpill 5thLd-Writethru a0415 06-24 0852</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Oil Spill, 5th Ld - Writethru, a0415,0871</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tanker Runs Aground, Leaks Oil Into Ocean</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto JO2</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 9 grafs to UPDATE with federal officials arriving,
oil washing up on shore, additional quotes from DiPrete, delete outdated
material. Picks up 12th graf pvs: `Michael A. ...</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEWPORT, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An oil tanker hit an offshore rock Friday afternoon and leaked about 1 million gallons of heating oil into the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said. The 560-foot tanker World Prodigy, carrying 7.6 million gallons of No. 2 heating oil, struck a rock at <LOCATION> Brenton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reef </LOCATION>, immediately south of <LOCATION> Newport </LOCATION>, at 4:40 p.m., said Petty Officer <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrington </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> office in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. The ship, bound for <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION>, was pulled off the rock almost immediately and anchored nearby. The leak was stopped at about 9:10 p.m., after about 1 million gallons of oil had leaked, <PERSON> Harrington </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> began replacing booms around the ship, which sails under a Greek flag, with a containment curtain shortly after 10 p.m. `` They'll determine overnight what the immediate environmental concerns are and place booms around those areas,'' she said. Like a boom, the plastic curtain is deployed around the spill, with its bottom weighted to keep it under water and its top suspended by buoys to contain the oil. Some of the oil was washing up on <LOCATION> Castle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> beaches early Saturday, said Gov. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> DiPrete </PERSON>. He said the ship's captain told him he had made a mistake in not having a pilot on board and also in plotting the course. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sent <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON> and other White House advisers to the scene early Saturday, and they met DiPrete shortly after midnight and planned to tour the affected area. <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Markos </PERSON>, <PERSON> DiPrete </PERSON>'s chief of staff, said state officials are considering legal action, but plan no criminal charges. `` Our bay is very important to us. We're a very small state,'' he said. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Annarummo </PERSON>, deputy director of the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> divers had reported finding two huge holes in the ship. `` There's a long 150-foot knifelike gash and divers are now talking about a wider gash lower on the ship,'' <PERSON> Annarummo </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Annarummo </PERSON> said state officials were confident they had enough booms to contain the spill, and said it was a lucky that the spill was heating oil. `` It's a light fuel oil,'' <PERSON> Annarummo </PERSON> said. `` The plus of that is you do n't get the heavy staining or coating or adhesion. It breaks up easier and evaporates.'' <PERSON> Harrington </PERSON> said the slick was moving east, parallel to the shore and away from the mouth of <LOCATION> Narragansett </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, but <PERSON> Annarummo </PERSON> said sensitive wildlife areas in the bay could be in danger by morning. `` That tide's going to change on us,'' he said. There were no immediate reports of injuries or harm to wildlife. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said the ship is owned by <ORGANIZATION> Ballard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipping </ORGANIZATION>, but did not know who owns the cargo. <PERSON> Brenton </PERSON> <PERSON> Reef </PERSON>, a nautical landmark where <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Cup yacht races were held for many years, is within sight of the shore and of the main shipping route into <LOCATION> Narragansett </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>. The cause of the accident was not known, she said. <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Lt. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said the spill should be a lot easier to contain than the crude oil spill that devastated <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> last winter when the tanker <PERSON> Exxon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> struck a rock near the port of <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION>. `` With any luck at all, the seas are calm enough that we'll be able to boom all around it,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said. `` Nothing like <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> where it got out of hand before anyone was there.'' Because the site is in the populous Northeast, it will take much less time to get booms and cleanup equipment into place, he said. The odor of the spilled oil wafted through this affluent resort city. `` Boy, it's enough to knock you off your feet,'' said <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Connell </PERSON>, who lives near the shore in suburban <LOCATION> Middletown </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> spill occurred March 23, when the tanker <PERSON> Exxon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> ran aground on <LOCATION> Bligh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reef </LOCATION>, a well-marked navigation hazard about 25 miles south of <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION>. The 987-foot tanker had just picked up a full load of 11.3 million gallons of oil at <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION>, the northernmost ice-free port in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the southern terminus of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> pipeline. At one point, the tanker was spilling 20,000 gallons of oil per hour into pristine Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>. Exxon later fired the tanker's captain, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>, after tests revealed his blood alcohol level was above legal limits more than nine hours after the accident. He faces criminal charges, including reckless endangerment, and operating a vessel while drunk. Exxon later was criticized because no containment booms were put around the tanker until more than 11 hours after the wreck. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> initially rejected requests by <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> officials to federalize the clean-up efforts, insisting that <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> could do the job. But on April 7, he ordered the military to join the clean-up effort.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DriftNets     06-24 0500</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drift Nets,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S.-Japan Agree on Monitoring Pacific Fish Catch</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TAMARA HENRY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A drift-net fishing agreement between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> averted a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embargo of Japanese fishery imports but sparked criticism in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> announced the one-year agreement Friday, days before a June 29 deadline. Rep. <PERSON> Jolene </PERSON> <PERSON> Unsoeld </PERSON>, D-Wash., called the pact disappointing Sen. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Murkowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, said he had `` serious doubts'' about the agreement. `` It certainly is n't the agreement we were looking for,'' said <PERSON> Unsoeld </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fisheries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` I think our fishermen had hoped for a lot more.'' `` Piracy of our fish will continue,'' said Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, R-Wash., also a member of the fisheries panel, pointing to `` evidence of past behavior. The Japanese use the nets for squid. Drift nets are small-mesh nets that can stretch more than 30 miles long, hanging in the water and snaring virtually any mammal, bird or fish that comes in contact. Officials said that on any given day, the nets can cover more than 30,000 miles of ocean. The <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has said the nets poses a threat to the marine environment and the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> fishing industry. The one-year agreement, confirmed in an exchange of letters between <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> negotiators and the <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fishing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, calls for some monitoring of the Japanese fishing fleet in the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>. But <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is not required to make any commitment about revising or curtailing its use of drift nets. `` This agreement achieves a real commitment, rather than a vague promise, that major advances in Japanese fleet monitoring and enforcement will take place on a multi-year basis,'' <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> said in a statement. `` If this progress is reflected in results, we will have achieved an important balance between our fishing trading relationship and our environmental responsibilities.'' <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Reichman </PERSON> said from <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> that the environmental group was concerned that `` this deal simply is n't going to go far enough in setting the level of observer participation and other measures that would set a foundation for a ban in the future. <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorman </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, said <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, as recently as last month, was unwilling to accept any proposal. He said the settlement was hastened by the threat of trade sanctions against <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, along with <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, on fishery products imported into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The Drift net Act of 1987 gave the <ORGANIZATION> commerce </ORGANIZATION> secretary until June 29 to reach an agreement. Under the agreement, up to four research fishing vessels will be allowed to accompany Japanese fishing fleets, which consist of about 460 vessels. The research vessels _ three from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and one from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> _ will be equipped with transmitters so data can be collected to determine `` who catches what and where,'' <PERSON> Gorman </PERSON> said. Japanese and American observers also will be placed on Japanese vessels so the location of the vessels can be determined.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890624-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-24-89 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-ChildCare-AtAGlance     06-24 0441</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Child Care-At A Glance,450</SECOND>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are highlights of the child-care packaged passed Friday by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. Changes are likely when the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> takes up the bill.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>SUBSIDIES</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 The legislation authorizes $ 1.75 billion in federal subsidies for child care in the fiscal year beginning Oct. 1, money that still must be appropriated. Seventy percent of the money would have to be used to help parents pay for child care. Twenty-two percent is earmarked for state programs such as grants to and training of child-care providers. The remaining 8 percent would be used for states to administer the programs. States which certified that availability of child care was more of a problem than affordability could reduce to 65 percent the amount for parents and increase to 27 percent the amount used on state programs.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>TAX CREDITS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
