<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 2328EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-NursingCrisis     05-02 0535</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nursing Crisis,0552</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study: Better Work Conditions Could Ease Nurse Shortage</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BERNARD SCHOENBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 High turnover among nurses is leaving hospitals short-handed, but better working conditions and higher pay should ease a national nursing shortage, researchers said Tuesday. `` Working conditions are more important than pay,'' said <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Wyatt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a consulting firm that conducted a two-year national survey on nursing, called `` I Love My Work. I Hate My Job.'' Besides higher pay, nurses should have more influence on their jobs, fewer menial or non-medical tasks, more chances for advancement, and more scheduling flexibility where possible, the study says. A separate <PERSON> Wyatt </PERSON> study issued in July showed that one in 10 hospital-nursing jobs is unfilled, and that one in five registered nurses leave their hospital employ every year, <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> said. `` There really is not a shortage of registered nurses in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Claudia </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyatt </PERSON>, a consultant in <PERSON> Wyatt </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> office The shortage is of those willing to work in hospitals, she said. `` Keeping nurses in hospital-based nursing is the key priority,'' Ms. <PERSON> Wyatt </PERSON> said. For the two-year study, <PERSON> Wyatt </PERSON> conducted interviews _ some lasting several hours _ with more than 500 people, including hospital administrators, nursing managers and more than 200 current or former nurses, Ms. <PERSON> Wyatt </PERSON> said. The sample of people at 100 hospitals in 10 states was designed to be nationally representative, including nurses with a range of jobs from hospitals of all sizes, she said. Spokeswoman <PERSON> Pamela </PERSON> <PERSON> Towne </PERSON> of the Chicago-based <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nurses </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said the group's parent organization, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nurses </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, issued a set of similar solutions to the nursing shortage a year ago. Improved salary and benefits, better working conditions, and helping part-time nurses return to full employment were among the suggestions, she said. According to the <PERSON> Wyatt </PERSON> study, the average staff salary for a registered nurse in August was $ 26,000, ranging from a low of $ 22,800 in the rural Southeast to a high of $ 30,400 in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> suburbs. The average starting annual salary for a newly graduated registered nurse was $ 22,300, ranging from a low of $ 20,400 in a rural hospital in the north-central region to a high of $ 25,500 in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> suburbs. The report noted that no relationship was found between salaries at facilities that perceive a nursing shortage and those that do not. Ms. <PERSON> Towne </PERSON> also said that an increasing demand for nurses, rather than nurses giving up hospital work, appeared to be creating the shortage in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, where 100,000 registered nurses work. She said nationwide, 2 million registered nurses are licensed, and 1.6 million _ the most ever _ are working. Of those, 65 percent to 68 percent work in hospitals, Ms. <PERSON> Towne </PERSON> said. Ms. <PERSON> Wyatt </PERSON> said giving nurses more say in defining their jobs, and more options concerning shifts and part-time work can pay off for hospitals. `` Nurses are true white-collar professionals who love being in the front line of patient care,'' she said, `` but sometimes they feel they get treated like blue-collar workers.'' The survey was conducted at hospitals in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 2331EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ReaganVisit     05-02 0255</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Reagan Visit,0260</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagans Set to Visit London in June in First Trip Abroad Since Presidency</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In his first trip abroad since leaving office, former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will visit <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> next month to give a lecture and visit the queen and Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, a spokeswoman said Tuesday. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will deliver the <LOCATION> Churchill </LOCATION> lecture June 13 at <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s ancient Guildhall as the guest of the English Speaking Union, an international volunteer organization devoted to promoting friendship and educational programs The lecture is named after former Prime Minister <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON>, who once was the group's chairman. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will be accompanied by his wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> will have lunch with Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> and her husband, Prince <PERSON> Phillip </PERSON>, and dine with <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> at 10 Downing Street, said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> spokeswoman <PERSON> Paula </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON>. It will be the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION>' first trip abroad since returning to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> on Jan. 20, the day he retired from the presidency after two terms in office. `` <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> and I are looking forward to renewing our friendship with Her Majesty the Queen and with Prime Minister <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said in a statement released by his office. `` There has always been a very special relationship between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION>, and I am deeply honored to have been invited to deliver the Churchill lecture,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. `` We have many fond memories of our visits to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and are very happy to have an opportunity to again be in the company of our friends there soon.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ForgottenProvince     05-02 0769</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Forgotten Province,0796</SECOND>
<HEAD>Life Of Quiet Isolation In Forgotten Philippine Province</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT H. REID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BASCO, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The jail in this windswept provincial capital is empty, except for a rusting bicycle stored in one cell and potted plants in the other. `` There are crimes here, but only small crimes,'' said Sgt. <PERSON> Clementi </PERSON> <PERSON> Cantor </PERSON>, chief of the two-man police force in <LOCATION> Basco </LOCATION>, capital of <LOCATION> Batanes </LOCATION>, the forgotten province of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. This year, Sgt. <PERSON> Cantor </PERSON> has investigated three `` crimes'' _ domestic disputes and fights between neighbors. None was serious enough for the courts. Only 23 crimes were reported in the entire province last year. The most serious, a murder committed by a soldier, was the first killing reported in 20 years. `` We've had judges come to hear cases and they say it's like a vacation in the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Tess </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillejos </PERSON>, executive secretary to the mayor. The low crime rate is one of many features that make <LOCATION> Batanes </LOCATION>, the smallest, most northerly and least developed province, unique in the violence-plagued <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. Its 15,000 people, known as Ivatans, live in quiet isolation. They fish and raise crops and cattle on 10 small islands about 250 miles -RRB- north of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> and only 140 miles south of <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>. Few outsiders venture to <LOCATION> Batanes </LOCATION>, whose lush green fields, mist-shrouded hills and villages on rocky cliffs make it look more like the Welsh coast than the tropics. Telephones? Forget it. The radio-telephone link was cut last year when communist rebels blew up a relay station on <LOCATION> Luzon </LOCATION>, the main Philippine island. <LOCATION> Batanes </LOCATION> is not perfect. It has the highest rate of alcohol consumption in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. Per capita income is only 416 pesos -LRB- $ 19.80 -RRB- a month, so many of the brightest youngsters leave after high school in search of opportunity. `` We need government investments in cattle, fishing, garlic and root crops and to improve the seaport so our young people can find jobs here,'' said the provincial governor, <PERSON> Telesforo </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillejos </PERSON>. `` Most provinces have an overpopulation, problem but our growth has been almost nill because of emigration.'' Typhoons and and other storms batter the islands frequently and <PERSON> Ivatans </PERSON> live in square, fortress-like stone houses for protection from them, but there are no communist rebels, no armed gangs and no beggars. Internal combustion engines do not pollute the air in <LOCATION> Basco </LOCATION>, a town of 6,000 people. All <LOCATION> Batanes </LOCATION> has only 120 motor vehicles and two-thirds are motorcycles. If roosters crowing can be called noise pollution, it is the most common form. Lt. Col. <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Poblete </PERSON>, provincial military commander, said `` I do n't feel very busy here.'' His major challenge is the occasional Taiwanese fishing vessel encroaching on Philippine waters. Otherwise, he said, `` All we do is run, train and have meetings. I do n't have much to do.'' `` I think it's the perpetual serenity which we do n't find in the metropolitan areas that keeps people here,'' said <PERSON> Tess </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillejos </PERSON>, an in-law of the governor and native of <LOCATION> Batanes </LOCATION> who returned with her husband after several years in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. `` In <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, I spent the whole day taking my children to and from school and driving to stores. Here, I kiss them in the morning and they come home in the afternoon. I can walk everywhere.'' Because of frequent storms in the Balintang Channel, commercial ships do not run regular services between <LOCATION> Batanes </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Luzon </LOCATION>, 140 miles to the south. Most supplies come on LST landing craft, which the <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> navy uses extensively for inter-island traffic. They reach <LOCATION> Batanes </LOCATION> about every three months. One ran aground in the harbor during a storm last year and its hulk is still there, quietly rusting. <ORGANIZATION> Philippine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> provides the main link with the world, a daily flight often canceled because of bad weather. A siren heralds the plane's arrival and scores of townspeople usually go to meet it, since the airport is within walking distance of downtown Basco. There is no television and residents can pick up Philippine state radio for only a few hours a day on a relay from <LOCATION> Tuguegarao </LOCATION>, 200 miles south. That hardly matters because only a few hundred homes in Basco can receive the part-time electricity. When the juice comes on for four hours each evening, residents flock to makeshift theaters where local entrepreneurs show movies at 5 pesos -LRB- 25 cents -RRB- a head. Those who have seen the available movies watch or participate in pickup basketball games in the town square until the electricity goes off. `` Fishing, swimming, biking, that's about all the recreation here,'' said <PERSON> Aniano </PERSON> <PERSON> Bata </PERSON>, 45, a lifelong resident. `` It's good, clean fun.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0004EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NYCSchools     05-02 0729</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-NYC Schools,0748</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tuesday Election Pivotal To New York City Schools</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RONALD POWERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's largest school system with nearly 1 million students has been beset by reports of drug abuse, theft and sexual misconduct by teachers, principals and school board officials. New Yorkers will have their first opportunity to render an electoral verdict on the scandals in today's elections for new community school board members, but few expected a large turnout. And no one even knows if the results of the election will stand up. A federal judge last week struck down a new law prohibiting school employees, political office holders and party officials from sitting on the boards, but challenges were expected. `` All of this is making the voters feel somewhat powerless,'' said state <PERSON> Assemblyman </PERSON> <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Serrano </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION>. The city's 32 school boards were set up two decades ago when the city's school system was decentralized to help parents and communities get a handle on their neighborhood schools. The local boards operate 800 elementary and intermediate schools. Each board hires its schools' principals, assistant principals and district administrators and is responsible for educating about 20,000 children from kindergarten through grades 8 or 9. The school system also maintains a bureaucracy of employees who work in the <ORGANIZATION> central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> headquarters. The central board operates the city's 115 senior high schools, negotiates citywide contracts, maintains the system's 900 schools, sets citywide policy and, in theory, oversees the community boards. But in the last few months, five school board officials in the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> have been indicted on felony charges ranging from theft to bribe taking. Outraged over alleged criminality and proved mismanagement, schools Chancellor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON> has suspended two <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> school boards. There also have been reports that principals and other administrators obtained their positions by paying bribes to school board members. `` The notion that you become a principal not on the merits, but on the basis of how much money you got in your pocket, to me, is just mind boggling and it's outrageous. It just makes my blood boil,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gill </PERSON>, a lawyer and former prosecutor heading a city commission charged with investigating the allegations of wrongdoing. At one school meeting in the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION>, women publicly confronted a school official with allegations he had offered to trade jobs for sex. Recent newspaper articles have told of booze-and-drug parties on school property, graft and corruption. The scandals broke last November when a principal at a <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> elementary school was arrested on drug charges. That was followed by arrests of several teachers on similar charges. Criminal inquiries of some boards are under way in the boroughs of <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION>; only <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> has escaped. Educators, analysts and teacher union officials agree that the wrongdoing at the root of the scandals has had an affect on the performance of many schools. `` When people are misusing funds, then it takes away resources from the educational program. It directly affects what goes on in the schools,'' said <PERSON> Thurston </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Atkins </PERSON>, a longtime observer of decentralization and a professor at <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. A <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> teacher who who asked not to be identified put it more succinctly: `` It kills morale when you have to worry ` Am I going to have enough chalk, enough of this, enough of that.''' The school system's decentralization was a product of the turbulent 1960s, a lengthy citywide teachers' strike and pressure from militant civil-rights activists. The reform divided up the system to give local residents, particularly parents, a greater voice in the operation of the schools. But with a disturbingly low voter turnout of 5 percent not uncommon in school elections, some boards are dominated not by parents but by political hacks who allegedly dole out jobs to supporters, friends, relatives and sometimes applicants willing to put cash in the right pockets. <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Litlow </PERSON>, executive director of Interface, a research organization concerned with education, has studied the schools for a dozen years and blames voter apathy on the timing of the elections _ which are not held on regular election days but in the spring of every third year _ and the little media attention they generally get. `` The confused structure'' of the school system also promotes low turnout, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Children-Dieting     05-02 0309</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Children-Dieting,0319</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study: Elementary School Pupils Watch Their Waistlines</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Children, like adults, may be keenly conscious of their waistlines and many have tried dieting, a hospital survey suggests. Nearly half of 318 elementary school children surveyed worried they were overweight, and more than a third said they had attempted diets, according to a study released Monday. `` This study tells us that it's not just the 15 -, 20 - or 40-year-olds who feel they're overweight _ 9 - and 10-year-olds feel the same way,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Maloney </PERSON>, director of psychiatry and psychology at <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> The study, `` A Survey of Dieting Behavior and Eating Attitudes in Children,'' will be published in September's issue of Pediatrics, a monthly professional journal. Researchers at the hospital surveyed girls and boys in the third through sixth grades at two randomly hosen schools in middle-income Cincinnati-area neighborhoods. Of those surveyed, the researchers said 45 percent indicated they were uncomfortable with their bodies and wanted to be thinner. Thirty-seven percent said they had already tried to lose weight, <PERSON> Maloney </PERSON> said. `` Girls in grades five and six reported significantly more discomfort about their bodies than girls in grades three and four or boys in all grades,'' he said. A total of 6.9 percent gave responses similar to those obtained in studies of teen-agers and young adult females who suffer from anorexia nervosa, a condition characterized by severe and prolonged inability or refusal to eat, he said. `` Previous research has determined that 70 percent of 17-year-old girls think they're overweight, but only 20 to 30 percent really are,'' he said. The researchers plan a six-year followup study in hopes of learning more about the possible causes of eating disorders and ways to treat them. <PERSON> Maloney </PERSON> planned to present his findings Thursday to the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pediatric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0033EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RocketFuelFire 2ndLd-Writethru a0730 05-02 0266</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rocket Fuel Fire, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0730,0268</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Burns 40,000 Pounds Of Rocket Fuel, But No One Injured</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES throughout with cloud rising 1,000 feet into air, investigation
not to begin until Tuesday, other details; no pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HILL AIR FORCE BASE, Utah (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Twenty tons of rocket fuel burst into flame Monday in a munitions igloo, sending a cloud of smoke and fumes 1,000 feet into the air, officials said. There were no injuries. The blaze burned part of the domed storage area and scorched a 2,000-square-foot area of adjacent grass before being put out 1 -LCB- hours after it started, said <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Sgt. <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Arana-Barradas </PERSON> Lt. Col. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Rianda </PERSON> said there was no explosion, but said the Minuteman I missile propellant burned rapidly at this base about 20 miles north of <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. There was no damage estimate, but <PERSON> Arana-Barradas </PERSON> said the igloo was `` built to withstand this kind of stuff.'' The cloud of smoke and fumes which rose 1,000 feet above the igloo drifted south over the base and dispersed into the atmosphere, base officials said in a statement. Taking into account the possibility that someone might have come into contact with remants of the cloud, base environmental officials cautioned that the type of fire involved normally produces large amounts of hydrogen chloride gas, which could irritate the nose, throat and lungs, the statement said. An investigation into the fire was not expected to begin until noon Tuesday, because of a mandatory waiting period to allow the igloo to cool off before <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> munitions crews can enter, <PERSON> Arana-Barradas </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0043EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MurphyBed     05-02 0404</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Murphy Bed,0413</SECOND>
<HEAD>Appeals Court: You Can Call All Disappearing Beds `Murphy'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN M. DOYLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s Law caught up with the <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> bed when a federal appeals court ruled that the name of the famous fold-down bed is now so commonly used that it's no longer protected by trademark laws. `` We hold that ` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> bed' is a generic term, having been appropriated by the public to designate generally a type of bed,'' the 2nd U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> said Monday in overturning part of a lower court ruling. The 2nd Circuit ruled that a federal judge on <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> erred in finding companies in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> _ both named <ORGANIZATION> Murphy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> _ had infringed on the trademark rights of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Murphy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Door </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which was founded in 1925 by the inventor of the disappearing bed. But like <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s Law, in which anything that can go wrong will, the appeals court also had some bad news for the <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> bed imitators: `` We agree with the district court that defendants engaged in unfair competition by passing off beds of their own manufacture as beds of the <ORGANIZATION> Murphy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>,'' which is based in <LOCATION> Amittyville </LOCATION>. The court also affirmed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> <PERSON> Mishler </PERSON>'s injunction, which bars the two companies from using the term `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> bed. At the turn of the century, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> invented a bed that could be concealed in a wall closet when not in use. He patented the idea in 1918. At least twice, <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> successfully convinced imitators who marketed their products as <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> beds to use a different name. But the appeals court noted that in 1981 and in 1982, the federal Patent and <ORGANIZATION> Trademark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> refused the <ORGANIZATION> Murphy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'s bid to register `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> bed'' as a trademark, and a trademark appeals board found in 1984 that `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> bed has for a long period of time been used by a substantial segment of the public as a generic term for a bed which folds into a wall or closet.'' While affirming the $ 6,330 in damages awarded The <ORGANIZATION> Murphy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Door </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for breach of contract, the appeals court dismissed the $ 801,161 awarded in compensatory damages and sent the case back to <PERSON> Mishler </PERSON> for a recalculation based on the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> companies' net profits. Court papers did not specify in which cities the companies are based.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0014EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Panama-Notebook Bjt   05-02 0691</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama-Notebook, Bjt,0725</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rough-and-Tumble Campaign Gets Even Nastier</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY7</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOSEPH B. FRAZIER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In its final days, this country's election campaign is getting nasty even by <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s rough-and-tumble Stumping opposition candidates for the presidency and other national and local posts call government leaders treacherous slime, thugs and thieves. The eight-party pro-government coalition counters with a television ad featuring President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> speaking with a bogus voice-over in English with Spanish subtitles. The voice-over, picking up on a published report, has <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> admitting he authorized $ 10 million to subsidize opposition parties, although the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> administration has not commented on the report. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> contends forces loyal to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s de facto leader, Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, intend to rig Sunday's election. Billboards proclaiming the charms of opposition presidential candidate <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> have had large American flag decals pasted on them with the slogan, `` For $ 10 million, he sold out his country.'' Much of the vilification has been undertaken in the name of two dead men _ Gen. <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON>, the charismatic dictator who died in a plane crash in 1981; and <ORGANIZATION> Arnulfo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arias </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Madrid </ORGANIZATION>, the grand old man of the Panamanian opposition. <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> was thrown out of the presidency three times by coups and died last year at age 87. Both men had large, almost fantaical cult-like personal followings, something both <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> and pro-government candidate <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Duque </PERSON> lack. Even some of <PERSON> Endara </PERSON>'s posters carry pictures not of him, but of <PERSON> Arias </PERSON>. <PERSON> Duque </PERSON>'s ads rarely mention his name without invoking the memory of <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON>, the prime mover in getting the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to agree to turn the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> over to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> at the end of the century. This week's cocktail party joke goes like this: <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON> and <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> meet in heaven. `` You look a little tired,'' observes <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON>. `` You look a little worn yourself,' replies <PERSON> Arias </PERSON>. `` I know,'' says the general. `` Maybe we should stop campaigning so hard.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Just over a year ago relations, both personal and diplomatic, were smooth between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. After <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was indicted on drug-running charges by two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> grand juries, they went sour almost overnight. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> tried to force out <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> through economic sanctions but failed, and the relationship has since been as tense as any <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> has. American diplomats are prohibited from speaking to some of their Panamanian counterparts, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is blamed for every conceivable ill and volunteer `` dignity battalions'' are training to fend off the <ORGANIZATION> Yankee </ORGANIZATION> invasion that has been predicted any day now for the past year. Headlines in a government-run newspaper announced that `` in the face of a threat of a <ORGANIZATION> Yankee </ORGANIZATION> invasion, the neighborhoods of the rich will be the battlefields,'' and that `` Gringo spies, traitors, and those who sell their country will be executed.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, in charge of defending the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>, has issued press passes to visiting reporters to help them gain entry to military bases. A government advertisement in one newapaper Monday said anybody caught carrying the pass would be arrested as an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> spy. The approximately 12,000 American troops in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> will go on alert status Saturday because of predicted disturbances in the capital. The alert calls for troops to try to avoid leaving base if possible. American troops were once something of an industry here, but the free-wheeling entertainment zones near their bases are quiet today.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Despite the negative tone of the campaign, there is a refreshing lightness to some of it. Latin jazz bands packed into pickups drive around displaying flags and decals from any of the 11 parties fielding candidates. Campaign songs blare from trucks that stop in the middle of busy intersections, play their message to a grid-locked audience, then drive off. A mish mash of colorful campaign posters covers just about everything that does n't move and many things that do. In one of the city's wealthier neighborhoods, a man patiently peeled 50 Christian Democrat posters off a wall around his house. Two hours later, the wall was covered again with posters from another party. It was hopeless.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PresidentialSalmon     05-02 0240</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Presidential Salmon,0245</SECOND>
<HEAD>Maine Sea-Run Salmon May be White House Bound</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGOR, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 His catch gave him quite a battle, but a fisherman known as `` Salmon Bill'' landed the season's first salmon on <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Penobscot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, earning him the right to offer his prize to the president. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellison </PERSON>, 41, who lives in a tent near the river during the May-mid-October season, caught the 25 -LCB- - inch, 6-pound fish early Monday `` This fish took me out in the middle of the river three or four times. She did n't want to come ashore no how, and it was nip and tuck right up to the end. But she finally came in,'' said <PERSON> Ellison </PERSON>, who was among about 100 anglers in the <LOCATION> Penobscot </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Bangor </LOCATION> for the opening of season. Within hours, the fish had been certified as a sea-run salmon and up to standards for delivery to the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, in keeping with tradition. <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> Inland Fisheries and Wildlife Department officials were making arrangements for a presentation later this month to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who is a fishing enthusiast, said department spokesman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Fournier </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ellison </PERSON>'s offer continues a tradition that started in 1912 when a sea-run salmon was presented to President <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Taft </PERSON>. Pollution of the Penobscot forced a halt to the practice during the 1960s, but with cleanup efforts, extensive restocking, removal of some dams and construction of fish ladders, the tradition was revived after President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was elected.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0058EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Letterman     05-02 0212</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Letterman,0219</SECOND>
<HEAD>Letterman Back In Heartland</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Letterman </PERSON> is taking his `` Late Night'' show to his native <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> for a week of `` deep-dish'' humor, Chicago-style. The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> City-based show today was opening a four-day stint at the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Theater. The set will be modeled after the city's downtown Loop district and feature a moving replica of an elevated train in the background `` The <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> seemed a natural place for <PERSON> Dave </PERSON>,'' executive producer <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON> said Monday. `` It's almost like coming home. ... It's the center of the country _ what do they call it? The heartland?'' <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON> noted that <PERSON> Letterman </PERSON> is a native of neighboring <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>. Producer <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> acknowledged that the show has a strong `` <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> feel,'' but said the host would adapt easily to the new surroundings. <PERSON> Letterman </PERSON> `` very much represents the sensibility of the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>,'' he said. Segments this week will feature a Midwestern or <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> flavor, such as wacky props that are `` deep-dish anything,'' Midwestern pets performing stupid tricks and a visit to <LOCATION> Wrigley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Field </LOCATION> that `` has something to do with the lights,'' <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> said. Guests include talk show host <PERSON> Oprah </PERSON> <PERSON> Winfrey </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bulls </ORGANIZATION> star <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>. Some of the city's blues artists will perform each night on the <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION> show.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-CityWolf     05-02 0302</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-City Wolf,0310</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ownership of Captured Wolf Tracked to `Flash Gordon' Actor Sam Jones</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A wolf that ran wild in a residential area and ate a pet rabbit belongs to actor <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, but the `` Flash Gordon'' star wo n't be getting his pet back, authorities said. `` We believe he purchased it as a pup from a breeder so it was raised in a sort of domestic environment. But still, you ca n't have them,'' Lt. <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> of the city's <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulation </ORGANIZATION> said Monday. The 100-pound wolf, a full-grown female named Hurricane, was captured April 14 near the <LOCATION> Encino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reservoir </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fernando </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. Residents of the hillside neighborhood had complained that a huge white dog had been roaming the area for about two months and gobbled down a rabbit. <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> said the predator is probably an endangered gray wolf. Its nearest wild relatives are in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. In addition to starring in the 1980 movie `` Flash <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> appeared in `` 10'' and in the television series `` <PERSON> Hardcastle </PERSON> and <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON>,'' `` Hunter'' and `` Highwaymen.'' His personal manager, <PERSON> Stan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kamens </PERSON>, said he had no knowledge of the matter and would not comment. Keeping wolves within city limits without a permit is a misdemeanor punishable by up to six months in jail and a fine of up to $ 500, said Lt. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> of the animal regulation department. But he said there were no immediate plans to prosecute <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>. Hurricane apparently lived by hunting wild rabbits, ground squirrels, opossums and quail in the uninhabited brush around the reservoir, officials said. `` We want to give the wolf to some type of a sanctuary that can handle that type of animal. We just do n't want to send it anywhere,'' <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> said. `` She's not going back to the owner.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0022EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-AirForceCrash     05-02 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Air Force Crash,0186</SECOND>
<HEAD>F-15 Crashes in Gulf of Mexico</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TYNDALL AIR FORCE BASE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> F-15 on a training mission crashed over a target range Monday in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, and a search was mounted for the pilot. The twin-engine fighter jet went down around 12:45 p.m. EDT about 65 miles southeast of this base on the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Panhandle </LOCATION>, said Staff Sgt. <PERSON> Gail </PERSON> <PERSON> Floyd </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Air Defense Weapons Center. Officials planned to search the area with ships overnight. If the pilot is not found by daylight Tuesday, search aircraft will be dispatched, <PERSON> Floyd </PERSON> said. The pilot, who was alone and on a student training mission, was not identified, but it was believed he was <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, 24. His father, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, said the family was notified Monday night that his son's plane had gone down. `` Maybe he's just sitting in his little rubber boat, just waiting,'' <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wayne </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- <PERSON> Journal-Gazette </PERSON>. `` It could be two or three days because the gulf's a pretty big place to be looking.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-FBI-CampusPolice     05-02 0250</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-FBI-Campus Police,0258</SECOND>
<HEAD>FBI Investigating ASU Police Treatment Of Blacks After Brawl</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TEMPE, Arizona (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> is investigating allegations that <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> campus police bullied black students while breaking up a brawl last month, officials said. <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartosh </PERSON> said Friday that agent <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Small </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> bureau called him that week to tell him his department would be investigated. Small said the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> has begun an investigation into possible civil rights violations, but would not say what the focus of the probe was. `` We welcome the investigation,'' said <PERSON> Bartosh </PERSON>. `` I feel our officers acted appropriately based on the information I have.'' <ORGANIZATION> ASU </ORGANIZATION> police came under fire for their handling of the April 16 brawl on Fraternity Row in which an unruly group of white students began yelling racial slurs at four black students who drove into the conflict. While trying to break up the fight, police handcuffed <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Rucker </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Liddell </PERSON>, both 20-year-old members of the university track team. <PERSON> Rucker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Liddell </PERSON> were put in patrol cars and taken to campus police headquarters. <PERSON> Rucker </PERSON> said that when he and <PERSON> Liddell </PERSON> complained the handcuffs were too tight, one officer said, `` Next time, I'll put them on so tight they'll make you cry.'' The allegations of rough treatment resulted in three days of protests by minority students and a promise by <ORGANIZATION> ASU </ORGANIZATION> administrators to take steps to reduce racism on campus. Small said the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> investigation could take several months to complete.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0043EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Paraguay 4thLd-Writethru a0741 05-02 0836</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Paraguay, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0741,0858</SECOND>
<HEAD>Governing Party Candidate Routs Opponents in Paraguay Election</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 15 grafs to UPDATE with Rodriguez claiming victory,
updated vote tallies. Picks up 15th pvs, `Election observers ...' ^LaserPhoto
ASU1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED McCULLOUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ASUNCION, Paraguay (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gen. <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, who ousted <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> and his 34-year dictatorship three months ago, routed seven other candidates in presidential elections Monday, unofficial returns showed. Opposition candidates denounced `` numerous and serious'' irregularities in the balloting, but by late Monday evening had not withdrawn from the election or challenged the early results. One opponent conceded. `` We promise our people we will carry <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION> on a bright path to its destiny of greatness and happiness,'' <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> told cheering party members at his home Monday night as he lifted a glass of champagne in a toast. Official returns had not been disclosed nearly eight hours after polls closed but unofficial tallies by <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>' ruling <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> as well as by the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> and the political science group <ORGANIZATION> CEPES </ORGANIZATION> showed the general won by an overwhelming majority. <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> <PERSON> Laino </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Authentic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and the presidents of three other opposition parties denounced `` serious deficiencies'' in the balloting. They refused to concede, but did not withdraw. According to the <ORGANIZATION> Colorados </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> received 576,312 votes of 772,785 cast for president, or 74.5 percent. The closest challenger, <PERSON> Laino </PERSON>, garnered 158,851 votes or 19.94 percent. The votes represented nearly more than a third of the 2.2 million people on official voter registration lists. Non-Colorado candidates have complained that the list was out of date and bloated, and even the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said the list might contain 600,000 duplicate or non-existent names. The <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, one of eight parties that submitted slates of candidates for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, said it garnered 552,542 votes for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> out of 743,150 votes cast, or 74.4 percent. It said <PERSON> Laino </PERSON>'s party received 148,202, or 19.9 percent. The Colorados would thus, by law, receive 24 of the 36 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seats and 48 spots in the 72-seat Chamber of Deputies. <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, 65, an army general and longtime aide to <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>, dissolved <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> after leading the Feb. 3 coup that ended nearly 35 years of <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> rule. He served as provisional president since then. <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> also belonged to the party, which has been in power since 1947. Turnout appeared high across this landlocked South American nation of 4 million, despite cloudy skies, light rain and cool fall weather. Diplomats and foreign observers said the balloting and vote count were reasonably fair and <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> clearly won. `` I think it was a very good attempt at something they have never done before,'' said British Ambassador <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>. Presidential candidate <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferreira </PERSON> <PERSON> Ibarra </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> acknowledged that <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> won. <PERSON> Laino </PERSON>, a former exile, said earlier Monday that the voting irregularities were `` numerous and serious. We do not have all the information, but the irregularities exceeded our expectations.'' Election observers and party officials said not every citizen was able to vote in private; ballots of opposition parties were stolen and so not available at election tables; indelible ink was not always used to prevent multiple voting, and the government added voters to the official list after the registration period ended three weeks ago. <PERSON> Euclides </PERSON> <PERSON> Acevedo </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Febrerista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said ballots for his party were stolen at several voting stations by <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> supporters `` who simply put them in their pockets.'' But <PERSON> Fernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Vera </PERSON>, the party's presidential nominee, said the four opposition parties were not about to withdraw from the election. `` Why the obsession about withdrawing?'' <PERSON> Vera </PERSON> asked a reporter. `` No one has to withdraw from the process. ... What must be done is determine on the basis of results if the fraud ... was significant in its entirety or not.'' Government and <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> officials denied irregularities were widespread, organized by them or influenced the outcome. Paraguayans seemed to accept as unavoidable one more general in the National Palace and the <ORGANIZATION> Colorados </ORGANIZATION> once more in control of congress, given the suddenness of elections following a long dictatorship. `` My party was founded in 1965. This is the first time we're participating in elections,'' said <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Caceres </PERSON>, 28, a Christian Democrat `` People are hopeful,'' he said, standing in a school courtyard. `` The period of <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> has n't ended ... but this is a beneficial transition _ peaceful, with people getting used to democracy.'' In <PERSON> Coronel </PERSON> <PERSON> Oviedo </PERSON>, a large rural town 80 miles east of the capital city of <LOCATION> Asuncion </LOCATION>, peasants traveled along muddy roads to voting stations by flatbed truck, horse, bicycle and tractor. `` The last time I voted was in <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>'s second re-election,'' in the late 1960s, said <PERSON> Dario </PERSON> <PERSON> Benitez </PERSON>, 60. `` Then I quit because I did n't like him anymore.'' Since becoming provisional president, <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> has criticized the former regime, permitted banned newspapers and political parties to operate and mended fences with foreign governments and the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. Prominent <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> aides and ministers have been arrested. <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>, 76, lives in exile in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0537EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Jennings-Preacher     05-02 0177</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Jennings-Preacher,0181</SECOND>
<HEAD>ABC Newsman Peter Jennings Becomes Preacher For Day</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> anchorman <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> questioned <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> defense spending while acting as preacher for a day at groundbreaking ceremonies for an Episcopal diocesan center. `` My question for all of us is: How much are we willing to spend against the other threats to our life?'' <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> asked Sunday from the pulpit of the Cathedral of the Incarnation. <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> noted that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> was considering a $ 300 billion defense appropriation request, but said agencies responsible for environmental protection, housing or schools received only a fraction of that amount. `` We know <PERSON> God </PERSON> has given us the means to ease the pain, to ease the suffering,'' <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> said. `` But somehow we must find the ingredients to do more, much more.'' Before his sermon, <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> joined <PERSON> Episcopal </PERSON> <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Eastman </PERSON>, Mayor <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmoke </PERSON>, the cathedral's dean and two lay officials. The six used a four-handled silver shovel to turn the first spade of dirt for the new $ 4 million center for the Episcopal Diocese of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     05-02 0962</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0999</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAKE BUENA VISTA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> helped open <ORGANIZATION> Disney-MGM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION>' new $ 400 million theme park, capping a star-studded weekend of parties and previews. `` It's the largest theme park run by actors, or cartoon characters, unless you want to count <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>,'' joked Hope. Hope joined <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisner </PERSON> in opening day ceremonies Monday on an outdoor stage in front of a re-creation of <PERSON> Grauman </PERSON>'s Chinese Theater on <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Boulevard </LOCATION>. The 135-acre complex combines filmmaking with backstage studio tours and attractions like the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> Jones Epic Stunt Spectacular theater show. `` The world you have entered was created by the <ORGANIZATION> Walt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> and is dedicated to <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> ... a world that never was and always will be,'' <PERSON> Eisner </PERSON> told the crowd. The grand opening followed a weekend of festivities, including a Saturday night gala in which 40 movie and television stars paraded down the park's <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Boulevard </LOCATION> in vintage automobiles. Among them were <PERSON> Bette </PERSON> <PERSON> Midler </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lauren </PERSON> <PERSON> Bacall </PERSON>, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>, <PERSON> Audrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON>, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Costner </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WEST HOLLYWOOD, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American rockers <PERSON> Bon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jovi </PERSON> and <PERSON> Motley </PERSON> <PERSON> Crue </PERSON> will join West German and Russian bands in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> this summer in a benefit concert for drug abuse programs on both sides of the Iron Curtain. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s Scorpions and the <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> ensemble Gorky Park will share the stge with the two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hard-rock groups at <LOCATION> Lenin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION> on Aug. 12-13 for the `` Moscow Music and Peace Summit,'' it was announced Monday. Proceeds will go to drug - and alcohol-abuse programs in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> `` There is really a very big problem in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> with drugs and alcohol,'' <PERSON> Gorky </PERSON> <PERSON> Park </PERSON>'s <PERSON> Sasha </PERSON> <PERSON> Minkov </PERSON> said at a news conference. `` Maybe not so much with drugs, as in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, but alcohol for sure.'' `` This is something we really think is going to make a difference. The youth is tomorrow's leader,'' said <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Bon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jovi </PERSON>, an admitted former drug user. The groups and other rock artists including <ORGANIZATION> Ozzy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Osbourne </ORGANIZATION> and Skid Row also will issue a related studio album in August. The album will feature new renditions of songs by groups who have lost a member to substance abuse, such as the Sex Pistols and The Who. Portions of the concert will be shown in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on <ORGANIZATION> Showtime </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Event </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> on a pay-per-view basis. The Westwood One radio network will carry the Aug. 13 show live.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version moving on sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>HOUSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Romanian-born gymnastics guru <PERSON> Bela </PERSON> <PERSON> Karolyi </PERSON> can pack a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> passport on his next international coaching tour. He's now a citizen `` It's a great moment and I'll never forget it,'' said <PERSON> Karolyi </PERSON>, 46, who guided <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Retton </PERSON> and other young Americans to Olympic fame after defecting eight years ago. `` Now, I am an American.'' <PERSON> Karolyi </PERSON>, his 46-year-old wife and fellow coach, <PERSON> Marta </PERSON>, and daughter, <PERSON> Andrea </PERSON>, 15, were among 1,201 people who became citizens in a ceremony Monday. `` My students are the ones who are representing the whole American young generation and, along with them, I would like to step on that floor not just as a professional coach but as an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> citizen,'' he said. <PERSON> Karolyi </PERSON>, who coached Olympic gold medalist <PERSON> Nadia </PERSON> <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, defected in March 1981 while on a tour of 15 American cities with the Romanian team. But the usual five-year citizenship process stretched to eight after immigration officials twice lost the <ORGANIZATION> Karolyis </ORGANIZATION>' paperwork.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Good Morning, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'' star <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> has married his girlfriend, the former live-in nanny of his son. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, 36, married <PERSON> Marsha </PERSON> <PERSON> Garces </PERSON> in a private ceremony in <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tahoe </LOCATION> attended by a few close friends, his publicist, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Rutenberg </PERSON>, said Monday. Miss <PERSON> Garces </PERSON> is believed to be in her late 20s or early 30s. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, whose credits including television's `` Mork and <PERSON> Mindy </PERSON>'' and the movie `` The World According to Garp,'' met Miss <PERSON> Garces </PERSON> five years ago when he and his former wife, <PERSON> Valerie </PERSON> <PERSON> Velardi </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, hired her as a nanny for their son, <PERSON> Zachary </PERSON>. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> and his former wife, who filed for divorce last year, share custody of the boy.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TRENTON, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A state appeals court has upheld most of a divorce judgment against comedian <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Piscopo </PERSON>, frustrating his effort to gain custody of his 10-year-old son. A three-judge panel Monday rejected <PERSON> Piscopo </PERSON>'s argument that his ex-wife should not have been allowed to move from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> with their only child. The judges also upheld the awarding of $ 500,000 in joint assets to <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Piscopo </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON> and an additional award of $ 50,000, which was half the value placed on <PERSON> Piscopo </PERSON>'s celebrity status. The court also said it was n't unreasonable to require the actor and former `` Saturday Night Live'' regular to pay $ 40,000 a year in child support to his ex-wife. Mrs. <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON> has remarried since the 1988 divorce decree. Attorney <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Donahue </PERSON> said he would discuss with <PERSON> Piscopo </PERSON> whether to appeal the case to the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer-songwriter <PERSON> Lionel </PERSON> <PERSON> Richie </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON>, have pledged $ 500,000 to <ORGANIZATION> Tuskegee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> to endow a chair in at their alma mater's business school. <PERSON> Richie </PERSON>, who won an Academy Award for `` Say You, Say Me,'' plus numerous Grammy and American Music awards, is a graduate of Tuskegee's business school. <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Richie </PERSON> has a social work degree from the <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> school's arts and sciences college. The endowment represents `` the <ORGANIZATION> Richies </ORGANIZATION>' genuine commitment to intellectual development in general and the special mission of historically <PERSON> black </PERSON> institutions and the people they serve,'' Tuskegee President <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Payton </PERSON> said in a statement released Friday. The Lionel and <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Richie </PERSON> <PERSON> Chair </PERSON> is the first of its kind at the university, <PERSON> Payton </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0131EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     05-02 0393</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pet Sematary Keeps No. 1 Plot</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD DE ATLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>'s terrifying `` Pet Sematary'' remained moviegoers' favorite for the second-straight weekend, and the comedy `` K-9'' made its debut in second place. `` Pet Sematary'' earned $ 8.3 million last weekend and has brought in more than $ 24 million in its two weeks of release. `` K-9,'' which stars <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Belushi </PERSON> as a narcotics detective teamed with a hot shot German shepherd, sold $ 7.4 million worth of tickets. `` Major League'' was in third place with $ 4.1 million. In fourth place was the debut of `` Criminal Law,'' starring <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Oldman </PERSON> as a criminal defense attorney who gets client <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON> off the hook, then has second thoughts. The movie earned $ 2.6 million. `` Dream Team'' from Universal was in fifth place with $ 2.3 million, just ahead of `` Say Anything,'' which also earned $ 2.3 million. Oscar-winning `` Rain Man'' remained in the top 10 at seventh place with $ 1.7 million. `` Loverboy,'' starring <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Dempsey </PERSON> as a college kid who delivers pizza and more made a weak debut in eighth place with $ 1.6 million. `` Field of Dreams'' earned $ 1.5 million for ninth place, and `` She's Out of Control'' was No. 10 with $ 1.3 million. Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, with distributor, weekend gross, number of theater screens, average per screen, total gross and number of weeks in release. 1. `` Pet Sematary,'' Paramount, $ 8.3 million, 1,585 screens, $ 5,287 per screen, $ 24.4 million, two weeks. 2. `` K-9,'' Universal, $ 7.4 million, 1,677 screens, $ 4,455 per screen, $ 7.4 million, one week. 3. `` Major League,'' Paramount, $ 4.1 million, 1,615 screens, $ 2,555 per screen, $ 31.2 million, four weeks. 4. `` Criminal Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> Hemdale </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.6 million, 1,170 screens, $ 2,253 per screen, $ 2.6 million, one week. 5. `` The Dream Team,'' Universal, $ 2.293 million, 1,365 screens, $ 1,680 per screen, $ 19.1 million, four weeks. 6. `` Say Anything,'' 20th Century <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, $ 2.291 million, 1,056 screens, $ 2,170 per screen, $ 12.1 million, three weeks. 7. `` Rain Man,'' <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.7 million, 1,221 screens, $ 1,416 per screen, $ 158 million, 20 weeks. 8. `` Loverboy,'' Tri-Star, $ 1.6 million, 1,089 screens, $ 1,518 per screen, $ 1.6 million, one week. 9. `` Field of Dreams,'' Universal, $ 1.5 million, 110 screens, $ 14,340 per screen, $ 2.3 million, two weeks. 10. `` She's Out Of Control,'' <PERSON> Weintraub </PERSON>, $ 1.3 million, 961 screens, $ 1,367 per screen, $ 8.5 million, three weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0539EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--FirstDog'sShower     05-02 0136</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--First Dog's Shower,0140</SECOND>
<HEAD>If Millie Could Talk ...</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If first dog Millie gossiped, she might be able to tell us whether our nation's leader sings in the shower. First lady <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told reporters that the family dog likes to shower in the bathroom in the presidential suite. `` Millie, of course, does n't take them alone, because she's too short to reach up,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` But someone, a very high public official, elected to office, takes a shower with <PERSON> Millie </PERSON> every week or so. `` They took one yesterday,'' she said Monday. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> to tour The Learning Bank, a center for adults who are learning to read and write. As she left the center, Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` I hope that same public official wo n't be sore at me.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     05-02 0437</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0455</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANNAPOLIS, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fans sipped champagne and led cheers in <LOCATION> Greek </LOCATION> as <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> won its only official intercollegiate athletic event, defeating the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Naval Academy at a day-long croquet tournament. The 6 -LCB- - hour match, played Sunday after rain postponed it for a day, ended with the home team capturing the `` Annapolis Cup. The music of <PERSON> Vivaldi </PERSON> and <PERSON> Beethoven </PERSON> filled the air and some spectators alternated between watching the game and reading <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Orwell </PERSON>'s `` Down and Out in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>.'' The croquet tournament is not so much an athletic event as a chance for neighboring schools that normally have little contact to have a little fun together. While the academy turns out naval officers drilled in tactics and terminology, St. <PERSON> John </PERSON>'s produces a small crop of literary scholars versed in Shakespeare and <PERSON> Socrates </PERSON>. Members of the two teams planned to meet later this week at a restaurant where the tournament trophy is kept. `` I see that as a step forward in the Midshipmen-Johnnie relationship,'' said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> of the St. <PERSON> John </PERSON>'s team.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TAMPA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two lost little kittens may owe their lives to a shop owner who stopped by his store to check on something, and heard tiny meows inside the wall. <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Squitieri </PERSON>, 41, grabbed a sledge hammer Sunday and whacked a couple of holes in the wall at Bay Windows, a window and construction material store. Out came two blue-eyed kittens, one black, the other black and white. <PERSON> Squitieri </PERSON> said the mother cat probably crawled into the attic of his store to give birth, and the kittens apparently fell down inside the wall. Saving the kittens was worth the $ 100 damage to his shop, he said. `` They're cute as a button,'' he said. `` When I pulled them out my heart felt good.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>GREEN BAY, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Green </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Packers </ORGANIZATION> Coach <PERSON> Lindy </PERSON> <PERSON> Infante </PERSON> is better known in that city than Police Chief <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Erickson </PERSON>, according to a telephone name recognition survey by the <ORGANIZATION> Green </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press-Gazette </ORGANIZATION>. While all 35 respondents knew <PERSON> Infante </PERSON>'s occupation, only eight recognized <PERSON> Erickson </PERSON>. Residents were asked by telephone to identify <PERSON> Infante </PERSON>, <PERSON> Erickson </PERSON> and eight other personalities. `` Obviously those were law-abiding citizens,'' said <PERSON> Erickson </PERSON>. `` I'm not concerned as long as the paymaster, my wife and my children were n't among those who said they do n't know me.'' Having a football team with a 4-12 record last season is enough to make any coach recognizable, <PERSON> Infante </PERSON> said. `` They're going to know who you are. They want to know who the fool is who did this to their football team,'' <PERSON> Infante </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-OnTheTown Bjt   05-02 0799</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-On The Town, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mild-Mannered Bureaucrat a Superman on Stage</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 He's a federal bureaucrat by day, an opera singer by night and soon to be making his debut in a Broadway-style musical. `` I understand how <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> feels,'' says <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Ekzarkhov </PERSON>. After he leaves his 8 to 5 job as a mild-mannered government financial analyst, <PERSON> Ekzarkhov </PERSON> ducks into a dressing room and emerges as a theatrical version of Superman, playing dual roles as a <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> dockhand and a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> cop in Arena Stage's recreation of `` On the Town.'' The hit 1944 musical created by the best in show business _ music by <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON>, book and lyrics by <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Comden </PERSON> and <PERSON> Adolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, and choreography by <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Robbins </PERSON> _ is the story of three sailors on 24-hour shore leave in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> during World War II. The Arena Stage production, which opens Thursday and will run through June 4, will be the first major revival of `` On the Town'' since 1971, at <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s City Center, and the first ever presented at a theater in the round. This production was underwritten by <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>. Arena Stage has no orchestra pit, so musical director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Huckaby </PERSON> installed his 18 musicians under the stage and will conduct while peeking up at the actors and dancers through a manhole in the floor. <PERSON> Ekzarkhov </PERSON> shows off his booming bass voice in the opening number, `` I Feel Like I'm Not Out of Bed Yet,'' as a workman at the <ORGANIZATION> Brooklyn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yard </ORGANIZATION>. At 6 feet 3 inches and 235 pounds, he's physically right for the part `` It's a wonderful piece,'' he says. `` The only bone I have to pick with <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> is that he did n't write at least 10 more pages.'' <PERSON> Ekzarkhov </PERSON>, 42, is the son of Russian emigres who fled their homeland after the 1917 revolution and met in <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, where they were married and <PERSON> Ekzarkhov </PERSON> was born. He was 5 when he and his parents moved to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and settled in <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, home of a large Russian and Polish community. `` It was a comfortable place to grow up in,'' said <PERSON> Ekzarkhov </PERSON>. A high school pal was <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Biletnikoff </PERSON>, who later earned fame as a star pass receiver for the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Raiders </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Ekzarkhov </PERSON> learned to sing in the local Russian Orthodox church choir under the direction of his steelworker father. `` They really like their basses to sing very low,'' he said. He met his wife, <PERSON> Dusia </PERSON>, the daughter of Soviet emigres, at a New Year's Eve party in 1969 in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> while he was on shore leave from the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. They still prefer to speak Russian at home after nearly 20 years of marriage. The couple and their two young children spent 2 -LCB- satisfying years in the central <LOCATION> Volga </LOCATION> region of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Ekzarkhov </PERSON> was office manager for an <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> chemical plant, then returned to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and its Russian-speaking community for good. `` It was an incredible experience,'' <PERSON> Ekzarkhov </PERSON> recalls. `` The people there looked exactly like the people I grew up with in Erie. In a way, we came home. Yet as Americans, we could n't help noticing that our point of reference was <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' With a family to support and a mortgage to pay, <PERSON> Ekzarkhov </PERSON> took a job at the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, where he specializes in gas transmission rate cases. `` I'm not knocking my job,'' he says, `` but it's not what I want on my tombstone.'' <PERSON> Ekzarkhov </PERSON> discovered his true passion _ singing _ when he landed a job in the chorus of a local amateur opera production of <PERSON> Verdi </PERSON>'s `` Aida'' 10 years ago Encouraged by friends, voice teachers and auditioners, including Soviet-born conductor <PERSON> Mstislav </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostropovich </PERSON>, he has sung with the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Opera </LOCATION>, the Summer Opera Theater at <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, the Opera Orchestra of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Opera </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canto </LOCATION> and local oratorio societies. `` I'm right up against reality now,'' <PERSON> Ekzarkhov </PERSON> adds. `` I'm at the point where I need an agent. You ca n't do anything in opera without an agent. I guess I never followed through because it would mean living out of a suitcase at very reduced pay.'' He's clearly ready to take the plunge, though, whenever his persistent round of recitals, choral work, stage appearances and auditions finally pays off, either in opera or musical comedy. `` I've spent many lonely hours singing at the piano,'' says <PERSON> Ekzarkhov </PERSON>. `` I keep saying to myself, ` What am I doing here? Who am I kidding?' `` But then there's the ecstasy of being on stage and performing at this level. What's important is that the audience have this look on their faces. If you can get the audience to get a little wet in the eyes, you've gotten them. That's it!''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-MonkeyBusiness     05-02 0198</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Monkey Business,0202</SECOND>
<HEAD>Monkeys Spark Panic During a Break From Confinement</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ten monkeys enjoyed a bit of freedom when a zookeeper at a park near <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> tried to please a group of squealing children by opening the animals' cage. One monkey hitched a ride by jumping on the head of a boy riding a bike then bit a zoo attendant in the hand before being recaptured at the <ORGANIZATION> Rishon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Letzion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zoo </ORGANIZATION>, animal keeper <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeitun </PERSON> said on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio. Two hours passed Sunday before all the creatures were back in the cage, <PERSON> Zeitun </PERSON> said. `` Open it, open it, we want to see the monkeys,'' a group of children yelled at him, <PERSON> Zeitun </PERSON> said. `` So I opened the inner door to the cage. I did n't notice that the outer door was n't locked.'' But the monkeys did, and made a quick dash for freedom. The last monkey captured was the largest. <PERSON> Sandak </PERSON>, Hebrew for `` godfather,'' spent two hours scampering through the park and chasing after children, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio said. A police official in Rishon Letzion confirmed the monkey escape and said the animals were about 20 inches in length, but could not identify the species.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Taxes Bjt   05-02 0734</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Taxes, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Next Year Could be Saying `Don't Read my Lips'</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> vowed `` read my lips: no new taxes'' all through his presidential campaign but never indicated for how long the message would be displayed there. Administration officials now are reluctantly conceding that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> may only stick to the pledge for a year, and that higher taxes may be part of a fiscal 1991 budget agreement. One possibility actively being considered is a swap trading <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> support for some new taxes, most likely on gasoline, for concessions from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in other areas, like a cut in the capital gains tax rate, said the sources, speaking on the condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has long made chopping the capital gains tax rate a key item, claiming it will eventually raise revenue for the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>. But it has found scant support in the Democratic controlled <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, which questions the logic of trying to raise revenue by cutting taxes. Despite <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s rhetoric against new taxes, reiterated as recently as Monday in a speech to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, many economists say higher taxes seem all but inevitable to get the federal deficit _ estimated at $ 163 billion this year _ under control. In fact, to many analysts, it was only a matter of time before the administration conceded that some forms of tax hikes were needed. Administration officials still have n't done this publicly. But privately they admit contingency planning is under way on new taxes _ and on what tradeoffs the administration might be able to wrest from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in exchange for White House support for them. Even the no-new-taxes budget compromise <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> recently reached with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for fiscal year 1990 calls for $ 5.3 billion in unspecified new revenues. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has claimed that slashing the capital gains tax from the present 28 percent to 15 percent will produce the bulk of this, $ 4.8 billion. But since <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> seems unlikely to go along with this tax cut, some way must still be found this year to come up with the $ 5.3 billion. And, a weakening economy could make the projected 1990 deficit even larger than the $ 98.6 billion <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> projected in his budget submission to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> _ meaning even more `` new revenues'' will be needed to meet deficit targets of the Gramm-Rudman law. That budget-balancing act requires a deficit of no more than $ 100 billion in fiscal 1990 _ or automatic across-the-board cuts are triggered. Budget Director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> will issue revised economic assumptions on the economy on July 15. Some administration sources suggested that a gas-tax-for-capital-gains-cut deal might even be considered as early as then, if the new economic numbers prove to be gloomy. But generally, administration officials said the president's clear intention was to honor his campaign vow through this year After that, all bets are off. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Monday showed no indication he was ready to make a deal, however. In his speech to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, he said: `` I mean to live by what I've said: No new taxes.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, `` We do n't have to raise taxes. We have to release the energies of free enterprise.'' He said his `` favorite source of new revenue'' was the capital gains tax cut. White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said Monday, `` We are talking to the tax-writing committees about it -LRB- the capital gains tax cut -RRB-. But we would n't want to speculate on how it might come out at this time.'' The notion of a deal trading support for higher gasoline taxes for a cut in the capital gains tax was first raised the weekend before last in a session between <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and a group of economists at the presidential retreat in Camp David, Md. Although <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was generally noncommittal, he did not object to discussing possible higher taxes, and the proposed swap was endorsed by some of the economists present, according to the sources. The federal gasoline tax is now 9.1 cents per gallon. There have been a variety of congressional proposals for raising the gasoline tax for amounts ranging from a few cents up to 50 cents a gallon. However, a major obstacle to any such rise is the opposition of <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0151EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Obit-Gaal     05-02 0313</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Gaal,0322</SECOND>
<HEAD>Canadian Photographer Found Dead In Thai Resort Hotel</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaal </PERSON>, a Canadian photographer who covered the war in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> as a stringer for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, was found dead at a Thai resort hotel, officials said today. He was 29. <PERSON> Gaal </PERSON>'s body was found about 1 p.m. Sunday at the bottom of the swimming pool at the Ocean View Hotel in the <LOCATION> Pattaya </LOCATION> resort, 70 miles south of <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>, said the hotel's assistant manager, <PERSON> Viroj </PERSON> <PERSON> Phunpiriyat </PERSON>. <PERSON> Viroj </PERSON> said <PERSON> Gaal </PERSON> had gone swimming in the pool alone at about 1 a.m. Sunday after having had some drinks. A large amount of marijuana and other drugs were found in his room, <PERSON> Viroj </PERSON> said. Foul play was not suspected, <PERSON> Viroj </PERSON> said. The body was taken to a police forensic institute in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> where an autopsy was to be peformed, said <PERSON> Nipha </PERSON> <PERSON> Kietniyom </PERSON>, assistant consular officer at the <ORGANIZATION> Canadian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Gaal </PERSON>, from <LOCATION> Kelowna </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, was vacationing in <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gaal </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Fernie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. Starting in 1978, he was a staff photographer for the <ORGANIZATION> Kelowna </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Courier </ORGANIZATION>. From 1983 to 1985 he was chief photographer for the <ORGANIZATION> Lethbridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Alberta </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gaal </PERSON> made his first trip to <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in 1984 and did a photo series on the war. In 1985 and 1986, he worked for the Toronto-based <ORGANIZATION> Fotopress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> covering the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. He returned to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> in 1986 and since made several trips into <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> with the Moslem guerrillas fighting the pro-Soviet government. Since September 1987 he had worked as a news and photo stringer for the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> based in <LOCATION> Peshawar </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. `` He took some of the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s most startling and dramatic photos of the war in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s chief of bureau in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. `` He was a mellow, quiet fellow who seemed to be fearless when in combat situations.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0158EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-EmployeeBenefits     05-02 0477</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Employee Benefits,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Delays Enforcing Health Insurance Test</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is delaying the deadline for employers to begin using complex tests to prove that their health insurance plans do not discriminate against lower-paid workers. The testing requirement, enacted at the request of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration as part of the 1986 tax overhaul, imposes an unreasonable compliance burden on business, <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> said. He chose a meeting of business executives at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> on Monday to announce, `` We have ordered a delay until Oct. 1 in the beginning date for ... testing plans for compliance with -LRB- Internal Revenue Code -RRB- Section 89 regulations.'' The audience, which has made repeal or modification of the law a major goal, applauded loudly. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> said the goal of the legislation _ to ensure that tax-deductible fringe benefits are distributed equitably among workers _ was a good one. `` A system that differentiates between people in the matter of health benefits subsidized by the taxpayers can not be sustained,'' he said. Nevertheless, the cost of compliance is excessive, <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> said. `` The law needs to be changed and we stand ready to encourage, support and work with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to revise and improve it.'' More than half the members of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and a large number of senators are sponsoring bills to repeal the provision or change it significantly. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, whose chairman and most of its members are sponsoring one modification bill, was holding hearings on the subject today. The law requires employers to conduct a lengthy series of complex tests to demonstrate that employee benefits, especially health insurance, are not weighted against workers making less than $ 50,000 a year. Paperwork required by the law is so voluminous that some employers are threatening to withdraw health insurance coverage for all employees. The Section 89 rules went into effect on Jan. 1, but the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> freed employers from any significant compliance requirements until July 1 and agreed that no employer would be penalized if a good-faith effort to follow the rules was made the remainder of 1989. The federal government forgoes more than $ 30 billion a year in taxes on the value of employer-financed health insurance. The employer deducts the cost as a business expense and the employee excludes the value from taxable income. Under the Section 89 law, highly compensated employees may be subject to taxation on the excess coverage if their health plan is more valuable than is offered to rank-and-file workers. Under the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> substitute plan, employers that provide a health plan would have to offer coverage costing workers $ 10 a week or less -LRB- $ 25 or less for a family plan -RRB- to 90 percent of employees. Higher-paid workers would be taxed on the value of coverage that was better than that provided other employees.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0212EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp     05-02 0793</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Women's Rights Groups Hail Supreme Court Workplace Ruling</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Women's rights advocates are hailing a <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling they say will lower a `` Catch 22'' barrier to advancement in the workplace. Women often have had be assertive to win promotion, they say, but at the same time not offend employers by sacrificing femininity. They said Monday's ruling is an important step in limiting the impact of such sexual stereotyping. The court said employers must bear the burden of proving they did not discriminate illegally once there is evidence bias played a part in personnel decisions. <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> said the ruling is an important victory for women's rights. `` In these situations there is substantial doubt who is going to win,'' she said. `` Now that we're going to see a shift in the focus, it's sufficient for a plaintiff to win.'' Ms. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> said the decision will help overcome a dual standard she labeled a Catch 22 that has held women back. `` It's been that you had to have the attributes of an assertive manager but also all the attributes of a passive, feminine non-assertive woman,'' she said. By a 6-3 vote, the justices ordered further lower court hearings in a suit against the accounting firm <ORGANIZATION> Price </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Waterhouse </ORGANIZATION> by a former employee, <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> said she was denied partnership because of `` macho'' attitudes that, in effect, demanded she behave more like a lady. The firm said other factors _ such as her failure to get along with others _ were decisive. Monday's decision may leave some questions unanswered because only four justices agreed on the standards that should govern such `` mixed-motive'' discrimination cases. There were three separate opinions by the six justices in the majority. `` This may not clarify things because of the split decision,'' said <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> McDowell </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Equal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> that sided with Price Waterhouse. But <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> of the Women's Legal Defense Fund said, `` Although this is not a complete victory, we consider it to be in the win category. We are gratified that the court said that once a woman proves gender was a factor, the burden shifts to the employer.'' Price Waterhouse, in a statement, said it expects to win against Ms. <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> when the suit returns to federal trial court. `` We are confident that after the lower court reconsiders the case, it will conclude ... Ms. <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> was denied partnership for legitimate reasons,'' the company said. Ms. <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> is seeking back pay and possibly reinstatement to the firm with promotion to partnership. The high court rejected a federal appeals court's requirement that Price Waterhouse show clear and convincing evidence its actions were unbiased. It is enough that the company show by a preponderance of the evidence it did not practice illegal discrimination, the court said. The clear and convincing standard usually means that to successfully defend against a lawsuit, an employer must show overwhelming evidence in its favor. By contrast, a preponderance standard means an employer wins by showing more evidence than not is on its side. The ruling is based on an interpretation of Title VII of the 1964 Civil Rights Act, banning discrimination based on race, religion and national origin as well as gender. Ms. <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON>, formerly a senior manager for Price Waterhouse here, quit the firm after she was denied partnership and later became a consultant to the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>. While she was under consideration for the promotion at the accounting firm, critics and supporters said she sometimes was overly aggressive, too harsh, impatient with her staff and very demanding. She said one partner who supported her for promotion told her she would stand a better chance of advancement if she would `` walk more femininely, talk more femininely, dress more femininely, wear make-up, have her hair styled and wear jewelry.'' In other action, the court: _ Agreed to consider blocking the partial merger of <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>'s two daily newspapers The court will hear a challenge to former Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s decision allowing a joint operating agreement of the newspapers. _ Ruled unanimously that additional environmental-impact studies are not required before building a ski resort in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state and completing a dam in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> _ Agreed to use a case involving the <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> to restudy what limits should be placed on campaign spending by political groups that incorporate _ Agreed to hear, in an <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> case, a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration appeal aimed at allowing the government to collect potentially hundreds of millions of dollars in taxes from multinational corporations _ Ruled, 5-4 in a case from <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, that lawyers may not be forced by federal law to represent poor people in non-criminal federal cases
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890502-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-89 0213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-RoweBurial     05-02 0535</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rowe Burial,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Army Hero, Killed in Manila, Buried at Arlington</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
