<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SlayingsDeportation     08-25 0345</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Slayings Deportation,0355</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Wanted in Mexican Slayings Won't Contest Deportation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TUCSON, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The man accused in the drug-related torture slayings of 12 people at his ranch near <LOCATION> Agua </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prieta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, will accept deportation to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, his attorney said Thursday. <PERSON> Hector </PERSON> <PERSON> Fragoso </PERSON> <PERSON> Burqueno </PERSON>, accused of murder and other charges in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, agreed to the deportation Thursday provided his <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizenship application remains valid, attorney <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Donau </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> said following a hearing before Immigration Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarrick </PERSON>. <PERSON> Donau </PERSON> said the effect of Thursday's deal `` was to preserve -LRB- <PERSON> Fragoso </PERSON>'s -RRB- right to pursue his citizenship application and at the same time set a date when he would be voluntarily returning to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>.'' The <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> lawyer said <PERSON> Fragoso </PERSON> would n't return to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> at least until Oct. 1 because he needs additional time to complete the application process. However, <PERSON> Donau </PERSON> also said he does n't expect the application to be succesful until the charges in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> are resolved. <PERSON> Fragoso </PERSON> is entitled to citizenship, <PERSON> Donau </PERSON> said, because he is a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> veteran. <PERSON> Fragoso </PERSON> had sought political asylum but that request was withdrawn after <PERSON> McCarrick </PERSON> refused to bar reporters from the courtroom. <PERSON> Donau </PERSON> said his witnesses consequently `` refused to testify if their testimony would be made known to the public at large.'' <PERSON> Fragoso </PERSON>, who remained in custody, is working to acquire Mexican legal counsel before facing <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s charges of first-degree murder, concealment of accomplices, criminal association and violation of burial laws, <PERSON> Donau </PERSON> said. Mexican officials have said statements by <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Tapia </PERSON>, 29, who is believed to be involved in the slayings, placed <PERSON> Fragoso </PERSON> at the ranch where the bodies of the torture victims were found, four in a septic tank pit and eight others stuffed into a well. <LOCATION> Aqua </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prieta </LOCATION> is just across the border from <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>. Authorities believe they were killed on March 24 and 25. <PERSON> Fragoso </PERSON> was arrested April 20 in a mobile home near Three Points, a tiny community about 25 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Tapia </PERSON> was turned over to <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> authorities Aug. 10 after he was detained and questioned by authorities in <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0309EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BedMakers     08-25 0530</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bed Makers,0549</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hotel Bed Makers Vie for Prizes, No Folds Barred</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KILEY ARMSTRONG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 They made their beds, again and again. But there was no time to lie in them during a contest for 50 housekeepers from the city's top hotels that was _ dare we say? _ sheer bedlam. `` People have been killed by flying percale,'' cautioned comedian <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Mauro </PERSON>, the master of ceremonies, before the `` Fastest Hands in the East'' contest for the coveted Brass Bed award got under way on Thursday. Twenty-five beds were lined up in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hilton </LOCATION> ballroom. The sheets, blankets and pillows were piled on tables three feet away. Unconfirmed reports surfaced about training that involved aerobics, high-carbohydrate diets and good-luck charms. Energy levels were raised a notch by an announcement that spending money _ $ 500, $ 300 and $ 200, respectively _ had been added to the top three prizes: a trip to the <LOCATION> Fontainebleau </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hilton </LOCATION> hotel in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, a weekend at the Arrowwood resort in <LOCATION> Rye </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brook </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, and a pair of his-and-hers watches. It was clear that <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahenkora </PERSON> of the Drake Hotel was a force to be reckoned with. She bounced in her chair, smiled confidently and cheered at just about everything. The housekeepers _ all women _ lined up at the head of their beds, hands poised above the linens. Judges with stopwatches stood at the foot of the beds; silence blanketed the room. Nervous contestants had a couple of false starts before <PERSON> Mauro </PERSON> blew the starting whistle. Then the sound of snapping sheets filled the ballroom as the contestants sprinted around the beds, deftly smoothing and stuffing. Ahenkora doubled her pillow with a karate chop, swiftly dispatching it into its case. The crowd _ filled with rooting sections of friends and coworkers _ went wild. `` Tuck! Tuck!'' screamed one spectator, reminding a panting contestant to make the required hospital corners. `` Come on, <PERSON> Hazel </PERSON>!'' `` Oh, that's messy!'' The contestants were divided into two groups for the preliminaries. Ten semifinalists went onto the three final heats. To signal the judge that they were finished, they perched or crumpled on the end of their beds. After everyone took a breather, <PERSON> Mauro </PERSON> announced the winners and handed out the trophies _ miniature replicas of brass beds. <PERSON> Hazel </PERSON> <PERSON> Maye </PERSON> of the <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> <PERSON> Windsor </PERSON> <PERSON> Hotel </PERSON> took the top prize, clocking her last three beds in a total time of 3 minutes, 37 seconds. Her friends joyfully tackled her to mark her Super Bowl of Beds victory. In a post-contest interview she revealed her winning strategy: `` Before I came here I made 10 beds in less than an hour.'' <PERSON> Dora </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> of the Empire Hotel was a close second, with a time of 3 minutes, 40 seconds. She also made the neatest-looking bed. `` I'm tired now,'' she told well-wishers. <PERSON> Ahenkora </PERSON> was clearly disappointed with her third-place finish at 3 minutes, 45 seconds. `` I did n't practice,'' she lamented. `` The bed is too soft; you make one side and it pops out on the other side.'' She can try again next year, though; sponsors promised to make it an annual event.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-MysteryCity     08-25 0579</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mystery City,0601</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mystery Surrounds Nan Mahdol, Pacific's Great Ruined City</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER O'LOUGHLIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NAN MAHDOL, Micronesia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Islanders say there is a curse on this mysterious 700 year-old ruined city they know as the Reef of Heaven. The curse is so strong, they say, that no one will stay overnight. `` No way. The last person who stayed there was a <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> governor about 100 years ago,'' said <PERSON> Bermin </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wellbacher </PERSON>, director of tourism and natural resources for <LOCATION> Pohnpei </LOCATION>, site of the city and one of the three island states that make up the Federated States of <LOCATION> Micronesia </LOCATION>. `` He was found mysteriously dead the next morning. You would n't catch me there, no way.'' But <PERSON> Wellbacher </PERSON> is more than happy for tourists to come in daytime to see a stone megalith that is one of the wonders of the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>. It is the prime tourist attraction of this impoverished, remote island 2,485 miles west of <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION>. Few people know about <PERSON> Nan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahdol </PERSON>. No one has fully explained how it was built or who built it. Most Pacific islands never had a Stone age, but at <LOCATION> Nan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mahdol </LOCATION> the walls are made of stone blocks that weight up to 50 tons. Archaeologists believe the stones came from another island and brought to the site on rafts. But how laborers were able to lift them remains a mystery. It takes an hour by fast boat across a lagoon to reach the city. At low tide visitors must wade through a sea grass swamp and climb slippery rocks to the dark gray, moss-covered walls of the ruin. <PERSON> Nan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahdol </PERSON> is a canal city built on 92 artificial islands 15 miles from <LOCATION> Kolonia </LOCATION>, the capital of <LOCATION> Pohnpei </LOCATION>. Built near the passage through the coral reef into the lagoon, it covers 160 acres. Huge walls of basalt rock up to 20 feet high enclose a deserted city with burial chambers, vaults made of giant stone slabs and pathways of crushed coral. Scientists believe an advanced civilization built a seawall, a priestly burial place, and adminstrative center, servants quarters, a ceremonial center, a coconut-oil processing area and a communications center where messages were sent by beating log drums. Carbon dating of the ruins indicates the city was built between the years 1285 and 1485. Recent underwater archaeology suggests it might be even older. Legend also says <PERSON> Nan </PERSON> <PERSON> Madol </PERSON> was created by magicians who then flew off into space. Nowadays, people of <LOCATION> Pohnpei </LOCATION> are divided over who owns the city. The local paramount chief, <PERSON> Salvadore </PERSON> <PERSON> Hadley </PERSON>, claims it is his. The government also claims it. At stake is who gets the revenues from tourism. `` I do n't ever want to see the day that a paramount chief and the government are fighting one another in court,'' said <PERSON> Wellbacher </PERSON> the tourism official. `` It goes against all our traditions. But it is our greatest tourist asset.'' Last year almost 8,000 tourists visited <LOCATION> Pohnpei </LOCATION>, a lush volcanic island which in turn was ruled by <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. It is now the capital of <LOCATION> Micronesia </LOCATION>, made up of the islands of <LOCATION> Pohnpei </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Truk </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kosrae </LOCATION>, all formerly part of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-administered </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Territory </ORGANIZATION> of the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Wellbacher </PERSON> wants to build a road to the shoreline near <LOCATION> Nan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mahdol </LOCATION> to make the trip easier for tourists. He'd like to add a restaurant and souvenir shop. But no hotel. `` No one will stay overnight,'' <PERSON> Wellbacher </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0151EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-LostChildren     08-25 0988</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lost Children,1021</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ethiopia's `Lost Children' Introduce a Sister</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 For 20 years, stories have been told in <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> about two white children kidnapped or abandoned when they were very young. A brother and sister have stepped forward, claiming to be those children. <ORGANIZATION> Nairobi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Reid </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> wrote about the two earlier this month and here is a follow-up report.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By REID G. MILLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ADDIS ABABA, Ethiopia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A young man and woman who may be the legendary `` lost white children'' of <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> say they have a sister, and they introduced her during a visit to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy. All three arrived at the embassy last week for an interview with consul <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> in an effort to find their parents. They say they were taken from a white family about 20 years ago by the <LOCATION> Ethiopian </LOCATION> housekeeper, whose sister and brother-in-law raised them as members of the Oromo tribe. The story of two lost white children is told in many variations, usually involving a kidnapping. A representative of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> has come to <LOCATION> Addis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ababa </LOCATION> in hopes of taking all three to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` We are prepared to arrange transportation, care and education for them in the States,'' said <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Laytner </PERSON>, an author and free-lance journalist from <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Laytner </PERSON> and <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> say that may be difficult because <PERSON> Haile </PERSON> <PERSON> Mariam </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadessa </PERSON> and his sisters <PERSON> Tegest </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lesa </PERSON> are, at least for now, considered to be Ethiopian nationals `` Anything we do will be legal,'' said <PERSON> Laytner </PERSON>, who carried a letter from former <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Angier </PERSON> <PERSON> Biddle </PERSON> <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>, a committee director, identifying him as its representative. The <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> is a non-partisan agency to assist, resettle, rehabilitate refugees. It is supported by foundations, corporations, unions, community groups and individual contributors. <PERSON> Haile </PERSON> <PERSON> Mariam </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tegest </PERSON> came to the attention of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials when an <LOCATION> Ethiopian </LOCATION> friend took them to the embassy in June. In their interview with consul <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, who retired earlier this month, they did not mention their sister, <PERSON> Lesa </PERSON> _ fearing for her safety, they say now. Meeting with the new consul last week, the three told essentially the same story <PERSON> Haile </PERSON> <PERSON> Mariam </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tegest </PERSON> related to Mrs. <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> through an interpreter two months ago. It was <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' first meeting with the young people, thought to be in their early 20s. An <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reporter was allowed to attend the two-hour interview. They say they have no clear recollection of their real parents, but spoke for the first time of seeing a photo album in the grass-thatched mud hut that became their home. Pictures in the album showed them as small children with their white parents, they said. <PERSON> Haile </PERSON> <PERSON> Mariam </PERSON> said fire destroyed the hut and photos years ago. They say they do n't know for sure why they were taken to live with the tribal couple. They believe their father became ill and had to be evacauated, and that their mother went with him. Mrs. <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> and others think the story of the lost white children may have been kept alive by occasional sightings of <LOCATION> Haile </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mariam </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Lesa </PERSON>. They were kept by the Oromo couple and <PERSON> Tegest </PERSON> was sent to another family as a maid. The embassy has found no record of the youngsters or their parents, but <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said a few vague clues arose after their story came to light. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> and an Ethiopian lawyer hired by the embassy are trying to run down the clues. He said one was a tip in a letter mailed from <LOCATION> Addis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ababa </LOCATION> that the father had been a brewery chemist in <LOCATION> Addis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ababa </LOCATION>. As a result of the article, people sent cash, checks and offers of help to the embassy. `` Initially we discouraged people from sending money because, unless these people are <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens, we would have no authority to set up a trust account for them,'' <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said. Later, he said, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> suggested establishing an account through someone not connected with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government. `` We would like to try to set up an account through a benign person here, a missionary or somebody,'' he said. `` There is significant interest in this, serious interest,'' at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The Oromo woman who raised the three recalls her brother bringing them to her and denied they were kidnapped, but was vague about brother's motives. She said he died soon afterward. `` They were beautiful children, very white,'' she told reporters through an interpreter at her farm 50 miles from <LOCATION> Addis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ababa </LOCATION>. She is in her 70s and divorced. Although they carry her last name, the youngsters bear no resemblance to the black woman who raised them. Their hair is light brown to blond, their complexions a ruddy bronze. They tell of a lifetime of physical abuse by their foster father and other villagers because of their strange appearance. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> ended the interview when they became agitated. The interpreter said they were tired of retelling their story to consular officers and reporters without result, and frightened by the increased hostility of fellow villagers caused by their notoriety. The <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> overseas service broadcast their story in <LOCATION> Amharic </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>'s official language, and many Ethiopians heard it. Because of what the interpreter said, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> took up an office collection to rent a small apartment in the capital for a month. He had the young people resettled and urged them to return to the embassy for more conversations. `` If only we can jog their memories enough, we may be able to find further clues to their identities and their parents,'' he said. Just before the meeting with <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> ended, <PERSON> Haile </PERSON> <PERSON> Mariam </PERSON> said: `` Our thought is that if our parents are dead, why have n't our grandparents, aunts or uncles come looking for us? This is what we always think. This is what we do n't understand.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0155EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Baltic-Notebook     08-25 0728</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Baltic-Notebook,0753</SECOND>
<HEAD>Politics, Lithuanian Style: Carbon Paper and Remembering the Grand
Duke</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 This week's astonishing protest that joined an estimated 1 million people in a human chain across the Baltic republics was the latest tactic used by local activists to advance their demands. Here are some other snapshots from grassroots political life in one Soviet Baltic republic.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By ANDREW KATELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VILNIUS, U.S.S.R. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democracy Central here is an ornate four-story building where the fledgling grass-roots political movement <ORGANIZATION> Sajudis </ORGANIZATION> uses high - and low-tech to get its message across in the drive for <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>'s independence On the third floor, college students duplicate political statements the old fashioned way _ by typing with carbon paper. The copying machine is broken. One floor up, the <ORGANIZATION> Sajudis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> uses a new fascimile machine to receive a letter from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> signed by members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> supporting freedom for the Baltic republics. The offices of <LOCATION> Sajudis </LOCATION>, just over a year old, have all the trappings of an upstart citizens group struggling with meager resources to change the world. There are n't enough phones, chairs or desks, and the staircase is crumbling, but there is no shortage of dedication. Dozens of helpers stream through the offices. Hundreds of people stop daily at the newsstand on the ground floor to pick up a copy of the Sajudis newspaper. The very existence of the office is an important political accomplishment in a country where the government tightly controls allotment of buildings, phones and copying machines. The windows look out on <LOCATION> Vilnius </LOCATION>' Cathedral Square, where protest posters demanding `` Occupiers Go Home'' _ a reference to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> soldiers who have been stationed in the republic since 1940 _ and `` Freedom for <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>'' are displayed around a bell tower.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Although the drive for independence is gradually gaining official, ambiguously worded support from the <ORGANIZATION> Lithuanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, sometimes activists have to settle for symbolism. Dozens of streets have been de-Sovietized, or given back the names they had before the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> tanks rolled in in 1940 and made <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION> a part of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The street where Sajudis headquarters is located, <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON> <PERSON> Prospect </PERSON>, was recently renamed for <PERSON> Gediminas </PERSON>, the Grand Duke of <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>, who made <LOCATION> Vilnius </LOCATION> the capital in 1322. A poster on the wall of Sajudis headquarters spells out the word perestroika, President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reform drive, in fading letters. A calendar depicts the currency used when <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION> was independent from 1918-1940. Independence activists hope the republic will soon be able to have its own currency again. Graffiti artists are getting into the act. `` Red Army Go Home'' was painted in red in English on a sidewalk near a hotel frequented by foreigners.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 They are portrayed as bride and groom or as soldiers with blood dripping from their mouths, and are constant targets of both verbal and physical abuse. Mere mention of <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> and <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> once struck hatred, loathing or fear into the hearts of millions, but in the <ORGANIZATION> Baltics </ORGANIZATION>, the two dictators are now openly ridiculed. Attacking <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> is certainly not new in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> is now officially vilified for `` repressing'' millions of people and setting up the tight, centrally commanded economy that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is trying to streamline. But the open accusation that <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> was in cahoots with <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> is relatively new. `` For the first time we pondered and publicly announced that <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> were branches of the same tree, and their policy was equally disastrous for our small <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Vilnius </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Vecherniye </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Novosti </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Evening News -RRB- said Wednesday. The most dramatic attack on the men who engineered the carving up of <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Latvia </LOCATION> in a secret 1939 agreement was their burning in effigy Wednesday. Members of the Lithuanian <ORGANIZATION> Liberty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> _ a radical group that demands <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION> secede from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> _ carried a <LOCATION> Hitler-Stalin </LOCATION>, two-headed soldier through downtown <LOCATION> Vilnius </LOCATION> on the anniversary of the secret deal. The effigy was carried to an independence rally in a park, where a speaker said the two dictators `` drank from one glass the blood of <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>.'' To wind up the demonstration, the effigy was burned. Orange flames quickly engulfed it, sending black smoke and ashes aloft. The dictators' heads and their blood-smeared mouths were the last to go up in smoke.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0311EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     08-25 0039</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0044</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Thursday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 0166.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 11; 12; 24; 38; 40; 41. Bonus: 48105.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 0225.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0014EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TheWho     08-25 0437</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-The Who,0451</SECOND>
<HEAD>Legendary Rock Group Stages Rock Opera `Tommy' One More Time</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN ANTCZAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNIVERSAL CITY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Who blasted off nearly a decade of rust with a thundering performance of their rock opera `` <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON>'' on Thursday night, bringing a graying crowd of baby boomer fans to their feet. Led by a 44-year-old <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Daltrey </PERSON>, the Who put on a stirring rendition of their old act, minus the guitar-smashing antics of 20 years ago. `` Everyone here is obviously full of love and good feelings,'' said former LSD advocate <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Leary </PERSON>, who once coined the phrase `` Turn on, tune in, drop out.'' <PERSON> Leary </PERSON> joked about his status as a hallucinogenic guru of the 1960s. `` Well, to tell the truth, I've just taken some mushroom,'' <PERSON> Leary </PERSON> quipped as the Who stepped onto stage. The sold-out Universal Amphitheater show was the second of only two complete performances of `` Tommy'' scheduled on the 25-city reunion tour of the Who's <PERSON> Daltrey </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Townshend </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Entwistle </PERSON>. A well-dressed crowd of people in the 30s and 40s walked into the amphitheater reading warning signs that announced sound levels could cause hearing impairment. Only the faintest odor of a rare whiff of marijuana smoke could be detected. The saga of `` the deaf, dumb and blind kid'' who becomes a fantastic pinball player also featured <PERSON> Elton </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON>, reprising his 1975 movie role as the Pinball Wizard, <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Winwood </PERSON> as the Hawker, <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> as Uncle <PERSON> Ernie </PERSON>, <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Idol </PERSON> as <PERSON> Cousin </PERSON> <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Patti </PERSON> <PERSON> Labelle </PERSON> as Gypsy, the Acid Queen. The show, benefiting the <ORGANIZATION> Nordoff-Robbins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Music </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Therapy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, was available live on a pay-per-view basis for $ 19.95 per subscriber on <ORGANIZATION> King </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Biscuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>, a division of <ORGANIZATION> DIR </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION>. The tour's first performance of `` Tommy'' was in June at Radio City Music Hall in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and featured the band and supporting musicians. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Meyrowitz </PERSON>, president of DIR, said the show had a potential audience of 12.5 million households. The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> performance was `` really mind-boggling,'' but the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> staging made the opera `` a much more musical piece,'' <PERSON> Meyrowitz </PERSON> said. The Who came together in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> in 1964 and were a premiere rock band through the 1970s. Drummer <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Moon </PERSON> died in 1978 and the remaining members of the band retired in 1982 after a concert in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>. Who albums between 1965 and 1982 included `` My Generation,'' `` Happy <PERSON> Jack </PERSON>,'' `` The Who Sell Out,'' `` On Tour: Magic Bus,'' `` <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON>,'' `` Live at <LOCATION> Leeds </LOCATION>,'' `` Who's Next,'' `` Meaty, <PERSON> Beaty </PERSON>, Big and Bouncy,'' `` Quadrophenia,'' `` Odds and Sods,'' `` The Who by Numbers,'' `` Who Are You,'' `` The Kids Are Alright,'' `` Face Dances,'' and `` It's Hard.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0311EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Poland-Chronology     08-25 0332</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Chronology,0350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Key Events in Poland's Post-War History</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Poland, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Major events in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s post-war history: Sept. 1, 1939 _ <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> invades <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> attacks from the east 16 days later. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> spends rest of war under German and Soviet occupation. April 1943 _ <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> breaks relations with exiled Polish government in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. July 22, 1944 _ Soviets install `` Polish <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION>.'' Six months later they recognize this committee as Polish government. June 28, 1945 _ Following <LOCATION> Yalta </LOCATION> conference, Soviet-dominated Polish Provisional Government of National Unity formed. Sept. 1980 _ Discontent underlying strikes intensified by revelations of government and <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> corruption and mismanagement. Party leader <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Gierek </PERSON> ousted. Dec. 13, 1981 _ Workers threaten general strike and Gen. <PERSON> Wojciech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> declares martial law, interning thousands of Solidarity members, including <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>. Oct. 8, 1982 _ Solidarity is banned and official trade union alliance is created to take its place. Nov. 11, 1982 _ <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> is freed. July 22, 1983 _ <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> lifts martial law but leaves many restrictive edicts in place. 1984-1987 _ Amnesty is approved for political prisoners and eventually all are freed. Aug.-Sept. 1988 _ Strikes spread across <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, creating worst labor strife in seven years Strikes end when <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> asks for time to talk with the government. Feb. 6, 1989 _ Negotiations begin with government. April 5, 1989 _ Deliberations conclude with endorsement of new `` social contract,'' including overhaul of legislative system and partly democratic elections. Solidarity is granted legal status. June 4, 1989 _ Solidarity is overwhelming winner over <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in legislative elections. Aug. 16, 1989 _ Peasant and <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> parties, former <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> allies, endorse <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>'s plan for a governing coalition led by Solidarity. Aug. 18, 1989 _ <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> approves Solidarity-led coalition. Aug. 19, 1989 _ <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> nominates journalist and Solidarity activist <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> to be prime minister. Thursday _ The Sejm, the lower house of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, overwhelmingly approves <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> as prime minister.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Video-Lawsuit     08-25 0383</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Video-Lawsuit,0392</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Issues Restraining Order on Video Law</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SALLY STREFF BUZBEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KANSAS CITY, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A state law that would have barred the sale or rental of violent videotapes to children was blocked Thursday by a federal judge who said the measure might clash with the right of free speech. Under the law signed June 20 by Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ashcroft </PERSON>, video retailers could be fined as much as $ 200 for renting or selling so-called `` slasher films,'' to children under age 17. The law was to take effect Monday. `` The gray areas are the important ones in this case, are n't they? said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brook </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON>. `` Because that's where a prosecutor and store owner could have a difference of opinion that could get the store owner in trouble. The measure, which would also apply to videos considered pornographic under <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> law, would require stores to maintain separate display areas for violent films. Video industry groups and retailers challenged the law with a class action lawsuit and sought the temporary restraining order, arguing that the law would force video store owners to decide by Monday which videos fell under the law. The lawsuit names Attorney General <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Cole </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> prosecutor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Callahan </PERSON> contends the law violates constitutional rights of free expression, equal protection and due process of law. The <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> law restricts videos that, based on contemporary community standards, would be interpreted by the average person to have `` a tendency to cater or appeal to morbid interest in violence'' for persons under 17, that depict violence that is `` patently offensive'' and lack `` serious literary, artistic, political or scientific value.'' The lawsuit said the law would require video retailers to limit sale and rental of videos that are not obscene and not constitutionally subject to restriction under state or federal law. The lawsuit said terms such as `` violence'' and `` morbid'' have no certain meaning. It also criticized the law for applying arbitrarily to videos only, and not to identical expression in television, movie theaters and magazines. The lawsuit was filed by the <ORGANIZATION> Video </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Software </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dealers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retailers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grocers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> and two retailers, <ORGANIZATION> Video </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON>'s C.C. <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Diabetes-Hormone     08-25 0426</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Diabetes-Hormone,0441</SECOND>
<HEAD>Researchers Suspect Hormone Link To Adult Diabetes</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 esbjd
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A hormone that may play a key role in developing the most common form of diabetes has been discovered by <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> and Swedish researchers. The hormone, islet amyloid polypeptide, or IAPP, appears to impair the ability of insulin to regulate the level of sugar in the blood, causing the development of Type 2 or adult-onset diabetes, the researchers said in Thursday's New England Journal of Medicine. IAPP and insulin are secreted by the islet cells in the tail of the pancreas, the researchers said. With the discovery, the researchers hope to find better ways to treat Type 2 diabetes, which affects an estimated 10 million Americans and often leads to blindness, nerve and kidney damage, and amputations as the result of gangrene of the feet. The researchers are Drs. <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON>, who are <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> veterinary pathologists, and Drs. Per <PERSON> Westermark </PERSON> and <PERSON> Christer </PERSON> <PERSON> Betsholtz </PERSON>, Swedish diabetes researchers. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Westermark </PERSON> first mentioned their discovery of the hormone in the 1987 Proceedings of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION>, subject to official confirmation by other laboratories. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said Wednesday that other researchers quickly replicated the findings. The hormone was isolated from amyloid, a protein often found around degenerating human and animal tissue, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. The researchers found amyloid in microscopic quantities surrounding the insulin-secreting islet cells of pancreases of diabetic humans and cats. He said the amyloid tissue around the pancreases of diabetics was reported in the early 1900s, but that researchers were puzzled about its role for more than 80 years because amyloid also was found around the pancreases of people who were not diabetic. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> began looking at the amyloid of diabetic cats 20 years ago, and 12 years ago he and <PERSON> Westermark </PERSON>, who worked with human cadaver pancreases, began collaborating. They found there were differences between the amyloid of diabetics and the amyloid of non-diabetics. Three years ago, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Westermark </PERSON> were able to purify IAPP from the amyloid surrounding insulin-secreting cells. IAPP, like insulin, is produced by normal pancreatic cells, but <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> said the researchers have evidence that an excessive amount is produced in adult-onset diabetics. It is likely that IAPP is just one of many hormones secreted by the islet cells of the pancreas involved in balancing the level of blood sugar, he said. `` We've found IAPP in virtually every species we have looked at _ humans, dogs, cats, guinea pigs,'' <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> said. `` Presumably it has an important role in healthy, normal people.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0145EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-25 0906</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0941</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Roseanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Barr </PERSON> faces a lawsuit that claims she paid `` thugs'' $ 50 to beat a celebrity photographer as he took pictures of her. <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Dominguez </PERSON> claims in a <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> suit filed Monday that he was photographing the star of the hit TV series `` Roseanne'' in her car outside the trendy restaurant <ORGANIZATION> Spago </ORGANIZATION> on July 14 when the beating took place. The suit, which seeks unspecified damages, said several men approached the car Ms. <PERSON> Barr </PERSON> was in and spoke with her. She allegedly paid them $ 50, after which they began to beat the photographer, according to the suit. Ms. <PERSON> Barr </PERSON>, who plays an earthy, sarcastic housewife in `` Roseanne,'' had no comment on the lawsuit, said her publicist <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasteler </PERSON>. No criminal charges were filed but <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> sheriff's deputies were investigating
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ST. PAUL, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The boy with a beanie painted on the wall outside <PERSON> Spanky </PERSON>'s Saloon is `` just some fat-faced kid,'' its owner says. But <PERSON> George </PERSON> `` Spanky'' <PERSON> McFarland </PERSON> thinks it's him. The lawyer for the star of `` Our Gang'' and `` Little Rascals'' movies from 50 years ago sued in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday, insisting the boy is <PERSON> McFarland </PERSON>, a 60-year-old businessman in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The lawsuit accuses bar owner <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Engelhardt </PERSON> of misappropriating <PERSON> McFarland </PERSON>'s name, identity and likeness without permission or compensation. <PERSON> McFarland </PERSON> is seeking damages of more than $ 50,000 and a court order prohibiting <PERSON> Engelhardt </PERSON> from using <PERSON> McFarland </PERSON>'s name and image. <PERSON> McFarland </PERSON> makes personal appearances as the grown-up <PERSON> Spanky </PERSON>. <PERSON> Engelhardt </PERSON> said that besides the boy painted outside his rock music saloon, two other representations of the bar's namesake are inside: a Spanky on a wooden plaque and a neon light depicting <PERSON> Spanky </PERSON> with orange hair. All three look different and none represents <PERSON> Spanky </PERSON> <PERSON> McFarland </PERSON>, he said. `` I must have missed the -LRB- movie -RRB- where he had orange hair,'' <PERSON> Engelhardt </PERSON> said. `` If every kid with a beanie on his head is him, this country is in trouble. If there were actual pictures of him here, I could understand, but not when it's just some fat-faced kid.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Rolling Stones will rehearse on a 110-foot-high stage early next week at <LOCATION> John </LOCATION> <LOCATION> F. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION>, where they planned a concert before city officials closed the 63-year-old stadium to the public. If the rehearsal stage being built is satisfactory, another just like it will be built in <LOCATION> Veterans </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION>, where the tour's opening concerts will be held next week. A stage ca n't be built inside Veterans Stadium until after the <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eagles </ORGANIZATION> play the <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steelers </ORGANIZATION> in an <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> exhibition game Saturday. After that stage is completed, the rehearsal set is to be transported to <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>, where the Stones have a Sept. 3 concert date. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>, the city's deputy recreation commissioner and manager of the stadium, said that even though the city decided fire code and other safety problems prevented a concert attended by 100,000 fans at <LOCATION> JFK </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION>, a rehearsal on the field would be safe.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A graying and glib <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> formally announced an international concert tour that he hopes will attract both misty-eyed Beatlemaniacs and a new generation of fans. `` There was a time when you thought music equals youth. I do n't think that applies anymore,'' said <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON>, 47, joining other middle-aged rockers on tour this year _ the Who, the <ORGANIZATION> Rolling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stones </ORGANIZATION> and former Beatles drummer <PERSON> Ringo </PERSON> <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> Asked on Thursday if he was touring to avoid being `` left out,'' he replied, `` I suppose there's an element of that ... but it's not my prime reason for going out.'' Instead, he credited the continual touring of the Grateful Dead and its leader, <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, with inspiring his first tour since 1976. `` If <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> can still do it that good, there's hope for us all,'' <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> said. <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> also said several nieces and nephews have asked him: `` Please play, because we were n't there the first time around.'' The tour opens with three shows at the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Forum Nov. 27-28-29.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Forrest </PERSON> <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>, the former co-host of `` The CBS Morning News,'' has been named anchorman for <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` World News Sunday,'' replacing <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Donaldson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>, who joined <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> in July 1988, has been the co-anchorman of the newscasts on `` World News This Morning'' and `` Good Morning America.'' He was the co-host of `` The CBS Morning News'' from 1985 to 1987. <PERSON> Donaldson </PERSON> left `` World News Sunday'' to work on his new program `` PrimeTime Live,'' which also features <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ALBUQUERQUE, N.M. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Charley </PERSON> <PERSON> Pride </PERSON>'s golf game may not be as smooth as his singing, but the veteran country and western star still is succeeding on and off the course. As a co-sponsor of the Sunwest Bank-Charley Pride Senior Tour Tournament, Pride has helped raise more than $ 447,000 during the past three tournaments to help four <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION> hospitals. Pride, a former baseball player in the <ORGANIZATION> Negro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> before making it big in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, performs annually at a pair of shows and also plays in the pro-am competition that accompanies the regular tournament. `` I need to play more and get more consistent, but that's what everybody says, is n't it?'' said Pride, who has a 10 handicap. Pride, who describes his age as `` plenty nine,'' has been playing golf 25 years. His singing career also continues to thrive, with his latest single, `` <PERSON> Amy </PERSON>'s Eyes,'' scheduled for release soon.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0204EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Poland-Text     08-25 0901</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Poland-Text,0930</SECOND>
<HEAD>Text of Sejm Address by New Prime Minister</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Poland, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Text of the parliament address Thursday of <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> shortly before his election as the first non-Communist prime minister in the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc. The speech was taped from state television and translated by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Mr. <PERSON> Speaker </PERSON>, High Chamber. I want to form a government capable of acting for the good of society, the nation and the state. Today such a task can be undertaken only by a government open for cooperation of all forces represented in parliament and based on new political principles. The history of our country is accelerating. It has happened due to a society which does not agree to continuing life as it has been until now. One has to return to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> the mechanisms of normal political life. The transition is difficult, but it does not have to cause shaking. On the contrary, it will be a path to normalcy. The principle of struggle, which sooner or later leads to elimination of one's opponent, must be replaced by a principle of partnership. We will not pass from the totalitarian system to democratic one in any other way. The current philosophy of the state must be changed. It can not take care of everything and guarantee everything. It should facilitate and regulate activities. The most important role for the government and administration at this moment is opening possibilities for common actions and individual actions. I want to be the prime minister of all Poles, regardless of their views and convictions, which must not be a criterion for dividing citizens into categories. I will undertake efforts so that the principles of constructing the government will be clear to all. I am especially obliged to do that for Solidarity. Helpful will be the understanding of the church, which has always stood in defense of human rights and has felt the worries of the nation as its own. The church was and is a stabilizing force in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. The future government must be truthful to society. It must also create mechanisms which will allow it to hear the voice of public opinion. We will pass certain problems to its judgment. If sacrifices are necessary, all must know their sense, understand them and be able to express their opinions on the problems occurring. High Chamber, The most important issue for society is the condition of the national economy, which now has to be considered critical. How bad it is and why _ already everything has been said about it. The problem is how to get out of it. I am fully aware of the great effort that repairing the economy will require of the new government and everybody. The long-term, strategic goal of government's activities will be restoring to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> economic institutions long known and tested. I understand by this a return to a market-oriented economy and a role for the state similar to that in economically developed countries. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> can not afford ideological experiments any longer. Any changes, on which the nation's prospects and citizens' welfare depend, are blocked today by inflation and the lack of an economic balance manifested by poor market supplies and queues, a state budget deficit and an unbalanced balance of payments Restoring equilibrium and stifling inflation is a task of utmost economic importance, as well as political and social significance. Disequilibrium and inflation, increasing social tensions, can undermine the Polish march to freedom. With high inflation there can be no discussion about creating normal working conditions for the nation, on which its material existence mainly will depend. The government, sensing an absolute and urgent need to challenge inflation, will prepare a package of required measures, utilizing what has been tried so far in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and in other countries, as well as by referring to the experience of international experts and financial organizations. We will start without delay demonopolizing the structures serving the food market, the excessive growth of which is one of the causes of high prices and halting rural development. Struggling with inflation and restoring market balance has always and everywhere been risky for government and painful for society. Keeping in mind the effectivness of the anti-inflation operation, the government will do everything to make it as painless as possible. One can not promise, however, that it will not be felt at all. Nobody responsibly can make such an offer. Poles themselves have to solve Polish problems. Our own ingenuity, work and patience _ our own effort _ will determine our success. This does not mean that we are doomed to be alone in this difficult undertaking. The world is watching the transformations taking place here with sympathy and hope. The government will aim energetically at obtaining as much economic support for <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> from the international community as possible, in all possible forms, according to existing procedures and customs. We will not apply for privileges denied others in a similar situation to ours. We will, however, expect the maximum possible support of our efforts to cure the economy. Governments by themselves do not create economic success for their nations and do not alone end economic crises. Many a government by stifling the initiative of citizens and trying to direct everyone and everything effectively overpowered the country economically. However, there have been and there are governments that release the economic energy dormant in talented and diligent people.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0156EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     08-25 0299</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0312</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Grace </PERSON> <PERSON> Quinones </PERSON> got married five years ago after meeting on a commuter van they took to work each day. On Thursday they celebrated, with Mayor <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, the 10th anniversary of the van-pool program that shuttles more than 21 percent of the employees to and from the downtown <ORGANIZATION> TransAmerica </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's good for everyone,'' <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said. `` You can read, sleep ... you can even propose for marriage if you like.'' <PERSON> Quinones </PERSON>, 32, sporting a top hat, and his 31-year-old wife, clutching a bouquet, said they met in 1981 when he was the designated driver of the van she took each day from <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION>, about 35 miles east of downtown. He eyed her in the rearview mirror for about a month before he got the nerve to ask her out on a date. Three years later, they were married. The Quinoneses still live in <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION> and remain in the van pool.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MARYSVILLE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 How about this name on a college sweatshirt: `` Yosubacola.'' It was one of several offered this week as <ORGANIZATION> Yuba </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> trustees discussed changing the district's name. `` We cover a large geographical area,'' said <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON>, the superintendent who suggested a change because `` <ORGANIZATION> Yuba </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> does not necessarily describe'' the district. Trustee <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Mathews </PERSON> offered <PERSON> Yosubacola </PERSON> in jest, using two letters from each of five counties the district covers: Yolo, <PERSON> Sutter </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Yuba </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colusa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>. The district also includes parts of Butte, <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Placer </LOCATION> counties. <PERSON> Mathews </PERSON> said he offered the name because he was `` scared to death someone's going to come up with a cutesy name.'' One trustee suggested that any new name be higher in the alphabet. The trustees agreed to think about the proposal and discuss it again.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0208EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Voyager-Facts     08-25 0298</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Voyager-Facts,0309</SECOND>
<HEAD>Facts About Voyager</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Voyager-Neptune, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RAEBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Editor</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PASADENA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It may not help you in your next Trivial Pursuit game, but here are some facts about Voyager churned out by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>'s public relations people: _ The Voyager mission has cost each <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> resident 20 cents a year since the project began in 1972. -LRB- That totals $ 865 million. -RRB- _ The two Voyager spacecraft have sent back 5 trillion bits of scientific data, enough to fill 6,000 complete sets of the Encyclopedia Brittanica. _ Each Voyager spacecraft has as many electronic components as 2,000 color televisions. _ The power it takes to operate a digital wristwatch is 20 billion times greater than the power of the Voyager radio signals reaching Earth. _ An unprotected human riding on Voyager 1 would have received a radiation dose 1,000 times the lethal level while passing Jupiter. _ The Voyager project has consumed 11,000 work years, one-third what it took to build the great pyramid at <LOCATION> Giza </LOCATION>. _ Each Voyager spacecraft has a slight roll that engineers can not control. The roll is 15 times slower than the motion of a clock's hour hand _ When the Voyager spacecraft swept past Jupiter, they got an energy boost and <ORGANIZATION> Jupiter </ORGANIZATION> suffered an energy loss, enough to slow its motion by one foot in the next trillion years. _ Voyager gets 30,000 miles to the gallon. _ Pele, the largest volcano on <ORGANIZATION> Jupiter </ORGANIZATION>'s moon Io, spews sulfur to a height 30 times that of <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Everest </LOCATION>, and the fallout covers an area the size of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. _ The Voyager spacecraft will leave the solar system in 20,000 years, at which time they will have traveled half the distance to the nearest star.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Poland-Mazowiecki     08-25 0865</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Mazowiecki,0912</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Prime Minister Favors Conciliation, Caution</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Poland, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DRUSILLA MENAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON>, a symbol of the astounding change in the Communist world, has emerged as a cautious, conciliatory negotiator who admits he is frightened by the challenge ahead. `` A lot of things terrify me,'' he said as he paused after his nomination last week to contemplate his momentous mission. The first non-Communist prime minister to head an East bloc government, <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> faces awesome responsibility. He must negotiate the competing demands of factions long at ideological odds while confronting economic disaster and inspiring a populace that has exhausted its faith in government of any stripe. `` At first I felt as if someone had put 100 kilos of stones on my head,'' <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> said. `` But I calmed down and started looking with a certain optimism. Otherwise, I could not take on this role.'' <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> was proposed as the head of a governing coalition by Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, for whom <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> has been a close adviser since the founding of the independent union during shipyard strikes in 1980. The 62-year-old lawyer and journalist, a lifelong anti-Communist with close ties to the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, was not among the most public Solidarity leaders. Nothing could have prepared him for the hopes now centered on him. He has responded with remarkable calm. There have been no fiery speeches, nor radical announcements. His diplomacy may smooth the delicate transition, or it may disappoint those waiting to be ignited. Although his demeanor has been mild, those who know him say he can be tough. <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON>'s Solidarity activism earned him a year in prison after the martial-law crackdown imposed in 1981 by <PERSON> Wojciech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON>, the Communist president who nominated him as prime minister Saturday. But associates say he was not embittered. His approach to the weakened but still crucial <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> so far has been to play down differences and offer compromise. There has been little sense of triumph. `` I think we should be mutually open to each other, and aim at a situation where no reluctance and aggression take place between us. Because what <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> needs now is a joint effort of all forces,'' he said after hearing of a sharply worded resolution from the party. To the Polish people, he has offered a mix of hope and realism, asking them to `` believe that it can be better in this country'' while acknowledging: `` Society has no concept how difficult it will be to reform this economy.'' Graying and dignified, <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> appears solemn, serious and even cool. But he has shown humor and a human side during the tense week, joking about running out of gas while driving _ `` not fitting for a premier'' _ and craving a cigarette away from the cameras. The widowed father of three sons who has four grandchildren, <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> was editing Solidarity's weekly newspaper when history turned to him. He had founded the newspaper during the union's first legal months in 1980 and resurrected it when Solidarity was legalized again in April. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> had entrusted him with a major role in the negotiations between the opposition and the Communist authorities that led to restoration of Solidarity's legal status and the freest parliament elections in post-war <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. He was in charge of the talks on trade union issues. This spring, <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> chose to remain an editor rather than run for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. He had been a Sejm deputy from 1961 to 1970 as a member of ZNAK, an officially condoned delegation under the church's protection that supported regeneration of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> based on Catholic values. In 1971, when he tried unsuccessfully to establish a <ORGANIZATION> Sejm </ORGANIZATION> commission to study the violent repression of strikes that swept the Baltic coast following price increases in December 1970, he overstepped official tolerance and was denied another term. Born April 18, 1927, to an intelligentsia family in the small central <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> city of Plock, <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> attended <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. By age 21, in the early years of Communist <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, he was dismissed from his academic editing house job for links too close to the church. He began to work for PAX, set up by the government to dilute church-based opposition but one of the few venues for independent thought. By 1955, he had been dismissed for criticizing the mix of politics and religion. In 1958 he founded the Wiez, or Link, a progressive <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> monthly magazine that he edited until 1981. The <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligentsia </ORGANIZATION> he helped found in 1957 became the core of the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> fight against to communist ideology. On Aug. 22, 1980, he arrived at the strikebound <ORGANIZATION> Lenin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipyard </ORGANIZATION> and after a nightlong session with <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, he took charge of a group of experts advising the workers on organizing the union. He stayed with <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> and the movement through seven years of resistance. In the Council of Minister building during his first hours as prime minister, he recalled walking out of the <ORGANIZATION> Lenin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipyard </ORGANIZATION> with workers in disappoinment after an unfruitful occupation strike in May 1988. `` I think that neither them nor I thought that exit would lead to my entrance here today,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0208EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CysticFibrosis Bjt   08-25 0775</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cystic Fibrosis, Bjt,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Researchers Discover Gene for Cystic Fibrosis, May Suggest New Treatments</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Researchers who isolated the gene that causes cystic fibrosis say the discovery may lead to breakthrough therapy within the lifetimes of young people now suffering from the disease. `` This is a milestone of the highest order, but it does not have applications for the doctor's office tomorrow,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, a co-discoverer of the cystic fibrosis gene. Dr. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Riordan </PERSON>, director of the CF research program at the Hospital for <ORGANIZATION> Sick </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>, said that finding the gene means that `` within the lifetime of CF sufferers, we can now say it's possible that drugs will be discovered'' to treat the fundamental condition causing the disease. <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, of the <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hughes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ann </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arbor </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Riordan </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Lap-Chee </PERSON> <PERSON> Tsui </PERSON>, also of the <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> research institute, announced Thursday they had isolated the gene responsible for CF. In cooperative research at labs in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>, they also discovered a mutation in the gene that causes production of a defective protein that leads to symptoms of the disease. A report of their finding is to be published in the Sept. 8 edition of Science, the journal of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Science. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dresing </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Cystic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fibrosis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> and father of <PERSON> Robbie </PERSON>, a 22-year-old with CF, said the discovery gives a burst of hope for treatment of a disease that has been largely untreatable. `` Now I can look in <PERSON> Robbie </PERSON>'s eyes and say we going to cure this disease and you will be a beneficiary,'' <PERSON> Dresing </PERSON> said at the news conference. The remark received long applause from a audience that included a number of cystic fibrosis patients and their parents. Cystic fibrosis is the most common lethal genetic disease of young people in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, afflicting about 30,000. The Cystic Fibrosis Foundation in <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, said that 1,000 to 1,200 new cases, usually children, are diagnosed annually. The disease causes the formation of a thick, sticky mucus that clogs the lungs and digestive tract, blocking breathing and digestion. Half of its victims die before their mid-20s. Treatment of the disease has been symptomatic, with drugs and therapy designed to control the thick mucus and to help patients avoid or combat repeated lung infections that often kill. <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> said treating the specific cause of the disease was caught in a `` bottleneck'' because the precise gene and the flaw that caused the disease were not known. `` That bottleneck has been passed through now,'' he said at a news conference on Thursday. First use of the new knowledge, said <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, will be to develop a screening test to identify the 12 million or so Americans who unknowingly carry the defective gene and can pass it along to their offspring. He said about 5 percent of the white population are carriers of the gene. CF occurs in a child only if it inherits two defective genes, one from each parent. The parents can each carry one defective gene and remain healthy, but there is a 25 percent chance that a child from the couple will have CF. <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> said a genetic test could be developed to help couples determine if their children were at risk of inheriting the CF gene. `` It's going to be possible and very soon,'' he said. <PERSON> Riordan </PERSON> said the researchers found a specific mutation in 70 percent of the chromosomes carrying the CF gene. This flaw, he said, caused the gene to create a protein that lacks an amino acid called phenylalanine. The flawed protein, now called the cystic fibrosis transmembrane regulator, somehow distorts the transport of charged particles across the cell membranes of some organs. This, in turn, plays a role in formation of the thick mucus. <PERSON> Riordan </PERSON> said the researchers now must determine the gene mutation that causes the other 30 percent of CF-related problems. Once this is understood, he said, researchers may be able to develop a therapy, perhaps some type of protein replacement, that will correct the flawed mucus secretion. Ultimately, <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> said, the discovery of the defective gene may help researchers correct the genetic flaw itself. This would mean permanently fixing the defect within the gene so that it would start producing the correct protein. Genes are segments within the threadlike structures called chromosomes. The CF gene was found on what is called chromosome 7. `` A gene therapy will take quite a bit of time -LRB- to develop -RRB-,'' said <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>. `` That is a path that has never been trod before for any disease.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0214EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-InnocentsAbroad Bjt   08-25 0769</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Innocents Abroad, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>State Department Guides Diplomats on Sitting, Standing, Speaking</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is advising its diplomats that while they need n't splurge on their wardrobe for overseas duty, shoes are a must. <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women going abroad, as diplomats or their spouses, are also advised to remove their gloves while eating or drinking at a formal function. This is some of the advice in a pamphlet entitled `` Social Usage Abroad'' given to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> representatives to help prepare them for foreign postings. The leaflet illustrates how protocol, that French invention which greases the wheels of statehood, can be a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomat's biggest nightmare. It also makes clear that proper behavior within the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomatic community abroad is just as tricky as behavior toward officials of the host country. The diplomat's training begins well before departure from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` It is customary when assigned to a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mission abroad to write to the principal officer -LRB- usually the ambassador -RRB- ... to express personal pleasure in the assignment,'' the guide advises. Wives -LRB- or husbands -RRB- of diplomats should do the same to the wife -LRB- or husband -RRB- of the principal officer. A new member of the embassy staff must call on the ambassador or chief officer within two working days, according to the manual. `` An expensive or extensive wardrobe is not necessary'' for junior diplomats. `` It is advisable, however, for newcomers to bring along a basic wardrobe, including shoes, because they will often be too busy on arrival to shop for new clothes.'' As for the dress code: for a daytime ceremony, `` a woman's shoulders should be covered. And in countries where gloves are worn for all daytime social occasions, `` it is useful to remember that they are always removed entirely for eating or drinking.'' Ambassadors, in addition to familiarizing themselves with treaties and other aspects of bilateral relations, must remember to take the place closest to the curbside when entering a car. When making social calls on officials of the host country in their homes, the American's calling card is left on a hall table `` and a caller should stay no longer than 20 minutes unless strongly urged.'' The pamphlet does n't explain how to judge whether such entreaties are `` strong.'' What it does do is answer every question `` ever put to us,'' said <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Forbord </PERSON>, relocation adviser for the Overseas Briefing Center. The center, run by the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, provides extensive reading materials on conditions in foreign countries, regulations of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign service, etiquette, educational and health facilities, and other information. Some 14,000 people, or about half of the Americans sent abroad last year by various government agencies, used the center in 1988, she said. The center also offers a mandatory two-day seminar on security overseas, and even a course designed to help teenagers adjust to life abroad, <PERSON> Forbord </PERSON> said. For American hostesses abroad, the pitfalls are numerous. Making a dinner table seating plan is `` full of complexities,'' warn the authors of the pamphlet. Hostesses should check with the embassy protocol officer to ensure they have not inadvertently planned to seat together people from countries which do not maintain diplomatic relations, for example. A proper seating arrangement requires mathematical talent. `` To seat eight, 12, 16 or 20 persons without two men or two women sitting together, the hostess sits to the left of the seat that is properly hers.'' Is that clear? Now, if the women are served before the men, the woman on the host's right is served first and the woman on the host's left is served second. Try explaining that to the servants. One also should be aware that an invitation for 8 o'clock does n't necessarily mean you show up at 8 In some countries, it's a signal to turn up at 9:30. `` At official dinners in certain <ORGANIZATION> Commonwealth </ORGANIZATION> countries, it is rude to smoke at the table before the toast to the Queen.'' And speaking of toasts, `` it is a good idea to leave enough wine in the glass at the end of the meal to join in the drinking'' of such salutations. And in case your parents neglected to tell you, the guide advises that `` before leaving, each guest should thank those hosting the party.'' Then there are ambiguities. For instance, men always rise when being introduced and when a woman enters the room. But `` whether a woman rises to be introduced to another woman is a more complicated question'' depending on age, social position, etc. The guide, however, does n't advise whether a woman should rise when being introduced to a man. <PERSON> Emily </PERSON> <PERSON> Post </PERSON>, help!
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0105EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-SouthAfrica-School Bjt   08-25 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-South Africa-School, Bjt,0657</SECOND>
<HEAD>Parents, Students, Staff Seek to Save School by Integrating it</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID CRARY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's a quintessentially South African paradox. <ORGANIZATION> Johannesburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Girls </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> has been ordered closed for lack of pupils, yet its neighborhood abounds with schoolgirls who wish they could enroll. Throughout its 102-year existence, the inner-city school has been open only to whites. Now, with closure imminent because of white flight to the suburbs, its students, teachers and parents are petitioning for it to become <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s first multiracial government-run school. `` We should prove to the rest of the world we can do it,'' said <PERSON> Candice </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>, a 15-year-old student excited by the idea of black classmates. `` Our school should feel privileged if it could be the first.'' The government has given no sign it will be swayed by the `` Save Our School'' campaign, even though organizers say they have gathered 12,000 signatures supporting integration at the city's oldest high school. But <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>, mother of <PERSON> Candice </PERSON> and chairman of the campaign, says she hopes that mounting pressure might prompt the government to reconsider its decision to close the school in December. On a brick wall at the school was a poster with the initials S.O.S. _ for `` Save Our School'' _ and a crayon drawing showing a white girl and black girl side by side, dressed in the school's uniform The school was built to accommodate 630 students, and now has 203. It is in the heart of the country's largest `` gray area,'' where thousands of black and Indian families have moved in defiance of residential segregation laws. Acting President F.W. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>, favored to win a full five-year term after the Sept. 6 parliamentary elections, says he opposes discrimination and favors legalization of selected multiracial neighborhoods. But he has recommitted himself to the concept of segregated public schools. Asked about <ORGANIZATION> Johannesburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Girls </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, he said children should have `` mother-tongue education among people of their own community.'' Parents who wanted multiracial education could send their children to integrated, state-subsidized private schools, <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> said. But Mrs. <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> said most girls at the high school were from low-income or single-parent families and could not afford the cost of private schools. The parent-elected management council at <ORGANIZATION> Johannesburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Girls </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> has been criticized by some parents for failing to consult the school community fully before it advised the government to either integrate the facility or close it. But council chairman <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> said the declining enrollment left no other option. `` It was n't educationally viable anymore,'' he said. `` We could n't offer the variety of subjects you need in a high school like that.'' `` It's a great, great pity,'' he added. `` The facilities are all there. It seems crazy not to utilize them.'' The school is a spacious complex of modern red-brick buildings on the border of <LOCATION> Hillbrow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Berea </LOCATION>, two neighborhoods dominated by high-rise apartment buildings. They officially are designated as `` whites only,'' but an estimated 60,000 blacks, Indians and people of mixed race have moved in and the government has virtually halted enforcement of residential segregation laws in the area. However, no state schools have been established for these non-white families. Their children must either go to costly private schools or commute long distances to crowded, poorly equipped public schools in outlying townships. Mrs. <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> said some black children spend nearly four hours daily commuting to and from schools in <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION>, southwest of <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>. If it closes, <ORGANIZATION> Johannesburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Girls </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> could be the first of many. A new study by education specialists at <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Witwatwersrand </ORGANIZATION> said 42 of the city's 175 white schools are at risk of closure within five years because of declining enrollments. The study calculated that there were 13,150 vacant places for students in the city's schools.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0217EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CocaineMonkeys     08-25 0611</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cocaine Monkeys,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Monkeys Lose Cocaine Interest After Buprenorphine Shots, Researcher
Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A pain-reliever that causes laboratory monkeys to lose interest in cocaine may now be tested to see if it can help human addicts lose the craving for drugs, researchers say in an article published today. Researchers at a <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> drug abuse research center report that five Rhesus monkeys that had been dosing themselves regularly with cocaine chose to ignore the drug after receiving injections of buprenorphine. The study appears in the journal Science. Dr. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mendelson </PERSON>, a co-investigator in the research, said as a result of the animals' response to buprenorphine, clinical studies are proposed to determine if the analgesic will help people overcome dependence on cocaine and heroin. `` We feel that it -LRB- buprenorphine -RRB- may provide an opportunity for some persons to stop using cocaine and not feel the adverse effects of cessation,'' <PERSON> Mendelson </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. `` This would provide a window in time for someone who might be able to stop using the drug and ultimately become drug-free.'' In the laboratory studies, five Rhesus monkeys were fitted with intravenous catheters that were connected to pumps operated by levers. Each monkey, if it chose to, could press the lever and receive a small dose of cocaine. `` The monkeys self-administer cocaine, but are under no compulsion to do so,'' <PERSON> Mendelson </PERSON> said. `` It is completely an elective act.'' He said earlier studies showed that when given this choice, nine out of 10 Rhesus monkeys will press the lever for cocaine, though they will choose not to self-administer some other types of pharmaceuticals. <PERSON> Mendelson </PERSON> said that when the five test monkeys received injections of buprenorphine, their cocaine use rapidly declined, and approached zero use at some doses of the buprenorphine. When a type of placebo, saline solution, was injected, the monkeys chose to press the cocaine lever repeatedly. `` The placebo did n't do anything,'' <PERSON> Mendelson </PERSON> said. `` But the buprenorphine suppressed the cocaine self-administration.'' At the same time, he said, the monkeys continued to press another lever to receive banana pellets, and otherwise behaved normally while taking the buprenorphine. `` It does n't produce the behavior changes and its safety is enormous,'' said the researcher. <PERSON> Mendelson </PERSON> said buprenorphine may be particularly useful in weaning abusers away from `` speedball,'' a combination of heroin and cocaine that is becoming more widely used by drug-dependent people. `` We've tried -LRB- buprenorphine -RRB- in heroin-dependent persons and most of them report they can detect that they've had a drug, but it does n't produce the degree of euphoria and certainly not the rush of a drug like heroin or methadone,'' he said. `` Most of the people who are heroin-dependent who have used the drug report that they do n't feel high, but they feel normal. The factors of drug addiction are highly complex and stopping dependence is not easy, <PERSON> Mendelson </PERSON> said. Though it appears that buprenorphine would not become a `` substitute addiction'' for cocaine, he said, it does not represent a `` magic bullet'' for the effortless control of substance abuse, but possibly only an aide for controlling such dependence. `` Some people,'' he noted, `` will abuse chicken soup.'' Buprenorphine is commonly used in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> for relief of moderate pain, and is used in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hospitals as an injectable pain reliever. <ORGANIZATION> Norwich </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eaton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pharmaceuticals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> markets it as the prescription drug Buprenex. The Rhesus monkey study was coauthored by <PERSON> Mendelson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mello </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bree </PERSON> and <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lukas </PERSON>, all researchers at the <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School-McLean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> drug abuse research center in <LOCATION> Belmont </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. Science, which published the study, is the journal of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Science.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0217EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Pentagon-Colombia     08-25 0512</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pentagon-Colombia,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon Provides List of Possible Hardware for Colombia</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Joint Chiefs of Staff have sent the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> a list of military hardware that President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> could send to <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> if that country seeks such aid in its war against drugs, sources say. The Joint Chiefs met Thursday to draw up the list, which includes UH-1 `` Huey'' troop transport helicopters, ammunition and radio equipment, said a military source who spoke on condition of anonymity. Top <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Colombian officials were expected to meet in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to discuss how the two nations can cooperate in the anti-drug battle. An administration source, who also spoke on condition of anonymity, stressed that no <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel were included in the Joint Chiefs' suggestions. This, he said, was in line with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s complaint that talk of such an idea had gotten `` out of whack.'' Colombian President <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> has also rejected the idea of seeking <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops. The administration official said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> could do other things to help <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> in its battle against drug terrorists _ such as offering training to members of the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> military and police forces. But, he cautioned, `` we are n't going to do anything unless the Colombians say they want it.'' The military source said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> helicopters _ which were widely used in the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> war and are being replaced by the more sophisticated Blackhawk choppers _ must be flown by <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> pilots since no <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> personnel will be involved. No precise numbers were disclosed, but the source said the amount of helicopters that could be provided was `` not extravagant.'' The administration source said the list was not a formal recommendation, but instead provides the president with `` a laundry list of items that the Pentagon could provide if called upon to do so.'' The official said the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s suggestions came amid those offered by other agencies, such as a $ 2 million <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> program designed to help <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> protect judges and other officials threatened by the drug cartel. The military source noted that the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION>' list is over and above the aid provided to <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> through the Foreign Military Sales program. Under the FMS program, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has sold <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s government almost $ 210 million worth of military goods and services since 1963, <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials said Thursday The focus of the sales have been the helicopters, ammunition, spare parts and support for the choppers. The Colombian government has requested that the <LOCATION> Export-Import </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> provide a loan guarantee for approximately $ 200 million, and the proceeds of loans obtained under the guarantee would finance additional FMS purchases for the counter-narcotics programs, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said. <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> is expected to purchase additional UH-60 and UH-1 helicopters, patrol boats, rifles, machine guns, ammunition, vehicles and spare parts as part of this program, the Pentagon said. In the 1988 fiscal year, a total of 775 Colombian military personnel were trained under the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> and Training program, while 898 Colombian military received such training so far this fiscal year, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel-Deportee Bjt   08-25 0677</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Deportee, Bjt,0699</SECOND>
<HEAD>Deportation Order Tears at Palestinian Family</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN ALT POWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RAMALLAH, Occupied West Bank (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Amal </PERSON> <PERSON> Aruri </PERSON> steeled herself for the worst but still found she was unprepared when the Israeli <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ordered her husband deported to <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. `` We fought it for more a year,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Aruri </PERSON> said, her voice shaking. `` Even though I expected it day by day, still I was shocked.'' The 28-year-old Palestinian nursery school teacher learned from Israeli radio news that an appeal by her husband, physics professor <PERSON> Taysir </PERSON> <PERSON> Aruri </PERSON>, was rejected by the court Thursday. He is accused of being a leader of the Palestinian uprising. The deportation order is expected to be carried out within a week and could mean a long separation for the family. Mrs. <PERSON> Aruri </PERSON> has no passport and fears she will not get special travel passes from the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> military government. `` I have n't told the children yet,'' she said in an interview, adding she was waiting `` until we can sit alone together ... maybe at bedtime.'' On Thursday, the sitting room in the family's white stone house was crowded with relatives who came to lend support and distract the three <PERSON> Aruri </PERSON> children, ages 2 to 7, while Mrs. <PERSON> Aruri </PERSON> talked with lawyers and reporters. <PERSON> Taysir </PERSON> <PERSON> Aruri </PERSON>, a 43-year-old physicist at the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Bir </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zeit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, was served on Aug. 17, 1988, with a deportation order signed by Defense Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON>. He has been jailed since in Juneid Prison near <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Aruri </PERSON> was never tried but was accused by the army of being a member of the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> Palestinian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and of being `` involved in planning the intefadeh and a member of the unified command of the intefadeh.'' `` Intefadeh'' is the Arabic word for the uprising Palestinians have been waging since December 1987 against <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> occupation of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> does not hear arguments in deportation cases and only decides if the army acted properly. The court has never overturned a deportation order. London-based <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> has adopted <PERSON> Aruri </PERSON> as a `` prisoner of conscience,'' and hundreds of scientists in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> signed petitions and launched a letter-writing campaign on his behalf. `` Maybe they did n't know they were dealing with a very cold government here,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Aruri </PERSON> said. Her husband was one of four Palestinians whose petitions were rejected Thursday. The others are <PERSON> Odeh </PERSON> <PERSON> Yusef </PERSON> <PERSON> Maali </PERSON> and <PERSON> Majed </PERSON> <PERSON> Labadi </PERSON>, both union organizers, and <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Matur </PERSON>, a teacher. <PERSON> Labidi </PERSON>'s brother, <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON>, also a union leader, was expelled in June The new expulsions to <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> will raise the number of deportees to 59. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> and international human rights groups have said repeatedly that the practice violates international law. This was not <PERSON> Aruri </PERSON>'s first run-in with Israeli authorities. He was jailed from 1974 to 1978 without charge or trial under Israeli administrative detention procedures. Then, too, he was championed by <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>. Asked about the allegation that her husband is a leader of the uprising, Mrs. <PERSON> Aruri </PERSON> said: `` I think every Palestinian is a leader of the intefadeh. It does n't depend on leaders, really, since it is a popular revolution.'' Petitions on <PERSON> Aruri </PERSON>'s behalf, including one signed by nearly 1,000 foreign scientists and published in the English-language <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> in May, describe him as `` a man of peace.'' An outspoken critic of the occupation, <PERSON> Aruri </PERSON> has urged an international conference leading to creation of a separate Palestinian state beside <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, an idea long opposed by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s government Two months before he was arrested, <PERSON> Aruri </PERSON> joined other prominent Palestinian and Israeli artists and intellectuals in signing a `` peace treaty'' calling for dialogue. He has argued that there can be no military solution to the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> conflict. Mrs. <PERSON> Aruri </PERSON> said the couple's children knew their father might be deported to <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Natasha </PERSON>, the 5-year-old, often asked during weekly prison visits about his future: `` Can we come to visit you? ... When will you come home?'' `` Right now I do n't have answers for her,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Aruri </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890825-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-89 0243EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Panama     08-25 0659</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Panama,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Noriega _ A Case Study in Smug Defiance</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
