<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0158EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-US-Cambodia 1stLd-Writethru a0656 04-08 0571</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Cambodia, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0656,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>State Department Says Elections Best Solution to Khmer Rouge</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDs: ADDS 3 grafs at end to UPDATE with Solarz calling for US military
aid to non-communist guerrillas</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The best way to prevent a resurgence of power by the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> is to hold free elections and let the <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> people reject the faction, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Friday. But the department's statement did not rule out a role in an interim coalition government for the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, under whose former rule international human rights groups estimate one-fourth of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>'s 8 million people died from famine or execution. Fear of a return to power by the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, the strongest of three insurgent groups in a <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> resistance coalition led by U.S.-backed Prince <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>, has been a major stumbling block to a negotiated settlement with the Vietnamese-installed government. <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> is scheduled to meet with <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON>, the Vietnam-backed Cambodian leader, on May 2 in <LOCATION> Jakarta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> comments followed <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s announcement this week that it would pull its remaining troops out of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> by the end of September, ending an 11-year occupation that ousted the communist <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> from power. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> totally opposes a return to dominance by the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>,'' the statement said. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> envisions an arrangement in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in which an interim coalition government is headed by <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>, `` the logical leader of such an arrangement,'' the statement said. `` Whether the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, minus <PERSON> Pol </PERSON> <PERSON> Pot </PERSON> and the other discredited <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> leaders who clearly must be excluded, are permitted to participate in such an interim arrangement is something the Cambodian factions themselves will have to decide,'' the department said. `` We are convinced that in free and fair elections'' for a permanent government, `` the <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> people would reject the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>,'' it said. Any future arrangements for a return to democracy in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> would also have to include `` effective guarantees'' to prevent power from falling into the hands of the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, the department said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials say such safeguards would include an international force to monitor the Vietnamese pullout, a halt to outside supply of arms to the Cambodian factions and improved international access to the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> camps along the Thai-Cambodian border. International human rights groups and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have accused the faction of committing atrocities against prisoners taken to those camps. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> view has concerned some <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> countries who reject any role for the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, even an interim one, but <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials say the group is a fact of life and has too much power in the resistance coalition to be ignored. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> announced this week that it would continue arming the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> until <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> makes good on its promise to pull out its troops, estimated to number 50,000 to 70,000. Meanwhile, Rep. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Solarz </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Subcommittee </ORGANIZATION> on <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, called Friday for the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration to send military aid to the forces backing <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> and one of his allies, Son <PERSON> Sann </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should do `` everything it can'' to support the resistance against the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Solarz </PERSON>, who just returned from discussions in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> on the situation in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. He proposed that the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> establish an interim government in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> to set up a political settlement through elections.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-DNAProsecutions     04-08 0198</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-DNA Prosecutions,0202</SECOND>
<HEAD>Attorney General Calls for DNA Analysis of Criminals for Crime Solving</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Criminals convicted of violent crimes would have their blood drawn for `` genetic fingerprinting'' to help solve future crimes, under legislation endorsed Friday by state Attorney General <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Kamp </PERSON>. Analysis of the unique genetic blueprint can be a powerful tool for investigating and prosecuting violent crime, <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Kamp </PERSON> said Friday in support of legislation proposed by state Sen. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>. DNA, or deoxyribonucleic acid, is found in the chromosomes of cells, including saliva, hair, blood, semen, tissue and bone marrow. Only identical twins can have the same DNA pattern, or genetic blueprint. Under the bill, blood samples already required of sex criminals would be taken also from people convicted of murder, assault or battery. DNA analysis of the samples would be stored in a computerized data base available to police. The information could link a suspect to a crime in which tissue is left behind. Rape investigations, in particular, would benefit from the system, <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Kamp </PERSON> said. The state of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> will begin providing DNA testing for its police and sheriff's departments on May 1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0009EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w BC-NorthTrial-Testimony 1stAdd   04-08 0966</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-North Trial-Testimony, 1st Add,940</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: those questions.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 JUDGE <PERSON> GESELL </PERSON>: Well, now, colonel, that would require going to the president, would n't it? ... Did you understand you had the power to assert executive privilege for the president? NORTH: It was my understanding, sir, that executive privilege could be exerted. JUDGE <PERSON> GESELL </PERSON>: By the president? NORTH: Well, by the office of the presidency, yes, sir. -LRB- There followed an exchange describing concerns by <PERSON> North </PERSON> about the response to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> suggested by <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON>, including concern about the disclosure of clandestine ammunition shipments to the Contras. -RRB- NORTH: I was disturbed that the answer he was going to give, given what the press was saying, the media was out there reporting in volumes on what was going on down in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, and all this was going to do was add, you know, fuel to the fire. It was like throwing gasoline on the fire. In fact, it ended up that way. ... My point was, this answer that you -LRB- <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> -RRB- are proposing is not going to help us. It is not going to help get the job done. It is not going to help get aid to the resistance. It is just going to make things worse. SULLIVAN: Did Mr. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> reject your advice then with respect to the draft that he had made? NORTH: Yes, sir, he did. JUDGE <PERSON> GESELL </PERSON>: What did he say, colonel? NORTH: My recollection is, sir, that he said that he had talked with the president about the approach we were taking on the letters and that my approach was far too confrontational. ... SULLIVAN: Congressman <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> received a response to his letter at about the same time, did n't he? NORTH: Yes, sir. ... SULLIVAN: Was ... Congressman <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON>' letter ... similar to the <LOCATION> Hamilton </LOCATION> letter? NORTH: Yes, sir, it is. -LRB- North refers to several additional inquiries from <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> and that <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> briefed the congressman. -RRB- SULLIVAN: Now, after then, in order, two letters _ these letters had been sent by Mr. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON>, two to <LOCATION> Hamilton </LOCATION>, one to <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON>? NORTH: Right. SULLIVAN: He -LRB- <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> -RRB- had been up to <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> twice? NORTH: Yes. ... There was a fairly steady flow of paper from Mr. <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> asking for documents, yes, sir. SULLIVAN: What are you telling Mr. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> that he should do with respect to <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON>' further inquiry ...? NORTH: What I said was that I had attached a letter from Mr. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> back to Congressman <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> in response to his request for documents. ... -LRB- I -RRB- told Mr. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> to remind Mr. <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> that the classified letter he had sent earlier had been revealed to the media. <PERSON> SULLIVAN </PERSON>: ... Is this your draft that you recommended <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> send to <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON>? -LRB- in response to the inquiries. -RRB- NORTH: Yes, sir, it is. SULLIVAN: Does your draft give <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> what he wants or what he is asking for? NORTH: No, sir, it does not. SULLIVAN: Does it take a hard line position saying, in essence, that the information should not be given? NORTH: Yes, sir, it takes the approach of executive privilege. ... SULLIVAN: In essence, you are telling him we are not going to give you documents? NORTH: We are not going to give you documents and here is why. -LRB- <PERSON> North </PERSON> says his draft letter was never sent. -RRB- <PERSON> SULLIVAN </PERSON>: So that you never did get your way in recommending that the executive branch simply say to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, we have a right not to provide information? NORTH: No, sir, I did n't. ... He -LRB- <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> -RRB- did call me over to his office and showed me this stack of documents, which I at that point did not realize was sitting over in his office. I know I was surprised that they were there but not shocked. I mean, they were his documents. SULLIVAN: Tell the jury what happened in that meeting with regard to these documents. NORTH: Mr. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> showed me the pile of documents and said, there are several in here that are _ my recollection of the word is problematical, that this handful, and he had pulled out several, are a problem and they are inconsistent with what we have said to the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. And certainly they were. I think he handed them to me and I looked at them. And they were documents that clearly showed what I had been doing at his direction in Central America. ... And he said, these need to be fixed. In fact, he handed me a list that had those documents on it and, as I recall, also cited several others that I wrote down on the back of that list. He gave me that list and said, fix these documents so that they are consistent with what we have basically told the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. SULLIVAN: Did you explain to him right there at the time that it did n't make sense to change any documents because the files were filled with similar documents? NORTH: Yes, I did. <PERSON> SULLIVAN </PERSON>: What was his response to that? NORTH: He just told me to fix the documents and I mean, what's important, those were his documents I had written them all. But they were his documents. SULLIVAN: What happened to the request that he made to change documents? Did it just sit there? NORTH: Basically it did. ... SULLIVAN: So why did n't you do what he said? NORTH: Because I just did n't _ I did n't think it made any sense. -LRB- A year later when <PERSON> North </PERSON> was about to be dismissed, he said he altered the document. -RRB- SULLIVAN: That was in November 1986? NORTH: Yes, sir. SULLIVAN: Did you believe it was unlawful to do that? NORTH: No, I had written those documents. I had prepared them for him. They were his documents. It never occurred to me that that could be unlawful.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0230EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-JailEscapees     04-08 0181</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jail Escapees,0187</SECOND>
<HEAD>Inmates Escape From Dedham Jail</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DEDHAM, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thirteen prisoners broke out of the <ORGANIZATION> Norfolk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> sometime Friday evening, state police said. State and local police and sheriff's deputies using helicopters and dogs converged on the area to begin a search. State police Sgt. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON> said the inmates were discovered missing during a 9:30 p.m. head count and may have escaped around 8 p.m. He said the inmates are believed to have escaped by cutting through a jailhouse wall. <LOCATION> Dedham </LOCATION> jail officials would only confirm that there had been a jailbreak and repeatedly hung up when asked further questions. State police said that the inmates were clad in green prison garb. WNEV-TV also reported that the inmates may be headed for <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and may have split up into small groups, making it more difficult for authorities to track them down. The <LOCATION> Dedham </LOCATION> jail is one of the most overcrowded prisons in the state. It was the scene of a disturbance on Feb. 8 when a fight broke out in the recreation room.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BushRdp Bjt   04-08 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush Rdp, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Puts Government in Control of Alaskan Cleanup</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says he wants `` complete restoration'' of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s oil-fouled Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> and is sending in federal troops and inviting an army of volunteers to help clean up the massive pollution. `` The job of cleaning up the oil from both the sea and the affected land areas will be massive, prolonged and frustrating,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Friday as he put the government in virtual control of the operation. Transportation Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON>, tapped to mobilize and coordinate federal efforts, said `` the resources of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> government have been put at my disposal'' to ensure that the area is returned to its pristine condition `` and I plan to use them.'' Administration sources, declining to be identified, said thousands of military personnel would be involved. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> announced his decision at a hurriedly called news conference where he doggedly refused to answer questions about his role in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's secret program to aid the Contra rebels. He said any comment could prejudice the trial of one-time White House aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>, at which new details of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s role emerged Thursday. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told a questioner, `` The legal process ought to run unfettered, without you or me endangering the trial process.'' Turning to foreign policy, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the situation in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> was slightly improved because of a proposal by <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> to hold elections among Palestinian Arabs in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>. `` In the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, a little step sometimes can be fruitful,'' he said. `` I think the climate is better than it has been.'' On other subjects, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said: _ `` I have no intention of budging one inch'' on Democratic attempts to get him to raise his minimum-wage proposal above $ 4.25 an hour, coupled with a six-month subminimum `` training wage.'' The House has passed a bill to raise the minimum wage to $ 4.55. _ He will not be prodded by Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to speed up a foreign policy review and return to strategic arms talks `` We're making a prudent review and I will be ready to discuss that with the Soviets when we are ready,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. _ Developments in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> were encouraging and represented a `` mind-boggling'' shift in the attitude of the communist government The <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> government this week approved a sweeping agreement for democratic changes and legalizing the once-banned Solidarity trade union. Opening the news conference, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> branded the 10-million gallon oil spill in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> a `` tragic environmental disaster'' and said it had produced `` deadly results for wildlife and hardship for local citizens.'' He said, `` our ultimate goal must be the complete restoration of the ecology and the economy of Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>, including all of its fish, marine mammals, birds and other wildlife.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> noted that <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> had acknowledged responsibility and liability for the spill. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> `` should remain responsible for both damages and for employing civilian personnel necessary to control further damage. `` However, <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s efforts, standing alone, are not enough.'' He said the federal effort `` should not in any way relieve <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> from any of its responsibilities or liabilities.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the military would provide personnel and equipment for direct cleanup activities as well as logistical support. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> said the military could beef up the <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION> airport to a 24-hour-a-day operation and provide housing and food for cleanup personnel. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he hoped facilities would be ready by summer to accommodate a corps of volunteers. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> said the volunteers might be mobilized later this spring to help clean up oil-fouled coastlines and wildlife on the dozens of islands affected by the spill. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> emphasized that `` we are not federalizing'' the cleanup. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> explained that the administration was not using the word `` federalization'' because of `` some legal connotations'' _ apparently dealing with liability for the spill and cleanup.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0233EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SexSurvey Bjt   04-08 0534</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sex Survey, Bjt,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Survey Aimed at Fighting AIDS Will be Toned Down After Darman Protests</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A sex survey designed to help stem the spread of the deadly AIDS virus must be revised to ensure the government does not pry needlessly into the personal lives of <LOCATION> Americans </LOCATION>, Health Secretary <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> has ordered. Heeding the advice of budget director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> on Friday ordered the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> to conduct a `` thorough review and revision'' of the survey so that it is scientifically sound and `` sensitive and appropriate to the proper role of government.'' <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> had been pressured to act against the survey by a few conservative Republicans in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> who have organized letter-writing and telephone campaigns expressing outrage at the survey proposal. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Mero </PERSON>, a spokesman for Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON>, R-Calif., who has been rallying opposition to the survey, said, `` We hope Secretary <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> will take it -LRB- <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>'s concerns -RRB- to heart and put this thing out to pasture where it belongs. He said that when the revisions are completed, he will conduct `` a final, personal review.'' <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said he recognizes the survey is needed to help health experts better understand Americans' sexual behavior so they can improve strategies to stem the sexually-transmitted AIDS virus. But the survey should `` gather only data which is essential to public health needs,'' he said. `` My initial review of the survey instrument does indicate to me potential problems with the tone and content of the questions,'' he said, noting it was prepared before he took over at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> in March. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> acted after receiving criticism from <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> in a letter Thursday in which he said: `` I have a great deal of difficulty understanding how many of the questions are related to essential public interests.'' The Office of Management and Budget, which <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> heads, must approve all government surveys as part of the Paperwork Reduction Act, but only for purposes of reducing burdensome federal paperwork. Citing that law, <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> told <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> in the letter that <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> officials do not `` have the authority at this point to stop the proposed study.'' The proposed project includes a pilot survey of 2,300 Americans to learn the intimate details of their sexual lives, including when they last had sex, what they did and whether their partner was a man or woman. Other questions asked about such things as masturbation, oral sex and anal sex. A subsequent survey, at an estimated cost of $ 15 million, would question 20,000 people. The department said the survey is intended to produce a comprehensive picture of Americans' sexual behavior to help health experts better plan strategies to fight the spread of the deadly AIDS virus and other sexually transmitted diseases. <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> said he recognized that need, `` but, as important as it is, that is a considerably narrower subject than the more general subject of sexual mores, preferences and behavior patterns in American society.'' `` While I in no way question the rights of private researchers to explore this subject, I do question the extent to which it may be appropriate for the public sector to subsidize such research,'' the budget chief said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0235EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AbortionRights Bjt   04-08 0485</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion Rights, Bjt,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Abortion Rights Activists Converge upon Capital</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Activists were thronging to the nation's capital today for a demonstration that organizers hope will cement public opinion once and for all in favor of a woman's right to an abortion March leaders say the demonstration on Sunday will launch a campaign that includes nationwide distribution of a videotape aimed at countering the anti-abortion movement's trademark video, `` Silent Scream.'' The 20-minute videotape `` Abortion: For Survival'' includes footage of a woman undergoing an abortion to show the procedure is `` safe and simple'' and the indiscernible remains taken from the uterus in a first-trimester abortion. The videotape `` puts it where it's at,'' said <PERSON> Eleanor </PERSON> <PERSON> Smeal </PERSON>, president of the Fund for the Feminist Majority. `` It talks about abortion as a public health necessity and essential for the well-being of millions of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women. `` It features the central issue of this debate: What is abortion, why it's needed and why the public health and medical establishment of our society and worldwide is for keeping it legal.'' The tape is being distributed to government officials and members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and state legislatures as well as on college campuses nationwide, she said. `` Silent Scream'' expresses the anti-abortion view by depicting a fetus being aborted. March organizers said other parts of their campaign include applying pressure on government agencies and pharmaceutical companies to improve available contraception and standing up to Operation Rescue's attempts to close down abortion clinics. The march is aimed at women's rights in general and a pending <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision that could reverse its 1973 landmark ruling, <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON>, which legalized abortion. Oral arguments in the new case are scheduled for April 26. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told anti-abortion activists a few days after he moved into the Oval Office that he wanted the decision overturned. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> faced White House reporters on Friday but was not asked about the march or his views on abortion at a news conference that covered issues ranging from the Iran-Contra affair to the minimum wage, the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> oil spill to foreign policy in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. March organizers said students were coming from about 500 college campuses, many of them in the <LOCATION> Northeast </LOCATION>, where many college students are within easy traveling distance of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Other delegations of students as well as activists representing churches, labor unions and other groups across the country are coming. Dozens of celebrities are also scheduled to appear. <PERSON> Molly </PERSON> <PERSON> Yard </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION>, said she expected the size of the demonstration will be `` easily double ... and probably -LRB- be -RRB- considerably'' larger than the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> march three years ago which drew a crowd police estimated at 90,000. A counterdemonstration by anti-abortion advocates is expected to draw about 300 people during Sunday's pro-choice march from the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Monument down the Mall to the Capitol.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0234EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     04-08 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0026</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 05; 14; 20; 21; 37; 38.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0618EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SpendingBill     04-08 0565</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spending Bill,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Threatens Veto of Rapidly Growing Spending Bill</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration wants <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> lawmakers to begin slicing chunks of money off a fiscal 1989 spending bill that has more than doubled in size in recent days. Figures gathered Friday showed that after a week of work by the subcommittees of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, a measure proposed by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for $ 2.2 billion in new spending this year has grown to $ 4.6 billion. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>, sent a letter Thursday to Rep. <PERSON> Silvio </PERSON> <PERSON> Conte </PERSON>, R-Mass., ranking Republican on the appropriations panel, warning the lawmakers that because of the added expenditures, he would urge <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to veto the bill <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> noted that under a 1987 budget summit agreement between then-President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and congressional leaders, additional spending for this year could be allowed only in case of a `` dire emergency.'' `` In action taken this week, we believe several of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations subcommittees have adopted items that are a clear violation of the summit agreement,'' <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> wrote. <PERSON> Conte </PERSON> said in an interview that he agreed that the extra spending should not be on the bill. `` They're not going to get anywhere with this,'' he said, referring to <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democrats who are pushing the more generous version of the spending measure. The new spending appended by the lawmakers includes $ 726 million for anti-drug efforts, including money for prisons, police officers and prevention programs; $ 256 million to pay reparations to Japanese-Americans interned during World War II; and $ 350 million on top of a $ 250 million request by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to pay the costs of fighting last year's western forest fires. The subcommittees also ignored a 1.1 percent across-the-board slash that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had proposed in many domestic programs. That cut would have saved $ 829 million, but was attacked by critics for deriving one-third of its savings from programs for the poor. The deficit for fiscal 1989 _ which ends Sept. 30 _ was recently projected by <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> at $ 170.2 billion, excluding this bill. The budget resolution passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last spring called for a 1989 deficit of $ 142 billion. For technical reasons, the total for new spending in a bill frequently differs from the impact the measure will have on the government's red ink. Among other expenditures added to the bill by the subcommittees were $ 96 million for the <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and other <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> law enforcement agencies plus $ 36 million for drug-testing and other anti-drug efforts by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. In addition, the lawmakers inserted $ 35 million for the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> to hire more security officers, safety inspectors and air traffic controllers; $ 35 million for the prosecution of savings and loan fraud cases; and $ 32 million for improvements in weather forecasting equipment and for other <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> expenses. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s bill had included $ 892 million for the guaranteed student loan program for college students; $ 850 million for cost-of-living increases in veterans' benefits and other Department of Veterans Affairs programs; $ 423 million for foster care and adoption programs; $ 100 million for the costs of increased immigration from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>; and $ 55 million for the government's uranium program. The full appropriations committee is expected to consider the bill no earlier than the week of April 18. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has yet to work on the measure.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0616EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MinimumWage     04-08 0448</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Minimum Wage,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>White House, Senate Democrats to Heat up Struggle</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democrats and the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> will clash directly for the first time next week over raising the $ 3.35 hourly minimum wage, with more skirmishes expected before the nation's 5 million lowest paid workers get an increase. Leaders of both parties in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> agreed Friday to hold back-to-back votes Tuesday _ the first on the latest Democratic version for annual increases of 40 cents an hour to $ 4.55 by October 1991, and the second on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s offer of yearly 30-cent boosts to $ 4.25 by January 1992. Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> conceded his party and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> are likely to lose both votes. But <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> expressed confidence of a victory when the president vetoes the measure, as he promised again Friday, and Democrats attempt to override the veto. The chief sponsor of the raise, Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., acknowledged he lacks the 16 additional votes needed to muster a two-thirds majority for overriding a presidential veto `` I would hope they do n't again lay down this line in the sand,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said, challenging the administration's insistence on no more compromises. `` They've come a long way, we've come a long way.'' Democrats on Friday subtracted a dime from the $ 4.65 federal floor on wages they had wanted, and they accepted for the first time a 60-day subminimum `` training wage'' for workers entering their first job. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, however, told reporters he had `` no intention of budging one inch'' on allowing a minimum wage that high or on accepting that short a period during which employers could pay a `` training wage'' 20 percent below the federal floor. `` I will veto any bill which exceeds a $ 4.25 wage level and which does not contain a six-month training wage for new hires,'' he said in a letter Friday to <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. The latest Democratic plan was put together by <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and Sens. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>. Except for minor differences on the subminimum scale, it is identical to a bill passed by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> last month. In the House version, an employer could pay the lower subminimum skill only to workers in their first job. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> measure would require a worker to have at least 60 days' experience in one or more jobs before any employer would have to pay the higher scale. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s subminimum would allow employers to continue paying $ 3.35 to any new hires, regardless of their previous experience, for six months. That subminimum would rise to $ 3.40 an hour in 1992 under the president's proposal while the <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> would do away with it entirely then.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0616EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Consulate     04-08 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Consulate,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Accuses Soviets of Eavesdropping, Issues Angry Statement</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> bugged the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Consulate in <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> charged in a statement that called the action reprehensible no matter how long ago the listening devices were planted. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Friday the listening devices were discovered in early February during an inspection by security personnel. `` Such hostile attempts at intelligence gathering, however long ago they may have been initiated, are deeply resented by the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people,'' the department said it had told the Soviets in a protest. The devices in the consulate, which was opened in 1973, were discovered by officers from the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diplomatic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION>, the statement said. According to a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, the devices were implanted `` deep in the structure a long time ago.'' He declined to provide further details. In 1985, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> accused the Soviets of planting listening devices in the new <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassy chancery in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. In 1987, a <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> guard, Sgt. <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Lonetree </PERSON>, was accused and court-martialed on charges he permitted <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> intelligence agents to gain access to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassy. The latest accusation of Soviet intrusion was unexpected. The two governments were in the process of deciding whether to open new consulates in <LOCATION> Kiev </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, meanwhile, was in the midst of deciding what to do about the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassy in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. The two aides he sent there on an inspection trip returned two weeks ago with a recommendation to salvage part of the chancery, an administration official said Wednesday. The inspection was conducted by <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Salgo </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Selin </PERSON>, who has been nominated to be undersecretary of state for management. They told <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> on their return that refurbishing the building or even constructing an annex would be cheaper than razing the chancery and starting over. The estimated cost of tearing down and rebuilding the structure is $ 500 million. A trade group headed by <PERSON> Dwayne </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Archer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daniels </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Midland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, offered to buy the building for use as business offices. <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON> is co-chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-U.S.S.R. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, which promotes trade between the two superpowers. He made the offer on behalf of a consortium of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> companies, which would use the building as a <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> headquarters.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0619EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SoftwareLawsuit     04-08 0311</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Software Lawsuit,0322</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Software Consortium Files Anti-Piracy Lawsuit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LESLIE H. DREYFOUS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Six American software companies have accused three Italian companies of pirating their programs in an unprecedented copyright infringment lawsuit, company officials said Friday. The lawsuit, filed Thursday in <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, accuses the European companies of unauthorized copying of software produced by <ORGANIZATION> Lotus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Cambridge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. and <ORGANIZATION> Ashton-Tate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Torrance </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Elettrocarbonium </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> S.p.A. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Montedison </ORGANIZATION>, S.p.A. and its affiliate, <ORGANIZATION> Montefibre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> S.p.A. </ORGANIZATION> were named as co-defendants in the lawsuit filed by the <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Software </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, D.C.-based industry group. The lawsuit did not specify what compensation the group was seeking. <ORGANIZATION> BSA </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> said the group would likely file additional lawsuits against several other companies in the months to come. `` The level of unauthorized copying of software in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> _ not only by dealers but by organizational users _ is one of the most egregious in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> said in a prepared statement. The breach had cost companies trying to develop and market legitimate software hundreds of millions of dollars, <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> said. Technical experts found evidence of widespread software duplication during inspections ordered by the Italian courts and conducted last week at two of the accused firms, <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> said. He said more than 90 percent of the software inspected at <ORGANIZATION> Montedison </ORGANIZATION> was reproduced without authorization and 80 percent of the software inspected at <LOCATION> Elettrocarbonium </LOCATION> consisted of unauthorized copies. Officials at the Milan-based Montedision and its affiliate have denied the charges. <ORGANIZATION> BSA </ORGANIZATION> officials did not know whether <PERSON> Elettrocarbonium </PERSON> had also denied the allegations. <ORGANIZATION> BSA </ORGANIZATION> was founded in 1988 to promote free and open trade in legitimate business software while protecting intellectual property. The consortium's membership also includes <ORGANIZATION> Aldus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Autodesk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Sausalito </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Microsoft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Redmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> WordPerfect </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Orem </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0625EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EmbarrassedNurse     04-08 0385</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Embarrassed Nurse,0396</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nurse Says School Ridiculed Her Weight</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PROVIDENCE, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A nurse has sued her former instructors for allegedly ridiculing her weight and using her as an example of how difficult it would be to care for an obese person. <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, now a nurse at All Children's Hospital in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Petersburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, sued <ORGANIZATION> Salve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and five faculty members contending they violated an implied contract by refusing to let her complete school, invaded her privacy and caused her emotional distress. She is seeking unspecified damages. <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> was told in 1985 that she would not be allowed to return for her senior year because she had failed to lose weight over the summer. <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> testified in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Court Thursday that instructor <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> once told her there was no uniform to fit her and said, `` You'll never make it around the bed because you're too big. Another instructor, Sister <PERSON> Maureen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hines </PERSON>, on one occasion `` had me get into bed to show -LRB- classmates -RRB- it's more difficult to make a bed with an overweight person in it,'' <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> said. `` I was embarrassed and humiliated.'' The nun also once grabbed her arm and said how difficult it was to give an injection through obese tissue, <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> testified. The nurse, who completed training at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joseph </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, in 1987, also contends the school should pay damages because she lost a year of prospective employment. <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Snow </PERSON>, the college's lawyer, said in his opening statement that the instructors `` knew better than she knew the physical demands that are placed upon a nurse in our society.'' <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> suffered from an eating disorder, was more than 200 pounds overweight and could not be fitted into a `` scrub gown,'' Snow said. He said the six unsatisfactory marks <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> received from her clinical instructors in 1984 all were related to her weight, but said she was ultimately given a passing grade in return for a promise to go on a diet. `` Time and time again she broke that promise,'' he said. <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> was allowed to register for her senior year only on the understanding she would diet during the summer, and she did not, <PERSON> Snow </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Salve </PERSON> <PERSON> Regina </PERSON>, a private college in <LOCATION> Newport </LOCATION>, is administered by the Roman Catholic Sisters of Mercy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0623EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NorthTrial     04-08 0425</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North Trial,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>North Says Administration Officials Knew of Hawk Shipments</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Administration officials knew at the time about a November 1985 shipment of missiles to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, according to <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s defense. During his examination Friday of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>, defense attorney <PERSON> Brendan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> brought out that top officials were given data from intelligence intercepts tracking the 1985 shipment almost hourly. North, examining one of the intercepts, noted the exact minute a plane touched down in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. North denied, however, that he falsely stated to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that no one in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government learned before 1986 that Hawk missiles had been shipped to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in November 1985. <PERSON> North </PERSON> testified that although he was at a meeting Nov. 20, 1986, where congressional testimony was discussed, he played no part in shaping prepared testimony. According to the evidence, those receiving summaries of such intercepts included national security adviser <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> or North and <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> or his deputy. Also receiving them were <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Caspar </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON>, and the chairman of the joint chiefs of staff <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Vessey </PERSON> and his deputy. <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> sat in on the Nov. 20, 1986, meeting which was intended to prepare him and national security adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> for congressional appearances on the <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> initiative the next day, according to testimony. The <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> participants brought to the meeting a proposed insert saying the spy agency had been told the shipment was oil drilling equipment. The <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> had arranged, at <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>'s request, to have one of its airlines transport the <ORGANIZATION> Hawks </ORGANIZATION> in 1985, but did so without first getting a presidential finding. North recalled that as the Iran-Contra affair unfolded in November 1986, he spoke to his former boss, <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON>, about the shipment of Hawks. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> said that it did n't happen, <PERSON> North </PERSON> said. `` You knew it happened?'' asked <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>. `` Yes sir,'' replied North. `` He called me up from <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and made it happen.'' In testimony during <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s trial, <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> had a different recollection. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> said <PERSON> North </PERSON> told him that `` he believed he and I had n't learned the precise details of what happened until'' 12 months after the shipment. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> said he doubted at the time of the 1986 conversation that <PERSON> North </PERSON> was correct, but that his own memory of the 1985 shipment was hazy so that he could n't contradict North. As a result, <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> said, he changed a chronology of the <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> arms shipments, removing a reference to the November 1985 shipment of <ORGANIZATION> Hawks </ORGANIZATION> and substituting instead a more general reference to other transfers of equipment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w BC-NorthTrial-Testimony 2ndAdd   04-08 0754</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-North Trial-Testimony, 2nd Add,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: be unlawful.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 SULLIVAN: When you were having the discussions with Mr. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> back in August and September of 1985 as to how to answer these congressmen, you were arguing to him that he should not respond. Did it ever occur to you that his response was unlawful? NORTH: No ... in fact, ... it never occurred to me the letter could be a violation of the law. SULLIVAN: Had you ever heard of a circumstance in which a letter from a <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> officer to a congressman would be the basis for a criminal charge? NORTH: No, these were political disputes. This was a political battle the likes of which I guess <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> has a lot of them. It was a nasty political dispute. It was politics at its worst but it never occurred to me, I've never heard of it before or since until this, that that kind of a thing could be unlawful. ... I mean my argument -LRB- against responding to <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> -RRB- was n't based on something being unlawful. My argument was based on the fact that if there's ever a chance to use this kind of privilege, authority, it ought to be used on this. ... it never occurred to me that it was unlawful. <PERSON> SULLIVAN </PERSON>: The next thing that happens, let's go to June 1986. What does the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> do at that time with regard to a resolution of inquiry? -LRB- The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> resolution formally requested information on North's activities. -RRB- What was the conclusion you drew -LRB- from this resolution -RRB-? NORTH: Well, the conclusion I drew is this was just one more chapter in this very bitter political dispute in which both sides were pulling out all the stops. ... -LRB- Our response was -RRB- the fact that we've answered these questions before, meaning Mr. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON>'s answers the year before ... -LRB- North then discusses an informal meeting with Rep. <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> in the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> situation room on Aug. 6, 1986. -RRB- SULLIVAN: What did that mean to you, informal? Off the record? NORTH: I guess my sense of it was that this was simply an effort to stop the inquiries ... SULLIVAN: Did you ever think you would be in a courtroom some day in 1989 being charged with a crime because of a meeting that occurred on August 6th, 1986, which was off the record, informal? NORTH: No, sir. SULLIVAN: Did you tell them the truth at that meeting on August 6th, 1986? NORTH: No. SULLIVAN: When you did n't disclose information they were looking at, did you believe that your conduct was unlawful? NORTH: No, I did n't think it was unlawful but I was raised to know the difference between right and wrong. I knew it was n't right not to tell the truth on those things, but I did n't think it was unlawful. <PERSON> SULLIVAN </PERSON>: How did you feel about being told by your boss to go into a meeting on August 6th, 1986? NORTH: I felt like a pawn in a chess game being played by giants. ... I had been told specifically that the Saudi aid that the president had gotten and that Mr. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> had gotten will never be revealed. And by this time we were also using monies from the sale of arms to the <LOCATION> Nicaraguan </LOCATION> resistance _ to the <LOCATION> Iranians </LOCATION> to help the Nicaraguan resistance, and that would never be revealed. <PERSON> SULLIVAN </PERSON>: Was it your understanding that if you answered frankly the questions that were asked in that session that it would lead to being confronted with having to reveal some of those things? NORTH: Yes, and that's why I did n't think that that meeting was a good idea. <PERSON> SULLIVAN </PERSON>: And did you tell Admiral <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> that? NORTH: I did. <PERSON> SULLIVAN </PERSON>: And what was his decision? NORTH: You can take care of it. -LRB- North describes exchanges in which his superior, Adm. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>, <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON>'s successor as national security adviser, discussed concerns that too many people were beginning to find out what <PERSON> North </PERSON> is doing in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. -RRB- NORTH: He ... told me that I ... must generate a cover story; just do n't be letting people know where you are going, what you are doing and why you are doing it. And so I did so. SULLIVAN: Now -LRB- <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> -RRB- speaks of `` operational roles''.. what did you understand it to mean NORTH: Well, he specifically said to me, that goes for the terrorism business, that goes for the hostage business, that goes for all the reasons that you're doing with the resistance.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0623EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RodeoBulls     04-08 0283</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rodeo Bulls,0289</SECOND>
<HEAD>Animal Rights Supporters Say Bulls At Rodeo Will Be Exploited</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ODESSA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Animal-rights activists say letting bulls loose in an arena with rodeo clowns will exploit and mentally torment the animals. `` It is morally, ethically and legally wrong to torment an animal to the point where it's going to charge you,'' said <PERSON> Raini </PERSON> <PERSON> Sequoya </PERSON>, president of the Tampa-based <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> `` If these clowns really want to have some fun, they should get in the ring and torment each other. Why pick on a helpless animal?'' But organizers of this weekend's <ORGANIZATION> Odessa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rodeo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Yukon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Days </ORGANIZATION> said nothing is wrong with the crowd-pleasing event. `` I do n't understand. Is waving a flag in a bull's face more cruel than getting on his back and riding him?'' said organizer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Burchell </PERSON>. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Professional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rodeo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cowboy </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, was taken aback by the criticism `` This is great. ... A clown goes out and stands in the middle of an arena and they let a bull out to chase him _ kind of like turning a bulldog loose on a mailman _ and people are worried for the bull,'' said <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON>. The event is for clowns to display their bravery and talent, he said. The clowns have 70 seconds to show judges how they avoid getting killed. They ca n't touch the bull or use weapons and have only a barrel to crawl into. The activists had vowed to seek an injunction to stop the event on the grounds that it breaks <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s 88-year-old animal cruelty law. But they had not done so by Friday, and were considering plans to file legal action after the event.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0624EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Flight103-Families     04-08 0668</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Flight 103-Families,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Families Of Flight 103 Victims Lambast `Callousness' Of U.S. Government</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Her voice trembling with pain and then anger, <PERSON> Eleanor </PERSON> <PERSON> Bright </PERSON> recalled her late husband and lambasted what she called the callousness of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials following the bombing of <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> Flight 103. `` After suffering the unimaginable loss of my husband, I have had to fight to get information. That's not right,'' said Mrs. Bright, the mother of a 19-month-old son, echoing complaints from other victims' family members. A <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> hearing room was hushed Friday, the only sound an occasional muffled cry from other family members, as the 32-year-old widow from <LOCATION> Brookline </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, told about the difficulties of getting information from the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> following the Dec. 21 terrorist bombing over <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> that claimed 270 victims. `` I call <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, I call <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, and in anger and frustration I call other victims,'' she told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Foreign Relations terrorism subcommittee. `` The stories never end,'' she said. `` Memorials unattended by <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials. Someone told to come ` pick up the shipment' when her husband's body arrived from <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>. Someone else watched as the body of her loved one was lifted off a platform using a forklift. One widow was told it was time to realize that her husband was dead and get on with her life.'' Mrs. Bright, unable to steady her voice, told a subcommittee headed by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>, D-Mass., of her own experiences _ how it was nine hours after the accident before the airline called, how the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> did not call for days and how the only answers at the accident scene in <LOCATION> Lockerbie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, came from Scottish officials `` I learned through my husband's employer that <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> was seated in seat 14A, directly over the bomb,'' she said. `` I need to know what that meant. Was he ever aware of what was happening? Was he ever afraid? Was he in pain? `` It was not until February that I learned by chance that an autopsy had been performed on <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON>. All of this information should have given by the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> or <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION>, but it was n't. Why were they silent? Instead of me being allowed to grieve for the loss of my husband, I was forced to seek out answers on my own.'' `` As my husband so strongly believed, there is a right answer and it's worth fighting for. The right answer is that we need a responsive, informative and compassionate <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>,'' Mrs. Bright said. `` It would not have taken a lot of manpower or dollars to have dealt with this differently.'' Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> defended the government's response, saying the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> had planned to contact next-of-kin, but <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> wanted to do it and the government has `` no legal authority to compel an airline to give us a passenger list.'' `` Our objective was to spare -LRB- the families -RRB- as much anguish as possible,'' she said. `` We refrained, however, from taking a more active role with family members for fear of intruding unnecessarily during that time of tragedy and shock.'' But she conceded that the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has `` learned a great deal from this experience'' and `` are reviewing our methods for handling crises and are making appropriate changes.'' She said the government is seeking an agreement with the major airlines to coordinate emergency action plans. In addition, the department has organized an 18-member special family liaison group to provide one-on-one information for each family of the Flight 103 disaster and is considering an 800 telephone number in disaster situations. <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> joined the family members in calling for a new policy to tell passengers about terrorist threats and to increase airport security checks even if it means much longer waiting times for passengers. <PERSON> Monte </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Belger </PERSON>, associate administrator at the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, said he believes new government regulations mandating devices to detect plastic explosives and other changes ordered in the wake of the Flight 103 disaster are sufficient.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0311EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TankerFreed     04-08 0321</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tanker Freed,0328</SECOND>
<HEAD>Exxon Tanker Runs Aground On Mississippi River; No Oil Spilled</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Tanker Spill, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB McKNIGHT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Powerful currents and a channel that's tough to negotiate may have been partly to blame for the grounding of an Exxon tanker on a sandbar in the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> official said. The 617-foot Exxon <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION>, carrying 13 million gallons of oil products, got stuck Friday on the muddy bottom near the mouth of the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. Four tugboats freed it after seven hours. No oil spilled from the ship. `` Where the river's at now, it's tricky down there,'' said Capt. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Klotz </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>'s district headquarters. <PERSON> Klotz </PERSON> said the river is rising and currents are powerful where the ship went aground _ a point where the main channel splits into three smaller channels emptying into the Gulf of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. He said the river is 38 to 39 feet deep there, though the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> tries to maintain a 45-foot depth. <PERSON> Klotz </PERSON>, who inspected the grounded <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wilmington </ORGANIZATION> from a helicopter, said checks of the ship's double hull indicated it was undamaged. The <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION> steamed Friday night to an anchorage in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> where <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> inspectors were to give its hull a final check for damage before letting it proceed to a refinery at Bayway, <LOCATION> N.J </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> is investigating why the <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION> ran aground. The ship was loaded with more than 8 million gallons of jet fuel and nearly 5 million gallons of other petroleum products, mainly paraffin. It took on the cargo at the <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> refinery at <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Reidy </PERSON>. It was the second Exxon tanker to run aground. On March 24, the <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valdez </ORGANIZATION> struck a reef in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> and spilled 10.1 million barrels of oil in the worst spill in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Gorbachev     04-08 0450</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gorbachev,0466</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Leader Ends Goodwill Tour By Inviting Queen To Moscow</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MAGGIE JACKSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> ended a six-day tour of <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> by announcing nuclear cutbacks and inviting <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> to visit <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said Friday that the queen gave `` a very definite yes,'' but that no date had been set. She would be the first British sovereign to visit the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> since the 1917 revolution. Her Russian ancestors _ the family of <PERSON> Czar </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> _ were slain by revolutionaries eight decades ago. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s invitation to the queen indicated his success in winning Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s trust. In addition, televised pictures of the <ORGANIZATION> Gorbachevs </ORGANIZATION> being escorted around <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Castle </LOCATION> by the 63-year-old queen and her husband, <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Philip </PERSON>, further warmed the royalty-loving British to the Soviet leader. Despite the invitation and the cordiality, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> disagreed on issues of nuclear disarmament and the balance of East-West forces in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, moreover, downplayed the importance of the Soviet leader's promise to halt production of weapons-grade uranium and shut down two more plutonium-producing reactors by the end of 1990. Nevertheless, she declared <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s third visit to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> `` very successful, warm and friendly,'' echoing his assertion that it had strengthened British-Soviet ties. The Gorbachevs' 40-hour British stay ended with a day steeped in pageantry. The president gave an unusually brief, 27-minute speech in the splendid setting of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s Guildhall, the 1,000-year-old seat of city government filled with city leaders in wigs and robes. In remarks broadcast live in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> called his proposals for cutting production of radioactive material `` another major step toward the complete cessation of production of fissionable materials for use in nuclear weapons.'' However, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> later ascribed little importance to the moves, saying existing Soviet stockpiles would mean the cutbacks `` will have no effect in practice.'' A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official said the weapons reactors could be started when the Soviet military runs low. The Soviet step followed <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s December announcement to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> would soon cut 500,000 soldiers from its standing army and withdraw troops and tanks from <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> and Chinese frontiers. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> lauded <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> for unilaterally eliminating chemical weapons stocks. He said his country had built a facility for destroying its own chemical weapons, and he would soon invite British experts to inspect it. The president also said the West should drop plans to modernize short-range nuclear missiles, but Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> maintained a nuclear deterrent was essential. After lunch at <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Castle </LOCATION>, the <PERSON> Gorbachevs </PERSON> were driven to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Heathrow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, where they flew home to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0314EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-08 0878</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0912</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STRUM, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jaimie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> only wanted a poster of <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruise </PERSON>, but the 8-year-old girl with muscular dystrophy got to have lunch with the popular actor instead. <PERSON> Jaimie </PERSON>'s date with the co-star of the Academy Award-winning movie `` Rain Man'' was arranged by <ORGANIZATION> Make-A-Wish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, a charity that grants wishes of children ages 2 -LCB- to 18 who have life-threatening illnesses. When applying to Make-A-Wish, <PERSON> Jaimie </PERSON>'s mother, <PERSON> Jacque </PERSON> <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON>, wrote that <PERSON> Jaimie </PERSON> saw Cruise's `` Top Gun'' 20 times and `` Cocktail,'' her favorite movie, twice. <PERSON> Jaimie </PERSON>, her parents and a friend flew to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> at the end of March to meet Cruise. `` She was real shy around him ... she hardly looked at him,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> said. `` The kids could n't think of a thing to ask him.'' Cruise talked about his newest movie, `` Born on the Fourth of July,'' about a paraplegic <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veteran, she said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BATON ROUGE, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The director of `` Blaze,'' a movie about the late Gov. <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON> and stripper <PERSON> Blaze </PERSON> <PERSON> Starr </PERSON>, says the film will treat a legendary portion of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> history with `` great tenderness and affection.'' <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON>, who directed `` Bull Durham,'' says the movie `` features two American legends who had their roots in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Starr </PERSON>, a stripper with whom Long had a scandalous affair 30 years ago, is serving as a consultant to the film, which stars <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> as the colorful governor in his waning days of office. The movie's script came from historical research and interviews with people who knew Long during the late 1950s and early'60s, when the governor created controversy by backing social welfare programs and voter rights, <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON> said. The movie, which begins filming Monday, is scheduled for Christmas release in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and general distribution in early 1990.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BERKELEY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> warned a crowd that `` war will not work'' as he dedicated the <ORGANIZATION> Berkeley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wall </ORGANIZATION>, two concrete slabs featuring painted ceramic tiles. The wall, two 4-foot-tall semicircular concrete arcs in a patio at Martin Luther King Jr.. Park, was the brainchild of local artist <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Marks </PERSON>, who calls it a `` basic human family quilt. The tiles came from more than a dozen countries, including the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, and carry slogans and artwork aimed at promoting peace. One read, `` Peace through learning about each other.'' Another said, `` Humanity is one.'' Some 2,000 people, from preschoolers to one elderly woman wearing a <ORGANIZATION> Gray </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Panthers </ORGANIZATION> button, gathered Friday under a bright blue sky in unseasonably warm weather to view the wall. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> compared the peace wall to the wall that separates East and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, saying: `` I look forward to the day when we can put tiles on the wall in <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. `` Our generation must be intelligent enough to give peace a chance,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MILWAUKEE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Talk is n't cheap when it comes to baseball announcer <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Uecker </PERSON>, former Gov. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Dreyfus </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> basketball announcer <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> McGuire </PERSON>, who have turned their silver tongues to gold by speaking their pieces for a price. A newspaper study found the going rates are $ 25,000 for <PERSON> Uecker </PERSON>, $ 7,000 for <ORGANIZATION> Dreyfus </ORGANIZATION> and $ 5,000 for <PERSON> McGuire </PERSON>. <PERSON> Uecker </PERSON> has little time for speaking these days, especially after suffering a mild heart atack in February. But when he does have time to squeeze in an appearance between taping his `` Mr. Belvedere'' television show and broadcasting <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brewers </ORGANIZATION> games, his appearance fee puts him in the range of such celebrities as talk-show host <PERSON> Oprah </PERSON> <PERSON> Winfrey </PERSON> and former Secretary of State <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>. Dreyfus, a Republican, left the governor's officer six year ago and his career as a lecturer has built steadily since then. <PERSON> McGuire </PERSON>, the former <ORGANIZATION> Marquette </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> coach, is especially in demand in the Southeast, according to his assistant, <PERSON> Jeannine </PERSON> <PERSON> McKeown </PERSON>. `` It's a basketball hotbed down there,'' she said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Phoenix </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Suns </ORGANIZATION> radio announcer <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON> was the iron man of the mike for 17 years, but his consecutive-game string has ended at 1,463. <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON>, the voice of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Basketball </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, contracted laryngitis after broadcasting <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>'s 114-104 win over <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> Wednesday night. He attended Thursday night's game at <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, but producer <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Schulte </PERSON> of radio station <ORGANIZATION> KTAR </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> handled the play-by-play. It was the first time in 17 years that <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON> did not do the broadcast. Suns officials said they are not sure if <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON> can recover in time to do tonight's game against the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clippers </ORGANIZATION> and start another streak.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Grateful Dead concert scheduled tonight will have beefed-up police presence because of violence at concerts in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> earlier this week. Thirty-three officers will be at Riverfront Coliseum, with 82 security officers and 60 ushers, said <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Rager </PERSON>, the city's assistant safety director Most of the 16,144 tickets sold went to out-of-towners, with almost 7,000 going to `` Dead Heads,'' as the group's ardent fans are called. They often camp out at concerts and trade tapes and souvenirs. Police in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> arrested 55 people, mostly on public intoxication and drug charges, at Grateful Dead concerts Sunday and Monday. <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> police clashed Monday night with a crowd of more than 500 who had surrounded the Civic Arena but did not have concert tickets.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w BC-NorthTrial-Testimony 3rdAdd   04-08 1003</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-North Trial-Testimony, 3rd Add,950</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: the resistance.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 -LRB- North resumes his testimony after a lunch break. -RRB- SULLIVAN: Would you read this letter. Is it a letter or the back and front of a postcard of some sort? Do you recall? NORTH: This appears to be a copy of a card with the front and back written on it, yes, sir. SULLIVAN: All right. Would you read that to the jury, please. This is from Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in November 1985. NORTH: It says, `` en route to <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>'s 11-29-85. <PERSON> Dear </PERSON> <PERSON> Ollie </PERSON>, as I head off to <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> for Thanksgiving, I just want to wish you a happy one with the hope that you get some well deserved rest. One with the hope that you get some well deserved rest. One of the many things I have to be thankful for is the way ... in which you have performed under fire in tough situations. `` Your dedication and tireless work with the hostage thing and with <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> really gives me cause for great pride in you, and thanks. Get some turkey. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.'' SULLIVAN: That was received in November 1985 ... correct? NORTH: Yes, sir. SULLIVAN: Now ... would you explain to the jury, please, how it is that you got involved in your office with trying to rescue hostages? NORTH: The hostage problem was part of the overall program of combating terrorism that the administration had, and it was a very important element of it because we had an increasing number of hostages being held. ... A consultant who was working for the <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION>, Mr. <PERSON> Ledeen </PERSON> ... had brought back from <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> information that they thought that they could achieve an opening to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, to moderate elements within the Iranian government, that there was great polarization, great disarray in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, that the Israelis were fairly sure of their information and had an agent working for them that could put us in touch with them. And it involved the exchange of certain <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> weapons to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> which could result in the release of both Israeli hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and the American hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. SULLIVAN: Colonel, would you explain why you are dealing with the country of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> if the hostages were in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>? NORTH: Within <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, there were several groups of Shia fundamentalists, Moslem fundamentalists who had political loyalty to the <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. ... and so the Israelis, and we agreed, though that if you could influence some of the more moderate elements in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to cut them off financially, or to convince them to turn loose the American hostages and the Jewish hostages that were being held, along with some other europeans like the French and Italians and British ... SULLIVAN: Were there missiles sent to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and did a hostage come out as a result? NORTH: Yes, it did. -LRB- The hostage was Rev. <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Weir </PERSON> -RRB- ... I took, at the direction of the president, a letter from the president to meet Mr. <PERSON> Weir </PERSON>, <PERSON> Reverend </PERSON> <PERSON> Weir </PERSON>; met with him; had a <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> airplane take me to the meeting, in an effort to assure <PERSON> Reverend </PERSON> <PERSON> Weir </PERSON> that his cooperation was necessary for us to be able to help rescue the other _ or recover the other hostages. -LRB- North describes how he continued meeting with Israeli intermediaries in an attempt to open up discussions with moderates in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in an attempt to gain the release of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hostages being held in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. -RRB- NORTH: I went and talked to Mr. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> about this in terms of how far we were going on this initiative and what role we were to play. And he told me simply that we were going to allow the Israelis to proceed with this, that it was their initiative and that we were to simply position the necessary people in the right places to be able to safely recover the hostages and be prepared for a high level meeting with the Iranians. <PERSON> SULLIVAN </PERSON>: Colonel, let's focus on the dates ... a little bit here. September,'85, <LOCATION> TOW </LOCATION> missiles are shipped, is that correct? NORTH: I believe so, yes, sir. ... SULLIVAN: You were not involved in the earliest stages of that, correct? NORTH: No, but at one point I did ask Mr. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> if the president approved it and he told me he had. -LRB- North describes a shipment of Hawk missiles to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> through the Israelis to get the hostages freed. -RRB- SULLIVAN: Were the transportation and logistical problems -LRB- with the shipment -RRB- eventually worked out? NORTH: Yes, they were from purely the transportation problem. But they were n't worked out as far as the Iranians were concerned. ... -LRB- the missiles -RRB- were eventually shipped and they did arrive in a city in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, not <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>, but another city, and it was n't the full 80 that they had asked for. It was only 18, I believe. <PERSON> SULLIVAN </PERSON>: And was it anticipated that hostages would be released as a result of this November,'85 Hawk shipment? NORTH: Yes, and we had gone to some lengths to position the appropriate people to receive them. ... we had no operational role in this other than to recover the hostages when they were released. We were n't planning any of this. We were kind of responding to it. SULLIVAN: Now, Colonel, focusing your attention after the Hawk shipment could you describe to the jury what problem arose after the <ORGANIZATION> Hawks </ORGANIZATION> arrived in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>? Did a hostage get out as anticipated? NORTH: On the November shipment, no. Apparently what the Iranians had been told by the Israeli agent was something different than what they expected. And they were to put it mildly very angry over what was delivered in that November shipment. The November shipment was 18 Hawk missiles and they had apparently expected something entirely different. ... the Iranians ... came back to the Israelis very, very upset about what had transpired and they said that they'd been cheated and that therefore nobody was going to be released, no Israelis, no Americans, no Europeans, nobody.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0316EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NuclearLicensing     04-08 0483</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuclear Licensing,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Major Streamlining of Nuclear Licensing Adopted by NRC</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> hopes its streamlining of the nuclear licensing process will keep the industry alive by cutting the time needed to build a nuclear power plant by roughly half. The new licensing procedures, approved by the five-member commission without dissent on Friday, have been under development for more than two years and have been the subject of hearings and briefings. The commission staff, utility executives and other analysts have said that there was no chance anyone would ever build another plant without some licensing simplification, although there is no sign that any utilities are close to seeking approval. The procedures try to resolve all major issues before a decision on whether to go ahead with a plant. They provide for advance approval of plant designs that could be used with little further examination, and of sites that utilities could designate far in advance of need. Also, the commission would go a long way toward the much-discussed `` one-stop'' license, issuing a combined construction permit and operating license. License applicants could still use the old procedure but the commission does not expect anyone to do so. Site approval would be good for 20 years. Without new legislation, which the commission has been unable to win, the procedure can not be completely one-stop. Under current law, the commission still will have to hold both a licensing hearing and a hearing after a plant has been built before it can be started. The new combined license would be issued only after safety and site issues such as planning for emergency evacuations had been resolved. The range of issues that could be raised at the second hearing on whether license conditions had been met would be narrowed, and <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lando </PERSON> <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> told reporters he did not think legislation was necessary now. At the second hearing, issues would be limited to allegations of `` material and uncorrected non-conformance'' with license conditions, or that `` adequate protection'' of the public is in jeopardy. Failure of state and local governments to cooperate in emergency planning has held up licensing of the completed <LOCATION> Shoreham </LOCATION> plant on <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Seabrook </LOCATION> plant on the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> coast. Under the new procedure, an applicant would have to show a `` good faith'' effort to win such cooperation in evacuation planning and that the plan could work even without it. These issues are not even considered under the current procedure until the plant is finished and the question before the commission is whether to allow operation. Huge cost escalations, a drastic slowing of growth in electricity demand in the past decade and fears generated by the partial core melt of the Three Mile Island plant in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> in 1979 and other accidents combined years ago to kill new orders for an industry that provides 18 percent of the nation's electricity.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Norway-SovietSub 3rdLd-Writethru   04-08 0680</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Norway-Soviet Sub, 3rd Ld-Writethru,a0430,0699</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Soviet Embassy Confirms Nuclear Sub Sank Off Northern Norway</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 15 grafs to UPDATE with oil slick, Russian vessels
at scene. Picks up graf 12 pvs, `It was ...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Soviet Sub</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OSLO, Norway (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Soviet Embassy confirmed that a nuclear-powered submarine suffered an underwater accident and sank in international waters off northern <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>, according to a radio report Saturday. Defense Minister <PERSON> Johan </PERSON> <PERSON> Juergen </PERSON> <PERSON> Holst </PERSON> said on Norwegian Radio that estimates of about 12 fatalities from the sinking Friday of the Soviet `` Mike'' class submarine appeared accurate. Some crewmen apparently were rescued, <PERSON> Holst </PERSON> said but he provided no details. A Norwegian Orion reconnaissance plane saw Soviet ships and planes circling the accident site north of the <LOCATION> Arctic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Circle </LOCATION> before nightfall Friday. A second <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION> passed over the area after midnight and spotted an oil slick on the sea, <PERSON> Holst </PERSON> said. He said a Soviet cruiser was en route to the scene, and that Norwegian vessels had made no attempts to approach the site, 118 miles south-southwest of <LOCATION> Bear </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Norwegian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> and 312 miles off <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>. Norwegian experts were meeting Saturday morning to discuss the situation and keep the government informed about the possibility of a radiation leak, the broadcast said. By Saturday, more than 12 hours after the accident, there was no word on the accident from the Soviet government or the official <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency. The sea is 6,600 feet deep at the site of the sinking, and <PERSON> Holst </PERSON> said there was `` no hope'' of raising the sub from the bottom. Military officials in <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> said it appeared the boat caught fire underwater before breaking up and sinking. The submarine, nicknamed `` Mike'' by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>, carries a crew of 95, is powered by two nuclear generators and is reportedly equipped with torpedoes and long-range ballistic missiles, Western sources say. The West German government radio also quoted <PERSON> Holst </PERSON> as saying pilots of reconnaissance planes reported seeing bodies at the site. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said there `` definitely'' were casualties aboard, but declined to estimate how many. `` The only thing we saw was an oil slick about three to four hundred meters long by 50 to 100 meters wide,'' Capt. <PERSON> Haavard </PERSON> <PERSON> Holm </PERSON>, the Orion reconnaissance pilot, said on Norwegian Radio after flying over the accident site. He said there were three Russian ships and one aircraft in the area, including a trawler, a freezer ship and what appeared to be an observation or intelligence vessel. <PERSON> Holst </PERSON> said he doubted the Soviets had sent the cruiser to keep other ships away. `` They want to have as much support as possible and want to transfer the survivors and the possible dead,'' he said. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> officials said earlier that the reconnaissance plane had seen Soviet planes and boats, including rubber dinghies with people in at least one of them. It was not clear whether the people were from the submarine or the surface vessels. `` With the observations we have made with the Soviet vessels and planes in the area, it seems the Soviets can handle this case alone,'' <PERSON> Holst </PERSON> said. The area is well above the <LOCATION> Arctic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Circle </LOCATION>, but is usually ice-free because of the Gulf Stream. Temperatures in the area were near-freezing on Friday. The `` Mike'' is one of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s modern submarines, and the only one in operation, according to <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>'s Fighting Ships, the British reference book. If Western descriptions of the submarine are accurate, `` the reactors are well-protected and have less radioactive material than in older submarines.'' said <PERSON> Johan </PERSON> <PERSON> Baarli </PERSON>, director of <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radiation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> He said on national radio that any radioactive material probably would remain in the sub and not escape into the sea. Norwegian and Swedish defense sources estimate the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has about 110 nuclear submarines operating in northern waters from bases on the <LOCATION> Kola </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>, one of the world's heaviest concentrations of naval power. The `` Mike'' might carry 16 missiles for surface targets, although the figure is unconfirmed, said Swedish <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Gur </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890408-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-89 0325EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DC-DrugWar     04-08 0469</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-DC-Drug War,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Prepares Massive Effort Against Drugs in Capital</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
