<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 2333EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-D'AmatoCase     11-27 0209</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-D'Amato Case,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Committee Switches Counsel</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ethics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> said Monday it has changed its outside counsel in a case involving Sen. <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, R-N. The committee hired former federal prosecutor <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schuelke </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> attorney, to replace <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, who is still handling two other cases for the committee. The committee announcement said <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, also of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, advised the panel last week that his law firm's diverse practice could lead to an appearance of conflict of interest in the <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON> case. Details of how such an appearance could arise were not given. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>'s election opponent in 1986, has filed a complaint with the committee accusing him of breaking <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rules in the <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> scandal and other matters. <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON> has denied any improprieties. <PERSON> Schuelke </PERSON> will take over <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>'s role of helping the committee determine whether to proceed with a formal investigation, a review that is expected to take several months. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> is still the committee's outside counsel in conducting a similar review in a case involving five senators who interceded with banking regulators on behalf of a contributor whose savings and loan was collapsing. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> also is the committee's counsel in an investigation of a book deal by Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>, R-Minn.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 2341EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     11-27 0516</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0535</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Back to the Future' Sequel Zooms to Box-Office Records</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HORN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> is feasting on the record $ 27.8 million earned by `` Back to the Future Part II'' in its Thanksgiving-weekend debut. The sequel to the 1985 hit knocked another sequel out of the record books as the highest-grossing Thanksgiving release, according to figures released Monday. `` Rocky IV'' grossed $ 20 million during the Friday to Sunday period in 1985. For the long holiday weekend that began Wednesday, `` Back to the Future Part II'' collected $ 43 million and set single-day admission records on Wednesday and Thursday, with grosses exceeding $ 7.2 million each day. But the strong opening of the film starring <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> and directed by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Zemeckis </PERSON> failed to surpass the all-time three-day opening record, set this year by `` Batman'' with $ 42.7 million, according to <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. Total movie house revenues for autumn hit a record of $ 832 million, up 24 percent from last fall Thanksgiving business for the top 10 was more than $ 78 million, up 50 percent from 1988. <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s gangster film `` Harlem Nights'' dropped to second place with ticket sales of $ 11.1 million from Friday through Sunday, down 31 percent from the previous weekend. Disney's animated hit `` The Little Mermaid'' rode a rising tide of popularity to surge 39 percent last weekend, making $ 8.4 million to come in third. The baby-rearing comedy `` Look Who's Talking'' earned $ 7.9 million to claim fourth place. In fifth was the ensemble drama `` Steel Magnolias,'' which collected $ 7.1 million. In sixth was another animated film, `` All Dogs Go to Heaven,'' grossing $ 5 million. The Christmas-themed reindeer movie `` Prancer'' came in seventh with $ 4.1 million. In eighth place was the sentimental drama `` Dad'' on $ 2.9 million, followed by `` The Bear'' with $ 2.3 million and `` Crimes and Misdemeanors'' with $ 1.5 million. Here are the top movies for Friday through Sunday as tallied by Entertainment Data and Exhibitor Relations. Figures are based on a combination of actual box-office receipts and studio projections where actual figures are not immediately available. 1. `` Back to the Future Part II,'' Universal, $ 27.8 million weekend gross, 1,865 screens, $ 14,925 per screen, $ 43 million total gross, one week in release. 2. `` Harlem Nights,'' Paramount, $ 11.1 million, 2,180 screens, $ 5,108 per screen, $ 34.9 million, two weeks. 3. `` The Little Mermaid,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 8.4 million, 999 screens, $ 8,393 per screen, $ 16.8 million, two weeks. 4. `` Look Who's Talking,'' Tri-Star, $ 7.9 million, 1,651 screens, $ 4,771 per screen, $ 96.6 million, seven weeks. 5. `` Steel Magnolias,'' Tri-Star, $ 7.1 million, 720 screens, $ 9,797 per screen, $ 15.6 million, two weeks. 6. `` All Dogs Go to Heaven,'' <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 5 million, 1,590 screens, $ 3,152 per screen, $ 11.2 million, two weeks. 7. `` Prancer,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION>, $ 4.1 million, 1,717 screens, $ 2,361 per screen, $ 7.8 million, two weeks. 8. `` Dad,'' Universal, $ 2.9 million, 1,188 screens, $ 2,465 per screen, $ 15.1 million, five weeks. 9. `` The Bear,'' Tri-Star, $ 2.3 million, 1,054 screens, $ 2,224 per screen, $ 23.5 million, five weeks. 10. `` Crimes and Misdemeanors,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.5 million, 525 screens, $ 2,777 per screen, $ 13.2 million, seven weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 2342EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CBS     11-27 0219</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CBS,0224</SECOND>
<HEAD>Changes Announced at CBS Morning and Late-night Shows</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, trying to raise the low ratings of its late-night and morning shows, is putting a veteran sports producer with `` The Pat Sajak Show'' and two new reporters on `` CBS This Morning.'' <PERSON> Sajak </PERSON>'s talk show will be getting <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Weisman </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sports </ORGANIZATION> producer for 15 years, as co-executive producer. <PERSON> Sajak </PERSON> is the other executive producer. <PERSON> Weisman </PERSON> has won 10 Emmy awards for his sports telecasts. The reporters joining `` CBS This Morning'' are <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Kmetko </PERSON>, of <ORGANIZATION> KCBS-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Freedman </PERSON>, formerly of <ORGANIZATION> KRON-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kmetko </PERSON> will report on the entertainment industry but continue at <ORGANIZATION> KCBS </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Freedman </PERSON>, who will be a features reporter for the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> show, will be based here. CBS announced the staff changes Monday. A spokesman also said that director <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Bogdanovich </PERSON>, who had reviewed videocassettes of classic films and interviewed film figures for CBS' morning show, is leaving the program. The show, co-anchored by <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, is a distant third in ratings against <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s top-rated `` Today'' show and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Good Morning America.'' <PERSON> Sajak </PERSON>'s show also has struggled in the ratings since its Jan. 9 debut. It began as a 90-minute program, but on Oct. 30 was cut back to an hour each night.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChickenMan     11-27 0655</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chicken Man,0674</SECOND>
<HEAD>Entrepreneur Wants to Put Contact Lenses on Chickens</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TONY ROGERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WELLESLEY, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON> had it all _ a <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> M.B.A. </ORGANIZATION>, a profitable computer software company. But he sold his firm to follow a dream, a dream to one day supply contact lenses to all the world's egg-laying chickens. Wise's red contact lenses are already on 100,000 chickens nationwide, and his company, <ORGANIZATION> Animalens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, is growing. Oh, sure, people laughed at first. `` We'd talk to investors. They'd say: ` Sounds neat. Good luck,''' Wise recalls. But while Wise is willing to joke a little about his enterprise, he's all business when it comes to discussing the future, which he says looks sunny side up. Before writing Wise off as a cuckoo, understand that there is a sound idea behind his scheme. Chickens become positively mellow when they see the world through rose-tinted glasses _ or better yet, fire-engine red contact lenses. Scientists are n't sure why, but a rosy outlook eliminates the pecking order among chickens, which normally tend to be pretty ornery critters. Red-eyed birds spend less time fighting and more time laying eggs. They also eat less. According to <PERSON> Wise </PERSON>'s calculations, that translates into an annual savings of at least 50 cents a chicken, or 2.5 cents per dozen eggs. With 1.2 billion laying chickens multiplied by the 20 dozen eggs each yields a year, the savings could be $ 600 million. With such benefits, Wise is sure farmers will soon flock to buy his contact lenses, which go for a modest 20 cents a pair, or 15 cents if bought in bulk. The hard lenses are put in place in seconds by holding the bird's head steady. They stay in place for the life of the bird, or about a year. `` The challenge is to go out and sell the product, especially when it's new and different,'' Wise says. `` This certainly falls into the category of being new and different.'' The idea for the lenses goes back to <PERSON> Wise </PERSON>'s childhood on the chicken farm his father managed in northern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> in the early 1960s. Wise's dad, <PERSON> Irvin </PERSON>, tried to produce lenses for chickens after a salesman told him about a farm where chickens afflicted with cataracts behaved better than those with normal sight. `` But the technology did n't exist at the time for the lens to work,'' explains Wise, 41. `` The early lenses blinded the chickens.'' The elder Wise's fledgling company folded. His son went off to college, worked in the shipping industry for a time and then founded a computer software firm in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> eight years ago that prospered. But the chickens and the lenses were still on his mind. Three years ago he sold his company for several million dollars and set out to pursue his dream. `` I got out of computers because of this,'' Wise says. `` And I still do n't miss computers. I've believed in this for a long time.'' Not that everything has flown smoothly since jumping from computer software to chicken eyewear. The lenses had to be painstakingly designed so they would n't distort the chickens' vision or irritate their eyes Wise keeps a jar in his office filled with hundreds of pairs of failed test lenses that looks like a container of jelly beans. `` I look at that and I think ` That's all behind us,''' Wise says. `` We already know a lot someone else would have to figure out.'' Eventually, a usable lens was developed. Wise contracted with several small plants around <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> to produce the lenses, and field tests were conducted on farms around the country. Now, Wise says, the testing is over and it's time for his dream to fly. `` I'm very confident,'' Wise says from his firm's small suite of offices in this affluent <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> suburb. `` 1990 is going to be the inflection point for us, when this really takes off.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 0042EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugsInSchools     11-27 1032</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drugs In Schools,1058</SECOND>
<HEAD>Schools Seek Various Ways To Discourage Drug Use</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TAMARA HENRY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> school principal <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Nesbit </PERSON> became suspicious when two students who had been suspended for illicit drug use passed a drug test with little trouble. `` We found out a couple of weeks ago that there's a chemical that washes drugs out of the system,'' said <PERSON> Nesbit </PERSON>, whose school _ <LOCATION> Spring </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> High </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> _ has received national acclaim for its drug-fighting efforts. `` The students use it full time: washing out their systems and being tested, all the time being high.'' The street name of the chemical is `` Golden Seal,'' said <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> teacher <PERSON> Leroy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, explaining the `` herb'' also is popular with students in the nation's capital. This latest student scam is proof that the war on drugs in schools is serious and must be waged in a no-nonsense but flexible manner, <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said. `` Kids recognize all the problems of the system,'' said <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government teacher at <ORGANIZATION> Spingarn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. `` They know how to circumvent us better than we know how to plan.'' The battle to keep the nation's youngsters away from drugs has evolved from a mere `` Just Say No'' slogan, devised by former First Lady <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, to a threat by the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration to end federal aid to schools, colleges and universities tat fail to document tough policies against illegal drug use. The tougher approach reflects the nation's growing concern with drug abuse. Statistics say that 5 percent of high school seniors drink daily and more than 60,000 adolescents ages 12 and 13 have tried cocaine. `` Young people show a faster propensity to develop an addiction and the damage by addiction can be more permanent,'' said <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parents </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resource </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>. The government is expected to spend some $ 500 million under the drug education program this fiscal year, about $ 180 million more than the year that ended Sept. 30. In 1986, only $ 3 million was budgeted for drug education. Almost all high schools and 87 percent of elementary schools offer some sort of anti-drug lessons. The new national drug strategy says school-based prevention programs should be reinforced by tough policies on use, possession and distribution of drugs. Schools are trying a variety of approaches with no clear trend emerging. Success is hard to determine since so many of the approaches are new. In <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, football players are tested. <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> laws allow spot searches of students, and <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> plans to use drug-sniffing dogs in the schools. <LOCATION> Jefferson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, schools notify police of every campus drug incident, suspend students for six to 10 days for drug possession or use, and transfer repeat offenders. The <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> has decided any student convicted of trafficking in or possessing drugs, on or off school property, will be subject to expulsion. `` Drug Free Zone'' signs surround public and private schools in Prince <PERSON> Georges </PERSON>' County, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, warning that anyone found possessing or distributing drugs within 1,000 feet of a school yard faces strict penalties, ranging from 5 to 40 years in prison. Education officials estimate as many as 25 states have some sort of drug-free zone programs or laws. `` We see more expulsions and suspensions for use because it's against the law,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Better </PERSON>, staff director of the Education Department's Drug-Free Schools Recognition Program `` But most schools have referral and re-entry programs.'' At the local level, Education Department officials estimate 73 percent of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s 16,490 school districts have written policies against substance abuse. Of these, more than 90 percent involve notification of parents and or police, suspension or counseling. Most major education groups avoid advocating specific drug policies for schools. At most they offer general guidelines, like those jointly developed by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administrators </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nurses </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` We have problems when the feds try to impose decisions on the locals, so national groups avoid doing the same thing,'' said <PERSON> Lew </PERSON> <PERSON> Armistead </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Secondary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Principals </ORGANIZATION>. Hall, vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parents </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resource </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, said: `` We do n't believe in dealing with these people as criminals. You really ca n't incarcerate your way out of a drug problem.'' Hall pointed to statistics that say `` school buildings or campuses are one of the least popular places'' for students to use or distribute drugs. Also, he said, students tend to use drugs more at night and on weekends. `` PRIDE supports treatment on demand,'' said Hall. `` But the problem is it's difficult to draw the line on whether the school is responsible or the parents.'' <PERSON> Nesbit </PERSON> insisted: `` It is a school problem because they ca n't learn when they are stoned They ca n't learn when they're dead. They ca n't learn when they're in the hospital. We're going to be paying for their rehabilitation forever and ever because so many people are hooked.'' <PERSON> Nesbit </PERSON> said his drug-fighting efforts encompass more grassroots approaches of `` sending out letters of complaints to local liquor stores that sell alcohol to minors'' to encouraging temporary suspensions for drug use and automatic expulsion for drug sales. In addition to the <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>'s citywide policies, <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> offers early-morning tutoring for students who want help with school work and `` to talk about what's going on with them, with somebody they want to trust.'' Jenlane Gee, a teacher from <LOCATION> Modesto </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> _ recognized along with <PERSON> Nesbit </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> as among the nation's best teachers and principals _ complained that the government's drug-fighting efforts have ignored elementary schools. Gee, who teaches third graders at <ORGANIZATION> Christine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sipherd </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, said just as much emphasis should be focused on the elementary schools because studies show that children usually decide by the third to fifth grade whether to experiment with drugs. <PERSON> Nesbit </PERSON> added that simply talking _ or acting _ tough wo n't stem student drug use. `` I think there's a hard line'' emerging in the schools, he said. `` But there's no comprehensive policy that helps kids to make good decisions about their future, their bodies and their values.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Gorbachev-Surprises     11-27 0629</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gorbachev-Surprises,0646</SECOND>
<HEAD>Western Leaders are Learning to Expect the `Gorbachev Surprise'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL PUTZEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> broke the mold of dour, intransigent Soviet leaders during his first foray onto the world stage, and he's been surprising now-wary Western counterparts ever since his 1985 summit with <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. Based on his past performance, there's every reason to believe that the 58-year-old <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> might spring a surprise on President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> when the two meet off <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> on Dec. 2 and 3 _ so much so that <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> officials say extensive preparations are under way to prepare the American president for anything that might be thrown at him. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reform policies in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> have been surprising enough to Americans. His style leans to the unexpected, as well. When <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> posed for pictures at the start of their meeting in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> four years ago, the American president kept mum, heeding his advisers' counsel not to take a chance on spoiling the atmosphere of his first U.S.-Soviet summit with an offhand remark. The Russian showed no such caution. When a reporter told <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> he had been described by a fellow Soviet official as a man with a nice smile but iron teeth, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> replied: `` I'm still using my own teeth, but as to the substance of your question, both the president and I have good grounds to believe we can have a good talk.'' Later the same day, after his tete-a-tete with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> stretched well beyond the carefully choreographed schedule, the Soviet leader broke a comment blackout imposed by both sides. `` I think we will have a good relationship,'' he said. At the last snap summit, in <LOCATION> Reykjavik </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iceland </LOCATION>, in 1986, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> went prepared to negotiate the framework for a treaty reducing intermediate-range nuclear missiles. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> instead proposed eliminating all nuclear weapons in all categories. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> took him up on the challenge, and the two men engaged in what was later described as history's highest-stakes poker game, seeing and raising each other one weapons category after another until they stumbled over the last chip: <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s beloved Star Wars plan. The American refused to concede; the Soviet insisted it was all or nothing. And nothing it was. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s advisers have let it be known the new <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president will not let himself be drawn into a game like that at the summit off <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>. But as recently as last May, when Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> went to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> expecting to set a date for the next U.S.-Soviet summit, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> caught the new foreign policy chief off guard with a bold new offer of substantial cuts in conventional forces in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. The initiative broke a years-old logjam over how to count and reduce the two sides' non-nuclear ground and air forces in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. But it embarrassed <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, who was unprepared for such a move, and gave <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> a public relations coup. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, facing criticism that he was slow and indecisive in developing a policy toward the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, recovered at the end of the month with his own conventional arms proposal announced at a <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> summit in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>. But six weeks later, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> pulled another trick out of his hat. As the leaders of the seven great industrial democracies gathered in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> for their annual economic summit, they received a letter from <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> appealing for entry to the world economic community. After decades of cold war and economic rivalry, the Soviet chief wrote that his effort to restructure the Soviet economic and society `` is inseparable from the policy tending toward full and entire participation in the world economy.'' His letter instantly became the central focus of the summit talks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador-War     11-27 0915</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador-War,0940</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bloody Offensive Previews More Carnage</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP Extra</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The two deadliest weeks of the 10-year-old civil war have served only to set the stage for more bloodletting. The battle of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> _ at least the first one _ is over. The huge rebel offensive that began Nov. 11 failed to achieve its principal objective of persuading the government to make significant concessions in the quest for a negotiated solution. Indeed, with the administration claiming victory and demanding what amounts to the rebels' surrender, and the insurgents promising to finish off `` the mortally wounded fascist beast,'' Salvadorans can only expect weeks or months more of warfare of an intensity unseen since early 1981, when the rebels' first `` final offensive'' failed. `` This battle against ARENA is a battle that can not turn back, a battle to sweep fascism once and for all from our country,'' the rebel clandestine <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Venceremos </ORGANIZATION> said late last week. ARENA is the rightist <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION>, the governing party. `` They -LRB- the guerrillas -RRB- tried, and they lost,'' President <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> said, proclaiming the military defeat of the <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION>. The government contends its forces killed or wounded a third of the rebel army, estimated at about 7,000 full-time combatants. Most foreign journalists who spent day after day in the combat zones doubt the official claim that more than 1,000 guerrillas were killed. The figure appears inconsistent with the relatively few dead guerrillas seen by reporters who daily compared notes on what they saw where and when. <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> says the decimation suffered by guerrilla forces has been so telling that they will be capable from now on of only `` terrorist'' actions. The contention is suspect, as the president, the defense minister and every colonel who went on record in the months prior to the spectacular push said the same thing: that insurgent capacity had been reduced to isolated terrorist activity. <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> acknowledged in an interview after the fighting waned last week that the guerrillas `` are doing some things that look more like regrouping than withdrawing.'' Radio Vencermos on Friday referred to the 10-day concerted assault on the capital and several provincial cities as `` the first period of offensive,'' implying that others are in the offing. The war began in late 1979, but its roots go back decades. <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> is the smallest country on the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION>'s mainland With 5 million people in an area the size of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, it is also the most densely populated. The consolidation of landholdings by relatively recent immigrant families _ not of the centuries-old Indian-Spanish mix that makes up more than 90 percent of the population _ disenfranchized hundreds of thousands of peasants who raised subsistence crops on collectively held village lands. Landless peasants became migrant peons who went seasonally from the coffee harvest to picking cotton to cutting cane _ the workforce of an economy that was almost completely dependent on the export of those three products. The agricultural export economy made vast fortunes for a tiny elite. The rich have mansions on their plantations, sumptuous homes in the capital's posh western sector and houses or apartments in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. They tune in to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> television stations with their satellite dishes and send their children to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> universities while the two-thirds of the population lives in dire poverty. Peasants and workers organized widely in the 1970s. By the end of the decade, left-leaning federations demanding profound structural reform to more equitably distribute wealth were regularly putting tens of thousands of people in the street. They probably constituted, if counted together, a plurality of Salvadorans. The growing left threatened the privileged, who reacted ferociously. About 30,000 people _ most of them real or perceived leftists _ are estimated to have been slain by government troops or right-wing death squads between 1979 and 1984, when such murders began to decline. Repression combined with the vast majority's manifest lack of economic opportunity to create a fertile field for revolutionary harvest. The government and its <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> patron _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> has provided <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> $ 4 billion in aid this decade _ contend a fledgling democracy is on its feet. The left says intimidation, persecution and murder still await those who avow social change. On Nov. 16, armed men broke into the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> campus residence of six Jesuit priests and educators who had been labeled subversive ideologues by the radical right. The gunmen killed the priests, their housekeeper and her teen-age daughter. Other Jesuits at the school say witnesses saw army troops enter the residence before the shots rang out. The government and guerrillas sat down in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> in September to discuss peace for the first time in two years. They met again in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> last month, but the sessions were strained and fruitless. <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> last week urged the rebels to admit their defeat, `` come to their senses, lay down their arms and incorporate themselves in the democratic process.'' Asked if that scenario was realistic, <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> said: `` It may not sound realistic to the <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION>.'' The Rev. <PERSON> Ignacio </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin-Baro </PERSON> _ one of the slain priests _ was vice-rector of the university and head of its prestigious polling institute. His recent surveys showed that the majority of Salvadorans were personally uncommitted to the program of either the government or the insurgency. The only cause that commanded majority support was peace.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-UkrainianCatholics     11-27 1045</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ukrainian Catholics,1078</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ukrainian Catholics Look to Pope-Gorbachev Meeting for Legalization</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARK J. PORUBCANSKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LVOV, U.S.S.R. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A priest who is Russian Orthodox by necessity, not choice, stood before his congregation in the Cathedral of the Transfiguration on a recent Sunday and proclaimed allegiance to Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>. <PERSON> Yaroslav </PERSON> <PERSON> Chukhny </PERSON>'s words echoed from <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, long competitors for the souls of <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. They are certain to reverberate back to the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> when <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> on Friday becomes the first Soviet leader to meet a Roman Catholic pontiff. The 35-year-old priest took the boldest step yet in a revolt against the forced consolidation of the small <ORGANIZATION> Ukrainian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> into the Russian Orthodox Church in 1946. After his proclamation, he said the Ukrainian church `` does exist and it has legalized itself.'' <PERSON> Chukhny </PERSON> never considered himself Russian Orthodox. He attended a Russian Orthodox seminary in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> because it was the only path to the priesthood. Ukrainian Catholics who kept the faith underground for two generations see the <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> trip as a sign they will regain legal status as a separate denomination. With that will come a chance to reclaim confiscated churches and property, including <PERSON> Chukhny </PERSON>'s cathedral, and an element of national identity in an area that was part of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> before World War II. `` I think <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is a cunning guy, and he would n't go to meet the pope with nothing in his pockets,'' said <PERSON> Miroslav </PERSON> <PERSON> Soltys </PERSON>, a 44-year-old communications engineer and Ukrainian Catholic. `` Behind two or three locked doors, I think the church already has been legalized.'' In the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, religious groups need government approval. Ukrainian Catholicism, with an estimated 2.5 to 5 million followers in the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION>, does not have it, and many followers have been fined or imprisoned. Expressing the Russian Orthodox Church's resistance to legalization, Metropolitan Filaret of <LOCATION> Kiev </LOCATION> said the Ukrainian church had been a `` source of national, social and religious oppression'' during its nearly 400 years. After <PERSON> Chukhny </PERSON>'s proclamation, <PERSON> Soltys </PERSON> and other believers took over the Cathedral of the Transfiguration, where Ukrainian Catholics are dominant in the congregation. In his liturgy for Sunday, Oct. 29, the priest acknowledged the spiritual leadership of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> and prayed for him instead of Patriarch <PERSON> Pimen </PERSON>, head of the Russian Orthodox Church. He recalled in an interview later: `` I told them I had gone over to the <ORGANIZATION> Greek </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. I said, ` Forgive me if you do n't agree, but I do n't feel any allegiance to the Russian Church.' <ORGANIZATION> Greek </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> is another name for the Ukrainian church. <PERSON> Chukhny </PERSON> said the religious tenets of the Russian Orthodox and Ukrainian Catholic churches are much the same, and the only real differences are in language and the ultimate superior. Believers keep a constant vigil inside the <LOCATION> Kiev </LOCATION> cathedral to prevent the Russian Patriarchate from taking it back. On a Sunday in November, several thousand people pressed into the church and about 100 more strained to hear the service from the steps. Russian Orthodox officials accused Ukrainian Catholics of taking over by force and have revoked <PERSON> Chukhny </PERSON>'s right to preach in the Russian Church, but they have not tried to recover the green-domed cathedral built just before the Bolshevik Revolution of 1917. `` I'm a religious person,'' said the bearded young priest. `` I've never been interested in politics, but what I did has taken on a political coloring.'' Ukrainian Catholicism has been colored by politics ever since a 16th century agreement gave the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> supremacy over believers in the Ukrainian and <LOCATION> Byelorussian </LOCATION> territory then controlled by <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. The church kept the ancient Orthodox ritual, and even its name reflects centuries of turmoil. It is known variously as the <ORGANIZATION> Greek </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Ukrainian </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Uniate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. After being separated from the rest of the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION> for nearly 600 years, the <LOCATION> Lvov </LOCATION> area was reunited with it by force half a century ago. After <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> attacked <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> on Sept. 1, 1939, <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> sent the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> into eastern <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. After the war, the areas were incorporated into the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The Ukrainian <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, accused of collaborating with the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION>, was merged with the <ORGANIZATION> Orthodox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, which took over its property and buildings. Among the priests who led the merger program, which Soviet and Russian Orthodox officials insist was voluntary, was <PERSON> Gavriil </PERSON> <PERSON> Kostelnik </PERSON>, pastor of the same Cathedral of the Transfiguration. Priests who refused to switch were sent to prison camps, where many died. <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Gel </PERSON>, who now leads the lay <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> to Support the Ukrainian <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, was imprisoned 18 years for nationalist and human rights activities and for supporting the church. Resistance to <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> rule in the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION> was such that bands of anti-Soviet guerrillas operated in the woods and mountains until the mid-1950s. Gel was released in January 1987, and as <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms loosened control of religion, Ukrainian Catholics became bolder. Services in private apartments were replaced by open rallies and demonstrations, but organizers often were fined or jailed. Ukrainian Catholics have reopened as many as 40 churches, and Gel said other priests are following Chukhny's lead. In Gel's life, as in the region, the church is part of the ethnic sentiment of a people dominated at various times over the centuries by Russians, Swedes, Poles, Lithuanians, Austrians and Hungarians. Ukrainians credit the church with keeping their language alive and accuse the Russian Orthodox Church of being cowed by whatever power rules <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>. `` We need a return to freedom of religion in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> as a principle right of a citizen in a democratic country,'' Gel said. `` Renewal of our nation, renewal of our church, is part of the process of decolonization of our people.'' `` A people without a church can not be sovereign.'' Gel said. He sees the Ukrainian church playing the role of the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> _ a center of resistance to Communist rule. That could worry the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>, which faces demands for greater autonomy or outright independence in regions along its western border. As for the Russian Orthodox Church, <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Filaret </ORGANIZATION> wrote to the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> News: `` You do n't need to be clairvoyant to understand that the restoration of the former <ORGANIZATION> Uniate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> will lead to religious and political struggle.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 0008EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-India 5thLd-Writethru a0786 11-27 0914</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-India, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0786,0935</SECOND>
<HEAD>Returns Show Opposition Ahead Of Governing Party</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Updates vote results and deaths (nne more death reported) grafs
2-7. Opposition seats in 3d graf includes National Front and three other
parties. Pickup 8th graf: The election commission...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SHARON HERBAUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Early election returns Monday showed opposition parties forging ahead of Prime Minister <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, threatening the family dynasty that has dominated independent <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> Reports by government-run television said the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> was leading in more races than any single opposition party but was falling short of enough seats in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> to form the next government without entering a coalition. The television network said that final results in 246 of the 524 contests gave the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> party 103 seats while the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> coalition </ORGANIZATION>, the major opposition force, and a fundamentalist <ORGANIZATION> Hindu </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> party </ORGANIZATION> and two communist parties captured 112. Smaller parties and independent candidates won the other seats. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> is no longer going to be the majority in the next government,'' the television commentator said. `` Who will form the next government and who will be the next prime minister is going to take some time to determine.'' The election campaign that began in October was the most violent since <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> gained its independence from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> in 1947. Balloting in the vast nation was staggered over three days _ Wednesday, Friday and Sunday _ and it was uncertain when final official results would be reported. Millions of ballots were ruled invalid by the election commission, including those cast in 18 percent of the precincts in <LOCATION> Gandhi </LOCATION>'s home district of <LOCATION> Amethi </LOCATION>, and it ordered that new elections be held Monday. By the time voting ended in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 25 states and seven federal territories, at least 137 people including six candidates had been killed in election-related violence since Wednesday. The election commission ruled there was widespread ballot-rigging, voter intimidation and murderous assaults and ordered new elections Monday in one-fifth of the country's 590,000 polling booths. The election was seen as a referendum on <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s leadership since he assumed power in 1984 amid hopes he could lead <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> toward a new age. While the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> was expected to sweep the southern states, it appeared to be in serious trouble in the north, its traditional stronghold. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> still could emerge as the single largest party, making it the likely choice to try to form the next government of the world's largest democracy. But it would be forced into an uneasy alliance with Hindu fundamentalists or the communists. The National Front coalition, led by former <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> ally <PERSON> Vishwanath </PERSON> <PERSON> Pratap </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, was running in second place. It was followed by the right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Hindu </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bharatiya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Janata </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> India-Marxist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. At stake in the elections were 524 seats in the 543-seat <LOCATION> Lok </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sabha </LOCATION>, or House of the People, the policy-making lower house of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> that will choose the next prime minister. Voting was postponed in several districts because of incomplete voter lists or candidates' deaths and the other 19 seats will be determined in later elections. Opinion polls had indicated <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> would win from 170 to 220 seats, far short of the 267 needed for a majority. The party 415 seats in the December 1984 elections that propelled <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> to power. The <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> accepted `` under protest'' the <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>'s order for new balloting in <LOCATION> Amethi </LOCATION>, said party spokesman <PERSON> Anand </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharma </PERSON>. He denied the allegations of fraud and said they were a plot to embarrass <PERSON> Ghandi </PERSON> who has represented the district since 1980. But the decision dealt a stunning blow to <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>, who had been expected to easily win re-election to <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. Although voter fraud is common in Indian politics, never has a re-vote been ordered in the prime minister's own backyard. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s position already had been weakend by criticism of his leadership and reports of high-level corruption in his government. Defeat for <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>, the grandson of Prime Minister <PERSON> Jawaharlal </PERSON> <PERSON> Nehru </PERSON> and son of Prime Minister <PERSON> Indira </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>, could herald the end of the dynasty that has governed <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> for all but 29 months since it became independent. The election will be won or lost in the Hindi heartland, the northern states of <LOCATION> Rajasthan </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Madhya </PERSON> <PERSON> Pradesh </PERSON>, <PERSON> Uttar </PERSON> <PERSON> Pradesh </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Haryana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bihar </LOCATION>, which together control more than half the seats in the <LOCATION> Lok </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sabha </LOCATION>. Neither Congress nor the opposition adopted a platform calling for major changes in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s domestic or foreign policy. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s leadership became the main issue of a bitter campaign that claimed at least 182 lives since it began in October The 45-year-old prime minister portrayed the election as a simple choice between stability and chaos. Only the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> _ the party of his mother and his grandfather _ could provide economic improvement and fight the ethnic and religious tensions threatening the country's unity, he said. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, a coalition of five parties with regional, religious and ideological differences, capitalized on accusations of high-level corruption and ineptitude and promised honest and efficient leadership. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> was propelled to power hours after his mother's assassination Oct. 31, 1984 He promised to clean up <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s notoriously corrupt and inefficient bureaucracy, liberalize the economy and initiate reforms that would attack poverty and illiteracy and prepare <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> for the 21st century But the initial aura inspired by the youthful <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>, a Cambridge-educated former airline pilot, faded as allegations of corruption dogged his friends, his party and his government.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 0301EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--BirthdayWhale     11-27 0162</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Birthday Whale,0168</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baby Shamu Celebrates First Birthday</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN ANTONIO, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The four-day party for <PERSON> Baby </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamu </PERSON> ended with the killer whale extinguishing a candle on her birthday cake with a playful squirt. `` We've had a pretty exciting weekend here with her,'' said <PERSON> Thad </PERSON> <PERSON> Lacinak </PERSON>, director of animal training for Sea World of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. `` She's quite a ham.'' The 1,100-pound whale, who turned 1 Sunday, is the first Texas-born killer whale and the fifth born in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The others were born at the Sea Worlds in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Baby </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamu </PERSON> has been performing some routines with her mother, <PERSON> Lacinak </PERSON> said. But this was the first time the baby whale held center stage alone. She does head stands, fast swims, flipper waves and bow jumps out of the water, he said. Its mother, <PERSON> Namu </PERSON>, is taking her child's newfound independence quite well, <PERSON> Lacinak </PERSON> said. `` Just like people it depends on the personality of the parent,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 0058EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Finland-Soviet Bjt   11-27 0757</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Finland-Soviet, Bjt,0777</SECOND>
<HEAD>Finns Mark 50th Anniversary Of The Winter War</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATTI HUUHTANEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HELSINKI, Finland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fifty years ago, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> invaded <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> and met the fierce `` ghost army'' of white-clad ski troops whose gallant fight in a hopeless cause was admired around the world. The Finns lost the 105-day war to their huge neighbor, but memories of their courage helped make their independence secure after World War II. `` The Russians were badly organized and stuck out like sore thumbs against the white snow in their dark uniforms,'' said Capt. <PERSON> Toivo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahjopalo </PERSON>, who was a junior artillery officer on the shores of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ladoga </LOCATION> on the Karelian isthmus. Although the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> soldiers were well equipped, their strategy and planning were poor. <PERSON> Ahjopalo </PERSON> said his artillery unit of two 57mm guns killed 1,600 Soviets in 48 hours. `` It was too easy ... almost shameful to kill them,'' he said. `` The Russians kept coming at us in straight lines and our two guns picked them off like flies. The frozen lake was awash with blood.'' A new Finnish movie called `` The Winter War'' will open Thursday, the anniversary of the outbreak of what may have been the coldest war in history. Several books and articles on the war also have been published recently. In the era of glasnost, Soviet historians have increased their casualty figures from fewer than 50,000 Soviet soldiers killed to 74,000, with more than 200,000 wounded. The official Finnish estimate of total Soviet casualties is nearly 1 million, a number also hinted at in the memoirs of <PERSON> Nikita </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON>, the former Soviet leader. <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>, a nation of 3.7 million in 1939, suffered 22,000 soldiers killed and 43,000 wounded. On Nov. 26, 1939, Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Vyacheslav </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Molotov </PERSON> accused Finnish troops of shooting across the border near <LOCATION> Mainila </LOCATION>, a village in southeastern <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>. The Finns denied it, and Soviet historians now say <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> used the incident as a pretext to invade <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> four days later. `` It looks very likely that <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> ordered the shots to be fired by his own troops,'' said <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Dongarov </PERSON>, a Soviet Foreign Ministry researcher. `` The Soviets were worried about developments in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and a possible German attack on their territory through <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>. Besides, there was great anti-Russian feeling and mistrust in <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> at the time.'' <PERSON> Dongarov </PERSON> spoke with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> during a visit to <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION>. The Winter War was fought in temperatures as low as minus 49 degrees. The severe cold caused frostbite and hallucinations that forced guard duty tours to be reduced from two hours to 30 minutes. <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> had occupied <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> in 1938, and in secret negotiations with the Finns, <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> demanded the right to build fortifications in the Gulf of <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> to protect <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> rejected that and other Soviet demands as violations of its sovereignty. Negotiations broke down after 18 months. The Finns still did not believe <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> would attack, but Field Marshal <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Gustaf </PERSON> <PERSON> Mannerheim </PERSON> mobilized more than 180,000 men near the border for what was called `` refresher training.'' `` I was literally admiring the sky above <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> when suddenly, totally unexpectedly, Russian planes broke through the clouds and dropped their bombs,'' said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Sjoblom </PERSON>, who covered the war for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. Minutes later, he scrambled out of a bomb shelter and found the mangled remains of his bicycle in the street. When the Finns had fought for three months against the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, which sent in 450,000 soldiers at the start of the war, they were suffering from lack of reserves and ammunition. After a Soviet offensive in March 1940, <PERSON> Mannerheim </PERSON> rejected an offer of aid from the Western powers as `` too little too late,'' and recommended a negotiated peace. A treaty was signed March 12 that forced <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> to cede large areas of eastern <LOCATION> Karelia </LOCATION> to the Soviets. More than 400,000 Karelians had to be evacuated. `` The Winter War demonstrated once again that, when a great power is faced by a small nation whose only goal is to survive, calculations of strength can not be based on pure arithmetic,'' wrote <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobson </PERSON>, a former Finnish ambassador and statesman. `` In the vast drama of World War II, it was but a short episode. <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>, like a recalcitrant pawn, refused to move to the square assigned to it by those who controlled the chessboard. ... Finally, it had to submit to fate.'' Fifteen months after the battle ended, <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> went to war with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> again, on the side of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--SumoWinner     11-27 0112</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Sumo Winner,0115</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hawaiian Takes Japanese Sumo Title</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FUKUOKA, Japan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 488 lb. Hawaiian on Sunday won the <LOCATION> Kyushu </LOCATION> Grand Sumo Tournament. <PERSON> Salevaa </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuauli </PERSON> <PERSON> Atisanoe </PERSON>, known as <PERSON> Konishiki </PERSON>, thrust Sekiwake Kotogaume out of the ring to clinch the tournament championship. The 25-year-old wrestler received a message from President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, telling him he gave all Americans something to boast about. The only other foreign wrestler ever to win a major tournament in the traditional Japanese sport, fellow <PERSON> Hawaiian </PERSON> <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuhaulua </PERSON>, told <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, `` I am more joyful than when I won the championship'' in 1972. <PERSON> Atisanoe </PERSON> started in football, starring at fullback for a <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> prep school team.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     11-27 0690</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0718</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gere </PERSON> has been devoting a lot of time in recent years to his <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> beliefs. But that did n't stop him from portraying a couple of old-fashioned bad guys in upcoming films. The 40-year-old actor, who has done little acting since his acclaimed performance in 1982's `` An Officer and a Gentleman,'' says in the current issue of Fame magazine that he has been supporting the cause of Tibetans, who have been under Chinese occupation since 1950. `` They are a gentle, spiritual people who have been systemically murdered by the Chinese,'' said <PERSON> Gere </PERSON>, who, along with composer <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Glass </PERSON>, founded the <ORGANIZATION> Tibet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> for Himalayan exiles in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> two years ago. <PERSON> Gere </PERSON>, best known for his sex-symbol roles in films such as `` Looking for Mr. <PERSON> Goodbar </PERSON>'' and `` American Gigolo,'' is a student of the exiled <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON>, this year's Nobel Peace Prize winner. `` His Holiness has been through so much,'' he says. `` His strength is ... He's just unbelievable.'' <PERSON> Gere </PERSON> himself, however, will soon be seen playing characters with a less-than-holy nature. In the soon-to-be-released `` Internal Affairs,'' <PERSON> Gere </PERSON> stars as an amoral career cop opposite <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>'s good guy investigator. And March is the scheduled release for `` 3,000,'' in which <PERSON> Gere </PERSON> stars as a ruthless Wall Street speculator.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HARRISON, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former first lady <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> greeted more than 100 alcoholism specialists from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> as part of a two-week exchange program on treatment of the disease. The Soviets, including physicians, treatment center directors, recovering alcoholics and celebrities, were met Sunday by Mrs. <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> at <LOCATION> Westchester </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. `` Alcoholism is the most treatable of our primary diseases,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> told her guests. `` I hope that this conference will lead to more joint communication with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and that our discussions will become even broader in scope.'' A spokeswoman for the Soviet-American Conference on Alcoholism, <PERSON> Kristen </PERSON> <PERSON> Jensen </PERSON>, said the conference will include tours of treatment centers throughout the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, including the <ORGANIZATION> Betty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treatment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in Rancho Mirage, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. Last April, an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> delegation attended a conference on alcoholism in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Frenchman <PERSON> Philippe </PERSON> <PERSON> Noiret </PERSON> won the best actor prize at the 1989 European Film Awards, better known as the <ORGANIZATION> Felixes </ORGANIZATION>, for his roles in the French film `` Life and Nothing Else'' and the Franco-Italian `` Paradise Cinema'' <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> claimed the best actress award for <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Leigh </PERSON>'s `` High Hopes,'' a satirical look at Thatcherite <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. The jury headed by Norwegian actress <PERSON> Liv </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullmann </PERSON> chose `` Landscape in the Mist,'' a movie about two boys searching for their father, as best film. The director, <PERSON> Theo </PERSON> <PERSON> Angelopoulos </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>, received the prize late Saturday at a theater on the Champs Elysees. The presentation was the highlight of the second annual awards competition among film makers from 27 countries. The film was chosen ahead of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s `` Little Vera,'' <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s `` Eldorado,'' <LOCATION> Iceland </LOCATION>'s `` Magnus,'' <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION>'s `` Memories of the Yellow House,'' and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s `` High Hopes.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge has given permission to the guardians of Sir <PERSON> Rudolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Bing </PERSON> to sell his possessions to pay for the care of the aged and ailing former head of the Metropolitan Opera. State Judge <PERSON> Eve </PERSON> <PERSON> Preminger </PERSON> gave the order Friday after <PERSON> Bing </PERSON>'s court appointed guardian, <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Korn </PERSON>, told her that <PERSON> Bing </PERSON> will have no more than $ 11,000 in cash by the end of the year <PERSON> Korn </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bing </PERSON>'s monthly expenses are about $ 14,500, for upkeep and pocket money, and his income from social security, his pension from the Met, and other sources total about $ 8,500 a month. <PERSON> Bing </PERSON>, 87, has Alzheimer's disease and lives in the Hebrew Home for the Aged. Three years ago, <PERSON> Bing </PERSON>'s net worth was estimated at $ 900,000, but much of that was depleted by legal and security expenses required for his protection from former psychiatric patient <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglass </PERSON>, 49, whom he married in 1987. On Sept. 5, state Judge <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ciparick </PERSON> annulled the marriage after finding that <PERSON> Bing </PERSON> suffered serious mental impairment because of Alzheimer's disease, and therefore was not capable of agreeing to a marriage contract.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 0055EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     11-27 0510</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0526</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PASADENA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The `` 14th Occasional Pasadena Doo Dah Parade,'' a tacky ensemble of floats such as the Hibachi `` grill team'' and a outhouse with <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION>'s wife inside, weaved through the streets before 50,000 people. Unlike the traditional Rose Parade, Sunday's <PERSON> Doo </PERSON> <PERSON> Dah </PERSON> boasted few rules, no queen and no formal judging, and featured marchers carrying briefcases, lawn furniture and snow shovels. The highlight was the <PERSON> Great </PERSON> <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Drill </PERSON> <PERSON> Team </PERSON>, in which several women and one burly man, all dressed as <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON>, re-created the actress' infamous policeman-slapping incident with men dressed as <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> motorcycle officers. Other favorites were The <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Chainsaw Massacre Drool Team of the Living Dead Dishonor Guard, featuring marchers with live, running chain saws _ with chains removed. There were several Exxon Valdez floats, including one operated by roller skaters who kept falling down and yelling, `` The reef, the reef.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Barbecue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Hibachi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marching </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Team </ORGANIZATION> members banged on barbecues with metal tongs behind a drum major with an ice chest around his neck. Replicas of bathroom fixtures were popular among entrants, including a <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION> who drove a bike equipped with an outhouse, whose door would open to expose a compromised Mrs. <PERSON> Claus </PERSON>. The <PERSON> Doo </PERSON> <PERSON> Dah </PERSON> parade was first held Jan. 1, 1978, when the Rose Parade was switched to Jan. 2 to avoid being held on a Sunday. Last year's event was the 12th parade, creating some confusion over why this year's was dubbed the 14th. `` Well, this is the ` occasional' parade, and 40 or so of my friends celebrated <PERSON> Doo </PERSON> <PERSON> Dah </PERSON> 13 with a pub crawl along the parade route on New Year's Day, while I was out of town,'' self-proclaimed <PERSON> Doo </PERSON> <PERSON> Dah </PERSON> <PERSON> Czar </PERSON> <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Apanel </PERSON> explained.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>GAINESVILLE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The cultivators of 200-pound radishes and watermelons the size of small deer will get official recognition soon, thanks to new registry for green-thumbed growers. `` Most of the calls I get have been, ` Is this the biggest pumpkin, tomato or whatever?''' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON>, a specialist with the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>. `` People will call up and say they have a 200-pound radish and ask if it is a record, and we'd have to say we did n't know. But <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON> has developed rules and procedures for harvesting and measuring about 30 varieties of vegetables grown in the state. Already, records have been established with a 10-pound cabbage, a 16-pound, 8-ounce cantaloupe, and a 146-pound watermelon. One of the secrets of growing a super vegetable is to extend its growing season, and that will make most vegetables tough and stringy. The texture of a giant radish, for instance, resembles wood pulp. <PERSON> Clyde </PERSON> <PERSON> Bumgardner </PERSON>, a retired air conditioning expert in <LOCATION> Levy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, was credited with producing <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s champion watermelon this past summer. `` That's the one that has the official record, but the year before I had one that was 170 pounds,'' said <PERSON> Bumgardner </PERSON>, 72. `` The world record is 270 pounds so I've got a way to go.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Panama Bjt   11-27 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Panama, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>General Says His Ouster From Panama Was Political</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYNA BRENNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The former head of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> says the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration ousted him from his post in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> for political reasons because he opposed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policies in that country. `` I believe the policy was flawed,'' Gen. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON> said in an interview in which he described the administration's goals as simplistic and short-sighted. `` The specific language was, the president decided it was time for a change,'' <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON> said in describing how <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> told him in July that he was being removed. `` And then when I said I was entitled to more of an explanation ... I was told it had nothing to do with performance but -LRB- was for -RRB- political reasons.'' <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON>'s contention contradicts the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s denial in July when it announced he was being replaced. <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON>, a longtime Latin American hand who retired from the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> earlier this month, left his post as head of the command just days before the failed Oct. 3 coup attempt to oust Panamanian Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. During the attempted overthrow, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops blocked two roads in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, spoke with the rebel leaders and watched the firefights from their hillside vantage point. Several congressional leaders contended later that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should have stepped in to oust <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON>, who generally opposes <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troop intervention, added, `` The president, I think, in his handling of the last major event, the failed coup, demonstrated his lack of willingness to commit troops.'' The American government started pushing for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s ouster after a series of demonstrations in 1987. The move heightened when the Panamanian general was indicted on drug-trafficking charges in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1988. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has repeatedly said he is not giving up on efforts to get <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> out of office. The president also has said he considers <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to be the problem _ not the <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> heads _ and that if <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is forced out and free elections are held, the country will have `` instant improved relations'' with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON> said that in the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's policy, `` There was a lot of heat generated but not necessarily sound policy or strategy to support <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. interests.'' He said the goals of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration were short-term: get <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> out and restore democracy. `` You link those two together and you have what the administration believed was an easy objective,'' <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON> said. `` That means you put your policy ... in the hands of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. If he stays your policy fails. If he goes, you succeed,'' <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON> said. `` I know <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>; I did n't want to put the success or failure in his hands.'' The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy assumed <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s ouster would remove the problem, but <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON> contended it only would create `` a promotion for the next thug.'' The general said his remarks were seen as being soft on <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. `` It is very difficult to speak out on <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in a position contrary to the administration's without appearing to be soft on <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>,'' he said. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> does have to be deposed for democracy to succeed, he conceded, but added the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy can not stop there. <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON> said he sought a plan calling for an internal opposition group, strong <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support for that group and international condemnation of the situation. `` I do not believe a problem of this magnitude can be solved by external forces in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` And we ca n't just transfer a democratic ideal or objective. `` I said we were greatly underestimating <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s staying power. And that was not a popular position to take,'' <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON> said. The answer is not military intervention, he said, adding: `` We could intervene and take out <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. That's the easy thing. It's getting out and leaving something behind to say those American military men that lost their lives changed <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> for the better.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 0128EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MaleNanny     11-27 0356</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Male Nanny,0371</SECOND>
<HEAD>New England School Graduates Its First Male Nanny</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto BX1</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WESTFIELD, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Another cultural stereotype will self-destruct when the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nannies </ORGANIZATION> graduates its first male nanny. <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> <PERSON> Stack </PERSON>, 18, of <ORGANIZATION> Westfield </ORGANIZATION>, will complete the 3 -LCB- - month program Dec. 15 Stack's sense of humor helped him in a similar situation _ in high school when he was the only male in a preschool child care class. Now, it has helped him parry the jests of friends who ca n't help asking if he wants to be <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Poppins </PERSON>. After graduating from <ORGANIZATION> Westfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> last spring, Stack did n't want to go to college, and ruled out military service. Instead, he opted for the nanny program, which he learned about during a job fair. `` The military keeps calling me, but I say, ` I'm going to be a nanny, not a Marine,''' he said. The $ 300 a week, plus room and board that he could earn as a live-in baby sitter, appealed to him. `` My pay goes into my pocket,'' he said. Besides, `` I love kids. They're awesome.'' <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Lord </PERSON>, vice president and director of admissions for the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nannies </ORGANIZATION>, said about 250 women have graduated from the 5-year-old school. Stack will be its first male graduate. `` We're quite proud of him. He's holding up the grades and he wo n't be hard to place,'' <PERSON> Lord </PERSON> said. `` It raises some eyebrows when men come into a field like this, like male nurse,'' Lord added. `` We've tried males before, they're uncomfortable about being the only male in the class <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON>'s going to break the door open.'' Stack said the program focuses on the business side of being a nanny as well as teaching child care and child psychology. To his surprise, a nanny can expect to have health insurance and taxes paid by the employer. He acknowledges that since men have traditionally avoided such occupations, some people question his motivation. But <PERSON> Stack </PERSON> said he's determined to be treated as a professional care giver. `` Hey, it's practice,'' said <PERSON> Stack </PERSON>, who wants to have children some day. `` A nanny is a practice parent.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Uruguay 2ndLd-Writethru   11-27 0845</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Uruguay, 2nd Ld-Writethru,a0780,0868</SECOND>
<HEAD>Governing Party's Presidential Candidate Concedes Defeat</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Leads with 6 grafs to UPDATE with early official results showing
Lacalle leading. Lacalle comment. Pickup 4th graf `Equipos Consultores...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto MVD1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED McCULLOUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MONTEVIDEO, Uruguay (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An opposition presidential candidate led in early returns Monday after the governing party's hopeful conceded defeat. <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Batlle </PERSON>, candidate of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said Sunday night before official returns were released that he had lost the race to <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Lacalle </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Both parties are center-right and both candidates have promised to trim down an atrophied welfare state in this small <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> country of 2.9 million people. `` According to the information available, the future president will be Sen. <PERSON> Lacalle </PERSON>, to whom I extend my most sincere congratulations and best wishes for success in his term,'' said <PERSON> Batlle </PERSON>, whose name is pronounced BAHT-lee. <PERSON> Lacalle </PERSON> said he would issue a public statement on Monday, but acknowledged that he had received congratulatory calls from President <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanguinetti </PERSON> and <PERSON> Liber </PERSON> <PERSON> Seregni </PERSON>, presidential candidate for the leftist <ORGANIZATION> Broad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>, issuing the first official returns shortly after midnight that results from 152 of the 8,493 voting stations gave 10,170 votes or 39 percent to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, 8,040 votes or 30 percent to the <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and 3,547 votes or 13 percent to the <ORGANIZATION> Broad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, a coalition of leftist parties. <ORGANIZATION> Equipos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Consultores </ORGANIZATION>, a respected independent polling agency, projected the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> received 38 percent of the total vote, compared to 31 percent for the <ORGANIZATION> Colorados </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Equipos </PERSON> did not state how many votes its projection was based on. The leftist coalition <ORGANIZATION> Broad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> tallied 22 percent of the vote nationwide, according to <ORGANIZATION> Equipos </ORGANIZATION>, and the front's cndidate for mayor of the capital <LOCATION> Montevideo </LOCATION>, Marxist doctor <PERSON> Tabare </PERSON> <PERSON> Vazquez </PERSON>, won that coveted post. <PERSON> Batlle </PERSON> acknowledged that the `` trend indicates a majority for the <ORGANIZATION> Broad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>'' in <LOCATION> Montevideo </LOCATION>. `` That trend is irreversible,'' he said. `` The next mayor of <LOCATION> Montevideo </LOCATION> will be <PERSON> Tabare </PERSON> <PERSON> Vazquez </PERSON>.'' At stake were the presidency, the vice presidency, the posts of 30 senators and 99 deputies, and governments in 19 provinces. A win for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> would be the first time it took power since 1967 and only the third time this century. Uruguayans voting to replace <PERSON> Sanguinetti </PERSON> and both houses of congress said their main concern was invigorating an economy that has been in decline for three decades. `` Things are n't going to change if politics do n't take a turn and politicians look for something different,'' said <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON>, a 63-year-old retiree. `` When we look at the outside world, there have been tremendous advances,'' said <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> <PERSON> Larghero </PERSON>, 47, a graphic designer. `` The opposite has occurred here. We deteriorate a little bit each year.'' Election officials anticipated a turnout of 90 percent or better of the 2.32 million Uruguayans eligible to vote. Radio stations reported that 21 percent had voted by 11 a.m. In the last elections in 1984, the main issue was who could best lead <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> back to democracy after a 12-year military regime that trampled human rights, stifled political opposition and ran the economy to the ground. <PERSON> Batlle </PERSON>'s great-uncle, <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Batlle </PERSON> y <PERSON> Ordonez </PERSON>, forged modern <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> during his presidencies in 1903-07 and 1911-15. Using huge surpluses from beef and grain exports, <PERSON> Batlle </PERSON> y <PERSON> Ordonez </PERSON> established the 8-hour work day, a minimum wage, retirement pensions and paid vacations. <PERSON> Batlle </PERSON>'s father, <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Batlle </PERSON> <PERSON> Berres </PERSON>, used reserves built up during World War II to promote local industry by blocking imports during his 1947-51 presidency. He also expanded social programs. Today, public education through college is free. The state provides mortgages and insurance as well as pensions, runs the banking system and employs 270,000 Uruguayans, or about one-quarter of the work force. However, salaries are so low that teachers, bus drivers and others frequently go on strike, retirees can hardly live on their pensions, and the quality of public services has declined. Teachers earn about 84,000 pesos -LRB- $ 110 -RRB- a month. The gross national product, now $ 8 billion, and real wages recovered modestly under <PERSON> Sanguinetti </PERSON>. But inflation, now at 82.5 percent, did not. Unemployment, at 14 percent in 1985, is down to 9 percent. <PERSON> Lacalle </PERSON> and <PERSON> Batlle </PERSON> pledged to reduce inflation, balance the national budget, sell gold reserves and pay off some of <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>'s $ 6.3 billion foreign debt, and sell inefficient public companies They also pledged to open the economy, encourage competition through deregulation, and restrict the right of organized labor to strike. <PERSON> Lacalle </PERSON> took the lead in public opinion surveys, analysts said, partly because he convinced voters he would seek solutions gradually on the basis of negotiation, not right away or by force. <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>'s aging, politically conservative population includes 650,000 retirees. A majority of voters are 40 years old or more. <PERSON> Lacalle </PERSON>, a 48-year-old attorney and senator and a member of a prominent political family, pledged to form a coalition government and said he would offer Cabinet posts to leaders of other parties. The new president takes office March 1, 1990, and <ORGANIZATION> congress </ORGANIZATION> and the departmental governments begin Feb. 15.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     11-27 0817</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Food Prices Expected to Rise Again Next Year</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Food prices will go up again in 1990 but farm exports probably wo n't. Crop production may equal or exceed this year's output, but that will depend on the weather. It's forecasting time at the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> when hundreds of bureaucrats, economists, consultants, researchers, commodity traders, bankers, food processors and even a few farmers gather to hear the latest predictions. Many foreign governments, notably the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and members of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> also watch the annual conference for tidbits that may help their agricultural trade fortunes. The department's 66th annual conference, Outlook'90, will run from noon Tuesday to noon Thursday. During that time, dozens of general sessions and individual meetings will cover the overall international and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> domestic situation, plus separate sessions for various commodities and other topics. Much of the outlook for 1990 already has been described in general terms by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> analysts in recent reports. For example, consumer food prices, which rose 4.1 percent in 1988, probably climbed about 6 percent this year, the sharpest annual increase since 1981. Analysts have been saying the 1990 increase wo n't be that sharp _ if there is normal weather. The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> also reports that agricultural exports, which provide much of the financial base for farmers, did well in 1989, reaching almost $ 40 billion, the most since the record $ 43.8 billion in 1981. But exports in 1990? Department analysts have been saying those will be down because of lower prices and reduced volumes expected for some key commodities. The net cash income of farmers rose to record levels in recent years, peaking at $ 59.9 billion in 1988. This is the money farmers have left over in a calendar year after deducting cash expenses from gross cash income. However, 1989 net cash income will drop to a range of $ 52 billion to $ 57 billion, according to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> economists. That reflects greater expenses from more cropland being put back into production this year, along with sharp declines in government payments. The outlook for 1990 farm income will depend greatly on national and international weather and crop situations, particularly for wheat, soybeans and feed grains. Livestock expansion _ or contraction _ also will reflect crops and markets. Thus, the conference will attempt to fill in many of the gaps concerning the supply and demand for commodities in the coming year. But those are n't the only concerns. `` Conditions affecting farmers and rural Americans will be an important focus of Outlook'90, with such topics as farm finance, new action on rural development, rural transportation policy, the well-being of rural families and children, and housing for older farm workers,'' organizers said. Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> will keynote the conference on Tuesday afternoon and will participate in discussions on the federal budget, national economy and the financial health of agriculture. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Donald </PERSON>, chairman of the department's world agricultural outlook board, will review the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and world outlook for agriculture. Various commodity briefings and discussions are scheduled for Wednesday, along with rural development and forestry. Another highlight will be <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s formal 1990 outlook for food prices by economist <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr </PERSON>. The concluding meetings on Thursday morning will include sessions on dairy and farm financial prospects, and global trade policies. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> is scheduled to lead discussions on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade negotiations and how those are expected to affect American farmers.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, for years the No. 1 overseas buyer of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> grain and other farm commodities, is turning into a lucrative market for pet food. An <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report says Japanese pet food imports increased five-fold from 1984 to 1988, reaching a value of $ 173.8 million. And the report by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> says the trend is expected to continue. The leading foreign suppliers are <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, with a 38 percent market share; <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, 27 percent; and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, 24 percent. Overall, including domestic production, pet food sales in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> are expected to double in the next five years, the report said. Total dog food sales were valued at $ 467.3 million in 1987; cat food, $ 359.3 million; fish food, $ 34.3 million; and bird seed, $ 9.8 million. `` Many new pet food products, especially upscale gourmet treats, have been introduced,'' the report said. `` The rapidly strengthening yen makes imports more price-competitive.'' Another factor has been the promotion by foreign pet food manufacturers, who have set up subsidiaries in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. Also, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> eliminated all tariffs on pet food imports on April 1, 1989. Japanese pet owners traditionally relied on leftovers to feed their pets and have started buying products specifically made for pets only in recent years. `` By 1987, 30 percent of the pet owners in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> had purchased pet food,'' the report said. `` This compares with more than 70 percent in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and most European countries.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Kemp-Housing     11-27 0355</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Kemp-Housing,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>HUD Chief May Seek Line-Item Veto Test Case</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> may get his chance to test whether courts will approve a line-item veto, if Housing Secretary <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> has his way. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said Sunday he may ask the president to test a line-item veto on housing projects earmarked for funding by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> over the administration's opposition. `` I am going to do everything I can to make sure that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> does not earmark monies, including asking the president to perhaps test on a line-item veto those programs which heretofore have just been shoved down our throat by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Meet the Press. The chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> did not say which specific programs would be involved. On Oct. 24, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> was seeking legislation on which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> could exercise a line-item veto _ and then allow the courts to decide whether he acted legally. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> told reporters at that time: `` We are looking for a vehicle that might be a suitable test case, but at this point we do n't have one.'' Congressional Democrats contend that under the Constitution, presidents do not have line-item veto authority, and they have vowed to challenge any such move by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in court. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> was questioned about a $ 4.2 billion housing initiative which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> announced on Nov. 10. Unlike congressional housing proposals, the president's program _ called Home Ownership Opportunities for People Everywhere, or HOPE _ would not provide any money for new construction of low-income housing. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said the administration plan concentrates on promoting ownership because `` at the heart of the American experience and dream is the desire to own a home and we're going to do everything we can to reorganize <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> with an eye on giving people that chance.'' The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> initiative would provide $ 728 million for the homeless _ to be equally matched by states, local government or private groups _ for housing and support services such as social and mental health programs. <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> officials have estimated that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> currently has about 600,000 homeless people.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891127-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-27-89 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-LincolnS&amp;L     11-27 0505</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lincoln S&amp;L,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gray Names DeConcini and Cranston in Lincoln S&amp;L Case</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
