<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EXP--Voyager-Neptune     07-02 1152</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-EXP--Voyager-Neptune,1181</SECOND>
<HEAD>Voyager 2 Approaches Neptune for Grand Finale of Solar System Trek</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE SIEGEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PASADENA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Twelve years, three planets and 4.4 billion miles after leaving <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, Voyager 2 is converging on <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>, a swirling, blue-green planet with a backward moon, for the last stop on an extraordinary tour. `` The solar system is our neighborhood, and we're getting to the end of the neighborhood,'' said <PERSON> Norm </PERSON> <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>, Voyager project manager at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Admnistration </ORGANIZATION>'s Jet Propulsion Laboratory. Voyager 2 already has detected a dark spot on <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> that may be a giant storm like <ORGANIZATION> Jupiter </ORGANIZATION>'s Great Red Spot. As it nears the planet, the probe will search for undiscovered moons and partial rings. And at 9 p.m. PDT on Aug. 24, <PERSON> Voyager </PERSON> will swoop within 3,000 miles of <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>'s north pole cloudtops _ the closest of its close encounters and the first spacecraft to visit the planet. It will be 2.75 billion miles from <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> after traveling 4.43 billion miles along its curving path. The information it sends back at the speed of light will take four hours and six minutes to arrive. Five hours after the closest encounter, <PERSON> Voyager </PERSON> will fly within 25,000 miles of the backwards-orbiting moon, <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION>. The other known moon is Nereid. Voyager 1 and 2, laden with TV cameras and an array of sensors, were launched from <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canaveral </LOCATION> in 1977. They visited Jupiter in 1979 and <ORGANIZATION> Saturn </ORGANIZATION> in 1980 and 1981, respectively. Voyager 2 reached Uranus in 1986. Voyager 1 now is heading toward interstellar space. Voyager 1 and 2 returned 65,000 photographs of <ORGANIZATION> Jupiter </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Saturn </ORGANIZATION> and their moons and rings. Voyager 2 sent back 8,000 pictures of Uranus and its moons, and will take another 8,000 of <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>. At a cost <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> pegged at $ 865 million through the <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> encounter, the Voyagers `` returned more new knowledge about the outer planets ... than existed in all of the preceding history of astronomy,'' according to <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>, discovered in 1846, is 30,700 miles in diameter _ six times <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>'s size and the fourth largest planet after <ORGANIZATION> Jupiter </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Saturn </ORGANIZATION> and Uranus. A Neptunian year lasts 165 Earth years, and a day lasts 17 to 18 Earth hours _ a detail Voyager may pinpoint. <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> usually is the eighth planet, but because of <LOCATION> Pluto </LOCATION>'s elongated orbit <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> will be the ninth and outermost until 2007. Scientists expect Voyager to discover at least 10 small moons, said deputy project scientist <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> <PERSON> Miner </PERSON>. Some moons may confine or shepherd the 5 - to 12-mile-wide incomplete rings, called `` ring arcs,'' orbiting <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>, said physicist <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s Voyager project scientist and a vice president at <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> Voyager also may discover dust bands and 50 to 100 partial rings in addition to the three to six arcs scientists believe they detected from <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> added. The partial rings, possibly made of dust and pebbles, most likely are debris from the collision of a comet and an ancient moon, he said. Voyager should be some 33,400 miles above <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>'s clouds when it crosses the ring region, so it is unlikely to be destroyed by an unseen arc, he said. The probe also will study Neptune's weather. Scientists believe the 6,200-mile-wide dark spot it found probably is similar to <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>'s hurricanes or <ORGANIZATION> Jupiter </ORGANIZATION>'s Great Red Spot. The source of the internal heat driving <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>'s storms is a mystery; <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>'s comes decaying radioactive material in rocks. <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> is pale blue-green because methane, or natural gas, in its mostly hydrogen-helium atmosphere absorbs red light. Scientists suspect that a third of the way toward the planet's center the atmosphere becomes a superhot slurry of hot water and rock, so <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> _ like neighboring <LOCATION> Uranus </LOCATION> _ probably lacks a distinct sky-sea boundary, <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said. Despite any internal heat, <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> receives 900 times less sunlight than <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, so the temperature at the top of its atmosphere is 350 degrees below zero Fahrenheit, about the same as on <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said. Scientists believe <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION> _ 1,400 to 2,240 miles wide, roughly the size of <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>'s moon _ will be the most fascinating part of Voyager's flyby. When a planet and its moons form from a spinning disk of gas and solid material, the moons should orbit in the direction the planet rotates. <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION>'s reverse orbit suggests it once orbited the sun like a comet or a planet but collided with a moon to form a new backwards-moving satellite, <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION> probably is cold and geologically inactive, with an icy mantle over a rocky core. But it once may have had a molten interior that created ridges, valleys, cliffs, canyons and volcanoes that Voyager might photograph. Observations from Earth indicate <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION>'s atmosphere contains methane and nitrogen. Sunlight likely converts methane into complex hydrocarbons, creating a transparent reddish-orange photochemical haze, <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said. The hydrocarbons may form heavier particles, coating the surface with frozen sludge. Could the organic chemicals have allowed life to develop on <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION>? `` The temperature is very, very cold, so I think it's unlikely,'' he said. Scientists believe <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION> has extreme seasons because its orbit around <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> is highly inclined: One pole faces the sun for 82 years and the other remains in darkness. This may mean <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION>'s atmosphere gets thinner and thicker as methane-nitrogen icecaps cover one pole, then the other Researchers discarded the theory that <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION> has liquid nitrogen oceans, but puddles or lakes are possible, along with fields of nitrogen ice crystals, <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said. Nereid, about 190 to 620 miles wide, has a very elongated elliptical orbit. <ORGANIZATION> Caltech </ORGANIZATION> astrophysicist <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldreich </PERSON> speculates Nereid once had a circular orbit that was disturbed by gravity from <ORGANIZATION> Triton </ORGANIZATION> or a large passing object. If Voyager confirms that <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> has a magnetic field, the planet also may have an aurora like <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>'s, and a mysterious ultraviolet `` electroglow.'' A magnetic field should trap a radiation belt around <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> similar to <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> belts. <ORGANIZATION> Jupiter </ORGANIZATION>'s radiation belts damaged some of Voyager's equipment; <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> doubts similar problems at <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> Voyager 2 has worked 12 years with only relatively minor failures, although it contains electronics equal to 10,000 television sets, he said. Commands sent to Voyager, and photos and information it sends to <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, travel at the speed of light. But the one-way trip still take four hours, six minutes. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> is using 38 dish-shaped radio antennas in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to capture the radio signal, which is like trying to see a 20-watt light bulb burning 2.75 billion miles away. `` Both Voyagers are expected to return valuable data well into the 21st century'' before their power supplies run out in about 2020, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> said. After <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>, Voyager 2 will join <ORGANIZATION> Voyager </ORGANIZATION> 1 and <ORGANIZATION> Pioneers </ORGANIZATION> 10 and 11 in seeking the true edge of the solar system, where solar wind gives way to interstellar wind billions of miles beyond the planets.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 2353EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EXP--Voyager'sEyes     07-02 0655</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-EXP--Voyager's Eyes,0669</SECOND>
<HEAD>Radio Telescopes Around The World Watch Voyager Signals</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-EXP--Voyager-Neptune</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT MYGATT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PLAINS OF SAN AUGUSTIN, N.M. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Imagine a 20-watt refrigerator light bulb burning in the dark, 2.75 billion miles away. Now imagine the sophisticated eyes needed to see the light. Voyager 2, heading for <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>, is emitting 20 watts of radio signals, information coded in binary bits _ ones and zeros _ on the space probe's health and from its scientific instruments and cameras. `` Think of that lightbulb as flickering, and that flickering contains the information that <PERSON> Voyager </PERSON> is sending back to us,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Brundage </PERSON>, Voyager preparation manager for the Very Large Array radio telescope. The signals have become fainter since Voyager's encounters with Jupiter in 1979, <ORGANIZATION> Saturn </ORGANIZATION> in 1981 and Uranus in 1986. The signals, and commands sent to the 12-year-old probe, take four hours and six minutes to cross 2.75 billion miles at the speed of light. Larger antennas and more sensitive receivers are needed on Earth to receive the signals, and more power is needed to transmit commands to the craft, which will pass fly within 3,000 miles of <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> on Aug. 24. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>'s Deep Space Network is used to talk to Voyager. The DSN has three complexes: <PERSON> Goldstone </PERSON> in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Desert </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>; and Tidbinbilla, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> Canberra </LOCATION>. When Voyager flew by Uranus, the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and Australian listening posts used three antenna dishes each _ one 210 feet across and two 112 feet _ and the <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> station used one of each, said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Beth </PERSON> <PERSON> Murrill </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Propulsion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Canberra </LOCATION> complex also was linked to <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>'s 210-foot <ORGANIZATION> Parkes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Astronomy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telescope </ORGANIZATION>. For <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION>, the 210-foot dishes at <LOCATION> Goldstone </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canberra </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> have been increased to 230 feet and another 112-foot antenna was built at <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>. In addition, the <ORGANIZATION> VLA </ORGANIZATION> is being used in conjunction with <PERSON> Goldstone </PERSON>, <PERSON> Parkes </PERSON> again is linked with <LOCATION> Canberra </LOCATION>, and a Japanese telescope will be added to the network. The different sites ensure that at least one station can communicate with the spacecraft despite the Earth's rotation, <PERSON> Brundage </PERSON> said. `` The <LOCATION> VLA </LOCATION> alone gives us almost a third more images than if we did n't have it,'' said <PERSON> Norm </PERSON> <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>, Voyager project manager at <ORGANIZATION> JPL </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> VLA </ORGANIZATION> is a one-of-a-kind space-age erector set sitting on an ancient lake bed. The site is skirted by four mountain ranges, protecting it from much of the electronic interference from television, radios, aircraft and the like. It consists of 27 white dish-shaped antennas, each 82 feet in diameter, 92 feet high and weighing 235 tons. The dishes sit on the Plains of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Augustin </LOCATION> amid tumbleweed, cattle and sparse vegetation at an altitude of 7,000 feet. The dishes are arranged along three arms of railroad track, laid out in the shape of a Y. Two arms are 13 miles long and the third is 11.8 miles. The Earth rotates the Y like a turntable, creating images that have the same detail as if using a radio telescope up to 26 miles in diameter. A special 36-wheel transporter moves each antenna to one of 72 observation stations along the three arms. This acts like a zoom lens _ the farther out the dishes, the higher the resolution; the closer in, the larger the field of view. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> spent $ 6.5 million to equip each dish to receive Voyager's signals It also set up special techniques and installed two big diesel generators to guard against lightning-caused power fluctuations during the thunderstorm season. The separation of the listening posts around the world _ just like the separation of the <ORGANIZATION> VLA </ORGANIZATION> dishes _ strengthen the sensitivity of the network. The signal <ORGANIZATION> VLA </ORGANIZATION> gets from Voyager is sent via satellite to <PERSON> Goldstone </PERSON>, where the two signals are combined, decoded and sent via microwave to <ORGANIZATION> JPL </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 2357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-LifeinEasternEurope-Democracy     07-02 0889</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Life in Eastern Europe-Democracy,0910</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democracy _ It's Breaking Out in Eastern Europe</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report; First in a five-part series.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DANISZEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The young woman's enthusiasm was contagious. `` I did it, I did it,'' she said, smiling broadly and barely standing still after casting her first vote in a democratic election. The right to vote is taken for granted _ and often ignored _ in countries with a longer tradition of rule by and for the people. But in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, brutalized by 50 years of war, Stalinism, police repression, false propaganda and economic mismanagement, that simple act in the Polish national elections June 4 seemed nothing short of a miracle. Communist rule came to <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> as the result of the World War II military might of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, but perestroika and glasnost under Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> are giving countries that used to be referred to as `` satellites'' the leeway to experiment with democracy. Economic pressures are also helping the cause of political reforms. With communist economies proven unable to compete with the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> in a high-technology age, the ideological rationale for Marxism-Leninism _ that it makes life better for the common man and woman _ has been stripped away. In the course of one or two years, the concept of free competition among different political parties has gone from being an unimaginable dream to being hoped for and even counted on in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. Poles and Hungarians will even get a rare, firsthand look at the leader of a <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> democracy this month, when President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> stops to visit prior to the annual summit of industrialized democracies in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will find a <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> that has just held the first democratic parliamentary elections since World War II, in which candidates backed by the Solidarity movement took 99 of the 100 seats. The elections to the <ORGANIZATION> Sejm </ORGANIZATION> were not free; the opposition was allowed only to run for 35 percent of the seats. Solidarity took all 161 of those. Its platform: Remove the party's `` leading role'' and hold free elections in four years. In <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, that might be too slow. A commission is working to draft a constitution expected to provide for fully free multiparty elections as early as next year. It also will guarantee free speech, independent courts and other human rights. The rapid pace of democratic change in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> was underlined by the reburial with honors June 16 of <PERSON> Imre </PERSON> <PERSON> Nagy </PERSON>, leader of the 1956 anti-Soviet revolt, who was executed for treason. Hundreds of thousands of people were on hand for the ceremony and joined a veteran of 1956 in swearing: `` We will never again be slaves.'' Party leaders in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> have been quoted as saying they hope the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> will win planned free elections in the future, but if not, the party will accept the voters' verdict and relinquish power. In <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, the opposition is led by <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> and the Solidarity movement which embraces workers, intellectuals and much of the powerful <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. In <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, reform is mainly the work of intellectuals, including a potent liberal wing of the communist party itself. Both countries already have seen the spontaneous reformation of long-banned political parties and associations, as if they only were in suspended animation for the past half century. There also are totally new political grouping, such as environmentally conscious `` Greens.'' Elsewhere in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, democratization is not so advanced, where it exists at all. What is happening in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> has raised hopes among some citizens while disquieting the mostly aging leaderships. <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, the most hardline states, have commented with dismay on <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s move toward democracy. `` Under the flag of ` renewing socialism,' forces are at work that strive for removing socialism,'' said East German Politburo member <PERSON> Joachim </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrman </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> said the ceremonies to honor <PERSON> Nagy </PERSON> were `` clearly fascist, anti-socialist in nature.'' Both countries brook no dissent. In <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, dissidents are jailed while in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> they are likely to find themselves deported to the West. In <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>, the Czechoslovak leadership has paid enthusiastic lip service to the Kremlin reforms, but failed so far to implement them amid an ongoing, if secretive debate about whether change is needed. In <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION>, leader <PERSON> Todor </PERSON> <PERSON> Zhivkov </PERSON> remains true to a lifetime of skillfully aping whatever policy holds sway in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. In July 1987, he embraced economic reform, exciting <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION>'s intelligentsia and younger technocrats. But <PERSON> Zhivkov </PERSON> and longtime comrades on the ruling <PERSON> Poltiburo </PERSON> blocked dissent within the party last year. Dissident groups, the first seen in four decades of communist rule, are closely watched by security forces and troublemakers are expelled. In <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>, the communist party leadership in <LOCATION> Slovenia </LOCATION>, the most economically advanced of the country's six republics, has tolerated a broad degree of pluralism, while rejecting demands for multiparty democracy from mushrooming independent groups. Those calls have been echoed by intellectuals in <LOCATION> Croatia </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Servia </PERSON>, the two largest republics, but ethnic tensions among the republics have complicated any broad alliance for reform. Serbian President <PERSON> Slobodan </PERSON> <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>, however, uses authoritarian tactics and insists on one-party, orthodox communist rule, putting him at odds with other republics _ particularly the Slovenes, who are now threatening secession if conflicts go unresolved.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEXT: Life in Eastern Europe-Soviets</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 2358EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Allison-Louisiana 3rdLd-Writethru a0785 07-02 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Allison-Louisiana, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0785,0798</SECOND>
<HEAD>Precede: NEW ORLEANS</HEAD>
<HEAD>Allison Leaves But Flooding Continues</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: LEADS with 14 grafs to UPDATE with storms in Dallas; 50,000
without power, dozen mobile homes damaged; minor editing; picks up 11th
graf pvs, `During the ...' ^By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Thunderstorms packing 90 mph gusts roared through northern <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> late Sunday, and rivers continued to rise in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>. The flooding, the aftermath of record rainfall from Tropical Storm <PERSON> Allison </PERSON>, could continue for weeks, meteorolgists said. <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> fire officials received reports of two tornadoes touching down. The storms knocked down power lines, leaving about 50,000 homes without electricity, authorities said. About a dozen mobile homes near <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> were knocked off foundations and struck by wind-blown trees, said <ORGANIZATION> Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Worth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> McConnell </PERSON>. There were no immediate reports of injuries. In <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, at least 700 homes and numerous roads remained flooded, with scattered storms and showers replacing the unremitting rain of the previous five days. One town got nearly 29 inches of rain in less than a week. A tornado destroyed a taxidermy business and 70 mph winds swept the outskirts of <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, in the central part of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, said Sgt. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Ribaudo </PERSON> of the Rapides Parish Sheriff's Department. <PERSON> Ribaudo </PERSON> said he could n't tell if the storm would worsen flooding in the area. `` It's already so bad one more storm does n't seem like anything,'' he said. An earthen dam in another rural part of the state was reported near collapse, and most residents near it had evacuated. In <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, a 12-year-old boy died when he jumped into a storm-flooded ditch and was sucked into a culvert Saturday afternoon, one of three deaths blamed on the storm, authorities said. Four deaths were blamed on the storm in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, authorities braved rain and lightning to search for a teen-ager missing after he and a companion went swimming in a swollen creek. The body of the companion was recovered early Sunday near <LOCATION> Natchez </LOCATION>, on the east bank of the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>. About 180 miles north, about 200 people were evacuated from <LOCATION> Coahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> homes as a flood swept through their neighborhoods. During the night, <PERSON> Allison </PERSON>'s leftover rain and thunderstorms moved slowly eastward and shifted the heavy rain pattern into the <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> valleys. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said fields and timberland were likely to stay flooded for weeks because there was nowhere for all the water to go. `` The Red River itself is at bank-full from Grand Ecore downstream to <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION> and below,'' said <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Ethridge </PERSON>, a weather service meteorologist in <LOCATION> Shreveport </LOCATION>. `` All these tributaries that received the torrential rains are unable to empty their water into the main channel,'' he said. `` So it spreads out, becomes a big lake.'' At least 10 parishes _ <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s equivalent of counties _ got 12 to 15 inches of rain, he said, with 20 inches or more measured in <PERSON> Winn </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Natchitoches </LOCATION> parishes. He said some lakes and rivers crested Sunday and others were expected to do so Monday or later. All were flooding, he said. In <LOCATION> Winn </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Parish </LOCATION>, about 70 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Shreveport </LOCATION>, deputies kept watch on the deteriorating <ORGANIZATION> Mirror </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dam </ORGANIZATION>, which initially had been expected to collapse by daybreak. `` It's doing better than we thought it would. But it's not going to hold long,'' said Deputy <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Phelps </PERSON>. `` Some trees that were holding it yesterday washed out during the night. Now it's just dirt.'' He said no evacuation had been ordered, but most of the people in the 50 or so homes nearby left on their own. `` There's people getting smart and getting out,'' he said. About 100 houses were evacuated around <LOCATION> Saline </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, along the western edge of the parish. Downstream, authorities estimated that the flooded lake <LOCATION> Saline </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, where about 100 houses were evacuated, would rise at least an extra foot if the Mirror Lake Dam broke. <PERSON> Winnfield </PERSON> got the week's worst rain _ 28.75 inches since Wednesday. `` The sun's out ... and the water's receding at the present,'' said Mayor <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON>. However, he said, more storms were expected and the <LOCATION> Dugdemona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> had not yet crested. About 100 houses were flooded in the town. `` I would imagine our economy is going to suffer,'' he said. At the weather service, <PERSON> Ethridge </PERSON> said <PERSON> Winnfield </PERSON> got 32 inches of rain in June _ the wettest month on record and 7 inches above the previous record, set in December 1983. <LOCATION> Shreveport </LOCATION> had its wettest June ever, with 17.01 inches of rain. He said lowland flooding would continue to increase for the next few days, and then probably remain for a couple of weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 0005EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Abortion-Convention 2ndLd-Writethru a0613 07-02 0540</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Abortion-Convention, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0613,0555</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congressmen Warn Against Complacency In Anti-Abortion Movement</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 9 grafs to UPDATE with Missouri governor blaming
abortion for problems of youth; picks up 6th graf, `In the...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Abortion Opponents, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BLOOMINGTON, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The governor of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> told anti-abortion lobbyists Saturday that legalized abortion contributes to dropouts, suicides and low self-esteem among youth. Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ashcroft </PERSON>, speaking to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Right </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> to </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s annual convention two days before the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> was expected to rule on a <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> case that could determine the future of legalized abortion in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, said abortions contributed to a `` vacuum of values'' among the youth. `` What kind of signal are we as a society sending them about the value of life? We need to send an unmistakable message that there is a fundamental value in life itself,'' he said. The law being reviewed by the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> puts restrictions on abortions and defines life as beginning at conception. Upholding the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> law, or even parts of it, could reverse or seriously erode the 1973 <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> decision legalizing abortion. `` The <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> decision is simply a miserable failure,'' <PERSON> Ashcroft </PERSON> said, drawing loud applause. `` And I hope that the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> announces it is overturning the <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> decision and giving back to the states the right to make public policy.'' The court has said it may rule Monday on the case, <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> vs. Reproductive Health Services, or delay its decision for further review. Earlier Saturday, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.J. </LOCATION>, told delegates they must not become complacent in light of victories the movement has achieved over the last 20 years. `` We've got to regroup. We've got to rededicate. We've got to realize that the fight is just beginning,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. `` Over the past two decades, our message has been getting through. Our efforts are bearing fruit. Without us, it would have gotten worse,'' said <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, one of three congressmen with strong anti-abortion records in the House. In the Minneapolis-St. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> suburb of <LOCATION> Robbinsdale </LOCATION>, meanwhile, about 300 protesters on both sides of the issue picketed and sang Saturday morning outside a clinic where abortions are performed <PERSON> Dixie </PERSON> <PERSON> Riley </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION> said NOW representatives were on hand `` to make sure that the women can get into the clinic and exercise their constitutional right _ for as long as it lasts. We all know the <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> v. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> decision is being reconsidered.'' Reps. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Oberstar </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Minn </LOCATION>., and <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ill </LOCATION>., also addressed the `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> ... has been called a disposable society, but that should n't include people,'' <PERSON> Oberstar </PERSON> said. Many religious groups support the anti-abortion position, he said. `` But there is more than religion alone to guide us in this issue because there's incontrovertible medical and biological evidence that life begins at conception,'' the congressman said. <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON> said abortion is just another indication of decay in the morals of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The high incidence of alcoholism and drug abuse and the lack of religious guidance for many people are other indications, he said. `` The moral infrastructure of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> has broken down,'' <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON> said. `` We must be the rebuilders.'' `` The greatest civil right, the greatest human right of all, is the right to life,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 0502EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-SriLanka     07-02 0312</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Sri Lanka,0320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bomb Explodes at Exhibition Attended by President</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PATRICK CRUEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLOMBO, Sri Lanka (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bomb exploded early Sunday at a crowded exhibition attended by President <PERSON> Ranasinghe </PERSON> <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> and senior members of his <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION>, but they escaped injury, police said. However, at least one person was killed and 30 were wounded, they said. No one claimed responsibility for the blast, which occurred shortly after midnight at a government-sponsored exhibition in <LOCATION> Mahiyangana </LOCATION>, 70 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>. But police blamed members of the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, a left-wing ethnic Sinhalese group trying to overthrow the Sinhalese-dominated government. Also Sunday, security forces in the south arrested 3,237 Sinhalese youths suspected of belonging to the front, according to a police official in <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>. It was the largest such crackdown against the group in nearly two years, said the officer, who can not be identified under briefing rules. The front has been blamed for more than 3,500 killings since July 1987, when Indian peacekeeping forces arrived on this <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> island to enforce a peace accord between the government and the Tamil minority. The front contends the accord grants too many concessions to the Tamils and the Indian soldiers threaten Sri Lankan sovereignty. Front members have vowed to kill anyone who supports the pact. Last month, <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> asked <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> to pull out its troops by the end of July. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> refused, saying a quick withdrawal could stir even more ethnic violence. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> sent troops to <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> under a peace accord signed by Indian Prime Minister <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> and <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON>'s predecessor, <PERSON> Junius </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jayewardene </PERSON>. The accord proposed to give Tamils limited autonomy in exchange for surrendering their weapons, but militant Tamils rejected it. Tamils, who comprise 18 percent of <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>'s 16 million people, contend they suffer job and educational discrimination. Sinhalese make up 75 percent of the population.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 1119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Nuclear'sNewChief Bjt   07-02 0763</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nuclear's New Chief, Bjt,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Retired Naval Officer Takes Helm of Nuclear Agency</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the office of <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Carr </PERSON>, the new chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, hangs a small framed copy of a once-secret message that reminds him both of atomic power's promise a generation ago and its troubles today. `` Under way on nuclear power,'' says the flash from the USS Nautilus, signalling the launching of the maiden voyage of the first vessel in the world to be propelled by a nuclear reactor. The date was Jan. 17, 1955, and <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> was a crew member. He remembers that historic moment as a high-water mark in the military use of nuclear power. A generation later, <PERSON> Carr </PERSON>, 64, is taking the helm of the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> with the commercial nuclear power industry at a low ebb, crippled in large part by a widespread public fear of the atom _ a fear <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> says is irrational but powerful and enduring. From his first day Monday as chairman of the federal agency that regulates commercial nuclear power, <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> says he intends to press the search for ways of overcoming public opposition to nuclear plants. He has no illusions of quick success. `` I think it's going to be a generational change before you get the public acceptance,'' he said in a recent interview. No electric utility has ordered a nuclear plant in this country since 1978, and even nuclear power's biggest advocates see no sign of the drought ending soon. Public opposition is n't the only reason for nuclear's stagnation, but <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> thinks it's the one obstacle most deeply rooted in the history of atomic power. Today's adult population, he says, was introduced to nuclear power in an era in which strict secrecy, not public education, was the watchword of nuclear's promoters and regulators. The result was a mystic of little-understood danger. `` We tried to keep it bottled up, keep the genie in the bottle, even long after it was out,'' <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> says, noting a determination of the <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> administrations to guard <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> nuclear know-how not only from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and other potential <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> enemies but also friendly nations and even the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> public. `` I think we did n't do a good job at all of educating the public,'' he says. <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> is a native of <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>. He retired from the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> as a vice admiral in 1985, last serving as deputy and chief of staff to the commander in chief <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> and the commander in chief of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fleet </ORGANIZATION>. He was a crewman on an assault landing craft in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> theater during World War II. Later he was appointed to the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> as a member of the class of 1949. Among his honors are the Distinguished Service Medal and Legion of Merit. His experience in the nuclear <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> gave <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> firsthand knowledge of the nuclear secrecy he now bemoans. Even more basic to Americans' unease about the atom, he says, is a lingering memory of the stunning destruction caused by the only two nuclear bombs ever dropped _ on the Japanese cities of <LOCATION> Hiroshima </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nagasaki </LOCATION> in August 1945. `` That's what our generation sees when the words ` nuclear' and ` atomic' come; they see that big ball over there and they see that picture of that one building standing there in the rubble,'' he says. The only thing that will change that, <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> believes, is the passage of time and a stronger effort by government and industry to teach young people about nuclear energy. If they fully understand it, he says, they wo n't fear it. <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> is replacing another retired <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officer, <PERSON> Lando </PERSON> <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, as <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> chairman. He has high praise for <PERSON> Zech </PERSON>, who served with <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> on the USS Nautilus for two years and has been a close associate since <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> became an <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> commissioner in 1986. `` Now he's leaving me _ bailed out on me,'' <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> says, using the maritime lingo that frequently flavors his speech. During the two years he expects to spend as chairman, <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> says his top goal will be to set the ground rules for deciding whether to extend the operating licenses of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nuclear plants. The licenses of existing plants are good for 40 years, and the first expirations will come toward the end of the century. Decisions must be made soon, he says, because utilities need at least 10 years lead time to replace their plants if it's decided that four decades of use make the reactors too dangerous to keep using.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 1125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-NorthKorea Bjt   07-02 0627</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-North Korea, Bjt,0647</SECOND>
<HEAD>Europeans Protest Treatment at North Korean Festival</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto BEJ4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM ABRAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PYONGYANG, North Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police at an international youth festival seized Danish and Finnish human rights banners, and some European delegates Sunday accused <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> of using the festival for self-promotion. More than 15,000 people from 180 countries are in <LOCATION> Pyongyang </LOCATION> for the 13th World Festival of Youth and Students, the biggest international gathering ever staged by the communist government. The banners were seized at the opening cremonies Saturday. The Danish banner read `` Human rights in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> too,'' while <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>'s banner protested <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s refusal to allow the human rights group <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> to attend the one-week event. The Finn delegation had decided to drop out of the festival to protest the confiscation but reversed its decision Sunday, after <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> apologized and said two <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> representatives would be given visas to attend. <PERSON> Matti </PERSON> <PERSON> Tohianen </PERSON> of the Finnish delegation said police hit the hands of the four students carrying the banner and grabbed it during opening ceremonies. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> apparently balked at allowing <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> representation because the group has criticized <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s human rights record. The Danish delegation also was considering pulling out of the festival after police briefly detained three of its members for unfurling the human rights banner during a speech by President <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Il </PERSON> <PERSON> Sung </PERSON>. The Union of <ORGANIZATION> Nordic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Youth </ORGANIZATION> issued a statement saying the confiscation of banners was `` not within the spirit of the festival.'' Other delegates said they had received letters from the North Koreans warning they would be held personally responsible for any actions at the opening ceremony that were critical of the host country or other participants. A Norwegian delegate said her group smuggled in a banner expressing solidarity with the suppressed Chinese pro-democracy movement. The Finnish delegates also circulated a statement calling for the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> government to `` respect the freedom of expression and stop the ongoing arrests and executions.'' <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> has supported <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s crackdown on the pro-democracy movement in that country. Twenty-seven people have been executed since the movement was crushed by the military last month. <PERSON> Rachel </PERSON> <PERSON> Kyte </PERSON>, a representative of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Youth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, said her group was `` not happy'' about the staging of the festival in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, one of the world's most closed and tightly controlled nations. She complained about the `` orchestrated chanting of national slogans'' at the opening ceremony, in which 70,000 North Koreans performed in a three-hour music, dance and light show. <PERSON> Tor-Hugne </PERSON> <PERSON> Olsen </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Youth </ORGANIZATION>, called for a ban on opening and closing ceremonies. `` We want festivals to be international events, and not events of the host country,'' he said. The festival, last held in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in 1985, brings together youth from socialist countries and mainly leftist organizations to discuss political topics and stage various art, theatrical and sports shows. The festival organizers refused to put the <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> events on the agenda. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> has set out to use the festival to show the world it can stage an international event as successfully as the rival South Korean government, which was host to the Summer Olympics in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> last year. Dozens of new stadiums, hotels and apartments have been built, and many of <LOCATION> Pyongyang </LOCATION>'s 2 million people have been mobilized to prepare or participate in the festival. In <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, about 1,000 radical students gathered at <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Yonsei </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday to protest the government ban on participation in the youth festival Relations have been strained between the two Koreas since the <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> peninsula was divided in 1945 into the communist North and capitalist South. The countries fought a war from 1950 to 1953 and remain bitter enemies.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 1125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--India-Doctors     07-02 0111</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--India-Doctors,0113</SECOND>
<HEAD>Doctors End 47-Day-Old Strike</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 5,000 doctors at state-run hospitals ended a 47-day-old strike Sunday that had paralyzed medical care to the city's poor. The doctors are to return to work Monday, according to negotiators for the government and the Junior Doctors Federation. The agreement ending the strike was signed following negotiations that stretched through the night. The doctors had demanded pay raises, higher allowances for not being allowed to maintain private practices, and schedules for promotion. Under the agreement, the doctors will receive raises of $ 25 a month, less than half they had sought. Their monthly salaries average $ 200 to $ 269.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 1126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Philippines     07-02 0236</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines,0241</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eight Rebels Killed in Clash Near U.S. Base</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Government troops clashed with communist guerrillas in a village near the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-run </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, and eight rebels and a government soldier were killed, the military reported Sunday. Four soldiers were wounded in the battle Saturday near <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, 50 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, a report from the Philippine Constabulary headquarters in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> said. Troops recovered six M-16 rifles and rebel documents from the slain <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas, the report said. The rebels were surrounded at a house in <LOCATION> Duquit </LOCATION> village, about a mile from the air base. The house had been under surveillance for some time, said a constabulary soldier who requested anonymity. The soldier was contacted by telephone from <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, home of <ORGANIZATION> Clark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>. He said the rebels fired first and troops retaliated after ordering civilians out of the house. He quoted officials as saying the rebels could have been preparing for operations in the city to coincide with July 4 celebrations. July 4 also is celebrated in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> as Fil-American Friendship Day. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> has been fighting 20 years to set up a Marxist system in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. It also wants the removal of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military facilities from the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. In October 1987, rebels killed three Americans and a Filipino of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> descent during a series of ambushes outside <ORGANIZATION> Clark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 1126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--FamilyKillings     07-02 0143</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Family Killings,0146</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dutch Businessman, Two Children Found Dead</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Dutch businessman killed his two children and wounded his wife Sunday before hanging himself at the family's <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> home, police said. Investigating officers, who asked not to be identified by name, said the motive for the killings was unknown. They said <PERSON> Rudoljus </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilhelmus </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> was found hanging from a staircase and his 6-year-old daughter and 4-year-old son were discovered by the family maid in a second-floor room. Both reportedly had multiple stab wounds. Police said his wife also was stabbed and was in a coma at a <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> hospital. Police said that <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> held a management position with the <ORGANIZATION> Philips </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electrical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, a Dutch-owned company. The police reports said the family was due to return to the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> soon. <PERSON> Maria </PERSON>'s wife was reportedly suffering from cancer.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 1126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Thatcher     07-02 0147</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Thatcher,0151</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thatcher Worried About German-French Axis</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> was quoted Sunday as saying <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> has an influential role to play in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> because many countries do not want everything determined by a `` German-French axis.'' She was responding to questions about the recent <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> summit in <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>, during which <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> was the most vocal opponent of a single European currency and a central bank for the 12 <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> countries. `` Let us face it, many other countries really do not want everything to be determined by a kind of German-French axis,'' she was quoted as saying in an interview with The Sunday Express. `` A number of the smaller countries realize the enormous part that <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> has played both in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s history and in her liberation and still pays in having very open financial markets,'' she was quoted as saying.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 1127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SAfrica-BusPlunge     07-02 0281</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-SAfrica-Bus Plunge,0289</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bus Crash Kills 56</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DURBAN, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bus skidded on a wet highway and plunged 900 feet down an embankment, killing 56 people, authorities said Sunday. More than 20 people were hospitalized, some with severe injuries, police and press reports said. The bus was carrying workers home from the <LOCATION> Natal </LOCATION> province town of <PERSON> Harding </PERSON> to the tribal homeland of <LOCATION> Transkei </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s southeast coast when it skidded off the road about 2:30 p.m. Saturday, police said As many as 100 people were aboard, according to one newspaper report. It reportedly was raining at the time of the accident. The South African <ORGANIZATION> Broadcast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> put the death toll at 56. It quoted <PERSON> Lew </PERSON> <PERSON> Corbett </PERSON>, traffic chief at <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shepstone </ORGANIZATION>, as saying the bus left the road and overturned, then tumbled into the ravine. Another police report quoted by the network said the top of the bus was sheared off as it fell. The South African <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said all the victims were black and included some children. It said at least three people were unhurt, including the driver and bus conductor. The injured were taken to hospitals in <PERSON> Harding </PERSON> and the coastal town of <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Shepstone </LOCATION>, each about 10 miles from the scene. Some of the most serious cases were brought to <LOCATION> Durban </LOCATION>, 60 miles to the northeast. Buses used to carry workers are frequently overloaded and not well maintained. The crash was the second serious bus accident in the country in two days. On Friday, eight people were killed and 53 hurt when a bus ran off a road and overturned near the <LOCATION> Numbi </LOCATION> gate entrance of <ORGANIZATION> Kruger </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION>, a wildlife reserve.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 1136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-HUD-Dean Bjt   07-02 0932</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-HUD-Dean, Bjt,910</SECOND>
<HEAD>Deborah Gore Dean: There to Help</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD L. VERNACI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The letter to <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>, an aide to the secretary of <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, did n't waste any words. `` Dear Debbie,'' it began. `` HELP! `` <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>'' <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Goulding </PERSON>, a financial consultant who was working on behalf of a community organization, said he was at the end of his rope that July day a few years ago. In his case, the plea did not work. In many others, it did. An examination of Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>'s correspondence during her years at the top of <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> shows that help was her business _ particularly for certain developers and well-connected <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> consultants. Relatively few of the hundreds of letters released by <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> were signed by Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>. However, accompanying documents show that she gave the final approval to many letters over the signature of her boss, then-housing Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr </PERSON>. They were then signed by a machine at her command. Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>, 34, is at the center of investigations of influence peddling at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>, where she has been identified as the person who controlled millions of dollars for housing rehabilitation. She has refused to testify before a congressional panel investigating <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>, citing her constitutional right against self incrimination. And aside from earlier interviews with The Wall Street Journal, she has avoided contact with the news media. Last week, when she accidentally answered a call at her lawyer's office from The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, she politely but firmly declined to talk and quickly put her attorney on the phone. Her rise through the ranks at the department was stymied only by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, which derailed her nomination to be assistant <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> secretary. But it was from her post as executive assistant to <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, the job she held until she left the department in 1987, that she exerted her control. <PERSON> Goulding </PERSON> said in an interview that he had gotten nowhere in trying to persuade <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> to boost a rent subsidy for a housing development on the south side of <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> already had given money to fix up the project, but it needed higher rent subsidies to make it financially workable, he said. <PERSON> Goulding </PERSON> wound up seeking the help of Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>. `` I took a shot and called her,'' he said. `` She was always very polite to me and very nice and offering to be of help but I did n't get anywhere, never translated into anything positive, unfortunately. <PERSON> Goulding </PERSON> was n't alone. Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> wrote to <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> to push for projects back home. Often they got letters back saying all the money had already been spent. In the spring of 1985, for example, Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON>, R-Pa., wrote a `` Dear Sam'' letter to <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> Although the news was bad, the tone was friendly when he got back letter addressed `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>'' and signed just `` <PERSON> Sam </PERSON>.'' The letter's tone was set by Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>, as was the signature. On formal occasions she would have the machine, called an autopen, sign `` <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>,'' but when the mood called for it, she would have the letter signed `` <PERSON> Sam </PERSON>.'' Internal file slips from <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>, carrying the initials of everyone in the chain of command reviewing a particular piece or correspondence, indicate that the final stop before the mail box was at Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>'s desk. It is not known whether <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> himself saw any of the correspondence because his initials are not on the slips. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, whose hands-off style of management at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> has been sharply criticized in the wake of disclosures about political influence, costly misjudgments and outright stealing that plagued the department, has said he was betrayed by his aides and singled out Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>. `` She liked power,'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. `` She liked the idea that, ` I can call the shots, I can get this for you if I want, I can stomp on you, I can kill you' _ that's the kind of thing she liked.'' Among the people who beat a path to her door were former <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Watt </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> political consultant <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Manafort </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> fund-raiser and now ambassador-designate to <LOCATION> Luxembourg </LOCATION> <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Winn </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> official who now is ambassador to <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>. All of them came away with money for the projects they represented, bringing some of them six-figure fees from grateful clients. But Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>, who held little formal authority at the department, occasionally invoked that lack of official power to give people the brush off. `` First, I feel I must explain once again,'' she wrote in 1985 to <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, who was seeking funds for a <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> project. `` Neither I nor Secretary <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> have any authority to designate moderate rehabilitation funds to you or your client. I have tried to make this clear in the past. `` They are issued on a competitive basis, and there are far more requests than there are units available,'' Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> wrote. No one would dispute that there were more requests for help than there was help available, but few people would agree that the <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> funds were awarded in fair competition. Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, D-Calif., chairman of a subcommittee investigating <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>, has called the notion of competition `` a sham and an illusion. <PERSON> Goulding </PERSON>, who said he was personally hurt for a while that his social contacts with Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> did not translate into money, has become forgiving over time. `` Unfortunately, <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> sometimes tells you things that are n't necessarily accurate,'' <PERSON> Goulding </PERSON> said `` It's not because she means badly, it's that she over commits herself.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 1209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-StrikeForces     07-02 0924</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Strike Forces,890</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shock Troops in War Against Organized Crime Feel Heat Themselves</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fierce dispute over the future of organized crime strike forces, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s shock troops in the war against the mob, is heating up within the law enforcement community. `` This is a turf fight _ it's as simple as that,'' says <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Vaira </PERSON>, a former strike force chief in that city who once headed the President's Commission on Organized Crime. A <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> hearing is set for July 21 on the strike forces, teams of prosecutors initially established by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to specialize in organized crime and labor racketeering. Currently based in 14 cities, they have compiled a record of achievements that even critics call impressive. Organized crime leaders from <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and other cities are currently serving long prison terms as a result of strike force investigations. Indeed, <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Jeremiah </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Sullivan </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> strike force chief, recalls a wiretap as early as 1981 in which hoodlums were heard to speak hopefully of chances that the strike forces would be disbanded. Actually, the strike forces will be disbanded _ in effect, if not in name _ under a plan announced by Attorney General <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>, say supporters of the units within the legal community. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> plans to place the strike forces, which now report directly to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, under the control of presidentially appointed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorneys, who traditionally have been the top federal prosecutors in their communities. `` I think it's an unfortunate decision,'' says <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> law professor <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogovin </PERSON>. `` Essentially what is being done is the dismantling of an apparatus that has really developed a remarkable kind of expertise.'' Former strike force officials say there have been resignations in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> that in part were caused by <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>'s plan. In fact, <PERSON> O'Sullivan </PERSON> says it was `` one factor'' in his own departure. He says he had battled for years to hold the strike forces together and, `` I just did n't have the energy to fight this fight one more time.'' <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>, formerly chief of the <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> strike force, is critical of what officials `` euphemistically call the merger of the strike forces. I like to call it the abolition or destruction of the strike forces.'' Nonsense, retort <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials. They say the plan guarantees that the strike force will remain intact but under control of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorneys, thus ending squabbling and rivalries. `` Are we going to spend 30 percent of our time arguing over whose case this is? Or are we going to make the case?'' asks <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> S.G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON>, assistant attorney general and No. 2 official at the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Praise is coming from virtually all of the nation's <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorneys. `` I think this is an excellent idea,'' says <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Anton </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON>. `` What it would do is substantially increase our ability to continue the war on organized crime.'' Gone are the days when <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorneys lacked the sophistication to launch the complex undercover investigations needed to catch mobsters, says <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON>. He points to the `` Operation Graylord'' cases that revealed widespread bribery in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> courts and resulted in conviction of scores of judges, lawyers and court officials. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Richmond </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Hammond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, chairman of the 15-member Attorney General's <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, points to stunning successes of <PERSON> Rudolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON> and other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorneys in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, where the strike force was merged into the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney's office. The arrangement has produced some spectacular successes against organized crime. `` This will certainly not diminish the fight against organized crime,'' says <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>. `` It will enhance it.'' Current strike force attorneys have remained silent in the debate. One current strike force prosecutor, who asked not to be identified by name, cited a March 9 memo from <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> warning that violations of publicity guidelines could mean firing. Former strike force chiefs, however, have mounted a lobbying campaign designed to save their old program. They say <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> has carried a longstanding grudge against the program. `` He had innumerable run-ins with the <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> strike force when he was <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney in the early 1970s and it left a bad taste in his mouth,'' says <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Roller </PERSON>, former strike force chief in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. And questions have been raised concerning the strong political ties that usually mark relations between <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorneys and the local establishments in their communities. Indeed, the post of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney has been a launching pad for many political careers. `` The loyalties of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorneys are to the senators who nominated them,'' says <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Fein </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official and now a conservative analyst of the federal court system. The issue came up at a June 20 hearing of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> criminal justice subcommittee when Rep. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Sangmeister </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ill </LOCATION>., questioned <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> `` There are always a lot of calls like, ` Old <PERSON> Moe </PERSON> has been a good contributor to the party for all these years and it's a shame that you're doing to him what you are,''' <PERSON> Sangmeister </PERSON> said. `` I think the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney should be completely absolved from that.'' <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> suggested that in such a case the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney might recuse himself _ bow out to avoid a conflict _ and let an aide make the decision. `` The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney is not going to recuse himself because somebody down in the party says take it easy on <PERSON> Moe </PERSON>,'' Sangmeister shot back. `` You do n't recuse yourself for stuff like that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 1207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Afghanistan-Crash     07-02 0178</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Afghanistan-Crash,0184</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thirty-Five Killed In Plane Crash, Afghan Rebels Report</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An Afghan government airliner crashed in the country's southern <LOCATION> Helmand </LOCATION> province, killing 35 people, a rebel-controlled news agency said Sunday. The Afghan News Agency, which is based in <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION>, did not say whether the June 26 crash involved a civilian or military aircraft. There was no indpendent confirmation of the crash. <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s government-run radio did not report it The guerrilla news agency said it was unclear whether the crash was caused by mechinical failure or whether it was shot down by rebels. The guerrillas have been fighting the country's Soviet-backed government for more than a decade The guerrilla-run news agency also reported that rebels shot down three government helicopters during the past week. Two were downed near the eastern city of <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION>, killing 29 government soldiers being transported to bolster government troops defending the city from rebel attacks, the news agency reported. The third helicopter was shot down in the northwestern province of <LOCATION> Badghis </LOCATION>, it said. The report could not be independently confirmed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 1215EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-BoatingSafety     07-02 0594</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Boating Safety,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pleasure Boat Fatals Down Dramatically, But Congested Waters Heighten
Fear</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fatal accidents involving recreational boaters have decreased dramatically over the past two decades, but many weekend skippers fear increasing congestion in waters has made pleasure trips more dangerous than ever. Fewer recreational boaters were killed last year than in any year since the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> began charting such statistics in 1961, despite a 300 percent increase in the number of pleasure crafts in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> waters. `` Without a doubt, the waters are safer,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dane </PERSON>, government relations manager at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's a dramatic improvement.'' The fatality rate, which peaked at 20.2 deaths per 100,000 boats in 1971, was 5.5 per 100,000 boats last year, according to <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> documents. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said 946 recreational boaters died in 1988, the first time the number fatalities has dipped below 1,000. The number of boats, meanwhile, has increased from less than 6 million to an estimated 17.3 million. But not everyone believes the fatality statistics are a reflection of a safer boating environment. `` I dare say the waters are probably less safe than they were 20 years ago,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Sciulla </PERSON>, vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Boat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Owners </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which represents 310,000 recreational boat owners. `` I hear from many boat owners that they are fearful of drunk boaters, that they are fearful of boat owners who do n't know the rules of the road, and they're fearful because of the increasing congestion of boats on our waterways.'' And congestion, it seems, will only get worse. In 1961, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> estimated that there were 5.85 million pleasure crafts in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> waters. The estimate for 1988 was 17.3 million, a threefold increase. `` Boating is approaching a $ 20 billion industry,'' <PERSON> Sciulla </PERSON> said. `` Seventy-five million Americans hop in a boat -LRB- at least -RRB- once a year. It's become an extraordinarily popular pastime over the past few decades.'' The boating explosion over the past 25 years may explain another <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> statistic that stands in stark contrast to the declining fatality rate: the rising number of reported accidents and reported injuries. Reported boating injuries increased from 2,757 in 1985 to 3,476 three years later. Boating officials, however, are quick to point out that only about 10 percent of the non-fatal marine accidents are reported. `` When the figures change, it's not easy to tell if there are more or less accidents or better reporting or other factors. It's hard to draw conclusions,'' said <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Marmo </PERSON>, assistant chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>'s auxiliary, boating and consumer affairs division Even if congestion is causing more accidents and injuries, most experts agree the steadily declining fatality rate is impressive. The first turning point in recreational marine safety came in 1971 when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> passed a sweeping safety law that included mandatory federal standards for boat construction. In the 11 years before the law was enacted, the annual fatality rate was 19.8 per 100,000 boats. Over the next 17 years, the average fatality rate was less than 10 per 100,000 boats. After dipping dramatically in the first five years following enactment of the federal law, from 20.2 to 9.9 per 100,000 boats, the fatality rate leveled off through the late 1970s. The rate, however, continued its downward spiral during the 1980s, from 9.5 in 1980 to 5.5 last year. Coast Guard Capt. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Griswold </PERSON>, chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>'s auxiliary, boating and consumer affairs division, attributes much of the recent decrease to public awareness programs targeting drunkenness at sea
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 1224EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Panama-US Bjt   07-02 0604</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-US, Bjt,0627</SECOND>
<HEAD>American Move to Bases a Further Blow to Panama's Economy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELOY O. AGUILAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> servicemen and civilians finished moving over the weekend onto <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bases, widening the rift with the regime of Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military's <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> says the move is intended to `` maintain a low military profile in the face of harassment by the <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> in recent months.'' It also seems designed to increase pressure on <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to step down as chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s de facto leader. It will deprive the country's already battered economy of about $ 60 million a year the Americans were spending. They will now make purchases in stores and other facilities within the Southern Command. A total of 6,400 Americans, including dependents, were involved in the move, which was ordered in May by the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> when violence broke out after the May 7 presidential election. Government opponents and international observers said opposition candidates won the vote by 3-1. But <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> voided the results, alleging interference in the campaign by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government, which has been trying to oust him since his indictment in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> last year on drug trafficking charges. The move to military bases involved not only servicemen, but also civilian employees of the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> and its various branches. All had been living in houses and apartments off-base. On-base, unmarried personnel are assigned to regular barracks, while married people and families live in military housing. The biggest complaint is lack of privacy. Civilians especially were reluctant to move. One civilian employee of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said they did `` not see the reason for it, since this was not a war zone.'' However, there were 55 reports of harassment by Panamanian authorities in May and six in June. They included the detention of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel who were questioned by police in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> for alleged petty offenses and then released. The mass move also disappointed some Panamanians who profited from the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> presence off-base. `` It is going to be hard to rent those apartments again soon,'' said a superintendent of one 34-unit apartment building. It was leased early this year by the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> for its servicemen and employees. A real estate agent, who like the superintendent spoke on condition of anonymity, said the building owners went into debt to finance improvements _ special water tanks, air conditioning, security _ as conditions for a contract with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military. `` They thought they were looking at long-term contracts,'' the agent said. The Americans were paying $ 15 million a year in rents alone in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. Their rent and the other money they spent helped keep this country's economy barely afloat after more than a year of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic sanctions imposed following <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s indictment. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> was a leading international financial center with about 120 banks holding an estimated $ 30 billion in assets. A flight of capital caused by the more than yearlong political struggle over <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s rule has reduced assets to about $ 8 billion, according to government figures. Opposition leaders say unemployment last year more than doubled to 23 percent. In March, Acting President <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON> said U.S.-imposed sanctions, which barred payments to the government, caused a 20 percent drop in the gross national product in 1988. A total of 12,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel are on duty in the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>'s 10 <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> installations in this country. The troops include 2,000 sent in May by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to protect <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> interests after the election.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 1225EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Israel-Suicides     07-02 0336</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel-Suicides,0346</SECOND>
<HEAD>35 Soldiers A Year Commit Suicide In The Israeli Army</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 35 soldiers in the Israeli army commit suicide each year, the head of the army's personnel department said in a newspaper interview published Sunday. Thirty-two soldiers committed suicide from April 1988 to April 1989, Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Matan </PERSON> <PERSON> Vilnai </PERSON> told the daily <ORGANIZATION> Haaretz </ORGANIZATION>. The military command confirmed the figures. <PERSON> Vilnai </PERSON>'s interview was a departure from the military's customary reluctance to provide such data, which could have a negative effect on soldiers' morale. No figures on attempted suicides were given. The newspaper and army said the average of 35 suicides was for recent years, but they did not say which years. Neither <PERSON> Vilnai </PERSON> nor the military command knew if any of the suicides were related to the 18-month-old Palestinian uprising against Israeli rule in the occupied <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Vilnai </PERSON> said 30 percent of those who killed themselves were reservists troubled by family and financial problems. They are pushed into the act by the availability of weapons and the hope that relatives will get financial compensation from the army, he said. Israeli men are drafted at the age of 18 for a three-year period of regular duty, and serve up to 40 days a year as reservists until age 55. Women are drafted for two years of regular service, and some of them are required to serve as reservists afterward. The Tel Aviv-based <ORGANIZATION> Jaffee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> says <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has a 170,000-strong standing army and 370,000 reserves. <PERSON> Vilnai </PERSON> said an average of two to three female soldiers commit suicide every year. He said most of the regular soldiers who have killed themselves did so during the first year of their military duty. <ORGANIZATION> Haaretz </ORGANIZATION> said the army's personnel department recently issued instructions on how to spot troubled soldiers to prevent suicides. However, the paper said `` This activity is quite limited since it is feared that dealing with the question of suicide may in fact increase the number of suicides.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 1241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Baker-Asia     07-02 0233</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Baker-Asia,230</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baker Heading To Tokyo For Meeting With Aid Donor Nations</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> sets out Monday for <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> where he will meet with representatives of other aid donor nations to discuss expanding economic assistance to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. The so-called Multilateral Assistance Initiative envisions $ 1 billion a year from aid donors over the next five years as well as foreign investments totaling a similar amount. Aside from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, representatives from the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, among others, are expected to attend. The meeting is being hosted by the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>. After a one-day visit to <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> heads for <LOCATION> Brunei </LOCATION> where he will meet with foreign ministers of the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Asian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> The major topics are expected to be the evolving situation in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the status of international efforts to promote a peaceful settlement to the <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> conflict. The <ORGANIZATION> ASEAN </ORGANIZATION> members are <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Brunei </LOCATION>. Afterward, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> heads for <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> where he will join President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> next Sunday at the start of his four-nation European visit. En route, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> will spend a day and a half in <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION>. The visit there is described as both a rest stop and also an opportunity to meet with officials of the government of <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION>, with which the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has had close ties for years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 1242EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-JazzFestival     07-02 0507</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jazz Festival,0520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Latin Jazz Stars Jam At JVC Jazz Festival</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RAEBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Latin jazz night has become a fixture at the annual <ORGANIZATION> JVC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jazz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Festival </ORGANIZATION>, and Saturday night's edition provided a fine cross-section of jazz, salsa and entertaining combinations of the two. The headliners were the Fania Six, all-star musicians from <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>. They were preceded by flutist <PERSON> Herbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>, whose 35-year career has been on the rise during the last few years since he formed the Brazilian group <ORGANIZATION> Brasil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jazz </ORGANIZATION>. The evening was opened _ and nearly stolen _ by the fiery Dominican jazz pianist <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Camilo </PERSON>. The crowded bill limited <PERSON> Camilo </PERSON>'s set to about half an hour, but in that time he generated enough energy to light a town of 10,000 for a week. <PERSON> Camilo </PERSON>'s command of the piano is unlike anything else heard in jazz. He is a consummate technician. Yet he keeps his technique under the tightest control, never allowing it to outrun his musical ideas. He played only his own compositions, taken from his latest album. The tunes revealed him to be a composer of considerable depth and inventiveness, particularly in the beautiful ballad `` Nostalgia.'' He introduced as his special guest <PERSON> Paquito </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Rivera </PERSON>, in whose group <PERSON> Camilo </PERSON> first came to prominence. The two have recorded together but no longer tour together. But they have n't lost their rapport; <PERSON> D'Rivera </PERSON> was ready to match <PERSON> Camilo </PERSON>'s fireworks. <PERSON> Herbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>'s group was a disappointment, but that may not have been entirely his fault. The restraint and sophistication of <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>'s Brazilian-inflected group was a poor choice to follow <PERSON> Camilo </PERSON> Although <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> is the bigger name, he should have opened for <PERSON> Camilo </PERSON>. His second problem was a poorly adjusted sound system. The bass, critical for the rhythmic sway of Brazilian music, was inaudible through much of <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>'s set. He repeatedly indicated to off-stage technicians that he could n't hear himself play, but the problem apparently was never corrected His special guest was <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Valentin </PERSON>, a flutist who <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> recalled encouraging when <PERSON> Valentin </PERSON> was 16. Despite the sound problems, <PERSON> Valentin </PERSON>'s arrival on stage gave <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>'s group some needed energy, and it became clear that the group had not been at its best. The highlight of the evening was the last set by the Fania Six, a group of Puerto Rican musicians -LRB- some of them based in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> -RRB- associated with the Fania record label. They are <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Pacheco </PERSON> on flute and vocals, <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Barretto </PERSON> on congas, <LOCATION> Papo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lucca </LOCATION> on piano, <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Valentin </PERSON> on bass, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Roena </PERSON> on bongos and <PERSON> Nicky </PERSON> <PERSON> Marrero </PERSON> on timbales. This was classic salsa. They rhythms were irresistible, the melodies engaging and the solos impressive. <PERSON> Pacheco </PERSON> made part of the set into a flute extravaganza when he invited <PERSON> Valentin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> on stage. The three flutists played off one another, reaching peaks they could n't have scaled alone. It was one of those special moments that can occur in jazz festivals, in which artists who do n't normally perform together are suddenly thrust on stage at the same time.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 1321EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-HongKong-Britain     07-02 0549</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hong Kong-Britain,0563</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thousands Protest British Snub</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of people shouting `` Shame, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>! Shame!'' protested the arrival of British Foreign Secretary <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> on Sunday and denounced his country's refusal to give refuge to <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> residents. `` <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> go home,'' a crowd of about 10,000 chanted as they raised their fists in front of <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, where <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> is staying on his three-day fact-finding mission. `` Justice for the people of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>!'' About 5,000 protesters also massed at the airport and about 1,000 mostly Western residents held their own rally in support of the protesters. The military crackdown on pro-democracy student protesters in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has caused much apprehension in this British colony, which is to revert to Chinese rule in 1997. Last week, the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Britain </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION> rejected a proposal to allow British passport holders in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> to emigrate to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> About 3.5 million of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>'s 5.7 million people hold British passports. <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> citizens believe that <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> can not be trusted to live up to its promise to keep <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>'s capitalist system intact for 50 years after 1997. In brief remarks upon his arrival, <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> did not raise the issue of mass immigration from <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. He said he had come here to `` reaffirm British determination to secure a democratic and prosperous future for <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>.'' `` You have no stauncher friend than <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` The whole world has condemned the violence and repression we've all witnessed in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> over the last few weeks,'' he added `` Nowhere has that view been more vigorously expressed than in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. You feel threatened and beleaguered by what has happened, so that's why I'm here.'' <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> said the British government believed that the 1984 British-Chinese agreement to return <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> `` still provides the right foundations'' for the future. At the airport, demonstration leaders gave <PERSON> Howe </PERSON>'s personal secretary a petition with about 600,000 signatures pressing for the right to emigrate to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. The protest organizer, the Rev. Lo <PERSON> Lung </PERSON> <PERSON> Kwong </PERSON>, said demonstrators were `` extremely dissatisfied'' that <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> did not accept the petition himself. `` We feel that he does not seem to have the courage to face the <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> people personally,'' he said. Earlier, about 1,000 Westerners gathered in central <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> to protest <PERSON> Howe </PERSON>'s visit. `` I've lived here for about 12 years and I consider <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> home,'' said <PERSON> Gasper </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> businessman who came to the rally with his two sons, both born in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. `` <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> is selling these people down the river. If they do n't act and act fast, <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> as a trading center, as a financial center, is finished. All the bright people in my company have left or are leaving.'' Another 10,000 people marched through <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> to the Government House, carrying signs that read, `` <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> can you sleep at night?'' and `` End to British honor?'' `` I fled the communists in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> in 1975,'' said <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Ho </PERSON> <PERSON> Fat </PERSON>, a restaurateur who was marching with his family of six. `` I look at these hooligans in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and ask myself, ` Am I going to have to flee them again?' We need an assurance _ the right to live in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> would help.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890702-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-89 1339EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-France-Gorbachev     07-02 0655</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-France-Gorbachev,0674</SECOND>
<HEAD>Disarmament, Trade To Be Discussed During Gorbachev Visit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SYDNEY RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
