<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 2331EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Barry-Taxes     04-17 0292</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Barry-Taxes,290</SECOND>
<HEAD>Barry Filed Federal Tax Returns Late</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 District of <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> Mayor <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> filed his federal income tax returns late in the early 1980s even though he had a refund coming each year, according to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. The newspaper quoted an unnamed source as saying that <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> waited until 1986 to file his 1982, 1983 and 1984 federal returns. Other sources told the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> filed several returns in 1986 but could not confirm the years. <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> declined a request by the newspaper to be interviewed about his tax returns. His press secretary, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, released a statement that <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>'s returns are filed every year. `` First, my taxes are a personal matter between myself and the federal and district governments. Second, my taxes are filed every year by my accountant in the year in which they are due. Third, it is a violation of law for someone to give out my tax returns other than myself,'' <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> said in a statement. The mayor, who has refused to publicly release copies of his tax returns since he was elected in 1978, filed late `` largely because of procrastination,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, in its Tuesday editions, quoted one of <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>'s associates as saying. Failure to file a federal income tax return is a misdemeanor and each count carries a possible one-year prison sentence. Although <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>'s federal returns for 1982, 1983 and 1984 were late, he apparently filed his <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> returns on time for those years, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said. <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> records show that <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> filed his 1982, 1983 and 1984 returns in the year in which each return was due, according a source familier with District tax records. <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> received <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> refunds for each of the years except 1982.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Philippines-Victim     04-17 0345</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Philippines-Victim,0353</SECOND>
<HEAD>Victim Wakes Screaming from Dreams of Torture</HEAD>
<BYLINE>With PM-Philippines-Rights, Bjt ^By EILEEN GUERRERO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAGAWE, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Her own screams wake <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Aniban </PERSON> from nightmares about military captors connecting wires to her thumbs, toes and breasts and sending jolts of electricity through her naked body. Miss Aniban, 26, a volunteer for the church-affiliated Task Force Detainees, said she and a male colleague were arrested in November and accused of being couriers for communist rebels. She denies it. She said she was interrogated at three military camps in the <LOCATION> Baguio </LOCATION> area, where they were arrested, and her captors tried to rape her three times. `` They tied my toes, thumbs and nipples with electric wires and then they plugged it into a socket,'' she said. `` They did it to me repeatedly and I fainted so many times. `` They took off my clothes and made me sit on a wet bed. I had my hands tied in the back and a pillow over my mouth. I screamed, and I felt like a chicken being butchered.'' After three days, Miss Aniban and her colleague were released. She said they had signed statements saying they were rebels and agreeing to serve as military informants. She said she did not file charges against her captors because whe felt it would be useless. Last year, she convinced her younger brother <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> to leave the rebels and he was shot to death five months later. As she cradled her dying brother in her arms, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Aniban </PERSON> said, he told her his assailants were pro-government militiamen. The family filed charges with the government <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> and a civil court, but no hearings have been held. Her experiences made her bitter. Although she works for a human rights group organized to monitor abuses under <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, the exiled former president, she now opposes <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, his successor. `` I expected my work to be risky, but I did not expect it could still happen under the new government,'' she said. `` Now, she is no longer my president.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0008EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MickeyMouseClub Bjt   04-17 0594</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mickey Mouse Club, Bjt,0609</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Disney Show Keeps Pace With The Times</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By IKE FLORES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAKE BUENA VISTA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Annette </PERSON> <PERSON> Funicello </PERSON> is gone, and so are <PERSON> Sherry </PERSON>, Cubby, <PERSON> Darlene </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON>. But <PERSON> Chase </PERSON> <PERSON> Hampton </PERSON> knocks'em dead with a calypso song-and-dance number. And <PERSON> Josh </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Tiffini </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Lindsey </PERSON>, <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> and the gang get the studio jumping with a rap-and-disco blend of M-I-C-K-E-Y-M-O-U-S-E. The `` <ORGANIZATION> Mickey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>'' is back. And although its style has been updated, the people at <ORGANIZATION> Walt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> say it's just as good and relevant as the original television show was when it began 34 years ago. `` We had a lot of skepticism about doing the ` <ORGANIZATION> Mickey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>' in the 1990s,'' said <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Fields </PERSON>, senior vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Channel </ORGANIZATION>, which will carry the show `` But so many elements -LRB- of the old show -RRB- were terrific, and kids still relate to kids.'' Just like its predecessor, the new show is for and by kids from about ages 8 to 12 and features music, dancing, comedy skits, celebrity guests and the <ORGANIZATION> Mickey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> movie. The comedy skits are often geared to preteens' problems: dating, sibling rivalry, messy rooms, homework. `` It's trying to say: ` Hey, it's not easy being a kid. ... We're going to make you laugh and reduce some of the stress,''' said <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Clements </PERSON>, executive producer The show is designed to provide `` education through entertainment,'' but the accent is clearly on the latter, <PERSON> Clements </PERSON> says. `` It's all great fun. There are no messages that are knocked into people's heads, no public service announcements about drugs or anything like that,'' he said. `` This is my dream job,'' said head writer <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Silberberg </PERSON>, who has a master's degree in education from <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` We take entertainment and use it to educate about kids issues. ... The show gives them a sense that they're not alone out there.'' There's one big difference from the 1950s show _ cartoons have been replaced by music videos. One of the early episodes features a jazzy song-and-dance number on a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> street set. Another innovation is a segment in which club members from around the country are selected to spend a day with their special heros. Among the celebrities taped so far are <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> pitcher <PERSON> Orel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hershiser </PERSON>, model <PERSON> Christie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brinkley </PERSON> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> developer <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>. In one segment, 13-year-old <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> goes to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s Trump Plaza to talk with the developer about his business life and disciplinary problems that caused him to be sent to a military academy. Dressed in a suit and tie and calling himself a `` winner,'' the teen-ager asks for advice about investing $ 250 he has saved. <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> tells him to put it in a bank until he is older. At the end, <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> presents <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> with a pair of <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Mouse </PERSON> ears, which he adjusts over his carefully combed locks. The show is being taped before audiences at the new Disney-MGM Studios complex in central <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and will be televised exclusively on the <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Channel </ORGANIZATION>, which has about 4 million subscribers. Fields said this will give <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> more control without having to worry about ratings. Talent scouts held auditions for about 5,000 kids around the country before selecting the lucky dozen featured on the show. The not-so-grown-up hosts are <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>, an actor, writer and comedian, and <PERSON> Mowava </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, a former camp counselor with theater experience who has appeared in dozens of television commercials. The <ORGANIZATION> Mickey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> makes its debut April 24. The half-hour show will be shown weekday afternoons.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0005EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-WinerySlayings 2ndLd-Writethru a0718 04-17 0806</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Winery Slayings, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0718,0825</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hunt For Suspected Killer Of 7, Including 2 Daughters Found In Trash</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 6th graf, `Salcido has...,' with 5 grafs to UPDATE with
owners of winery offering reward, establishing trust fund for daughter,
other victim, discounting reports that Salcido was about to be fired. Picks
up 7th graf, `Carmina, her...' DELETES outdated 22nd graf, `The Grand...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANTHONY MARQUEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GLEN ELLEN, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 3-year-old girl, the survivor of a rampage that claimed her mother, grandmother, two sisters, two aunts and an unrelated man, was showered with toys Sunday as she recovered from a slashed throat. Lawmen hunted her father, 28-year-old winery worker <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Salcido </PERSON>, from <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. The object of compassion was 3-year-old <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON> <PERSON> Salcido </PERSON>, who was rescued bleeding and barely conscious Saturday from a wine country dump between <LOCATION> Petaluma </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sonoma </LOCATION>, near the bodies of her two sisters, whose throats also were cut. <PERSON> Salcido </PERSON> has been hunted since Friday morning when officers discovered the bodies of his wife, <PERSON> Angela </PERSON>, 24, at their <LOCATION> Boyes </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> home; his mother-in-law and her two young daughters at their home in <LOCATION> Cotati </LOCATION>; and a co-worker at the Grand Cru Winery. Police have not yet pieced together the sequence of killings. `` We've got to find him, we've got to find him,'' <LOCATION> Sonoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Michaelsen </PERSON> mumbled at a news conference Saturday after the discovery of <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON> and her sisters. On Sunday, the owners of the Grand Cru Winery, where <PERSON> Salcido </PERSON> worked as a forklift operator, offered a $ 5,000 reward for information leading to his capture. `` These atrocities have caused fear and terror to invade an area known for its beauty and hospitality,'' <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bettina </PERSON> <PERSON> Dreyer </PERSON> said in a statement. The couple also established a trust fund for both <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON> <PERSON> Salcido </PERSON> and for the family of <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Toovey </PERSON>, an assistant winemaker at <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cru </LOCATION>, who was shot to death in Friday's rampage. <PERSON> Salcido </PERSON> has been described by neighbors as a hostile gun-toter who drank a lot, a husband who harbored chronic, towering jealousy of his attractive wife _ to the point that he drove home from work several times a day to spy on her. Despite reports of <PERSON> Salcido </PERSON>'s having problems at work, however, <PERSON> Dreyer </PERSON> remembered his employee as a `` very competent'' worker who was `` quick to please.'' <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON>, her throat cut nearly from ear to ear, and her dead sisters, <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON>, 1, and <LOCATION> Sofia </LOCATION>, 4, were found near a landfill transfer station not far from where <PERSON> Salcido </PERSON> had fled with them Friday. <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON>, also suffering exposure and dehydration, was flown to <LOCATION> Petaluma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, where she told deputies her father had slashed her sisters and herself. After two hours of surgery, <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON> was in stable condition. `` She's still in stable condition and doing well,'' nursing supervisor <PERSON> Stasia </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> said Sunday. `` Different people have sent stuffed animals. She has a teddy bears and a couple of bunnies.'' Doctors said she suffered some vocal cord damage but is expected to recover. A trust fund was being established for <PERSON> Carmina </PERSON> in a <LOCATION> Sonoma </LOCATION> bank. <PERSON> Michaelsen </PERSON> said <PERSON> Salcido </PERSON> is the only suspect in the killings. A ranch worker who was shot in a shoulder, apparently the first person attacked, had alerted authorities, sending them first to the winery where they found one man shot to death. At a news conference Friday, <PERSON> Michaelsen </PERSON> said a department psychologist had warned that the savagery of the slayings indicated <PERSON> Salcido </PERSON> `` no longer felt any affection or attachment to his own children.'' The three girls were spotted in a ravine near the dump by a man working on his truck. `` At first he thought they were dolls,'' the sheriff said. The man, unidentified, called to a worker from the dump and the two found `` yet another horrible scene,'' <PERSON> Michaelsen </PERSON> said. `` I tried to talk to the little girl who was still alive and I tried to comfort her,'' said the dump worker, <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. `` Her throat was nearly cut from ear to ear.'' Autopsies performed Saturday in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> revealed that Mrs. <PERSON> Salcido </PERSON> had been shot, and her mother had been shot and her throat was slashed, the sheriff's office reported. Mrs. <PERSON> Salcido </PERSON>'s two sisters, age 8 and 12, died of throat wounds apparently inflicted with a knife and had been raped and sodomized, <PERSON> Michaelsen </PERSON> said. A friend and a neighbor described <PERSON> Salcido </PERSON> as fiercely jealous of his wife. `` He's crazy. He was always going around with a gun,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, a next-door neighbor to the Salcidos. `` I could see it coming.'' `` One time he threatened to blow -LRB- his wife's -RRB- head off,'' he added. During the past week, <PERSON> Salcido </PERSON> was served with a <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> court order to pay $ 511 a month child support to his ex-wife in <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION> and nearly $ 6,000 for back support payments, according to court papers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0306EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--ToweringFacelift     04-17 0148</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Towering Facelift,0152</SECOND>
<HEAD>$6 Million Renovation for LA Landmark</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Moviegoers remember its destruction by Martian invaders in `` War of the Worlds'' and TV viewers knew it as the Daily Planet in the `` Superman'' series. But for millions, the city's most recognizable landmark, the Byzantine-style City Hall tower, has been the center of government in the nation's second largest city. The 27-story building, the area's tallest structure through the 1950s but now dwarfed by skyscrapers twice its size, is about to get a facelift. Built in 1928 at $ 5 million, City Hall will soon undergo a $ 6 million makeover that includes illuminating the building at night. The renovation also includes a museum to display hundreds of gifts that the city has received, many from visiting dignitaries. Project Restore, a nonprofit organization of business and civic leaders, has raised about $ 1.5 million toward the project.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Zimbabwe     04-17 0662</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Zimbabwe,0683</SECOND>
<HEAD>Zimbabwe Marks Ninth Birthday With Little to Cheer About</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN EDLIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HARARE, Zimbabwe (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Once hailed as a rare success story in a continent plagued by coups, civil wars and corruption, this country enters its 10th year of independence Tuesday with little of the jubilation that marked its birth. When President <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mugabe </PERSON> led the white-ruled British colony of <LOCATION> Rhodesia </LOCATION> to independence as black-governed <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION> on April 18, 1980, he inherited one of the healthiest agriculture-based economies in black <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. After having waged a bloody, seven-year guerrilla war for control of his homeland, he promised the 100,000 whites and 9 million blacks peace and prosperity. Many analysts believed <PERSON> Mugabe </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION> could serve as an example for the white rulers of neighboring <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, who maintain their black majority is not ready to run the country. Today, though still black <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s most prosperous nation, <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION> is ailing. The economy is hemhorraging through shortages of foreign currency and a lack of foreign investment, both symptoms of bad policy making. Exporters who earn hard currency complain they get little encouragement from the government, and because there is no investment code the only significant foreign capital has been plowed into a baked beans cannery and a bubble-gum factory. The leadership of <PERSON> Mugabe </PERSON>'s avowedly egalitarian and socialist state is crippled, thanks to a series of corruption scandals. Five Cabinet ministers, a provincial governor and a junior minister have resigned and several others face prosecution in the latest scandal, the black marketeering of cars and trucks. A war in neighboring <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION> is bleeding this country's treasury to the tune of half a million dollars a day The 12,000 Zimbabwean troops there are guarding supply lines vital to landlocked <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>'s survival. At home, unprecedented popular discontent is growing over a host of ills ranging from official greed and economic mismanagement to record unemployment and galloping inflation. And homeless blacks often complain that land hunger, the main cause of the war for independence, remains nine years later. While 160,000 families were promised plots, only 40,000 have actually been resettled. On the credit side, <PERSON> Mugabe </PERSON>, 65, a onetime cattle herder and school teacher, has fulfilled his promises of cheap education for all and free health care for the poor, who comprise most of the population. He also instilled national pride in the black majority that had been subjugated by colonizers for nine decades, crushed a rebellion by armed dissidents in the <LOCATION> Matabeleland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Province </LOCATION> of western <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION> and ended a feud with his old political foe, <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON> <PERSON> Nkomo </PERSON>. The two signed an accord that will unite their parties in the next year as a prelude to establishing a one-party state in one of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s few Western-style democracies. But there has been mounting criticism that it could transform <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION> into a leftist dictatorship, like <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>, where the vote Zimbabweans fought for will be worthless. `` The leadership is rotten, and it will get more rotten in a one-party state,'' says <PERSON> Edgar </PERSON> <PERSON> Tekere </PERSON>, 52, a founder of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Zimbabwe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> and now its most vocal critic. <PERSON> Tekere </PERSON>, fired from the 15-member Politburo and the 90-strong <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in October after he denounced top-level corruption, represents <PERSON> Mugabe </PERSON>'s only real political challenge. He has won widespread popular support for his stand. Public hostility toward elected leaders has grown in the last few years as politicians have vaunted their wealth, power, position and privileges. Cabinet ministers last year voted themselves earnings 20 times the statutory minimum wage of $ 50 monthly, which they also set. Most own several homes and farms, have interests in stores, hotels and other businesses, drive around in chauffeured limousines and frequently travel abroad to buy luxury items not available at home. `` In our pubs we do n't talk much about anything else but crooked politicians,'' said <PERSON> Oddwell </PERSON> <PERSON> Mlambo </PERSON>, 34, an unemployed laborer. `` No one attacks <PERSON> Mugabe </PERSON> himself, but if there were elections tomorrow, just about all his <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> would be thrown out.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0040EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Poll-Method     04-17 0592</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poll-Method,0606</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Poll-Abortion, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General-Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> poll is based on telephone interviews conducted March 6 through March 15 with 1,108 adults in the continental <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Phone numbers were selected randomly and interviews were conducted with the adult who had the most recent birthday, a random phenomenon. The results were weighted to adjust for variations in the sample. The poll has a 3-point margin of error, meaning that if every adult American were asked the same questions, the results theoretically would be within 3 points of the poll's results, 19 times out of 20. The error margin is larger for subgroups. There are other sources of potential error in polls, including the wording and order of questions. These are the questions in this poll; because of rounding, sums may not total 100: 1. If a woman wants to have an abortion and her doctor agrees to it, should she be allowed to have an abortion, or not? Yes: 65 percent. No: 25 percent. Do n't know or no answer: 10 percent. 2. Should abortion be legal as it is now; legal only in such cases as rape, incest, or to save the life of the mother; or should it not be permitted at all? As now: 50. In cases: 39. Not at all: 7. Do n't know-No answer: 4. 3. Would you favor or oppose a constitutional amendment that would make abortions illegal except in cases of rape, incest or to save the life of the mother? Favor: 44. Oppose: 50. Do n't know-No Answer: 5. 4. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled in 1973 that states can not prevent a woman from having an abortion if she wants one at any time during the first three months of pregnancy. Do you favor or oppose that ruling? Favor: 53. Oppose: 41. Do n't know-No Answer: 6. 5. If the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> reversed its 1973 ruling and let each state make its own abortion laws, abortion could become legal in some states and illegal in others. Would you want abortion to be legal or illegal in your state? Legal: 57. Illegal: 37. Do n't know-No Answer: 7 6. If abortion was illegal in your state, do you think that would stop most women there who want abortions from having them, or would most of them go to another state where it was legal? Stop: 7. Go: 87. Do n't know-No Answer: 6. 7. If abortion was illegal in every state, do you think that would stop most women who want abortions from having them, or would most of them have illegal abortions or go to another country for abortions? Stop: 20. Go: 73. Do n't know-No Answer: 7. 8. A group that opposes abortion has been holding demonstrations where its members block the entrances to abortion clinics until the police arrest them and carry them off. How do you feel about these demonstrations _ support them strongly, support them, oppose them, or oppose them strongly? Support strongly: 4. Support: 18. Oppose: 37. Oppose strongly: 30. Do n't know-No Answer: 11. 9. A pill is now available in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> that stops pregnancy by preventing the fertilized egg from becoming implanted in the uterine wall. Do you think this drug should be legal in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, or not? Yes: 51. No: 24. DK-NA: 25. 10. I'd like to ask your opinion on this statement: The government should help a poor woman with her medical bills if she wants an abortion. Please tell me whether you agree or disagree. Agree: 41. Disagree: 49. Do n't know-No Answer: 11.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-SriLanka 1stLd-Writethru a0702 04-17 0405</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sri Lanka, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0702,0411</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bombs in Sri Lanka Kill One, Injure 20 After Offer for Talks</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 4th pvs, `The blasts..., to ADD background
on Premadasa accepting rebel offer. Pick up 5th pvs, `The talks... DELETES
8th graf to conform.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PATRICK CRUEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLOMBO, Sri Lanka (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A series of bomb blasts in this city's crowded commercial center killed one person and injured 20 Sunday, the fifth day of a government-called cease-fire, authorities said No one took immediate responsibility for the bomb blasts. Both Tamil militants and majority Sinhalese extremists have carried out their own campaigns of terror. Police said all the victims were Tamil, and most of the injured were in critical condition. The blasts came in the wake of an offer for peace talks by Tamil rebels. A spokesman for President <PERSON> Ranasinghe </PERSON> <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> called the rebel offer `` a major breakthrough'' shortly after it was made Saturday. <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> responded by asking the <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tamil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eelam </ORGANIZATION>, the largest and most powerful Tamil rebel group, to send their leaders to meet with him. Presidential press secretary <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooray </PERSON> said a message had been sent to <PERSON> Anton </PERSON> <PERSON> Balasingham </PERSON>, political leader of the group, asking him to choose representatives for the talks. The Tamils made their offer hours after an ambush blamed on the rebels left 21 soldiers dead. The attack raied to 79 the number of people killed in three days of violence. Two of the bombs went off near a stand for buses bound for northern <LOCATION> Jaffna </LOCATION> town, a Tamil stronghold, police said. All the casualties occurred there. Another bomb, also placed in a bag and left on the sidewalk, exploded near a building where a former Tamil rebel group that has now joined the political mainstream kept its offices, police said. The building was damaged. Militant Tamils are waging a war against the government for an independent state. At least 10,000 people have been killed since the Tamil insurrection started in 1983. The Tamils claim they suffer discrimination at the hands of mostly Buddhist Sinhalese, who make up 75 percent of the population and control the government and military. Tamils, who are mostly Hindus, comprise 18 percent of <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>'s 16 million people. <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> ordered a one-week cease-fire and offered amnesty to rebels willing to surrender arms in an effort to curb the ethnic violence that has plagued this <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> island.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Malaysia-Ads     04-17 0201</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Malaysia-Ads,0206</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Banning TV Ads That Show Only Non-Malaysians</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government is banning racy television advertisements and commercials that show only non-Malaysian models, the information minister said in an interview published today. Beginning July 1, Caucasian and other non-Malaysian models can continue to appear in commercials only if the ads also include Malays, Chinese, Indians or other races that predominate in <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>, said Information Minister <PERSON> Mohamed </PERSON> <PERSON> Rahmat </PERSON>. `` We have told advertisers that if the cast is a mix of Caucasian, Pan-Asian and some of the multi-racial groups in <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>, we will allow the commercials to appear,'' <PERSON> Rahmat </PERSON> said in an interview published in the New Straits Times daily. Commercials with women in swimsuits and scanty clothing will also be banned in this country Islam where is the official religion. Of the country's three TV channels, two are owned by the government and the other belongs to the ruling party. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Tang </PERSON>, Association of Accredited Advertising Agents of <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> President, said the ban was `` a little too harsh and debatable'' and called for the review of the ban. <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>'s 17 million population is 55 percent Malay and 37 percent Chinese, with the remainder mainly Indian.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TaxDay Bjt   04-17 0570</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tax Day, Bjt,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>IRS, Late Filers Both Putting in Overtime Today</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> employees put in overtime, post offices set up special mail drops and demonstrators made their cases as the nation prepared to end another federal tax return filing season at midnight tonight. <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> had no way of knowing how many taxpayers were waiting until the last minute to file. But the agency expects to receive 18 million returns this week, including those filed over the weekend, he said. The deadline is one day later in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and most of upstate <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> because today is Patriot's Day, a legal holiday, in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, site of the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> center which processes returns from taxpayers in those states. The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> expects to receive more than 109 million returns this year, many of which will come in well after the deadline. About 6 million couples and individuals are expected to get an extra four months to file _ but not to pay any taxes due _ by mailing Form 4868 before midnight. Many of the 650,000 Americans who live and work abroad are likely to take an automatic two-month extension. And, as usual, some taxpayers simply will miss the deadline and face a late-filing penalty. In many <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> offices, employees planned to continue offering advice tonight as long as taxpayers were asking for it. The Postal Service was doing its part by setting up booths at ballparks, selling stamps by the curb, and cooperating with radio stations and civic groups that were offering refreshments around post offices in an effort to make things a little easier for procrastinators. Around the nation, the Jobs for Peace Campaign sent demonstrators into the streets to protest military spending. They planned to pass out `` Build Homes _ Not Bombs'' stickers for taxpayers to attach to the envelopes containing their tax returns. The campaign is urging support for a bill to finance more housing by cutting military spending. The group calculates that 52 cents of every tax dollar goes for military spending, retirement and interest on money borrowed to finance weapons. By government figuring, the military will take 27 percent of next year's budget, not including interest or pensions. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, Sen. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, R-Ore., repeated a tax-day act he has performed for 10 years: introducing a bill that would allow conscientious objectors to pay their taxes into a fund that would be spent for non-military purposes `` We recognize conscientious objection in time of war,'' <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON> said in a statement. `` It is now time to recognize it in time of peace.'' The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employees </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, which represents most <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> employees, issued a statement accusing the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration of failing to budget enough money to finance the tax-collection agency. Employee travel and training have been cut and technicians have been pressed into clerical work because of the tight budget, said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tobias </PERSON>, president of the union. By its actions, he said, the administration `` effectively declared April 17 a national holiday for tax cheaters.'' The Church of Scientology used the filing deadline as a way of reminding taxpayers of a new law designed to protect them when they have disputes with the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION>. The church, which has had its share of scraps with the agency, announced it has published a free guidebook to the `` Taxpayer Bill of Rights.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Nuke-Sleeping     04-17 0607</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuke-Sleeping,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nuke Plant Shut for Sleeping Operators Set to Reopen</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: meeting late afternoon EDT; top prospects uncertain</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The only nuclear plant ever shut down because control room operators slept on duty is ready to resume operations, amid signs that the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> will give its assent. An <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> order has kept the Peach Bottom plant in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> dormant for two years, but the commission planned a meeting for this afternoon along with a `` possible'' vote on reopening. Privately, commission officials said last week that all signs pointed to the plant gaining permission _ if not today, then shortly afterward _ to begin a slow ascension that would take it back to full power. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Murley </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s top reactor licensing official, declined to make a prediction Friday on the outcome of the meeting. But he said in an interview that the commission has seen significant progress in the management of the plant by <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> `` Clearly there have been big changes in the company, and it's a new company as far as <ORGANIZATION> Peach </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bottom </ORGANIZATION> is concerned,'' <PERSON> Murley </PERSON> said. `` The operators have been retrained and there appears to be a new attitude.'' As the only plant ever shut down because of operator negligence, <ORGANIZATION> Peach </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bottom </ORGANIZATION> is unique in the industry. Dealing with operators _ with people _ is vastly different than replacing equipment, and the shutdown has meant a review of the plant's entire management structure. The plant, located on the <LOCATION> Susquehanna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> near the <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> border, was ordered to stop producing power on March 31, 1987, by the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>, which said continued operation posed a public safety threat. A year later, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> stepped down as the utility's chairman and chief executive officer following criticism of the handling of Peach Bottom <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> has spent about $ 250 million in shutdown-related costs. The figure includes modifications to the plant, purchases of replacement power, and the company's share of a $ 1.25 million fine, the largest in <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> history. While the utility has shuffled its personnel, the changes at the plant have included more than just new faces. The company said management will play a broader role in day-to-day plant affairs than before. To end catnaps by operators, plant officials replaced comfortable, high-backed chairs in the control room with low-backed models. Operators' rotations have been changed so that workers do a week of days, followed by a week of an afternoon-evening shift, and then work the overnight. The rotation, which includes days off, used to go in the reverse order. The sleeping problems at Peach Bottom were not confined to a few workers. Last August, 33 present or former operators were fined $ 500 to $ 1,000 for `` sleeping and-or other acts of inattention to duty.'' `` We did n't set out to pick somebody and make an example of them,'' <PERSON> Murley </PERSON> said. `` It's just that the behavior we saw at Peach Bottom was so egregious that we felt we had no choice but to order them shut down. INPO -LRB- the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- came to same conclusion and put more pressure on the top management.'' INPO, an Atlanta-based nuclear watchdog group, termed the plant `` an embarrassment to the industry and the nation'' in 1988. But this year, the group said <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION>'s corrective actions at Peach Bottom have been `` responsive and effective.'' The utility said it would propose restarting one of its two working reactors, then seek permission to fire up the other one later this year. It would take a few months for either of the units to reach full power once approval is granted.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites SUB a0426 04-17 0307</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites, SUB, a0426,0314</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf of first item to CORRECT that 26,400 people live
in Cleveland, sted Bradley County</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some small towns aspire to bigger things. But folks in this one hope to get even smaller _ about a thousand pounds smaller. In a modern day battle of the bulge, about 200 people in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> _ population 26,400 _ and surrounding <LOCATION> Bradley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> are competing with residents of <LOCATION> Sac </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, to see who can shed the most. The competition is designed to promote the benefits of proper nutrition and exercise. `` The county that loses has to fly the flag of the other county for 30 days,'' says <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland-Bradley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wellness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which is sponsoring the effort. <LOCATION> Sac </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, a farming region of about 14,000 people in northwest <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, organized a mass slim-down two years ago to bolster morale during the farm crisis, says <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Sac </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tourism </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. Last year, nearly 800 participants walked or biked 286,686 miles and lost 6,438 pounds. That was enough to get national media attention. When <LOCATION> Bradley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> officials called for information, the Iowans issued their challenge and the meltdown was on. This year, more than 1,000 people from <LOCATION> Sac </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> are involved, including 543 who are competing against 203 Tennesseans. The <LOCATION> Sac </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> team weighed in at 78,851 pounds earlier this month; the <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> team tipped the scales at 36,926 pounds. Whichever teams loses the greatest percentage of weight by June 24 wins. Both counties feature competitions among individual teams with names like `` Bulge Busters.'' <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> says that's helped make things interesting. `` When you see 15 women get on a big scale and check in at over a ton, well, that's something,'' said <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Speakers'Woes     04-17 0862</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Speakers' Woes,840</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Echoes of a Speakers' Scandal Followed Blaine for
Life</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 On the morning of June 5, 1876, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON>, the speaker of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION>, stood in the well of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and waved a packet of letters in the air. <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON>, one of the nation's foremost politicians, was in serious trouble. And he was about to confound his accusers. Nearly 113 years later another speaker of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> _ faces accusations of unethical behavior in office. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> adamantly denies any wrongdoing. But he has been the subject of the most prolonged and intense of the several investigations conducted over the decades into the private and public affairs of a speaker of the House. Speaker <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON> rode out his scandal, but echoes of it were to follow him for the rest of his career. In the spring of 1876, <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON> was a frontrunner for the Republican presidential nomination in the election that would replace President <PERSON> Ulysses </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>'s corruption-ridden administration. Three years earlier Reps. <PERSON> Oakes </PERSON> <PERSON> Ames </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Mass </LOCATION>., and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, D-Mass., had been censured by the House for involvement in the so-called Credit Mobilier scandal in which railroad construction stock had been given to selected members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, allegedly for favors Now <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON> became embroiled in the scandal, facing accusations that the <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railroad </ORGANIZATION> had paid the speaker an inflated price for stock of a defunct and bankrupt rail line. An investigation was launched by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> but it was sputtering when new evidence emerged. It took the form of a set of letters between <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON> and a business partner which had come into the possession of a third man, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulligan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mulligan </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to testify before the committee, encountered an unexpected visitor at his hotel _ Speaker <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON>. According to <PERSON> Mulligan </PERSON>, an emotional session followed in which <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON> fell to his hands and knees and begged for the letters, threatening suicide if he did not receive them. <PERSON> Mulligan </PERSON> claimed <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON> obtained the letters by a pretext and left the hotel. An uproar followed and <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON> came under intense pressure to make the <PERSON> Mulligan </PERSON> letters public. He refused, claiming they were private property. Instead, he obtained a statement from two lawyers who said they had examined the letters and found nothing relevant to the investigation. The uproar continued and <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON> set about to defuse it. On June 5 he appeared on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor and waved the packet exclaiming, `` There they are. ... There are the original letters.'' <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON> then read aloud what he said were the contents of each of the letters. He said he had handed over `` every solitary scrap and scrimption'' for inclusion in the Congressional Record. They had, he declared, `` no more to do with that investigation than the North Pole.'' But no one was ever shown the originals of the letters to verify <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON>'s reading of them. Events moved rapidly. <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON> collapsed outside his church suffering from a possible heat stroke. The investigation was postponed for two weeks to await his recovery. But before the committee could reconvene, the governor of <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> appointed <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON> to fill a vacancy in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The investigation was postponed again, and eventually died. <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON>'s political backers proceeded, in classical <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> fashion, to make the best of a bad situation. In the 20th century it's called making lemonade out of a lemon. <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON>'s name was placed in nomination at the Republican National Convention by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ingersoll </PERSON> on June 15, 1876, with words that gave <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON> an enduring nickname: `` The plumed knight from the state of <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>.'' `` Like an armed warrior, like a plumed knight, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON> marched down the halls of the American <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and threw his shining lance full and fair against the brazen forehead of every traitor to his country and every maligner of his fair reputation.'' <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON> never obtained the presidency. But he twice was appointed secretary of state. No House speaker has ever been ousted. But several have been singed during the 200-year history of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Clay </PERSON>, who was elected speaker six times, drew accusations of `` corrupt bargain'' when the close election of 1824 was thrown into the House of Representatives. The choice was between <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Quincy </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>. <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> and other members of the <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> delegation tipped the balance in favor of <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>. The accusations flew after the victorious <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> named <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> as his secretary of state. Speaker <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Randall </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> Democrat, promptly called for his own investigation in 1879 after being accused of favoritism toward a company which provided the paper for the bonds and banknotes produced by the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engraving </ORGANIZATION>. He was quickly cleared. In 1910 Speaker <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cannon </PERSON> faced a rebellion against his imperious and heavy handed rule of the House. Although not deposed, <PERSON> Cannon </PERSON> was stripped of much of his power. Speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> `` Tip'' <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON>, D-Mass., was named in the so-called `` Koreagate'' influence peddling scandal in the 1970's but was
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Knutson </PERSON> covers <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScandalTour Bjt   04-17 0691</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scandal Tour, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Scandal Tours' of Capital Are Hit Among Jaded Tourists</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Note contents</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Leave the kids at home, skip the <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> and take a `` scandal tour'' of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, a raunchy romp through the ruins of political careers that takes ogling grownups from the Watergate to <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>'s old townhouse. With a <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> impersonator acting as host, the 75-minute bus tour leaving on weekends from the posh Ritz-Carlton Hotel is just the tonic for bored tourists willing to spend 20 bucks to indulge their taste for the trashy. Careening through city streets in a red, white and blue bus, a satirical comedy troupe called Gross National Product entertains customers with a bawdy commentary on passing landmarks where some of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s most prominent residents fell prey to sex, booze, greed or lust for power. Mostly sex. Outside the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, a <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON> look-alike croons a song to <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, the gentleman who supposedly preferred blondes. `` In my eight years in office, there will be no sex in the White House,'' vowed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, seizing the microphone. Past the Executive Office Building, where mock secretary <PERSON> Fawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> sobs her admiration for Col. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> _ `` the most patriotic man in the universe'' _ and recalls their Iran-Contra shredding parties. Passengers are given small plastic bags filled with shredded paper and signed `` Love, Fawn.'' On to the <LOCATION> Tidal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Basin </LOCATION>, where an inebriated <PERSON> Wilbur </PERSON> <PERSON> Mills </PERSON> saw both his congressional career and his companion, stripper <PERSON> Fanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Foxe </PERSON>, sink beneath the waves. Then to the Capitol, where <PERSON> John </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rita </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenrette </PERSON> enjoyed a congress of a different sort and where a homosexual congressman `` let his fingers do the walking through the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> pages.'' The bus screeched to a halt behind the <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> townhouse where <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> was caught entertaining model <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON>, dooming his 1988 Democratic presidential hopes. It's still the highlight of the tour. `` Everybody out for some fresh air and fresh smut,'' shouted a female tour guide. `` You're going to get out of the bus, you're going to see it, you're going to touch it, you'll be there. The crowd clustered around the garage where `` <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> made her backdoor debut for the <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION>,'' then strolled to the front of the house to pose for pictures. Back on the bus, the tourists sighed happily. `` What makes the best scandal?'' the guide asked. `` Sex,'' someone replied. `` Illicit sex,'' corrected a woman sitting in the rear. As the bus forged ahead, a black-robed comic posing as former <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> nominee <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Ginsburg </PERSON> offered to sell nickel bags of marijuana and `` crank up some <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlin </PERSON> tapes.'' A mimic of Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> promised to `` serve you like I served the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> _ on weekends.'' <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> London </PERSON>, the 34-year-old writer and producer who founded `` Scandal Tours'' last August, said he was inspired while escorting friends and relatives from his native <LOCATION> Hattiesburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, to the city's usual monuments and historical sites. `` I'd take them to the Capitol or the White House and you could see their eyes start to glaze over,'' he says. `` Sooner or later, they'd ask, ` Where's <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>'s townhouse?' and I'd take them. Then I thought, I ought to charge for this.'' The tours are especially popular with British tourists and Japanese businessmen, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> says. He's making plans to start `` scandal tours'' in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, where `` the Brits take the prize,'' and possibly <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>, who plays <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on the tour, says <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> provides a constant source of comedy material because of its explosive mixture of power, money and sex. The result, he says, is `` bad things happening to people it is hard to feel sorry for.'' <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> says the tour focuses on sex scandals because they're `` easier for people to understand'' than complicated affairs involving financial wrongdoing He says he's found that Republicans account for 90 percent of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s money scandals, while Democrats are usually the culprits in sex scandals. `` That means that Republicans are spending a lot of time making money,'' he said, `` and you can guess the rest.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0203EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-17 0938</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0975</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TAMPA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Princess <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> took a riding lesson during the 1989 World Cup show equestrian jumping championships, then dismounted and sidestepped sensitive questions. The princess, whose marriage of 15 years to <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> is said to be in trouble, maintained a low profile during her three-day visit for the championship that ended Sunday. During a 15-minute session with reporters at the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fairgrounds </LOCATION>, the daughter of Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> declined to comment on Saturday's melee at a British soccer stadium that left at least 94 people dead. Reporters asked about the tragedy although they had been told to limit their questions to horse-related matters. Earlier, she took a morning ride at the <ORGANIZATION> Bob </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thomas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Equestrian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> under the direction of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, a leading equestrian trainer. A small crowd, consisting mostly of photographers and plainclothes guards, watched the lesson, which Princess <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> said was `` a very interesting experience and no doubt will do me a world of good.'' The princess presented the World Cup trophy to <PERSON> Ian </PERSON> <PERSON> Millar </PERSON>, who successfully defended his title.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NAIROBI, Kenya (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former actress <PERSON> Audrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> has given emotional testimony on the hunger, starvation and death she witnessed during a mercy mission to <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>. Describing new arrivals at a refugee camp near the center of the war-torn country, the goodwill ambassador of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday: `` They have nothing left _ not even their bodies. They are so emaciated. It seems that all they have left are their souls.'' Ms. <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> spoke at a news conference in <LOCATION> Nairobi </LOCATION>, the first of many she will conduct to publicize a massive U.N. Relief effort for the southern <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>. That effort has been plagued by delays caused by political problems, weather and lack of equipment. <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> officials have all but conceded they will not meet their initial deadlines. They had hoped to move 105,000 tons of food, medicine and other supplies into southern <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION> before the start of heavy rains in May that close most roads and all but a few airstrips. With time running out before the storm season, directors of the $ 172 million Operation Lifeline <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION> are considering air drops to isolated and stranded villages. Ms. <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON>, 59, visited three refugee camps in <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION> last week.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Director <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pakula </PERSON>'s latest film is about the difficulties of a couple in their courtship leading to a second marriage _ a subject he knows from personal experience. It is no accident that `` See You in the Morning'' is the first film <PERSON> Pakula </PERSON> has written, directed and produced because the question of personal control and vulnerability is key to the project. <PERSON> Pakula </PERSON>, director of such films as `` Klute,'' `` All the President's Men,'' and `` <PERSON> Sophie </PERSON>'s Choice,'' slipped into the second person tellingly while discussing the film with The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. `` Coming out of a bad experience, a relationship that failed, there's a part of you that matures underneath that,'' <PERSON> Pakula </PERSON> said in the interview published Sunday. `` But there's a part of you that goes back to younger kinds of insecurities and vulnerabilities. Rejection can do that to you.'' In the film, which opens this week, <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON> and <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> <PERSON> Krige </PERSON> play a couple whose previous marriages have failed. The film relies on flashbacks to reveal how the two are haunted by the past as they encounter one another. <PERSON> Pakula </PERSON>'s first marriage, to the actress <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> <PERSON> Lange </PERSON>, ended 20 years ago. His current wife, biographer <PERSON> Hannah </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohn </PERSON> <PERSON> Boorstin </PERSON>, was a widow when they met. They married in 1973. <PERSON> Pakula </PERSON>'s troubles took place in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, while the film is set in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, and the couple portrayed are in their mid-30s, younger than he was while he endured his own tough times, <PERSON> Pakula </PERSON> said. `` I deliberately did not place them in a setting that would be literally familiar to me,'' <PERSON> Pakula </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>GRAND RAPIDS, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Monaghan </PERSON> owns the <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION> baseball club and one of the biggest pizza chains in the country, but he always wanted a farm. So <PERSON> Monaghan </PERSON>, owner of <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Arbor-based </PERSON> <PERSON> Domino </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Pizza </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, joined with a retired <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> agriculture professor in a project they hope will prove there's still money in small farms. <PERSON> Monaghan </PERSON> is financing the 25-acre spread three miles outside of <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Arbor </PERSON>. The soggy fields began their transformation last fall under the supervision of <PERSON> Booker </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Whatley </PERSON>, author of the book `` How to Make $ 100,000 Farming 25 Acres,'' The Grand Rapids Press reported Sunday. The goal is to show that farms of 10 to 200 acres can succeed as well as family-run operations of 200 to 1,000 acres and agribusiness concerns of 1,000 acres or more. `` This country can and should support all three categories,'' said <PERSON> Whatley </PERSON>, 73, formerly of the faculty of <ORGANIZATION> Tuskegee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> and publisher of the Small Farm Technical Newsletter. <PERSON> Monaghan </PERSON> read about <PERSON> Whatley </PERSON> in The Wall Street Journal. Seeing a chance to fulfill his own dream, he introduced himself at a speaking engagement by the agricultural theorist in <LOCATION> Lansing </LOCATION>. Since fall, workers have dug a trout pond, established a fallow deer herd and begun building a 1-acre sinking garden for vegetable production, farm manager <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Trout </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Whatley </PERSON>'s book argues that small farms can succeed if they provide a year-round daily cash flow, produce at least 10 different products with no one product making up more than 10 percent of the gross, and produce goods that have definite markets. <PERSON> Monaghan </PERSON> said he will give his Domino's headquarters employees the option of spending occasional days at the farm instead of working their desk jobs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Uruguay-Amnesty 4thLd-Writethru a0414 04-17 0817</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Uruguay-Amnesty, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0414,0841</SECOND>
<HEAD>Voters Reject Move To Deny Amnesty To Rights Offenders During Dictatorship</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 7 grafs to UPDATE with amnesty opponent conceding
defeat, newer figures. PickS up 5th pvs, `Shortly after...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED McCULLOUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MONTEVIDEO, Uruguay (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Uruguayans on Sunday voted not to end an amnesty for soldiers and police accused of human rights abuses during the 1973-85 military dictatorship. With 6,360 of 7,072 districts reporting in the referendum on the 1986 amnesty, supporters tallied 922,185 votes, or 53.32 percent, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>, and while opponents numbered 678,087, or 39.21 percent. About 128,969 votes, or 7.47 percent, were blank, annulled or ruled questionable for technical reasons. Early today, a co-president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> for a Referendum conceded defeat. `` The law has been confirmed,'' <PERSON> Matilde </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Larreta </PERSON> told reporters. `` Without doubt, the pronouncement of the popular will should be adhered to.'' However, she called for a `` national compromise'' on the issue, and said, `` about 40 percent voted to annul the law. ... The country and all its institutions can not be insensitive to the circumstances that nearly one-half of the population disagrees radically'' with the amnesty. Unofficial tallies indicated that voters in the capital narrowly rejected the amnesty while voters in the countryside heavily favored it. Shortly after polls closed at 7:30 p.m -LRB- 6:30 p.m. EDT -RRB- and before any results were known, President <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanguinetti </PERSON> called for national unity in an address carried on national radio and television. `` Until a short while ago, some of us were ` yellows,' others ` greens,''' he said. `` That has just ended. ... We are all Uruguayan citizens and now we have to listen to the voice of the people.'' Supporters of the amnesty cast yellow ballots; opponents cast green ones. The government, including <PERSON> Sanguinetti </PERSON>, supported the 1986 law giving amnesty to scores of police and soldiers accused of human rights abuses in a campaign against leftist guerrillas during 12 years of military rule. Leftist political parties and human rights groups, which mounted a huge petition drive to put the issue to a vote, say trials of those accused of human rights abuses are necessary before democracy can be considered fully restored. After campaigning ended on Thursday, both sides pledged to respect the outcome. By late Sunday night, neither side had claimed victory or conceded defeat. `` We're still gathering information and making our own computations,'' said <PERSON> Alberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> for a Referendum. The <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> estimated that about 65 percent of the 2.3 million Uruguayans eligible to vote had cast ballots. Voting is mandatory in <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> and turnout usually tops 80 percent. Turnout apparently was lower than usual Sunday because of gray skies and rain. But lines were long from the moment schools, cultural centers, movie theaters and other places used as polling stations opened. Many voters waited for an hour or longer huddled under umbrellas or building overhangs. `` A country that forgets its past has no future,'' said a well-dressed woman standing in line to vote in a neighborhood along the estuary of the River Plate. `` A future of peace and justice depend on overturning'' the amnesty, said the woman, who refused to give her name. If voters rejected the amnesty, trials would not start immediately. Vice President <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Tarigo </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> then would have to decide whether the amnesty would be annulled _ meaning a ruling that it never legally existed _ or merely overturned. If the law were just overturned, the change could not be applied retroactively. The amnesty freed security forces from the possibility of prosecution in connection with a 1970s crackdown on leftist subversion. About 150 Uruguayans were killed and 200 were arrested and never seen again. Thousands suffered physical and psychological torture under detention. The military maintains it was fighting a war against urban guerrillas, particularly the leftist <ORGANIZATION> Tupamaros </ORGANIZATION>, whose bombings, kidnappings and assassinations had convulsed the country for years. The military took control in February 1973 by setting up a security council with the authority to veto government decisions. Four months later, it forced President <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bordaberry </PERSON> to dissolve congress. The Tupamaro urban guerrillas by that time had been quelled as a military threat, and the armed forces began to crack down on leftist subversion in general. <PERSON> Sanguinetti </PERSON> was elected in November 1984 after democracy was restored. By 1986, about 50 cases had been filed accusing about 180 soldiers and police of kidnapping, murder and torture. The military high command said it would not require soldiers to answer charges in civilian courts. <PERSON> Sanguinetti </PERSON> broke the impasse by pressing for an amnesty, which <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> passed on Dec. 22, 1986. Human rights and leftist political groups vowed to challenge the amnesty in a vote. The <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> last year affirmed that the required 555,701 voters, or 25 percent of the electorate, had signed petitions for a referendum.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SSISurvey     04-17 0434</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SSI Survey,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>For release noon EDT; time set by source</HEAD>
<HEAD>One Million Social Security Recipients Missing Benefits</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Most of the 1 million elderly poor people who do not get the government benefits to which they are entitled either do not know they are eligible or are incapable of filling out the necessary forms, a private foundation said today. The study by <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Villers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> was aimed at answering the perplexing question of why only about half of those eligible take advantage of the Supplemental Security Income program established by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1972. The program is intended to provide a minimal income floor for the nation's aged, disabled and blind. `` Some people say that the poor do n't apply for SSI because they are embarrassed. We found that's not the heart of the problem,'' said <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollack </PERSON>, executive director of the non-profit foundation that concentrates on issues affecting the elderly poor. `` The main reasons they do n't apply are that they do n't know they can or they do n't have the help they need to fill out the application form. `` A safety net does n't do any good hidden in a bureaucrat's desk,'' added <PERSON> Pollack </PERSON> `` You've got to get it out there, under the people whose lives are falling.'' The foundation based its conclusions on interviews with 6,214 elderly people at community meal sites in 15 states and on interviews with staffers at 31 district Social Security offices and 358 community organizations serving the elderly. It was not designed as an academic study and did not seek to ensure that the 6,214 elderly people questioned were a scientifically drawn survey of elderly people eligible for the program. Given those parameters, the survey found that: _ Only 33 percent knew <ORGANIZATION> SSI </ORGANIZATION> could increase an eligible person's _ More than 90 percent assumed, incorrectly, that having a low paying job would automatically prevent an individual from receiving SSI _ Half thought, incorrectly, that owning a house or car would automatically bar an applicant from eligibility _ More than a third thought, incorrectly, that anyone receiving regular Social Security benefits would be barred from also collecting SSI A third of the Social Security district office managers had no staff to assign to outreach activities and 40 percent of the <ORGANIZATION> SSI </ORGANIZATION> client contacts with the 358 community organizations were for help filling out the 12-page application that asks 45 multiple-part questions. Applicants, some of them frail and functionally illiterate, are required to supply documentation of age, rent or mortgage payments, employment status, living arrangements, assets, Social Security and pension benefits, insurance and property ownership.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0208EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WashingtonBicentennial     04-17 0426</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington Bicentennial,0441</SECOND>
<HEAD>Carriage Breaks Down As Re-enactment Journey Begins</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOUNT VERNON, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The start of the bicentennial celebration of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>'s presidential inauguration went off without a hitch. But not without a problem. A sparkling antique carriage carrying an actor portraying <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> was less than 100 feet into the 250-mile trek from <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vernon </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> when it broke down Sunday. One of the wheels hit a fence post and broke the main shaft connecting the harnesses and the carriage. The shaky departure was the only problem during opening festivities celebrating the bicentennial of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s inauguration on April 30, 1789 The eight-day trip will take the entourage to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on April 23. The first inauguration will be recreated in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s Federal Hall on the anniversary date `` It is far more, far more indeed, than a re-enactment and a celebration of a 7 -LCB- - day trip,'' former <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Chief Justice <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Burger </PERSON> told the crowd of about 3,000 `` This is a trip, a journey that has lasted 200 years, and God willing, will last for many hundreds of years in the future.'' <PERSON> Burger </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Bicentennial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, opened the ceremony with the dedication of a 25-cent stamp bearing the likeness of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in honor of the bicentennial of the executive branch of the government. One spectator in particular was moved by the performance. `` This is something very special for me,'' said <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, 67, of <LOCATION> Gulfstream </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, who said she is a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> descendent. `` This is one of the foremost families in the history of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. To think that any of those genes are in my body gives me something to look up to and to strive to emulate.'' About half the journey is to be made by carriage. The trip will take the entourage through the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. In his role as <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, actor <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sommerfield </PERSON> began the journey by greeting an actor playing the role of Secretary of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Thomson </PERSON> arrived at <ORGANIZATION> Mount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vernon </ORGANIZATION> on April 16, 1789, with the news of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s election. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> immediately left for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> _ but not without apprehensions. `` No one has filled this great office before,'' he said. `` Each thing I do will be a precedent.'' Just as <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> before him, <PERSON> Sommerfield </PERSON> left by carriage, but after it the post the actor jumped into a van. `` Strange vehicle, strange vehicle,'' said <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> of his first automobile ride. `` In the war, the unexpected was the expected.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-RitualSlayings-Bodies 3rdLd-Writethru a0424 04-17 0673</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ritual Slayings-Bodies, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0424,0683</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Two More Bodies Found Buried At Ranch</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 5-9, `Acting on ...' with five grafs to UPDATE with
funeral home saying new victims killed by machete blows; CORRECT age of
man in 5th and 9th grafs to 72, sted 77.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOLDEN LEWIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MATAMOROS, Mexico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities discovered two more bodies Sunday buried on a collective farm two miles south of a ranch where 13 victims of a cult of human sacrifice were found last week. Investigators said they have evidence the male victims were killed by the same drug smuggling cult suspected of performing human sacrifices on the 13 males discovered Tuesday at <LOCATION> Rancho </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Elena </LOCATION>, about 20 miles west of <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Cameron </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> said the victims found Sunday were connected to the drug smuggling operations of the cult, but were not victims of the cult's rites as were the other 13. Unlike the bodies uncovered at <ORGANIZATION> Rancho </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elena </ORGANIZATION>, the bodies found on the farm were not mutilated, said Mexican federal police group chief <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Elias </PERSON> <PERSON> Salazar </PERSON>. Acting on a tip from some children, a 72-year-old man led police Sunday to the common grave in a clearing in an orchard on the farm, <LOCATION> Ejido </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Librada </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Salazar </PERSON> told reporters. The dead were identified as <PERSON> Moises </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON>, the son of the man who led police to the site, and <PERSON> Hector </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> la </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuente </PERSON>, also known as `` El Guero'', or `` The Blond.'' Both were killed by machete chops to the back of the head, said <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Degadillo </PERSON>, an employee at <LOCATION> Funerales </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rosario </LOCATION>. Some of the victims found on the ranch last week also were killed by machete chops. `` It was a revenge type killing. It was a drug deal gone sour,'' <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> said. The sheriff said the men apparently died in May. He said he knew about the men because of an ongoing investigation into the drug smuggling ring. However, a spokeswoman for the federal judicial police in <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION> said the two men were farmhands who had been missing since last May. The children told the 72-year-old man, <PERSON> Hidalgo </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON>, that they had seen some people burying a body in an orchard last October, <PERSON> Salazar </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON>'s son, <PERSON> Moises </PERSON>, 52, disappeared last May. <PERSON> Salazar </PERSON> said <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> had discounted the children's tale until the 13 bodies were dug up. The two bodies were stacked and appeared to be those of adults, investigators said. Neither had been positively identified as of Sunday night. Officials disinterred the second body just before sunset Sunday. <PERSON> Salazar </PERSON> searched through the pockets of a pair of black pants found on the second body and discovered 3,000 Mexican pesos and a $ 5 bill. Four suspects arrested in the slayings of the 13 discovered on <LOCATION> Rancho </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Elena </LOCATION> have told police they killed 13 or 14 people in bizarre rites intended to protect a marijuana smuggling ring. Among the victims were a 16-year-old boy and <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON>, missing since March when he came here during spring break from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION>. Police said the suspects have been cooperative in pointing out the bodies and had not mentioned burying anybody on Ejido <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Librada </LOCATION>. Ejido means collective farm in Spanish. Officials said the group trafficked in drugs and believed the human sacrifice would protect them from police. In <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION>, authorities found altars covered with black chicken feathers, burned turtles, cigars and other occult offerings. The bodies had been mutilated, some with their hearts or brains ripped out. Police in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are seeking alleged ringleader <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> and three others, including <PERSON> Sara </PERSON> <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON>, a college student identified as the `` godmother'' of the cult. In a related development, <ORGANIZATION> Notimex </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> government news agency, reported Saturday that a woman identifying herself as <PERSON> Sara </PERSON> <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> <PERSON> Villareal </PERSON> called a local radio station threatening to kidnap children as hostages and burn them if the four prisoners were not released. The news agency said local police in <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION> dismissed the report as a hoax.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0309EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--StatenIsland     04-17 0173</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Staten Island,0179</SECOND>
<HEAD>NY Senate Approves Secession Bill</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALBANY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved a bill to let <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> residents vote on whether to secede from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. The bill was introduced after the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s declaration in March that the city's powerful <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estimate </ORGANIZATION>, which rules on spending and projects, violated the principle of one man, one vote <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, the city's smallest borough with about 400,000 residents, has an equal presence on the board as the other four boroughs, including <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> with 2.2 million residents. `` There are 41 nations in the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> with less people than <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>,'' Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Marchi </PERSON> said after Sunday night's vote `` Who could be against one man, one vote, but it has to accommodate the human condition,'' said the <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> Republican, who sponsored the bill. The measure was approved 34-1 without debate in the Republican-controlled <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. It is given little chance of approval in the Assembly, which is dominated by Democrats from the city's more populous boroughs
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtoninBrief     04-17 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington in Brief,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kemp Moves To Make Drug-related Evictions Easier in Federal Housing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The federal government is making illegal drug use or sales a specific violation of public housing leases as a way to ease the eviction process for local authorities. Housing Secretary <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> announced the step Sunday as he released a report describing actions public housing authorities around the country are already taking to solve drug-related problems. In a prepared statement, the secretary of <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> said <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> would also inform local housing authorities of ways they can use already appropriated federal funds to make physical and management improvements aimed at improving security against drug crimes. He said <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> would publish a notice informing local housing authorities that leases must include explicit provisions that allow termination of the lease if any member of a household or person under the tenant's control engages in drug-related criminal activity.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>Feds Help Break Up Huge Capital Cocaine Ring</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal and local police say they capped a two-year investigation by breaking up a drug cartel that brought as much as 440 pounds of cocaine into the violence-torn <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> area. Authorities arrested about two dozen people during a weekend anti-drug sweep that netted the alleged leadership of a group that controlled much of the cocaine market in the nation's capital. Among those arrested were <PERSON> Rayful </PERSON> <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 24, and <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, described as being in his mid-twenties. Officials said Sunday that the two led a network that controlled up to 20 percent of the cocaine and crack traffic in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> quoted sources as saying the pair's alleged drug network employed more than 150 people and has been linked to scores of homicides. The <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> quoted sources as saying that more than a year ago <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON>'s alleged drug gang was generating income of more than $ 300,000 a day. <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> were arrested Saturday on cocaine distribution charges. The arrests resulted from a two-year joint investigation conducted by the <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and district police.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>AIDS Research Funds Being Used for AZT Treatments</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Millions of dollars intended for AIDS research is instead being used to the drug AZT for needy AIDS patients because <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> reauthorized the free drug program without providing money for it. The program was to expire last September, but was extended without an appropriation. Congressional leaders subsequently made clear they expected <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> officials to tap other AIDS accounts for the money. Although the program is authorized at $ 15 million for the current fiscal year, the company that makes the drug _ <ORGANIZATION> Burroughs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wellcome </ORGANIZATION> _ is picking up $ 5 million of the cost by making that much of the drug available free. The remaining $ 10 million had to be found elsewhere in the <ORGANIZATION> HHS </ORGANIZATION> budget. About $ 7.4 million comes from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> budget, and about $ 6 million of that from <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> research funds.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0230EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Insurance-Poor-Glance     04-17 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Insurance-Poor-Glance,0662</SECOND>
<HEAD>States Consider Laws Requiring Companies to Insure Workers</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Poor-Insurance, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a list of some of the states considering legislation to help workers who have no health insurance. <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> have laws requiring employers to insure their workers. _ <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>: A bill in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> would provide up to 10,000 uninsured people with state-subsidized health insurance Lawmakers also are considering a mandatory insurance bill based on <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>' law. _ <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>: Five bills have been introduced, including one requiring companies with five or more employees to provide health care benefits About 2.7 million workers are uninsured, or about one out of 10 <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> residents. _ <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>: A measure pending in a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committee is aimed at providing insurance for the indigent Between 80,000 and 90,000 people are uninsured. _ <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>: Legislators are considering a measure based on <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>' law, requiring employers to insure their employees An estimated 1 million to 2 million people, or one-sixth of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s population, are uninsured. _ <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>: The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> passed a measure creating a high-risk health insurance pool that will arrange health insurance for those who could not previously qualify for insurance About 2 million people are uninsured. _ <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>: A bill would require businesses with five or more employees to provide health benefits for employees who work more than 17 -LCB- hours weekly About 1.5 million Illinoisans have neither private health insurance nor Medicaid, or more than 13 percent of the state's 11 million people. _ <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>: The state <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> is considering a measure that would create a commission to study the need for state-sponsored health care services <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> has 769,000 people, or about 17 percent of the population, with no insurance. _ <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>: A bill passed by a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> committee creates a $ 200,000 study, eventually calling for businesses with 40 or more employees to provide insurance coverage About 350,000 people, or more than 10 percent of the state's population, are uninsured. _ <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>: A bill in the appropriations committee seeks to establish an insurance `` buy-in'' program for workers who meet poverty guidelines and whose employers do not provide coverage About 480,000 Kansans, or 14 percent of the state's population, are uninsured. _ <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>: Bills pending in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> aim to guarantee that all Minnesotans have access to affordable health insurance About 400,000 people, or 9.3 percent of the state's population, are uninsured _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>: A pilot program will provide health insurance to 14,500 uninsured New Yorkers, mostly those unemployed or employees of small companies About 2.5 million people are uninsured, and 75 percent of them are working. _ <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>: A <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> bill would require insurance coverage for low-paid workers with a 1 percent payroll tax on employers About 1.4 million of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>'s 11 million residents are uninsured. _ <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>: A bill seeks to provide ` insurance of last resort'' to workers without health insurance An estimated 636,800 people are uninsured out of a population of 3.3 million. _ Oregon: The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved a bill that would revamp the federal-state Medicaid program with the aim of covering more poor people About 400,000 people are uninsured, about 15 percent of <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>'s population of 2.7 million. _ <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>: Lawmakers are considering a measure that creates an accident and health insurance pool to help uninsured workers About 440,000 of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>'s 3.1 million people are working without insurance and are ineligible for Medicaid. _ <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>: Lawmakers are considering a plan to help small companies provide health insurance to their workers About 31,000 of <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>'s 550,000 residents are uninsured. _ <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>: The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> passed a $ 14.8 million program to provide medical care for those with little or no health insurance About 880,000 of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s 5.9 million residents have little or no insurance. _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>: The state's five-year <ORGANIZATION> Basic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> pilot project provides health care to the `` working poor'' who are not covered by welfare programs About 720,000 people, or 16 percent of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s residents, are uninsured.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890417-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-89 0234EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Star-Onassis     04-17 0551</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Star-Onassis,0566</SECOND>
<HEAD>Biography: JFK Left Behind Nuclear Codes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
