<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0020EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ClimbingDeath     05-13 0309</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Climbing Death,0317</SECOND>
<HEAD>One Climber Dead, One Missing on Mount Rainier</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ASHFORD, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Park rangers and volunteers searched the summit of <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rainier </LOCATION> on Friday for a missing climber whose partner was found dead just below the summit, <ORGANIZATION> Mount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rainier </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> officials said. Park spokesman <PERSON> Cy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hentges </PERSON> said helicopters ferried four groups of ground searchers to the mountain, but found no sign of the missing man. A helicopter also was flying around the 14,410-foot peak as part of the search. The two men were in a party of four men aged between 26 and 33, all from the <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tahoe </LOCATION> area, <PERSON> Hentges </PERSON> said. The other two men notified authorities Thursday that one of their companions had died and the other was missing. The names of the four have not been released. <PERSON> Hentges </PERSON> said not all relatives of the dead and missing men had been notified as of Friday afternoon. In all, about 21 people were involved in the search. A commercial helicopter was en route Friday to pick up the dead man's body, which was found Thursday evening about 400 feet below below Liberty Cap, <PERSON> Hentges </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION>, at 14,410 feet, is the mountain's highest point, while Liberty Cap, on the northwest side, is at 14,112 feet. The third summit, Point Success, is at 14,158 feet. <PERSON> Hentges </PERSON> said the man probably died of hypothermia since he had taken off his parka earlier and tied it to his skis. The parka was still tied to the skis when he was found. The survivors searched the summit area and searched the eastern side of the peak for the missing man before descending to the <LOCATION> Ipsut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> campground to report the death Thursday. The four climbers, all of whom had skis to use on the descent down the mountain's glaciers, started their ascent Sunday morning, <PERSON> Hentges </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AIDS-Stats     05-13 0220</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Stats,0243</SECOND>
<HEAD>CDC Statistics on U.S. AIDS Cases</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest statistics on acquired immune deficiency syndrome in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, as reported by the national Centers for Disease Control:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Number of Cases</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Total cases reported since June 1981: 94,280. Cases, last 12 months: 21,782. Total deaths: 54,402, or 58 percent of all cases.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Transmission Categories</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Homosexual or bisexual males: 56,783, or 60 percent. Intravenous drug abusers: 18,819, or 20 percent. Homosexual male and drug abusers: 6,620, or 7 percent. Heterosexual cases: 4,128, or 4 percent. Transfusion or blood cases: 2,478, or 3 percent. Hemophilia patients: 977, or 1 percent. Children of parents with AIDS or at risk: 1,233, or 1 percent. Other or undetermined transmission cause: 3,242, or 3 percent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Age and Race</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Childhood cases -LRB- under age 13 -RRB-: 1,561, or 2 percent. Cases among whites: 53,759, or 57 percent. Cases among blacks: 25,276, or 27 percent. Cases among Hispanics: 14,358, or 15 percent. Cases among Asians or Pacific Islanders: 557, or 1 percent. Cases among American Indians or Alaskan natives: 111, or 0 percent. -LRB- NOTE: These statistics are through April 1989 and have been rounded to the nearest whole percent. Cumulative totals are for AIDS cases reported since June 1981 and include 75 cases subsequently found to have occurred before that date. -RRB-
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0022EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Basra     05-13 0607</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Basra,0628</SECOND>
<HEAD>Demolished City Rises from Dead in Record Time</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SALAH NASRAWI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BASRA, Iraq (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> is spending $ 6 billion to rebuild this city at almost head-spinning speed, turning a town left virtually demolished by the war with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> into `` <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s most beautiful and elegant city.'' Workers have built bridges, replaced buildings, fixed roads, added new water and electricity systems and have even begun replacing palm trees decapitated by artillery fire. Officials plan to erect almost 100 statues of war heroes, with their fingers pointing forbiddingly in the direction of neighboring <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. `` What we are doing can not be compared with the sacrifices of thousands of brave men who lost their lives in defending <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION>,'' said engineer <PERSON> Nawaf </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdullah </PERSON> as he supervised a street repaving in downtown <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION>. President <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> in February imposed a three-month deadline for completing reconstruction of this strategic city overlooking the <PERSON> Shatt </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Arab </PERSON> waterway, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s main outlet to the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. The deadline was to end May 12, but Gov. <PERSON> Anwar </PERSON> <PERSON> Sa'eed </PERSON> <PERSON> Hadithi </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Friday that the renovation has been extended to June 12 to cover more of the city and encompass new projects. At least 90 percent of the buildings in <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION> were destroyed or damaged in fierce Iranian artillery barrages during the 8-year-old war with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. Iranian troops reached within six miles of the city last spring before being driven back, and Iraqis consider the city a symbol of their defense. After the August cease-fire, the <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> government announced it would rebuild <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION>, and so far said it has committed $ 6 billion to the project. <PERSON> Hadithi </PERSON> said six small rivers in <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION> had been cleared of debris, their banks resurfaced and 40 bridges constructed. A new electricity grid and new pipe network for drinking water have been installed. <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> authorities have said they will build a new drinking water processing plant in <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION> that will tap water from the <LOCATION> Euphrates </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Nasrriya </LOCATION>, 75 miles north. Residents consider the current water from the <PERSON> Shatt </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Arab </PERSON> too brackish. <PERSON> Hadithi </PERSON> said the government offered unlimited money to finance the development plans so <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION> can be `` <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s most beautiful and elegant city.'' But the city still bears scars from the shelling, including shrapnel holes in buildings. <PERSON> Hadithi </PERSON> said the city, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s second-largest after <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION>, is back to its prewar population of 1.5 million. An estimated half the population fled during the shelling. The government has encouraged people to return by offering plots of land, cash gifts and loans or grants of up to $ 32,000 to build new homes. The government also is offering similar incentives to get people with no <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION> roots to move into the city. Among the projects is the construction of 96 statues of senior <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> officers killed while defending the city. The statues will be erected on the corniche of the Shatt <PERSON> al-Arab </PERSON> with their arms pointing east, toward <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, `` warning against the dangers which have always come from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>,'' the governor said. The government did not use independent contractors for the reconstruction drive, relying its own men and machinery to do the work. At least 100,000 workers and 40,000 machines from different parts of the country were dispatched to take part in the project, called `` The national drive for the reconstruction of the city of cities.'' <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION> has as much strategic as symbolic importance to <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> insists a 1975 treaty that places the countries' southern border in the middle of the <PERSON> Shaat </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Arab </PERSON> to still be valid. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> says the treaty is invalid and that the border is on <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s eastern bank
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-IndianInvestigation     05-13 0583</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Indian Investigation,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Changes Planned in Indian Oil Rights Protection</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The new director of the <ORGANIZATION> Minerals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> says the agency is developing a plan for doing a much better job of protecting Indian oil rights. <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON>, who took over April 3 as head of the agency charged with protecting oil royalties to Indians, told a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> investigating committee Friday that he is working on a package of changes from current policy. The special unit of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Indian Affairs spent the past week taking testimony from witnesses who criticized the minerals service, the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>, and the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> for not fulfilling the federal responsibility to protect Indian oil rights. `` The purpose of these hearings is to expose what has happened in the past, but more importantly chart a new course,'' said Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>. When lawyers showed <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON> evidence the minerals service had not acted in accordance with the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> and Gas Royalty Management Act, he promised improvements. `` We can do better than we have done in the past'' was his refrain throughout questioning. Earlier Friday, a homeless <PERSON> Cherokee-Arapahoe </PERSON> woman said she was receiving only sporadic royalty payments on three wells in which she has an interest. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Limpy </PERSON>, who lives in an abandoned house in <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>, said the $ 30 to $ 60 payments she gets periodically keep her on the oil royalty rolls and make her ineligible for public assistance. Disabled by childhood polio, Mrs. <PERSON> Limpy </PERSON> can not work and said the state took away her two youngest children two years ago. She has n't been able to get any of the federal agencies responsible for Indian oil to tell her what has happened to her payments, she told the panel. Mrs. <PERSON> Limpy </PERSON> said her wells originally were leased by the <ORGANIZATION> Tenneco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> which sold the leases to Koch Oil. She said that at one point, she heard the wells had been capped, but the farmer who works the land where the wells are located said trucks kept going on and off the oil field. Other witnesses told the committee that <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, which is based in <LOCATION> Wichita </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, had been taking more oil than it had paid for from Indian wells, a charge the company has denied. Mrs. <PERSON> Limpy </PERSON> is a participant in a federal class-action suit charging the government has violated its trust responsibilities to Indians with oil well interests, said attorney <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said the suit's plaintiffs include 7,000 allottees with interest in 944 oil leases in western <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>. That suit has been held under advisement by Judge <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> of the western district of <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> for two and one-half years, said <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>. A statement issued by <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON>, court clerk for the western district of <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, said counsel for both sides have reported to the court that settlement offers have been ongoing while they watched an `` almost identical'' case pending in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. The statement said the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> case was settled by an entry of consent decree in March, and that both parties in Mrs. <PERSON> Limpy </PERSON>'s case filed a status report last month that `` specific settlement offers were forthcoming'' and that the parties would report on their progress in July The court said they waited on the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> case to avoid a potential conflict in rulings, to avoid delays in possible appeals and to `` enhance the prospects of an agreed settlement in the case.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0023EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Iran-Contra-Fernandez     05-13 0422</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra-Fernandez,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Attorney for Iran-Contra Figure Argues Against Classified Law</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALEXANDRIA, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The attorney for former <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> agent <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> says a classified documents law would force him to give prosecutors `` a soup to nuts disclosure'' of the defense's case before the Iran-Contra figure goes to trial. Defense lawyer <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> told a court hearing Friday that the Classified Information Procedures Act was unconstitutional and would seriously harm <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>'s case. <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> was the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> station chief in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> when former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> was helping supply weapons to the Nicaraguan Contras during a congressional ban on such assistance. A federal grand jury, under supervision of Iran-Contra independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>, charged that <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> lied about his role in the Contra arms network. The Classified Information Procedures Act would force the defense to notify prosecutors in advance of the classified documents <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> plans to use. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> told U.S. District Judge <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Hilton </PERSON> that `` 100 percent of the domain of evidence is classified'' and that <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> would have to `` reveal his defense in a way that would be wholly unreciprocated by the government.'' Iran-Contra prosecutor <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> told the judge that much of the information in the case no longer involves classified matters and that the defense `` overstates what is required.'' <PERSON> Hilton </PERSON> took the case under advisement. <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>, who used the code name of <PERSON> Tomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, was charged with four criminal counts. He is accused of obstructing inquiries by the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> general counsel and the presidentially appointed Tower commission that investigated the Iran-Contra arms and money affair, and false swearing in connection with those inquiries. The indictment said <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> falsely told the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> that an airstrip in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, used to supply the Contras, was built by the <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rican </LOCATION> government to train pilots for a possible Nicaraguan invasion of <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> allegedly lied to the Tower commission by denying that he knew the now-convicted <PERSON> North </PERSON> was involved in helping arm the Contras. Each of four charges in the indictment carries a maximum five-year sentence and a $ 250,000 fine upon conviction. <PERSON> Hilton </PERSON> noted that a hearing was scheduled May 26 on documents that prosecutors might have to reveal to the defense. The judge said that if he rules the government must give the defense substantial information about the prosecution case, there would be no harm to <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>. North's trial on Iran-Contra charges was conducted under the classified procedures law, after surviving a similar challenge from the defense.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0023EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Police-Drugs 1stLd-Writethru a0803 05-13 0594</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Police-Drugs, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0803,0607</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Appeals Court Upholds Right Random Drug Testing of Boston Police</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 5th graf ``These rules ..., with 5 grafs background; ADDS
5 grafs background on police drug testing nationally.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANA KENNEDY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After three years of court battles, a federal appeals court ruled Friday to permit the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to conduct random drug testing of police officers. The 1st U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> ruled in favor of a police department regulation issued in 1986 that requires random drug testing of all police department employees. `` I am deeply concerned for the health and safety of our police officers,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roache </PERSON> in a statement prepared after the decision. `` They are human and engaged in perhaps the most stressful profession in our society. Therefore I believe that this drug testing policy is beneficial to the public as well as to the police officers in this city and in the country.'' The 1600-member <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrolmen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which claims the law is unconstitutional, vowed Friday to take the case to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. Under agreement reached by both parties in the case, the regulation will not be imposed until the appeals process has been fully exhausted. `` These rules conjure up memories of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Orwell </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> McGee </PERSON>, chief counsel for the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrolmen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` There are very major implications here. The broader question is how far can the government go in searching the bodies of its employees? Are blood tests and mandatory psychiatric tests next?'' The two-page decision by the appeals court cited two <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling in March that upheld the government's right to require drug and alcohol tests for <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> workers involved in drug interdiction and for railroad workers involved in accidents. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled that public safety outweighs constitutional guarantees against unreasonable searches. The decision reached in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> was one of three suits filed by police unions around the country against proposed drug detection programs. Cases involving drug testing in the <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Chattanooga </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, police departments are still under review. The appeals court decision stemmed from a suit brought in federal court in October 1986 by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Guiney </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrolmen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Earlier that year, <PERSON> Roache </PERSON> had proposed mandatory random testing as part of efforts to ensure a drug-free force. In May 1988, U.S. District Judge <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keeton </PERSON> upheld urine tests of police officers as a result of suspicion of drug abuse but ruled that a provision of the regulation imposing random tests without suspicion was unconstitutional and was an unreasonable search and seizure of an officer's body fluids. Drug testing of police officers has been a controversial issue in police departments across the country. Most police departments have attempted to test only those officers under suspicion or involved with drug interdiction. In March, the <ORGANIZATION> Nassau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> began random drug testing of certain narcotics squads. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, random testing for drugs was started last October among the estimated 1,000 officers assigned to the <ORGANIZATION> Organized </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crime </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION>. In 1986, the <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> began a random mandatory testing program for its members. The program was suspended after eight months when the state attorney general advised it may be an unconstitutional invasion of privacy. <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> police officers have asked that an annual mandatory drug screening exam be written into their contracts. Approximately 5 million Americans are subject to drug testing each year, usually as a condition of employment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0025EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Business-Budget Bjt   05-13 0611</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Business-Budget, Bjt,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Business Leaders Dissatisfied With Deficit-Reduction Progress</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NANCY BENAC</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOT SPRINGS, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> business leaders, saying they're tired of warning about the ill effects of massive federal deficits, expect a sharp slowdown in economic growth to result in disappointing revenues for the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> and exacerbate the nation's deficit The Business Council, made up of 65 chief executives from the nation's top corporations, predicted Friday that the government's red ink next year will total $ 135 billion, well above the $ 100 billion maximum that is allowed under the Gramm-Rudman deficit-reduction law `` Every year I've been here I have to say the same thing,'' <PERSON> Edmund </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pratt </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Pfizer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, told business leaders at this mountain resort. `` We in the business community are still very concerned ... about the deficits.'' <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, after protracted negotiations with the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, has drafted a fiscal 1990 budget that it says would hold the deficit to just under the Gramm-Rudman limit. The business leaders were unconvinced of that projection, yet somewhat encouraged that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration at least were talking to one another. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kearns </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Xerox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, said the latest $ 1.2 trillion spending plan wo n't do much to reduce the deficit, `` but the fact that they're not fighting, that they've come to step one, is positive in my mind.'' `` Step two will have to be for them to deal with it in real terms, and it must be dealt with or we're going to have some discontinuities that could be severe,'' he said. <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and of the <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, said the budget and trade deficits are being closely watched because they `` have a direct bearing on our industry and how people feel about the economy.'' `` It's going to be a good year ... from what we can see, providing nothing untoward happens in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Pratt </PERSON> said corporate officials are `` disappointed that a more serious bite of the apple was n't taken in the new budget.'' `` On the other hand, we do have a feeling of encouragement that at least ... <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the executive branch act like they're more serious about trying to grab hold of the problem,'' he said Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, told the council in a private session Friday that the 1990 budget would come in right around the Gramm-Rudman target and was `` worth an awful lot'' because it set the stage for further negotiations. `` I remain convinced that there is a very significant process that has been set in motion that might address the deficit that otherwise would go totally unattended and create grid lock and chaos,'' <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON> said after the session. <PERSON> Rudolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Penner </PERSON>, senior fellow at the <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> and former head of the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, told the business leaders the budget was disappointing because it again uses accounting gimmicks to reduce the red ink. `` Every year we do a little bit; every year we claim we did more than we do,'' he said. The Business Council is forecasting that economic growth, as measured by the gross national product, will slow from last year's healthy 3.9 percent pace to 1.4 percent by the end of the year The council projected GNP growth of 2.9 percent for all of 1989 and 1.7 percent next year. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Breeden </PERSON>, a top aide to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, told the council that the recent slowing in economic activity was `` a pause and a base for further expansion.'' The administration is pinning its deficit-reduction plans on an optimistic expectation for GNP growth of 3.2 percent this year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0034EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Panama-Americans     05-13 0674</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama-Americans,0698</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wheeling, Dealing and Fading, U.S. Business Plugs Along</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOSEPH B. FRAZIER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The American business community has been able to operate successfully in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> despite political violence, government-fanned hostility toward the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sanctions against the government. The community plans to stay open for business, but its greatest threats come from long-range political instability and a continued economic downturn, said a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. Companies gradually are relocating and will keep doing so as long as Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> remains in power and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sanctions remain in place, he said. The spokesman, who also is a partner in a Panamanian business, asked not to be named for fear of reprisal. `` I do n't see any short-run solution,'' he said Friday. `` Members of the chamber do n't feel our friend -LRB- <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> -RRB- is showing any willingness to move, and we have to make plans on that sort of scenario. `` Companies that have plants here, such as <LOCATION> Borden </LOCATION>, probably will continue as long as they can pay their payroll and so forth. Others, like <ORGANIZATION> Kodak </ORGANIZATION>, which have regional offices here, may decide to locate them elsewhere,'' he said. In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Kodak </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said operations have not been affected by the unrest. He said <ORGANIZATION> Kodak </ORGANIZATION>'s fewer than 100 employees in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> include a handful of Americans, and they have not been advised to leave or take unusual precautions. On Thursday, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> advised <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> businessmen to make plans to get dependents out of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. However, one executive of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> importing firm said he did not plan to move his wife and children `` because we do n't want to live in an Army base.'' Like most Americans contacted, he said he had encountered no hostility from Panamanians or had any problems. `` The anti-Americanism just is n't out there,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> official said. An anti-U.S. offensive by the government found little support among Panamanians, he said. `` <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> has been a regional center for a lot of companies. In the last two years this configuration is down at least 50 percent. It will drop further if this thing continues much longer,'' the spokesman said. A foreign business specialist, who also spoke on condition of anonymity, said: `` In <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, the key to Americans doing business these days is, ` let's make a deal.''' When economic sanctions aimed at getting rid of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> were announced in 1988, there was widespread fear that <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> would close businesses that did not pay required taxes to the government. That did not happen. The businesses, which hire thousands of Panamanians and buy millions of dollars worth of goods from Panamanian companies each year, stayed open. `` There certainly is some bartering of services to the government in lieu of taxes paid,'' the specialist said, but added that <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> also recognizes the economic impact that closing the businesses would mean in a nation with a 20 percent unemployment rate. Many executives of many multinational corporations, including several leaders, have been replaced the past two years by Panamanians, he said. `` The chairman of <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> here is a Panamanian, so is the chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Colgate-Palmolive </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. `` The banks in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> are pretty well locally managed now too.'' The economic sanctions, he said, are more damaging to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> business than to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s government. The sanctions prevent American companies and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government entities from paying taxes to the government. `` By <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> calculations all the taxes we should pay and do n't would keep the Panamanian government afloat for only two days,'' he said. He added that many multinational businesses have been losing money in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> because of its economy, and some company officials soon may decide to close operations there. `` <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> is a small country, and it would not be a major loss to some of the biggest companies,'' he said. `` The tragedy is that once <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> loses those companies, it is hard for it to get them back.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GreggNomination     05-13 0545</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gregg Nomination,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Bush Aide Questioned on Contra Knowledge</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON>, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s ambassador-designate to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, faces further questioning by a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> panel about his knowledge in 1985 and 1986 of <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s secret network to arm the Nicaraguan On Friday, Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON> accused <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s national security adviser when he was vice president, of `` sponsoring a free-lance, covert operation out of the vice president's office.'' <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, D-Calif., said <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> was making `` sweeping denials'' of his knowledge about the Nicaraguan Contra network `` apparently in order to cover up the truth and to limit embarrassment to your boss, then-presidential candidate <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Even though <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> at the time had banned <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid to the Contras, <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> said it did n't occur to him that there was anything `` ipso facto illegal.'' He said former <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> operative <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> had been focusing on alleged corruption by some of the arms dealers involved in the network and did n't think that kind of matter was sufficiently `` vice presidential'' to tell <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> underwent a three-hour hearing before a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> foreign relations subcommittee chaired by <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, who said later through an office spokesman that there will be further questioning on the Iran-Contra affair. `` There's going to be another hearing,'' said the spokesman, <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> <PERSON> Flander </PERSON>. `` The questions have not all been asked or answered.'' <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> says he did n't find out until August 1986 from <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> that <PERSON> North </PERSON> might be involved with facilitating the supply of lethal aid to the Contras. With support from <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> was sent to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> to help the air force there counter guerrilla insurgents. <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> said he did n't know until the August 1986 meeting that <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> was involved in helping the Contras. <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON>'s training at the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> and friendship with <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> `` apparently led you to believe you could serve the national interest by sponsoring a free-lance, covert operation out of the vice president's office,'' <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON> said. The senator said a cover story about <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>' sole mission in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> being to help the Salvadoran air force `` was seemingly concocted.'' `` I think it is a rather full-blown example of a conspiracy theory,'' <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>'s comments. `` That's not what I was doing. It is not what <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> was doing, to my knowledge. My job was to keep the vice president informed. I did not have operational responsibility for anything. ... To do that would have been the quickest way for me to lose my job.'' The ambassador-designate for the first time offered what he called `` a speculative explanation'' of the fact that two April 1986 documents from his office said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was to be briefed on `` resupply of the Contras'' in a meeting with <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>. `` I believe the agenda item was a garbled reference to resupply of copters'' in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> `` instead of resupply of the Contras,'' <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> testified. He declined to specify whether he thought his aide, Col. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Watson </PERSON>, or a secretary, had gotten the wording garbled. <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> recalled that at the time, <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> was concerned that helicopters being used by the Salvadoran military needed spare parts. He said he came to the conclusion that the reference had gotten garbled after seeing galleys of a book <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> recently completed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0034EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Panama Bjt   05-13 0443</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Panama, Bjt,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>OAS Foreign Ministers To Meet on Panama</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is preparing to lobby hard for a tough resolution denouncing <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> when <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> foreign ministers meet next week to discuss the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> crisis. But Panamanian authorities are expected to blame the upheaval in their country on what they regard as systematic <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intervention in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s internal affairs. The <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> permanent council on Friday approved a <LOCATION> Venezuelan </LOCATION> proposal for the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> foreign ministers to meet next Wednesday to discuss the `` serious crisis'' in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. While many delegates expressed concern about the interruption of the election process and the violence directed against some Panamanian opposition leaders, others argued against interfering in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s internal affairs. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s representative, <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, used the occasion to blast <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> actions, saying, `` We will not bow to the colossus of the north.'' He cited reports alleging that the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration donated $ 10 million to the opposition candidate's campaign. He also said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government had funded a clandestine anti-government radio operation, that preparations were being made to scuttle the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> treaties and that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military forces in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> are engaged in hostile military maneuvers. But the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> delegate, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryce </PERSON>, said that in the interest of the people of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> must raise its collective voice `` against the dictator <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and demand that he respect the will of the courageous people of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>.'' On Thursday, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> began referring to the opposition candidate, <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Endara </PERSON>, as the president-elect of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, based on exit polls showing he had a sizeable lead over the pro-Noriega candidate, <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Duque </PERSON>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, who asked not to be identified, said there seemed to be little likelihood that the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> foreign ministers would designate <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> as the winner. There also was some doubt that the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> would approve a resolution condemning <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, the officials said. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was expected to fight hard for a toughly worded resolution, but strong resistance was anticipated from a number of countries, especially <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, both of which attach high priority to the principle of non-interference. Even <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>, which initiated the call for a foreign ministers meeting, was restrained in outlining its reasons. Ambassador <PERSON> Edilberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Moreno </PERSON> made no direct reference to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, saying only that `` the popular will'' of hemispheric nations must be respected and that a meeting of foreign ministers at this time is appropriate given the `` grave crisis'' in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. The strongest anti-Noriega statement during the meeting was delivered by Jamaican Ambassador <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, who denounced `` this blatant rape of democracy'' in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DuneShacks Bjt   05-13 0538</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dune Shacks, Bjt,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cape Cod Dune Shacks Win Historic Designation, Future Still In Doubt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Seventeen rustic shacks on the outer dunes of <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cod </LOCATION> could still be ripped down even though the huts, which provided soul-searching solitude to <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerouac </PERSON> and scores of other creative minds, have won national historic designation. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> on Friday placed the primitive huts on the National Register of Historic Places over the objections of regional officials at the <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cod </LOCATION> <LOCATION> National </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Seashore </LOCATION>. `` The dune shacks are an important part of the pattern of artistic and cultural life on the outer <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> and merit the protection and recognition of the National Register,'' said <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Historical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> that pushed for the designation. But <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Cables </PERSON>, regional director of the <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, said earlier this year that a historic designation `` affords no guarantee of protection.'' `` The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> could raze these shacks. There's still potential for that to happen,'' said <PERSON> Edie </PERSON> <PERSON> Shean-Hammond </PERSON>, a regional <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> But she said regional officials vowed in December that all the huts would be preserved until plans for the area are completed. She said preservation of the dune shacks in those plans `` is under full consideration.'' `` For the next few years, we do n't see anything happening at all,'' <PERSON> Shean-Hammond </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Gail </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, a dune hut activist, remained skeptical. `` All I know is for 30 years they've been doing everything they could to destroy these shacks,'' she said. <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> called the historic designation `` a small victory, but it really does n't mean a lot. It's still up to the National Seashore -LRB- officials -RRB- to decide what to do with them.'' She said three of the shacks have been razed since 1984 and two of the remaining 17 had been slated for destruction. The one - and two-room gray shingled beach huts lie between <LOCATION> Truro </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Provincetown </LOCATION> near the tip of <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cod </LOCATION> Built in the 1920s and 1930s by the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> as shelters, the weather-beaten shacks offer none of the conveniences of modern life, such as electricity and plumbing. But they provide peaceful hideaways in a strikingly unspoiled setting reachable only by four-wheel drive vehicles or walking. `` Yes, residence on the dunes ... is uniquely sheltering and certainly stimulating to creative work,'' <PERSON> Kerouac </PERSON> wrote in a 1963 letter. `` It's true that I was working on ` On the Road' there, summer of 1950.'' Preservationists say the shacks have been used by <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kerouac </PERSON>, poet e.e. cummings, author <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Mailer </PERSON> and scores of lesser-known painters, poets, playwrights and novelists, earning them a place in American history and worthy of protection. The shacks came under <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> control in 1961 when the government purchased 27,000 acres of outer <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> land for the <ORGANIZATION> Cape </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cod </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seashore </ORGANIZATION>. A private group has been managing the rustic huts, renting them for $ 150 a week. <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> officials in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> previously had maintained that the dune shacks did not have the architectural or historic value to warrant preservation. The service had indicated the shacks would be demolished after leases with the current owners expire over the next 16 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Landsat     05-13 0525</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Landsat,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Space Council Seeks to Extend Landsat</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LISA M. HAMM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> is urging President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to commit to funding the Landsat earth-sensing satellites, which were almost shut down in March, through fiscal 1991. The council, under the leadership of Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, made the recommendation Friday. `` This signifies a real commitment of the <ORGANIZATION> Bush-Quayle </ORGANIZATION> administration to be aggressive in space,'' said an administration official who spoke on the condition of anonymity. The Landsat program, launched in 1978, has long been plagued by funding uncertainty because the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration had hoped to commercialize it. That proved not to be feasible, the source said. `` For the first time, the administration has stepped forward and said it -LRB- Landsat -RRB- could not be fully commercialized well into the 21st century,'' the source said. `` The demand for the data has not grown as rapidly as early forecasts had projected.'' Indeed, the federal government is Landsat's biggest client, although 13 countries have bought Landsat stations, he said. The Landsat satellites were due to be turned off March 31, when the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> was to run out of money to operate them. But <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> announced on March 6 that he had gained a commitment for funds to keep the program going until the space council, which studies national space programs, completed a review. Two satellites currently are in operation, Landsat 4 and Landsat 5. They provide photos for mineral exploration, checking soil conditions and vegetation, urban and rural planning, monitoring volcanoes and tracing ocean currents. But both have been running well beyond their expected lifetimes and are no longer fully functional. An improved satellite, Landsat 6, is scheduled to be launched in 1991. The space council recommended money be made available to continue operations of Landsat 4 and Landsat 5 through fiscal 1990. That, combined with the $ 200 million already committed to launching Landsat 6 in 1991, `` will give you data continuity until 1996,'' the source said. However, the source of funding after fiscal 1991 remained a question. The space council directed the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> and council staff to focus on ways to keep the data flowing. The council's decision calls for user departments and agencies such as the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> departments and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> to provide the $ 5 million needed to continue the program through the remainder of fiscal 1989. The space council hopes to obtain $ 19 million needed for the 1990 fiscal year through a supplemental request for the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s budget, the source said. `` We've already paid almost $ 200 million for <ORGANIZATION> Landsat </ORGANIZATION> 6,'' the official said. `` This signals commitment in the long run, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' continued leadership in space and space technology.'' The official said <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> demonstrated during the meeting the satellites' ability to highlight environmental concerns. `` The vice president had in the room images from April 7 from the Valdez oil spill in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, and you could clearly see where the oil spill was,'' the administration official said. `` You could clearly see that Landsat can have real use to environmental matters.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-IowaTrains     05-13 0351</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iowa Trains,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>For release 9 a.m. EDT; time set by source</HEAD>
<HEAD>Railroad Administration Says It Wasn't To Blame for Iowa Crash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railroad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> was unfairly blamed for contributing to a fiery train collision in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> last summer that killed two people, an <ORGANIZATION> FRA </ORGANIZATION> official said today. The complaint was voiced by <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Lindsey </PERSON>, chief counsel for the agency, in a letter to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> said last Tuesday that failures by the <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interstate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railroad </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> FRA </ORGANIZATION> to enforce train operating rules were part of what caused the July 30 head-on crash between two freight trains. Two crewmen on a westbound train were killed when it collided with an eastbound train at <LOCATION> Altoona </LOCATION>. More than 2,000 people were evacuated from their homes as two tank cars containing 20,000 gallons of denatured alcohol burned for more than two days. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> blamed <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interstate </ORGANIZATION>, which operated both trains, and said the eastbound train had been operated by a fatigued crew. The panel also blamed the FRA for failing to act against <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interstate </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Lindsey </PERSON>, in a letter to the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION>, said the criticism of the FRA `` is not only unfounded; it demonstrates a basic lack of understanding of the difference between a railroad's own rules and federal regulations, and it evidences a remarkable ignorance of <ORGANIZATION> FRA </ORGANIZATION>'s rail safety program and rules.'' The crash was caused by one train leaving too early in violation of an internal railroad order, <PERSON> Lindsey </PERSON> said. `` To state the elementary, violation of a train order constitutes a violation of railroad rules, not federal regulations; responsibility for enforcing compliance with the railroad's own rules is the railroad's, not <ORGANIZATION> FRA </ORGANIZATION>'s,'' he wrote. `` FRA is not the guarantor of rail safety,'' he said. `` Instead, its mission is to develop appropriate safety standards for the industry, to monitor railroad compliance and to conduct an enforcement effort that will have a deterrent effect overall.'' `` FRA can not prevent every instance of non-compliance, nor can it control the propensity for human beings to make bad decisions or to behave negligently,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-BushText 6Takes   05-13 0331</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 6 Takes,330-1,700</SECOND>
<DATELINE>COLLEGE STATION, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the prepared text of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s speech Friday to graduating seniors at <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> A & amp; M <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. My sincerest congratulations go to every graduate, and to your parents. In this ceremony, we celebrate nothing less than the commencement of the rest, and the best, of your life. When you look back to your days at <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> A & amp; M, you will have a lot to be proud of _ a university that is first in baseball and first in service to our nation. Many are the heroes whose names are called at Muster. Many are those you remember in Silver Taps. We are reminded that no generation can escape history. Parents _ we share a fervent desire for our children, and their children, to know a better world, a safer world. Students _ your parents and grandparents have lived through a world war, and helped <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to rebuild the world. They witnessed the drama of postwar nations divided by Soviet subversion and force, but sustained by an allied response most vividly seen in the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Airlift. Wise men _ <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Vandenberg </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Rayburn </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>, <PERSON> Acheson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kennan </PERSON> _ crafted the strategy of containment. They believed that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, denied the easy course of expansion, would turn inward and address the contradictions of its inefficient, repressive and inhumane system. And they were right. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is now publicly facing this hard reality. Containment worked. Containment worked because our democratic principles, institutions and values are sound, and always have been. It worked because our alliances were and are strong; and because the superiority of free societies and free markets over stagnant socialism is undeniable. We are approaching the conclusion of an historic postwar struggle between two visions _ one of tyranny and conflict, and one of democracy and freedom. The review of U.S.-Soviet relations that my administration has just completed outlines a new path toward resolving this struggle.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-BushText 1stadd   05-13 0367</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 1st add,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>COLLEGE STATION, Texas: this struggle.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Our goal is bold _ more ambitious than any of my predecessors might have thought possible. Our review indicates that 40 years of perseverance have brought us a precious opportunity. Now it is time to move beyond containment, to a new policy for the 1990s _ one that recognizes the full scope of change taking place around the world, and in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> itself. In sum, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> now has as its goal much more than simply containing <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> expansionism _ we seek the integration of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> into the community of nations. As the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> moves toward greater openness and democratization _ as they meet the challenge of responsible international behavior _ we will match their steps with steps of our own. Ultimately, our objective is to welcome the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> back into the world order. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> says it seeks to make peace with the world, and criticizes its own postwar policies. These are words we can only applaud. But a new relationship can not be simply declared by <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, or bestowed by others. It must be earned. It must be earned because promises are never enough. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has promised a more cooperative relationship before, only to reverse course and return to militarism. Soviet foreign policy has been almost seasonal _ warmth before cold, thaw before freeze. We seek a friendship that knows no season of suspicion, no chill of distrust. We hope perestroika is pointing the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to a break with the cycles of the past _ a definitive break. Who would have thought we would see the deliberations of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on the front page of Pravda, or dissident <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> seated near the councils of power? Who would have imagined a Soviet leader who canvasses the sidewalks of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>? These are hopeful _ indeed, remarkable _ signs. Let no one doubt our sincere desire to see perestroika continue and succeed. But the national security of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and our allies is not predicated on hope. It must be based on deeds. We look for enduring, ingrained economic and political change.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-BushText 2ndadd   05-13 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 2nd add,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>COLLEGE STATION, Texas: political change.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 While we hope to move beyond containment, we are only at the beginning of our new path. Many dangers and uncertainties are ahead. We must not forget that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has acquired awesome military capabilities. That was a fact of life for my predecessors. That has always been a fact of life for our allies. And that is a fact of life for me. As we seek peace, we must also remain strong. The purpose of our military might is not to pressure a weak Soviet economy, or to seek military superiority. It is to deter war. It is to defend ourselves and our allies, and to do something more _ to convince the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> that there can be no reward in pursuing expansionism _ to convince the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> that reward lies in the pursuit of peace. Western policies must encourage the evolution of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> toward an open society. This task will test our strength. It will tax our patience. And it will require a sweeping vision _ let me share with you my vision. I see a Western Hemisphere of democratic, prosperous nations, no longer threatened by a <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> or a <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> armed by <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. I see a Soviet Union that pulls away from ties to terrorist nations _ like <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> _ that threaten the legitimate security of their neighbors. I see a Soviet Union which respects <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s integrity, and returns the Northern Territories of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>; a prelude to the day when all the great nations of <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> will live in harmony. But the fulfillment of this vision requires the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to take positive steps, including: First: Reduce Soviet forces. Although some small steps have already been taken, the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact still possesses more than 30,000 tanks, more than twice as much artillery and hundreds of thousands more troops in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> than <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>. They should cut their forces to less threatening levels, in proportion to their legitimate security needs. Second: Adhere to the Soviet obligation _ promised in the final days of World War II _ to support self-determination for all the nations of Eastern and <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. This requires specific abandonment of the <ORGANIZATION> Brezhnev </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Doctrine </ORGANIZATION>. One day it should be possible to drive from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION> without seeing a single guard tower or a strand of barbed wire. In short, tear down the Iron Curtain.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-BushText 3rdadd   05-13 0343</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 3rd add,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>COLLEGE STATION, Texas: Iron Curtain.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Third: Work with the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> in positive, practical _ not merely rhetorical _ steps toward diplomatic solutions to regional disputes around the world. I welcome the Soviet withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> agreement. But there is much more to be done around the world. We're ready. Let's roll up our sleeves and get to work. Fourth: Achieve a lasting political pluralism and respect for human rights. Dramatic events have already occurred in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. We are impressed by limited, but freely contested, elections. We are impressed by a greater toleration of dissent. We are impressed by a new frankness about the <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> era. Mr. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, do n't stop now. Fifth: Join with us in addressing pressing global problems, including the international drug menace, and dangers to the environment. We can build a better world for our children. As the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> moves toward arms reduction and reform, it will find willing partners in the West. We seek verifiable, stabilizing arms control and arms reduction agreements with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and its allies. However, arms control is not an end in itself, but a means of contributing to the security of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, and the peace of the world. I directed Secretary <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> to propose to the Soviets that we resume negotiations on strategic forces in June. And, as you know, the Soviets have agreed. Our basic approach is clear. In the Strategic Arms Reduction Talks, we wish to reduce the risk of nuclear war. In the companion <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> and Space Talks, our objective will be to preserve our options to deploy advanced defenses when they are ready. In nuclear testing we will continue to seek the necessary verification improvements in existing treaties to permit them to be brought into force. We will continue to seek a verifiable global ban on chemical weapons. We support <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> efforts to reduce the Soviet offensive threat in the negotiations on Conventional Forces in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. And, as I've said, fundamental to all of these objectives is simple openness.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-BushText 4thadd   05-13 0306</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 4th add,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>COLLEGE STATION, Texas: simple openness.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Make no mistake, a new breeze is blowing across the steppes and cities of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Why not, then, let this spirit of openness grow, let more barriers come down. Open emigration, open debate, open airwaves _ let openness come to mean the publication and sale of banned books and newspapers in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Let the 19,000 Soviet Jews who emigrated last year be followed by any number who wish to emigrate this year. Let openness come to mean nothing less than the free exchange of people, books and ideas between East and West. And let it come to mean one thing more. Thirty-four years ago, President <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> met in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> with Soviet leaders who, after the death of <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>, promised a new approach toward the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. He proposed a plan called `` Open Skies,'' which would allow unarmed aircraft from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to fly over the territory of the other country. This would open up military activities to regular scrutiny and, as President <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> put it, `` convince the world that we are ... lessening danger and relaxing tension.'' President <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>'s suggestion tested Soviet readiness to open their society. The Kremlin failed that test. Let us again explore that proposal, but on a broader, more intrusive and radical basis _ one which I hope would include allies on both sides. We suggest that those countries that wish to examine this proposal meet soon to work out the necessary operational details, separately from other arms control negotiations. Such surveillance flights, complementing satellites, would provide regular scrutiny for both sides. Such unprecedented territorial access would show the world the meaning of the concept of openness. The very Soviet willingness to embrace such a concept would reveal their commitment to change.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-BushText 5thadd   05-13 0340</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush Text, 5th add,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>COLLEGE STATION, Texas: to change.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Where there is cooperation, there can be a broader economic relationship. But economic relations have been stifled by Soviet internal policies. They have been injured by <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s practice of using the cloak of commerce to steal technology from the West. Ending discriminatory treatment of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> firms would be a helpful step. Trade and financial transactions should take place on a normal commercial basis. And should the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> codify its emigration laws in accord with international standards and implement its new laws faithfully, I am prepared to work with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for a temporary waiver of the Jackson-Vanik Amendment, opening the way to extending Most Favored Nation trade status to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Unon </LOCATION>. The policy I have just described has everything to do with you. Today you graduate. You will start careers and families. And you will become the leaders of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> in the next century. What kind of world will you know? Perhaps the world order of the future will truly be a family of nations. It is a sad truth that nothing forces us to recognize our common humanity more swiftly than a natural disaster. I am thinking of <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, just a few months ago _ a tragedy without blame, warlike devastation without war. My son took our 12-year-old grandson to <LOCATION> Yerevan </LOCATION>. At the end of a day of comforting the injured and consoling the bereaved, father and son sat down together amid the ruins and wept. How can our two countries magnify this simple expression of caring? How can we each convey the goodwill of our people? Forty-three years ago, a young lieutenant by the name of <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kotzebue </PERSON>, Class of 1945 at <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> A & amp; M, was the first <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> soldier to shake hands with the Soviets at the banks of the <LOCATION> Elbe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. Once again, we are ready to extend our hand. Once again, we are ready for a hand in return. Once again, it is a time for peace.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>End Bush Text _ 6 Takes</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpaceShuttleSchedule     05-13 0309</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Shuttle Schedule,0317</SECOND>
<HEAD>NASA Shuffles Space Shuttle Launch Schedule</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The space agency is juggling the launch schedule for five space shuttle flights, including postponement until 1990 of the Hubble Space Telescope mission long awaited by scientists. The schedule changes, announced Friday, became necessary when <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> decided last month that the shuttle <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> could not be readied in time for a July launch because of modifications that must be made. Because of <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>'s lag, officials said they could not support two missions in the July-August time period and still preserve an October launch period for the high-priority <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> flight to <LOCATION> Jupiter </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> said in April that it was moving the <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> flight, a classified <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> mission, to August, and was shifting a Discovery military mission set for August until sometime after the <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> launch on Atlantis, which is set for Oct. 12. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> announced this new sequence Friday for post-Galileo missions: _ Discovery on the military mission that had been scheduled in August _ <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, to dispatch a communications satellite and retrieve a science satellite orbiting since 1984 Officials want to recover the 10.7-ton satellite before it can re-enter the atmosphere and burn up late this year or in early 1990. _ Atlantis on a <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> mission _ Discovery with the <ORGANIZATION> Hubble </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telescope </ORGANIZATION>, which is to study the universe far beyond the sun and its planets Under a previous schedule the telescope had been scheduled for launch in December. The earliest now is February. _ <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> with the Astro-1 payload, a package of ultraviolet and X-ray telescopes to observe deep space <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> said it would announce dates for these flights within a few weeks. It appears there will be three or four more launches this year, with the others slated for 1990. Two missions have flown so far in 1989.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0511EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--ChinaBeach-Nurses     05-13 0127</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China Beach-Nurses,0129</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nurses Group Awards `China Beach' For Portrayal Of Profession</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Critical-Care </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nurses </ORGANIZATION> will honor the <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> series `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>'' for what it considers the program's realistic depiction of Vietnam War nurses. <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Searle </PERSON>, president of the nurses group, said `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>'' was chosen because of its sensitive portrayal of nurses in an episode titled `` VETS,'' which cast actual <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> nurses. `` It is very encouraging to see a prime-time television show communicate such intelligence and accuracy in their portrayal of nurses without compromising the dramatic impact and entertainment value of the show,'' she said Friday. Representatives from the show's cast and crew will accept the award Monday during the <ORGANIZATION> AACN </ORGANIZATION>'s 16th annual <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teaching </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     05-13 0676</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0704</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TORONTO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 British rock star Sting brought his campaign to save the <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> rainforest to <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>, urging Canadians to contribute to the cause before the world `` enters a new dark age.'' Accompanied by several Brazilian Indian leaders, Sting told reporters Friday that the deforestation of <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> by farmers, miners, loggers and dam builders will rob the world of a major oxygen source within 30 years. `` Then, we will be haunted by famine, drought, pestilence, disease _ and haunted by our own self-inflicted ignorance,'' he said. Sting's forecast of apocalypse was echoed by his Brazilian companions, who said that their people are already experiencing catastrophe and a forest preserve must be set up before it is too late. Sting helped establish <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rainforest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, which aims to establish an <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> conservation area the size of <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. He is on a 28-day publicity tour in which he will visit 14 countries.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MOBILE, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Carradine </PERSON> eluded high kicks and strong forearms often as the half-Chinese priest in the television show `` <LOCATION> Kung </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fu </LOCATION>,'' but taking a blank pistol from his pants on a movie set proved trouble. <PERSON> Carradine </PERSON>, 48, suffered a minor injury Friday when he accidentally shot himself in the groin with a .45 - caliber blank pistol during the filming of the movie `` One For The Money Fire Department spokesman <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Cosgrove </PERSON> said paramedics were called to the scene after the incident at the Mobile docks, but the actor's injury was superficial and he refused treatment. <PERSON> Carradine </PERSON> was removing the pistol from his pants when it fired, officials said. Nobody on the film crew would discuss the incident, and filming continued Friday afternoon. `` One For The Money'' is about one man's fight against corruption in an era of privately controlled police. The director is <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Prior </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Sesame Street'' has a new character, a baby girl named <PERSON> Gabriela </PERSON>, thanks to help from the rarely cooperative Oscar the Grouch. The birth of <PERSON> Luis </PERSON>' and <PERSON> Maria </PERSON>'s child on Friday was eagerly awaited. Muppet and human characters gathered around <PERSON> Maria </PERSON>'s bed to be introduced to the infant. `` Welcome to Sesame Street and the world!'' said Big Bird. But not everything went smoothly. When it was time to go to the hospital for the delivery, <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> found that their car had been towed. <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> drove them to the hospital, occasioning much hand-wringing on his part. `` I'm a grouch,'' he explained, and grouches are not supposed to do nice things or be happy about events like the birth of a baby. The marriage of <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> and <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> was the finale for last season. <PERSON> Sonia </PERSON> <PERSON> Manzano </PERSON>, who plays <PERSON> Maria </PERSON>, became a mother 13 months ago and her real-life daughter will eventually play her television daughter.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ANKARA, Turkey (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> is in <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> over the weekend for business and pleasure. He arrived Friday for meetings with Turkish leaders, including Premier <PERSON> Turgut </PERSON> <PERSON> Ozal </PERSON>, and a cruise along <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>'s Aegean coast. The prince was to fly to the coast aboard his private plane and go on a yatch chartered by <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Kent </PERSON>, a friend and fellow polo player from <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, for a weekend cruise. During the cruise Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> was expected to visit historical sites such as the ruins of the Hellenistic city <LOCATION> Ephesus </LOCATION> south of <LOCATION> Izmir </LOCATION>. The prince also was to spend time at the house of <PERSON> Ahmet </PERSON> <PERSON> Ertegun </PERSON>, the owner of <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION>, at <LOCATION> Bodrum </LOCATION>, which is in the southwestern tip of <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Duchess of <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, daughter-in-law of Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, will make a two-day visit to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> at month's end, Buckingham Palace said The 29-year-old duchess, who is married <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, will take the salute at the queen's birthday parade of British forces in <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> on May 26. The duchess, the former <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>, flies into the city on May 24, and will visit the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall, the historical exhibition at the Reichstag, the former German parliament, and several schools, a palace spokesman said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     05-13 0440</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0458</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHITTENANGO, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's not exactly somewhere over the rainbow, but this central <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> village promises a resemblance to the magical land of Oz. Organizers are expecting up to 20,000 people to travel today to this community of 3,600 people, 15 miles east of <LOCATION> Syracuse </LOCATION> for its annual Ozfest, which this year is celebrating the golden anniversary of the movie, `` The Wizard of Oz.'' It's the biggest day of the year for <LOCATION> Chittenango </LOCATION>, the birthplace of Oz creator <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Baum </PERSON>, said Ozfest Chairwoman <PERSON> Beverly </PERSON> <PERSON> Brickner </PERSON>. The day will be marked by a parade and other entertainment, people dressed up as characters from `` The Wizard of Oz,'' and an appearance by the 73-year-old actor who played the <LOCATION> Munchkinland </LOCATION> coroner, <PERSON> Meinhardt </PERSON> <PERSON> Raabe </PERSON>. The first celebration was in 1978. `` For seven or eight years nobody here took it seriously, but now everybody realizes this is all worthwhile,'' she said. The village now has visible signs of its Oz connections: a yellow brick sidewalk in the business district; signs featuring Oz characters on the edge of the village; and Oz-inspired business names such as Aunt Em's Kitchen -LRB- which sells Oz cream -RRB-, Emerald City Bowling, Over the <ORGANIZATION> Rainbow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crafts </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Tin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Man </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Construction </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Baum </PERSON> lived in <LOCATION> Chittenango </LOCATION> only a few years after his birth in 1856; his birthplace has burned down <PERSON> Brickner </PERSON> would like officials to put up a bronze plaque at the house and she has hopes of building an Oz museum. `` I'd like to even see us build an <LOCATION> Emerald </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> here,'' she said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LORTON, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Gambino </PERSON> decided to give his home a name after seeing many of his neighbors do the same. `` You have River View this, and Mountain View, and Valley View,'' he said. <PERSON> Gambino </PERSON> looked out his window for an idea, and there it was. The name: `` Prison View Estate.'' He said there was no use in ignoring the nearby 3,000-acre <ORGANIZATION> Lorton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Complex </ORGANIZATION>. Gambino, a postal worker, placed a decorative sign next to his driveway and had Prison View Estate printed on his family checks. The name is so widely recognized that when he calls for a delivery of heating oil, he does n't have to give his name. `` I say I need a delivery at Prison View Estate, and the next day it's there,'' said <PERSON> Gambino </PERSON>, 35. He has n't had any problems with the prison, which is 20 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, and run by the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. He said the prison keeps a neat lawn, and he does n't worry about escapees. `` They're good neighbors, as far as neighbors go,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0040EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TrainDerails 3rdLd-Writethru a0806 05-13 1042</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Train Derails, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0806,1066</SECOND>
<HEAD>Runaway Freight Jumps Tracks, Lands in Houses; Survivor Found In
Rubble</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 3rd-4th grafs, `At least ...' to UPDATE with one man found
alive in rubble and his tentative identity. Picks up 5th graf: `Southern
Pacific ...' SUBS 20th graf, `Another crew ...' to UPDATE with one man
listed as missing now.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos SBO1,2,3</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT JABLON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN BERNARDINO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A runaway freight train jumped its tracks at 90 mph on a downhill grade and plowed into a row of houses Friday, killing at least three people, two of them children. `` The train was all over the place. It looked like a toy in a sandbox. It was just everywhere _ in people's yards. Pieces of the axles were in people's yards,'' said witness <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorame </PERSON>. Late Friday evening, a 24-year-old man was found alive in the wreckage of a home more than 14 hours after the accident, said police Sgt. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>. He was found shortly before 9 p.m. Tentatively identified as <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>, he had been asleep when the 69-car train derailed and plowed through his home. Earlier Friday, at least two people were reported missing and firefighters and police combed the wreckage of the residential neighborhood. Two specially trained dogs from the volunteer <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dog </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> were used to search the rubble of the homes and the train. <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> said it would not begin moving the wrecked cars until word was received that all homes had been searched. Hospitals reported treating at least eight people for varying injuries, including the train's engineer <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Holland </PERSON>, 34, a 14-year <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> employee who was pulled from the wreckage by witnesses. <PERSON> Holland </PERSON> was listed in serious condition with broken ribs, bruises and cuts, said <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Coffey </PERSON>, a nursing supervisor at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bernardine </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> freight apparently lost its brakes toward the top of treacherous, 4,190-foot Cajon Pass and came raging down the grade at more than 90 mph before the derailment, said <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephanson </PERSON>. It flew off an embankment and into a neighborhood of modest two-and three-bedroom homes on the northwest outskirts of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION>, smashing houses and throwing out its load of sand-like potash. <PERSON> Stephanson </PERSON> said one of the five crewmembers radioed to a dispatcher in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> that the train was out of control. `` They said the speed was 90 mph a few miles up the track -LRB- from the crash site -RRB-,'' he said. `` They absolutely were out of control. ... It was a runaway train.'' He said the train apparently lost its brakes near the top of the pass in the mountains about 60 miles east of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. The train had four engines in front and two `` helper engines'' in back, and had between 55 and 69 cars in all. The rear engines had applied full brakes, <PERSON> Stephanson </PERSON> said. Police Sgt. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> said the train hit 11 homes. Six were destroyed, one had major damage and four had minor damage inflicted by the train, flying dirt and rocks from the roadbed and the potash, a mineral used in making fertilizer and soap. Property damage was estimated at $ 600,000. `` The engine came off the track and went through a house,'' said <PERSON> Dane </PERSON> <PERSON> Maloney </PERSON>, who saw the crash on his way to work. `` It was terrible, there were train cars on top of houses, train cars on top of cars. It sounded like a couple of bombs going off.'' `` It was going down from <LOCATION> Cajon </LOCATION> real fast, did n't have no brakes. I looked over, part of the train was in the air. It just fell back on the ground and all the sand started flying up in the air and stuff,'' said <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Michaels </PERSON>, a little boy who saw the wreck. The pass is the major road and rail conduit from the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> basin to <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>. Interstate 15 passes through it. The dead were identified as conductor <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Crown </PERSON>, 36, a member of the Bakersfield-based train crew and a <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> worker since 1972, and stepbrothers <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, 9, and <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, 7, whose home was smashed by the train. Another crew member, brakeman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reiss </PERSON>, 44, who has been with <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> since 1971, was still listed as missing, said train master <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Givens </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Bakersfield </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Loveland </PERSON> said the railroad will help people left homeless by the crash. `` We feel terrible about this,'' he said. <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwartz </PERSON> said a shelter had been set up at the <ORGANIZATION> Inland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Job </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> and 10 people had registered by late afternoon. About 200 people were kept from their homes for a time for fear that leaking diesel fuel could ignite, <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> said. He said most of the injuries were minor. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Kolstad </PERSON>, acting chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, was flying in from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, to direct the investigation, said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Mucho </PERSON>, the regional director. He said there was no indication of the cause. The train was carrying potash from the high-desert town of <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Pera </PERSON>. The tracks were expected to remain closed at least a day, forcing detour of 15 freights and two passenger trains a day, <PERSON> Pera </PERSON> said. The trains, including <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles-to-New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> service, would use a route through <LOCATION> Saugus </LOCATION>, he said. Elsewhere, a derailment near <LOCATION> Meridian </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, spilled thousands of gallons of antifreeze and diesel fuel into the <LOCATION> Chunky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, and residents were told Friday to keep away from the river. No injuries were reported in the Thursday night derailment of a <ORGANIZATION> MidSouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railroad </ORGANIZATION> train but more than 200 people were evacuated from the area and told they may not be able to return home until late Saturday or Sunday. Officials said those evacuated early Friday included 22 residents of a nursing home. `` We now estimate that 20,000 to 25,000 gallons of ethylene glycol alcohol _ antifreeze _ got into the river along with 3,000 to 5,000 gallons of diesel fuel,'' said <PERSON> Eleana </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Mississippi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pollution </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>. Twelve cars and three of the train's five engines left the tracks, with two of the engines landing partly in the river.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890513-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-13-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MotherGrads Bjt   05-13 0625</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mother Grads, Bjt,0643</SECOND>
<HEAD>Law School Next for Single Mother of Six Graduating with 4.0</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto SX1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM KELLY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SPOKANE, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
