<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 2332EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-OhioSnow 1stLd-Writethru a0748 05-07 0290</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ohio Snow, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0748,0293</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rare May Snowstorm Blamed for Bus Accident</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf to UPDATE snowfall in Rochester.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Storm Rdp</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANDUSKY, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Greyhound bus driving through a spring snowstorm overturned and slid down an embankment, injuring 16 people, and in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> snow fell Sunday for the first time in May in nearly a century. Snow also fell in parts of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, 10.1 inches of snow fell, breaking that city's snowfall record for May by more than 6 -LCB- inches. The unusual spring storm dumped up to 2 inches of icy slush on this northern <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> city, and was blamed for the bus accident Saturday that left three people hospitalized Sunday. Thirteen other people, including driver <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, were treated at two hospitals for minor cuts and bruises and released, said Highway Patrol Sgt. <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Meyer </PERSON>. Rains and light snow abruptly changed to a heavy mix of snow and sleet and quickly covered <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> Route 2 along <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION> just west of <LOCATION> Sandusky </LOCATION> when the accident occurred around 8:30 p.m. Saturday, <PERSON> Meyer </PERSON> said. `` I've never seen anything like -LRB- the weather -RRB- last night in May,'' <PERSON> Meyer </PERSON> said. `` It was an isolated condition, a snow and sleet downpour. Within a matter of seconds, it seemed like you had two inches of slush on the road.'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> was trying slow the bus by downshifting when it spun 180 degrees in the road, flipped onto its left side and slid gently down the 20-foot road embankment, <PERSON> Meyer </PERSON> said. In <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>, overnight temperatures dipped into the low to mid-30s. Snow Saturday and Sunday came exactly 91 years after the city recorded its last measurable snowfall in May.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 2333EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-RitualSlayings 3rdLd-Writethru a0754 05-07 0811</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ritual Slayings, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0754,0834</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cult Members Say Ringleader Ordered His Own Killing</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 27th graf, `Also arrested...,' with 1 graf to CORRECT name,
Guero Lopez sted Bueno Lopez. Pick up 28th pvs, `De Leon...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRIS ANGELO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The leader of a drug-smuggling cult that killed 15 people and buried their bodies along the U.S.-Mexican border ordered his own killing when police closed in on him, two of his companions said Sunday. <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> was shot and killed Saturday after police appeared outside the <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> apartment building where he was staying with <PERSON> Sara </PERSON> <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> and five other alleged cult members. Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON>, 24, a former honor student at <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southmost </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION>, told reporters <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> ordered <PERSON> Alvaro </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> to kill him and his right-hand man, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Quintana </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON>, described as the `` witch'' of the cult, de <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> and three others arrested after the shootout were presented to reporters Sunday at the <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> City Attorney General's office. They stood behind a 3-by-6-foot table bearing confiscated cult items, including a skull apparently made of wax and a female doll holding another doll. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> said he shot <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Quintana </PERSON> with a machine gun after <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> ordered him to do so and hit him when he resisted. `` He went crazy, crazy'' when police came, said <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON>, who had had collar-length blond hair and a beard and wore a dirty white shirt. `` He grabbed a bundle of money and threw it and began shooting out the window,'' he said. `` He said everything, everything was lost.'' He quoted <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> as saying, `` No one's going to have this money.'' Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> said <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> `` ordered him to kill him because it was the end and he wanted to die with <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>.'' She referred to <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON>, 26, as <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Padrino </LOCATION>, or the godfather. The bodies of <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Quintana </PERSON> were found slumped together inside a tiny closet in the <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> apartment. Their shirts were smeared with blood. Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> said she did not see the shooting or the killings of 15 people whose bodies were found on the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Elena </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ranch </LOCATION> outside <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION> along the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> border in April. She said she did not know about those killings until she saw reports of them on television. <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> are believed to have directed human sacrifices, mutilations and the boiling of brains and other organs in rituals to bring occult protection to their drug-smuggling ring. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON>, 22, said he took part in the killing of <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> college student, and of some of the others on the ranch. But he and Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> indicated <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> committed most of the killings. Asked who killed <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON>, Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> said: `` Adolfo.'' De <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> said the young American was killed with a machete chop to the head. His back was opened to remove his spinal column for a necklace, he said. Appearing calm, Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> said she was sorry about the death of <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON> and the others. `` I feel sorry because when he disappeared I was trying to help the -LRB- <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON> -RRB- family,'' she said in response to reporters' questions She did not explain what she meant. `` If I had known it was like this, I would n't have been in it,'' she said of the cult. Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> told authorities <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> invited her to join `` Christian Santeria'' and asked her to use voodoo to help people with problems, said <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Polo </PERSON> <PERSON> Uscanga </PERSON>, deputy city attorney general. She said <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> initiated her into the cult in 1988. Santeria is a blend of Catholicism and old African beliefs that includes animal sacrifices. Asked if she was in love with <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON>, Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> said, `` No, but I followed him.'' <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> said he met <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> while working as a laborer on a northern <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> ranch. He said he was `` marked'' for divine protection in January at a ceremony in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> because he had killed someone in <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION>. Pulling back his shirt, he showed reporters a design of arrows on each upper arm. <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON>, missing since the first 12 bodies were uncovered on the ranch April 11, were among 11 people indicted in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on a four-count drug indictment. Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON>, de <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> and the others were being held in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> on charges including homicide, criminal association, wounding a police agent in the arrest, and damage to property, <PERSON> Polo </PERSON> said. Also arrested Saturday were <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> del </PERSON> <PERSON> Rocio </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuevas </PERSON> <PERSON> Guerra </PERSON>, 43, of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, who told authorites she loaned <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> $ 2,000; <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Orea </PERSON>, 23, a journalism student at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>; and <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Lourdes </PERSON> <PERSON> Guero </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>, 29. The connection of the latter two was not immediately clear. De <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> said two others involved in the cult were fugitives.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 2342EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Horowitz     05-07 0220</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Horowitz,0228</SECOND>
<HEAD>Art Deco Pioneer Dies Of Complications From AIDS</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Industrial designer <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Horowitz </PERSON>, whose eye for color helped transform this city's Art Deco District into a rainbow of pastel colors and renovated beachfront hotels, died of complications from AIDS. He was 43. <PERSON> Horowitz </PERSON>, who died Friday, saw the potential of buildings that had weathered through the years when few others could. Up to 150 Art Deco buildings in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> are painted pink, purple, peach and periwinkle, and about half are <PERSON> Horowitz </PERSON>' designs. He founded the <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Design </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Preservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> with <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Capitman </PERSON> in 1976. `` Really, he taught me what I know about Art Deco,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Capitman </PERSON>. In 1980, much of the Art Deco District's buildings displayed weathered, cracked stucco. But <PERSON> Horowitz </PERSON> could see past the peeling paint, and came up with a scheme for a whole block of buildings that made them look like confections. The idea caught on. <PERSON> Horowitz </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, and grew up with visions of the Art Deco-style Radio City Music Hall. He started a design firm in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, but moved to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>. He continued doing interior design as well as the <LOCATION> Deco </LOCATION> district's colorful exteriors It was not immediately known if <PERSON> Horowitz </PERSON> left survivors. Plans for a memorial service were pending.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 2356EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpaceShuttle-Coverage     05-07 0071</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Shuttle-Coverage,0074</SECOND>
<HEAD>Networks to Cover Shuttle Landing Live</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Space Shuttle, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 CBS, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> plan to provide live coverage of this afternoon's landing of the space shuttle Atlantis. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s coverage plans were undecided Sunday, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Adde </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> planned to go live five minutes before the scheduled 3:43 p.m. EDT landing. No details were available on <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s coverage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 0004EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BargeBlast 1stLd-Writethru a0609 05-07 0354</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Barge Blast, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0609,0359</SECOND>
<HEAD>Empty Barge Explodes on Ohio River: One Missing, Two Injured</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 1st graf to UPDATE that one man missing sted dead; SUBS
grafs 8-10, `The identity ... blast occurred' with 4 grafs to UPDATE with
details of blast, plan to drag river for missing man; picks up last graf,
`None of ...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EAST LIVERPOOL, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Chemical fumes sparked an explosion in a barge docked for cleaning at this <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> town Saturday, igniting a fire that injured two men and left one missing. The barge was empty but apparently contained residues from its usual cargo of benzene, a flammable chemical solvent, police said. Residents within a half-mile of the 3:30 p.m. blaze were asked to close their windows late Saturday afternoon and evening to avoid breathing possibly hazardous fumes, said <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Liverpool </LOCATION> police Officer <PERSON> Virgil </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. Benzene may produce irritating or toxic gases when burned. Vapors from the chemical also can cause coughing and lung irritation, as well as dizziness. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said the barge had been docked between the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> and some railroad tracks for cleaning. <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Liverpool </LOCATION> is in eastern <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. `` They were cleaning the barge,'' he said. `` It was empty and fumes apparently ignited.'' The blaze was extinguished by the town's Fire Department about two hours after it began, he said. Firefighters remained at the scene Saturday evening, wetting down ashes. Rescue crews planned to drag the 40-foot-deep river Sunday in search of the missing man, who disappeared when the blast blew the hatch off the vessel, said city police Capt. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Hyder </PERSON>. The two injured men were taken to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Liverpool </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, where one, <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Newbrough </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Chester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, was listed in serious condition with burns, a concussion and fractures, said a nursing supervisor who refused to identify herself. The other victim, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Liverpool </LOCATION>, also suffered burns but refused treatment and left the hospital, she said. <ORGANIZATION> Hyder </ORGANIZATION> said the three men were on the barge looking down into the hatch when it exploded. None of the chemical spilled into the river, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 0004EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-GasSpill     05-07 0198</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gas Spill,0204</SECOND>
<HEAD>Barge Spills 80,000 Gallons of Gasoline</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CATSKILL, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A barge carrying over 2 million gallons of gasoline struck a buoy Saturday and spilled about 80,000 gallons into the rain-swollen <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, environmental officials said. The leak aboard the <PERSON> Bouchard </PERSON> 45 was stopped and <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> officials were investigating the cause of the accident, the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> said. The accident about 30 miles south of <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION> was reported about 4 a.m., said <ORGANIZATION> DEC </ORGANIZATION> regional director <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Magee </PERSON>. The barge continued upriver to <LOCATION> Ravena </LOCATION> after the accident, where workers pumped out some compartments of the craft and shifted gasoline to other parts of the barge, she said. <ORGANIZATION> Getty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> owns the gasoline, <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> officials said. Once the gasoline was shifted, <PERSON> Magee </PERSON> said, the barge was to continue on to <LOCATION> Rensselaer </LOCATION> and unload, then return to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> for repairs. Rain and wind broke up most of the gasoline by Saturday afternoon, she said. A contractor was hired to clean up the rest of the spill, <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> officials said. `` We're expecting it will have a minimum impact and are arranging to get some biologists on the river,'' <PERSON> Magee </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 0015EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--RadioactiveContainer     05-07 0114</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Radioactive Container,0118</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eighty-Eight Passengers, Eight Crew Members To Be Checked For Radiation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Officials found a damaged container carrying radioactive material on a <ORGANIZATION> Mexicana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> plane Saturday and were checking the passengers and crew for contamination, police said. Residue from a package of molypentachloride, a corrossive that emits low-level beta radiation, was found in the cargo hold, according to fire officials. Flight 820 from <LOCATION> Acapulco </LOCATION> was carrying 88 passengers and eight crew members. While in flight, the pilot of the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727 radioed to <ORGANIZATION> Mexicana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> officials that there was a problem with the container and airline officials contacted <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> police, said Cpl. <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Chowmentowski </PERSON>. The incident was under investigation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 0020EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ZapII 2ndLd-Writethru a0600 05-07 0638</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Zap II, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0600,0649</SECOND>
<HEAD>Zap Hosts Reunion Of College Spring Fling That Ended In A Riot</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 7-8, `Saturday's reunion ... Kessler said' with 2
grafs to UPDATE with bigger crowd estimate, 30 arrests; picks up 9th graf,
`The mood ...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB IMRIE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ZAP, N.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Only about 50 leather-clad motorcyclists and a few hundred other peaceable partyers zipped into Zap on Saturday for the anniversary of the `` Zip to Zap'' party that ended in a riot 20 years ago. `` That makes my day. I love people and I love things happening. We do have it in order, so I am not worried,'' said Mayor <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Sailer </PERSON> said, smiling and waving beneath his blue baseball cap, which was emblazoned with the slogan `` I Zipped To Zap And Had A Blast.'' `` This is n't anything like it was 20 years ago,'' said <LOCATION> Mercer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON>, who was among the police who tried to quell the original riot. `` It was a long evening then.'' <PERSON> Sailer </PERSON> had been told to expect 500 bikers for Zip To Zap II, which was originally planned as 12 hours of partying and rock music in one of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>'s smaller towns. In 1969, this quiet hamlet of 300 people about 90 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Bismarck </LOCATION> hosted the first Zip to Zap, an idea hatched by the editor of the student newspaper at <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dakota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. It ended in disaster. The National Guard was called in to chase 2,000 drunken revelers out of town. Celebrants set a bonfire in Main Street and caused about $ 3,000 in damage before the crowd was dispersed. Saturday's reunion started quietly but livened up as the sun went down. People began dancing in the street to the blare of recorded music, and Zap's two bars were jammed. <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> said the crowd swelled to more than 500 people. Thirty people had been arrested by late Saturday night, mostly for being too young to drink or for drinking on public property. Middle-aged people and more than a few locals mingled with the student crowd. The mood was festive, far from a mob scene. There were guest books for people to sign. Soda pop and hot dogs were for sale everywhere, although beer was banned in the streets. D.J. <PERSON> Guerrero </PERSON> of <PERSON> Fargo </PERSON>, who attended the first Zip to Zap in 1969, remembered that beer prices helped touch off the riot. `` It was a mass of humanity out on the streets and everybody was having a good time, a good time gone sour,'' he said. `` Townspeople started jacking up the prices on beer and food and everything and kids got upset. They doubled the price on six-packs of beer.'' <PERSON> Guerrero </PERSON>, 53, brought his wife and two children to Zap for the reunion. `` They wanted to zip to Zap, so I said OK,'' he said <PERSON> Guerrero </PERSON> was also making amends for what happened in 1969. `` I apologized to the people here for what happened. The National Guard ... had to save the town. There would have been nothing left here.'' <PERSON> Alda </PERSON> <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON> transformed her garage just off Main Street into a mini-cafe, complete with $ 9 souvenir T-shirts: `` Zip To Zap. We're Back. The reunion was a good idea, the 64-year-old woman said. `` You have to let the kids do something, and the older people are just as nosy.'' Her son called her from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Friday night, asking if she was ready for the `` zippers'' and envious that he could not be home, Mrs. <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON> said. `` If everything is kept under control, it would be nice to be an annual event,'' she said. But the denizens of Zap are far from agreement on that idea. Some wanted the town barricaded Saturday to keep the visitors out, she said. `` It's a touchy question,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-China-NoReunion 1stLd-Writethru b0672 05-07 0756</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-China-No Reunion, 1st Ld-Writethru, b0672,0778</SECOND>
<HEAD>For Release Sun May 7 or Thereafter</HEAD>
<HEAD>Differences Still Exist Between China and Soviets</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 8th graf `Ties between...' with 1 graf to CORRECT that
ties were close between 1950 and 1960, sted last 10 years. Pickup 9th graf
`The main...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>With BC-Lessons from China, b0671</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> were brothers in communism, but the first summit since they fell out nearly 30 years ago will not be a family reunion. The Chinese, determined to show independence from their one-time tutor in revolution, have forced the Soviets to make the overtures and concessions toward normal relations. When <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> comes to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> on May 15, it will be <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>, the 84-year-old Chinese leader, who plays big brother, because of both age and his pioneering of economic reforms the Soviets are just beginning. During the past year, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> pulled Soviet troops out of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, announced unilateral troop withdrawals from the Chinese border and put pressure on the Soviet ally <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> to withdraw from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> after more than a decade of occupation. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> has said it will do so by Sept. 30. Those actions met <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s three conditions for a summit with the Soviet leader and moved closer to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s own goal of reducing international tension so he can focus on domestic economic problems. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> agreed to the summit almost grudgingly. When <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>, the Soviet foreign minister, announced the date during a visit to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> in February, the Chinese initially denied it and then issued a confirmation two days later. Ties between the two nations in trade, foreign policy and cultural exchange were close between 1950 and 1960, but <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> leaders say they have no intention of resuming the alliance. The main immediate value of the summit for <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, which is wary of an expansionist <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, has been the concessions on <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. Diplomatic sources said the Chinese were trying to extract new pledges even in the final weeks before <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s arrival. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s withdrawal plan does not include a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeeping force or establishment of an interim government to oversee elections. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is said to want both endorsed in the summit communique. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> seeks a general statement of principles guiding the relationship, like the <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> Communique signed by President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> on his 1972 visit to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. `` It's not obligatory'' to mention <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in the communique, said V.V. <PERSON> Duhin </PERSON>, cultural counsellor at the Soviet Embassy. `` This document is designed for many years, and <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> is a problem of this year and next year.'' <PERSON> Igor </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogachev </PERSON>, Soviet deputy foreign minister, slipped into <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> quietly in late April, hoping to resolve the matter. A Western diplomat described it as a `` game of chicken.'' Animosity and disagreement between the two countries have a long history. From the 17th century to the early 20th, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION> contended for influence in the vast Asian interior. Soviet agents helped organize the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in 1921 and gave it assistance, but also tried to dictate strategy in a way that irked the revolutionaries, especially <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse-tung </PERSON>. <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> thought little of <PERSON> Mao </PERSON>'s plan for revolution in the countryside. The Soviet dictator continued recognizing the Nationalist Chinese government even as <PERSON> Mao </PERSON>'s peasant guerrilla army was sweeping to victory. Friction continued after the Stalin-Mao alliance of 1950. The Soviets insisted on special rights to ports and railways in northeastern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in return for military and technological aid, embarrassing Chinese leaders who claimed to have ended foreign control. The split came in the early 1960s, after the Soviets refused to back <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in its 1959 border conflict with <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, would not help recapture <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> from the Nationalists and scrubbed an agreement to help the Chinese build a nuclear bomb. A border dispute led to a brief but bloody clash in 1969. Pragmatism took precedence over ideology under <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> resumed trade and other non-political exchanges with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Both <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> like to be seen as international peacemakers, and both have serious economic and political problems at home. Restless nationalist groups in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> have been demanding autonomy or independence. University students in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> have demonstrated for democracy on an unprecedented scale. <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> already has done away with <PERSON> Mao </PERSON>'s communes and shelved his theories of continuous class struggle. By meeting <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> is addressing one of <PERSON> Mao </PERSON>'s last remaining legacies: the Chinese-Soviet estrangement that has affected the world political map for three decades.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>End Adv for Sunday, May 7</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RadioactiveContainer 1stLd-Writethru a0616 05-07 0208</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Radioactive Container, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0616,0207</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eighty-Eight Passengers, Eight Crew Members To Be Checked For Radiation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Passengers and crew on a <ORGANIZATION> Mexicana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> plane that had recently dropped off leaking packages of a radioactive chemical showed no sign of radiation contamination, officials said Sunday. Officials said earlier that an undetermined amount of molypentachloride, a corrosive that emits low-level beta radiation, was found in the cargo hold of the plane. Flight 820 landed at about 10:20 p.m. Saturday. But fire communications supervisor <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Maier </PERSON> said checks showed the plane was n't contaminated, nor were the 88 passengers or eight crew members aboard Flight 820. The plane landed here at about 10:20 p.m. Saturday. Two or three packages of the radioactive material were loaded on the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727 at <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> O'Hare </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> for a previous flight to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Gagner </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The packages were unloaded in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and were found to be leaking while the plane was en route from <LOCATION> Acapulco </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, according to the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> and police. While in flight, the pilot of the airliner radioed to <ORGANIZATION> Mexicana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> officials about the leak and airline officials contacted <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> police, police Cpl. <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Chowmentowski </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-NorthernIreland 3rdLd-Writethru a0623 05-07 0282</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Northern Ireland, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0623,0285</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Bombs Injure Nine Soldiers</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Leads with 3 grafs to CLARIFY that explosions occurred overnight
Saturday. Pickup 4th graf `They said...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BELFAST, Northern Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two bombs exploded near <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> patrols overnight, injuring nine soldiers, police said Sunday. The <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> claimed responsibility for the first attack, saying it marked Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s 10 years in power. There was no immediate claim of responsibility for the other explosion. In the first bombing, police said the soldiers were in a mobile patrol at <LOCATION> Moybane </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> Crossmaglen </LOCATION>, close to the south <LOCATION> Armagh </LOCATION> border with the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> on Saturday night when the bomb exploded in an abandoned house. They said one of the five men was seriously hurt by being hurled through the air with flying debris, and the house was wrecked. The five soldiers were airlifted by helicopter to a hospital, and the area was sealed off to await inspection by daylight in case of booby traps, police said. The <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement that it carried out the bombing to mark Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s 10th year in power. On the actual anniversary on Thursday it said it set off a roadside bomb that day in <LOCATION> Silverbridge </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Crossmaglen </LOCATION> that kiled one soldier and wounded three others. The second bomb exploded several hours later on Sunday, 12 miles away at <LOCATION> Camlough </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Down </LOCATION>, as another mobile patrol was passing. One soldier was sent to a hospital for treatment and three others were given first aid, police said. The <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> is fighting to end British rule in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and unite the mainly Protestant province with the overwhelmingly <LOCATION> Roman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Catholic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 0151EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-TexasMayoralRdp 3rdLd-Writethru a0610 05-07 0732</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Texas Mayoral Rdp, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0610,0750</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Dallas, Fort Worth Mayors Win Election</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 4 grafs to UPDATE with El Paso runoff declared and
final figures in Dallas race; SUBS 14th graf, `In El Paso ... with 3 grafs
to UPDATE with final figures; picks up below dash.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID SEDENO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN ANTONIO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The mayors of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> easily won re-election Saturday, and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>'s former mayor regained her office by a commanding margin in elections in four <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> cities. The least predictable contest all day was in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>, where two <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> members in the six-candidate field will face each other in a runoff election. The campaigns in all four cities failed to inspire much voter interest. In <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, with all 299 precincts reporting, Mayor <PERSON> Annette </PERSON> <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> had 60,895 votes, or 73 percent, to 17,002, or 20 percent, for attorney <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Lesser </PERSON>. <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Ludwig </PERSON> had 3,510 ballots, or 4 percent, and <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Crenshaw </PERSON> had 2,658, or 3 percent. Mrs. <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON>, backed by a huge campaign fund and polls showing widespread support, had been expected to win a second two-year term in the nation's seventh-largest city. Her main opponent had been Lesser, who picked up some support from some minority groups that once backed the incumbent. City Secretary <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Sloan </PERSON> said he expected 15 percent or less of the city's nearly 500,000 registered voters to cast ballots. In <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, former Mayor <PERSON> Lila </PERSON> <PERSON> Cockrell </PERSON> won by 45,300 votes, or 59 percent, to 24,107, or 31 percent for insurance executive <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Mauthe </PERSON>. They were trailed by five other candidates who had no more than 2 percent of the vote each. Ms. <PERSON> Cockrell </PERSON>, who was mayor of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> from 1975 to 1981, was supported by the man who replaced her, <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Cisneros </PERSON>, a leading Hispanic political figure. <PERSON> Cisneros </PERSON>, beset by personal problems, decided against running for a fifth term. <LOCATION> Bexar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Elections Administrator <PERSON> Marco </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> predicted an 18 percent voter turnout. Fort Worth Mayor <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolen </PERSON>, who faced no serious opposition in his bid for a fourth two-year term, won with 14,292 votes, or 89 percent. He was trailed by <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, who had 1,099 votes, or 7 percent, and <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, with 656 votes, or 4 percent. In <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>, with all ballots counted, <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> member <PERSON> Suzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Azar </PERSON> had 16,220 votes, or 31 percent, to 11,930 votes, or 23 percent for Mayor Pro Tem <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Elsey </PERSON>. The other four candidates did not receive significant votes. <PERSON> Azar </PERSON> and <PERSON> Elsey </PERSON> will face off May 27. Mayor <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> was prevented by law from seeking a fifth, two-year term.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> ballot was the first one in 14 years that did n't include <PERSON> Cisneros </PERSON> He was a city councilman for six years before becoming mayor in 1981. Beset by a troubled marriage and his son's ill health, <PERSON> Cisneros </PERSON> last fall said he would n't run again and accepted a job in the private sector. <PERSON> Cisneros </PERSON> briefly reconsidered his re-election decision in January after <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> voters approved a transportation tax to pay for a domed stadium that he supported. But he decided against running after Ms. <PERSON> Cockrell </PERSON>'s supporters said they would stay behind her. In the <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> race, Mrs. <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON>, 65, raised $ 300,000 compared with Lesser's $ 16,000. But she spent more than $ 1 million to be elected two years ago, when neither was an incumbent. `` It certainly is a different campaign,'' said <PERSON> Lorlee </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartos </PERSON>, a campaign consultant for Mrs. <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON>. `` The races are much less expensive throughout the city. It's a different economy.'' The shooting deaths of five <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> police officers in 1988 clouded Mrs. <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON>' first term. Police blamed city leaders for not providing enough support to the force, which was also beset by a congressional investigation into its officers' use of deadly force. Minority leaders insist on increased citizens review of police. A non-partisan committee appointed by Mrs. <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> studied the city's racial problems and this spring recommended redistricting the City Council. There have never been more than three minority members on the 11-member council, though the 1990 census is expected to show that minorities make up more than half the city population. <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> have city manager governments in which the mayor plays a lesser, often ceremonial role. The <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION> mayor has more power because there is not a city manager.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 0155EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--RideStuck 1stLd-Writethru a0618 05-07 0132</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Ride Stuck, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0618,0132</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eight People Stuck 60 Feet Above Ground In Carnival Ride</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: New thruout to reflect revised police numbers on people trapped
in ride; UPDATE with rescue; two people hospitalized; no pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A carnival ride malfunctioned Saturday, trapping eight people upside down 60 feet off the ground for 2 -LCB- hours, police said. Two people were hospitalized for treatment of hypothermia, said Sgt. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Calabro </PERSON> of the 100th precinct. The riders were stuck in a `` loop-the-loop'' ride, which is about six stories high, <PERSON> Calabro </PERSON> said. Authorities were called about 9:45 p.m. and worked until 12:15 a.m. Sunday to free the riders. Police initially reported 20 people were trapped. The ride is part of a temporary carnival. No reason was given for the malfunction.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 0206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Takeshita     05-07 0352</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Takeshita,0362</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japanese Prime Minister Ends Southeast Asian Tour, Hints At His Replacement</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By YASMIN ARQUIZA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Japanese Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> ended his five-nation Southeast Asian tour Sunday and headed back to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to annoint a successor and restore his party's scandal-ridden image <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, in a report from the <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> capital, said <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> hinted he would ask veteran politician <PERSON> Masayoshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Ito </PERSON> to accept the premiership despite his reluctance to take the post. President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> and other senior Filipino officials were on hand for a 10-minute farewell ceremony at <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> airport, where <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> received a 19-gun salute before boarding the plane for <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. There were no speeches. <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> went ahead with the visit despite his announcement April 25 that he would resign to take responsibility for a scandal in which the <ORGANIZATION> Recruit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> is accused of seeking to buy influence with political donations or stock transactions that yielded huge profits to politicians, bureaucrats and others. On Monday, <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> is expected to meet with <PERSON> Ito </PERSON>, a former foreign minister. Japanese sources say <PERSON> Ito </PERSON> is expected eventually to accept the appointment if certain conditions are met, though these are unclear. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday that <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> hinted to Japanese reporters traveling with with him that he would ask <PERSON> Ito </PERSON> to take the job. <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> stopped short of mentioning <PERSON> Ito </PERSON> by name but said `` it is quite natural for a respectable man to win the heart of the people.'' The governing <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> has focused on <PERSON> Ito </PERSON> as a successor because so many of the party's leaders are tainted by Recruit donations or stock deals, while <PERSON> Ito </PERSON> as seen as basically clean. But the 75-year-old <PERSON> Ito </PERSON>, chairman of the party's policy-making Executive Council, has cited his age and heart problems caused by diabetes as reasons for declining the nomination to be party president and thus prime minister. During his trip, <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> also visited <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION>. All five countries he toured are members of the non-communist <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Asian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, the major regional trading bloc.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 0227EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Iran-Refinery     05-07 0210</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Iran-Refinery,0218</SECOND>
<HEAD>Abadan Refinery, Once World's Largest, Resumes Exports After 8-Year
Gap</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Abadan </LOCATION> oil refinery, once the world's largest, resumed exports Saturday after an eight-year gap, the official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported. The agency, monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, said a 10,000-ton shipment of fuel oil from the refinery left <PERSON> Bandar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahshahr </PERSON> port, but did not say where it was headed. The refinery, located only a few miles from the border with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, shut down soon after the Iran-Iraq war broke out in September 1980. The 3,200-acre complex was heavily shelled by <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> artillery during the war. More than 150 personnel were killed and lost production was estimated at $ 9 billion. Around 6,000 technicians and specialists started round-the-clock repair work immediately after a United Nations-sponsored cease-fire halted the gulf war Aug. 20. Production resumed April 1 with an initial capacity of 130,000 barrels a day of oil products, <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION> said. Capacity is expected to rise later this year and reach 360,000 barrels a day in the next two to three years. Before the war, the refinery produced 650,000 barrels a day. Following repairs of war damage at <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s six other refineries, the country's total refinery capacity is currently estimated at 850,000 barrels a day.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 0313EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-Earthquake     05-07 0138</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Earthquake,0142</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mile Earthquake Shakes California</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BREA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A mild earthquake jolted Southern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Saturday night, but there were no immediate reports of injury or property damage, authorities said. The quake struck at 11:07 p.m. and measured 3.7 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale of ground motion, said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Rourke </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION>. The temblor was centered one mile northwest of <LOCATION> Brea </LOCATION>. Telephone banks at the <ORGANIZATION> Orange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> lit up with calls following the jolt, said Deputy R. Nink. `` Everybody said they were feeling it shake a little bit,'' <PERSON> Nink </PERSON> said. `` We've had maybe 10 or 15 calls. It was n't anything huge, but I guess it shook some people up.'' An earthquake of 3.5 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale can cause slight damage in the local area, 4 moderate damage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 0328EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Britain-Missiles     05-07 0229</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Britain-Missiles,0235</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report British Boycott Threat To European Missile Talks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A newspaper reported Sunday that the British government will refuse to negotiate with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> on reducing short-range nuclear missiles in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> even if the other 15 members of <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> agree to do so. The Sunday Telegraph, in a Washington-dated story, said Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> made her views known to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in diplomatic notes and telephone conversations last week. `` Her tough stance on the issue is proving the main obstacle in the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's frantic search for a compromise after <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s insistence that negotiations must take place as soon as possible,'' the newspaper reported. It said Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> called <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> after failing to agree on a united <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> policy at her meeting with West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> on April 30. At that meeting in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> failed to persuade <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> to abandon his quest for early talks with <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> on reducing the missiles. The <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> leader argued that the 88 Lance missiles should be modernized, not removed, and that their reduction or removal would put <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in greater danger of sudden nuclear war involving strategic nuclear missiles. The Sunday Telegraph said <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> want to update the Lance because of Soviet modernization of short-range nuclear armory and Soviet superiority in conventional and chemical weapons.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 0345EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-RitualSlayings 4thLd-Writethru a0621 05-07 0464</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ritual Slayings, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0621,0472</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Police: Ringleader of Ritual Slaying Cult Killed in Gunbattle</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf, ``They have...' to UPDATE with government-run
Mexican news agency confirming the report; picks up 4th graf pvs, `Alleged
cult ...'; SUBS 7th graf pvs, `Mexico City...' with 1 graf to UPDATE with
attorney general saying he'll hold news conference; DELETES now-outdated
8th and 9th grafs pvs and picks up 10th graf pvs, `Constanzo, 26...</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY30</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOEL WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BROWNSVILLE, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The ringleader of a drug-smuggling cult that killed 15 people was slain in a gunbattle with <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> police Saturday, and his girlfriend, the alleged `` high priestess,'' was captured, police said. <LOCATION> Cameron </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's Lt. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Gavito </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> authorities told <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> investigators Saturday night that cult leader <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON>, 26, was killed and that police have arrested <PERSON> Sara </PERSON> <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON>, a 24-year-old former <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> college student described as the `` witch'' of the cult. The government-run <ORGANIZATION> Notimex </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported early Sunday that unidentified officials in the attorney general's office had confirmed the killing and the arrest. Alleged cult member <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Quintana </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> also was killed in the shootout at a <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> residence about 4:30 p.m., said <LOCATION> Cameron </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>. Three other people believed to be cult members were also arrested. <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON>, the alleged `` godfather,'' and <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> had been sought in an international manhunt and are believed to have masterminded the activities of the cult that killed 15 people in a series of ritualistic sacrifices and drug-related slayings. <PERSON> Gavito </PERSON> said he spoke on the telephone with Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON>, who is in police custody in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, for about five minutes Saturday night, but he would not divulge details of the conversation. The attorney general's office in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s Federal District would not immediately confirm the story, but said he would discuss the details at a news conference Sunday. <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON>, 26, and Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON>, 24, had been charged with aggravated kidnapping by <LOCATION> Cameron </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> authorities and are believed to have directed human sacrifices, mutilations and the boiling of brains and other organs in rituals to bring occult protection for their drug-smuggling ring. The ring and its macabre activities was discovered when authorities unearthed 15 bodies buried west of the border city of <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, beginning on April 11. <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON>, missing since the first 12 bodies were uncovered April 11, are among 11 people indicted in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on a four-count drug indictment. Four of the five men in custody in <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION> said the cult leaders were <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON>. The pair flew from <LOCATION> McAllen </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> on April 11, officials have said. In the Mexican capital, the investigation led to searches of residences where occult altars were found.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 0837EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-SpaceShuttle     05-07 0221</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Space Shuttle,0225</SECOND>
<HEAD>Atlantis Streaks Around Earth, Magellan Continues Voyage to Venus</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SPACE CENTER, Houston (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Atlantis' five astronauts awoke to music from the movie `` Rocky'' on Sunday, the final full day of their shuttle mission in which they deployed a planetary probe now bound for <PERSON> Venus </PERSON>. The Magellan probe continued on its 15-month voyage to <PERSON> Venus </PERSON> at a rate of about 6,500 mph. The spacecraft, launched from the shuttle's cargo bay Thursday night, already had traveled more than 430,000 miles by early Sunday morning. Later Sunday, shuttle commander <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> and pilot <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Grabe </PERSON> planned to run through a series of tests to make sure the shuttle's computers and control jets are ready for the fiery plunge through the Earth's atmosphere on Monday. Atlantis, which blasted away from <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday, is scheduled to end its four-day mission with a landing at <ORGANIZATION> Edwards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, at 12:43 p.m. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> time. Also Sunday, the astronauts planned to try to photograph lightning strikes at night and work on a metals processing experiment as well as pack their belongings in preparation for the return home. The workload on the four-day flight has been limited because the <ORGANIZATION> Magellan </ORGANIZATION> probe and its rocket booster, which together weighed 45,000 pounds, did not allow for many experiments to be carried aboard.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 1136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Greece-MayDay     05-07 0309</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Greece-May Day,0317</SECOND>
<HEAD>Greeks Celebrate Labor Holiday Six Days Late</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATHENS, Greece (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tens of thousands of workers rallied in central <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> and marched on <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday in a May Day celebration that was delayed six days because of Orthodox Christian Easter. More than 300 Turkish and Kurdish refugees held their own demonstration and marched to the Turkish Embassy where they burned that country's flag. They were protesting the death of an 18-year-old worker during violent unauthorized May Day demonstrations in <LOCATION> Istanbul </LOCATION> last week. More than 100 riot police prevented the demonstrators, who chanted `` Death to the fascist Turkish regime!'' from approaching the embassy. There are about 700 Turkish and Kurdish political refugees living in <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>. The Kurds belong to an outlawed movement that seeks the formation of an independent Kurdish state in southeastern <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>. The May Day celebration, organized by the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Confederation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Greek </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>, was the first unified workers' gathering in more than four years. `` On a day like this our various views, ideological differences and political choices are put aside under the joint goal that brings workers together,'' said <PERSON> Lambros </PERSON> <PERSON> Kanellopoulos </PERSON>, the group's <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> president The confederation, which represents most of <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>'s 3.5 million workers, was bitterly divided after its pro-government socialist leadership pushed for support of an austerity policy in 1985. Support for the two-year austerity policy, imposed by the governing <ORGANIZATION> Panhellenic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, was opposed by radical socialist and communist labor leaders who split the confederation. But working under a new, more moderate leadership, those differences have since been resolved. The confederation issued a resolution Sunday calling on the government for wage increases linked to the inflation rate and a reduction of the workweek from 37.5 hours to 35. Inflation in <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> was running at 14 percent at the end of 1988, the highest in the 12-nation European Economic Community.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 1138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--TankerAccident     05-07 0157</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Tanker Accident,0160</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chemical Leak Kills Crewman Aboard Ship In Japan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A crewman was killed and two of his companions were hospitalized after inhaling a gas aboard a Panamanian tanker at <LOCATION> Shimotsu </LOCATION> port in western <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Maritime </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday. The agency, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s coast guard, said the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> sailor who died, <PERSON> Chon </PERSON> <PERSON> In-su </PERSON>, 39, entered a hold aboard the ship Saturday night to measure what he thought were residual amounts of benzene. When he fell to the floor, a colleague, Ok Nam-suk, 52, put on a mask and went to help, but he also collapsed, the agency said. A third sailor, <PERSON> Yun </PERSON> <PERSON> Won-sup </PERSON>, 23, rescued Ok but became ill before he could bring out <PERSON> Chon </PERSON>. Japanese rescuers brought out <PERSON> Chon </PERSON> 30 minutes later, but he died. The agency was investigating the cause of the accident aboard the 687-ton <ORGANIZATION> Modern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION>, which arrived Saturday with a cargo of benzene from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 1138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-IraqiReactor     05-07 0197</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iraqi Reactor,0202</SECOND>
<HEAD>French Deny Negotiations Under Way To Rebuild Iraqi Nuclear Reactor</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday denied <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> reports that <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> is negotiating with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> about a plan to rebuild a nuclear power plant destroyed by <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> warplanes in 1981. The ministry spokesman, who under French rules may not be identified, denied a statement attributed by a <LOCATION> Sharjah </LOCATION> newspaper to <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> <PERSON> Kamal </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s minister of industry and military production. The newspaper, <PERSON> Al-Khaleej </PERSON>, quoted <PERSON> Kamal </PERSON> as saying: `` <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> is determined to rebuild the <LOCATION> Tamouz </LOCATION> nuclear reactor for peaceful purposes and negotiations for this purpose have started with <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Kamal </PERSON> was quoted as saying <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> has no intention of manufacturing or possessing nuclear weapons. The ministry spokesman said the problem of rebuilding the reactor has been brought up in the past by <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> authorities and was brought up again recently. But he said: `` There are not any talks on this subject at the present time.'' Israeli warplanes destroyed the Osirak nuclear reactor at <LOCATION> Tamouz </LOCATION>, outside <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION>, in 1981, saying it could be used to build nuclear weapons. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> recently accused <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> of attempting to develop a nuclear warhead capable of hitting Israeli territory.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 1138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Burma     05-07 0104</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Burma,0105</SECOND>
<HEAD>Burmese Insurgents Attack Railway Line</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Burmese guerrillas blew up two sections of a railway line in southern <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>, the state-controlled <ORGANIZATION> Rangoon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> said in a report Sunday. The radio, monitored in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>, said the attacks occured Saturday on the line between <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Martaban </LOCATION> and between the towns of <LOCATION> Moulmein </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Ye </PERSON>. No injuries were reported and train service was restored shortly after the raids, the radio said. The attack was carried out by <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> and Mon guerrillas, it said. The Karens and <LOCATION> Mons </LOCATION> are among a dozen ethnic minority groups fighting for greater autonomy in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 1138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Turkey-Crash     05-07 0087</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Turkey-Crash,0088</SECOND>
<HEAD>14 Killed In Truck-Bush Crash In Turkey</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DORTYOL, Turkey (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A tanker truck and a minibus collided head-on Sunday, killing 14 people in southern <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Anatolia </LOCATION> news agency said. The news agency said two people were injured in the collision, which occurred when the tanker truck rammed the minibus while trying to pass another vehicle. <ORGANIZATION> Anatolia </ORGANIZATION> said the truck driver received minor injuries and was detained by police. The collision occurred near <LOCATION> Dortyol </LOCATION> township in southern <LOCATION> Hatay </LOCATION> province near the Syrian border.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 1139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-China-Earthquake     05-07 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Earthquake,0274</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quake-Ravaged Region of China Hit by Another Temblor</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A strong earthquake Sunday struck a region of southwest <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> where 730 people were killed by a temblor in November, but this time officials said only about 10 people were injured. Sunday's quake collapsed some houses and opened rifts in some streets in <LOCATION> Gengma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Yunnan </LOCATION> province, the official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said. <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> said there were no reports of deaths or injuries, but the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seismology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> quoted local authorities as saying about 10 people were injured, four seriously. The quake measured 6.3 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, signifying a quake capable of causing severe damage. The Nov. 6 quake that shook <PERSON> Gengma </PERSON> and devastated nearby counties was more than 10 times stronger, measuring 7.6. That quake, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s worst in 12 years, destroyed several villages in <LOCATION> Menglian </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lancang </LOCATION> counties, 90 miles south of <LOCATION> Gengma </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> said <LOCATION> Menglian </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lancang </LOCATION> were shaken by the new quake that hit at 9:38 a.m. Sunday. All three counties are in a remote mountainous region near the Burmese border that is prone to quakes. Gengma is largely inhabited by members of the Va and <PERSON> Dai </PERSON> minorities, most of whom farm. More than 1,300 aftershocks were recorded in less than two weeks after the Nov. 6 quake. Seismologists said after that quake that the region had entered a new period of quake activity. The Richter scale is a gauge of the energy released by an earthquake, as measured by ground motion recorded on a seismograph. Each increase of a digit indicates a 10-fold increase in severity.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 1139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF-India-BusCrash     05-07 0103</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF-India-Bus Crash,0103</SECOND>
<HEAD>18 Killed In Bus Crash In India</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bus overturned and caught fire Sunday in the northern state of <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>, killing 18 passengers and severely burning 35, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> reported. The bus toppled over when the driver swerved to avoid colliding with a tractor coming from the opposite direction, the news agency said. The accident occurred near <LOCATION> Jivarai </LOCATION> village, 220 miles northwest of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>, the news agency said. It said the fuel tank of the bus exploded and many of the passengers were trapped in the burning wreckage of the vehicle.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 1139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF-Cholera     05-07 0088</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF-Cholera,0089</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cholera Outbreak in Central Tanzania Kills 23</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DAR ES SALAAM, Tanzania (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A cholera epidemic in central <LOCATION> Tanzania </LOCATION> has killed 23 people in the last 90 days, the official news agency said Sunday. Another 35 people have been hospitalized in the epidemic, which began around the district capital, <LOCATION> Singida </LOCATION>, 350 miles west of the <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> port of <LOCATION> Dar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> es </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salaam </LOCATION>, the <PERSON> Shihata </PERSON> news agency said. The report did not say what caused the cholera outbreak or what authorities were doing to contain it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 1139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--China-Poisoning     05-07 0123</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--China-Poisoning,0125</SECOND>
<HEAD>16 Die From Food Poisoning in Remote Chinese Province</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sixteen Chinese laborers died last month after eating industrial salt at a construction site canteen in the far northwest province of <LOCATION> Xinjiang </LOCATION>, according to a local newspaper. Another 25 laborers received food poisoning in the April 25 incident in <LOCATION> Jeminay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> county </LOCATION>, 280 miles north of the provincial capital of <LOCATION> Urumqi </LOCATION>, but were out of danger, according to the May 1 issue of Xinjiang Daily. <LOCATION> Xinjiang </LOCATION> is an autonomous region of the Moslem Uygur minority, but the report said all of the poisoned workers were ethnic Han Chinese. The story did not say how the salt wound up in the canteen and its food. Authorities were investigating the incident.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 1139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-NewCaledonia     05-07 0357</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-New Caledonia,0366</SECOND>
<HEAD>French Premier Revives Elections</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NOUMEA, New Caledonia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 French Premier <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON> on Sunday said elections in this territory will proceed as planned, reversing an earlier decision to cancel them because of the slayings of two independence leaders. <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON> was among an estimated 5,000 people who attended the funerals Sunday of <PERSON> Jean-Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Tjibaou </PERSON>, leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Kanak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Tjibaou </PERSON>'s top assistant, <PERSON> Yeiwene </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeiwene </PERSON>. The two were shot and killed on the island of <LOCATION> Ouvea </LOCATION> on Thursday by <PERSON> Djubelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Wea </PERSON>, a hard-line separatist opposed to <PERSON> Tjibaou </PERSON>'s moderate policies <PERSON> Wea </PERSON> was killed by <PERSON> Tjibaou </PERSON>'s bodyguards after the attack. <PERSON> Andre </PERSON> <PERSON> Tangopi </PERSON>, another hard-line separatist, was charged in both shooting deaths but police did not say what role he played in the attack. He was wounded in an exchange of gunfire that followed the assassinations and was hospitalized under police guard in <LOCATION> Noumea </LOCATION>, the provincial capital. <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON> on Friday had postponed the elections in the restive territory after the slayings. On Sunday, he said they would proceed as planned June 11. `` A criminal does n't stop the course of peace in progress,'' the premier said. `` Tolerance will not abdicate in the face of fanaticism.'' Last year, <PERSON> Tjibaou </PERSON> abandoned demands for immediate independence in the territory and signed an agreement in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> for a peace process that would end in 1998 with a referendum on independence. Many of <PERSON> Tjibaou </PERSON>'s followers were unhappy with the accord, which was aimed at ending three years of sporadic separatist violence here. Tjibaou and <PERSON> Yeiwene </PERSON> had gone to <LOCATION> Ouvea </LOCATION> to take part in ceremonies marking the first anniversary of the assault by <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> police on a cave where separatists were holding more than 20 other <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> officers hostage. The fighting left 19 separatists and two policemen dead. Native Melanesians, known as Kanaks, make up 43 percent of the inhabitants of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION>, an archipelago 1,000 miles off the coast of <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. Most Kanaks favor independence. European settlers and their descendants make up 37 percent of the population and most want to remain French. The rest of the population is Polynesians and Asians, most of whom also favor remaining French.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0030 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 1136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-US-Soviet Bjt   05-07 0726</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Soviet, Bjt,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baker To Seek Soviet Help In Middle East On First Trip To Moscow</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> is about to launch his first diplomatic venture on Soviet soil with an appeal for superpower cooperation in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and a challenge to <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to make his `` new thinking'' a reality. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> also will propose that the superpowers resume in June their work on a treaty to reduce long-range nuclear weapons by 30-to-50 percent. But his focus primarily will be on regional problems that a close aide on Friday said were growing to `` frightening'' proportions. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> will ask the Soviets to join the Untied States in backing direct negotiations between <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israelis </LOCATION> and to curb the $ 500 million in military aid <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> gave to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s Marxist government last year. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, who held his first meeting with Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> in March in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, has never been to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in private or public life. The trip to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> also will be the first for <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gates </PERSON>, the deputy director of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, who will accompany <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> along with officials of the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. One of the issues projected for discussion in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> is a joint approach to terrorism. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> hopes to persuade the Soviets to end financial support to countries that sponsor terrorism. A group of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> experts is planning to go to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> later in the spring for further talks. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> set the tone for his trip in a speech Thursday in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in which he contrasted the `` new thinking'' that has marked the <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> era with ` ` the reality of both Soviet capabilities and actions. He said the Soviets continue to pose a significant military threat to Western interests and sought to minimize <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s unilateral force reductions in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> as still leaving the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact with a 2-to-1 edge in tanks and artillery <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> also said it was too early to tell whether <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s restructuring of the economy, known as perestroika, will succeed <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s schedule will give him high visibility. Besides meetings with <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> on Wednesday and Thursday mornings and a two-hour session with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> Thursday afternoon, several public events are planned to enhance his knowledge of Soviet affairs and get his views across to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> people. These include an interview on Soviet television, meetings with Soviet parliamentarians and Jewish dissidents, and an inspection of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassy in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> that will revive allegations the Soviets planted eavesdropping devices. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> flies to <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> on Monday morning and relaxes there and meets with Finnish officials until his departure for <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> on Wednesday morning. On his way home he will stop in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> to brief Western allies at NATO headquarters. This also will provide an opportunity to try to resolve a dispute with <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> over short-range nuclear missiles. Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> is resisting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and British demands that the Lance's range be extended to more than 250 miles. The German leader wants <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> negotiations with the Soviets to reduce short-range weapons on both sides. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> have rejected the demands as a mistake, but may be losing ground as other countries in the 16-nation alliance tilt toward the West German position. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hope is to resolve the dispute before <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> attend a <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> summit meeting in the Belgian capital with the <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> partners May 29-30. On another arms control front, however, the administration seeks a resumption of talks. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said Friday that <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> would propose in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> that negotiations to sharply reduce strategic nuclear weapons be reopened in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> the week of June 18 and basically pick up where they left off last November when they were recessed. But <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> will not outline to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> the position the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> intends to take on specific issues once the bargaining resumes, said the officials, who spoke on the condition of anonymity. `` Essentially, we are looking for continuinity and keeping arms control on a fast track,'' an official said. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration had tentatively decided to resume the negotiations in mid-February. But <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, after taking office in January, ordered a delay for a review, now complete, of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms control and weapons policies.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0031 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 1140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Arafat     05-07 0282</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Arafat,0289</SECOND>
<HEAD>Palestinian Leader Rejects Iranian Call to Kill Westerners</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TUNIS, Tunisia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> on Sunday denounced a call by an <LOCATION> Iranian </LOCATION> official to kill Westerners in retaliation for Palestinian deaths in the Israeli-occupied territories. `` I reject this call in its totality,'' <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> told reporters in a news conference at <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Liberation </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Organization </LOCATION> headquarters. On Friday, Iranian <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> speaker <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> called for five Britons, French or Americans to be executed for every Palestinian killed in the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> by the Israeli army. The statement brought immediate condemnation from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. More than 460 Palestinians have been killed since the Palestinian uprising against <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> occupation of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> began in December 1987. The <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> leader called on the international community `` to act rapidly to put an end to the crimes and the massacres perpetrated by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> against the population of the occupied territories.'' On Nov. 15, the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s parliament-in-exile, decided to recognize <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, renounce terrorism and work toward peace based on two separate states, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> announced the peace initiative in a December <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> session in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. Asked if he planned to withdraw his peace initiative because of the deteriorating situation in the territories, <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> said: `` It is an initiative of the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> and it is not up to me to modify it.'' The initiative, along with further statements by <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> to clarify the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s intention, led to U.S.-PLO talks in <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION>, the headquarters of the Palestine provisional government. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pelletreau </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION>, met twice with a four-man <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> delegation, in December and in March.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0032 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 1140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Nigeria     05-07 0128</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Nigeria,0131</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nigerian President Says He's Ready to Relinquish Military Power</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION>'s military leader, Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Ibrahim </PERSON> <PERSON> Babangida </PERSON>, says he will be ready to give up power after the country elects a civilian president in 1992. `` I think I should. I had to do a job. ... I have done the job,'' <PERSON> Babangida </PERSON> said on Channel 4's `` The World This Week'' program broadcast Saturday. The last civilian government under President <PERSON> Shehu </PERSON> <PERSON> Shagari </PERSON> was overthrown by the army on Dec. 31, 1983. <PERSON> Babangida </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION> is going through a transition from military to civilian rule, which included last week's introduction of a new constitution and the lifting of a five-year ban on political activity. <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION> is expected to elect a civilian president in October 1992.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0033 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 1140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SouthAfrica     05-07 0484</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-South Africa,0495</SECOND>
<HEAD>Black Newspaper Welcomes Plan to Include Blacks in Parliament</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID CRARY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Arica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The country's largest black newspaper Sunday welcomed a <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> minister's proposal to include blacks in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, saying the government `` has finally seen the light.'' City Press described a speech in Parliament last week by Constitutional Development Minister <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Heunis </PERSON> as `` possibly the most significant policy statement'' ever by a senior government official. <PERSON> Heunis </PERSON>, however, made clear that the governing <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> would oppose any system in which white interests could be overruled. <PERSON> Heunis </PERSON>, outlining the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s latest constitutional strategy, said the black majority should have a role in the Cabinet, in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> and in the election of a president. He said the government might allow <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africans </LOCATION> to participate in political structures that transcend racial lines. `` Strange but true,'' said a City Press editorial. `` The government has finally seen the light _ realizing the need to establish an authentic Parliament that will represent all South African communities.'' <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s 28 million blacks have no vote in national affairs. Parliament has chambers for Asians and people of mixed-race, but the constitution gives almost total power to the party that wins the most votes among the 5 million whites. Militant anti-apartheid leaders, committed to the concept of one-person, one-vote, have ignored <PERSON> Heunis </PERSON>' speech. But mainstream white newspapers Sunday joined <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in depicting it as a milestone. The Sunday Times, the country's largest-selling newspaper, described the speech as a `` dramatic U-turn'' and `` one of the most important policy shifts of the past decade.'' `` The government has accepted that <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africans </LOCATION> be allowed to choose their own political and social groupings, irrespective of race,'' said The Sunday Times. `` The stand contradicts <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s classical apartheid dogma which holds that all South Africans must exercise their political and social rights through the group to which they belong.'' Rapport, a pro-government, <LOCATION> Afrikaans </LOCATION> newspaper, ran a front-page banner headline saying: `` Now: One Parliament.'' The accompanying article evoked the image of `` a united <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> where all _ white, black, brown and Indian _ can be represented in one Cabinet and one Parliament.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> MacLennon </PERSON>, a political writer for the <ORGANIZATION> Argus </ORGANIZATION> newspaper group, said <PERSON> Heunis </PERSON>' speech suggested the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> would forsake the votes of far-right whites during the campaign leading to general elections Sept. 6. He said the Nationalists will adopt a pro-reform platform aimed at whites who favor change but not majority rule. The far-right <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Heunis </PERSON>' plan would lead swiftly to black domination. The anti-apartheid <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which hopes to replace the Conservatives as the largest white opposition faction in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, called <PERSON> Heunis </PERSON>' speech promising but questioned whether the rhetoric could be converted into law. City Press also expressed caution, saying blacks `` have been let down time and time again by people who make promises and never live up to them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0034 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 1137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-EnergyPolicy Bjt   05-07 0949</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Energy Policy, Bjt,890</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nuclear Power Taking Key Role In Bush Energy Policy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nuclear power, new technologies and a closer eye on the environment are emerging as key elements of what a senior <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official says will be `` the first real national energy policy this country has ever had.'' Energy Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> has told <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> he'll have an energy plan ready by next April, although there are indications this target may be missed. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> and his chief deputy, <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, have appeared before several key industry groups recently to sketch in some of the key contours of what <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> says will be a `` common sense approach'' to putting <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> on a more solid energy foundation. Some of the main areas of emphasis will be familiar: greater leeway for oil companies to explore on federal lands, tax breaks for oil drillers, decontrol of natural gas prices, expansion of nuclear power and pursuit of basic research. More novel will be the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s pursuit of what <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> calls `` technology transfer'' _ ensuring that energy research advances made in the department's national scientific laboratories are made available to industry and universities. The labs' main focus is on top-secret nuclear weapons programs, but <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said they have done extensive work in unclassified energy areas. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> also has said his energy strategy will be more comprehensive than anything produced during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. It will take into account, for example, the links between energy and the environment, including acid rain and the global atmospheric warming trend caused mainly by burning of fossil fuels, he said. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> has billed the evolving strategy as a clear departure from past policies. `` We're going to fashion the first real national energy policy this country has ever had,'' the former <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> congressman said at his swearing-in ceremony April 20. The government has produced many energy policies in the past, but <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>'s remark seemed to reflect the fact that the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's policy suffered from criticism by environmentalists and a lack of interest by the general public. `` You could ask 100 people if the country had an energy policy and 99 would say ` no,''' <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodel </PERSON>, the energy secretary from 1982-85, said in a telephone interview. He said there was a policy but that it was not commonly recognized. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, an engineer by training and a career naval officer, wants to broaden the scope of the government's energy involvement. Beyond the traditional issues of energy production, price and supply, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> sees room for his department to help stimulate young people's interest in science, math and engineering _ areas of education that he says are vital to the nation's energy future. This is where the nuclear issue fits in. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> is a devoted supporter of commercial nuclear power, and he is troubled at the depth of public distrust of this energy source, which accounts for nearly one-fifth of all electricity generation. No orders for new nuclear plants have been placed in 11 years and none are expected for the rest of the century. Scores of plants have been canceled in the past decade, and nuclear's share of energy production is projected to fall in the 1990s. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration supported nuclear power but failed to revive it. This has produced two results that <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> says threaten the nation's long-term energy security: a shrinking energy base and a deterioration of nuclear expertise. This is part of <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>' motivation for launching a publicity campaign against <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>'s plan to tear down the <LOCATION> Shoreham </LOCATION> nuclear plant on <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, which earlier this month was cleared for startup by federal regulators. `` Because Shoreham is the right energy source at the right time for the right place, its operation should stand as a symbol of the promise and potential of nuclear power in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said after the plant got its license. <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> wants to tear it down because of doubts about whether <ORGANIZATION> Long </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Islanders </ORGANIZATION> could safety evacuate in the event of an accident. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> has vowed to fight the dismantlement. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> is taking an analogous approach to the problem of a slumping oil industry, whose prospects for long-term revival have been damaged by the Exxon Valdez oil spill. As a result of that accident _ the biggest spill in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history _ industry hopes for expanding exploration on the North Slope have diminished. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> has expressed alarm at the decline in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> oil production since 1986, which has coincided with a rise in oil use and a resulting jump in oil imports. Besides making the country more reliable on oil from the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, the domestic oil slump has weakened young people's interest in learning the business, he said. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> recently cited figures showing that between 1982 and 1987 the number of freshmen enrolled in petroleum engineering schools plunged from 3,300 to 271. `` Let us at least be forward thinking enough to prepare <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s young people to be part of the energy breakthroughs of the next century,'' <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said. The technological advances that <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> thinks are most important include: _ A `` clean coal'' method of burning the nation's most abundant energy source in ways that provide more power with less pollution The department plans to spend $ 5 billion through 1992 on demonstration projects by private companies. _ New designs for nuclear reactors to reduce their vulnerability to meltdowns or other serious accidents that have eroded public confidence in the industry Numerous such `` passively safe'' designs are under development. _ A superconducting super collider <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> says he will push for federal financing of the $ 5.9 billion physics installation in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> at which scientists plan to explore the fundamental components of matter and energy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890507-0035 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-07-89 1144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-JerseyCityElection     05-07 0652</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jersey City Election,0671</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sport Of Politics In Full Swing In Jersey City</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TODD RICHISSIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERSEY CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
