<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 2338EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Bush-CampaignFinance 2ndLd-Writethru a07</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Campaign Finance, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0752,860</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Nearing Decision on Campaign Finance Overhaul</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDs: INSERTS grafs 8-9 bgng: ``Bush has,'' with report of gerrymandering
decision.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is weighing changes in campaign finance law to limit the multimillion-dollar influence of special-interest political action committees, officials said Tuesday. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> indicated in a news conference that he has not made his final decisions on what he will propose Thursday in the way of revamping the federal campaign finance laws. But officials said he is considering a version of his previously announced wish for a ban on political action committee contributions, which in the 1988 election amounted to $ 151.3 million for congressional campaigns, according to <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> records. One administration official, speaking only on condition of anonymity, said other proposals <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is reviewing include: _ Barring members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> from carrying over campaign fund surpluses from one election to the next Members who win their races handily sometimes amass huge warchests by rolling over the funds from one year to the next. _ Setting up a system in which executive branch agencies would have to log calls they received from members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> trying to sway them on a policy _ Limiting the amount congressional incumbents could spend on mailings with their `` franking'' privileges Critics say these mailings to constituents give the incumbents unfair advantage over election challengers at the expense of the taxpayers. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has made at least one decision, according to unidentified officials quoted in Wednesday editions of The Washington Post: to seek legislation outlawing ` gerrymandering,'' the drawing of congressional districts to favor one party. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would request a new requirement _ that districts be compact, contiguous and respecting community boundaries in addition to current court-enforced requirements that a state's districts contains equal numbers of people as nearly as possible. Instead of ruling out all PACs, the options he is now considering would ban corporate or labor union PACs, according to the official. The options would allow those that are not connected to such groups, so-called ideological PACs that are centered on a political philosophy or agenda. The president also is looking at the possibility of lowering the current $ 5,000 per candidate limit for PAC contributions to $ 1,000. In the category of banned PACs, if <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> agrees to this option, would be so-called leadership PACs, those headed by politicians and used to dispense campaign funds to other candidates. They also are used as a springboard for presidential candidates, including <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who headed the one of the nation's two most successful PACs in the years before his presidential bid. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told reporters that one proposal he will not adopt is a system of public financing for congressional campaigns, as is now the system for the presidential elections. `` I oppose public financing of these campaigns. I think people should be able to attract private support, and I think participation by individuals in a the political process through financial support is very, very important,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. Current law allows individuals to contribute a maximum of $ 1,000 per candidate in each election, while PACs may give $ 5,000. Some groups and members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> advocate setting up a federal fund to pay for congressional races after the model now used for the presidential elections and supported by the voluntary $ 1 checkoff on individual income tax forms. Besides speaking against that idea, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he would not reveal any specifics of his thinking on campaign finance reform before Thursday, when he speaks to a group of congressional interns at the Library of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. White House spokeswoman <PERSON> Alixe </PERSON> <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> said the intention of the president's plan will be `` to strengthn the parties, increase competition and fairness in elections and to curtail special interest'' in campaigns. `` I will have specific proposals,'' he said, adding they would be `` fairly far reaching because I want to see reform _ real reform.'' If he calls on <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to outlaw leadership PACs, he will be speaking against an increasingly influential funding mechanism that many presidential contenders use in their pre-announcement phase to finance their travels around the country to whip up support. Officially, such PACs are set up to help like-minded candidates for congressional or other offices and are not allowed to fund presidential campaign activity. But there is little doubt that they serve immense benefit for politicians who are preparing a White House bid. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s PAC, called Fund For <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Future, was the second largest of some 4,000 PACs that file records with the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Comission </ORGANIZATION>. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> PAC raised $ 9.4 million in the years when it was most active, the 1985-86 campaign cycle, second only to the conservative <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> founded by Sen. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, R-N. The <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> and its affiliated groups raised $ 16.6 million. The corporate PACs were led by <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION>'s which raised $ 1.8 million, <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> records show. Of labor-related PACs, the <ORGANIZATION> Teamsters </ORGANIZATION> had the largest, raising $ 4.4 million that cycle. Among the trade association-related PACs, the Realtors' PAC raised $ 5.7 million and the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> PAC </ORGANIZATION>, just under $ 5 million. In the 1987-88 election cycle, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> PAC </ORGANIZATION> raised just under $ 2 million as his presidential campaign geared up and fund-raising efforts were diverted to it. In the primary season, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign received $ 862,950 in contributions from special-interest PACs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 2338EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SunkenTreasure     06-27 0359</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sunken Treasure,0370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Treasure Hunters Hope Sunken Ship Will Be 17th Century Galleon</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KEY WEST, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A well-preserved ship believed to be a 17th century Spanish galleon loaded with gold has been found in 1,500 feet of water near the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Keys </LOCATION>, according to a salvage company. Much of the wooden vessel and its cargo appears to be intact because of the pressure and temperature of the water. `` It's worth a fortune in history.'' <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Stemm </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION> businessman who hopes to recover the riches, told The <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petersburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> for an article published Wednesday. <PERSON> Stemm </PERSON> believes the wreck is the <ORGANIZATION> Nuestra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senora </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> la </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Merced </ORGANIZATION>, a Spanish Colonial galleon believed to have vanished during the same hurricane 350 years ago that felled another galleon, the <LOCATION> Nuestra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Senora </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Atocha </LOCATION>. The Atocha, laden with gold and silver, was found by treasure hunter <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> in 1985, about 50 miles north of <PERSON> Stemm </PERSON>'s discovery. If <PERSON> Stemm </PERSON>'s research proves correct, the wreck he discovered could hold a treasure worth millions. <PERSON> Stemm </PERSON>, 32, is co-owner of a deep-sea research company that discovered the sunken vessel in April. <ORGANIZATION> Seahawk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deep </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ocean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tampa </ORGANIZATION> plans to disclose the details of its remote-camera exploration of the ship on Wednesday. Archaeologist and treasure hunters are hoping photos prove it's the Merced, sunk in 1622. `` This is just like a time capsule because nothing's been touched,'' said <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bagley </PERSON>, a Seahawk director. By the end of the summer, the salvors aboard <PERSON> Stemm </PERSON>'s 85-foot research vessel Seahawk will begin a full-scale operation to retrieve the fragile artifacts and confirm the ship's identity. So far, they have discovered a ship's bell and a number of olive jars that could be filled with wine, food and other commodities. The project could take up to two years. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, a state archaeologist, said he has talked to the salvors about the importance of preserving the artifacts and other salvageable items from the wreck. `` Regardless of what vessel it is, archaeologically, it's an extremely significant site,'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. `` If you consider the historic value, it's very great. The other side of that question is the monetary value.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 2344EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Nofziger 4thLd-Writethru a0748 06-27 1068</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nofziger, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0748,1,050</SECOND>
<HEAD>Appeals Court Overturns Conviction of Former Reagan Aide Nofziger</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS grafs 7-10 bgng: ``President Bush,'' with president's
reaction, others in White House</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal appeals court Tuesday overturned the conviction of former <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration aide <PERSON> Lyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> for illegally lobbying his <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> colleagues months after he left the government. In a 2-1 ruling, the panel said <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>'s 1988 conviction must `` be set aside because it is not based on a finding that he had knowledge of each element of the offenses'' he was accused of committing. `` The government was required to prove that he had knowledge of all of the facts making his conduct criminal,'' said the decision written by <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON>. <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> was joined by judge <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. Both are <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> appointees. Appeals court judge <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> administration appointee, dissented, saying there was `` no basis for overturning <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>'s conviction.'' Asked at a news conference whether he thought he had gotten off on a legal technicality, <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> said, `` Absolutely no. ... I think they came after me on a technicality.'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>, the independent counsel who prosecuted <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>, issued a statement saying he `` will consider his options to pursue further appellate review of this decision.'' The prosecutor could seek a review by the entire federal appeals court in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> or appeal to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and other high level administration officials were clearly pleased. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, asked at a state dinner honoring Australian Prime Minister <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> what he thought of the ruling, smiled broadly and said only, `` I'm always glad when soembody is found not guilty of something.'' Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> was more effusive, calling the decision `` terrific.'' Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said it was good news and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s chief of staff, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> said he had called <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> to congratulate him and let him know `` at least some of his old friends had n't forgotten him. The case against <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> political director in 1981, was the first major test of the revolving-door provisions of the Ethics in Government Act. The law imposes a one-year ban on lobbying former government colleagues once an upper-echelon employee leaves service in the executive branch. <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> said he was `` certainly pleased'' by the decision. `` I think I was innocent from the beginning; I still think I am innocent,'' he said. He was convicted Feb. 11, 1988, of three counts of illegally lobbying top presidential aides on behalf of private clients after he left the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> one year into the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. The clients were scandal-plagued <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a maritime engineers union and the manufacturer of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>'s A-10 anti-tank plane. <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>, who is 65, was sentenced to 90 days in prison and fined $ 30,000. He said that defending himself cost `` a bundle, a bundle,'' with legal fees running over $ 1.5 million and `` I suppose, more than that'' in lost income. As a lobbyist accused of felonies, `` you not only lose clients, you do n't get clients.'' But he acknowledged he has been able to keep his business going while the case made its way through the courts. Asked about the `` revolving door'' provisions of the ethics law under which he was prosecuted, <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> said, `` I do n't think I am part of any revolving door syndrome.'' `` People lobby in this town; the main industry in this town besides government is lobbying,'' he said. The ethics law prohibits executive branch officials from `` knowingly'' acting as agents or attorneys before their old agencies within one year after leaving the government. <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> contended the word `` knowingly'' also applied to a prohibition against making `` oral or written communications'' to their previous government colleagues on matters in which the agency had `` a direct and substantial interest'' within one year. Prosecutors said the word `` knowingly'' referred only to acting as an agent or attorney. `` This is not an idle grammatical inquiry,'' said <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON>'s ruling `` If <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>'s interpretation is correct, no one may be convicted ... unless it is proven that he had knowledge of each of the facts constituting the offense.'' The court found that the wording was ambiguous. `` Canons of statutory construction require that an ambiguous criminal statute be interpreted in the defendant's favor,'' said <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON>. The prosecutors never alleged that <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> knew his former colleagues had a direct and substantial interest in the matters on which he was lobbying them. Under the prosecution's theory, `` if an ex-official tries to interest his former agency in a particular project in the mistaken belief that it had no ` direct and substantial interest' in it, he will have committed a felony punishable by up to two years in jail,'' said <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON>. In his dissent, <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said the law was clear and that the word `` knowingly'' did n't apply to the provisions under which <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> was convicted. `` The majority has labored mightily to find an ambiguity,'' said <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>. But there is no ambiguity to resolve `` and, consequently, no basis for overturning <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>'s conviction,'' he said. `` I can not comprehend my colleagues' convoluted attempts to embrace'' <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>'s `` fancied ambiguity, and their ... willingness to ignore clear legislative history and engage in overt legislating,'' said <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>. <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> and <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> remanded the case to the <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> `` for proceedings consistent with this opinion.'' `` The <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> should have dismissed the indictment filed by the prosecution,'' said the decision. A federal court jury found <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> guilty of illegally using his influence by sending an April 8, 1982, memo to then-presidential counselor <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>. The memo suggested that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> enlist the support of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and others to persuade the Army to give a no-bid contract to build small gasoline engines to <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION>, which in the last years of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration became the focus of a massive federal corruption probe. While he was attorney general, <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> himself came under criminal investigation in connection with <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION>. He was n't prosecuted <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> also was convicted of sending an Aug. 20, 1982, memo to <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>, <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s deputy, urging the administration to put civilian sailors on <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> vessels. The policy was being pushed by the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beneficial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which paid <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>'s lobbying firm $ 100,000 a year Additionally, the jury said <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> illegally lobbied two <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> officials about continued production of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>'s A-10 anti-tank plane, which was made by <ORGANIZATION> Fairchild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 0008EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--AbortedTakeoff     06-27 0099</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Aborted Takeoff,0101</SECOND>
<HEAD>American Pilot Aborts Takeoff After Blowout</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GRAPEVINE, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The pilot of an <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> flight from <LOCATION> Dallas-Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> aborted takeoff Monday when four tires on the plane blew out, an airline spokeswoman said. No injuries were reported on Flight 66, which carried 204 passengers and a crew of 12. The plane returned to the gate under its own power, said <PERSON> Sonda </PERSON> <PERSON> Byington </PERSON>, spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>. It was not immediately know what caused the blowout of the four tires, which were located in the same area, Ms. <PERSON> Byington </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 0009EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HungerStriker     06-27 0668</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hunger Striker,0687</SECOND>
<HEAD>Inmate Protests Conviction with Lengthy Hunger Strike</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JUDY DAUBENMIER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOUNT CLEMENS, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Rene </PERSON> <PERSON> Acuna </PERSON> is starving himself to protest a life prison sentence, but he's on a well-worn road that state corrections officials say will end in court-ordered force feeding. `` I am innocent and I do n't eat,'' said <PERSON> Acuna </PERSON>, a Cuban immigrant who speaks broken English. <PERSON> Acuna </PERSON>, 37, of <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, stopped eating _ except for water and sugared coffee _ March 3 after he was convicted of conspiracy and delivery of two pounds of cocaine. His sentence is life without parole. <PERSON> Acuna </PERSON> once carried 180 pounds on his 5-foot, 5-inch frame. As of Friday, he had lost 64 pounds. His body swims in his prison blues. His cheeks are sunken. `` I see the food like a chair, like a sofa. The hunger? When you have a reason to support your spirit and your mind, you do n't need anything more,'' he said in a telephone interview from the hospital at the State Prison of <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION>. But a series of court rulings across the nation have upheld the power of prison officials to force feed inmates on long-term hunger strikes. Corrections experts say no record is kept of how many hunger strikes occur each year in American prisons, but they believe long ones are rare. Typically, courts decide that prison authorities' need to control their institutions outweighs prisoners' rights to privacy and control of their bodies, said <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Koren </PERSON>, staff assistant for the National Prison Project of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>. `` Obviously, they have an interest in controlling the institution and when a prisoner does something like this, he is embarrassing the heck out of them,'' he said. Department of Corrections officials label <PERSON> Acuna </PERSON>'s hunger strike a publicity stunt, and have doctors check him each day. The department will go to court to get the authority to force feed him if his condition worsens, said <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> Lalonde </PERSON>, deputy director of the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION>, adding `` that could be today. That could be tomorrow.'' <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> officials seek such authority about 10 times a year in order to safeguard the health of inmates who refuse food or medical care, said <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> DeWitt </PERSON>, spokesman for Attorney General <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON>. <PERSON> Acuna </PERSON>'s lawyers say his determination poses an ethical dilemma. `` This is the stuff ` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law' is written about. What do you do when your client wants to die?'' asked <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Neuhard </PERSON>, director of the <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> Appellate Defender's office, which will handle the appeal of <PERSON> Acuna </PERSON>'s drug convictions. `` I told him if he dies from not eating, even if he is innocent, his appeal will be stopped right then,'' said <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Girard </PERSON>, director of <ORGANIZATION> Prison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. In a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> case, inmate <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Calk </PERSON> decided to starve himself to death rather than serve a 180-year sentence. <PERSON> Arpy </PERSON> <PERSON> Saunders </PERSON>, <PERSON> Calk </PERSON>'s lawyer, said the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> allowed authorities to force-feed <PERSON> Calk </PERSON> to keep him alive so that he could face another charge pending in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. `` It was n't up to him to determine how long he should serve,'' said <PERSON> Saunders </PERSON>, summarizing the court's ruling. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, sentenced to 20 years to life for the murder of former Beatle <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>, staged a hunger strike to call attention to starving children. But the appellate division of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decided prison security needs outweighed <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>'s claim that the right to privacy includes a right to refuse to eat. One exception to that philosophy came in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, where inmate <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Prevatte </PERSON> won a lawsuit to prevent authorities from force-feeding him, but eventually ended his hunger strike, aimed at winning transfer to another prison system, said <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Siler </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> found force-feeding was too great an invasion of an inmate's right to privacy, saying the state `` has no right to destroy a person's will by frustrating his attempt to die if necessary to make a point.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 0020EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Tokyo     06-27 0126</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Tokyo,0129</SECOND>
<HEAD>Survey Shows One-Third Favor Relocating Japan's Capital</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One in three Japanese favor moving the capital out of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> because the city of 11.6 million is so crowded, a government poll released today indicates. The poll, conducted by the Prime Minister's office, found 32.6 percent of respondents to favor relocation, with 17 percent opposed. Another 34.3 percent were undecided and 16.1 percent had no answer. Those favoring relocation say it is necessary to correct overconcentration of the population and solve housing and transportation problems. Those opposed say businesses should instead be distributed to places other than <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. Nearly 10 percent of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s people live in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. The office said it questioned 10,000 people age 20 and older at random in December.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 0031EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-FearofFlying     06-27 0289</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fear of Flying,0296</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former European Parliament Member Fined for Plane Incident</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fear of flying has cost a former British member of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> $ 1,240, the fine imposed by a court because he refused to fasten his airplane seat belt. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Cottrell </PERSON>, 45, was arrested at <LOCATION> Heathrow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> on May 24 after arriving from <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> on a <ORGANIZATION> Lufthansa </ORGANIZATION> flight. An airline spokeswoman said at the time that <PERSON> Cottrell </PERSON> had refused to fasten his seat belt as the flight approached <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and attempted to continue the argument in the cockpit with the captain. <PERSON> Cottrell </PERSON>, a Conservative, was fined Monday after pleading guilty to acting in a manner likely to endanger an aircraft or the people aboard. At the magistrate's court hearing, the defense said <PERSON> Cottrell </PERSON>'s fear of flying was the reason he refused to fasten his seat belt <PERSON> Cottrell </PERSON> went to the cockpit door and told the pilot, `` I am a member of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>,'' after he was told international regulations required all passengers to wear seat belts, the court was told. Prosecutor <PERSON> Neville </PERSON> <PERSON> Casselmann </PERSON> said <PERSON> Cottrell </PERSON> remained at the cockpit until the pilot shouted: `` Out _ we are landing.'' He returned to his seat about two minutes before the landing. Defense attorney <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Darby </PERSON> said his client `` for some considerable time had a large-scale phobia of flying. It arose out of an incident 15 years ago when he was a passenger in a light aircraft forced to make an emergency landing. He was badly shaken up by it.'' He added that his client `` always sits near the emergency exits and never fastens his seat belt.'' In this month's European <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> elections, <PERSON> Cottrell </PERSON> lost the <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION>, western <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, seat he had held for 10 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-OilSpillRdp 3rdLd-Writethru a0773 06-27 1063</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Oil Spill Rdp, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0773,1088</SECOND>
<HEAD>Delaware River Cleanup Continues, Worst Over in Rhode Island</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 7th graf, `He said...,' to UPDATE with
harbor pilot saying he tried to warn tanker. Picks up 8th graf pvs, `In
Texas...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos BX6, PX4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ERICH SMITH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CLAYMONT, Del. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Workers in boats scooped blobs of congealed oil the size of basketballs and bigger from the <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> on Monday and tried to contain the 800,000-gallon oil spill, the biggest of three weekend spills. Deep-water booms were installed to keep the heavy oil on the <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> from moving out to sea. Skimmers sent out after a Uruguayan tanker ran aground early Saturday could n't handle the dense oil blobs and jammed. Coast Guard Capt. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Murdock </PERSON> said Monday a call was issued for more boats, and 300 <ORGANIZATION> Delaware </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guardsmen </ORGANIZATION> were activated to help 250 private contractor employees scoop the goey mess from the water. However, federal officials said shoreline damage in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> was almost nonexistent. That was because the oil congealed and did not wash up like lighter oils spilled over the weekend in <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and crude oil spilled earlier this year along the coast of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. Near <LOCATION> Newport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>, the 420,000 gallons of lighter oil that spilled from a tanker after it hit a reef had largely dispersed or evaporated by Monday morning, officials said. Conditions were `` much, much better than yesterday,'' said <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morin </PERSON>, a state environmental official. Coast Guard Capt. <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>, marine safety office said there was no evidence that anything but human error played a role in the spill. He said there was no evidence of mechanical failure and noted that the ship's captain, <PERSON> Iakovos </PERSON> <PERSON> Georgudis </PERSON>, told Gov. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> DiPrete </PERSON> he had made a mistake. <PERSON> DiPrete </PERSON> said over the weekend that <PERSON> Georgudis </PERSON> told him he erred in plotting the ship's course. A harbor pilot on his way to a rendezvous with the tanker tried to warn the ship it was heading into dangerous waters, but his radio message came too late, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported in Tuesday's editions The newspaper quoted Capt. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Northeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newport </ORGANIZATION>, as saying that the harbor pilot, Capt. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON>, gave such an account to <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> investigators. In <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, most of the oil spilled Friday in the <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ship </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Channel </ORGANIZATION> by the collision of a tanker and an oil barge was concentrated in a smaller channel by wind and waves from approaching Tropical Storm <PERSON> Allison </PERSON>, allowing the use of huge vacuum machines to pick up the oil. By Monday afternoon, about two-thirds of the 6,000 barrels spilled had been recovered, said <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Morehead </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the president's press secretary, <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, complained Monday that the oil industry was moving too slowly on oil-spill cleanup technology and said the latest spills show ` the pervasiveness of the problem.'' He said they also underscored the need for legislation to better define tanker owners' liabilities. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> ruled out a moratorium on new oil drilling and exploration, as some have urged in the wake of the spills. Master Chief Petty Officer <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Kosch </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said he doubted any investigations into the spills had reached conclusions. <PERSON> Kosch </PERSON> said it's usually weeks before such probes reach preliminary findings. In <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Murdock </PERSON> said there wo n't be any problems unless the oil spilled when the tanker <PERSON> Presidente </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> ran aground somehow warmed to 95 degrees or higher and liquefied. Oil blobs were floating intact below the surface of the 60 - to 65-degree water, he said `` Yesterday we had a clump that had to be 30 gallons in one piece,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Gartin </PERSON>, operations manager for <ORGANIZATION> J </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; J Spill Service, <LOCATION> Norristown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> `` It was about four feet by four feet and three feet deep. We just broke pieces off and stuffed them in bags.'' <PERSON> Gartin </PERSON> said the oil was staying pretty much in the <LOCATION> Claymont </LOCATION> area, just south of the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania-Delaware </LOCATION> border. But tidal action moved the oil back and forth, up and down the river, and globs were spotted as far north as <LOCATION> Ridley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, on the outskirts of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>; and as far south as <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Castle </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Del. </LOCATION>, about 30 miles downstream. <PERSON> Gartin </PERSON> said he doubted the oil will be cleaned up by the end of the week. <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> wildlife officials worked to protect <LOCATION> Pea </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Patch </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, in the river south of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Castle </LOCATION>, which is home to several species of nesting shorebirds. Crews laid 1,700 feet of oil-retaining booms along the island. As of Monday, only one bird had died, said <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Nugent </PERSON>, manager of the <ORGANIZATION> Tinicum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, located near <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. The cause of the tanker's grounding was under investigation. Drug and alcohol tests were performed on everyone involved in navigating the ship. The results were not immediately available. In <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sound </LOCATION>, only a few small patches of oil could be seen Monday, state and federal officials said. `` The worst is over,'' said <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Payton </PERSON>, an oceanographer with the <ORGANIZATION> Natonal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanographic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. She estimated no more than 5 percent of the highly toxic oil remained floating on the water. One of the heaviest patches of remaining oil was just east of <LOCATION> Block </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, but no booms were flown there because the island's most sensitive shore is on the opposite side, officials said There had been some reports of lobsters killed and several small birds found dead, but officials said those did not appear to be widespread. Agents from the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and three other state and federal agencies met with <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> attorneys to begin their investigation of the accident, said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> <PERSON> Almond </PERSON>. The Coast Guard planned hearings Tuesday into the <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> spills. State beaches from <LOCATION> Jamestown </LOCATION> almost to <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> remained closed as a precaution, although eastern beaches were open. A statewide shellfishing ban remained in effect. In <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, heavy rain from the approaching tropical storm slowed cleanup Monday, but three more huge vacuum machines were brought in to help the cleanup for a total of a dozen on the scene, <PERSON> Morehead </PERSON> said. `` The wind makes the -LRB- water -RRB- choppy and the rain is a pain in the neck, but they're still going ahead,'' he said. Much of the area affected by that spill was industrial.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 0022EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HarvardUnion     06-27 0448</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Harvard Union,0461</SECOND>
<HEAD>Harvard, Union Reach Tentative Contract</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN COOPERMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and its clerical workers' union said Monday they have reached tentative agreement on their first contract, culminating 17 years of labor organizing and four months of negotiations. The union's chief negotiator, <PERSON> Kristine </PERSON> <PERSON> Rondeau </PERSON>, said the pact would provide pay raises averaging 32 percent over the next three years. `` It's the prettiest contract you've ever seen,'' said <PERSON> Rondeau </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> laboratory assistant who led the campaign that succeeded last year in organizing the 3,500 workers over strenuous opposition from the university. `` It's got great economics and cooperative labor-management relations, and it addresses the concerns of working women,'' she said. Former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of Labor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunlop </PERSON>, a professor of economics at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>, led the university's bargaining team. The negotiators, who had been meeting since February, said they reached agreement in principle late Sunday night. The <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clerical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> is scheduled to hold a ratification vote Thursday. The tentative contract provides several new benefits, including a $ 50,000 annual scholarship fund for child care and eight weeks of paid maternity leave. It also gives the workers free use of the university's athletic facilities, increases their dental and pension benefits and raises the university's contribution to their health insurance premiums to 85 percent from 70 percent. The union, which is affiliated with the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Municipal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employees </ORGANIZATION>, represents secretaries, library aides, laboratory personnel and mailroom workers throughout the university. The effort to form a union among the clerical workers, 83 percent of whom are women, began in 1972. It culminated in a May 17, 1988, vote that the labor organizers won by 44 votes, or less than 2 percent of the total cast in the 1,530-1 ,486 decision Harvard President <PERSON> Derek </PERSON> <PERSON> Bok </PERSON>, a former law professor whose academic writings have been supportive of labor unions, opposed the union's formation. The university challenged the vote before the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> but lost. <PERSON> Bok </PERSON> said Monday the university will work with the union to complete and sign the formal contract. `` We look forwad with increasing confidence to a positive relationshp between <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> and the union,'' he said. <PERSON> Rondeau </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dunlop </PERSON> tried to foster an atmosphere of cooperation and goodwill toward the union in the aftermath of the bitter organizing battle. `` I think he did everything that he could to change the way the university and the union related to each other, and I think he did a good job at that,'' she said. <PERSON> Dunlop </PERSON> was traveling to <LOCATION> Cambridge </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on Monday evening and could not be reached for comment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-AfghanNomads Bjt   06-27 0657</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghan Nomads, Bjt,0679</SECOND>
<HEAD>Koochi Nomads Embody The Spirit Of Afghanistan ^An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SHARON HERBAUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> TANGIYE </LOCATION> <LOCATION> POL-I-CHARKI </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ Bearded, turbaned men slowly guide their camels, sheep and goats down the mountains and carry lambs on their shoulders along the rugged path. Women in colorful traditional dress and small children run beside the flock to keep the bleating animals from straying. They travel along the potholed road past the artillery guns and tanks and through this military checkpoint, undisturbed by the soldiers. `` We are free people,'' <PERSON> Habibullah </PERSON> said as he unloaded sacks of goods from his kneeling camel. `` We are the true spirit of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. Or maybe we're what <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> used to be.'' <PERSON> Habibullah </PERSON> and the other 15 members of his clan are among the estimated 2 million Koochi nomads who wander between winter and summer pastures, pitching their hide tents in fields, building fires and turning their sheep to graze. The Koochis, which means wanderer in the <LOCATION> Pashto </LOCATION> language, have traveled the rugged hills and valleys of Afghanstian for thousands of years. They are ethnic Pathans, like most people in eastern <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. But unlike their brothers, they never settled down. Most still divide their time between the warm lowlands around <LOCATION> Peshawar </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, and the hilly fields of northern and central <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. The 11-year-old civil war has made the journey more difficult for the Koochis. But it has n't stopped them. <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, the capital, is a common stopping point for the <LOCATION> Koochis </LOCATION>, and their camel trains are as much a part of the urban landscape as the old bazaars, the military outposts and high-rise apartment buildings. They halt in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> at least once a year to sell camels, sheep and goats at the meat market. `` The <LOCATION> Koochi </LOCATION> people are an important part of our homeland, an important part of our tradition. We respect them,'' said <PERSON> Sulaiman </PERSON> <PERSON> Laeq </PERSON>, the minister of clans and a Politburo member. The government has tried to provide them with education, health and the benefits of progress, such as helping them purchase trucks and organize a transport union. But the Koochis have made it clear they do n't want to enter the modern world, especially if it means owing alligence to the ruling <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Afghanistan </ORGANIZATION> or any other government. In the early days of the 1978 Marxist revolution that touched off the civil war, efforts were made to force the <LOCATION> Koochis </LOCATION> to stop wandering and settle in the north. The move backfired, said the 37-year-old <PERSON> Habibullah </PERSON>. Some of the <PERSON> Koochis </PERSON> took up guns and joined the Moslem guerrillas in the battle against the Soviet-backed government troops. `` Some are still fighting, but most have returned,'' <PERSON> Habibullah </PERSON> said through a translator. Laeq and other party officials speak of the mistakes the government made while trying to bring progress to the <LOCATION> Koochis </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Koochi </PERSON> men had never been asked to serve in the Afghan armed forces, but that tradition was reversed when the Marxists seized power 11 years ago in a bloody coup. By 1985, the government had modified its policy, formally exempting the <LOCATION> Koochi </LOCATION> men from government military service. But the war has not been easy for the Koochis. They often step on land mines planted by the armed forces and by the Soviets during their nine-year intervention. And their travels frequently take them into battle zones near <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION>, an eastern city under rebel siege since early March. `` This war has been very bad for our people,'' says another <LOCATION> Koochi </LOCATION> leader, <PERSON> Azizullah </PERSON>. `` The bombs, and rockets and land mines have killed so many of our people.'' Occasionally, he says, the rebels demand money to allow them to pass through guerrilla-controlled territory. Often the roads are neither open nor safe, forcing the <LOCATION> Koochis </LOCATION> to travel through the mountains and turning an easy one-day journey into a dangerous, two-week affair. `` We are our own people. We do n't want to be on either side,'' says <PERSON> Azizullah </PERSON>. `` We do n't want anyone else's war.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DumpFight Bjt   06-27 0641</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dump Fight, Bjt,0660</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Mexico Town Fights `Manhattan Project</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED MORENO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LORDSBURG, N.M. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Like many small <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> towns, <LOCATION> Lordsburg </LOCATION> wants new jobs, tourists and its businesses to grow. But promoters never dreamed the hottest development deal here in decades would involve a Manhattan-size landfill that has thrown the town into the debate over the nation's mounting solid waste problem. Immense, isolated and sparsely populated, the <LOCATION> Hidalgo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> desert near <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> has been chosen by a <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> company for the commercial landfill. The dump would accommodate up to 20,000 tons of garbage a day from <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> cities. The proposal was not exactly a secret. A major construction firm, <ORGANIZATION> Driggs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, acting locally as Innovative Environmental Systems of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, had secured property in the area and in January asked the state for a landfill permit. But elected officials and their constituents _ caught off guard when news of the proposal surfaced _ sent a shock wave of opposition that has since reverberated in every <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> town and county as well as the Capitol in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fe </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, mayor of this southwestern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> town of 3,200 people, recalls that January morning when he saw a map of his town on the front page of a newspaper: `` There's <LOCATION> Lordsburg </LOCATION> on the map right there, and <PERSON> Driggs </PERSON>, and I looked at my wife and said, ` What is this?' My phone started ringing, ` What is this? What is this?''' The 7,300-acre landfill site would sit on 36 square miles now occupied by lizards, snakes, mesquite brush and yucca. The property is neatly and conveniently bisected by Interstate 10 and the busy <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railroad </ORGANIZATION> line. The opposition moved fast, turning trash into a major environmental-political issue in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and focusing attention on the state's inadequate landfill regulations and the national quest for suitable landfill space. When the 1989 Legislature convened in mid-January, a bill was introduced to toughen the landfill law and block commercial dumps. It received overwhelming support. But the bill was vetoed by Gov. <PERSON> Garrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Carruthers </PERSON>, who cited technicalities that he said would have forced the immediate closure of every landfill in the state. But in March, <PERSON> Carruthers </PERSON> issued a moratorium outlawing all new commercial landfills except under special circumstances. The state <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Improvement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> adopted new regulations two months later. <LOCATION> Hidalgo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, responding to the public demand, also imposed a landfill moratorium and initiated its first-ever land use planning effort. `` Now that we are aware ... that they are looking at deserts for landfills, we need to protect ourselves,'' said County Commissioner <PERSON> Maura </PERSON> <PERSON> Rico </PERSON>. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON>, <PERSON> Driggs </PERSON>' director of special projects who was the company's local representative, and <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Golden </PERSON>, executive vice president, refused to be interviewed by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, citing fears of adverse publicity. However, <ORGANIZATION> Innovative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION>' director, I.M. `` Ike'' <PERSON> Smalley </PERSON>, who retired last year from the state <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> after 38 years, said <LOCATION> Lordsburg </LOCATION> residents never waited for a full explanation, leading to misconceptions about the landfill and its potential benefits. <LOCATION> Lordsburg </LOCATION> would reap economic benefits, including up to 150 jobs and a $ 3 million payroll. Few residents are tempted. `` My first reaction was that no waste disposal operation of this size could possibly be a good thing for the community ... no matter how many jobs it creates,'' said <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, a school administrator and leader of the opposition. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> also said he worries that <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> could get a reputation as the nation's dump, a status some have conferred because of the Waste Isolation Pilot Plant, the nation's low - and intermediate-level nuclear waste repository near <LOCATION> Carlsbad </LOCATION> And he fears what the landfill would mean to <LOCATION> Lordsburg </LOCATION>'s image with tourists. `` People will come in and say, ` Children, we're coming into <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> now. This is where the world's largest dump is.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BoxOffice 2ndLd-Writethru a0725 06-27 0778</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Box Office, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0725,0798</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Batman' Breaks Box-Office Records in Opening Weekend</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS graf 14, `In sixth...,' and 23rd, `6. ``Star...,' to CORRECT
Star Trek V's figure to $3.7 million, sted $3.8.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserGraphic</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HORN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Batman'' made more money in three days than most movies generate in their lifetimes, with a $ 42.7 million opening that broke a week-old record and drove the industry to a record $ 90 million-plus weekend. Despite attracting less-than-overwhelming reviews, `` Batman,'' starring <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Keaton </PERSON> in the title role and <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicholson </PERSON> as the Joker, set new marks for the best opening day with $ 15.3 million Friday, according to figures released Monday. It also recorded the biggest Saturday at $ 14.6 million and Sunday at $ 12.7 million in movie history. Those figures were rounded off; the exact figures yielded the $ 42.7 million gross, according to <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Krier </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which tracks box-office performance. The previous opening-weekend record was set a week earlier by `` Ghostbusters II,'' which grossed $ 29.5 million. Overall, American and Canadian movie fans spent more than $ 95 million at theaters during the weekend, breaking yet another record by $ 3 million. `` This is tremendous. It is the biggest weekend ever in the history of the business,'' said <PERSON> Krier </PERSON>. This summer's box office is now running 14 percent ahead of last year's record season of $ 1.7 billion, according to industry estimates. Grosses have been boosted by higher ticket prices, up to $ 7 in some theaters. The unprecedented popularity of <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>' `` Batman'' may even have helped the competition, as moviegoers _ perhaps frustrated by unbearably long `` Batman'' lines at some of its 2,194 screens _ dashed to <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>'s modest comedy, `` Honey, I Shrunk the Kids,'' in record numbers. `` Honey,'' which is being shown with a new 7 -LCB- - minute <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabbit </PERSON> cartoon called `` Tummy Trouble,'' collected $ 14.3 million in its first weekend to finish in second place It broke all of Disney's opening box-office records, including those set by its hits `` Cocktail'' and `` Three Men and a Baby. The Disney production enjoyed the third-best opening weekend of any non-sequel movie, trailing only `` Batman'' and `` <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> Cop,'' the studio said. The most noticeable victim of the `` Batman'' and `` Honey, I Shrunk the Kids'' onslaught was <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Ghostbusters II,'' with <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Aykroyd </PERSON>, which fell sharply after its record opening. Finishing third on the box-office charts, `` Ghostbusters II'' grossed $ 13.9 million, a collapse of more than 52 percent. In fourth place was <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Indiana <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and the Last Crusade,'' which grossed $ 8.2 million. It was followed in fifth place by <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Dead Poets Society,'' $ 7.3 million, featuring <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> as a crusading high-school teacher. `` We are so excited about that picture,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>'s president of distribution. `` With ` <PERSON> Indiana </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>,' ` Star Trek,' ` Ghostbusters' and ` Batman,' to have this movie performing at the level that it is ... It's going to be around for a long, long time.'' In sixth was `` Star Trek V: The Final Frontier,'' the <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Shatner-directed </PERSON> sequel that seems overwhelmed by the summer competition. After opening strongly two weeks ago, `` Star Trek V'' grossed only $ 3.7 million over the weekend. Universal's baseball movie `` Field of Dreams,'' with <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Costner </PERSON>, landed in seventh with ticket sales of $ 2.1 million. In eighth was the comedy `` See No Evil, Hear No Evil,'' with estimated grosses of $ 1.6 million. Rounding out the Top 10 were `` Road House'' with $ 913,000 and `` No Holds Barred'' with $ 808,000. Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by Exhibitor Relations, with distributor, weekend gross, number of theater screens, average per screen, total gross and number of weeks in release. 1. `` Batman,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 42.7 million, 2,194 screens, $ 19,465 per screen, $ 42.7 million, one week. 2. `` Honey, I Shrunk the Kids,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 14.3 million, 1,371 screens, $ 10,403 per screen, $ 14.3 million, one week. 3. `` Ghostbusters II,'' <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, $ 13.9 million, 2,410 screens, $ 5,749 per screen, $ 58.8 million, two weeks. 4. `` Indiana <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and the Last Crusade,'' Paramount, $ 8.2 million, 2,103 screens, $ 3,881 per screen, $ 136.3 million, five weeks. 5. `` Dead Poets Society,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 7.3 million, 1,091 screens, $ 6,732 per screen, $ 35.6 million, four weeks. 6. `` Star Trek V: The Final Frontier,'' Paramount, $ 3.7 million, 2,007 screens, $ 1,866 per screen, $ 38.3 million, three weeks. 7. `` Field of Dreams,'' Universal, $ 2.1 million, 995 screens, $ 2,135 per screen, $ 47.7 million, 10 weeks. 8. `` See No Evil, Hear No Evil,'' Tri-Star, $ 1.6 million, 1,465 screens, $ 1,085 per screen, $ 41 million, seven weeks. 9. `` Road House,'' <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 913,093, 1,051 screens, $ 869 per screen, $ 25.7 million, six weeks. 10. `` No Holds Barred,'' New Line, $ 808,594, 1,005 screens, $ 805 per screen, $ 13.9 million, four weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 0029EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-HUDInsurance 1stLd-Writethru   06-27 0585</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-HUD Insurance, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0716,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mortgage Company Defaults Subject of HUD Probe</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDs: INSERTS new information about ``Robin HUD'' turning over home
to department to cover thefts in new grafs 3-4: ``In addition,'' ADDS three
grafs to elaborate.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> faces some $ 650 million in loan defaults from nine mortgage companies whose practices now are under review, a spokesman said Monday. Three of the nine companies have been suspended indefinitely from doing business with the department, three others have been placed on probation for six months and three more face examination of their projects, <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> documents show. In addition, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> general counsel-designate, said escrow agent <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrell </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and agents in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> became the first agents that <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> would bar from future government contracts, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said in Tuesday editions. The cases are part of a nationwide investigation of <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>' dealings with about 280 closing agents who handled government foreclosures. Ms. <PERSON> Harrell </PERSON>, whose diversion of $ 5.5 million from the government's primary housing subsidy program earned her the nickname `` <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> HUD </PERSON>,'' turned over her house to the department to cover part of the thefts and moved out on Monday. The mortgage companies have been involved in `` coinsurance programs'' at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>, under which they earn lucrative fees for servicing loans for federally backed housing programs but stand to lose little if the borrower defaults. The mortgage companies have to absorb the first 5 percent of the loss on the loans, but <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> takes 85 prcent of the remaining loss. `` Lenders were underwriting unsound loans, overmortgaging properties, failing to detect indications of troubled loans in a timely manner, and were not taking adequate and timely actions to minimize mortgage defaults and coinsurance losses,'' according to a <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> inspector general's report issued earlier this year. That report estimated that loans worth some $ 700 million were in default, but <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Glavin </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said some of the potential losses have been recovered, lowering the overall liability to $ 650 million. That represents about 13 percent of the money loaned under the program, he said. The lenders suspended indefinitely were <ORGANIZATION> DRG </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Funding </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Puller </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mortgage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Funding </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. The three on probation through Nov. 1 are <ORGANIZATION> Benton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mortgage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Evans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> L.P. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Citadel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mortgage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The three lenders under review are <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mortgages </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Eagle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mortgage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> TRI </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. At the beginning of May <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> placed a moratorium on the entire coinsurance program until Sept. 1 while the agency reviews the program. To preempt a federal eviction, Ms. <PERSON> Harrell </PERSON>, 46, spent the weekend hauling six truckloads of furniture from the house she purchased with her own money in 1986, including a white baby grand piano and a large-screen television set. She moved in with her mother nearby. Ms. <PERSON> Harrell </PERSON> said she gave <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> the title to her home in December when her contract as a closing agent for <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> ran out and agents were asking about millions missing from her title company. She said she also had transferred to <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> the deeds to five other houses she paid for with <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s money and used for various charities and homeless families. Last week, Ms. <PERSON> Harrell </PERSON> said two vans and a pickup truck used by her company were seized at her business office in <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON>, Md.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 0056EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp Bjt   06-27 0754</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp, Bjt,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Death Penalty Opponents Outraged by Court Ruling on Children</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Death penalty opponents are calling for new state laws to protect juveniles and the mentally retarded in the wake of <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> rulings they say are `` medieval and barbaric.'' `` To give up, with ultimate finality, upon a person even before they emerge from childhood ... is squarely in opposition to the fundamental premises of an enlightened juvenile justice system,'' said <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Raven </PERSON>. `` We strongly urge states to enact legislation which recognizes that minors ... should not be held to ... the ultimate sanction of death,'' he said. Of the 37 states permitting capital punishment, 15 now bar its use for anyone who committed the crime before age 18. The court, voting 5-4, said Monday the Constitution does not bar states from executing murderers who committed their crimes as young as 16 or mentally retarded adult killers. In the case of the mentally retarded, the justices said convicted murderers may demand that sentencing juries and judges consider their limited reasoning capacity as a factor weighing against the death penalty. The court upheld the death sentences of a <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> murderer who was 17 when he killed, a <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> killer who was 16, and a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> killer who has the mental capacity of a 7-year-old. Last year, the court decided that 15 was too young for execution. The justices, expected to wrap up the current court term on Thursday, have yet to issue a decision in a closely watched <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> case in which the court's 1973 decision legalizing abortion is under attack. The court must either announce a decision or schedule the case to be argued again during its next term beginning in October. In other matters Monday, the court: _ Ruled, 7-2, that skyrocketing punitive damage awards in personal injury lawsuits do not violate the Constitution's ban on excessive fines The decision left open the possibility that such hefty awards violate due-process rights. _ Said police may stray from the precise wording of the famous Miranda warnings given to criminal suspects, voting 5-4 to reinstate an <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> man's conviction for attempted murder _ Unanimously interpreted a key federal anti-racketeering law broadly in a <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> case to make it easier to use the law in civil lawsuits against businesses accused of fraud _ Agreed to decide in an <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> case whether states may outlaw possession of `` lewd'' photographs and films depicting child nudity The court in 1982 said states could ban the promotion and distribution of such material, but stopped short of allowing its possession to be a crime. Law enforcement authorities said the juvenile death penalty decisions will advance the fight against violent crime. `` In an era of growing concern over the increase and seriousness of violent crime, the court's decision ... reaffirms that state legislators, the juvenile justice system and local juries _ not the federal courts _ can and should decide upon the proper age to impose the death penalty,'' said Attorney General <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowan </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>. `` Clearly, some 16 - and 17-year-olds in our society are fully mature and capable of plotting and carrying out the most heinous of crimes,'' he added `` The court has obviously responded to society's demand to hold youths who are mature enough to commit horrible crimes responsible for their actions. The court's juvenile-killers ruling affects about 25 of the 2,200 death row inmates across the nation. As for mental retardation, people who function at below-average intelligence comprise between 12 and 30 percent of all death row inmates, according to one group opposed to the death penalty. The rulings prompted widespread concern among activists for individual rights. `` It is quite appalling that the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> would read the Constitution ... as not banning the execution of children,'' said <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwarzschild </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>. `` To let the society hang children is medieval and barbaric.'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retardation </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` It now falls to state legislatures to assure that no individual with this disability is ever put to death in this country. The execution of any such person would represent a tragic injustice.'' <PERSON> Michele </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Against </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Death </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Penalty </ORGANIZATION> said the rulings give states `` rein to execute children.'' But Missouri Attorney General <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> said the rulings will not prompt more executions of minors. `` I think that's hogwash. There's a lot of people that say it's going to open the door That's ludicrous,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Wright Bjt   06-27 0564</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wright, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wright Quitting Friday; Won't Seek Re-election</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> says he's leaving <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for good on Friday, ending speculation that he might seek re-election to the seat that ethics charges forced him to give up <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> issued a statement saying he is gratified by supporters' calls for him to seek re-election _ and political vindication _ in a special vote to be called after he steps down `` As deeply as I appreciate the devoted friendship which impels these sincere petitions, I must conclude that I was right in announcing my retirement from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>,'' the <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, Democrat said Monday. `` It is best for the institution and best for the people whom I've served that I step aside now and make room for others,'' he said. He said his nearly 35-year <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> career will end Friday and he will not seek elective office again. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee had charged <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> with 69 violations, involving whether he sidestepped <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> limits on outside income through bulk sales of a book he wrote, and whether he improperly accepted $ 145,000 in gifts from a business partner with a direct interest in legislation. In an emotional speech to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on May 31, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said he would step down as speaker and resign his <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> seat by the end of June. He was replaced as speaker by Rep. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, D-Wash., a week later But <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> had left open the possibility he might seek re-election to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> in an attempt to counter the ethics charges that made him the first <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> speaker ever to resign under fire. He said last week he might run if there were `` an absolutely genuine draft of a bipartisan nature.'' In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, however, colleagues were privately aghast at the suggestion he might seek to stay on. An aide, speaking on condition of anonymity, said a weekend poll showing home-district support for <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> figured prominently in the decision not to run again. `` He just felt like that was vindication,'' the aide said. Sixty-five percent of <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s constituents who were polled said they would vote for him again. About 81 percent believed <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> was doing an `` outstanding'' or `` good'' job in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and 67 percent said he gave up too soon in his fight against the ethics charges. The poll, which sampled 407 residents last week and had an error margin of plus or minus 5 percentage points, appeared in Sunday's <ORGANIZATION> Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Worth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star-Telegram </ORGANIZATION> `` To seek and gain the splendid honor of a public endorsement one more time would be vainglorious,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said in the statement. `` To do so without intending to serve for a prolonged period would be pointless. To postpone the moment when another may begin would be a disservice.'' Had he run again and won, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> still could have been subject to disciplinary action by the ethics committee, which apparently decided to set the case aside after he announced his intention to resign. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said he has accepted `` five or six'' invitations to deliver speeches and is considering `` some limited business and professional relationships'' and writing opportunities. He will maintain an office in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, he said. He and his wife, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON>, plan to attend a `` Welcome Home, <PERSON> Jim </PERSON>'' celebration Thursday in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, sponsored by Mayor <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolen </PERSON> and former Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Vandergriff </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-ForeignPress Bjt   06-27 0836</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Foreign Press, Bjt,0867</SECOND>
<HEAD>Foreign Press Uses Imaginative Tactics to Report Crisis</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRIL JONES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Covering the news in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> under the growing obstacles created by martial law requires more in the way of imaginative tactics by foreign journalists than derring-do. Reporting on <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s political crisis has become increasingly difficult as soldiers and police strictly enforce restrictions on the press. Newsgathering is basically banned under martial law, except for the infrequent government-orchestrated peasant rally or news conference. But virtually all reporters in the capital and other <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> cities ignore the regulations, coming up with their own ways of getting around martial law. `` The most effective trick these days is to act like a dumb tourist,'' says an Asian photojournalist. `` Wear bright clothes and shorts, and do n't hide your camera.'' If stopped by security personnel, he says, `` the best defense is to go on the offense. Ask them some questions. It's better than trying to run away.'' Martial law was imposed May 20 in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> in a move to quell the student-led democracy movement that was finally crushed June 4 when soldiers killed hundreds of unarmed civilians in the capital. Under the vaguely worded decree, foreigners are prohibited from entering or taking pictures at schools, factories or `` organizations''. Television networks face the greatest difficulties. Their equipment makes them easy to spot. `` For television, we do n't have a story unless we have a picture that can convey the information,'' says a CBS News official. `` We get chased away all the time. We're very frustrated at not being able to shoot pictures.'' Coverage has been reduced to relying on government-controlled TV news. `` A great deal of what we're doing is recording their material and reworking it,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> official. `` We're very much at their mercy.'' Foreign television networks can no longer send segments through state-run <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> to <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> via satellite. They must now somehow get their videotapes to <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. `` We smuggled out our tapes, did the double shuffle with the cassettes and that sort,'' said <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>, a correspondent for <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> whose videotape was `` confiscated'' by police after he filmed on a university campus in <LOCATION> Chengdu </LOCATION>, central <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. `` Our piece, which would have greatly upset them, was aired all over the <LOCATION> U.K. </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION> -RRB-.'' <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> was expelled from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> for the incident. Still photographers have an easier time. One wrapped his camera in a jacket and put the bundle in his bicycle basket, shooting frames as he passed soldiers guarding intersections. Another put aside his complex single-lens reflex camera and instead went out with the automatic-focus variety so all he had to do was point and push. Most photographers have resorted to taking pictures from cars, some with darkened windows, as they zip past soldiers on patrol or troops checking identification. One cameraman from a European photo agency took a dramatic shot through the back window of a taxi of a man in handcuffs being led away by soldiers. `` One guy saw me, and I just hit my driver on the back and said, ` Let's get out of here!,''' he said. Print journalists face more subtle difficulties. With most Chinese frightened into silence by widespread arrests, including the nationally publicized arrest of a man who talked to an American television crew, reporters' sources are drying up. `` I've simply stopped telephoning people,'' said one <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> reporter, noting that he and most colleagues assume their phones are tapped. `` I think of my Chinese contacts first and foremost as friends and I've stopped making any attempt to contact them.'' Other journalists discover that acquaintances refuse to meet them. A German reporter was turned away when he showed up at the doorsteps of some Chinese friends. He says now he does not even take notes on the streets, preferring to keep his eyes open and later write down what he saw. The few who do make appointments do so with great caution, calling from public telephones, instructing friends not to say their names in phone conversations, making appointments by prearranged code and meeting sources furtively in discrete locations. `` I only move around at night,'' said a Japanese reporter. `` Even though it's easier for me to blend into a crowd than Westerners, I still stand out.'' He says while many people who have helped him have gone underground, he has n't stopped seeing people because `` Chinese have information you ca n't get otherwise.'' He, too, says meetings are much harder to arrange. `` You ca n't meet people in hotels _ they have secret cameras everywhere,'' referring to footage taken by a hidden camera of a student leader feasting at the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Hotel Now he finds the only place he can interview people is in his car _ during the day, when soldiers are n't checking vehicles for fugitives. `` The greatest danger in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> now is that the people have lost their voice,'' he said. `` The reformists and intellectuals are all gone. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> have lost its good-heartedness.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HawaiiEarthquake 1stLd-Writethru a0655 06-27 0395</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hawaii Earthquake, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0655,0402</SECOND>
<HEAD>Strongest Quake in Six Years Strikes Hawaii Island</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 7th, `The quake...,' to UPDATE with aftershocks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VOLCANO, Hawaii (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The strongest earthquake to hit <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> in six years shook a sparsely populated area of <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> already ravaged by lava, destroying two homes and generating a small tidal wave. No serious injuries were reported. Authorities were investigating reports of damage to other homes Monday, said <ORGANIZATION> Hawaii </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kim </PERSON>. `` Our first priority this morning is to check certain remote areas to make sure no one is trapped in their homes,'' <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> said. `` Early reports we are getting indicate no one is trapped.'' The temblor, caused by the 6 -LCB- - year-old eruption of <LOCATION> Kilauea </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Volcano </LOCATION>, struck Sunday evening and measured 6.1 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Geological Survey said It was centered west of <LOCATION> Kalapana </LOCATION>, a small coastal town on the south flank of the volcano, said <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, a geophysicist at the <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tsunami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Warning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION>. The quake was triggered by the release of pressure generated by the movement of underground magma, or molten rock, said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Koyanagi </PERSON>, a seismic analyst at the <ORGANIZATION> Geological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Survey </ORGANIZATION>'s Hawaiian Volcano Observatory. <PERSON> Reggie </PERSON> <PERSON> Okamura </PERSON>, a spokesman for the observatory, said scientists had recorded numerous aftershocks. The strongest, measuring 4.0 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, was recorded Sunday night, he said. <LOCATION> Kilauea </LOCATION> lava has destroyed 68 homes in the <LOCATION> Kalapana </LOCATION> area since its latest eruption began Jan. 3, 1983. Four homes were destroyed in May, and last Thursday a <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> Volcanoes National Park visitor center burst into flames as lava crept beneath the wooden structure. <PERSON> Koyanagi </PERSON> said pressure became too great within the world's most active volcano, causing its south flank to move and triggering the earthquake. The tidal wave, which measured 22.8 inches high at <LOCATION> Honuapo </LOCATION>, 8.4 inches at <LOCATION> Kapoho </LOCATION> and 5.6 inches at <LOCATION> Hilo </LOCATION>, caused no damage, <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> said. Five people were injured by falling debris inside homes, but none required hospitalization, <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> said. Crews were working to repair downed power lines. It was the strongest earthquake to hit the state since Nov. 15, 1983, when a 6.6 temblor caused several million dollars damage on <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. The <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale is a measure of ground motion as recorded on seismographs. Every increase of one number means a tenfold increase in magnitude.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 0126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Spills-Contrasts     06-27 0658</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spills-Contrasts,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Latest Oil Spills Far Different From Alaskan Disaster</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Major oil spills in <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> provided a big challenge for the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> but the tasks differed sharply from the massive <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> spill that is still being cleaned up three months after it happened. `` Here we have a spill that we hoped would n't happen, but we were prepared for it,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Meidt </PERSON>, who worked on both the Alaskan spill and the spill last Friday at the mouth of <LOCATION> Narragansett </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> off <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. `` Up there in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, it was a spill that could n't happen, but it did, `` he said. The same pumps used to evacuate 40 million gallons of Alaskan crude from the Exxon Valdez after it ran aground March 24 in <LOCATION> Prince </LOCATION> <LOCATION> William </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sound </LOCATION> and spilled more than 10 million gallons were being used on the World Prodigy in <LOCATION> Naragansett </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>. But they were pumping a far different substance. While the Alaskan crude continues to pollute shorelines as far as 450 miles away from the original spill, the 420,000 gallons of refined heating oil that poured out of the World Prodigy have largely evaporated or dissipated. On the <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, cleanup crews were contending with yet a different consistency: basketball-sized globs of oil from 800,000 gallons that oozed out of a Uraguayan tanker Saturday. But that was also easier to clean up than the Alaskan crude. <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> officials said shoreline damage downriver in <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> was almost nonexistent because the oil was thick and was not washing up on the shore. In <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, by contrast, the soft crude seeped deep into beach sand. In the <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> outside <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, 250,000 gallons of oil that spilled in the collision of a tanker and a barge was confined to a small shipping channel and most of the oil that washed ashore affected only industrial property. Weather conditions after both the Alaskan and the recent weekend spills were mild, but brought far different results. Off the <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>, the sun speeded up evaporation of the light oil off the <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>. `` In <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, what we needed was a storm to break up the oil,'' said <PERSON> Meidt </PERSON>. He said booms also were used quickly and effectively in the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> spill to contain and divert the oil in a way that was never possible after <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s midnight spill 25 miles out in <LOCATION> Prince </LOCATION> <LOCATION> William </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sound </LOCATION>. `` This one was literally in the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>'s backyard,'' said <PERSON> Meidt </PERSON>. `` We just went out and put a boom around it.'' Officials said a response system being reviewed as a result of the Alaskan spill appears to be working well in handling the smaller spills. But officials still need to know how the response system would work with a much larger spill. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pascoe </PERSON>, chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>'s environmental response branch, said that response of officials may have been heightened over the weekend because of the reviews they are conducting, but he said there have been no policy or operational changes since the Alaskan spill. No equipment or personnel had to be moved from <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> for the latest spills, he said. The workload is also being handled differently. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> is paying thousands of workers to clean up oil in the Alaskan spill. Private contractors, volunteers, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guardsmen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> personnel are involved in cleaning up the latest spills, but shippers have to pay the costs. In each of the latest spills, local <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> officials were overseeing the cleanup, said <PERSON> Pascoe </PERSON>. He said it was too early for the Alaskan spill to have much impact on the way the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> or other agencies respond to spills. But he noted <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is considering several measures to deal with spills in the wake of the Alaskan disaster. The oil industry last week announced its own plans for a cooperative response.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890627-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-27-89 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-EPAFines     06-27 0647</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-EPA Fines,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Companies Fined for Failure to Report Toxic Chemical Releases</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
