<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Germany-SovietPOWs     06-13 0310</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Germany-Soviet POWs,0319</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Release Names of Missing German Soldiers In Humanitarian
Gesture</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Germany-Gorbachev, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a gesture of reconciliation more than four decades after the end of World War II, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has released the names of 1,500 German soldiers who died in its prisoner-of-war camps. The list was presented to the German <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> to coincide with the arrival Monday of Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. It was the first time the Soviets had provided a list of German soldiers still unaccounted for after the war, West German officials said. Thousands of German soldiers died in Soviet prisoner-of-war camps and many prisoners were not released until the early 1950s. German <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> officials applauded the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> action, saying it was a `` moving gesture of reconciliation and an important first step in clarifying the fate of these missing men.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> and another West German group, the Federation for the Preservation of German War Graves, said they hoped to be able to inform relatives of the soldiers on the list soon. The <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> said it hoped that additional lists of missing soldiers would follow. The <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> has also agreed allow greater access to several cemeteries in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> where German soldiers are buried. German <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Botho </PERSON> <PERSON> Prinz </PERSON> zu <PERSON> Sayn-Wittgenstein </PERSON> called the Soviet gesture a `` breakthrough in the humantarian relations'' between the two nations. The bitter legacy of World War II and the Nazi attack on the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has clouded West German-Soviet relations for decades. According to official estimates, more than 20 million Soviets were killed in the war and <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> armies destroyed vast areas of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Soviet prisoners of war were subjected to brutal treatment by the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> and thousands died in forced labor and concentration camps until the German defeat in 1945.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Egypt-Drugs     06-13 0143</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Egypt-Drugs,0147</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eight Heroin Smugglers Sentenced to Death</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAIRO, Egypt (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> court has sentenced eight people, four of them Lebanese nationals, to death by hanging for trying to smuggle more than six pounds of heroin into the country. Also Monday, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>'s parliament passed a new law stiffening penalties for narcotics users to include the life sentence. The sentencings Monday brought to 27 the number of convicted drug smugglers sentenced this month to death by hanging. A court in the port city of <ORGANIZATION> Suez </ORGANIZATION> last week sentenced to death 19 people, including three Palestinians, an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> and a Lebanese-born naturalized American for trying to smuggle 5.9 tons of opium and hashish and nearly 600 pounds of heroin. All the convicts have the right to appeal the sentence within 40 days. <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> has in recent weeks launched a nationwide anti-drug campaign.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0003EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r e PM-APArts:OperaBastille     06-13 1014</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Opera Bastille,1039</SECOND>
<HEAD>Opera Bastille: High Tech Musical Complex</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARILYN AUGUST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The countdown has begun at the Opera Bastille. Some 1,500 hard hats are working double shifts putting finishing touches on the gleaming glass and steel structure scheduled to open July 13 as the French mark the bicentennial of their revolution. French opera buffs hope the high-tech musical complex _ built on the square where revolutionaries stormed the Bastille prison on July 14, 1789 _ will finally put <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> on the international music map. For the moment, doubts remain. The new Opera had been leaderless since last January when <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> conductor <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Barenboim </PERSON> was fired because of what President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>'s representative said were his high fees and `` elitist views'' on opera. <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Berge </PERSON>, the head of the <ORGANIZATION> Yves </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Saint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laurent </ORGANIZATION> fashion empire and the man <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> appointed to manage the project in its final days, said <PERSON> Barenboim </PERSON>'s replacement would be someone who understood the president's wish to create a `` modern and popular opera'' accessible to the masses. Five months of speculation and uncertainty ended last month when that someone turned out to be <PERSON> Myung-Whung </PERSON> <PERSON> Chung </PERSON>, a 36-year-old Korean conductor known for his skills as a pianist. Soft-spoken and unemotional, the new music director said he would be a team player eager to work `` in harmony and unison'' with Opera Bastille administrators. Warning he would not get entangled in the political infighting that has beset the project from the start, he said, `` If there is a fight, and I'll say it publicly right now, I wo n't fight. I'll just leave.'' Although <PERSON> Berge </PERSON> declined to divulge <PERSON> Chung </PERSON>'s salary, he said his five-year contract requires the maestro be in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> for 27 weeks a year for a minimum of 30 performances, <PERSON> Chung </PERSON> also let it be known he has his own ideas on `` popular opera.'' `` Popular means the house is full and people are dying to get in,'' he said in an interview. `` I'd like to broaden the opera-going public and see more young people and students in the audience.'' Meanwhile, workers are busy getting ready for the inaugural concert, billed originally as the centerpiece of official bicentennial celebrations to be performed before <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>, President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and other luminaries. French conductor <PERSON> Georges </PERSON> <PERSON> Pretre </PERSON> will conduct the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> Opera Ballet Orchestra and Chorus, with a host of international celebrities performing selected arias from well-known French operas. The concert will be staged by <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> director <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, the longtime darling of the French avant-garde. The Opera-Bastille's first bona fide operatic production is scheduled for next February. Although <PERSON> Chung </PERSON> did not reveal the program, the real star of the show is sure to be the building itself. The new Opera is a hulking mass of polished granite, glass and stainless steel designed by Canadian architect <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Ott </PERSON>. Critics compare it to an ocean liner in dry dock, looming over the <LOCATION> Place </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> la </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bastille </LOCATION> in eastern <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. The prison was torn down during the revolution. A technical wonder, the Opera Bastille is everything the ornate, century-old <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> Opera is not. The Palais <PERSON> Garnier </PERSON> may be a landmark known worldwide for its baroque design and Chagall-decorated ceiling, but it has been inadequate for decades. The old Opera has a scant 1,600 seats with unobstructed views and virtually no backstage, which meant that sets had to be built elsewhere, dismantled, brought in and reconstructed. The cost was staggering, and so were ticket prices. Tickets to the new Opera Bastille are expected to cost a maximun of 250 francs -LRB- about $ 40 -RRB-, less than half their cost at the Palais <PERSON> Garnier </PERSON>, which from now on will be devoted to ballet. The Opera Bastille has 12 stages in all, including a main stage flagged by five stages and an adjoining rehearsal stage identical to the main stage, plus five identical stages one level below. All are fitted with freight elevators, electronically controlled and motorized wagons on conveyor tracks so that sets for an entire opera can be moved from rehearsal stages to the main stage within 10 minutes. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dittmann </PERSON>, the scenic director who drew up the technical specifications, calls the Opera Bastille `` practical, not sophisticated.'' `` Sophisticated means complicated, and this building is n't complicated,'' he said during a tour of the building `` It's very simple. It's a place where you have a lot of space. Here we do n't have the daily problem of where to put our decor in between performances. The main stage offers 4,300 square feet of space and is 66 feet high. It is equipped with 9 elevators, 72 traps and a movable orchestra pit that can be open or closed in two to three minutes. A bridge over the main and backstages allows stage hands to load the ceiling with carpets, curtains and other decor without monopolizing the stage. The ceiling is also designed for storage, thus economizing two hours a day when productions alternate. There is ample space for costumes, workshops and storage areas, connected directly to the main stage. The Opera Bastille is a musician's dream with rehearsal rooms galore _ three for the orchestra, two for ballet, two for the chorus, 16 studios for singers and 12 for musicians. While backstage areas are still dusty construction sites, the main hall itself is nearly ready. On a recent visit, workmen were busy polishing granite pillars, washing windows, waxing hardwood floors and installing cushions. Despite a glass ceiling and a cold color scheme in white, black and gray, the atmosphere is pleasant and intimate, aided, in part, to wooden walls and two tiers of graceful balconies reminiscent of Japanese pagodas. <PERSON> Dittmann </PERSON> says the hall's computer-analyzed acoustics are excellent. Even the hall's chairs have been designed with acoustics in mind: There are small holes which allow the sound to pass through when they are empty. A polystyrene joint under the building absorbs vibrations from the three metro lines that intersect under the Place de la Bastille. `` If that is n't enough, the subway cars themselves will be fitted with special rubber tires,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MedicineBehindBarsII     06-13 1221</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Medicine Behind Bars II,1255</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Death Row: AIDS Is Explosive Prison Health Issue</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITORS' NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Take a population rejected by society for its misdeeds. Then look the other way when a killer virus takes hold and the afflicted complain about cruel treatment and deficient medical care. That's the impact of AIDS in prison. `` Prisoners are regarded as ... people who do n't matter. It's a double stigma for inmates with AIDS,'' said <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Fruedenberg </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> expert on AIDS counseling and education. The second story in a three-part AP Extra series, `` Medicine Behind Bars,'' addresses care and treatment of inmates with AIDS.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>By ROBERT DVORCHAK</NOTE>
<NOTE>AP National Writer</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WETUMPKA, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, isolated with other female <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> prisoners carrying the AIDS virus, feared she would bleed to death in her cell. Stitches from routine uterine surgery had torn open, but nurses on three shifts failed to answer her pleas for help in November 1987, she said. `` They was afraid of the blood. They was afraid of catching the virus. They had a fear of the word AIDS,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, who waited 12 hours before she was taken to a hospital near <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>. `` You're treated like an alien, like you had the plague,'' she said. `` I got sentenced for manslaughter. The judge could have just as well sentenced me to death row. It's like being punished for my crime and my diagnosis.'' Behind prison walls, AIDS is a crackling health issue. Some states isolate inmates who have the virus even if they have n't developed symptoms. Those in segregation consider it cruel confinement to a new death row. Prison officials defend it as a way to contain the virus and protect those infected from harm. While arguments can be made for segregation, nothing excuses the failure to provide medical care, inmates' advocates say. Yet prisons are n't equipped to treat the long-term debilitating illnesses wrought by AIDS. `` Those on the new death row are not getting appropriate medical attention. They are being condemned to waste away,'' said <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Schatz </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> AIDS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Project </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advocates </ORGANIZATION>. `` They are treated as if infection indicates they have done something wrong.'' `` AIDS has made the job of providing prison health care more difficult, more hazardous and more expensive,'' said <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON> <PERSON> Prout </PERSON>, director of the internship program at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. Acquired immune deficiency syndrome is most commonly transmitted during homosexual acts and the sharing of contaminated needles while injecting drugs, two behaviors common among prisoners. In the most recent count last October, 3,136 AIDS cases had been diagnosed among the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> prison population of more than 627,000, according to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>. AIDS in prison increased 60 percent last year, as against a 76 percent jump in the general population, which can pursue high-risk behaviors more freely. <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> and five other states _ <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> _ segregate prisoners who carry the HIV virus that causes AIDS, whether or not they have the disease. Prisoners with full-blown AIDS are segregated in 20 other states, and 14 states test or will soon start testing all incoming inmates for the disease. Federal prisons randomly test 10 percent of incoming inmates and all those leaving the system. Those with AIDS or the virus are not isolated. Mandatory mass screening and segregation of all HIV-positive inmates is opposed by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION>, which sets voluntary standards for health care in prisons. It favors solutions such as education and changing behaviors that cause AIDS. <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> inmates who tested positive to the AIDS virus have charged in a class action lawsuit that they receive poor medical care and cruel treatment. The federal trial began in March. Suits are pending in two other states that segregate. Inmates with AIDS in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> say their medical care is grossly inadequate. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> prisoners assert that the level of their medical and psychiatric care is `` atrocious.'' `` They're treated like lepers. They might as well be wearing a scarlet letter. They're shunned, ostracized and stigmatized,'' said <PERSON> Alexa </PERSON> <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON>, an attorney with the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, which filed the <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> suit. `` There is no logic, no rational basis and no medical basis to the -LRB- segregation -RRB- policy,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, former medical director at <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Rikers </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prison </LOCATION> and an expert medical witness. `` It is only fear and discrimination which gives rise to such barbarous actions.'' Of the 12,000 inmates in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, 138 have tested positive for HIV since 1987. All but eight are men. Men are segregated at the Limestone Correctional Facility inside Dorm 7, where even the exercise yard is cut off from the main yard by a 14-foot-high chain-link fence topped with razor wire. The sense of doom is so heavy that inmates call it Thunder Dorm, recalling the futuristic city in `` Mad Max Beyond Thunderdome,'' a movie about society's collapse after a nuclear holocaust. Inmates eat with wooden ice cream sticks instead of forks and spoons. Meals come on color-coded trays. Their dirty laundry goes out in red plastic bags so it is washed separately. They worship apart from other inmates and do n't have equal access to programs that would allow them to have jobs or earn early parole. One inmate with the virus was forced to mop the halls behind him as he walked. Others were given surgical masks and made to clean telephones with bleach or ammonia swabs after making calls. `` The same hysteria on the streets is multiplied in prison,'' said <PERSON> Alvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bronstein </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Marsh </PERSON>, 41, a thief, said life in Thunder Dorm features fights, knifings and high-risk sex among prisoners who figure they're going to die anyway. `` Guys would rather be killed here than die from AIDS. They hunger for death another way. Any other way. Something that would be honorable,'' <PERSON> Marsh </PERSON> said. `` It's like living in the valley of the shadow of death. If AIDS do n't kill you, one of the guys might.'' Some inmates want to keep the HIV prisoners isolated, saying those infected would be killed `` as soon as they got into the yard.'' `` It's either we take them out or they take us out,'' said <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughey </PERSON>, 28, a rapist, who testified in favor of segregation in the <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> case. `` If one of them gets his semen or blood on an open cut, they just signed your death warrant.'' In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> state </LOCATION>, where AIDS is the leading cause of death among inmates, medical care is deficient, according to an 18-month study released last year by the <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION>. Doctors were unfamiliar with AIDS treatment and detection, the study said. Since 1981, more than 500 prisoners have died of AIDS; in 25 percent of the cases, the disease was not diagnosed until an autopsy. Prisoners with AIDS also have an unusually low survival rate, the report said. Inmates from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> who got the disease from dirty needles had a mean survival rate of 159 days, half that of those in the outside community with similar backgrounds. `` AIDS and prison is proving to be a devastating combination,'' said <PERSON> Cathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Potler </PERSON>, author of the report. `` Imprisonment becomes a virtual death sentence.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEXT: Geriatric Inmates and Their Costly Health Problems</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0010EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CraisinControversy     06-13 0394</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Craisin Controversy,0405</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Wrinkle for Raisin Growers: Dried Cranberries Dubbed `Craisins'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANA KENNEDY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> raisin growers heard it through the grapevine that <ORGANIZATION> Ocean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Spray </ORGANIZATION> plans to market sweetened dried cranberries as `` Craisins,'' which they say capitalizes on the success of their dancing raisins campaign. `` Why do they call it a Craisin if it's a cranberry?'' said <PERSON> Clyde </PERSON> <PERSON> Nef </PERSON>, manager of the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Raisin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION>. `` The farmers are upset. We've spent millions of dollars in changing the image and promoting <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> raisins. This appears to be an effort to capitalize on business we've created.'' The Craisin, a registered trademark, will be introduced this summer in <ORGANIZATION> Ralston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Purina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'s Muesli cereal, which already contains raisins. It is red, slightly tart, and about the same size as a raisin. Ocean Spray, the Plymouth-based cooperative of cranberry growers in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, said it will be the first time cranberries will be used in cereal. The company hopes they are someday used in granola, cakes, muffins and other foods. Raisin growers, who have spent nearly $ 8 million this year on ads, have asked <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s attorney general to look into what they say is unfair use of the raisin name. `` We've spent millions of dollars building the raisin image up as a healthy, natural fruit of the sun. Now they put a ` c' in front of it and call it a Craisin,'' said <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Bedrosian </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Raisin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Fowler </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> `` We made it so popular, they just want to shirttail on our success.'' Ocean Spray spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawlor </PERSON> disputed the raisin growers' claims `` I do n't think there's any confusion here,'' he said Monday. `` It's very clear when you say Craisins are dried cranberries you're not getting a raisin We do n't feel it's unfair. We've taken out the trademark. It's been approved.'' Ocean Spray, which last year grossed $ 781 million from cranberry products, has steadily diversified over the years. Some raisin growers are convinced the Craisin wo n't prove to be much competition. Raisins, they pointed out, are merely grapes dried in the sun, while Craisins must be infused with sugar to make them palatable. `` It's just the skin of the cranberry, sugar infused, and it's very tart,'' said <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Penner </PERSON>, vice chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Raisin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0019EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Gorbachev-Euphoria     06-13 0658</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gorbachev-Euphoria,0679</SECOND>
<HEAD>Giddy Over Gorbachev: Soviet Leader Charms West Germany</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN COSTELLOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FRANKFURT, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 He hugs a high school student as cameras click away. A major newspaper trumpets his `` erotic aura.'' His advance man hobnobs with `` <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Vice'' heartthrob <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> on live television. Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> brought his entourage and his charisma into <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> on Monday, arriving amid enough hoopla for a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Super Bowl or, more appropriately, a World Cup soccer final. He also brought his penchant for pressing the flesh at unexpected times. After a state banquet <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> bounced from his limousine and started shaking hands in a crowd of well-wishers along his route to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Embassy </LOCATION>. He was cheered with chants of `` <LOCATION> Gorby </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Gorby </LOCATION>!'' The response to his first-ever visit here has so far overshadowed the reception President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> received when he visited <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> two weeks ago. The two main TV networks have led the way, flooding the airwaves with hours of shows and documentaries that include everything from interviews with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s school teachers to a German-Russian songfest. On Saturday night, the Soviet government's top spokesman appeared on the hit TV show `` Wetten, <PERSON> Dass </PERSON>,'' a live potpourri mixing daredevil stunts, celebrity chatter and song numbers. `` We should exchange jokes and not rockets,'' said <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON>, drawing wild applause and cheers from the audience in an auditorium in the Ruhr industrial city of <LOCATION> Dortmund </LOCATION>. `` We want to be friends with your country.'' The smiling <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON>, who arrived in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> last week to put final touches on the trip preparations, also listened attentively when actor <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> joined the celebrities. `` We're in the same boat,'' <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said, shaking <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON>'s hand as he noted that neither speaks German <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, enjoying an improved East-West climate, is looking to West German investment and know-how to help ease a growing economic woes at home. Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s government especially wants <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s help in mending the split that divided <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> into two nations after World War II. The changed climate between the old foes was obvious after <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s arrival on Monday at the <ORGANIZATION> Villa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hammerschmidt </ORGANIZATION>, official residence of West German President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON>. Smiling and relaxed, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> mingled with invited guests, some of them ordinary West Germans. They included a group from the <PERSON> Heinrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Heine </PERSON> classical high school in <LOCATION> Dortmund </LOCATION>. The Kremlin chief suddenly reached out and hugged Bielefeld high school student <PERSON> Annette </PERSON> <PERSON> Lang </PERSON>, who had greeted him and his wife, <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON>, in Russian. The young woman also gave <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> a West German pfennig and a Soviet kopeck to symbolize friendship. <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON> gently led <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> away from his enraptured fans. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> ZDF </ORGANIZATION> television network he had arrived with `` the best feelings'' toward <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Later, a wedge of motorcycle police led the Soviet leader's black limousine to <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s office. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> waved from the open car window to a crowd of about 100 people, some of whom had been standing in the afternoon sun for nearly an hour. According to a weekend poll conducted by <ORGANIZATION> ZDF </ORGANIZATION>, 90 percent of those contacted said they trusted <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and his politics of reform and disarmament. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s rating surpassed that of both <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who received a 58 percent approval rating, and <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, who only received 50 percent. `` He Has an Enormous Erotic Aura,'' gushed a headline in Monday's editions of the <ORGANIZATION> Bild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zeitung </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s most widely read newspaper The newspaper, run by the arch-conservative <PERSON> Springer </PERSON> publishing empire, added: `` The man who now fascinates Germans more than any other head of state in the world is arriving this morning.'' As <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> began his visit, red Soviet flags fluttered along stately <PERSON> Adenauer </PERSON> avenue, named after the iron-willed chancellor who guided the first years of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> after the havoc of World War II. <PERSON> Konrad </PERSON> <PERSON> Adenauer </PERSON> directed his nation toward the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. For this week at least, the nation's attention is definitely focused on the East.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Iran-Khomeini     06-13 0715</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Khomeini,0737</SECOND>
<HEAD>Khomeini's Grave Has Become a Shrine</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALEX EFTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TEHRAN, Iran (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A week after <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> was buried, his grave in a dusty field has become a golden-domed shrine to which hundreds of thousands of Iranians a day make a mass pilgrimage in the scorching heat. They travel from all over the country to keep night-long vigils and touch the temporary monument over the grave of the octogenarian patriarch of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s revolution, who is rapidly being elevated to the pantheon of Shiite Moslem saints. Many believe <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s blessing and protection are bestowed on anyone who touches the square monument, fashioned from metal shipping containers covered in green cloth and topped by the large golden dome. The containers are on metal pillars and a metal grille gilded with spray paint allows people to see the grave. Marble slabs around it, buried under flowers, make the temporary structure resemble the tombs of other Moslem holy men. `` The Imam is the greatest man in Iranian history,'' said a teacher, who identified himself only as <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> and struggled with his 6-year-old son through the mass of humanity around the shrine. Iranians call <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> `` imam,'' or spiritual leader. `` He led the people back to our original faith, away from the materialism of the West,'' the teacher said in fluent English. `` I brought the boy here so he can remember this great day.'' `` Tell the world how we loved the Imam,'' said a white-bearded old man. He rode on the shoulders of a young man, leading chants extolling <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> `` the idol smasher.'' Around him, women wailed `` <PERSON> O </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, our days will never be the same without you!'' The golden dome, sparkling in the sun by day and floodlighted by night, has become a beacon for followers of the fierce-eyed cleric whose fundamentalist Islamic revolution ended a 2,500-year-old monarchy. All roads lead to the compound, 500 yards square, beside the huge <LOCATION> Behesht </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zahra </LOCATION> cemetery 10 miles south of <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> was buried there last Tuesday, three days after his death, to the accompaniment of hysterical anguish by 2 million Iranians. Shiite Moslem zealots, most of them poor people who saw <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> as their savior, struggle for hours through the crowds to reach the shrine. Officials estimate more than a half million people visit the grave every day. Toothless old men from the <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> slums and cities as far away as <LOCATION> Isfahan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mashhad </LOCATION> and Shiraz mingle with women clad in black head-to-toe chadors, babies clutched in their arms. As the waves of mourners inch closer to the grave, men beat their heads and breasts with their hands, hoarsely chanting verses from the Koran, <ORGANIZATION> Islam </ORGANIZATION>'s holy book, and slogans of loyalty to <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s teachings Some flail themselves with steel chains as drums beat slowly, a traditional ritual during Ashura, the month of mourning for <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>, the first Shiite spiritual leader and founder of the sect. Fire engines spray water over the crowds to cool them in temperatures that reach 104 degrees Fahrenheit under a blazing sun. People arrive in unending thousands in packed buses and trucks, tractors towing trailers, in cars and on motorbikes. Water tankers are parked every few yards for the thirsty throngs. Free iced lemonade and canned soft drinks are provided. Visitors to the grave must walk two miles through open fields under a thick cloud of choking dust raised by the constant traffic. The last half-mile to the square compound marked off by 10-foot-shipping containers is a nightmare of shoving and jostling. Revolutionary Guards in black uniforms herd women to one side of the compound, to keep them away from the men. They wail in mourning, their shrill lamentations drowning out the men's chants. Prayers chanted by mullahs, or Moslem clerics, blare from loudspeakers and blend with the wailing and chants into a numbing wall of sound. State radio and TV broadcast reports from the teeming scene almost every hour. Vast crowds pressed into the area the first days after the funeral, but no one was allowed to visit the grave until Friday, after the compound had been enlarged and the temporary monument erected. Authorities have begun a fund-raising campaign to finance a permanent monument. Money began pouring in as soon as it was announced.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0031EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Suppression     06-13 0655</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Suppression,0674</SECOND>
<HEAD>Is China Turning Back The Clock?</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-China, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s current leaders, once victims of the Cultural Revolution, are raising fears that they may be ushering in a new period of political chaos with their own crackdown on dissent. Many Chinese say they find strong similarities between the crushing of the pro-democracy movement and the leftist ideological purges of 1966-76, when thousands were suppressed by a campaign of propaganda, arrests and executions. The government of <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>, who was imprisoned twice during the Cultural Revolution, had pledged that there would never be a return to the rhetoric and radicalism of the past. But his government, as part of a propaganda campaign to discredit the protesters, has revived language not heard for more than a decade. Phrases such as `` counterrevolutionaries'' and `` a small band of schemers'' are reappearing in government announcements. The government is again making stinging criticisms of foreign governments and media. The <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, the broadcasts of which have been jammed recently, has come in for especially tough treatment for its coverage of the army's violent crackdown in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. Already, many Chinese are refusing to meet with foreign reporters as a climate of fear spreads in the capital. The military, which had withdrawn from an active involvement in the country's politics, again is playing a critical role. During the Cultural Revolution, the military intervened often to restore order caused by political conflicts. With the military's crucial assistance, the government is trying to round up the organizers of the democratic movement. During the Cultural Revolution, <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> was branded one of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s main `` capitalist roaders. Now he is using the techniques of his one-time accusers to fight the pro-democracy activists. The first volley came in April with the publication of an editorial that called the student movement `` chaotic turmoil'' and urged the suppression of its leadership, described as a `` small band of schemers.'' Chinese sources said the editorial was written on <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s command. `` It was as if I went back to the'70s,'' said an East European diplomat, who did his first tour of duty in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> in the 1970s. `` The use of terms like ` small band of schemers' and warning about ` chaotic turmoil' are a return to the thinking of the Cultural Revolution. In the space of a month, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> went back 10 years in time.'' In May, the government organized its own demonstrations to counter the pro-democracy protests being held in <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>. Workers in state offices were threatened with fines if they did n't attend, another throwback to Cultural Revolution-era practices Those who did attend were rewarded with bread and eggs. At one government rally, an effigy of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s most-famous dissident, <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> <PERSON> Lizhi </PERSON>, was burned. `` The government doing that is like something like 20 years ago -LRB- when -RRB- <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse-tung </PERSON> sent out the Red Guard. That is dangerous,'' said <PERSON> Fang </PERSON>, who has since taken refuge in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. On June 3, the government took another page from its past when it used violence to clear <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, home to thousands of students and their protest for freedom. On April 5, 1976, when hundreds of thousands had gathered to commemorate the death of Premier <PERSON> Chou </PERSON> <PERSON> En-lai </PERSON>, the police were called out to empty the square with sticks and clubs. Many died in the police onslaught. Another similarity is that Chinese have been encouraged to inform on those who took part in the protests. In a modern twist, telephone numbers of reporting stations were published in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> newspapers. One man, identified as a `` rumor monger,'' was reportedly turned in two hours after his picture was broadcast on television. A main difference between the techniques of the Cultural Revolution and today's struggle is that the current campaign has yet to extend throughout the nation. One week into the crackdown, there are fears the worst has yet to come.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Panama 1stLd-Writethru a0696 06-13 0497</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0696,0509</SECOND>
<HEAD>OAS Mission Meets With Opposition, Government Officials</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 10 grafs to UPDATE with Solis Palma meeting Noriega
after talks with OAS mission. Pickup 4th pvs, ``Joao Baena ...''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALINA GUERRERO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Acting President <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON> met with military strongman Gen. <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> Monday after he conferred with an <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> mission trying to mediate <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s election deadlock. On its second trip to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, the Organization of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> mission met separately Monday with <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON> and opposition party members. Immediatedly after his one-hour meeting with <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> officials <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON> met for another hour with <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. The general was seen entering the governmental palace in civilian clothing with <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Duque </PERSON>, the government's candidate in the May election that was annulled. Panamanian Foreign Minister <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Ritter </PERSON> told reporters later that Panamanian officials and the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> representatives were trying to find `` an acceptable formula'' for a dialogue between the government and opposition. `` This mechanism even though it obviously does n't exist yet.. this is what we are searching for,'' <PERSON> Ritter </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> did not speak with reporters. One OAS delegate, Ecuadorean Foreign Minister <PERSON> Diego </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON>, said earlier he is confident the government and opposition have the political will to settle their differences. He said it is up to the Panamanians to resolve the dispute. The OAS only can `` promote a dialogue and perhaps give ideas based on our national experience based on similar situation,'' he said. <PERSON> Joao </PERSON> <PERSON> Baena </PERSON> <PERSON> Soares </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> secretary-general, and the foreign ministers of <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> and </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tobago </LOCATION> are the other members of the mission. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s political crisis began with the May 7 election, which international observers said the opposition won by at least a 2-1 margin. The government controlled by <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> annulled the election and opposition candidates were attacked and beaten by his supporters. The <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> then agreed to send the mission to negotiate a national dialogue on the transfer of power on Sept. 1, as required by the constitution. On their first visit to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> at the end of May, the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> diplomats could not persuade the opposition and government to hold direct talks. Opposition leaders said they would talk only with <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, and he refused. <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> official who negotiated the Soviet withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, was optimistic Monday. `` I think there is a political will in the government and the opposition that has to be translated into specific steps,'' he said. `` It seems to me that it is most urgent to establish mechanisms that allow Panamanians to talk and negotiate.'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and government officials blame <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s problems on the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which they say wants to renege on 1977 treaties that turn over the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> at the end of the century. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, commander of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>, was indicted on drug trafficking charges last year in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He denies the charges and has refused <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> demands he resign.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0009EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MissingPlane 2ndLd-Writethru a0698 06-13 0596</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Missing Plane, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0698,0606</SECOND>
<HEAD>Search Continues for Missing Hawaii Tour Plane With 11 Aboard</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 6 grafs to UPDATE with emergency signal detected,
details. Picks up 3rd graf pvs, `A Coast...'</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 SUBS grafs 8, ` The sky ...,' to end to edit to conform, ADD that most aboard were Americans.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By STEVE ELLIOTT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A sightseeing plane that vanished between the islands of <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Maui </LOCATION> with 11 people aboard may have sent out an emergency signal Monday, but foul weather prevented rescuers from searching for it. `` There's an emergency signal coming from valley and we think it could be the plane,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Spangler </PERSON>. `` But the weather's so bad helicopters ca n't go in, and otherwise it's about a 10-hour hike.'' A <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> helicopter picked up the emergency transmitter's signal from the remote <LOCATION> Waimanu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> region of the island, which is on the northwest end of the island and within the missing plane's flight path, <PERSON> Spangler </PERSON> The valley had no vehicular access, he said, adding that no decision had been made whether to dispatch searchers to hike in. `` We're getting all our information together and seeing if the weather will let up,'' <PERSON> Spangler </PERSON> said. Heavy rain and low clouds persisted in the area Monday. The Scenic Air Tours Hawaii plane disappeared Sunday on what was to be have been an hour-long flight. A <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> cutter, <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> helicopter and seven <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> planes searched 1,279 square miles of ocean, said <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartvigsen </PERSON>. Police on <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Maui </LOCATION> islands also checked areas where tour aircraft fly, he said. Air strips also were checked in case the pilot landed without informing the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>. The twin-engine Beechcraft carrying a pilot and 10 tourists had left <LOCATION> Hilo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> Kahului </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> and headed up <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>'s coast under partly sunny skies, disappearing without any indication of trouble, officials said The plane's last reported position according to <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> radar was about 10 miles north of <LOCATION> Hilo </LOCATION>, flying along <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>'s northeast coast, <PERSON> Hartvigsen </PERSON> said. Its altitude at that point was not known, <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> said investigators suspect that if the plane went down it is in the area of that last radar fix, because it was passing out of radar coverage and if it had gone further it likely would have been picked up by another radar station. The sky over the area was partly sunny with low scattered clouds, no rain and 15 to 20 mph wind at the time the plane disappeared, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. The plane took off about 1:15 p.m. and was to have landed at <LOCATION> Kahului </LOCATION> at 2:30 p.m., officials said. Alenuihaha Channel, which the plane would have had to cross to get to <LOCATION> Maui </LOCATION>, had 5 - to 6-foot seas at the time The last communication with the pilot was when he radioed an <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> ground station that he had taken off from <LOCATION> Hilo </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> Maui </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> said. The plane was on a six-island tour, said company owner <PERSON> Doris </PERSON> <PERSON> Tom </PERSON>. The passengers had taken a ground tour of the erupting <LOCATION> Kilauea </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Volcano </LOCATION> before leaving <LOCATION> Hilo </LOCATION>, she said. Most of those aboard are Americans and two are from <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, but the names are not being released because not all the families have been notified, said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Tom </PERSON>, the operations manager for the tour company. In 1987, a twin-engine <ORGANIZATION> Panorama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tours </ORGANIZATION> plane with eight people aboard disappeared without a trace on a flight from <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Molokai </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0056EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ArtSting     06-13 0573</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Art Sting,0586</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stolen Art Recovered Through FBI Sting</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> art dealers set up a sting with the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> that led to the recovery of nine Old Master paintings stolen from a <LOCATION> Swiss </LOCATION> art gallery and three arrests, according to a televised report. The nine paintings, worth more than $ 5 million, were stolen along with 12 other Old Masters on April 12 from the Koster Gallery in <LOCATION> Zurich </LOCATION> by three men who tied up a gallery employee at gunpoint, <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> Agent <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Pickard </PERSON> told the Art Market Report, a weekly <ORGANIZATION> Financial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> program that aired Monday night. The theft and arrests were disclosed for the first time on the cable television station. Swiss police did not announce the theft, hoping the robbers would try to sell the paintings if it was not publicized that they were stolen, said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Schillay </PERSON>, one of the three art dealers who run a gallery in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>. A week after the theft, a man called Schillay from <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and told him he had an important collection he wanted to sell in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Schillay </PERSON> and his partners at the <ORGANIZATION> Schillay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Rehs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> gallery, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> and <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Rehs </PERSON>, became suspicious when the man could not explain why he wanted to sell the paintings here and not in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. The man also `` went through a whole grandiose story about how important his family was. ... In our dealings here in the gallery, we meet a number of people of wealth and virtually none of them present themselves in this manner,'' said <PERSON> Schillay </PERSON>. The man also could not answer questions about the condition of the paintings, estimated the worth of one painting at $ 500,000 when it was actually worth $ 1.5 million, and made no inquiries about the gallery's background, as is customary for sellers to do, the dealers said. A man who claimed to be the seller's son brought the paintings to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and later the seller came too. Schillay & amp; <PERSON> Rehs </PERSON> had several experts examine the paintings, and they were found to be genuine Old Masters. Eventually, <PERSON> Schillay </PERSON> came across an expert who had heard of a theft of Old Masters from a Koster Gallery. The tip led Schillay to contact a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> dealer who often invests in works at the <LOCATION> Koster </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> man confirmed that the paintings were stolen. Schillay & amp; <PERSON> Rehs </PERSON> then called the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>. On May 1, two <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents posing as employees of <ORGANIZATION> Schillay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Rehs </PERSON> arrested the seller, <PERSON> Rene </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Grove </PERSON>; <PERSON> Thierry </PERSON> <PERSON> Houze </PERSON>, the man who had posed as his son; and a woman, <PERSON> Martine </PERSON> <PERSON> Wins </PERSON>, according to <PERSON> Schillay </PERSON>. <PERSON> Pickard </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent who set up the sting, said the trio were being held without bail in the <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, awaiting indictment on charges of possession of stolen goods and bringing stolen goods into the country. One of the gunmen in the heist is still at large, <PERSON> Schillay </PERSON> said. The other 12 paintings stolen in <LOCATION> Zurich </LOCATION> were not recovered, but <PERSON> Schillay </PERSON> said <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Grove </PERSON> was negotiating turning them over in exchange for being transferred to a Swiss prison. The paintings recovered were still-lifes, landscapes, portraits and other 17th - and 18th-century Dutch and French paintings, most of them 7 by 9 inches or smaller, by the following artists: <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Heem </PERSON>, <PERSON> Marten </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryckaert </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Meartens </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Steen </PERSON>, <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Moillou </PERSON>, <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Reysdael </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Hals </PERSON>, <PERSON> Adrien </PERSON> <PERSON> Coorte </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cornelius </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Heem </PERSON>, <PERSON> Schillay </PERSON> said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0020EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Newspage-Leonard-Hearns     06-13 0213</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Newspage-Leonard-Hearns,0219</SECOND>
<HEAD>Leonard, Hearns Battle to Draw</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sugar </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> and <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hearns </PERSON>, calling on skills many supposed they no longer had, battled to a 12-round draw Monday night at <ORGANIZATION> Caesars </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palace </ORGANIZATION>, almost eight years after their first fight. <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON>, knocked down in both the third and 11th rounds, probably earned the draw with a dsperation rally in the final two minutes of the final round that had <PERSON> Hearns </PERSON> holding on. <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> went down from a right to the side of the head in the third round and three straight rights to the head put him down in the 11th. <PERSON> Hearns </PERSON> was never dropped but was on wobbly legs several times and was cut on the left cheek. Judge <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> scored it 113-112 for <PERSON> Hearns </PERSON> and there were loud cheers from a crowd of over 15,000. <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaczmarek </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> scored it 113-112 for <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> and there were some boos. Judge <PERSON> Dalby </PERSON> <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> scored it 112-112 and <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> kept the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boxing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> super middleweight title on the draw. Neither man appeared to be the fighter he was on Sept. 16, 1981, when <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> won the undisputed welterweight title by stopping <PERSON> Hearns </PERSON> in the 14th round of a great fight.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0026EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-GrayStatement     06-13 0364</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gray Statement,1st Ld-Writethru,a0405,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Justice Says Pennsylvania Congressman Not a Target</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: ADDS 3 grafs after last graf pvs with Gray statement, aide's
account of Justice Department's reasons for releasing its statement</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said for the first time Monday night that Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, D-Pa., is not the target of a criminal investigation The department statement backed up what <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> and his lawyer said they have been told by <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents ever since word leaked out last month that <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> had been visited by two <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents on Memorial Day. The department's statement came less than two days before a vote in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION> for the post of majority whip, the third-ranking leadership position among Democrats. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> is contending with two others for the job. `` Congressman <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> is not the target of a criminal investigation by the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>. Congressman <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> and his office have been fully cooperating with the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>,'' said a statement read by spokesman <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Eramian </PERSON>. The spokesman said Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> had authorized his executive assistant, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, to make the statement. <PERSON> Eramian </PERSON> declined to answer questions on why the statement was issued Monday night. Government sources, speaking earlier on condition that they not be identified, said the department had opened a preliminary investigation into whether <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> had a `` no-show'' employee on his staff. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> said from the outset he knew of no such employees, and members of his staff have said since that they had found no evidence of one. In a statement issued Monday after the department's, <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> said: `` I have said from the beginning that I am not a target and this confirms it. I have said from the beginning that I and my staff have cooperated full and this confirms it. I have done nothing wrong and this too will be confirmed.'' <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Plebani </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>'s chief of staff, said he had been told that the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> decided to issue the statement because reports about the investigation of <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>'s office `` have done Congressman Gray a serious disservice and have inappropriately been a factor'' in the Whip contest.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Quine     06-13 0306</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Quine,0314</SECOND>
<HEAD>Film Director Richard Quine Commits Suicide</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Quine </PERSON>, who directed <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Lemmon </PERSON> in a variety of oddball comedies including `` How to Murder Your Wife,'' committed suicide by shooting himself in the head, police said Monday. He was 68. <PERSON> Quine </PERSON> died Saturday night at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said Sgt. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schlotthauer </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Division station. He said that <PERSON> Quine </PERSON> had been despondent for years over poor health. An actor's son, <PERSON> Quine </PERSON> was born Nov. 12, 1920 in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich </LOCATION>. The vaudeville performer made his movie debut when he was 12. As an actor, his work was confined to supporting roles in films such as <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Eyre </PERSON> in 1934 and `` Command Decision'' with <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Gable </PERSON> in 1948. He made the transition to directing. He directed movies including `` Rainbow ` Round My Shoulder,'' which he also co-wrote, in 1952; did the 1954 remake of `` So This Is <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>'' starring <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gloria </PERSON> <PERSON> DeHaven </PERSON>; the 1965 film `` The Solid Gold Cadillac,'' narrated by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>; and the 1964 comedy `` Sex and the Single Girl,'' with a cast that included <PERSON> Natalie </PERSON> <PERSON> Wood </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lauren </PERSON> <PERSON> Bacall </PERSON> and <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Holden </PERSON> starred in <PERSON> Quine </PERSON>'s 1960 film, `` The World of <PERSON> Suzie </PERSON> <PERSON> Wong </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Quine </PERSON> became a journeyman at comedy direction, working with <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Novak </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lemmon </PERSON> in 1958's `` Bell, Book and Candle,'' from a successful Broadway play about a New Yorker who discovers he's in love with the witch in the apartment next door. In 1959, he directed <PERSON> Lemmon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Doris </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON> in `` It Happened to <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>.'' He also directed <PERSON> Ernie </PERSON> <PERSON> Kovacs </PERSON> with <PERSON> Lemmon </PERSON> in the 1957 comedy `` Operation Mad Ball'' and went on to work with <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Novak </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kovacs </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> in `` Strangers When We Meet,'' a sultry melodrama about changing mores in the postwar suburbs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     06-13 0960</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1004</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Olympic ice skater <PERSON> Tai </PERSON> <PERSON> Babilonia </PERSON> says she is ready to return to the rink, nine months after a suicide attempt during a time she `` hit rock bottom.'' Miss <PERSON> Babilonia </PERSON> posed with her skating partner <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> in Times Square on Monday to announce their professional return Wednesday at a show in <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> `` I'm excited about being back with my partner andscared to death about performing again,'' said <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Babilonia </PERSON>. `` But it was my decision to come back. I missed it.'' Nine months ago, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Babilonia </PERSON>, 29, tried to kill herself by taking an overdose of sleeping pills. Miss <PERSON> Babilonia </PERSON>, who has been skating since she was 7 years old, said she was `` burnt out'' on skating. `` I had taken on too much, more work than I can handle, and that just sort of caught up with me,'' she said. Miss <PERSON> Babilonia </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> won the world figure skating title in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, in 1979. The pair had to drop out of the 1980 Olympic Winter Games in <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Placid </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, when <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> suffered a leg injury.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 People who wish they were skinny might want to talk to actress <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernhard </PERSON>. `` Emaciation is n't all that it's cracked up to be,'' said the lanky comedian in the July issue of Mademoiselle magazine. Over the years, she says, people have called her `` spaghetti-legs,'' `` bony maroney,'' `` anorexic freak'' and `` will o' the wisp.'' `` I've been skinny for so long now, sometimes I'm known simply as ` the bone woman,''' she says. `` Hordes of compulsive dieters constantly mill about me.'' Many ask how she does it. `` It's just the way I am; I eat and my metabolism knocks it out,'' <PERSON> Bernhard </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WICHITA, Kan. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pop superstar <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> will be getting a new addition to his menagerie of animals this week when he receives a baby giraffe. <ORGANIZATION> Sedgwick </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zoo </ORGANIZATION> officials said Monday a 1-year-old giraffe named <PERSON> Mahali </PERSON> was set to leave Wednesday for <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, where an animal dealer will deliver her to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. Zookeeper <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Gulker </PERSON> said she is n't a typical giraffe, which may suit <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> just fine because she's on the shy side. `` She's not as outgoing as some of the other giraffes that we've had,'' <PERSON> Gulker </PERSON> said `` She seems to be a little bit more to herself.'' Zoo officials would not disclose <PERSON> Mahali </PERSON>'s price, but said female giraffes normally run about $ 15,000.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Brenner </PERSON> likes a little bubbly with his billiards so he's planning to open a pool hall that will serve champagne and boutique beer. <PERSON> Brenner </PERSON> said the chain of billiards rooms, bearing his name, also will have a dress code. He plans to make appearances, now and then, he said. `` Some people have old-fashioned connotations of 1950s poolrooms,'' he said. `` But this is going to be the social meeting place for yuppies.'' If he did n't mean it, he said, `` I would have just called it the Benjamin Franklin Billiards Room. Or the Liberty Bell Pool Hall.'' <PERSON> Brenner </PERSON>, who grew up in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> and lives in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, said he hopes to open the first parlor by October in the historic Society Hill section.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>STAUNTON, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Country music singer <PERSON> Ricky </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON> canceled his appearance with the <ORGANIZATION> Statler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> at an annual Fourth of July concert because a cover could not be rigged for the stage, the entertainers said. The <ORGANIZATION> Statler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> said Monday that <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON> `` made elaborate and expensive demands that we are not willing to provide'' for the 20th Happy Birthday USA Celebration. <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON> said in a statement he canceled because of a personal policy not to accept any bookings that did not provide a cover for the stage. `` Mr. <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON> believes that he can not deliver the caliber performance his fans expect of him in a rain downpour or with an extreme sun beating down on him,'' the statement said. Earlier this year, <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON> won male vocalist of the year, single of the year and favorite music video awards from the Music City News Country Awards. The <ORGANIZATION> Happy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Birthday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> U.S.A. </ORGANIZATION> committee, which runs the event, said a stage cover would interfere with an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> flag that is used in the <ORGANIZATION> Statler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION>' finale, <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON>'s statement said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sex appeal is in the eye of the beholder, says actress <PERSON> Meg </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>, who is getting used to being called sexy. `` There's just no one way to be sexy,'' she told <ORGANIZATION> Mademoiselle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION> in its July issue. `` There are many different means of attractiveness. Some people will respond to you and some wo n't.'' These days, actor <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Quaid </PERSON> is responding to her and she said she likes it. `` It's so precious to us. I do n't mind telling people we're in love'cause that's true,'' said <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>, who has appeared in `` Top Gun,'' `` Presidio,'' and `` When <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Met </PERSON> <PERSON> Sally </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Country music singer <PERSON> Tanya </PERSON> <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>, who is 8 -LCB- months pregnant, said she saved her friend from choking on food by performing the Heimlich maneuver. After attending a baby shower for her Sunday, Ms. <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON> and several friends went to a <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> area restaurant. During their meal, <PERSON> Rosemarie </PERSON> <PERSON> Farone </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> started choking on food and began turning blue. `` We were eating steak,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>. `` All of a sudden she took a bite and -LRB- began coughing -RRB-. I asked her, `` Are you choking?'' Despite her pregnancy, Ms. <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON> reached her friend from behind and dislodge the food with a quick thrust to her abdomen. Ms. <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>, 30, said her brother, <PERSON> John </PERSON>, taught her the <PERSON> Heimlich </PERSON> maneuver after he used it to dislodge aspirin stuck in her throat prior to a concert performance several years ago.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lebanon-University     06-13 0754</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon-University,0781</SECOND>
<HEAD>American University, Schools Closed By Shelling ^An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RODEINA KENAAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fighting between Christian and Syrian forces has paralyzed the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>'s most prestigious academic institute, and much of the rest of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s educational system. But senior university officials are bent on reopening as soon as they can the seaside facility that has given the Arab world at least three presidents, 10 prime ministers and more than 100 Cabinet ministers and ambassadors. Acting President <PERSON> Ibrahim </PERSON> <PERSON> Salti </PERSON> contends the university will resume classes 48 hours after the latest round of fighting stops in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s 14-year-old civil war. Since fierce artillery battles broke out March 8, thirty-three shells from Christian east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> have hit the campus of the 123-year-old <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, causing damage estimated at $ 600,000. <PERSON> Salti </PERSON>, a Jordanian, insisted in an interview: `` AUB is still healthy despite its unhealthy environment.'' The university was founded in 1866 by <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Bliss </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> missionary from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. It was chartered under the laws of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> state. Classes were suspended March 23, one month into the final 1989 semester, when the artillery battles broke out. The campus drew Christian artillery fire after the Syrians set up gun positions near the university. Despite a shaky cease-fire declared by the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> on May 11, Syrian gunners, including those near the university, daily shell Christian ports to stop supplies reaching their foes. The only reported university casualty among the 363 people killed and more than 1,400 wounded was <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> <PERSON> Haddad </PERSON>, 60, a Lebanese librarian killed by shrapnel April 16 as she walked to the medical library. Many of the 80 red-roofed stone buildings around the 73-acre campus are pocked with shell splinters. Most of the 5,300 Arab, Asian and African students have gone. The medical school, with 268 students, remained functioning throughout the fighting. Its hospital, the largest in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> with 421 beds, treated 60 casualties an hour during the worst of the shelling. Students at the university and at other colleges who had hoped to graduate and head abroad to study in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and western <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> have been forced to take shelter in bunkers rather than take exams vital to careers. <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdel </PERSON> <PERSON> Samad </PERSON>, director of student affairs at the Education Ministry, said more than 200,000 students were unable to take final tests for their high school diploma because of the fighting. <PERSON> Abed </PERSON> <PERSON> el-Naser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arayissin </PERSON>, 26, a computer science student at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-affiliated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> hoping to study in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, hoped to finish school by the end of summer. `` But because of what's happened, I'll have to do another year making up for the one I've lost because of the civil war.'' In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> AUB </ORGANIZATION>'s American president, Dr. <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Herter </PERSON>, said recently: `` We're prepared to extend the current semester into the summer in order to complete all necessary academic requirements.'' No one is sure when the <ORGANIZATION> AUB </ORGANIZATION> will reopen. <PERSON> Herter </PERSON>, a 68-year-old surgeon, has not been to the university since he was named president in March 1987. <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> is off-limits for Americans because of the wave of assassinations and kidnappings that engulfed the university, the first to introduce American education into the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and a target for anti-Western Moslem fundamentalists. The university founder's grandson, <ORGANIZATION> AUB </ORGANIZATION> president <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodge </PERSON>, became the first of many kidnap victims in 1982. He appeared in <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Syrian </LOCATION> capital, a year later. His successor, <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON>, was assassinated by a gunman outside his office on Jan. 18, 1984. Soon after, the campus was swept by a wave of abductions. Among those kidnapped was <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> librarian <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Kilburn </PERSON>, seized Dec. 1, 1984, and political science professor <PERSON> Leigh </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, a Briton, kidnapped March 28, 1986. Their bodies, along with that of another kidnapped British educator, were found April 18, 1986, three days after <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> air raids on <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>. Two other kidnapped <ORGANIZATION> AUB </ORGANIZATION> officials _ acting dean of agriculture <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutherland </PERSON> and acting comptroller <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON> _ are among nine Americans still in captivity. Education Ministry officials say that if <ORGANIZATION> AUB </ORGANIZATION> stays closed, so will <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s 17 other universities in Moslem and Christian sectors and most of the country's 3,000 schools, which have a combined enrollment of more than 800,000. `` We ca n't run the risk of resuming classes under repeated shelling threats and have our students get killed on campus,'' said <PERSON> Elias </PERSON> <PERSON> Maroun </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> schools official. Schools and colleges in north and south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, untouched by the fighting, have remained open.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ZooSculptor Bjt   06-13 0596</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Zoo Sculptor, Bjt,595</SECOND>
<HEAD>Zoo Sculptor Takes Hints From Apes, Uses Spectators for Models</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Children, grownups, even the monkeys and apes stare up at sculptor <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Weitzman </PERSON> as he transforms a 28-foot tree stump at the National Zoo into a mirror of the exotic life around him. Using chainsaw, drill, mallets and chisels from his scaffolding, <PERSON> Weitzman </PERSON> is sculpting a tribute to zoo volunteers from the barren trunk of a nearly century-old willow oak that was chopped down last year because it was dying. He found the stump lying abandoned near a creek in the zoo. <PERSON> Weitzman </PERSON>, 36, a native of <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, who came to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> by way of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, has been working since last August to convert the trunk into a work of art honoring those who `` maintain our extended family _ the flora and fauna of the planet.'' He already has inhabited the upper reaches of the stump with a miniature zoo. Among the carved figures are a swooping American bald eagle, a scowling orangutan, a contented panda, great blue heron, water lizard, tree shrew, fish, squirrel and a giraffe nibbling greenery offered by the outstretched hand of a young man. `` Can you find the tree frog?'' <PERSON> Weitzman </PERSON> asks passersby. -LRB- It's crawling out of its hole just below the black palm cockatoo. Operating on a $ 20,000 commission from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zoo </ORGANIZATION> and its volunteer organization, Friends of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zoo </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Weitzman </PERSON> works almost daily _ except when it rains _ in the hope of finishing his sculpture by the end of October. His studio is a fenced-in plot on the sun-drenched lawn facing the zoo's reptile and monkey houses. The tourists swarming below are n't simply gawkers. <PERSON> Weitzman </PERSON> occasionally invites someone to mount the scaffolding to model an ear or nose for the human figure he is carving. Early on, <PERSON> Weitzman </PERSON> got some helpful kibitzing from a denizen of the zoo's nearby monkey island. `` I was trying to carve an eagle but the tree was saying, no, this wo n't work,'' he said. `` I wrestled with it for two or three days, cussing at myself, but it was not becoming an eagle. It just got worse and worse. `` Then I had the feeling something was watching me. I looked over my shoulder and there was a Barbary ape sitting over there with his hands on his knees, staring at me. So I forgot the eagle and carved him looking back at himself.'' With a friendly eyes and a smile as wide as his mustache, <PERSON> Weitzman </PERSON> encourages his spectators to step forward, grab a chisel and make their own artistic imprint. `` One of my aims is to dispel the illusion that artists are a unique branch of humanity, to show the public that creating a piece of art work is not beyond most people's ability,'' he said. `` People say, aw, you're so lucky. I wish I could carve like that. I say, come up here, confront your fears and I'll show you how to do it. `` Three hours later, they're still carving. They say, ` Wow, I can do it','' <PERSON> Weitzman </PERSON> says. `` It's all about pursuing your dreams. My dream is to do this sculpture out of a five-ton tree stump. Yours might be singing, dancing, writing, painting, crocheting. Everyone has something to communicate. What it takes is tenacity ... pursuing it with all of your heart. `` If you work your butt off, if you work really hard, you can do it. Maybe it wo n't be the best in the world, but so what?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-VaPrimary     06-13 0346</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Va Primary,0352</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Republicans Seek Gubernatorial Nomination</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Polls open at 6 a.m. EDT.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOE TAYLOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RICHMOND, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Virginians vote today in a <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> primary to choose an opponent for <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, the Democratic nominee seeking to making history as the nation's first elected black governor. Polls show a deadlock in the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> contest among former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Trible </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, former Attorney General <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Stanford </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Parris </PERSON>. Today's primary is the first GOP gubernatorial primary in the state since 1949. <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, the state's lieutenant governor, was nominated Saturday at a unified state Democratic convention. He and his running mates, businessman <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Beyer </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> for lieutenant governor and <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> for re-election as attorney general, launched a statewide tour Monday. All 2.6 million registered voters can participate in the primary because <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> does not have registration by party, but turnout in the Super Tuesday presidential primary in March 1988 was only 235,000 on the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> side. <PERSON> Trible </PERSON>, 42, had led all polls until last week. But two surveys published as <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> turned 47 on Thursday put him about even with <PERSON> Trible </PERSON>. <PERSON> Parris </PERSON>, 59, was was close enough to the leaders to fall within the polls' sampling errors. A poll released last week showed each of the three <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> contenders leading <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, but only slightly. <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, 58, is nurturing his image as an underdog, a tactic which helped parlay him into the lieutenant governorship in 1985. A grandson of slaves, <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> grew up in segregated <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION> and attended <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on a state stipend because he could not go to <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s all-white law schools. He has portrayed himself as a social moderate and fiscal conservative and has played down the racial aspect of the contest, as have the three <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> contenders. The nation has not had a black governor since Reconstruction and has never actually elected one. Lt. Gov. <PERSON> Pinckney </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> became acting governor in 1872-73 after Gov. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Warmouth </PERSON> was removed from office.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0154EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DixonInvestment Bjt   06-13 0841</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dixon Investment, Bjt,840</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wife of Ethics Chairman Makes Big Profit on Small Investment</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The wife of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee chairman <PERSON> Julian </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> earned over $ 150,000 in two years from an investment of less than $ 15,000 in companies that help run stores at <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. Airport officials are looking into the two companies to determine whether they qualified properly as minority contractors. Although they had identical boards of directors, one was listed as a minority enterprise while another was listed as being run by women. On Monday, <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> amended his 1986 financial disclosure form to show that his wife, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON>, paid between $ 5,000 and $ 15,000 for the investment in the companies. <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Calif., initially told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> he did not have to reveal how much Mrs. <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> paid for the high-yield investment because she owned no stock in the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> companies, <ORGANIZATION> Mir </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kanon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Peideau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION> But he told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> clerk in a letter Monday that `` upon recent review'' of the companies' articles of incorporation `` it appears that, technically, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> is deemed a stockholder.'' `` In this light, her acquisition of interest in Mir Kanon-Peideau in July 1986 also should have been reflected in the transaction section,'' <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> said. He said in a telephone interview he was `` sorry that I made that mistake'' of not disclosing the cost of the investment. `` Obviously I feel badly about it.'' <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>'s forms from 1986 showed that Mrs. <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>'s investment was worth between $ 100,000 and $ 250,000. Thus, the investment appears to have soared after she paid between $ 5,000 and $ 15,000 for it in July 1986. Mrs. <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> invested in Mir Kanon and <PERSON> Peideau </PERSON> three months after the companies were part of a joint venture awarded the concession to run duty-free stores at the world's third-busiest airport. <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, who gained prominence in presiding over the ethics committee probe that ended with the resignation of Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, said in a telephone interview that the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> investment has been `` better than we ever expected.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> received dividends of over $ 100,000 in 1988 and of between $ 50,000 and $ 100,000 in 1987, according to financial forms disclosed for those years. <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> said there was nothing improper about his wife's business arrangement and that she was the `` ideal person'' to sit on the companies' boards because she has a background in retailing. Her <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> business, `` <ORGANIZATION> Much </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> About </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Something </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>,'' distributes advertising novelties. As a member of both companies' boards, Mrs. <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> said she attends meetings and helps set corporate policy. `` I do n't have a job there, not a 9-to-5 job,'' she said. <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> airport officials are checking to see if the companies meet requirements to qualify as minority contractors. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Kroh </PERSON>, the airport's property manager, said he has uncovered nothing `` illegal or immoral'' about the multimillion-dollar concession business. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, the airport's deputy executive director, said officials `` want to make sure they are a bona fide minority business enterprise and women's business enterprise.'' When airport commissioners awarded the duty-free concession, <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said, <PERSON> Mir </PERSON> <PERSON> Kanon </PERSON> was classified as a minority enterprise, while <PERSON> Peideau </PERSON> was classified as a business run by women. But <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> records show the companies had identical boards of directors on Sept. 28, 1988. They also had the same agent, who listed the same address in <LOCATION> Culver </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> `` That is not the way it was proposed to us originally,'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. However, he said airport officials knew from the beginning there was overlapping ownership in <LOCATION> Mir </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kanon </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Peideau </PERSON>, in that prominent <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> businessmen <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, a contractor; and <PERSON> Felker </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>, an attorney, own part of the businesses. <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, who also a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said his wife's high-yield investment has never affected his decisions in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` I'm sure I've supported bills that have supported the airport,'' said <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, whose congressional district abuts the airport. `` I do n't recall any specific requests that I've made to members, nor have I contacted the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>'s revision came as the finances of congressional spouses are in the spotlight because of <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s resignation after being charged with 69 violations by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee. The committee contended that <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s wife received improper gifts from a wealthy businessman, a charge <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> denied. Last week, <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> initially declined to disclose how much his wife paid for her investment, saying she did n't own stock in the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> companies. House ethics rules permit members to amend their financial disclosure statements if a change is made in a timely fashion after new information is brought to a lawmaker's attention. In 1988, <ORGANIZATION> Duty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shoppers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, the majority partner in the duty-free concession, accumulated gross revenues of $ 78 million from the airport shops, airport officials said. Mir <PERSON> Kanon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Peideau </PERSON> have 32 percent of the business in a joint venture with Duty Free Shoppers to run the duty-free stores, airport officials said. The companies also are part of the concession for gift and news stores.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890613-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-89 0058EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Argentina 4thLd-Writethru a0408 06-13 0680</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Argentina, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0408,0699</SECOND>
<HEAD>Alfonsin Says He Will Resign June 30; Menem Says He Won't Take Over</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 9 grafs to UPDATE with Menem saying Senate president
shud be interim president. Picks up 9th pvs, `Menem had...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED McCULLOUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
