<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 2340EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Egypt-Jordan     08-27 0360</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Egypt-Jordan,0375</SECOND>
<HEAD>Egypt and Jordan Call For Syria To Cooperate With Arab League</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAIRO, Egypt (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> on Sunday urged <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> to cooperate with an Arab league committee appointed to mediate an end to conflict in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> that has left nearly 800 people in less than six months. King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> met with <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>'s President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> for three hours of talks on regional issues, principally the escalating violence in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> between Christian troops and Syrian-backed Moslems. The latest round in the conflict broke out in March when <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> army commander, Gen. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>, blockaded illegal Moslem-run ports. The Syrians responded by blockading the 310-square-mile Christian enclave. <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> said he hoped `` <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> would cooperate with'' a three-member Arab League committee of <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> appointed in a May Arab summit in <LOCATION> Casablanca </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION> to mediate peace in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. `` Must not leave the solution for what is happening in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> to non-Arab countries, because that would make us appear weak,'' <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> told reporters after the meeting. `` We as Arabs are responsible for what happens in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> apparently referred to French and Soviet negotiations last week with <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> and Moslem leaders in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s principal weapons supplier. <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> said, however, it was uncertain whether the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> committee will be able to carry out its mandate to end to the war. The committee said this month that its efforts had failed and blamed <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> for refusing to schedule withdrawal of its estaimted 40,000 troops from <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. `` We must wait and see whether the committee will continue its work or not,'' <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> entered <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> with a 1976 <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> peacekeeping mandate but became involved on the Moslem side of that country's civil war A Jordanian official said in <LOCATION> Amman </LOCATION> on condition of anonymity, that <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and other Arab countries were mediating with the Syrians to end <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s violence. On Saturday, <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> met with <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s foreign minister, <PERSON> Farouk </PERSON> <PERSON> el-Sharaa </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Amman </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> have no diplomatic ties, but relations have improved recently after 10 years of bitterness that followed <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION>'s peace treaty with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 0228EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-HurricaneKiko 4thLd-Writethru   08-27 0615</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hurricane Kiko, 4th Ld-Writethru,a0612,0635</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Hurricane Kiko Hits Southern Baja California</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 16 grafs to UPDATE with Kiko hitting land, details.
Pickup 10th graf `La Paz, with...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LA PAZ, Mexico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hurricane Kiko, packing winds up to 115 mph, hit the southeastern coast of the <LOCATION> Baja </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> peninsula Saturday, blowing down trees and unleashing downpours, officials said. The storm lashed <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Buenavista </LOCATION> and other small towns on the coast of the sparsely populated <LOCATION> Baja </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sur </LOCATION> state. `` The wind is very strong. There's a lot of water. There are trees down. But there have been no casualties,'' <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> <PERSON> Acevedo </PERSON>, public security director in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION> <LOCATION> del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cabo </LOCATION>, said of <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON>. About 4,000 people live in the town and surrounding area, he said. <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> is about 75 miles south of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paz </LOCATION>, the state capital. `` The eye is brushing along the southeastern edge'' of the peninsula, approximately between the town of <LOCATION> Buenavista </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barriles </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Case </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in in <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, said by telephone. <LOCATION> Buenavista </LOCATION> is about 60 miles southeast of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paz </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barriles </LOCATION> lies between the two cities. At 11 p.m. local time, -LRB- 2 a.m. EDT Sunday -RRB- the storm was located near latitude 23.9 north and longitude 109.7 west, or about 40 miles east-southeast of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paz </LOCATION>. It was moving northwest at about 5 mph, said the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. The weather bulletin said <PERSON> Kiko </PERSON> made landfall but did not say when. The storm expected to lose strength as it crossed the peninsula in the next 24 hours, it said. Electricity was off in <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rivera </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Buenavista </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION> <LOCATION> del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cabo </LOCATION>, near the tip of the peninsula, <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> <PERSON> Acevedo </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> <PERSON> Acevedo </PERSON> said the few hotels along the coast around <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> had not been evacuated. `` They are the type of construction that can take it,'' he said. Waves more than 10 feet high were crashing on the coast in <LOCATION> Buenavista </LOCATION>, a town of 800 people, said <PERSON> Hector </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> <PERSON> Marron </PERSON>, the security and transit agent on duty. Many people who were staying in the town's three hotels took the Saturday morning plane to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, he said. Heavy rain fell afternoon, rushing down normally dry gullies, he said. He said about four families who live along a gully in <LOCATION> Buenavista </LOCATION> had been told they should leave their homes. A strong wind was blowing about 7 p.m. -LRB- 9 p.m. EDT -RRB-, and some residents had taped or boarded up windows, he said. According to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Kiko </PERSON> was a `` small'' hurricane with sustained winds up to 115 mph Saturday night. <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Paz </PERSON>, with 160,000 inhabitants, has half the population of the state, which occupies the southern half of the <LOCATION> Baja </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>. It is about 760 miles south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Zatarain </PERSON> said emergency supplies were being mustered and shelters stocked with food and blankets throughout the state. Storm warnings were being broadcast, civil defense units had been mobilized and military units were standing by, he said. Ferry service between the peninsula and the mainland was canceled, he said. On the mainland, the <LOCATION> Sinaloa </LOCATION> state government had an emergency plan in effect, the government news agency <ORGANIZATION> Notimex </ORGANIZATION> said. The airline <ORGANIZATION> Aeromexico </ORGANIZATION> canceled or diverted service to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mochis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mazatlan </LOCATION> and <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> on Saturday after making an early morning flight to the three cities, the reservations office said. The weather service said hurricane warnings were in effect for the Gulf of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> side of the Baja peninsula from the southern tip northward to <LOCATION> Bahia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Conception </LOCATION>, about 200 miles north of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paz </LOCATION>. It said possible flash floods and mudslides could occur.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 0855EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Kiko 3rdLd-Writethru   08-27 0601</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Kiko, 3rd Ld-Writethru,a0620,0616</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hurricane Kiko Weakens Over Southern Baja California</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 8 grafs to UPDATE with storm weakening, new position.
Pickup graf 9 pvs, `Bob Case...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LA PAZ, Mexico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hurricane Kiko slammed into the <LOCATION> Baja </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> peninsula with 115 mph winds that blew down homes and forced hundreds of people to evacuate, but it lost strength Sunday as it passed over hilly terrain. After striking the southeastern coast of the peninsula and driving toward the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>, the storm's top sustained winds fell to 90 mph by 5 a.m. -LRB- 8 a.m. EDT -RRB-, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> said. <PERSON> Kiko </PERSON> bore down hardest on <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON>, a city of 4,000 people 75 miles south of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paz </LOCATION>, said Lt. <PERSON> Ignacio </PERSON> <PERSON> Cortez </PERSON> <PERSON> Telechea </PERSON>, assistant state government director. `` There were homes of thin wood and laminated cardboard that blew down,'' he said. `` They had palm or cardboard roofs that blew away. Trees, antennas, electrical poles fell.'' There were no immediate reports of injuries, but more than 300 people left their homes and were housed in shelters in the area, officials said. Sgt. <PERSON> Ruben </PERSON> <PERSON> Burgoin </PERSON> <PERSON> Peralta </PERSON>, the police officer on duty in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION> <LOCATION> del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cabo </LOCATION>, said 20 homes were destroyed in <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rivera </LOCATION>, which is in his district. At 5 a.m., the storm was located near latitude 23.7 north and longitude 110.5 west, or 35 miles south of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paz </LOCATION>. The capital of <LOCATION> Baja </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> is 760 miles south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>. The storm was moving west at about 5 mph, said the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The weather bulletin said <PERSON> Kiko </PERSON> hit the coast at midnight Saturday and lost strength as it struck the coastal cliffs and high terrain of the peninsula. The weather service said hurricane warnings were in effect for the Gulf of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> side of the Baja peninsula from the southern tip northward to <LOCATION> Bahia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Conception </LOCATION>, 200 miles north of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paz </LOCATION>. They were also declared for the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> side south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carlos </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Case </PERSON>, a hurricane specialist at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, said the worst of <PERSON> Kiko </PERSON> is over for <LOCATION> Baja </LOCATION>. `` The biggest problem is continued heavy rains, flash floods and mudslides,'' he said in a telephone interview early Sunday. `` It should come out over the open waters of the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> during the day and resume a west-northwest track, and we expect it to continually weaken as it heads over cooler waters in the next day or two,'' he said. The storm also lashed <LOCATION> Buenavista </LOCATION> and other small towns south of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paz </LOCATION> on the coast of the sparsely populated state and sent water rushing down normally dry gullies, stopping traffic along the highway from <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jose </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> del </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cabo </ORGANIZATION> to <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paz </LOCATION>, officials said. Electricity was out from <LOCATION> Cabo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lucas </LOCATION>, at the tip of the peninsula, up the coast to towns south of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paz </LOCATION>. The lack of power also cut water service since pumps are electric. <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> <PERSON> Acevedo </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jose </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> del </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cabo </ORGANIZATION> public security director, said the few hotels along the coast around <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> had not been evacuated. `` They are the type of construction that can take it,'' he said. <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Zatarain </PERSON>, the state public security coordinator, said emergency supplies were being mustered and shelters stocked with food and blankets throughout the state. Storm warnings were being broadcast, civil defense units had been mobilized and military units were standing by, he said. The airline <ORGANIZATION> Aeromexico </ORGANIZATION> canceled or diverted service to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mochis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mazatlan </LOCATION> and <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> on Saturday after making an early morning flight to the three cities, the reservations office said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 1030EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-PhoneStrike     08-27 0286</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Phone Strike,0294</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wisconsin Bell, Union Reach Tentative Settlement</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MILWAUKEE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bell </LOCATION> and the union representing some 4,200 striking workers reached a tentative settlement early Sunday but the workers would stay off the job until their counterparts in other Midwestern states reached settlements, a spokesman said. The settlement came a day after workers at <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> also reached a tentative contract. Both state companies are subsidiaries of the five-state <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION> regional telephone company, which has been strikebound since Aug. 13. `` We are still on strike until all -LRB- bargaining -RRB- tables with <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION> are resolved,'' <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Communication </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Local </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> 4603 </ORGANIZATION> said in a tape recorded message to union members announcing the <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> settlement. <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Vyto </PERSON> <PERSON> Kapocius </PERSON> confirmed the settlement but declined to comment further, saying the company would reveal the details at an afternoon news conference. Some 37,000 <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> workers at <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION> subsidiaries in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> walked off the job Aug. 13. The regional telephone company, one of the so-called `` Baby Bells'' created by the breakup of <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T in 1984, is based in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION> strike is one of four that began earlier this month, involving a total of 200,000 workers in 20 states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. Unions have negotiated tentative settlements with striking employees at <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Telesis </LOCATION>, which serves <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>; and <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION>, which covers <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and theDistrict of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> NYNEX </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> said Friday it had agreed to resume bargaining with its striking workers for the first formal talks since that walkout started almost three weeks ago. That regional company serves <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and most of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 1144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Hilary'sHardship Bjt   08-27 0798</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hilary's Hardship, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Child Turns 7 In Hiding As Custody Fight Continues</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GINSBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonia </PERSON> <PERSON> Foretich </PERSON> turned 7 last week in hiding, with her father marking the birthday at a subdued Capitol Hill ceremony and her mother nearing two years in jail for refusing to disclose the little girl's whereabouts. <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON> has been missing for two years on Monday, since a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> judge ordered her mother, Dr. <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, to surrender the youngster for unsupervised visits with her father. <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> refused to comply and remains in jail on contempt of court charges. <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> claims that <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON>'s father, Dr. <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Foretich </PERSON>, sexually abused the girl. <PERSON> Foretich </PERSON> vehemently denies the allegation and contends that his former wife is suffering from delusions. While the parents' struggle continues, mental health professionals are questioning whether <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON> can survive the ordeal without emotional scars. `` For any child, a separation from both parents on an abrupt and sudden basis is very harmful and could cause serious long-term consequences,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiener </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Child </ORGANIZATION> and Adolescent Psychiatry. `` There's no way that she could not be significantly affected from this experience, and I would think that any effects could not be undone.'' <PERSON> Constance </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahrons </PERSON>, a noted <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> psychologist in the field of child custody cases and author of the book `` Divorced Families,'' said <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON>'s separation from her parents could leave the child feeling isolated, even under protective custody. `` This is bound to have a profound effect on her,'' <PERSON> Ahrons </PERSON> said. `` If she was close to her parents, she may feel abandoned. In a case like this, the child is the most vulnerable because of her age and because she has no control in what happens to her.'' <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Holman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON>'s court-appointed attorney, declined to be interviewed and said she refuses all media requests for interviews concerning this case. She said such interviews `` contribute to the long-term negative impact on <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON>.'' District of <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> has said <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> will remain in jail for contempt of court until she surrenders <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON>. A three-judge panel of the <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>, the city's highest local court, ordered that <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> be released. However, the entire court overturned that decision on Aug. 21 _ <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON>'s seventh birthday _ and ordered a new hearing on the case before the full court next month. That same day, <PERSON> Foretich </PERSON> and about a dozen family members and friends marked his daughter's birthday with a small ceremony on the steps of the Capitol. Legislation passed by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and awaiting a vote by the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> would limit the length of contempt jailings in the nation's capital and, in effect, free <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>. Later that same day, <PERSON> Foretich </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> he thinks <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON> is suffering through an experience that could ultimately lead to an early death. `` If my daughter is not brought back within the near future, it will be too late. She will lose her ability to ever recover from this,'' he said. `` I knew her to be a resilient child, but at some point that resilience is going to fade. I do n't want my daughter to be an example, another statistic, of a teen-age suicide because she feels abandoned by both parents and has been led to believe that her father is a pervert and her mother is a crazy woman.'' <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> did not respond to a written request for an interview relayed through jail officials. However, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Froning </PERSON>, a child psychologist who treated <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON> for two years at her mother's request, said the only hardship that the young girl has undergone is being apart from her mother for so long. `` Her ordeal is being separated from her mother, the only person in the world she trusts,'' Froning said. `` She is with the people she chose to be with, so I have every reason to believe she is safe.'' <PERSON> Wiener </PERSON>, however, wondered whether the one-way communication that he presumes <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON> receives is n't hurting the girl. `` One presumes she is told positive things about her mother and negative things about her father,'' <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON> said. `` That is not constructive, not at all.'' <PERSON> Ahrons </PERSON> said she also was concerned that some problems could result from the girl acting as a fugitive to disguise her real identity. `` There are certainly possible problems with issues concerning her own identity,'' said <PERSON> Ahrons </PERSON>. `` It could have some effect on her life. A profound effect? Who knows?'' <PERSON> Foretich </PERSON> has his own theory. `` At what point will <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON> cease to even know who she is?'' he asked. `` I mean, how many times has her name been changed, has her hair been colored? Does she even know who she is anymore? Her self-image will soon be destroyed, if it has n't already happened.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 1152EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-TyphoonRoger     08-27 0173</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Typhoon Roger,0177</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Dead, Two Missing as Tropical Storm Hits Western Japan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A storm with 55 mph winds and heavy rains caused landslides and flooding Sunday that left two people dead and three missing, police said. Seven people were reported injured by objects thrown by the winds. The storm, earlier designated Typhoon <PERSON> Roger </PERSON>, had been downgraded to a tropical storm by the time it hit western <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, forecasters said. The heavy rains flooded 550 houses, caused about 70 landslides and damaged or destroyed roads in 40 places, a police official said. The storm hit <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Muroto </LOCATION> on Sunday morning and had moved north to <LOCATION> Fukui </LOCATION> in central <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> by early evening, forecasters said. The police official said a 61-year-old man was buried by a landslide in Ome on the outskirts of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, and an 8-year-old girl drowned after falling into a swollen river in <LOCATION> Saitama </LOCATION> state northwest of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. The official said three men were missing. Two of them fell into flooded rivers, one while repairing a bridge.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 1158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Fitzgerald-Families     08-27 0747</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fitzgerald-Families,0771</SECOND>
<HEAD>Underwater Pictures Bring Memories To `Wives And The Sons And The
Daughters'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAIGE St. JOHN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TRAVERSE CITY, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A macabre drama unfolded for a small fellowship who, with horror and fascination, watched television film clips of the first clear pictures of the wreck of the <PERSON> Edmund </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>. `` Oh yes, I've watched it. I ca n't not watch it,'' said <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON>, whose only child, <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON>, 22, died aboard the steel freighter during a fierce storm Nov. 10, 1975. His body and those of 28 other crewmen remain at the bottom of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Superior </LOCATION>. For three days last week, explorers using a submersible robot penetrated the cold, deep water that has cloaked and preserved the Fitzgerald since its sinking. Their video images will provide data on the wreck as well as the technology to study other underwater sites. For the families of the <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> crew, the expedition opened wounds. `` People say it gets easier. Naturally, it's eased some. But to me it was just yesterday,'' said <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION>, of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Olmstead </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. Startling footage of the 556-foot-deep wreck _ funded by the <ORGANIZATION> Great </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lakes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipwreck </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Historical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> _ was difficult for <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION> to watch. `` It's a hard time for me. It brings back all of the panic,'' she said. `` But I ca n't say I do n't want them to do it. I have a lot of friends that are really angry. They ask, ` Why are they doing that to the families?' But this is history. My son would have wanted it shown.'' She feels good about public fascination with the wreck. `` They really have n't forgotten,'' she said. The tragedy became American folklore, particularly after Canadian balladeer <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Lightfoot </PERSON> wrote a hit song in 1976 about the death of the boat he called `` the pride of the American side.'' `` All that remains is the faces and the names of the wives and the sons and the daughters,'' he sang. <PERSON> Edmund </PERSON> <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> said by telephone from <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> last week that his father, the <PERSON> Edmund </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> for whom the the freighter was named, was haunted by the wreck until his death in 1986. The father was president of <ORGANIZATION> Northwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mutual </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which built the ship in 1958. The <PERSON> Edmund </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> left <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, under threatening skies Nov. 9 on what was to have been its last trip down the Great Lakes before docking for the winter. By the next day, the <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> was in a gale. Capt. <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> McSorley </PERSON> reported topside damage and a list to his boat as 30-foot waves crashed over the freighter. Just 15 miles short of the protection of <LOCATION> Whitefish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, <PERSON> McSorley </PERSON> spoke by ship's radio to the <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, another freighter struggling through the storm. Although the beacon light that marked the entrance to the bay had gone out, both skippers were sure they'd make it `` We are holding our own,'' <PERSON> McSorley </PERSON> told the <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s crew. Shortly afterward, the <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> disappeared from radar screens without even a distress call. No bodies and very little wreckage was found. There are conflicting theories on how the <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> sank _ whether water entered its hold through leaking hatch covers or it hit a shoal. Underwater divers later found that the ship went down with such force it broke in two. The search robot's first images Wednesday were of a stark white bow rising crumpled and torn out of the blackness. Researchers were struck not by the damage but by the incongruity of a gleaming water cooler surrounded by overturned equipment in the pilothouse. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Peckol </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ashtabula </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, is eager to see the footage being filmed for a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Geographic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> television show. He's already seen the snippets on newscasts `` Naturally, they're not going to change anything that has happened,'' said <PERSON> Peckol </PERSON>, whose 20-year-old son, <PERSON> Karl </PERSON>, died on the ship. `` But maybe they can shed more light on what possibly happened.'' <PERSON> Bettie </PERSON> <PERSON> Peckol </PERSON> remembers her relief when <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> took a job on the <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>, transferring from a smaller and, she thought, more dangerous boat named <PERSON> Sensibar </PERSON>. `` The irony of it is, the <PERSON> Sensibar </PERSON> is still sailing,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Peckol </PERSON>, who skipped newscasts of the wreckage. `` I'm not happy about opening up a lot of old wounds. I guess you never forget the loss of a child. `` Plus, I do n't believe in living in the past. I want to remember <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> the way he was the last time I saw him.'' That was Nov. 7, 1975. He was waving goodbye.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 1214EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BushParaphernalia Bjt   08-27 0837</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush Paraphernalia, Bjt,830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Souvenir Business Flourishing At President's Summer Home</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KENNEBUNKPORT, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Suppose you have a craving for some `` Bush Sauce'' with your quail dinner. Or maybe you want to snuggle your feet into a pair of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> flag slippers adorned with <PERSON> George </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> dolls. Perhaps you'd just like to pick up a `` Read my lips'' wall clock. <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION> is your shopping destination. The proliferation of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> paraphernalia in this resort town of nearly 3,000 people is giving tourists a variety of souvenir options to prove _ once they get home to <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> _ that they have, indeed, been to the summer vacation home of the 41st president. What kitchen, for example could n't use a little refrigerator magnet with a plastic <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> lobster and the words `` <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. Home of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'' on it? Those sell for $ 2.50 each at the What's In Store, a curio shop that also features mugs emblazoned with the eagle symbol of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and a picture of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s home on <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>'s Point. In the same shop, you can have your picture taken with a lifesize picture of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for $ 5. Or how about a kid's bib that says `` I was a guest at Walker's Point, <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>,'' or a dishtowel bearing the blue grinning image of the president at $ 4.99 each The president himself gave a plug Friday for a new item selling at the <ORGANIZATION> Cape </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arundel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Golf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> shop. `` You want me to sell some shirts for you?'' he asked golf pro <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Raynor </PERSON> as they teed off. He turned to a group of reporters and photographers and pointed to the insignia on his knit shirt. `` It says <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. They're really nice. I'm recommending them.'' The `` new presidential shirts'' sell for $ 36 in the golf shop, where photos of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> driving a golf cart adorn the wall. Back in the quaint center of town, all manner of Bush-inspired T-shirts are hot sellers. Slogans emblazoned across shirts include the well-worn `` KenneBushport,'' `` The Summer White House, <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>,'' with a picture of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>'s Point home, and `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> Sleeps Here.'' For those getting ready for Halloween, the Paper Plus toys and curio store sells cardboard <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> masks, with cutout eyes, for $ 3.95. The masks are displayed on a wall between an autographed photo of comedian Pee Wee <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> and a photo of <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, smiling in a white negligee and autographed with the words, `` To all my darlings at Paper Plus. I'll always cherish this day.'' The store also sells the `` Sleeping Partnerzzz'' slippers, at $ 30 a pair, which feature plastic <PERSON> George </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> heads peeping out from flag-striped slippers. Each plastic doll head rests on a pillow, also part of the slipper, emblazoned with the eagle seal of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> grimaced a few months back when a local restaurateur showed her a pair of the slippers. The Open Door Gift Shop features Bush Sauce, created by The <ORGANIZATION> Hagen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> company of neargy Orgunquit, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, at $ 5.25 for a 16-ounce jar. Proprietor <PERSON> Jody </PERSON> <PERSON> Bibber </PERSON> says it's so popular `` I ca n't keep it in. ... It's just a fun item.'' The label says the tomato and onion relish is `` excellent with quail'' and makes a nice garnish for chicken or fish. In keeping with the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> jargon, one flavor is labeled `` kinder-gentler,'' and the label also urges the shopper to `` Shower your taste buds with a thousand points of light.'' Another Bush-ism inspired a $ 46 clock at the Argo gift shop. The clock is in the shape of bright red lips with a cartoon-style balloon coming from them carrying the words `` Read my lips.'' Proprietor <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Joslyn </PERSON> said he's not really into <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> paraphernalia but picked up two of the novelty clocks at a craft show. He sent one to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> via the son of a friend who cares for the Bushes' pool. He does n't know if the president received it. Irreverence is the key to some of the novelties. One version of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> mask carries the caution: `` Not intended for use by children under the age of 3 or by <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. May cause drowsiness while operating heavy machinery, pitching horseshoes, vetoing legislation. ... Misuse may result in 1,000 points of light.'' <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Mills </PERSON>, who runs a corporate and personal shopping service, said her clients are looking for all types of more refined Bush-oriented gifts. `` Everybody wants <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> products with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s home painted on them,'' she said adding that a popular item has been a $ 35 breakfast-in-bed tray with <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>'s Point on it. The more thrifty souvenir shopper can pick up plastic thimbles, at $ 6.99 each, with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s picture on them, or shot glasses, $ 3.95 each, bearing the presidential seal and the words <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. Chamber of <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> Chairwoman <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Aiello </PERSON>, contending that <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION> has n't let itself be overwhelmed by tackiness, acknowledged that some of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> products are `` borderline tasteful'' and that `` expensive tacky is creeping in.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 1234EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-ThirdWorldDebt Bjt   08-27 0962</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Third World Debt, Bjt,920</SECOND>
<HEAD>Record Lag Expected in Third World Interest Payments</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Major Third World countries are expected to fall nearly another $ 5 billion behind in the interest payments and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and other banks this year, but, unlike individual debtors, there's no car to repossess and no home to foreclose on. Sovereign governments do not allow foreign bankers to seize the property of their citizens, although sometimes lenders are allowed to buy up pieces of it in debt-equity swaps. Fifteen countries singled out by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for special help will fall behind by another $ 4.868 billion in their interest payments this year, raising their arrears to a record $ 15.079 billion, according to the banks which are owed the money. <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> owe the most, according figures on the 15 major debtors compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION>, a group of the leading lending banks, and made available to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> last week. Bankers know them as `` the <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> 15'' after Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, who made up the list in 1985 when he was secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>. Most are in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, but the list also includes <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>. By the end of 1990, the 15 countries will owe about $ 524 billion to lending banks and governments, with nearly another $ 50 billion in interest payments falling due. Most have not paid anything on the principal of their debt since the crisis began in 1982. <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON>, an economist at the institute, said falling behind on servicing the debt is a conscious policy of Third World government leaders. `` Their governments need capital, and that's the way they decide to get it,'' <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> said. `` But it's a policy that discourages new lending from abroad and discourages their own citizens from bringing home the money they've sent abroad.'' More money has been leaving Third World countries than has arrived in them this decade. Leaders of the debtor countries complain that the net outflow _ about $ 30 billion last year _ is unnatural and a major cause of their declining standards of living through the 1980s. `` Poverty has increased because of debt,'' said Finance Minister <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Chidzero </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>, whose country owes a modest $ 2.5 billion and is not among the 15 major debtors. `` Malnutrition has increased as a result of more money going into debt service,'' <PERSON> Chidzero </PERSON> said. `` There is a decline in social services, because they can not be maintained because people want to service debt. And I think that is an untenable situation.'' The interest payments are cited as a major factor in the net exodus but part of it also is due to their wealthy citizens putting their money in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> and other safe havens. Much of this `` capital flight'' is illegal, and there are no reliable figures on it. <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> thinks that citizens of many debtor countries have stashed away assets abroad that approach or even exceed the value of their own countries' debts to the commercial banks. Finance Minister <PERSON> Mailson </PERSON> <PERSON> Nobrega </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, which owes about $ 109 billion and is the Third World's biggest debtor, predicts there will be economic chaos if a solution is not found soon. `` If we do not find a solution for the debt, then it will be solved by itself through political turmoil, through social unrest, and then industrial nations will wake up and find a solution,'' he said. `` So, it is better for them to help us find a solution now.'' Norbrega and <PERSON> Chidzero </PERSON> made their comments on a program prepared by <ORGANIZATION> WETA </ORGANIZATION>, a public television station in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The program will be broadcast Sept. 28 when the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monetary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> hold their annual meetings here <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> pose two of the biggest problems. <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> already has delayed some payments and the prospects are uncertain that it will make a $ 3 billion payment due next month. Brazilian leaders say they are not planning another stop on payments, but the creditor banks say they expect the country to pile up another $ 700 million of interest arrears this year. Last year <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> caught up on its arrears through an agreement with the private banks and the multigovernment <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monetary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-. New loans were provided on the condition that <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s government reduce its own borrowing at home. Since then, the <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> has said that <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> failed to live up to the agreement and has halted further disbursement of the new loans. Many private banks followed suit. What happens next depends largely on the results of <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s upcoming November election in which the debt burden is a major issue. <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, where the new government of President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> is settling in, will owe about $ 68.6 billion at the end of this year, according to the bankers' institute. Of that, $ 5.8 billion represents past-due interest. Total debt of Third World countries is estimated at $ 1.3 trillion. But many big debtors are not considered in financial trouble. Among them are <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, with a $ 60.2 billion; <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, with $ 42.4 billion, and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, with $ 39.3 billion. For the troubled countries, <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> has achieved a minor breakthrough by getting multigovernment-owned <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> to effectively guarantee interest payments on new loans or reduced interest rates proffered by private banks in debt-reduction agreements. So far deals have been struck with <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. But it is uncertain how much the arrangements will actually reduce borrowers' debt-service costs. Many fear the debtor nations will be left only further in the red. And some influential governments are skeptical that their taxpayers will be stuck for the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> guarantees if and when the deals sour.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 1303EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Baltics Bjt   08-27 0835</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Baltics, Bjt,0859</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baltic Residents Make Bold New Push For Independence</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANN IMSE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TALLINN, U.S.S.R. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Independence. A year ago, only a few former political prisoners dared whisper the word in the nation's three Baltic republics Today, it is the goal of a mass movement, putting the three tiny lands in direct conflict with the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>. On Wednesday, a 370-mile chain of determined Baltic families stood hand in hand, protesting the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> annexation of their independent nations. But that was just the most dramatic manifestation of a profound change that has occurred in recent months on the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s western frontier. The activist groups of <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Latvia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>, known as the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, once worked for more authority within the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Now, they are openly calling for restoration of their free nations. `` The declarations of the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> in the past year have become ever closer to the ideals our people have carried in their hearts for all these 50 years,'' <ORGANIZATION> Estonian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> leader and lawmaker <PERSON> Marju </PERSON> <PERSON> Lauristin </PERSON> said. `` All of us would like to have freedom, and freedom without independence is n't realistic,'' she said. From the <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION>'s point of view, it is Baltic independence that's unrealistic, and a sharply worded statement from the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Saturday made that point clear. `` Things have gone far. Serious danger is threatening the Baltic peoples,'' the policy-making body said. `` People should know what abyss their nationalist leaders are pushing them toward.'' `` If they managed to attain their goals, the consequences could be catastrophic for their people. Their very ability to survive could come under question,'' it said. The statement was carried on national television. Not long ago, such a warning from the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> would have sent shudders through many activists. On Sunday, it did little more than raise eyebrows in the <ORGANIZATION> Baltics </ORGANIZATION> _ yet another indication of how far the region has come in establishing for itself an identity outside the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. `` We expected this,'' said <PERSON> Raimona </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakalouskis </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the Lithuanian activist group. But leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> movements did n't interrupt their weekend plans to discuss the statement. The radicalization of the fronts is backed by more than 2 million people who signed documents implying they want freedom from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>, 1.3 million people have signed petitions saying the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> annexed their nation `` against the will of Lithuanians.'' It demands removal of the Soviet `` occupation army'' and seeks <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> supervision of free elections for a new Baltic government. In <LOCATION> Latvia </LOCATION>, 430,000 people have registered themselves as desiring to be considered citizens of an independent <LOCATION> Latvia </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION>, more than 400,000 have signed petitions asking the Estonian parliament to declare illegal the 1940 Estonian parliament's approval of the Soviet annexation. That legislature was elected under Soviet occupation and only Communists were allowed to run. For the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Baltics </ORGANIZATION> are front-line territory, home to missile bases, naval and army units, and vital ports. Activists say one in eight people in <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION> is a Soviet soldier. Soviet television called the idea of redrawing boundaries `` political naivete'' in its coverage of Wednesday's protest. `` Independence _ it'll never happen,'' said a <LOCATION> Tallinn </LOCATION> taxi driver, the son of a Russian-Estonian marriage. The economy is a wreck and hopes of developing a new tourist industry fail to take into consideration the cold, damp Baltic climate, he said. Significant opposition to independence also has come from the 2.7 million Russians and other non-Baltic people among the 8 million Baltic residents. Yet amid the pride and determination exhibited by the tens of thousands of Estonians holding hands on the crest of <LOCATION> Tallinn </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Toompea </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> on Wednesday evening, independence seemed possible In the past year, the <ORGANIZATION> Baltics </ORGANIZATION> have waged a parliamentary and legal struggle, taking full advantage of each step toward democracy permitted by the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>. Each move has run into condemnation in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, giving way to grudging acceptance, and a new push by the <ORGANIZATION> Baltics </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION> made international headlines in November when it claimed the right to overturn Soviet laws. The Kremlin declared the move invalid, but <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION> has not backed down. A plan for economic autonomy greeted with derision two years ago has been approved in principle by the new Soviet legislature. Recent strikes by Russians in <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION> over a voter residency law disturbed activists, but the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> refrained from issuing orders and strove for a peaceful compromise. <PERSON> Alvydas </PERSON> <PERSON> Medalinskas </PERSON>, a leader of the Lithuanian activist group <ORGANIZATION> Sajudis </ORGANIZATION>, said it would not now exist if it had spoken of independence even in January. On Wednesday, the <ORGANIZATION> Sajudis </ORGANIZATION> council pushed again. It voted to call for `` creation of an independent democratic Lithuanian republic not under the power of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.'' A day earlier, the Lithuanian parliament passed a resolution calling the Soviet annexation `` an international crime.'' In <LOCATION> Latvia </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> will take a formal vote soon at its congress on changing its platform to full independence, said Chairman <PERSON> Ianis </PERSON> <PERSON> Freimanis </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 1320EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Lightning     08-27 0650</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Lightning,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Researchers Find Lightning A More Widespread Danger</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Researchers have found lightning to be an even more widespread danger than was believed, with more than five dozen Americans losing their lives and hundreds more injured by lightning last year. A hazard whose scattered victims usually attract only local notice, lightning finally made the national headlines in 1988 by sparking forest fires that ravaged much of <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION>. In the past, weather observers have recorded the presence of lightning through the simple expedient of listening for the thunder that comes after the electrical discharges. But electromagnetic detection systems have discovered that, because of interference with sound waves, between 22 percent and 40 percent of all lightning occurs without observers hearing the thunder that follows. That is not good news, researchers note, pointing out that lightning can strike with no warning, sometimes occuring prior to storms or reaching out ahead of the clouds. Detailed thunderstorm records go back to the late 1800s, but they have always depended on the reports of trained observers, primarily listening to thunder. This means that the operators of electrical plants and others who use weather records to anticipate the danger of lightning have underestimated the risk. The toll of 68 lightning deaths in 1988 was the same number as in 1986, tying for the lowest in this decade. In between, however, 1987 recorded the most in the decade with 86 fatalities. The long-term average is 96 lightning deaths annually, an average boosted by several very deadly years back in the 1960s, including 1963 when 210 people were killed by lightning. As usual, in 1988 many victims were in the open or under trees, with several on golf courses or in boats. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> retained its place as leading in lightning deaths with nine, while six died in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>. There were four lightning deaths in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported. And states with three fatalities were <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> had two lightning deaths each. States reporting one fatality last year were <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. More than half of all electrical storms had only a few cloud-to-ground lightning flashes, while a small number of storms had hundreds of strokes. Indeed, in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, three years worth of records showed that nearly one-quarter of all the lightning strokes were accounted for in just two big storms. One reason lightning does n't get the respect that meteorologists think it deserves is that it is like automobile accidents, usually claiming victims one or two at a time over a scattered area. The sudden arrival of thousands of volts of electricity, however, can sometimes involve a lot of people. For example, on July 17, 1988, lightning struck a utility pole at a speedway in <LOCATION> Snyder </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>. Twenty-two spectators were injured by the charge which traveled down the pole and into the bleachers Happily, no one was killed. On July 10 of last year a group playing volleyball in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s Prospect Park was n't so fortunate Seeking to avoid a sudden downpour, they sought shelter under a tree. Lightning struck, killing a 28-year-old man and injuring a dozen others. Lightning results from a buildup of electrical charges in a storm cloud. The process is n't fully understood, but is appears to involve movement of raindrops up and down in the cloud, propelled by strong winds. When the electrical charges build up to large levels an invisible `` step leader'' moves down from the negatively charged cloud base in segments about 50 yards long, until it reaches the positively charged ground. When that contact is made, thousands of volts of electricity move in that circuit _ often in several `` bolts'' giving lightning its sometimes flickering character.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 1410EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Church-HousingBattle Bjt   08-27 0957</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Church-Housing Battle, Bjt,910</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tenants Win Battle With Church Over HUD-Financed High-Rise</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRUCE V. BIGELOW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PASADENA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fundamentalist church group improperly spent $ 117,000 earmarked for a low-income housing project here and tried to evade government rules in order to sell the building at an enormous profit, <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> records and court documents show. The sale of The Concord, a 150-unit high-rise building, was halted through the persistence of tenants who feared they would be evicted or their rents would triple, lawyers familiar with the case said. The tenants urged the inspector general at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> to conduct an audit, which found $ 117,787 in project funds were improperly spent by The Concord's owner, <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Churches </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> Among other things, <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> found that <LOCATION> Concord </LOCATION> funds were used to pay church group officers and purchase two vans used for church events. The housing agency eventually reached a settlement with the group on the misspent money. The Glendale-based fundamentalist group first tried to sell the apartment building in 1982 for $ 5.5 million, after paying off the balance of a $ 2.05 million <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> loan to the original developer. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has since prohibited pre-payment of <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> loans unless the housing secretary finds that existing tenants are protected from eviction or higher rents. Community Churches tried again in 1985 to sell the building for $ 5.5 million, under the protection of a bankruptcy reorganization. But the bankruptcy sale was blocked after objections were raised by tenants, church creditors and <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> lawyers, according to court records on file in nearby <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. Community Churches was headed by the Rev. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> McBirnie </PERSON>, a charismatic preacher. Community Churches acquired The Concord in 1979 and organized a non-profit foundation to run the building in accordance with <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> regulations. The building was erected in 1966 to provide subsidized housing for the elderly and handicapped. But there were problems from the outset, said <PERSON> Clements </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, 81, a former building manager who spearheaded the tenants' fight. McBirnie planned to use the <LOCATION> Concord </LOCATION> to house his own parishioners and the loyal listeners to his anti-communist radio broadcasts, `` Voice of Americanism,'' she said. By 1982, <PERSON> McBirnie </PERSON> decided to sell The Concord because `` we were constantly being frustrated at making improvements in the building and not being able to do the good work that we had intended,'' he said in a legal declaration. He did not return a reporter's telephone call seeking comment <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s `` decision to allow the prepayment was very suspect,'' said <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Logan </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> lawyer representing the building's tenants. After the <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> loan was repaid, the agency lost its regulatory control over the building. Even the church's lawyer, <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> McNutt </PERSON>, acknowledged, `` The idea of <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> authorizing this prepayment for the benefit of a private owner was a real political hot potato at the time.'' Tenants asked <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> about the legality of the sale, and were told <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> regulations did not prohibit Community Churches group from paying off its loan early, Mrs. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> said. Of course, <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> `` was concerned over the impact upon existing tenants,'' <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Deputy Assistant Secretary <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> wrote Mrs. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> in July 1982. `` We insisted upon an agreement by the project owners that all existing tenants would have the opportunity to remain in occupancy without interference by the -LRB- new -RRB- owner until such time as they may freely choose to leave.'' But in testimony about a week later before the House Select Committee on Aging, <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> conceded the sale was authorized before <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> received any written pledge from <PERSON> McBirnie </PERSON>'s group guaranteeing the residents' life tenancy. `` The primary concern of the tenants was that they were going to be evicted or that their rents were going to be raised so high they were going to have to leave,'' <PERSON> McNutt </PERSON> said. `` But that was never reflected in reality.'' In August 1982, Mrs. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> and other tenants filed suit to block the sale of The Concord. There was intense pressure to settle because McBirnie's groups had obtained a short-term loan at high interest to pay off the <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> loan, <PERSON> McNutt </PERSON> said. McBirnie's groups had used the short-term loan because they intended to sell the building immediately, but their plan was thwarted by the tenants' lawsuit, <PERSON> Logan </PERSON> said. `` The deal essentially was shoved down the foundation's throat, because it was either lose the building through foreclosure or accept the government's offer,'' <PERSON> McNutt </PERSON> said. As a result, a 1983 settlement was reached that included a new $ 2.6 million <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> loan on the building and again HUD-imposed rules on its operations. New trouble surfaced in May 1985 when a <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> issued a $ 1.28 million default judgment against McBirnie's church groups in a suit that alleged 26 people were defrauded after investing about $ 200,000 in loans for new church facilities. Eventually, 380 creditors filed lawsuits claiming they were owed as much as $ 3.7 million. The next month, Community Churches filed for bankruptcy reorganization in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, eventually listing The <LOCATION> Concord </LOCATION> as a major asset. In the bankruptcy proceeding, <PERSON> McNutt </PERSON> proposed to satisfy creditors by selling The Concord to the same buyer lined up in the 1982 deal. The resurrected sale of The Concord in bankruptcy court `` was just a transparent attempt to do in bankruptcy court what the civil suits and the congressional hearings had prevented earlier,'' <PERSON> Logan </PERSON> said. After the case was transferred to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, the bankruptcy court appointed an independent trustee to supervise the reorganization. Three more years of legal maneuvering ended July 31 with a deal that closed the sale of The Concord for $ 1.35 million and assumption of the $ 2.2 million remaining on the <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> loan. The new owner, the <ORGANIZATION> Retirement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, has pledged to operate the building according to <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> regulations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 1429EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Poland Bjt   08-27 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Poland, Bjt,0636</SECOND>
<HEAD>Walesa Says Reforms Will Collapse Unless Economy Improves</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH G. SEWARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said Sunday that the nation's historic political and economic reforms will collapse unless Poles' living standards improve within six months to a year. `` Society's patience has its limits. It is so bad that if there is no visible effect -LRB- of reform -RRB- in half-a-year to a year then everything will collapse,'' <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. `` In my opinion they -LRB- Poles -RRB- will not stand any more of it,'' he said. He said another wave of strikes could result, or society could lose confidence in the Solidarity labor movement's ability to initiate change. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said he issued the same warning during a meeting in <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> on Sunday with <PERSON> Norbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bluem </PERSON>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s labor and social affairs minister. The new Solidarity-led government of Prime Minister <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON>, the first non-Communist leader of a Soviet bloc nation, has been urging Western nations to increase economic investment in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> met Saturday with <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kansas, and his wife, Labor Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, and gave them a letter for President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> seeking more <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic aid than the $ 119 million already promised. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> is beset by chronic food shortages and a $ 39 billion foreign debt. The nation has begun free-market reforms, such as relaxing price controls, that in the short term are likely to result in a drop in living standards. Solidarity, by luring Western aid, is seeking to make the tough sacrifices needed to bail out the economy as palatable as possible. After a Mass at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brygida </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> told a crowd in the courtyard: `` We must solve all our problems without economic losses.'' Solidarity leaders have been seeking a $ 10 billion assistance package from Western countries that includes investments, credits and rescheduling of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s debt. <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON>, who assumed office last week, spent his first days in office meeting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>, Soviet and West German officials. The Soviets have expressed support for the Solidarity-led government after previously voicing concerns about the role of the Communists in the new government and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s place in the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact military alliance. Solidarity has said it will allow the Communists to control the important defense and interior ministries and to have full participation in the new government. <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> is expected to announce a <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> within a week. <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> was elected prime minister after Solidarity-backed candidates trounced Communist candidates in parliamentary elections, then formed a coalition with two smaller parties to gain control of the legislature. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said he discussed German-Polish relations with <PERSON> Bluem </PERSON>. The 50th anniversary of the Nazi invasion of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> is on Sept. 1. In his sermon at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brygida </ORGANIZATION>'s, Rev. <PERSON> Henryk </PERSON> <PERSON> Jankowski </PERSON> called for Polish-German reconciliation. After Mass, <PERSON> Bluem </PERSON> and <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> addressed a crowd of 2,500 people in the courtyard and around the church premises. A band played the Polish and West German national anthems. `` You -LRB- Poles -RRB- can be proud of our nation because man does not live only on bread. The Gdansk shipyard and <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> are connected with the notion of freedom. You can be proud of it,'' <PERSON> Bluem </PERSON> told the crowd. `` I hope your premier can prove he can make a better country than the Communists,'' <PERSON> Bluem </PERSON> said. He also appealed for forgiveness from the Poles. `` A nation without history is a people without memory. We must not forget about suffering. We beg you for forgiveness. Let us embrace you ... No more war, no more violence, no more exile,'' he said. The Solidarity leader is planning to travel to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> Sept. 5-8 at the invitation of the Federation of West German Trade Unions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 1447EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Israel-Lebanon 1stLd-Writethru a0633 08-27 0422</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel-Lebanon, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0633,0430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Precede JERUSALEM</HEAD>
<HEAD>Israeli Warplanes Attack Hezbollah Target</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 5 grafs to UPDATE with details from scene of bombing.
Pick up 6th pvs, `The attack...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SIDON, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Israeli jets bombed a pro-Iranian Shiite Moslem stronghold in southeast <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> Sunday, killing one guerrilla and wounding five others, police reported. The fundamentalist <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, or Party of God, said a a statement that its main base in the village of <PERSON> Ein </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu-Suar </PERSON> `` sustained extensive damage'' in the attack at sundown. In <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, military officials reported destroying the <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> stronghold and said all Israeli planes returned safely. The <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> statement said `` there were material and human losses in the raid'' without giving specific casualty figures. But police in <LOCATION> Sidon </LOCATION>, 25 miles south of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, said the body of at least one <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> guerrilla and five wounded men were taken to the port city's <LOCATION> al-Rai </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ein </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu-Suar </PERSON> is 40 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> near the northern edge of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s self-designated `` security zone'' in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The attack was <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s ninth air raid in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> this year. The last air strike was on June 21 when <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> jets pounded a base of <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Jibril </PERSON>'s Popular Front for the <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palestine-General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, a radical Syrian-backed Palestinian group, in the village of <LOCATION> Naameh </LOCATION> south of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. Sunday's air raid is believed to come in retaliation for the Aug. 9 suicide car bomb attack carried out by the Iranian-supported <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>. That attack occurred in a south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> strip of land along the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> border that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has declared its security zone. Five Israeli soldiers and an allied Lebanese militiaman were injured in the car bombing, and <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials have vowed to avenge the attack. <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, or the <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> God </ORGANIZATION>, has said it carried out the bombing to avenge <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s kidnapping of a Shiite Moslem cleric, <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul-Karim </PERSON> <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>. Israeli commandos seized <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> in a southern Lebanese village on July 28. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> said it abducted <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> in order to win the release of three Israeli servicemen missing in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> since 1986. They are believed held by <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>. It has offered to swap <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> and other captive Shiites for the three Israeli captives and all 16 foreign hostages, including eight Americans, who are believed to be held by <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> or its affiliated groups. <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> has rejected the offer. A pro-Iranian Shiite faction called the Organization of the Oppressed on Earth claimed on July 31 that it killed an American hostage, Marine Lt. Col. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>, in retaliation for the <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> abduction.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 1451EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-RestaurantTippers     08-27 0536</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Restaurant Tippers,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Italian Restaurants Attract Biggest Tippers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Waiters in Italian restaurants in this country get the biggest tips from customers while those in Mexican eateries fare the worst, the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> has found. The average tip in Italian restaurants in 1986 was 15.8 percent, compared with 15 percent in <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> restaurants and 14.8 percent in <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> restaurants, according to an <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> study. On the other hand, patrons in <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> restaurants were more likely to leave a tip _ 90 out of every 100 did _ than in Italian restaurants, where only 88 saw fit to leave something. In restaurants serving Mexican food there were 86 tips for every 100 customers. The study did not try to give any reason for the differences, nor did it ask about restaurants that serve the foods of other countries. At least one waiter at a small <LOCATION> Italian </LOCATION> restaurant in <LOCATION> Georgetown </LOCATION>, a popular <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> restaurant area, agreed that he got better tips there than in other places he had worked. `` It's the European atmosphere,'' explained <PERSON> Mouez </PERSON> <PERSON> Zemni </PERSON>, who comes not from <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> but from <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION>, on the other side of the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION>. `` There's the European flair. People like the atmosphere and it relaxes them. It does n't even matter about the food. I do n't like Italian food much myself _ I think French food is much better.'' At a bigger and pricier Italian place, the maitre d' was not so sure about high tips. `` Some people come in here with a couple of kids and leave a dollar,'' said <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> Estrada </PERSON>. `` About 20 to 25 percent do n't leave anything.'' A waiter at a <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> restaurant would not agree that his tips were inferior. `` It's a matter of food and service,'' he insisted, a little stiffly. `` If a customer gets good food and good service, he tips well.'' What started the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> investigation is that waiters are required by law to include tips in their earnings and pay income tax on them. `` Underreporting of tip income has long been a concern,'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> researcher, wrote in his report on the situation. So the service hired the Survey Research Laboratory of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> to query its panel of nearly 13,000 households, both families and individuals. They kept records of their tips over two-week periods between 1983 and 1986. `` The diary approach used in this study was adopted on the ground that tipping information obtained from people leaving tips is likely to be more accurate than data obtained from tip recipients,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. Before narrowing the survey down to ethnic restaurants, the study tried other classifications, with labels that included `` family-type restaurants'' and `` atmosphere @ specialty restaurants.'' That turned out to be too vague. People tipped more in restaurants that accepted credit cards and those that served alcohol. Patronage at what the report called `` tip-type'' restaurants declined between 1983 and 1986, but tipping stayed level. There was a shift to establishments where people do not normally leave tips. `` Total eat-in and carryout occasions at hamburger, pizza and chicken places increased from 4.06 million in 1983 to 4.77 million in 1986, an increase of more than 17 percent,'' the study said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 1452EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People Sub a0644 08-27 0187</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People, Sub, a0644,0191</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS DERRY, N.H.-dated d4th item to CORRECT in 2nd graf that
Shepard was first U.S. man in space, sted first man in space. ADDS 2 grafs
on end with background.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DERRY, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former astronaut <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON> was the big draw at an auction of his boyhood home. `` It's a happy day,'' said the man who made the first <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> flight into space in 1961, as he autographed the backs of pictures and seat panels of chairs for winning bidders Saturday. Someone paid $ 160,000 for the house, where <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON> has not lived since he entered the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Naval Academy in 1944. <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON>, who now lives in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, said his mother has purchased a smaller home near his sister in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. As one of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' first group of astronauts, <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON> made a 15-minute suborbital flight on May 5, 1961, becoming the first American in space. The previous month, <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Gagarin </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> became the first man in space when he orbited the earth. In 1971, <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON> was the fifth person to walk on the moon.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 1459EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Austria-Refugees     08-27 0567</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Austria-Refugees,0581</SECOND>
<HEAD>Austrian Authorities Say 180 More East Germans Crossed from Hungary</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE JAHN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Austrian officials on Sunday said about 180 East Germans had crossed the Hungarian border in a 24-hour period, despite increased attempts by Hungarian officials to stop them. In <LOCATION> Hamburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Welt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> am </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sonntag </ORGANIZATION> newspaper reported that Hungarian officials told their West German counterparts that there was rising Soviet and East German concern about the stream of East Germans fleeing through <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> officials, meanwhile, told West German radio that <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> had repeated assurances that no East German now in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> would be sent back against his will. Austrian police officials in <LOCATION> Eisenstadt </LOCATION>, about 10 miles north of the border, said that new refugees were arriving despite Hungarian attempts to keep cars with East German license plates away from the boundary, the <ORGANIZATION> Austrian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported. The officials were quoted as saying about 180 had crossed since Saturday. All East German cars approaching Nagycenk, two miles east of the border and 20 miles south of <PERSON> Eisenstadt </PERSON>, were being turned back by police, several refugees were quoted as saying. East Germans frustrated with the lack of domestic political or economic reforms and unable to emigrate legally to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> began fleeing through <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> into <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> early this summer. Their final goal is <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, which considers them citizens. The border between <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> is relatively easy to cross. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, a reform-minded Soviet bloc country, removed barbed wire and other barriers from the border in April in a symbolic opening to the West. Because <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> is an allied Communist country, East Germans can visit relatively easily. West German authorities estimate that more than 5,000 have fled through <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> since July. Hundreds of others refuse to leave West German diplomatic property in <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> unless guaranteed safe passage to the West. Like-minded East Germans are crowding West German embassies, consulates and missions in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, facing pressure from <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, tightened controls after East Germans massed in groups of as many as 500 and stormed border points. Authorities in <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> announced Friday that border guards would be bolstered by armed units of the Workers' Militia. But <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> is also interested in West German support as it strives to improve its trading status with West European countries and seeks convertible currency to modernize its economy. Hungarian Foreign Minister <PERSON> Gyula </PERSON> <PERSON> Horn </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Hungarian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> TV </ORGANIZATION> late Saturday his government can not guarantee East German officials that all those caught trying to escape through <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> will be returned home. <PERSON> Horn </PERSON> spoke after returning from <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>, where he and Hungarian Premier <PERSON> Miklos </PERSON> <PERSON> Nemeth </PERSON> met with Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> and Foreign Minister <PERSON> Hans-Dietrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s official news agency <ORGANIZATION> MTI </ORGANIZATION> said the talks focused on Hungarian trade ties to the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> and on the refugee problem. The refugee situation has resulted in months of bad publicity for <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Welt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> am </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sonntag </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Nemeth </PERSON> told West German officials that <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> was under increasing pressure from <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to resolve the problem. The paper did not elaborate. The newspaper said Hungarian officials estimate that about 20,000 of the 200,000 East Germans now vacationing in the country will seek to flee to the West. West German officials have urged <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s hard-line leadership to implement economic and political reforms to help stem the flow of fleeing East Germans.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 1507EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China 1stLd-Writethru   08-27 0768</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China, 1st Ld - Writethru,a0631,0788</SECOND>
<HEAD>Citizens Must Carry I.D. Papers as Hunt For Dissidents Intensifies</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 7th graf, `Public anger...' to delete extraneous characters;
picks up 8th pvs: Thousands of...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Security forces will begin stopping people on the streets and checking their identification papers in a new effort to round up dissidents, the official <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Daily said Sunday. Starting Friday, residents must carry identification papers whenever they leave home `` to be prepared for examination,'' the paper said. Drivers licenses also will be examined. `` Counter-revolutionary elements have not been thoroughly cleaned up and motor vehicles often are used as tools of crimes,'' the paper said. `` Therefore the martial law troops and police must, according to the law, stengthen inspections of motor vehicles and drivers.'' The order runs counter to a recent, although gradual, lessening of the security presence on streets of the capital since the June 3-4 military crackdown on pro-democracy protesters. Martial law imposed May 20 remains in effect, but most army checkpoints on city streets have been removed. Soldiers stand guard only around Tiananmen Square, the former center of the protests, and at key overpasses and intersections. However, local authorities appear concerned that college students and others who joined the seven weeks of demonstrations will use the Oct. 1 anniversary of 40 years of <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> rule to stage some kind of protest. Public anger over the army attack on the protesters _ in which hundreds or perhaps thousands were killed _ remains deep, although most people remain outwardly quiescent for fear of arrest or censure. Thousands of people have been arrested since the June crackdown, some disappearing with no word to their families. The hard-line officials who led the crackdown have shown no sign of easing their attacks on the ideological front. <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> <PERSON> Xitong </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Ximing </PERSON> instructed local officials in a series of meetings last week to keep up the fight against `` bourgeois liberalism,'' or Western liberal thought. They ordered leaders in all work units to `` mobilize the masses to make reports and expose clues -LRB- to the identification of -RRB- counter-revolutionary elements. `` The greatest danger in inspection work is to pause, to treat big matters as small and let small matters go, to give up half way,'' <PERSON> Li </PERSON> told one meeting, according to a <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Daily report. `` Our party and nation still face a life-and-death problem.'' <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> residents say there have been relatively few cases of neighbors reporting on neighbors, as was common in the 1966-76 leftist Cultural Revolution and earlier political campaigns. They say many work units are quietly covering for members who took part in the protests, and even some police are reported to be dragging their feet in making arrests. National party chief <PERSON> Jiang </PERSON> <PERSON> Zemin </PERSON> and Education Minister <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Tieying </PERSON> showed concern about the mood on campuses by visiting students at one of the capital's leading schools, <ORGANIZATION> Qinghua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. Sunday's national and local newspapers quoted <PERSON> Jiang </PERSON> as assuring a group of <ORGANIZATION> Qinghua </ORGANIZATION> students in a four-hour meeting Friday that the party's current policy of classing intellectuals among the working class would not change. During the first decades of Communist rule, intellectuals were not classed with workers but were instead vilified as bourgeois. <PERSON> Jiang </PERSON> said most students are fervent patriots, but said they lack political experience and too easily become conceited over their successes and discouraged over obstacles. A college student interviewed recently in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> said the despite the appearance of normalcy, people are scared. `` There's no law any more, no legal protection. They can just come and take you away,'' said the student. Many say they fear the soldiers. Others fear the telephone hotlines and the boxes in every work unit to report people to the authorities. One man noted that any one could put a neighbor's name in a box and accuse him of throwing stones at soldiers, and the police would come to arrest him. He, like many other people, told of friends who were hauled away, beaten and interrogated. `` The police beat first and ask questions later,'' he said. <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> residents also worry about the miles of footage shot during the weeks of demonstrations by police crews and cameras mounted on main streets. Police now are studying the film, and many people wonder if their faces will be found. One elderly man, persecuted during the Cultural Revolution, was asked by a foreigner how the police could find a single person in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s population of about 10 million. He waved his hand and looked away impatiently _ to show what a silly question that was.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 1523EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Brites     08-27 0418</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brites,0436</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bright &amp; Brief</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AUSTIN, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This city has gained national pre-eminence in waste. No, not frivolous spending, but real human waste. The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> has bestowed the National Award for Beneficial Reuse of Sludge on <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>, acting director of the city's <ORGANIZATION> Wastewater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treatment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, said last week: `` It may be sludge to you, but it's our bread and butter. It's a resource.'' Through a complicated _ and smelly _ scientific process, <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION> turns its 250 tons of sludge per month into fertilizer for city park grass and crops that feed cattle. The city also turns human waste into compost, which has been dubbed `` Dillo Dirt'' to entice residents to pay for something they flushed down the toilet three months ago. <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dillo </PERSON> <PERSON> Dirt </PERSON> was selected because `` calling it Human Doo-Doo would n't have been too appetizing.'' Dillo is short for armadillo, in honor of the critters that proliferate in the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> countryside. Bond credits engineer <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Doersam </PERSON> as the person `` most responsible for the success'' of the Dillo Dirt program. <PERSON> Doersam </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> award shows <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> has turned a nasty situation around. For 30 years, the city disposed of its sludge in large lagoons. By the early part of this decade, <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> was knee-deep in something, and it was n't civic pride. `` You can only put so much sludge in a pond before it comes back to haunt you _ which it did,'' he said. <PERSON> Doersam </PERSON>, who friends call `` The Sludge Guru,'' says he's thrilled about the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> award and thinks the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> might have something new to brag about. `` This will attract a lot of visitors!'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>EATONTOWN, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Big <PERSON> Zac </PERSON>,'' weighing in at 4.27 pounds, pulverized his opponents at the stake and made a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> woman top manager for a third time in the contest to find the beefiest tomato. <PERSON> Minnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Zaccaria </PERSON> won $ 1,100 Saturday in the 12th annual New Jersey Championship Tomato Weigh-In. She described winning for a third time as `` overwhelming.'' `` I really did n't think I was going to win it today,'' Ms. <PERSON> Zaccaria </PERSON> said. `` It was quite thrilling.'' Ms. <PERSON> Zaccaria </PERSON>, who also won the contest in 1986 and 1988, earned $ 1,000 for finishing first and $ 100 for having the largest homegrown tomato in <LOCATION> Monmouth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, said contest organizer <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Heimbold </PERSON>. `` She is a fantastic gardener,'' <PERSON> Heimbold </PERSON> said. `` Maybe if she had left it out on the vine a few more days, maybe it would have been five pounds.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890827-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-27-89 1524EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Kiko     08-27 0372</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Kiko,0383</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hurricane Weakens to Tropical Storm Over Baja Mountains</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LA PAZ, Mexico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
