<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-FloridaCrackdown     07-01 0255</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Florida Crackdown,0263</SECOND>
<HEAD>Florida Sheriffs Crack Down On Cocaine</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JACKIE HALLIFAX</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of local law enforcement officers were buying and selling cocaine Friday in sting operations across the state aimed at slowing down street-level drug traffic. Operation Rock Pile made at least 480 arrests Friday during its first night. `` To our knowledge it's the first time anything like this has been done,'' <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Crolius </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Broward </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff's spokesman, said in a telephone interview from the <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> command center. The <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriffs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> organized the operation. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Doyle </PERSON>, an assistant project director with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriffs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said he had never heard of local law enforcement agencies working together in a statewide effort _ although other states have had statewide operations organized from a state level. Fifteen city police departments and at least 61 of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s 66 sheriff's departments are participating, according to <PERSON> Crolius </PERSON>, who estimated that more than 1,000 officers were involved in the project. <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, which has a countywide police department rather than a sheriff's office, is also participating. The crackdown was scheduled to end midnight Saturday. The operation is targeted equally at buyers and sellers, and includes both `` buy busts,'' which result in the arrests of dealers, and reverse stings, which result in the arrests of users. Search warrants will be served as well. Most arrests will probably be made in urban areas like <LOCATION> Broward </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> counties, the <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION> area and <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Petersburg </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Crolius </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Bolivia     07-01 0316</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bolivia,0325</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Arrest Members Of Group That Killed Two U.S. Missionaries</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LA PAZ, Bolivia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities have arrested members of a Marxist group that killed two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> missionaries and bombed the motorcade of ex-U.S. Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> during a visit last year, the government said. `` In recent days, we apprehended three important members of the group <PERSON> Zarate </PERSON> <PERSON> Willka </PERSON>,'' one of whom confessed to the motorcade attack, Interior Minister <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Beltran </PERSON> told a news conference Thursday night. The <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zarate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Willka </ORGANIZATION> claimed responsibility for the killings in May of <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON>, both 20-year-old Mormon missionaries from <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>. Police found a copy of the group's message to the media on the killings when they searched the residence of brothers <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nestor </PERSON> <PERSON> Encinas </PERSON> <PERSON> Laguna </PERSON>, the interior minister said. Authorities also found explosives and detonators there. <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Encinas </PERSON> <PERSON> Laguna </PERSON>, a sociology student, and his brother, a member of the technical faculty at a local university, were at large. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Beltran </PERSON> said sociology student <PERSON> Constantino </PERSON> <PERSON> Uujra </PERSON>, alias <PERSON> Pancho </PERSON>, was arrested. The interior minister said the suspect confessed to the attack in August last year during <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s visit. In the attack, an assailant threw an explosive device near the motorcade taking <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> from the airport to the city center. The blast broke the windows of some vehicles but there were no injuries. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Beltran </PERSON> said authorities also arrested the group's ideologue, physician <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rojas </PERSON>, and medical student <PERSON> Telma </PERSON> <PERSON> Salazar </PERSON>, identified as another group member Ball, of <LOCATION> Coalville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Wellington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, were gunned down late May 24 as they returned to their apartment in downtown La Paz. The two were machine gunned by occupants of a small yellow car. <PERSON> Zarate </PERSON> <PERSON> Willka </PERSON> is named after a leader of a civil uprising in 1890 against a law permitting the sale of communal land used by peasants.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ChurchofChrist     07-01 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Church of Christ,0186</SECOND>
<HEAD>Black Woman Nominated For President of Denomination</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT WORTH, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A black woman was nominated Friday as a candidate for president of the 1.7-million-member <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christ </ORGANIZATION>. Delegates at the annual meeting in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> will decide Monday whether to choose the Rev. <PERSON> Yvonne </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Delk </PERSON> to succeed the Rev. <PERSON> Avery </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Post </PERSON> as the denomination's president. If she wins, Ms. <PERSON> Delk </PERSON> would be the first black and the first woman to be elected to head the denomination, according to The Dallas Morning News. She currently serves as executive director for the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. The Rev. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sherry </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> also was nominated Friday by the 17th General Synod's nominating committee. <PERSON> Sherry </PERSON> serves as executive director of the church's <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Renewal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. Post has headed the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christ </ORGANIZATION> for 12 years and is stepping down in October. Another black, the Rev. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, briefly served as president in 1977, but he was appointed to fill an interim term and was not elected. The annual meeting continues through Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HUD-Pool     07-01 0255</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-HUD-Pool,0264</SECOND>
<HEAD>LI Town Cancels HUD-Financed Swimming Pool</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>'s hometown on <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> will return $ 1 million in <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> funds that were earmarked to build a swimming pool, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported. Island Park officials requested earlier this week that their application for the pool be withdrawn, citing local opposition to the project and rising costs, the Times reported in its Saturday editions. The officials denied that the cancellation was spurred by a federal inquiry into HUD-sponsored projects on <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, including in <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, the Times said. Island Park was awarded the $ 1 million in grants for the pool last year after <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, a village resident, personally lobbied then-HUD Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, the Times said. The money for the pool came from <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s discretionary fund. In a letter to village residents last fall, <PERSON> DAmato </PERSON> praised <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s `` wise decision to approve this grant,'' the Times reported The pool was to have been built near a beach. An assistant to <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> secretary <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> was pleased the pool project was dead. `` We think the funds can be used for a purpose that will be more in line with assisting low-income individuals,'' <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Brunette </PERSON>, the assistant, told the Times. The Times said it got no answer to telephone calls made to <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>'s office Friday afternoon. In <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, investigators are looking into allegations that HUD-sponsored houses went to politically connected residents instead of to minorities, as had been planned.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-GangViolence 1stLd-Writethru a0808 07-01 0309</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gang Violence, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0808,0314</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Renew Mass Gang Sweeps on Eve of July Fourth Holiday Weekend</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 5th graf, `Police made ..., to UPDATE arrest totals, restore
dropped first reference for Detective Tony Celli.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELIZABETH COTE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police swarmed through gang-infested neighborhoods Friday night in the first widespread dragnet for drug-dealing street thugs since the highly-publicized sweeps dubbed the `` Hammer'' last summer. The eight-hour operation on the eve of the July Fourth holiday weekend targeted gangs in the three neighborhoods terrorized by gangs. Assistant Chief <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> told 300 officers at a 4 p.m. roll call that they should remember many residents are law-abiding citizens. Portable booking trailers were set up at the Police Department's Southeast Division station in the heart of the <LOCATION> Watts </LOCATION> district which was ravaged by riots in 1965 Police made 70 arrests in the first four hours of the operation, 30 of them narcotics felonies, and 19 of those arrested were identified as gang members, said police Detective <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Celli </PERSON>. Twenty vehicles lacking current registration tags were impounded, he said. `` We are here to enforce all the laws that are applicable,'' said <PERSON> Celli </PERSON>. Community outcry over gang thugs who keep residents prisoners in their own homes prompted the first full-scale police assault in April 1988. The 1,000-officer weekend sweeps continued at intervals through the summer. Mayor <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, a former police lieutenant sworn to a fifth term Friday, vowed during the first of the 1,000-officer gang task force sweeps 15 months ago: `` We are going to take these terrorists off the streets of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>.'' Gang violence continued unabated. More than one person died in a county gang-related killing for every day of 1988. There were 452 gang-related slayings in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> in 1988, surpassing the 387 gang-related murders reported the year before.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ComputerArt     07-01 0257</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Computer Art,0263</SECOND>
<HEAD>Computer Art Exhibit Opens at Computer Museum</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANA KENNEDY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Neon and videotape have replaced oils and watercolors at an art exhibit devoted exclusively to computers. More than 50 works by computer artists from around the world went on display Friday at The Computer Museum. The art, including two - and three - dimensional works, kinetic sculpture, animation and poly-dimensional works on videotape, runs until Among the works: the 144 neon lights that form <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> artist <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> X. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hauser </PERSON>'s `` wall-o-fish'' and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> artist <PERSON> Lillian </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwartz </PERSON>'s chrome-plated mobile `` Capricious Constellation.'' `` The one thing all these pieces have in common is that they've been created by both humans and computers,'' said museum spokeswoman <PERSON> Gail </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennes </PERSON> The exhibit titled `` Computer Art in Context'' is part of a conference on computer graphics sponsored by <LOCATION> Siggraph </LOCATION>, one of the world's leading professional associations of computer graphics researchers and practitioners. <PERSON> Hauser </PERSON>, 34, a glass blower by trade, arranged his neon work with the use of a computer that controls the lighting and shape of the design. <PERSON> Schwartz </PERSON> designed her giant mobile `` Capricious Constellation'' with the help of scientist <PERSON> Arno </PERSON> <PERSON> Penzias </PERSON>, who won the Nobel Prize for physics in 1978. The mobile is driven by a computer programmed to move it at random as if blown by winds. The Computer Museum officials say theirs is the only museum in the world devoted exclusively to computers and their impact on society. It includes 60 permanent exhibits, an animation theater and a multimedia robot show.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-OilSalvage     07-01 0723</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Oil Salvage,0744</SECOND>
<HEAD>Salvagers Don't Cry Over Spilled Oil, They Recycle It</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT DVORCHAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP National Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the inlets of <ORGANIZATION> Prince </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> William </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sound </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> workers flush gooey crude from the craggy shore back into the sea so it can be skimmed. The glop, which has the consistency of mayonnaise, is mixed with sediment, seaweed and other flotsam. But instead of being burned or buried, some of it is going to a <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> refinery where it can be salvaged as fuel. `` They're probably going to try to get every nickel they can, even if it's turned into asphalt, to try to recover some of their costs,'' said <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, a scientist with the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION>. `` I'd rather see them refine the stuff than incinerate it or put it in a landfill,'' <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. `` It's still fuel It still has heat potential.'' Nearly 11 million gallons of North Slope crude smeared Alaskan waters three months ago, and almost 1 million gallons of fuel slicked three sites within 13 hours last weekend. Environmentalists and oil company executives may cry over the spilled cargo, but salvagers are going to work recycling as much of it as they can. `` It's better to use it for it's intended purpose than have it otherwise foul the environment. Out of these tragedies, we'd like to see the best made out of a bad situation,'' said <PERSON> Clifford </PERSON> <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. The ooze is piling up after the latest tanker accidents. About 210,000 gallons of goop was put in storage tanks near <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, after the Panamanian tanker Rachel-B collided with a barge in the <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> Ship Channel. `` The material is relatively clean,'' said Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanographic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. In <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> has stored about 10 million gallons of fuel and a blend of oil and water skimmed from <LOCATION> Narragansett </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> after the Greek tanker World Prodigy hit <LOCATION> Brenton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reef </LOCATION>. The ship's owner is working on a salvage plan. `` Our job is to keep it out of the water. We're not sure how much can be recycled,'' said Lt. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON>. The stickiest problem may be the 243,802 gallons of gunk recovered from the <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> after the Uruguayan tanker <PERSON> Presidente </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> dropped anchor too soon and lurched into shallow water. The fuel is so heavy it must be heated before it can be pumped. When it mixed with water, the spillage congealed into basketball-sized, fudgelike clumps. The state of <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> set up four temporary disposal sites, and it probably will be buried or burned, officials said. `` That stuff coming out of the river is non-recyclable. It's ruined It has no value,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Caron </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Guardian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in Bear, Del. In the calamitous Alaskan spill, procedures are simplified because <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> owned the tanker and the cargo that gushed into the sea. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> has shipped about 2 millions gallons of goo that is 30 to 50 percent oil to <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> EnviroServices </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, for refining. The brew contains water, sand, seaweed and other junk scooped up by the skimmers, but it can still be refined into gasoline, kerosene and diesel fuel. `` We would expect to derive some useful energy out of it,'' said <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Dragnich </PERSON>, waste manager for <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION>. `` But the value of recovery is inconsequential in terms of the cost of the cleanup and environmental damage. You're trying to have the least overall negative impact.'' `` Once we remove the water and debris, it can be used in a wide spectrum of petroleum-related uses,'' said <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Banchero </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> EnviroServices </ORGANIZATION>. `` One of our foremost goals is to reduce the volume that has to be disposed of.'' <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> has been burning some non-recyclable oily trash at three small hospital incinerators in <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION> while it tries to obtain federal permits to fire up large furnaces on barges. Burial is costly because <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> has no hazardous waste sites; crude-tainted garbage is being shipped to <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>. Even recycling carries a high price tag. `` It's very costly to recycle oil loaded with lots of junk. The cost of refining may be way beyond the value of the oil,'' said <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Gould </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, an industry group.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-VegasCurfew     07-01 0654</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Vegas Curfew,0670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officials Hope To Cope with Strip Cruising</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT MACY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Faced with the wrath of crabby cabbies, miffed motorists and irate casino owners, officials hope a new curfew will detour thousands of cruisin' teens who transform the glitzy <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> into a giant parking lot. Two years ago the teen-agers were considered a nuisance by <ORGANIZATION> Las </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vegas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Metro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> as they tried to control cruising and congregating. `` Then we were talking about 500, maybe 1,000 kids on a weekend night,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Metro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Capt </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Connett </PERSON>, who is commander of the police detachment covering the Strip area. `` It was a manageable number. Now we're talking upwards of 4,000 kids on a given night. The problem has mushroomed out of proportion.'' The problem is blamed on the Strip's growing popularity among teens and the growth of the city _ from 300,000 eight years ago to more than 700,000 today. `` The numbers were overwhelming,'' <PERSON> Connett </PERSON> said. `` We tried to control the blocking of the Strip, but all we could do was herd them up and down the Strip, unless people were willing to hire 500 more officers'' to bolster the current Strip contingent of 16. Casino owners are unhappy because the teens sometimes hassle tourists, often bumping them into the busy Strip traffic, <PERSON> Connett </PERSON> said. Cab drivers complain it takes forever to drive a few blocks as teens drive side-by-side down the six-lane road at 5 to 10 mph, exchanging conversations, obscenities, even passengers. The traffic problem is compounded by the fact that 45 percent of the city's visitors come here by car _ leaving more than 10,000 cars, hundreds of cabs and scores of tour buses jockeying for position on any given weekend. In addition, teen-agers who used to cruise past casinos on <LOCATION> Fremont </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>, also known as Glitter Gulch, now drive the Strip because they were chased away by anti-cruising forces in the late 1970s. Flooded with letters from upset tourists and hammered by those who make a living from the city's $ 2.5 billion tourism industry, the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> huddled with county officials and police in search of a solution. `` It came down to finding a way to get the kids off the Strip earlier,'' <PERSON> Connett </PERSON> said. `` What we're talking about here is an ` adults only' park in a manner of speaking.'' The answer was a curfew restricting those under 18 from the Strip after 9 p.m. Fridays, Saturdays and holidays, unless accompanied by an adult. The curfew went into force June 23 and police reported many warnings, but no arrests for curfew violations. <PERSON> Connett </PERSON> said officers will warn teens about the curfew for an unspecified grace period before turning offenders over to juvenile authorities. Teens with legitimate purposes on the Strip, such as visiting restaurants, are exempt as long as they can explain their presence. Violators will be detained until their parents pick them up and repeat offenders will be sent to Juvenile Hall. Unhappy teens, who have become accustomed to sharing the neon-bathed Strip that some call a `` Disneyland for adults,'' have responded to the cruising ban with the generations-old response `` We have no place to go, nothing to do.'' `` That's idiotic,'' <PERSON> Connett </PERSON> says. `` It's the dumbest thing I've ever heard out of a kid's mouth This city has probably done as much or more for its kids than any city in the country. `` Some children could be in the center of <LOCATION> Disneyland </LOCATION> and say they have nothing to do,'' she said. <PERSON> Connett </PERSON> noted the city has snow skiing and water skiing 30 minutes away plus a water theme park, free parks, recreation centers, movies, ice and roller skating rinks, arcades and other attractions. But <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> teens _ or at least a vocal minority _ want to head for the flashy Strip to mingle with some 100,000 tourists who flock here each weekend.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-JunkDispute     07-01 0403</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Junk Dispute,0418</SECOND>
<HEAD>Elderly Woman Fights City in Dispute Over Can Collecting</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Honey <PERSON> Breske </PERSON> is trying to make ends meet by recycling, but prosecutors have taken the 92-year-old widow to court over the pile of trash in her yard. Now she is looking for a job to earn the money for the court battle. `` Spry ... widow seeking any employment,'' her advertisement reads. `` Need funds to fight Housing Court. They wo n't let me recycle cans for cash.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Breske </PERSON> placed the ad in a weekly newspaper after the city went to court to force her to clear debris from her yard, where she keeps aluminum cans, boxes and other junk she recycles to supplement her $ 369 monthy Social Security income. Her neighbors complained about the mess. `` I do n't think it's fair. These things did n't happen until our husbands died,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Breske </PERSON> said. `` Then they started picking on us.'' One of Mrs. <PERSON> Breske </PERSON>'s friends, <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunlap </PERSON>, is in trouble with the city for the same reason. The court has issued a permanent injunction against storing debris in her yard and issued more than $ 10,000 in fines over the last 12 years. `` I ca n't pay nothing,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Dunlap </PERSON>, 70. City attorneys handling such cases say many elderly residents are turning up in Housing Court, accused of creating dangerous piles of refuse in attempts to earn money. `` We have one to two cases every week with this type of problem,'' said <PERSON> Dolores </PERSON> <PERSON> Quiroz </PERSON>, the assistant corporation counsel prosecuting Mrs. <PERSON> Breske </PERSON>. `` And that's a conservative estimate. Sometimes it's one or two a day.'' The city gets involved in cases where debris poses possible fire and health hazards. `` It was not just a matter of cans and things like that,'' she said. `` The problem is that they keep collecting it, and it's causing serious problems with the neighbors. Mrs. <PERSON> Breske </PERSON> finds recyclable items by rummaging through alleys in her neighborhood. She started collecting about 10 years ago just after her husband, <PERSON> Harry </PERSON>, was hospitalized for a heart attack. He died five years later, leaving Mrs. <PERSON> Breske </PERSON> with a $ 45,000 hospital bill. She emptied her bank account and sold jewelry to help pay it. `` I went looking for a job a couple of times. When I told them my age, they said, ` What do you want to work for?''' she said. `` So I got tired of that. I said, ` I'll just go pick cans.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0027EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Canada-Jet     07-01 0123</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Canada-Jet,0126</SECOND>
<HEAD>United Jet Carrying 212 People Forced to Land in Saskatchewan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SASKATOON, Saskatchewan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> 767 jet en route to <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> was forced to land Friday in <LOCATION> Saskatchewan </LOCATION> because of engine trouble, airline officials said. None of the 212 people on board the jetliner were injured. Airport manager <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Restall </PERSON> said the passengers had to wait in the plane more than an hour after landing Friday afternoon while customs officers processed the unexpected visitors. Because <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> decided to repair the broken engine in <LOCATION> Saskatoon </LOCATION>, the airline arranged overnight hotel accommodations for the passengers, <PERSON> Restall </PERSON> said. The flight was expected to continue on to <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> on Saturday, he said. No cause of the engine trouble was given.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Eastern-Protest 2ndtLd-Writethru a0406 07-01 0816</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Eastern-Protest, 2ndt Ld-Writethru, a0406,0835</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eastern Strikers Airport Slowdowns; Lorenzo: `Not Dependent' On Pilots</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 5 grafs after 6th, `Airport spokesman ..., UPDATE with
Newark protest, Miami report; DELETES outdated 11th graf pvs, `Actions
were ...; picks up 7th graf pvs: `In New York ...</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police arrested at least seven striking <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> pilots and employees Friday as they stopped their cars in a baggage area at <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>'s big airport on one of its busiest days. `` It is a grassroots movement,'' said <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Weber </PERSON>, a spokesman for the Eastern pilots union in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. `` Some disgruntled Eastern strikers, including non-union people, are trying to show their frustration.'' Those arrested were charged with misdemeanors _ disobeying an officer and impeding the flow of traffic _ and nearly all of the arrested were pulled from cars at an Eastern baggage area at <LOCATION> Hartsfield-Atlanta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. Other strikers gathered signatures on petitions that called for a continued boycott of the airline, which has been crippled by a four-month strike. `` We asked them to move along, but they wanted to shut down this airport,'' said police Maj. W.B. <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON>. `` This was an obvious attempt by the union to hurt the citizens of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. We do n't like it, and we're not going to take it.'' Airport spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Braden </PERSON> said Friday was one of the busiest days in <ORGANIZATION> Hartsfield </ORGANIZATION>'s history, with about 140,000 travelers passing through the airport. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, about 300 Eastern strikers and supporters marched on Friday to <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> and blocked evening rush-hour traffic heading to the terminal of <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s sister airline. About 50 police wearing riot gear and holding night sticks tried to keep the crowd moving through the airport's roads, and another 50 tried to control Friday's rush hour traffic. There was no violence and no arrests were reported. `` The intent is to tell everyone in the whole world that <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s still on strike,'' said <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Borowick </PERSON>, president of Local 1445 of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Borowick </PERSON> said the union was under a court-ordered limit of 15 pickets per entrance, but marchers took over the four traffic lanes where passengers debark to get to <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION>'s departure counters for about an hour. Similar plans to greet <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> travelers with airport slowdowns failed to materialize. A few strikers drove slowly through <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, but they were moved along by special police teams. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s boss <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> warned that striking pilots who might want to come back to work likely will find they've already been bumped from their jobs `` We're not dependent on the pilots coming back, by any means,'' said <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s parent company, <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. Pilots union officials were to meet this weekend with management and <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s court-appointed bankruptcy examiner for talks on a contract agreement to end their walkout against the company <PERSON> Weber </PERSON> said the slowdown was n't sanctioned by <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s unions, which mark four months on strike July 4. But strikers from the pilots, flight attendants and <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> unions said they would drive their cars slowly through airport terminal areas on Friday afternoon, and possibly next Tuesday. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Gunther </PERSON>, operations director at <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, said extra police officers and tow trucks were called out to lessen traffic tie-ups. He said holiday travelers should leave an hour or so earlier than usual to allow for possible delays. `` If the unions pull off this blockade-type activity, my reaction would be they're making the traveling public the innocent victims in a labor-management dispute,'' <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Matell </PERSON> said. Eastern, meanwhile, was gearing up for a tripling of its daily schedule. With 79 daily flights this week, <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> was set to hit 226 daily flights beginning Sunday. `` We have to see whether they can make the announced schedule and whether they can sustain it for seven days,'' <PERSON> Weber </PERSON> said. `` Watch for canceled flights. They do n't have enough pilots.'' The carrier has been operating less than 10 percent of its pre-strike schedule of around 1,000 flights a day since the strike that started March 4. It filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy reorganization on March 9 and says it will rebuild as a smaller airline. In an interview Friday, <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> said any returning strikers would find most of the available jobs at the new, scaled-down Eastern were taken up by the 500 or so new hires and 300 who crossed picket lines who already are working and by other pilots who will complete training in the weeks ahead. Eastern also is near agreement with creditors over its plan to emerge from bankruptcy court protection as a scaled-down carrier that would require only about 1,700 pilots to operate by December at its target level of around two-thirds of its pre-strike size. That compares with the 3,600 that flew the pre-strike version. The unions are backing a buyout bid for Eastern led by <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> commodities trader <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Ritchie </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     07-01 0518</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0540</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the dog-eat-dog world of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> politics, the publishers of `` The Washingtonian'' magazine have decided to eat a little crow for calling the presidential pet the ugliest canine in the capital. `` Before you go away for the July 4th weekend, we would like to apologize for picking <PERSON> Millie </PERSON> the ugliest dog in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>,'' Editor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Limpert </PERSON> said in a letter delivered Friday to the White House. He also sent a gift of dog biscuits to the offended beast. `` You'll be pleased to know that our mail and phone calls are running about 99 to 1 in favor of <PERSON> Millie </PERSON>,'' he said. `` It's clear that our words were unpopular as as well as impolite.'' President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> jotted off a note in response: `` Not to worry! <PERSON> Millie </PERSON>, you see, likes publicity. ... Arf, arf for the dog biscuits.'' <PERSON> Millie </PERSON>, an English springer spaniel whose confinement and delivery of a litter of pups kept <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the part of the rest of the country in suspense earlier this year, was listed in a `` Best and Worst'' story in the magazine's July issue. The magazine called <PERSON> Millie </PERSON> the `` White House mutt.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> promised this week that <PERSON> Millie </PERSON> would get the last word in a book the first lady planned to ghostwrite for the pet. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> called <PERSON> Millie </PERSON> beautiful and said, `` I know how <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> felt with the attack on <LOCATION> Fala </LOCATION>,'' his dog.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DUBLIN, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Toads have invaded a street in this <LOCATION> Alameda </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> town and no one seems to mind. Thousands of thumbnail-size toads have taken over Spruce Lane and cover driveways, back yards, patios and the street. There are so many that residents have to take special care when walking and have given up mowing the lawns. `` They're just babies and we are afraid we'll run over them,'' said <PERSON> Jeanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>. `` When we go out, we just tippy-toe out of our house so we do n't step on them.'' Officials say the toads are nothing to worry about. `` They carry no diseases that we know of and they do n't particularly harm anything,'' said <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON>, a vector control supervisor Besides, toads enjoy dining on the same insects that can be pests to homeowners and gardeners, he said. The toads probably came from a nearby drainage canal, he said. Toad invasions occur occasionally, <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> said, but the reasons for sudden surges in toad population are unclear.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>GRAND RAPIDS, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> museum officials finally took a stand to retrieve a podium. Members of then presidential candidate <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s advance team borrowed it in September because it's bulletproof. Since then, museum workers have been trying to get it back, said <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> VanAllsburg </PERSON>, the museum's program director. `` I think it just got lost in the shuffle,'' said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Mackaman </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Gerald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION> and Museum. On Friday, <PERSON> Mackaman </PERSON> went public, telling WOOD-AM in Grand Rapids about his podium plight. Hours later, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> communications staff called to say it would be returned soon, although no date was given, <PERSON> VanAllsburg </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0155EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FernaldSuit Bjt   07-01 0619</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fernald Suit, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Settles Ohio Nuclear Weapons Lawsuit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has tentatively agreed to pay at least $ 73 million to <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> residents who claimed damage by radioactive contamination from a government-owned plant near <LOCATION> Fernald </LOCATION> that produces nuclear weapons materials. A lawsuit filed by five residents as a class action had sought $ 300 million. The settlement underscores the government's intensified effort to regain public confidence in its nuclear weapons program, which is run from 17 major plants in 12 states. Many of the sites are badly polluted from four decades of bomb making. The government has acknowledged that at least 383,000 pounds of radioactive uranium oxide dust had been released through faulty filters at the Fernald facility since the plant opened in 1951. The full extent of environmental damage has not been determined. <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Roselle </PERSON>, one of the attorneys for the 14,000 people living within five miles of the plant who are represented in the class action, said the settlement allows for an additional $ 5 million payment to nearby businesses if they can show lost property value. <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, the deputy energy secretary, said the terms were approved by <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> late Friday and would be presented to U.S. District Judge <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> next week. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> has said he would step up department efforts to resolve past environmental damage from nuclear weapons plants and limit future harm. `` It's a major concern to us,' said <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>. `` This whole idea of this lawsuit, with people being upset, diminution of property values _ all these kinds of things would not have occurred if we had done it right in the past.'' <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> earlier this week blamed his own department for disarray in the weapons program, saying key managers and supervisors lacked technical skills and some lacked the necessary discipline for safe operation of nuclear reactors. The congressman whose district includes the plant predicted more lawsuits by people who live near contaminated bomb factories. `` It's a tragedy that the taxpayers are bearing the brunt of 35 years of contamination and concealment,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Luken </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION> In the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> lawsuit, residents near the Feed Materials Production Center at <LOCATION> Fernald </LOCATION>, about 18 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>, said radioactive contamination from the uranium plant polluted soil, air and water in their area. They claimed this caused them mental stress and reduced the value of their property. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said he sympathized with the public's concerns about possible illegal pollution from nuclear weapons plants, but he expressed doubt about the <PERSON> Fernald </PERSON> claims. `` A lot of that is hysteria,'' he said. `` There really was n't, judging by what I heard ... a lot of hard evidence of anybody losing anything _ as a matter of fact, almost none.'' He said he believed the settlement, if made final, would be the first of its kind. Judge <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON> scheduled an Aug. 23 hearing on the agreement. If the judge approves the settlement, the government must deposit the money into four <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> banks no later than Oct. 15, said <PERSON> Roselle </PERSON>. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> jury in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> earlier this month recommended in a mock trial that the Fernald residents be awarded $ 136 million. The recommendation was issued as a non-binding verdict, a procedure used in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> to encourage settlement of a lawsuit before it goes to trial. The plant was run for the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> by </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lead </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, until 1986. The residents' group filed suit against <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lead </ORGANIZATION> and its parent company, but the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> has accepted responsibility for its contractor because of an indemnification clause in its contract, and the government has provided defense counsel to its contractor.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-CivilRights Bjt   07-01 0564</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Civil Rights, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Calls for Renewed Effort on Civil Rights</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, marking the 25th anniversary of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, says he will be satisfied `` with nothing less than equality of opportunity for all Americans'' including 36 million who have disabilities. `` While celebrating our achievements and recommitting ourselves to their preservations, we must recognize that the full promise of the civil rights movement has still not been achieved,'' he told 200 civil rights leaders at a White House ceremony Friday. `` The hard lesson of the passing years is that it has not been enough to wage a war against the old forms of bigotry and inequality,'' the president said before flying off for a long holiday weekend in <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> called on <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> `` to join me in a new partnership to reauthorize the <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> with a goal of launching a renewed civil rights mission.'' The commission's six-year authorization expires Nov. 30. Civil rights leaders <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hooks </PERSON>, <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Farmer </PERSON> attended the ceremony. The landmark civil rights law was signed by President <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> on July 2, 1964. The act banned segregation in public accommodations and paved the way for court action to end bias in hiring and promotions. Also in the audience was <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON> <PERSON> Parks </PERSON>, whose defiant refusal to move to the back of a <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, bus on Dec. 1, 1955, was an early milestone in the civil rights movement. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the gathering was `` not only to commemorate an anniversary, but to celebrate a movement, and to rededicate our efforts to the unfinished work of that movement.'' However, some civil rights leaders say recent <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decisions restricting affirmative action and making it more difficult to prove discrimination in the workplace have hurt the civil rights movement. `` There was more damage done to civil rights statutes in the last 2 -LCB- weeks than in the last 2 -LCB- decades,'' said <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Neas </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did not directly address civil rights leaders' concerns, but called for `` vigilant and aggressive enforcement'' of civil rights and said his administration wo n't tolerate discrimination. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> told reporters that justice had become `` more expensive, more distant and less likely to come'' because of the high court rulings. He said `` we need a meeting of some substance with the president to deal with legislative remedies to offset the impact'' of the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decisions. But some said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> seems more interested in defending the flag than the ideals the flag represents, alluding to his call for a constitutional amendment to outlaw desecration of the flag. `` So far they have put flag rights over workers' rights, over basic civil rights,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said after the ceremony. Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> earlier this week that the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration wo n't pursue legislation to overturn the recent high court decisions affecting civil rights, preferring to wait until their impact can be assessed. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said economic barriers affect the lives of the disadvantaged as much as the remnants of legal discrimination. `` For that reason, I continue to support affirmative action and minority outreach programs,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` We will be satisfied with nothing less than equality of opportunity for all Americans _ and the removal of final barriers to self-reliance.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0152EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     07-01 0898</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0932</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTA MONICA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two bandits who robbed <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> slugger <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> of money and a luxury car probably never realized the celebrity status of their victim, police said. `` They hit a citizen who happened to be a baseball star,'' police Sgt. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Miehle </PERSON> said. `` It was just a random deal.'' The outfielder and his wife were followed to their home in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monica </LOCATION> and held up early Thursday morning by a gunman and an accomplice. <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> handed over about $ 500 and his keys to one of the robbers, who then fled in the baseball star's 1988 blue BMW. No arrests had been made by Friday. <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>, 32, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>'s Most Valuable Player last year, and his 31-year-old wife, <PERSON> Joann </PERSON>, were unharmed.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Superior Court Judge <PERSON> Laurence </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rittenband </PERSON>, the `` judge of the stars'' who once vowed to remain on the bench until director <PERSON> Roman </PERSON> <PERSON> Polanski </PERSON> returned for sentencing, has turned in his gavel. <PERSON> Rittenband </PERSON>, 83, whose legal career spanned 60 years, presided over <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON>'s divorce, <PERSON> Marlon </PERSON> <PERSON> Brando </PERSON>'s child custody battle and a paternity suit against <PERSON> Cary </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>. `` I ca n't wait that long,'' <PERSON> Rittenband </PERSON> said Friday of his vow to wait for <PERSON> Polanski </PERSON>, the film director who fled to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> in 1978 rather than appear for sentencing after he'd been convicted of having unlawful intercourse with a 13-year-old girl. <PERSON> Rittenband </PERSON> said he has not forgotten Polanski. `` I'll quote a <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> opera: ` I've got him on my list. I've got him on my list. He wo n't be missed. He wo n't be missed.'''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON> has been charged with three misdemeanors, including battery, for allegedly slapping a policeman who pulled over her $ 215,000 Rolls-Royce Corniche and arrested her. <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Deputy District Attorney <PERSON> Eldon </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> said the misdemeanor charges lodged against Ms. <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON> on Friday accuse her of battery on a peace officer, disobeying a peace officer and having an expired driver's license. There were also two infractions, which are violations of the Motor Vehicle Code, alleging that she had an open container of alcohol in a vehicle and had an expired registration when stopped June 14. The charges carry various sentences upon conviction ranging from a $ 100 fine for the violations of the Motor Vehicle Code to a $ 2,000 fine and a year in jail on the battery charge. The actress maintains she was roughed up unnecessarily during the June 14 arrest and has threatened to sue the Police Department. She is scheduled to appear in Municipal Court on July 12.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BATON ROUGE, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON>, who became famous after her dalliance with the former <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>, drew little fire when she ventured into the hometown of the Rev. <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> this week. <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON>, now a traveling radio personality, spent Monday through Friday as a talk-show host at station WKJN. `` She took phone calls every morning and there were two sides. The number of people who support her were more than there were against her,'' said <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, general manager of the country-music station. Most of the calls were about <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>, whose <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> ministry crumbled after it was revealed he once had sex with <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON>, a former church secretary. <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON>, 29, said she had never talked to <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON>, whose television ministry also was shaken by a sex scandal, although she told her listeners he had many things to say about her when the <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> allegations became public.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four-time world boxing champion <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Duran </PERSON> pleaded no contest to a drunken driving charge in <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Court </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> felt we had an excellent case,'' his attorney <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said Thursday. `` But if we went to trial and lost, he would have to go to jail. He's very proud of his position in this community. He thought, ` How would it look for <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Duran </PERSON> to go to jail?''' The Panamanian middleweight got the standard sentence for a first offense: six months' probation with a suspended license, 50 hours of community service, drunken driving school and a $ 250 fine. He was arrested Jan. 14 when <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> police saw him weaving. A breath test indicated his blood-alcohol level was .13. In <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, .10 is considered legally drunk. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said the fighter remains `` a gentleman. Today, I could barely talk to him, he was so busy with the autographs.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW HAVEN, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Television talk-show host <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> <PERSON> Jessy </PERSON> <PERSON> Raphael </PERSON> is leaving <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> for the Big Apple so her show can draw more big-name guests, according to her producers. `` We have an obligation to our audience to give them celebrities _ and we ca n't, because they ca n't come to us. This move allows us to give the audience a better program,'' <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Dubrow </PERSON>, executive producer of `` <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> <PERSON> Jessy </PERSON> <PERSON> Raphael </PERSON>,'' said Friday. Since the show moved to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Haven </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> in June 1987, the number of television stations carrying it has nearly doubled, to about 170, according to the program's producers and syndicators, Multimedia Entertainment. <PERSON> Raphael </PERSON> earned her first Emmy on Thursday after 33 years in the broadcast industry. She won for best daytime television talk-show host. The last taping of a show in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Haven </LOCATION> will be Aug. 16, and the producers hope to begin airing from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on Sept. 25.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0154EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChappaquiddickJurors     07-01 0621</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chappaquiddick Jurors,0639</SECOND>
<HEAD>Grand Jurors Say They Were Held Back In Kennedy-Chappaquiddick Probe</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN COOPERMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nearly 20 years after Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s car plunged off the bridge at <LOCATION> Chappaquiddick </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, several grand jurors who investigated the accident have come forward to say the district attorney hindered their probe. One of the jurors, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Maciel </PERSON>, said Friday that there was a `` cover up'' in the case, but said he believed <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was the victim, not the perpetrator. `` I think the man is innocent,'' <PERSON> Maciel </PERSON> said. `` I do n't believe <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was driving that car. I think he took the blame for somebody else.'' <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Kopechne </PERSON>, a 28-year-old secretary, was a passenger in <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION>'s Oldsmobile when it skidded off Dike Bridge in <PERSON> Martha </PERSON>'s Vineyard on July 19, 1969 Trapped in the vehicle, she drowned in 8 feet of water in a tidal pond. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Democrat, who did not report the accident to police until 10 hours later, received a suspended sentence for leaving the scene. <PERSON> Maciel </PERSON> and the grand jury foreman, <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>, said former District Attorney <PERSON> Edmund </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinis </PERSON> prevented the 23-member jury from calling several key witnesses, including <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and his cousin, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Gargan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, because they had previously testified at an inquest. <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>, a 49-year-old pharmacist on <PERSON> Martha </PERSON>'s Vineyard, said <PERSON> Dinis </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Dukes </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> prosecutor, also refused to let the grand jury read the transcript of the inquest. `` When those two avenues were closed off, there was nothing for us to do really but go home,'' <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Dinis </PERSON>, who is now in private practice in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION>, did not return telephone calls from The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> to his home and office Friday. He previously has denied stonewalling the investigation and has said there was not enough evidence to justify indicting <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> for manslaughter. <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> and <PERSON> Maciel </PERSON> said they have spoken out after two decades because they want the truth to come out and to clear the grand jury's name. `` I've lived with this thing for 20 years, and there have been all these innuendos that we were bought off,'' <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> said. `` The bottom line is, the grand jury tried its hardest to get to the truth, but we were not able to do our job.'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> has said he made a wrong turn that night and ended up on the narrow Dike Bridge. He also has said that he and a friend repeatedly dove to the car in unsuccessful rescue attempts, and that afterward he was `` exhausted and in a state of shock.'' <PERSON> Maciel </PERSON>, who owns a boatyard on <PERSON> Martha </PERSON>'s Vineyard, said he did not believe that <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, a frequent visitor to the island, would have made that wrong turn. He said he did not know why <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> would have taken the blame for someone else, `` unless it was someone very young.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Standard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bedford </ORGANIZATION> also reported Friday that several other jurors have backed statements by <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> criticizing the investigation. `` It was a coverup,'' said <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Mayhew </PERSON>, a grand juror now living in <LOCATION> Mattapoisett </LOCATION>. `` I support every single word Mr. <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> said. Everybody covered for <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> was quoted in the July 3 issue of <ORGANIZATION> Newsweek </ORGANIZATION> as saying that two unidentified `` key lawmen'' took him for a ride and told him there was no need for a thorough investigation. He said Friday he stood by that account. <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosher </PERSON>, a Tisbury housewife, told the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bedford </ORGANIZATION> newspaper that the jury experience left her `` disgusted.'' `` What took place, took place, but it should've been handled differently,'' she said. `` I got a lot of questions from people, but I'd say nothing. People said ` you got paid off' and all that, but I let it go over my head.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HUD-Probe Bjt   07-01 0548</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-HUD-Probe, Bjt,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Inspector General Says HUD Ignored Warnings</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENISE CABRERA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>'s inspector general says the agency ignored repeated warnings for tighter controls on lenders in a troubled program now under <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> investigation. `` On at least five occasions ... we have reported to <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> management and to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that program improvements were needed,'' said <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Inspector General <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> as the House Government Operations housing and employment subcommittee began hearings Friday on the program. The program, known as `` coinsurance'' because the government assumed part of the liability on loans with lenders, showed signs of problems two years after it was instituted in 1983 as a hallmark of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration efforts to turn the functions of many government programs over to private business. A November 1985 internal audit of eight projects showed `` inappropriate lender underwriting practices caused inflated mortgages,'' <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said. The subcommittee has been examining possible abuse, influence-peddling and mismanagement in <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> programs during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> officials promised to `` improve lender monitoring processes and enforcement actions,'' although they rejected <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' assessment of the problems and said controls he suggested were so strict they would discourage participation, he said. Lenders are paid an annual fee of about 4 percent of a project's operating income as an incentive to repair, rehabilitate or build low - and moderate-income multi-family If a borrower defaults, lenders are responsible for about 20 percent of the loss while <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> picks up the tab for the remaining 80 percent. <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> now faces more than $ 100 million in claims against bad loans made in the program, said Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, D-Calif., subcommittee chairman In the most recent audit in March 1989, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> found the <ORGANIZATION> Benton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mortgage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, had misrepresented mortgage amounts and rents on 14 projects it had underwritten, creating an estimated $ 22 million in excessive mortgages, said <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>. He said the government would pay excessive subsidies of $ 37 million over the 15-year period of contracts for rental housing <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> had coinsured. <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> is one of three companies which has been placed on six months' probation from the program. Three companies have been suspended and three others are under review by <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> revealed Friday that <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> is the subject of a grand jury investigation, which he said he would not discuss. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said his first report of problems in the coinsurance program was sent to then-Assistant Secretary of Housing <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON>, one of several former <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> employees who was paid as a consultant on projects funded under the moderate rehabilitation program. Rep. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, D-Conn., observed that `` <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> used <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> in all of his deals,'' in that program Meanwhile, congressional pressure is mounting for a complete review of the housing department. One staffer said <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Banking, <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>, D-Mich., has sent a letter to panel members seeking authorization for an investigation Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, D-Calif., chairman of the Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs subcommittee on housing, said Friday he would vote for a probe of the `` scandal-ridden'' department And <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> would testify before his panel July 12 to discuss reform measures being developed in the agency.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0222EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SpacePlane     07-01 0259</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Plane,260</SECOND>
<HEAD>National Space Council: Don't Kill Space-Plane Program</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The National Space Council has decided to urge President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to keep the `` space plane'' alive but limit its development program to the testing of unproven technology. The program is aimed at the development of a plane capable of taking off from a conventional runway, going into orbit and landing on a regular runway. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> called it the `` <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION>'' for the projected two-hour flight time from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> proposed eliminating the project or transferring to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> most of the $ 427 million proposed by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget for the next fiscal year. The council recommended the project get $ 254 million next year, shared equally by <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said in its Saturday editions. A spokesman for Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, chairman of the council, said Friday night he did not have dollar figures for the recommendations. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> recommended $ 412 million, with $ 127 million from <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>. A council staff member who spoke on condition of anonymity said the program's focus had expanded over the past four years, so that nuts-and-bolts questions like payload were being considered before researchers had proven with an experimental craft that the plane would be able to fly at 25 times the speed of sound. Nearly $ 2 billion has been spent on the program over the past four years. Potential contractors have spent $ 700 million of their own funds.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0223EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PentagonReorganization     07-01 0304</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pentagon Reorganization,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cheney to Overhaul Pentagon Bureaucracy</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> is proposing a broad overhaul of top <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> committees that would give a small group the power to make major decisions, according to an administration source. <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION>, responding to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s request for a review of defense management, recently sent the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> a proposal to form an `` Executive Committee'' that would assume many of the powers of the current <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, the source told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> late Friday. `` We are waiting for the president's decisions,'' the source said. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, which advises <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION> on major weapons and budgetary decisions, would become the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Planning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> with a broader planning task. It would be subordinate to the Executive Committee, which would be comprised of the secretary, the deputy secretary, the undersecretary for policy, the undersecretary for acquisitions, the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION> and the secretaries of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>. `` These are the people who are setting the policy anyway,'' said the source, who spoke on condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> also would reorganize the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Acquisitions </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> in an effort to `` streamline the lines of authority in procurement in carrying out acquisition policies down through the service acquisition chiefs and program managers,'' the source said. The acquisitions board would scrutinize the cost and performance tradeoff decisions made in the early stages of a weapons program. The service secretaries would be dropped from the acquisitions board, `` cut out of the loop, but at the same time they would be put back in at the top'' through membership on the Executive Committee, the source said. The source largely confirmed an account of <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION>'s plans first reported Friday night by <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, a weekly journal of defense policy and politics.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0229EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-PLO     07-01 0452</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-PLO,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Hopes Tunis Talks Will Lead to PLO Help With Elections</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration says it is looking for help from the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> in holding elections on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>. `` If they can be responsible and constructive here in helping, great,'' <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman, said Friday while defending two unannounced meetings in <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION> with <PERSON> Salah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khalaf </PERSON>, the second-in-command to <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>. But supporters of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> accelerated their criticism of the expanded dialogue <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Pelletreau </PERSON> is having in <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION> with <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> officials. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dine </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said `` we are deeply distressed to learn that the administration has conducted secret meetings with the founder of Black September, one of the most brutal terrorists of recent years.'' <PERSON> Dine </PERSON> said in a statement that <PERSON> Khalaf </PERSON>, known also as <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Iyad </PERSON>, `` has publicly boasted of his terrorist deeds against Americans and Israelis and bragged about his ability to deceive the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' The head of the pro-Israel lobbying and research group called the meetings in <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION> `` a blow to the confidence necessary to move the peace process forward.'' <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reich </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presidents </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Major </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jewish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organizations </ORGANIZATION>, called <PERSON> Khalaf </PERSON> a `` notorious terrorist'' and said bringing him into the talks `` can only breed mistrust and cast suspicion on the depth of our country's longstanding commitments to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. On Thursday, Israeli Ambassador <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Arad </PERSON>, registered his government's regret and disappointment in a meeting with Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>. <PERSON> Arad </PERSON> told the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> specialist on the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> the meetings hurt prospects for holding the elections. The elections were proposed by <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> and endorsed by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> as a way of getting peace talks started. The idea is to have the 1.4 million Palestinian Arabs living under Israeli control on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> choose leaders who would negotiate temporary and local self-rule. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> would negotiate a permanent settlement in a second stage of talks. The <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> has publicly criticized the plan as a device to prevent creation of a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state. Spokeswoman <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> claimed only limited progress in the talks. `` I have no reason to believe that it has not been constructive,'' she said. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official said <PERSON> Pelletreau </PERSON> had held several unannounced meetings with various <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> officials and was likely to hold others. `` Our objective in the dialogue is to advance the peace process and to underscore our expectation that the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> will adhere to its renunciation of terrorism,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0231EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GenericDrug     07-01 0443</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Generic Drug,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drug Maker Says Product Safe Despite Lack of Full Test</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> pharmaceutical company says its employees appear to have won government approval for one of the firm's generic drugs for treating high blood pressure by substituting the brandname product for its own in comparison tests. `` It would appear that that is the case,'' <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Vitarine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pharmaceuticals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gardens </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, said Friday. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> said he believes the company's drug, which has been recalled, is safe. A congressman, however, said the case raises questions about the drug's safety as well as the government's drug approval process. The drug is a generic Dyazide, a widely prescribed treatment for high blood pressure. <ORGANIZATION> SmithKline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beckman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> developed Dyazide and marketed it for 20 years before the first generic version was approved two years ago. <ORGANIZATION> Vitarine </ORGANIZATION> was approved in February 1988. <ORGANIZATION> Vitarine </ORGANIZATION> recalled its product a month ago. At least three employees have been suspended, the company said. However, <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> said, preliminary results of a just-completed comparison study measuring the rate and extent of absorption of the two drugs shows that <ORGANIZATION> Vitarine </ORGANIZATION>'s product falls within an `` acceptable range.'' `` <ORGANIZATION> Vitarine </ORGANIZATION> has no reason to expect any safety or efficacy problems with this product. <ORGANIZATION> Vitarine </ORGANIZATION> has produced millions of dosage units since the product was first introduced in February 1988 and as of this date has received only six adverse experience reports,'' he said. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> declined to elaborate on the findings of the company's internal investigation, except to confirm that the company told the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> it suspected Dyazide was substituted for <ORGANIZATION> Vitarine </ORGANIZATION>'s product in comparison tests As a result, Dyazide would have been tested against only another sample of Dyazide. The chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> investigations subcommittee, which brought the possibility to public light Thursday, said the case raises questions about how the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> approves generic drugs. `` Events suggest that we can no longer be assured that the products tested are the products marketed,'' said Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, D-Mich., subcommittee chairman `` That such a simple but apparently effective fraud could have gone undetected raises some serious new questions about the safety and efficacy of these drugs, and about the law,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> acknowledged that it is investigating the company, but spokesman <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Nesbit </PERSON> said he could n't comment on the inquiry or address the safety of the <ORGANIZATION> Vitarine </ORGANIZATION> drug. An <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> source, who spoke on the condition of anonymity, said the agency doubted the generic version was unsafe because it had undergone other tests and no problems with people using it had been reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0244EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SexScandal     07-01 0518</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sex Scandal,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Alleged White House Tour for Male Prostitutes is Focus in Sex Ring
Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Secret Service does not know who authorized a private <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> tour allegedly given to members of a homosexual prostitution ring now under federal investigation, a spokesman says. The focus on private White House tours came after <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported that prominent <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> lobbyist <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Spence </PERSON> arranged tours of the White House _ once around midnight _ for friends and business associates. The paper reported in its Friday editions that one such group included two male prostitutes from escort services that are now the subject of an investigation by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cramer </PERSON> said Friday that staffers holding <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> passes can escort guests through the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wing </LOCATION>, site of the Oval Office, at special times. But he said records from the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, when the tour in question allegedly occurred, are no longer available. One unidentified man quoted by the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> recalled a tour late on the night of July 3, 1988. <PERSON> Cramer </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> did not know who vouched for the party that night because all White House records from the period, including visitors' logs, have been shipped to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> for eventual placement in the <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> library, which has yet to be constructed. The Times said credit card records it obtained show that <PERSON> Spence </PERSON> frequently patronized a homosexual prostitution network that ran the escort services. <PERSON> Spence </PERSON>, once a registered foreign agent for <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, is known as a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> power-broker whose parties during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration attracted prominent individuals including former <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>, journalist <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Koppel </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Lilley </PERSON>, the ambassador to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> confirmed Thursday they are investigating possible credit card fraud involving the escort services, which operated under names such as `` Dream Boys'' and `` Man to Man.'' The investigation is based on records seized in raids on a house in an upscale <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> neighborhood that police say was used by the services. Police seized numerous bank statements, credit card slips and a diary of the business. The Times reported the ring was patronized by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration officials and congressional aides. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Balach </PERSON> resigned his job as Labor Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s political personnel liaison to the White House on Thursday after his name appeared in the Times' original story on the investigation. <PERSON> Spence </PERSON> spent thousands of dollars on the escort services, the Times said. On Oct. 5, 1988, for instance, he made four separate payments totaling $ 1,525 with his <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION> card for male escorts from <ORGANIZATION> Professional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, it said. In the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, White House staff members can bring guests on private tours of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wing </LOCATION> on Monday, Wednesday and Friday between 7 p.m. and 10 p.m., after 1 p.m. on Saturday and all day on Sunday, <PERSON> Cramer </PERSON> said. Before a guest is cleared into the White House compound, a staff member must provide agents with information such as a date of birth and Social Security number.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0248EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-North-Juror     07-01 0391</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North-Juror,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge's Ruling Leaves North Sentencing Next Week</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge has cleared the way for <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s sentencing next Wednesday in the Iran-Contra scandal. North, facing up to 10 years in prison and $ 750,000 in fines, lost a bid for a mistrial Friday. <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said no evidence existed that a juror who gave the court inaccurate information was biased against the former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide. Juror <PERSON> Tara </PERSON> <PERSON> Leigh </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> responded ` no'' last Feb. 1 when asked whether she or relatives had been involved in court proceedings or an investigation. <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s lawyers disclosed after his trial that one of King's brothers had served time in prison for armed robbery and that the woman had testified before a grand jury in connection with the criminal investigation of her brother She testified Wednesday she forgot about the episode when she answered the courtroom questionnaire Feb. 1. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said in a nine-page order that King's testimony probably was n't believable, but that it did n't matter in deciding whether she was biased against <PERSON> North </PERSON>. `` The court can not credit King's testimony ... Her omission was knowing, but she had no desire to help or to hurt North or the prosecution,'' <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said in a nine-page order. ` No proof was presented indicating that King was unfair or that she failed in any way to serve conscientiously,'' he added. North was convicted May 4 for aiding and abetting an obstruction of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, altering and destroying documents and illegally accepting a gratuity. North had moved for the mistrial, saying King was prejudiced against <PERSON> North </PERSON>. ` She voted to acquit <PERSON> North </PERSON> of many felony counts,'' <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said of King. North was acquitted on nine other charges. The judge said that embarrassment and a desire to serve on the jury, rather than forgetfulness, were the reasons King failed to disclose the background information last February. <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s lawyers hired a private detective agency to investigate her background after she told a television interviewer she had used drugs, adding that she had stopped months before <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s trial. `` Situations of this type arise with some frequency in cases when the defense has ample resources,'' said the judge. `` They must be resolved in favor of the verdict when bias against the defendant has not been established in fact or by implication.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0250EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LukensSentencing     07-01 0418</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lukens Sentencing,0432</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congressman Sentenced In Sex Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BETH GRACE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lukens </PERSON> is confident of winning an appeal despite receiving a 30-day jail term for having sex with a 16-year-old girl, an aide said. The 58-year-old Republican was freed on a $ 100,000 surety bond Friday. Franklin County Domestic Relations Court Judge <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Solove </PERSON> sentenced <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION> to the maximum penalty on the misdemeanor charge of contributing to the unruliness of a child, but overturned <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION>' conviction of contributing to the delinquency of a minor <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarrell </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION>' chief of staff, said in an interview from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> that the dropping of the delinquency charge was a `` very good sign for our appeal.'' <PERSON> Solove </PERSON>, citing <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION>' apparent lack of remorse, told the congressman he was `` convinced you are a sex offender.'' The court was `` struck by the unwillingness of the defendant to recognize that he was not the victim,'' <PERSON> Solove </PERSON> said. `` You have refused to take that degree of responsibility.'' <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION>, who is divorced, was convicted May 26 for paying <PERSON> Rosie </PERSON> <PERSON> Coffman </PERSON> $ 40 to have sex with him at his <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION> apartment on Nov. 6. <PERSON> Solove </PERSON> sentenced him to 180 days in jail and a $ 1,000 fine, but suspended all but 30 days of the sentence and $ 500 of the fine. <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION> was placed on probation for one year. <PERSON> Solove </PERSON> said the suspended sentence and fine depend on whether <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION> follows terms of his probation, which require him to participate in sex offender programs and submit to testing for sexually transmitted diseases. <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION> left the courtroom without commenting to reporters. But <PERSON> Jarrell </PERSON> said the congressman had no need to show remorse. `` When Congressman <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION>' conviction is overturned at the appeals level, Judge <PERSON> Solove </PERSON> will then understand why he showed no remorse. He is innocent,'' he said. Mrs. <PERSON> Coffman </PERSON>, whose complaint about <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION> led to his indictment, was escorted from the room immediately after the hearing. She is serving a jail term for violating probation stemming from a 1983 drunken driving conviction. Conviction on a misdemeanor does not automatically bar <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION> from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. He has vowed to remain in office and pursue his appeal. Local Republicans have called for <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION> to resign, and the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ethics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> has been asked to investigate the case. <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION> served two terms in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> from 1967 to 1970, when he lost a bid for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> gubernatorial nomination. After 15 years in the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, he was returned to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> by voters in 1986.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0251EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AbortionConvention     07-01 0356</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion Convention,0365</SECOND>
<HEAD>Action Urged Against Growing Acceptance of Euthanasia ^With PM-Abortion
Consent, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KARREN MILLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BLOOMINGTON, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The National Right to <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s convention turned its aim from abortion to euthanasia, and members were urged to fight what one speaker called `` institutionalized heartlessness. `` Euthanasia is a clear and present danger in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bopp </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, general counsel of the committee, said Friday on the second day of the group's annual convention. Many who have strong convictions that abortion is wrong have n't taken such a firm stand on euthanasia, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dolan </PERSON>, a member of the steering committee of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION>'s Program in Human Rights and Medicine `` We have to protect the elderly and disabled as we would protect ourselves,'' <PERSON> Dolan </PERSON> said. `` There is a movement toward institutionalized heartlessness, contempt and disdain for caring. Euthanasia is the necessary terminus of this movement,'' he said. `` People have died of deliberate dehydration. The patients did not ask to be starved to death and were not terminally ill.'' Dr. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> argued that artificial administration of nutrition and hydration is not the same as using extraordinary medical means to keep a patient alive The <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> physician gained national attention when he refused a court order to withhold food and water from a 92-year-old Alzheimer's patient whose daughter wanted to end her life. <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> said it was important that physicians know they have the right to follow their moral and ethical conscience. `` Having a physician's role in society defined by legislators or attorneys is a terrible, terrible thing,'' he said. `` We are all responsible for our own actions regarding our own conscience.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Steen </PERSON>, the committee's executive director, urged members to oppose euthanasia as strongly as they do abortion. Withholding artificial administration of food and water `` is really starving people to death,'' said <PERSON> O'Steen </PERSON>. The logical next step would be lethal injection, he maintained. `` When we come to this point, it will be too late,'' he said. `` The time to act is now because society at large has not yet accepted the stark reality of what is being done.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890701-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-89 0153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-China-Tiananmen     07-01 0347</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-China-Tiananmen,0357</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tiananmen Square Re-Opens to Tourists</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRIL JONES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
