<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0026EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ManintheBazaar     11-30 0601</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Man in the Bazaar,0619</SECOND>
<HEAD>Who Was the Man Who Spoke Russian and Sold the Gun?</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man who spoke Russian entered a store in the bazaar, opened a black briefcase and produced an automatic weapon. After several minutes of negotiation, the shopkeeper paid him 200,000 afghanis, or $ 500, for the gun. When a reporter approached him in the street seconds later and addressed him in English, the man got into a green jeep without license plates and drove away. Who was this man? Merchants said he and dozens like him identify themselves as Soviet soldiers. Since the Soviet withdrawal was completed Feb. 15, they say, those `` soldiers'' have sold them at least 20 automatic weapons. Where the men are stationed, or what they are doing here, the shopkeepers can only guess. Diplomats from countries with close ties to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> say the only <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> soldier in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> is the embassy military attache. They say all the others left in February. The Afghan government's position on the issue has not been clear. On Oct. 14, the official news agency <ORGANIZATION> Bakhtar </ORGANIZATION> reported the presence of Soviet military advisers in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. It added that they `` only handle deliveries of arms and provide information on the specifications of arms and ammunition to the Afghan side, and do not take part in military operations at all.'' A day later, government spokesman <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Nabi </PERSON> <PERSON> Amani </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Bakhtar </ORGANIZATION> report was `` an error,'' that there were no Soviet soldiers in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. Another government official quoted an Afghan military officer as saying <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> soldiers operated a missile base on the outskirts of <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. He said the Soviets were unwilling to train Afghan soldiers to use the Scud rockets they provide, which require advanced tracking methods and use of computers. More than 1,000 Scuds have been fired and the government has credited them with important victories over Moslem guerrillas, according to diplomats in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> and neighboring <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence report has alleged that Soviets in Afghan uniforms operate the Scud base. Many diplomats discount the report and say Soviet soldiers no longer are engaged in combat in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. Some add, however, that Soviet officers direct the civil war and the operations of <ORGANIZATION> KHAD </ORGANIZATION>, the Afghan intelligence and secret police agency, at the Defense and Interior ministries. A communist bloc journalist who visited the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> frequently said he discovered Soviet advisers in several departments. `` Any country that is supplying billions of dollars a year to another country is not going to sit by and let that country direct its war effort,'' one diplomat said. Such influence by the Soviets over <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s security, politics and economy has created problems between the two governments. Afghan officials say privately that Soviet officials tend to treat them like colonial subjects, and a recent incident illustrates the point. Journalists were taken to a battlefield to see captured weapons. A Soviet bodyguard armed with grenades, an assault rifle and seven clips of ammunition accompanied a Soviet television crew. During the helicopter flight to <LOCATION> Lalandar </LOCATION>, 12 miles south of <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, the bodyguard, dressed in blue jeans and a combat jacket, ordered an Afghan officer to give up his seat and barked commands to the pilot. When a Swiss journalist snapped his photograph, the guard grabbed the camera and exposed the film. The journalist appealed to officials from the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>, who said they could do nothing. The ministry later protested to the Soviet Embassy. And the question still remains: Who was the man in the bazaar?
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 2348EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CraneCollapse 1stLd-Writethru a0753 11-30 0686</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Crane Collapse, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0753,0703</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brother Says Operator in Crane Collapse had Drinking Problem</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 14th, ``All of ..., to UPDATE with report
of drug tests.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES O. CLIFFORD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The operator of a crane that collapsed and killed five people said he was considering entering an alcohol treatment program to `` dry out'' after his work on the high-rise was over, his brother said Thursday. The crane operator, <PERSON> Lonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Boggess </PERSON>, was among those killed in Tuesday's accident. He had twice tried to commit suicide during the last nine months and had been hospitalized for psychiatric observation twice since March, according to court documents obtained by <ORGANIZATION> McClatchy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspapers </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Boggess </PERSON>, 45, died with three other construction workers and a school bus driver when the 240-ton crane he was operating plunged 16 floors in the bustling Financial District. <PERSON> Boggess </PERSON>' brother, <PERSON> John </PERSON>, said the machine operator had a drinking problem and suffered from stress related to his high-risk job. `` He told me he was considering admitting himself to an alcohol program to dry out after this job was over,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Boggess </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> coroner's office said Thursday that an autopsy would attempt to determine <PERSON> Boggess </PERSON>' blood-alcohol level at the time of death. It will be made public in two to three weeks, the coroner's office said. Family members were also `` concerned about, perhaps, a heart problem or stroke,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Boggess </PERSON> said from his home in <LOCATION> Exeter </LOCATION>, a small city in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joaquin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. But he conceded he had no specific information that his sibling, a heavy smoker, had a heart condition. `` We mostly were concerned about high cholesterol,'' said <PERSON> Boggess </PERSON>, a sales executive. He attributed his brother's problems to `` a bitter divorce and the stress of a high-risk job.'' Authorities were checking into reports that <PERSON> Boggess </PERSON> was seen slumped over the controls as the crane began its plunge. `` We're waiting for the coroner's report to find out whether there may have been a heart attack or something like that, because we have heard _ they are unconfirmed reports _ that someone saw him slumped over,'' said District Attorney <PERSON> Arlo </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. `` We're trying to find that individual, if there is somebody, who reported seeing that.'' <PERSON> Boggess </PERSON>' sister, 34-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Genoa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hefke </ORGANIZATION>, said she spoke Wednesday afternoon with a worker who was on the ground and in radio contact with <PERSON> Boggess </PERSON> before the accident. She said the worker told her that the radio suddenly went silent and that <PERSON> Boggess </PERSON> may have had a heart attack. `` All of a sudden he stopped answering, and then it started rocking back and forth,'' she said. The state <ORGANIZATION> Occupational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, said it is investigating reports of illegal drug use among workers at the construction job site, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Friday editions. <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fairburn </PERSON>, the agency's deputy director, said <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> would conduct toxicological tests on the bodies of <PERSON> Boggess </PERSON> and three other workers who died, the Times reported. <PERSON> Boggess </PERSON> was in the crane's cab 200 feet above the ground when the accident occurred. The crane was being raised from the 16th floor to the 20th floor of a high-rise under construction for the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>. The reports of <PERSON> Boggess </PERSON>' alcoholism and suicide attempts appeared in Thursday's editions of The Sacramento Bee and The Morning News Tribune of <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Boggess </PERSON> lived. <PERSON> Boggess </PERSON>' employer, the <ORGANIZATION> Erection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Kirkland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, refused to comment. Officials at <ORGANIZATION> Swinerton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Walberg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, the general contractor for the high-rise project, `` had no knowledge of his personal life,'' said company spokesman <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Duggan </PERSON>. The contractor said the accident apparently was triggered when the head of the crane accidentally rotated 180 degrees while the crane's height was being increased, an operation that requires the machine to be perfectly balanced. However, it said in a statement that the rotation occurred `` for unknown reasons.'' State officials say they are focusing on mechanical or human error, giving `` low priority to such factors as wind or structural failure,'' said <LOCATION> Hamilton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fairburn </LOCATION>, deputy chief of the state <ORGANIZATION> Occupational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-MiGsForSale     11-30 0387</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-MiGs For Sale,0396</SECOND>
<HEAD>Western Companies said Negotiating to Market Soviet Fighter Jets</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hungry for foreign currency and Western consumer technology, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is seeking to sell its MiG-29 warplanes in the West, a respected journal of military affairs reports. <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weekly </ORGANIZATION> says in its issue published Wednesday that Western companies are negotiating to buy MiG-29 `` Fulcrum'' fighters, first operational in 1985, for research and experimental purposes. The <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> recently hosted a joint venture group of six American, British, West German and Danish businessmen who could act as a sales outlet for up to 150 MiG-29s at $ 20 million apiece, <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>'s said. Quoting an unnamed businessman who participated, <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>'s said a <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> agency told the visitors that the `` whole range of MiGs,'' was available to Western customers, as well as the Sukhoi Su-25 `` Frogfoot.'' The MiG is named after the initials of its original designers, <PERSON> Artem </PERSON> <PERSON> Mikoyan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gurevich </PERSON>. `` Fulcrum'' and `` Frogfoot'' are <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> codenames. MiGs have long been a symbol of superpower rivalry. They featured in the Korean and <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> wars, in the Soviet-supplied air forces of <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> countries against the U.S.-supplied Israelis, and now in the Ethiopian civil war. Starting with the MiG-15 and leading up to today's MiG-31, each new generation and its Western rivals symbolized a fresh escalation of the East-West arms race. <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>'s said the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> declined to comment. The British <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said it knew nothing of the reported proposals. <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>'s said the businessmen's visit was prompted by the apparent grounding of MiG-23 `` Flogger'' aircraft said to be used by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> in aggressor training roles at <ORGANIZATION> Nellis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>. It said the U.S.-operated MiGs were reportedly obtained from <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> in an arms deal involving U.S.-made F-16s, and were grounded because of their poor condition. <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>'s quoted one of the businessmen as saying the joint venture group has already mediated to provide these MiG-23s with spare engines. A businessman was quoted as saying the Soviets were keen to sell modern warplanes to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> because they are `` almost desperate to bring in foreign currency and modern consumer technology such as telefax machines, microwave cookers, desktop and hand-held computers ... `` They used to request very large deposits, but now they're acting like normal businessmen.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--EGermanBard     11-30 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--EGerman Bard,0186</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prominent Singer Allowed to Return to Perform</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EAST BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a sign of further liberalization, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> says it will allow dissident songwriter and singer <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Biermann </PERSON> to perform in the country for the first time since his 1976 expulsion. The official news agency <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> said Wednsday that <PERSON> Biermann </PERSON>, who lives in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, would give performances in <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> on Friday and Saturday. Culture Minister <PERSON> Dietmar </PERSON> <PERSON> Keller </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Biermann </ORGANIZATION>'s visit had been approved `` at the wish of many East German artists.'' <PERSON> Biermann </PERSON> was stripped of his East German citizenship and banned from returning home after making critical remarks about the country's Communist government during a tour of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. He was allowed to make a three-day trip to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in 1982 to visit a dying friend. As recently as Nov. 4, East German authorities had prevented <PERSON> Biermann </PERSON> from attending a huge demonstration in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, turning him back from the border. <PERSON> Biermann </PERSON> became a symbolic figure for <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s dissident artists, many of whom emigrated to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> following his expulsion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0101EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Sino-SovietBarter     11-30 0150</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Sino-Soviet Barter,0151</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese to Barter Consumer Goods for Soviet Planes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A southern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> company will barter $ 94 million worth of clothes, electrical goods and daily necessities for six medium-range Soviet passenger jets, an official newspaper said today. The <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, a collectively owned company based in the special economic zone of <LOCATION> Hainan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, would soon sign the agreement with the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Import </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Export </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. It quoted the Chinese company's president as saying the three Tupolev-154 and three Yak-42 planes would be sold to local airlines in <LOCATION> Jiangsu </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fujian </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sichuan </LOCATION> provinces. The report said there was real potential for such deals since both countries are short of hard currency. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> would be able to supply consumer goods _ piling up due to a domestic economic slowdown _ to a <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> plagued by chronic shortages of such products.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Summit-Baltics     11-30 0613</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Baltics,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lithuanian Leader Seeks US Intercession With Moscow</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The head of the people's front of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION> says he expects President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to ask <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> for guarantees not to use force against peaceful independence movements in the Baltic republic. `` We have the right to be an independent state,'' <PERSON> Vytautas </PERSON> <PERSON> Landsbergis </PERSON>, chairman of the people's front, or <ORGANIZATION> Sajudis </ORGANIZATION>, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday. He said he asked <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policymakers to seek a commitment that the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> or <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> security police will not crack down on secessionist movements in <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION> or the neighboring republics of <LOCATION> Latvia </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION>. `` My information is that they will'' seek such a commitment, said <PERSON> Landsbergis </PERSON>, who met Wednesday with <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Seitz </PERSON>, assistant secretary of state for <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> Affairs. <PERSON> Landsbergis </PERSON>, in an interview with <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> editors and reporters, declined to disclose details of his discussions with <PERSON> Seitz </PERSON>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have not specified what <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will tell <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> when he meets with him in this weekend's shipboard summit off the coast of <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Landsbergis </PERSON>, a 57-year-old musicologist, praised the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for refusing to recognize the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s forced annexation of <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Latvia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION> at the end of World War II. The Soviet parliament this week passed legislation to give the Baltic republics a large degree of economic autonomy from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, a significant step toward independence. `` The recent legislation should mean we will be able to be less attached to the colonial -LRB- centrally planned Soviet -RRB- system, and should have more room to maneuver,'' he said. Last March, in the most democratic elections in Soviet history, <ORGANIZATION> Sajudis </ORGANIZATION> candidates won 36 of 42 seats allocated to <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION> in the national <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Landsbergis </PERSON> predicted that <PERSON> Sajudis </PERSON> would win a majority in elections scheduled for February for the Lithuanian parliament, which he said would then negotiate for independence from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. `` But <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> might not hear our declaration,'' he said. Therefore, <PERSON> Landsbergis </PERSON> said he asked <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials to seek guarantees of non-intervention and to raise the issue at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> or another international forum. `` We have received support from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for decades in that it has refused to recognize the legality of Soviet annexation. And that has had great importance to us,'' he said. `` Now that the <LOCATION> Baltic </LOCATION> issue has become a matter of international importance, we would like <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy to become even more active. `` We would like the <LOCATION> Baltic </LOCATION> occupation to be raised at the <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> summit as an international issue that has not been resolved,'' he said. `` Soviet efforts to portray the <LOCATION> Baltic </LOCATION> issue as an internal affair have failed.'' <PERSON> Sajudis </PERSON>' immediate goals, he said, are to `` have a pluralistic, multi-party system, and in conjunction with that, to eliminate the monopoly by the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and the privileges that go with it.'' `` The object is to re-establish sovereignty not only as an expression of our own legitimate right, but because we feel that it is useful for <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in general and also very useful for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` We already have that which we would call spiritual independence. Our people have lost their fear and openly speak their minds,'' <PERSON> Landsbergis </PERSON> said. Asked whether a sovereign <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION> would join the Kremlin-led <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION> military alliance, <PERSON> Landsbergis </PERSON> said, `` It is possible that it will be a condition for gaining our independence.'' Soviet and Lithuanian negotiators will sit down at a bargaining table in the foreseeable future to hammer out details of Lithuanian independence, he predicted, `` and it may well be that <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> will make entry into the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact one of the conditions.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MXMissiles Bjt   11-30 0704</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-MX Missiles, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Six New Sites Chosen for Rail-Based MX</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, as President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> departs for the <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> summit with <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, says it will move ahead with plans making the giant MX nuclear missile a rail-mounted weapon. The 50 intercontinental ballistic missiles _ which are to be stored at military sites scattered around the country and moved on trains during times of crisis _ are designed to launch a devastating retaliation in the face of any Soviet attack. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> announced Wednesday that the 50 missiles in underground silos in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> will be moved to `` garrisons,'' or shelters, at military installations in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. The dispersal will allow the weapons to survive a surprise strike, the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> argued, as well as provide `` the potential for prompt retaliation vital to the successful deterrence of war.'' The new system is expected to be completed by 1994, the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> said. The Soviets have two land-based mobile ICBMs, the SS-25 and SS-24. The 50 MX missiles _ dubbed the `` Peacekeeper'' by former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> _ will be placed on 25 trains, each with two MX missiles aboard. The trains will be kept on seven <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> bases and moved onto civilian railroad tracks in time of crisis. The announcement came Wednesday as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> prepared to depart for his <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> meeting with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> said the meeting will permit the leaders `` to be in much better shape and much better prepared'' to reach an agreement on slashing such long-range weaponry at their second summit set for next year. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet leaders have expressed hopes of signing an agreement at that later meeting to cut strategic weapons by as much as 50 percent. But Wednesday's announcement also represents the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's commitment to push ahead with plans to modernize the nation's strategic nuclear missile force, even amid projections of <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> belt-tightening, heightened prospects for arms-control agreements and sweeping changes in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and its <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact allies. The new basing system is the latest step in the controversial missile's 18-year history. The MX _ which stands for missile experimental _ was first proposed in 1971. In its early development, it was seen as a mobile missile designed to prevent the Soviets from knowing where to aim to destroy it. Subsequently, the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> studied more than 30 `` basing modes,'' including trucking it around the country, submerging it in lakes, or keeping it airborne on special planes. In 1979, President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> proposed shuttling the weapon on `` racetracks'' in southern <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and eastern <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, but <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> rejected that plan in 1981. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, in a four-year battle with the administration, slashed <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s request for 100 of the missiles to 50, and they were placed in hardened underground silos. In 1986, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> proposed shifting to the rail-based system advocated by the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>. Earlier this year, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> opted to move forward with two mobile intercontinental ballistic missile systems by putting the 10-warhead MX on trains while also building the smaller, truck-based Midgetman. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s decision has run into considerable opposition in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> _ both among those who contend the two-prong program is too expensive and among those who favor one weapon or the other. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> signed a military spending bill last week that establishes a $ 1.1 billion fund for both the MX and the Midgetman, with the exact spending split left to <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>. The cost of taking the nation's 50 MX missiles out of their underground silos at <ORGANIZATION> Warren </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> and building the new `` garrisons,'' or shelters, is expected to be at least $ 5.6 billion, said a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> source who requested anonymity. `` Hopefully, it will be completed by 1994, but that clearly depends on the budget,'' the source said. The Pentagon said the missile trains will be housed at <LOCATION> Warren </LOCATION> and these other <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> bases: <PERSON> Barksdale </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Dyess </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, Fairchild in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Forks </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wurtsmith </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> AFB </PERSON> will be the center of the MX operation and the training site for the garrison crews.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     11-30 0656</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rail Car Shortage May Affect Agriculture</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One of the biggest agricultural problems of the next decade will be a shortage of railroad cars for transporting grain, a railroad spokesman says. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Howarth </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> CSX </ORGANIZATION> assistant vice president, said Wednesday that his company has about 13,000 covered hopper cars, but that nationwide the fleet is shrinking. <ORGANIZATION> CSX </ORGANIZATION>, one of the nation's largest freight railway companies, operates between the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and as far south as <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Howarth </PERSON> said railroad companies do n't get enough profit from hauling grain, and that big freight companies will abandon more and more lines for lack of business in many rural areas. `` You ca n't get away from the fact that the railroad system was overbuilt for today's transportation,'' <PERSON> Howarth </PERSON> said, adding that his company supports the growth of shortline rail companies to carry products short distances or to larger freight train systems. <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said some business might return to railroads as the cost and congestion of trucking increases. <PERSON> Howarth </PERSON> and <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> spoke at Outlook'90, a three-day conference sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to examine farm policies and factors that affect them. <PERSON> Howarth </PERSON> said that when <ORGANIZATION> CSX </ORGANIZATION> decides to discontinue a line, it looks for a shortline operator to take over. `` We want to see as many lines as possible continue operating,'' he said. `` Shortline owners are sometimes public entities, but 90 percent tend to be private owners who feel they can make a go of a piece of railroad that a big company ca n't.'' <ORGANIZATION> CSX </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Howarth </PERSON> said, recommends that grain companies buy their own railroad cars to ensure transportation is available. During another segment of the conference Wednesday, a housing consultant described the plight of elderly farm workers who often find themselves with no money and no home when they retire. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Belden </PERSON>, deputy executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, said a study he conducted showed no federal housing projects exist specifically for farm workers. Although they often qualify for subsidized housing under other programs, the biggest problem is that farm workers tend to stop working about age 45 rather than 62 as required to qualify for retirement housing under many federal programs. `` Because of the working conditions, this group is going to be older at a younger age,'' <PERSON> Belden </PERSON> said, describing the back-breaking toil and harsh lifestyle of migrant farmworkers. He said there was anecdotal evidence to show that many farm workers do n't get Social Security benefits, either because their employers never withheld payments from their wages or because they were stolen by dishonest employers. Another problem facing rural planners is poverty among children. <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> demographer, said studies show that since the late 1970s there has been an increase in poverty among both urban and rural occupants. <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said that in 1987 about 24 percent of the children in rural areas were below the poverty line. Another 9 percent were considered `` near poor,'' which means they are either right at the poverty line or in families that make just 149 percent of the poverty threshold. The poverty threshold of a three-person family with one child under 18 was $ 9,142 in 1987 and for a four-person family with two children under 18 it was $ 11,519. <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said much attention had been paid to the breakdown of families in central cities, but statistics show that the number of rural children living with just one parent also has increased _ from 14 percent in 1960 to 25 percent in 1988. About 29 percent of urban children live with one parent. Rural development policies need to include education and employment that lead to greater earnings for parents and improved financial conditions for their children, <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said. `` The type of childhood experienced in the rural community will undoubtedly affect the decisions of the next generation about remaining in the community,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-Security     11-30 0694</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Security,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Superpower Summit Security Huge Task for Tiny Nation</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Summit-Bush, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRY LEONARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VALLETTA, Malta (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Providing security for the superpower summit is a huge task for this tiny country, which will dedicate its entire military and most of its police to protecting the American and Soviet presidents. The shipboard location of this weekend's summit between President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Marsaxlokk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> has added to security problems and stretched Maltese resources, one official said. But Prime Minister <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Fenech </PERSON> <PERSON> Adami </PERSON> and others say no special security problems are posed by <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, which is about 220 miles north of <LOCATION> Marsaxlokk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>, or by the ability of Libyans to travel freely here. Maltese officials say they are confident their 1,200-member armed forces and 1,800-member police force can protect the leaders during their three-day stay. `` I think our police forces and armed forces are equipped enough and trained enough to provide the necessary security,'' <PERSON> Fenech </PERSON> <PERSON> Adami </PERSON> said in an interview Wednesday. `` Being a small country does not mean that security problems are larger,'' he said. `` In fact, on the contrary, being a small country, both as to the size of the country itself and the size of the population, can render security less of a problem.'' <PERSON> Fenech </PERSON> <PERSON> Adami </PERSON>, who met with Libyan Col. <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> on Sunday in <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> is in favor of the summit and objects only to it being held on warships in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION>. `` I see no special security threat,'' said armed forces commander Brig. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Spiteri </PERSON>. `` We've always had good relations with the Libyans. ... They have never given us any trouble and there is no reason to suppose they will this time. `` We have n't identified a serious threat from anybody,'' said <PERSON> Spiteri </PERSON>, who commands the security operation. `` But, of course, that can make security concerns more difficult.'' <PERSON> Spiteri </PERSON> said that if there were a specific threat against either <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> or <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> during the summit meetings Saturday and Sunday, authorities could look for it and plan accordingly. One senior government official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said holding the summit aboard the guided missile cruiser USS Belknap and the Soviet missile cruiser <PERSON> Slava </PERSON> had added to security concerns. `` If the summit was only on land, you have just one restricted area to close off,'' the official said. `` But since the leaders will be moving on the island and staying on the ships, we will have to close off areas both on the land and the water.'' He said the government will close the port to commercial traffic _ other than small fishing vessels _ for the three days the leaders are in <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>, and close the air space above the harbor to private aircraft. For security reasons, the government has stopped work on a construction project inside the harbor that employed 800 workers, who still will be paid. <PERSON> Spiteri </PERSON> said one Maltese boat will patrol outside the entrance to the harbor and another around the two warships anchored in the center, keeping all pleasure craft and fishing boats at least 200 or 300 meters away from the cruisers. Soldiers will patrol the shoreline and seal off an area near the St. Luciano Tower, a 16th century watch tower built by the Knights of <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> on a jagged cliff that juts out into the harbor at the point closest to the warships. Police plan to set up roadblocks and checkpoints near the harbor and close off some roads to the public. The security force will include <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>'s entire military force and most of its police, including an anti-terrorist squad of about 100 members. A source who spoke on condition of anonymity said the three-day security operation is expected to cost the government the equivalent of $ 150,000 in overtime costs, plus at least $ 400,000 from the closing of the harbor and <ORGANIZATION> Malta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Freeport </ORGANIZATION> and from stopping construction on the terminal. `` We assume the Soviet and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> governments obviously will cover the commercial costs and expenses,'' said the source. `` We do not expect that the two superpowers will expect a small country like <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> to bear the costs of a superpower summit.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-USDA-Watchdog     11-30 0651</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-USDA-Watchdog,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Some Farmers Getting Around Subsidy Limits</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s watchdog agency says some large farming operations are successfully using highly complex methods to get around federal limits on crop subsidies. Despite recent reforms ordered by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, these farming operations have been able to dodge a $ 50,000 limit on federal crop subsidies and probably will continue collecting the fat subsidies again this year. The department's Office of Inspector General said 1987 legislation failed to effectively limit the use of `` multiple legal entities'' to avoid the payment curbs. Other loopholes were also cited. A new audit report released to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday included an example of how the curbs are circumvented: One operation reviewed by auditors in <LOCATION> Tunica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, created 51 irrevocable trusts in 1989 so as not to have payments reduced by further restrictions taking effect this year. The remodeled operation involved three joint ventures controlled by two intermingled families, which had included 43 `` persons'' in 1988. Auditors said the 43 `` persons'' consisted of six individuals and 37 corporations. Owners of the 37 corporations consisted of 11 individuals and one corporation. `` Seven of the individual owners were the immediate members of the two families -LRB- a father and two daughters, and a father, two sons and a daughter -RRB- that controlled the operation,'' the report said. If the complex arrangement had remained as it was in 1988, it would have collected no more than $ 700,000 in payments in 1989. But with reorganization, the operation is expected to collect as much as $ 1,431,576 in subsidies this year. `` One of the family members of this organization told us that the main purpose of the reorganization was to maintain the maximum program benefits,'' the report said. `` He said it became a challenge to see if he could get a trust established for all of the operation's full-time employees. He called it a profit-sharing plan.'' Although the reorganization was allowed by current regulations, auditors said the trusts are believed to be `` flow-through entities'' to avoid new regulations last year limiting a person's membership in more than three entities `` We conclude this because about $ 1.3 billion per year will be routed back to the seven immediate family members through management fees, equipment and land leases, and loans,'' the report said. The heart of the crop subsidies are federal `` deficiency'' payments used to make up part of the difference between a higher target level and a lower market price are supposed to be limited to $ 50,000 per person. As an example, last month's average corn price at the farm was $ 2.20 per bushel. The target price for 1989 corn is $ 2.84. `` However, our review determined that producers have found new, innovative ways to reorganize farming operations so that 1989 payments will not be limited significantly by the legislative changes,'' the report said. The audit report followed one sent to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> describing the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> inspector general's activities for the six-month period that ended Sept. 30. In that review, the excessive crop subsidies were noted among a number of abuses checked by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> investigators and auditors. The audit report released Wednesday dealt specifically with operations of crop programs handled by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stabilization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The auditors checked five state offices of the agency and 14 county offices. In the counties, 822 of 7,424 farm operating plans were selected for preliminary review. Finally, 52 farms were chosen for in-depth analysis. No individual names were released. States and counties selected for in-depth review included: <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>: <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Crittenden </PERSON> and <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> counties; <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>: Butte and Kern; <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>: <ORGANIZATION> Morehouse </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Natchitoches </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tensas </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>: <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Soto </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Noxubee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tunica </LOCATION>; and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>: <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Lubbock </LOCATION>. The review of 52 farming operations identified 12 that reorganized so that all entities _ which can be individuals, corporation, association, trust or other legal entities _ could continue receiving payments as `` persons'' under the program.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WrightBook     11-30 0669</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wright Book,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ethics Committee Lawyer Denies High-Expense Lobbying</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Note that some readers might find language in last graf offensive</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> lawyer who investigated the ethics case of former <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> is rejecting a report that he unfairly lobbied <ORGANIZATION> Ethics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> members by taking them to expensive <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> restaurants. A new book on <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s tenure as speaker, `` The Ambition and the Power,'' contends that <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON> `` routinely took committee members out to dinner at some of the most expensive restaurants in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'' as part of a calculated campaign to win his case. The book by <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> free-lance writer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>, published this month by <PERSON> Viking </PERSON>, contends <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON> ran up a $ 150,000 expense account while seeking to curry favor with what amounted to <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s jury `` That is absolutely nonsense,'' said <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>, who is running for president of the <ORGANIZATION> Cook </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, the top elective post in the county that includes <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. He said he did take several committee members out to lunch and dinner, but when he did, `` it was cheapsville'' _ the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> dining room or a low-priced <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> restaurant. The $ 150,000 figure represented food, lodging and other expenses for a staff of 10 people over a seven-month period, he said. `` The idea that some lawyer from <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> could come out and schmooze 12 hard-nosed congressmen into bulldozing the speaker of the House ... defies any kind of logic at all,'' <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>, during the two years he spent working on the book, was granted unusually broad access to otherwise private meetings of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leadership and meetings with staff and other lawmakers. He also obtained access to some transcripts from closed-door meetings of the ethics panel. In June, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> became the first speaker in history to resign under fire in mid-term after the ethics panel formally charged him with 69 violations of House rules. How much <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>'s lobbying of the ethics committee affected the outcome of the case will remain in dispute. Detailed expense records for <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>'s investigation are not available to the public. The records are kept by a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee chaired by Rep. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaydos </PERSON>, D-Pa., who also is a member of the ethics committee Despite its sympathy with <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s plight before the ethics committee, the book concludes that the former speaker's downfall was largely the result of his own arrogance. House Republicans had long complained about his heavy-handed way of running the chamber, and they believed he overreached to take control of <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> policy from President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. By the time his ethics problems cropped up <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> had become a lonely figure, estranged even from his own power base among Democrats. The book contrasts what it calls <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>'s conscious strategy of playing to the political side of the committee with what it portrays as a weak and inept defense of <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> by his lawyer, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Oldaker </PERSON>. <PERSON> Oldaker </PERSON> appeared not to recognize that committee members were worried about justifying their decision on <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> to the public and the news media, <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> writes. <PERSON> Oldaker </PERSON> once angrily quoted <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON> as having told him, `` This case will be decided by the editorial pages of the nation's newspapers,'' according to the book <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, while contending that he never broke <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> rules, also seemed to believe that the rules should n't apply to him, <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> concludes. A former close aide, <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Raupe </PERSON>, once said, `` I do n't understand how <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> can be so politically in tune and then be almost totally blind to appearances,'' <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> writes The book also contains glimpses inside the sometimes profane and rough world of leadership meetings. At one, members were discussing whether to assign a member who is Jewish to the Foreign Affairs Committee. Ways and <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, D-Ill., objected `` You ca n't put him there. There are already four kikes on that committee,'' he is quoted as saying. A <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON> spokesman denied the statement was ever made, but <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> said he was certain of the remark.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0103EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Scotus-Abortion     11-30 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus-Abortion,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Abortion Rights Advocates Face Challenge in Parental Notification
Cases</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD CARELLI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the battle for public opinion on abortion, a daunting challenge confronts those who say young girls should be able to obtain abortions without first telling their parents. The problem for abortion rights advocates is that most Americans view the issue _ now under <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> study _ primarily as one of parental rights. Many who support the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s 1973 decision that women have a constitutional right to abortion also favor parental involvement when minors seek abortions, public opinion polls indicate. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, after hearing arguments Wednesday in cases from <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, must decide whether states may outlaw abortions for most unmarried girls under 18 unless their parents are notified or a judge's approval is given. About half the states have such laws, although most of them have been blocked by court challenges. Those who oppose notification laws may be in danger of being perceived as enemies of parents and families. That perception has not escaped anti-abortion forces stung by the momentum their movement lost after July's <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision giving states more power to regulate abortions. `` It defies common sense to suggest that children should be allowed to undergo ... surgery without the foreknowledge of their parents,'' <PERSON> Ann-Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Lohr </PERSON>, an attorney with <ORGANIZATION> Americans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION>, said after Wednesday's high court session. `` The common-sense solution -LRB- is -RRB- that parents be informed of their minor daughter's medical situation,'' she said. <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> lawyer <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Sogg </PERSON>, however, earlier told the justices that not all young girls have loving and supportive parents. Some young girls must be protected from abusive mothers and fathers, she said. Of the approximately 180,000 girls under 18 who obtain abortions each year, about half are accompanied by one or both parents when they go for the operation. Ms. <PERSON> Sogg </PERSON> argued that state parental notification laws likely do not affect such girls, but others who may be better off not telling their parents need to be protected from intrusive state regulation. Whatever the court says about parental notification laws, in decisions expected by July, will not necessarily endanger the 1973 <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> decision that legalized abortion. The consensus among lawyers on both sides of the abortion issue is that the justices will not use the <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> cases as vehicles to reassess the 1973 ruling. But <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bopp </PERSON>, general counsel of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Right </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> to </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, disagrees. `` Roe vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> is on the table,'' he said. `` The court has to decide whether there is a right to abortion'' before saying whether a particular parental notification law violates any right. If the parental notification cases are to carry any impact for adult women, the words of Justice <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> will be decisive. <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, who as the court's sole woman never has said explicitly whether she believes an abortion right exists, controlled the outcome of last July's ruling. She has never voted to invalidate a state regulation on abortion, but seemed greatly troubled by <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>'s requirement that both biological parents be notified. The question is whether <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> could vote to strike down the <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> law without stating, or at least implying, that it violates some constitutional right enjoyed by young girls. Four justices support the 1973 conclusion that abortion is constitutionally protected. Four justices appear ready to abandon that decision. If <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, a critic of the rationale used in <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON>, decides to articulate some alternative approach, she will have charted a new course for the future of abortion law.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EDITORS: <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Carelli </PERSON> has covered the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1976.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Medicare     11-30 0517</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Medicare,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Needs More Muscle in Substandard Medicare Care: Panel</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Members of a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> committee say the government needs more disciplinary muscle against doctors and hospitals that provide substandard care for <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> patients. The recommendation was in a report Wednesday by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> that also criticized the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> for a four-year delay in writing regulations to implement a law that gives the agency more power to punish health-care providers. The law, enacted in 1985, allows <ORGANIZATION> HHS </ORGANIZATION> to deny payment to hospitals and physicians in cases where substandard care is provided. The department is working on the regulations, said <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Siebert </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Financing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. That agency handles <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION>, the government health care program for 33 million elderly, blind and disabled Americans. `` They're fairly controversial and complex regulations,'' he said. `` We've spent a lot of time consulting with medical care industry.'' Physicians may be terminated from participating in Medicare or fined up to the amount of the care provided, but only in cases where there has been a clear pattern of incompetence by physicians who were `` unwilling or unable'' to improve their treatment. The report said the standard that must be met is too stringent because it allows physicians to escape punishment by agreeing to take an educational course to indicate their willingness to improve. It also said the monetary penalty is too low. HHS Inspector General <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Kusserow </PERSON> has recommended that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> strengthen the standard and raise the fine to $ 10,000 per case. The report, based on a three-year investigation by the panel's Human Resources and <ORGANIZATION> Intergovernmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Subcommittee </ORGANIZATION>, estimated that more than 800,000 errors are made each year by doctors and hospitals caring for <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> patients The most common error was not having adequate discharge plans for post-hospital care, the report said. That was the case for about 3 percent of the <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> admissions selected randomly and reviewed by peer review organizations in 1989, the report said. Extrapolating that to the 11 million annual Medicare admissions amounts to 330,000 failures. `` The large number of beneficiaries who may be at risk of inadequate hospital-discharge planning is of special concern to the committee due to fears that the <ORGANIZATION> PPS </ORGANIZATION> system -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION>'s system for paying hospitals -RRB- ... is resulting in patients being discharged faster and less stable,'' the report said. Eight Republicans on the 39-member committee cautioned in an accompanying document that the error estimate was derived by extrapolating from reviews, called generic screens, that are designed to detect potential problems. An error can result from merely failing to sign a form in the proper place, they said. `` If an exhaustive look were taken at all generic screen failures, we are convinced the number of quality problems would be far below the committee report's projections,'' they said. Under the <ORGANIZATION> PPS </ORGANIZATION> system, or prospective payment system created in 1983 as a <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> cost-saving measure, hospitals are paid a flat fee for each treatment they provide. The fee assumes a certain length of hospital stay and medical services.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Pentagon-Budget     11-30 0358</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pentagon-Budget,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon Estimates $1.7 Billion Cut</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Pentagon estimates it will be forced to slash about $ 1.7 billion from its planned 1990 spending because of the effect of the Gramm-Rudman budget reduction law. <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> said Wednesday it was n't immediately clear what the exact impact of the cuts would be, or how they would affect manpower decisions <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> called the figure a `` preliminary estimate'' pending formal notification from the Office of Management and Budget. `` We're still trying to figure out how it's all going to fall,'' <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> said. Had the terms of the Gramm-Rudman deficit reduction law been fully enforced over a year, defense programs would have been pared by $ 8 billion, or half the $ 16 billion spending reductions the law would have automatically imposed on most federal programs. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said repeatedly in recent weeks that he preferred retaining the across-the-board cuts for a full year to accepting congressional efforts to reduce the deficit, which he said contained phony savings. Pentagon officials had warned of severe cutbacks in military personnel and weapons acquisition if the Gramm-Rudman cuts had been left in place the entire year. The development comes as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> signed, with reservations, a bill authorizing $ 305 billion for defense programs for the current fiscal year, including a cut in his request for the Strategic Defense Initiative. The measure cuts $ 1.1 billion from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s $ 4.9 billion request for spending on the SDI program, or Star Wars, in the fiscal year that began Oct. 1. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in a statement that the measure would provide sufficient funds to `` provide a national defense sufficient to meet foreseeable threats to the national security'' in the coming year. The legislation represents the first cut in the SDI program in six years. The bill also trimmed his request for other major strategic programs such as the MX and Midgetman nuclear missiles and the B-2 stealth bomber. The legislation reduces the ceiling on the number of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops overseas by about 15,000. Those troops were associated with intermediate-range nuclear weapons, banned by a U.S.-Soviet treaty signed in December 1988.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HUDReports     11-30 0509</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-HUD Reports,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>HUD Inspector Says Improvements Being Made</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> is moving aggressively to clean up scandal-plagued programs but it's too soon to say whether his efforts will be successful, the agency's chief watchdog says in a report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Despite <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s efforts, staffing problems caused by budget constraints threaten to undermine even the best attempts to rid the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> of mismanagement and political influence, Inspector General <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said in the report issued Wednesday. `` The department and <ORGANIZATION> OIG </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Office of the Inspector General -RRB- face critical staffing shortages resulting'' from across-the-board budget cuts made under the Gramm-Rudman deficit-reduction law, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said in his semiannual report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` Adequate staffing, continuity of leadership and management accountability are essential if the reform measures are to work,'' he said. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said that while it was premature to grade the substance of <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s efforts, the secretary `` has already taken aggressive corrective actions and proposed widespread reform measures, including the elimination of programs not benefiting the needy.'' <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said the media and congressional attention <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> has received since April, when his report on a rehabilitation program riddled with wasteful spending and political favoritism was issued, have complemented <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s reform efforts. `` The positive aspect of the current situation is that it creates an environment in which needed reform can take place,'' <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said. `` While it is too soon to predict the reform actions' success, I will continue to evaluate the effectiveness of those measures. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, in a separate report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, said his management team had resolved 97 percent of the nearly 1,700 internal audit recommendations awaiting management action when he took over <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> early this year. `` <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s management team is aggressively cleaning up problems which, over many years and during several administrations, have made well-intentioned programs susceptible to fraud, political influence and the waste of taxpayers' hard-earned dollars,'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' report recounted the problems found in virtually all of <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s major housing and loan programs _ fraud, waste and mismanagement with a pricetag estimated at more than $ 6 billion. The government, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said, could save millions if <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> would amend federal housing laws to allow refinancing of HUD-backed mortgages at today's more favorable interest rates. He renewed his call for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to grant inspectors general subpoena powers to force witnesses to cooperate with investigations. He warned that <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mortgage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> _ often referred to as `` <ORGANIZATION> Ginnie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mae </ORGANIZATION>'' _ saw its default portfolio grow from $ 3.1 billion to $ 12.5 billion last year, in large part because of bad real estate markets in `` oil patch'' states. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said the agency needs to increase its reserves to offset losses and take steps to reduce future defaults. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> acknowledged in his report that no steps had been taken to improve GNMA management, but said an analysis was underway. Since April, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> has recovered more than $ 25 million owed the government, implemented reforms that saved $ 21 million and committed itself to recovering another $ 50 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Riegle-LincolnS&amp;L     11-30 0448</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Riegle-Lincoln S&amp;L,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Testimony Shows Senators Didn't Influence Regulators, Riegle Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN FLESHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>, voicing frustration with the controversy over the nation's biggest savings and loan failure, says news reports downplay evidence that he and four other senators did nothing improper. `` Very sensationalized stories have run, putting such a sinister colorization on this thing,'' <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>, D-Mich., said Wednesday `` I resent it. I think it's unfair.'' He said little attention was given to sworn testimony by federal regulators that the senators did not influence the regulators' actions toward <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> Such testimony `` basically blows away the story,'' he said. <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, has said little publicly about his role in the battle between federal regulators and <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>, which the government seized in April. Regulators estimate the thrift's failure will cost the taxpayers $ 2 billion, making it the costliest S & amp; L collapse in the nation's history The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ethics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> has hired an independent counsel to examine allegations that five senators improperly intervened with regulators on <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>'s behalf. The senators are <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>; <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, D-Calif; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>.; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>; and <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ariz </LOCATION>. All the senators except <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON> attended an April 2, 1987, meeting with <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, then chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> says the senators improperly pressured him to drop a regulation that would have curtailed risky savings and loan investments. <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON> joined the other senators at an April 9, 1987, meeting with <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> regulators who were investigating <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>. All five received large campaign donations from former <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> owner <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>. <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON> returned the $ 78,250 he received from <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> and associates In an interview, <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON> voiced frustration over allegations that <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> bought the senators' influence. He said <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> and other regulators who testified before the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> repeatedly said the senators did not influence them. `` They were absolutely clear-cut on that issue and they said it over and over again,'' he said. Some of the senators have described their involvement as a normal constituent service. <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>, however, said he did not consider his attendance at the April 9 meeting a constituent service _ even though he had visited <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> properties in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> the previous year and <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> had purchased and renovated the Pontchartrain Hotel in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>. `` I went as a member of the banking committee,'' he said. `` The responsibility for handling their situation was in the hands of others who had them as a direct constituent.'' He said he was confident the ethics committee would find that `` all my actions were entirely proper'' and that case would do him no long-term political damage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-USX-Icahn     11-30 0486</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-USX-Icahn,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Icahn Seeks Permission to Acquire 25 Percent of USX Corp.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN M. DOYLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Investor <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Icahn </PERSON> is making another play for <ORGANIZATION> USX </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, the giant oil, gas and steel concern. <PERSON> Icahn </PERSON>, who announced plans to acquire sizable stakes in Pittsburgh-based <ORGANIZATION> USX </ORGANIZATION> twice before, disclosed Wednesday that he is requesting federal approval to acquire at least 25 percent of the corporation. <PERSON> Icahn </PERSON>, known for his past corporate takeover attempts, owns <ORGANIZATION> Trans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> USX </ORGANIZATION> finished down 12 -LCB- cents at $ 33.62 -LCB- in <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> trading Wednesday <PERSON> Icahn </PERSON>'s disclosure came after the markets closed. In a filing with the <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Icahn </PERSON> revealed that he was seeking permission from the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> to increase his stake in <ORGANIZATION> USX </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> FTC </ORGANIZATION> antitrust clearance for such an acquisition is required under the Hart-Scott-Rodino Antitrust Improvements Act. <ORGANIZATION> USX </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> said the company was aware of <PERSON> Icahn </PERSON>'s filing but had no comment. <PERSON> Icahn </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> said, made similar requests in late 1987 and late 1988 but never boosted his stake to the amount requested with the allotted year. `` This is the third time he's filed,'' <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> said. `` This is a renewable thing.'' According to the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> filing, made public just after 5 p.m. Wednesday, <PERSON> Icahn </PERSON> owned nearly 34 million, or 13.26 percent, of <ORGANIZATION> USX </ORGANIZATION>'s outstanding shares of common stock. The <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> document noted that in November 1988, <PERSON> Icahn </PERSON> made a Hart-Scott-Rodino filing indicating his intention to acquire more than 15 percent of <ORGANIZATION> USX </ORGANIZATION>'s voting securities `` and, depending upon market conditions, more than 25 percent'' of its voting securities. But because his group did not acquire in excess of 15 percent within a year, a new filing is required to permit acquisition above 15 percent, said the filing. In the latest <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> filing, <PERSON> Icahn </PERSON> said he was doing so under Hart-Scott-Rodino `` indicating that the registrants have a good faith intention'' to acquire more than 15 percent and up to 25 percent of <ORGANIZATION> USX </ORGANIZATION>'s voting securities. The filing said the acquisition was dependent on market conditions and redemption or invalidation of a `` poison pill' shareholder rights plan adopted by <ORGANIZATION> USX </ORGANIZATION> on Oct. 10 in an attempt to ward off a hostile takeover The <ORGANIZATION> USX </ORGANIZATION> plan would take effect once a person or group acquired at least 15 percent of the company's common stock. Under the plan, shareholders would be issued one stock right for each common share they already hold. The <ORGANIZATION> USX </ORGANIZATION> board could give shareholders the option of exchanging the rights for common stock, at the ratio of one share of common stock for each right, thus increasing the number of shares a raider would have to acquire. <ORGANIZATION> USX </ORGANIZATION> has said the plan was designed to prevent someone from gaining control of the company without offering a fair price to all stockholders. In October, <PERSON> Icahn </PERSON> said his group was considering making proposals for `` business combinations'' with <ORGANIZATION> USX </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Mulroney     11-30 0649</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Mulroney,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mulroney Says Gorbachev Deserves Help from the West</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Summit-Bush, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Canadian Prime Minister <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>, fresh from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, says Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is n't looking for miracles from <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>, but deserves help from the West such as observer status at world trade talks President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> had a private dinner at the White House Wednesday night in the last of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s pre-summit consultations with leaders of the Western alliance before he leaves today for <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> and this weekend's shipboard talks with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>, who returned Sunday from his own talks with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, spent nearly three hours at the White House before flying back to <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> thanked him profusely for coming. `` I ca n't tell you how much I appreciate your advice and your observations,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. Then, in what the president acknowledged was `` a little unorthodox'' fashion, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> left his guest on the driveway to hold forth for Canadian and American reporters. <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> defended <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> against charges that he has been too timid in responding to the fast-moving tide of democratic and economic changes sweeping the East Bloc nations. `` The administration has a responsibility to act with prudence,'' he said. `` President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and leader of the Western alliance, and it is important that he act not in haste, but that he act effectively. `` I believe that his intensive preparations and his very constructive attitude, I believe that this is going to bring about good results.'' <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> said he recommended that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> be granted observer status at the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade talks _ the discussions where the world's major industrialized nations lay the ground rules for international trade _ and that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> get a personal briefing after each economic summit of the seven major nations of the West. That briefing, he said, should be conducted by the chairman and host of the <ORGANIZATION> G-7 </ORGANIZATION> summit, which happens to be <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for the 1990 meeting to be held next spring or summer in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. `` What did President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> think of it? I think he kind of liked it,'' said <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>. `` My belief is that President <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> looks upon the <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> summit not with a view to any achieving any miracles, but with a view to building a sustained and solid relationship with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> that will give rise to major accomplishments down the road,'' <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> said, is `` in for the long haul himself. I think he's got an ambitious, progressive agenda for the future. `` Some of his suggestions are worthy of thoughtful and generous response, and on the basis of that, there are some gestures that can be taken,'' he said. There also `` might be a series of steps to bring -LRB- the Soviets -RRB- more closely into the INF and <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> ambit,'' the <LOCATION> Canadian </LOCATION> leader suggested. The meeting was the fourth one-on-one session this year between the two North American leaders. Also attending the private dinner were: Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>; <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Chief of Staff <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON>; <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON>, the national security adviser; <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gates </PERSON>, deputy national security adviser; and <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ney </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> was accompanied by Canadian Secretary of State for External Affairs <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>; <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartt </PERSON>, the prime minister's chief of staff; and <PERSON> Derek </PERSON> <PERSON> Burney </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Canadian </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> conferred with <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> at Camp David, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, last Friday, and has spoken with other <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> and Western alliance leaders by telephone in advance of the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> summit. He has promised not to spring any surprises on the allies. Asked if <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had assured him of no surprises such as former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s discussing abandoning nuclear arms with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> at <LOCATION> Reykavik </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iceland </LOCATION>, in 1987, <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> said, `` Oh, you can be certain of that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Thornburgh 750   11-30 0730</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Thornburgh, 750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thornburgh Ordered Prison Officials to Withdraw Plan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> ordered federal prison officials to withdraw a day-old plan to restrict press interviews of inmates just hours after reporters sharply questioned him about it. The attorney general faced angry questions Wednesday about his plans for new <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> guidelines being drafted to stem the flow of unauthorized information. During the tense session, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> defended the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prison </ORGANIZATION>'s proposal to limit each inmate to one press interview a month as part of `` what is necessary to properly manage prison facilities.'' But late in the day, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> abruptly and unexpectedly issued a brief statement saying he had ordered the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prisons </ORGANIZATION> to withdraw the proposed regulations, which had been put out for public comment. The plan would have limited the number of press interviews at each prison facility to one a day. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> had also faced hostile questioning about a provision of the plan that would have empowered wardens to bar future interviews by reporters who failed to seek comment from officials about allegations made by inmates of mistreatment or other conditions. <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Koren </PERSON>, an attorney for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> prison project called the provision a form of censorship designed `` to cut off any kind of criticism and to protect the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prisons </ORGANIZATION> from any embarrassments.'' <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> told reporters the regulations were designed to ensure an `` accurate flow of information.'' `` I think there is a problem that they are trying to address of reconciling their management responsibility with the flow of information in and out of prisons.'' But the attorney general said he had not personally reviewed the proposed regulations before they were published in Tuesday's Federal Register In his statement released late in the day, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said `` this proposal was submitted prematurely and without my personal review. It will be subject to further review before resubmission.'' <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> said <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> was told of the proposed regulations Tuesday night. He decided Wednesday afternoon to order them rescinded. He met Wednesday morning with reporters. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, chief spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prisons </ORGANIZATION> said there were only a few changes from current policy in the proposed regulations. He said the bureau has long required reporters to seek its response to allegations about prison conditions made by inmates. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said leaks of information about criminal investigations prompted him to order a full review this fall of press guidelines in the department and all its component agencies. `` I expect it to result in two things: one, that we will have some success in reducing the number of leaks of pending criminal investigations and, secondly ... that we speak with one voice on policy matters. `` It was ` let's leak like a sieve' when I got here,'' <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said. The attorney general repeated his warning that he would prosecute department officials who leak details of an ongoing criminal investigation. `` Those persons are criminals themselves because they violate the privacy statutes and the theft of government property statutes that the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has enacted.'' <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> has ordered investigations of numerous leaks, including a probe to identify the source who disclosed an investigation of alleged financial irregularities in the office of Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, D-Pa. The leak unleashed a storm of accusations from <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democrats that the disclosure was politically orchestrated by <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>'s aides while <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> was seeking election as <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> majority whip The department eventually issued a statement saying <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> was cooperating with the investigation and was n't a target. Asked Wednesday if he were satisfied the Gray leak had not come from his staff, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said: `` I have n't had an opportunity to review the results of the investigation.'' The review of department press guidelines that <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said he ordered earlier this fall has already resulted in new press guidelines at the Immigration and <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> McNary </PERSON>, the new <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> commissioner, ordered all field offices to get clearance from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> before responding to a wide variety of press questions. In September, <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> had rebuked <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> officials for confirming reports that <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> agents had arranged the sale of crack in a park near the White House at the request of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s speechwriters. The president, displaying a plastic envelope containing the crack, told of the undercover sale in his televised speech to unveil his anti-drug strategy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtoninBrief     11-30 0547</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington in Brief,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Postage Stamps and Envelopes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, already testing a self-adhesive stamp, is about to try marketing a plastic stamp and a hologram. The self-adhesive 25-cent stamps, showing an eagle and selling for slightly more than face value, are being tested in 15 cities. Early sales have been reported good. The plastic stamp, also self-adhesive, was unveiled this week at World Stamp Expo here and will be test-marketed in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. It was designed to be sold in bank automatic cash machines, and is made of plastic to make it easier for the machines to dispense. A 25-cent stamp, the plastic model features a stylized American flag, with a dozen stamps sold together on a backing sheet the size of a dollar bill. Testing will begin early next year. The hologram, a specialized design in which the image changes color when viewed from different angles, goes on sale Sunday. It is on a stamped envelopes and features a picture of the planned space station. The stamped envelope will cost 30 cents, including the 25 cents postage.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Machinists Leaders Vow Continued Strike</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Machinist union leaders are vowing to continue their strike against <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>. Machinists President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Kourpias </PERSON> said Wednesday that the union would try to pressure <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s parent company, and the bankruptcy court overseeing the cash-strapped carrier into a settlement. The union also plans to push Eastern to make overdue payments to its pension plan, which is owed as much as $ 1 billion, and take legal action against <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> if the payments are not made. Eastern is strapped for cash and court actions involving the underfunded pension plan could affect <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s attempt to emerge soon from bankruptcy. <PERSON> Kourpias </PERSON> said the union would lobby <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to win enough support to override President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s veto of legislation creating a congressional panel to recommend a solution. Eastern pilots and flight attendants cited the veto last week in deciding to end sympathy strikes in support of the machinists, who walked off the job March 4 after refusing to grant more than $ 150 million in work-rule and other concessions. The union represents more than 3,000 Eastern employees who worked as mechanics and baggage handlers.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Bentsen Says Panel Will Ponder Savings, Investment Incentives</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> says his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> will consider a wide array of proposals next year to encourage saving and investment, including a cut in capital gains taxes. Expanded Individual Retirement Accounts also will be considered as <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> looks for ways to increase productivity and the nation's ability to compete with foreign producers, the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Democrat said Wednesday in remarks prepared for a meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> Tax </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. With <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, leading the way, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> this year defeated President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s call for a reduction in taxes on capital gains, profits from the sale of investments. Democratic leaders viewed the proposed reduction as a windfall for the rich, the beginning of the undoing of the landmark 1986 tax overhaul and a deficit-increaser that would do little for the economy. They responded with a plan to liberalize tax-deductible IRAs, but withdrew that proposal when the capital gains cut failed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0025EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-JacksonPainting     11-30 0161</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jackson Painting,140</SECOND>
<HEAD>Art Critics Hammer Home Point On `White' Jackson Painting</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An large outdoor painting of <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> as a white man _ entitled `` How Do You Like Me Now?'' _ drew an immediate response Wednesday from a half dozen passers by. They did n't like it at all. So they knocked it down with a sledge hammer. `` They really were offended very deeply,'' <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Brookman </PERSON>, director of programming for the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Project for the Arts, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. `` I understand the way people can really misread it _ I think that's part of why it's such an interesting work.'' On Wednesday evening, most of the 14-foot-square work, painted on tin, was in pieces, while just the figure's blond hair, forehead and part of the eyes and ears still hung near a subway stop. The painting was the work of <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammons </PERSON>, whom <PERSON> Brookman </PERSON> described as `` an extremely important and well-known artist in the black community.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Thornburgh-CivilRights 250   11-30 0252</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Thornburgh-Civil Rights, 250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Membership in All-Male Club Shouldn't Disqualify Dunne: Thornburgh</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> says the man whom President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is expected to name civil rights chief should n't be disqualified simply because he's a member of an all-male golf club. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> refused to discuss former <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> state Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunne </PERSON>'s expected nomination to be assistant attorney general for civil rights, saying `` that is a matter for the White House.'' But the attorney general dismissed suggestions Wednesday that <PERSON> Dunne </PERSON>'s membership in an all-male golf club would pose a problem. `` Mr. <PERSON> Dunne </PERSON> has indicated that if he is nominated by the president he will resign. So I think he feels it's inappropriate for the head of the civil rights division to belong to such a club.'' White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said Wednesday that <PERSON> Dunne </PERSON> was the top candidate for the job. Sources at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, speaking on condition of anonymity, said they expected <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to nominate <PERSON> Dunne </PERSON>, a personal friend of the attorney general for 17 years. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> refused to approve <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s first nominee, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>, after critics said he lacked professional experience for the job. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said membership in all-male clubs does n't disqualify candidates because `` we do n't believe in litmus tests.'' `` My objection is to a litmus test which says hat somebody because of any characteristic or any part of their background ought to be excluded,'' the attorney general told reporters. `` They ought to look at the whole record.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891130-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-30-89 0029EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Summit 1stLd-Writethru   11-30 0867</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Summit, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0679,830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baker Says Summit Will Prepare US, Soviet for Nuclear Progress</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 8th graf: ``In Rome,'' with report of Gorbachev's aims
at summit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
