<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 2346EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF---Honduras-US     11-14 0154</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF---Honduras-US,0159</SECOND>
<HEAD>Embassy Says U.S. Troops Will Hold Three Exercises in Honduras</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 24,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel will take part in joint military exercises in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> during the coming year, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> said Tuesday. He said that during the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> fiscal year 1989-1990, which started Oct. 1, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Honduran troops would participate in at least three joint training programs. <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> did not give any specific dates or time periods for the maneuvers. In the past, the embassy usually released more detailed plans for the exercises about a week in advance. Some 25,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel took part in two, six-month training programs in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> in 1988-89. Military exercises involving thousands of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> troopers and Honduran forces have been held frequently since 1982. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has some 1,200 military personnel based at the <LOCATION> Enrique </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Soto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cano </LOCATION> air base, 37 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION>, the capital.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0027EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Germany-Brandt 1stLd-Writethru a0628 11-14 0525</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Germany-Brandt, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0628,0534</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brandt Says Part of Berlin Wall Should Stand as a Cold War Reminder</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Inserts 3 grafs after 8th pvs bgng: He rose to world... with
comments about Allies and President Kennedy. Pickup 9th pvs: Brandt said
he thinks...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRENCE PETTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former West German Chancellor <PERSON> Willy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON> said Monday he hopes some of the crumbling <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall will stand permanently, not as a barrier but as a reminder of the Cold War. `` A part of it should be allowed to remain standing, to serve as something of a museum,'' said <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON>, who was mayor of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> when the wall was erected in 1961. East German officials have opened new passages through the wall but have made it clear they will leave much of it standing for now to continue marking the line between <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON>, 75, said he was deeply moved when he visited <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> over the weekend and watched people freely moving through _ and over _ the wall. He said he would never forget how, for the first time, he saw East German border guards smiling at East German residents as they passed through border control points. `` They were so friendly. And the -LRB- East -RRB- Berliners who came back called over to the police _ ` Hey look, we're back!''' Even though <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON> is from the northern city of <LOCATION> Luebeck </LOCATION>, there are few politicians in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> whose personal histories are so closely linked with the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall. He rose to world prominence in 1961 when <LOCATION> Communist </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> constructed the wall, which became the scene of dozens of fatal escape attempts. Angered by the wall's deadly threat to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berliners </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON> immediately condemned the structure as a human rights violation. In an interview shown Monday night on the Macneil-Lehrer NewsHour broadcast in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON> was reminded of his anger in 1961 when the three <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Allies </ORGANIZATION> _ <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> _ did nothing to tear the wall down and he was asked if President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was right not to take action. `` I never asked President <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> to take military action,'' <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON> said. `` What I was angry about at the time ... was that there had been so much talk about the four-power responsibility -LRB- the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Allies </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> -RRB- for <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> as a whole and when it came to a critical point, we had to acknowledge that four-power responsibility had to be reduced to a three-party responsibility for <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. `` I was happy that we could count on that protection _ responsibility and protection. No, I think looking back at it, it was the right thing not to take the kind of military action which could have brought us into a new World War.'' <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON> said he thinks <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> should not intervene in what is happening in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> but be ready to offer its help. `` Leave it to people in the other part of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> to find their proper answers to their problems, but be as helpful as possible, especially in the field of economic cooperation,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0043EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BeatingDeath     11-14 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Beating Death,0278</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Beaten to Death, Husband Arrested</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Sharyn is cq</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VIRGINIA BYRNE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A hotel executive's husband was arrested Monday and accused of bludgeoning her to death on her 44th birthday with unopened wine bottles in their luxury apartment. `` This was a domestic dispute that escalated into a violent confrontation,'' said police Deputy Inspector <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Frankel </PERSON>. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>, 45, was charged with second-degree murder early Monday, a day after police went to the couple's apartment in lower <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> and found the battered body of his wife, <PERSON> Sharyn </PERSON>, 44, said <PERSON> Frankel </PERSON>. The couple had been married 17 years. Mrs. <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>, a personnel director with <ORGANIZATION> Hilton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, had turned 44 Sunday, the day she was slain, <PERSON> Frankel </PERSON> said. `` There was a lot of blood,'' said detective Sgt. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Norris </PERSON>. `` She was very badly beaten.'' Investigators believe Mrs. <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> was bludgeoned to death with up to five unopened wine bottles, which were found shattered near her body. `` A wooden meat tenderizer, like a mallet, was found near the body,'' <PERSON> Frankel </PERSON> added. The argument between the couple apparently escalated Sunday afternoon, when neighbors heard screams coming from the apartment in <LOCATION> Battery </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> near the financial district. After the killing, <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>, covered with blood, left the apartment and stood in the hallway shouting for help, <PERSON> Frankel </PERSON> said. Police responding to neighbors calls arrived at the apartment. The distraught husband, a self-employed food and beverage consultant, had scratch marks on his face and hands. Cole was restrained by police. `` He was visibly upset,'' <PERSON> Frankel </PERSON> said. `` He did n't want to leave the body.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SmellofFreedom     11-14 0735</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Smell of Freedom,0751</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pollution the New Smell of Freedom in West Berlin</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-East Germany, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HUGH A. MULLIGAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Ach, the stinking fumes from those terrible one-lung wrecks! Who would have thought pollution was the smell of freedom?'' With that, cabbie <PERSON> Augustin </PERSON> <PERSON> Vogel </PERSON> left the wheel of his <ORGANIZATION> Mercedes-Benz </ORGANIZATION> taxi and helped a laughing, cheering crowd of West Berliners push another backfiring `` Trabbi,'' the East German two-cylinder car, through the newly opened hole in the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall at <LOCATION> Potsdamer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Platz </LOCATION>. Two blue-bereted French soldiers amused the crowd and shocked the children peering out the streaky windows of the stalled car by chipping away at the Wall with hammers and chisels. The big weekend shopping spree that saw 3 million East Germans live the fantasies that tantalized them for years on western TV had slowed from a torrent to a steady gush, but every daylight hour was still rush hour on the streets of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. You had to wait in line to get into <ORGANIZATION> Woolworth </ORGANIZATION>'s on <ORGANIZATION> Tauentzien </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strasse </ORGANIZATION>, but on the opposite side of Checkpoint Charlie sales girls looked out the windows of empty boutiques with names like `` Lotus'' and `` Panda'' along <ORGANIZATION> Leipziger </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strasse </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s fashion avenue. Shoppers hurried through the chilling fog with baby carriages, shopping carts and rucksacks crammed with free world goodies. Even a sale on the eastern side _ `` stark reduziert'' _ of snuggie wool damen slips, ladies' almost knee-length panties from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, at 4 marks and Russian-made <PERSON> Strumpf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hose </PERSON>, at 14 marks, failed to stem the exodus to the big mall over the Wall. A surpising consensus of sidewalk opinion along the Kurfuerstendamm, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s Fifth Avenue, blamed the fog on the fume-spewing Trabants and the slightly larger Wartburgs. `` Still it's a miracle to see all those DDR plates,'' enthused refrigeration repairman <PERSON> Otto </PERSON> <PERSON> Esser </PERSON>, who played hookey from work to spend his third day watching the flow of traffic through the Wall. `` This has been the happiest time of my life. I was two years old when the Wall went up. I'm taking pictures for my infant son, who hopefully wo n't even have the Wall, as a memory.'' `` Oranges, bananas and coffee, that's what the Easties mainly buy with the 100 marks handed out free to them by the banks,'' reported <PERSON> Helga </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosmunsen </PERSON>, a beautician who also called in sick to spend another day watching the ceaseless flow of humanity along a dust-beaten thoroughfare that only a week ago had been a death strip. `` Even on a crowded downtown street you can tell an East from a West Berliner by the happiness in their eyes. No wonder. Have you ever tried to get real coffee over there?'' Absenteeism was only a minor problem as another work week began in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, but the weekend of wonders glowed brighter than the few Christmas tree lights looming faintly in the fog. The Volkskammer, the Communist-dominated parliament, was electing a new prime minister in the old town hall up by the <LOCATION> Brandenburg </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gate </LOCATION>, but at a Bierstube just a few blocks away blue-collar beer drinkers switched off the government television news to see if the Western channels were reporting any new holes in the Schandmauer, the wall of shame. Meanwhile, on the other side of the Brandenburg Gate, now sheared of its barbed wire curls, a procession of famous Western TV anchors from several dozen countries waited their turn to do stand-ups in the floodlit splendor of this landmark rubbled arch. Even at the Museum at <ORGANIZATION> Checkpoint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Charlie </ORGANIZATION> _ with its bizarre collection of motorbikes, battered buses, homemade submarines and hot-air balloons that had confounded <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s wall guards, patrol dogs and mine fields _ <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Brokaw </PERSON> and crew had to line up for an interview with the curators. At the CSSR Kultur und Informationszentrum just a few hundred yards to the east, there was no wait for interviews and no culture customers either, despite a display of children's patriotic poster art. `` The Easties will be back in even larger numbers this weekend,'' predicted postcard vendor <PERSON> Axel </PERSON> <PERSON> Gruber </PERSON> at the Potsdamer hole in the wall. `` This time it wo n't be for just shopping. They'll want to see our famous zoo and the Rembrandts and the Head of Queen <PERSON> Nefertiti </PERSON> in the <LOCATION> Dahlem </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Museum </LOCATION>. They know free <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> has more to offer than blue jeans and cassettes of the British rock group Exodus.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Whistleblowers     11-14 0543</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Whistleblowers,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>There's No Reward for Being a Whistleblower, Senate Panel Told</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The federal government should reward _ not punish _ workers who blow the whistle on fraud, say employees in telling a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee how they were thwarted in efforts to expose abuse. `` There's no reward for being a whistleblower,'' complained a <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> worker in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> who went public with allegations about a <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> defense contractor. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kusen </PERSON> said Monday that the government saved $ 3.3 million on a contract when she brought allegations of fraud to their attention, but all she got in return were two lines of commendation. `` When someone finds a wallet, they get a reward,'' she told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Governmental Affairs subcommittee on general services, federalism and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, which held a hearing into the inspectors general fraud hotlines. The 16-year federal employee described for the committee her nearly five-year effort to persuade the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to investigate pricing irregularities by the <ORGANIZATION> Elliott </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, then a subsidiary of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technologies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. Twenty-six letters to the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> hotline describing contract problems, including some with audit reports, progress payment records and copies of contracts, produced little action, <PERSON> Kusen </PERSON> said Finally, she took her information to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. After a series of articles in the newspaper, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Price </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fighter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detachment </ORGANIZATION> conducted its own inquiry. The Detachment found that on an order for 26 rotor assemblies, <ORGANIZATION> Elliott </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> charged $ 6,613.49 for items that should have been $ 1,485.89, Ms. <PERSON> Kusen </PERSON> said. Federal employees fear retaliation for reporting waste and abuse, said the <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> worker who said she would never use the hotline again. <PERSON> Phillip </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Doe </PERSON>, an employee with the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reclamation </ORGANIZATION> who blew the whistle on a land scandal, said he never considered the inspectors general hotline. `` Friends ... said the reaction would be one of damage control,'' <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> told the committee. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Diefenderfer </PERSON>, deputy director of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> and chairman of the President's Council on Integrity and Efficiency, said the testimony was `` the most demoralizing thing I've heard.'' But he said he did not think `` it is that bad,'' and suggested an increase in congressional oversightof the day-to-day operations of the inspectors general hotline. <PERSON> Dina </PERSON> <PERSON> Rasor </PERSON>, director of the Project on Military Procurement which recently released a 52-page survival guide for the whistleblower, said one problem with the system is that confidential complaints to the hotline, after proceeding through the investigative channels, usually end up on the desk of the whistleblower's boss, and `` it does n't take long to find out who the employee is.'' The other problem is that investigators rarely work with the whistleblower on their inquiries. `` They go through a stack of documents without understanding the problem,'' Ms. <PERSON> Rasor </PERSON> said. `` I've never known a whistleblower to be successful with the hotline,'' said <PERSON> Rasor </PERSON>, who has spent nine years investigating the military. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, the investigative arm of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, said their study of the hotline system found that some telephone hotline numbers were not listed and others did not have an 800-number, like the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>. Overall, the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said the hotlines `` can be useful in receiving calls and complaints.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0105EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Wilder-Democrats     11-14 0537</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wilder-Democrats,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wilder Urges Democrats to Embrace Mainstream Values</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, the first black to be elected governor of any state, says the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> should follow his example in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> by offering a moderate, `` mainstream'' message in presidential elections. `` In presidential elections it is time for the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> to take a plunge into the waters of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s new mainstream,'' <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> told a gathering of party leaders Monday. `` There was a time when Democrats were elected by campaigning against big government and high taxes,'' he said. `` But for too long, we have let the other party take these issues away from us _ indeed, we have allowed them to hammer us with these issues.'' <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s lieutenant governor, spoke to the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, a group of conservative and moderate Democrats formed in 1985 to counteract liberals who have dominated the party's presidential nominating process. The group has tried to steer the party toward the right, and <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> has bickered publicly with the group and some of its leaders in the past. After taking office in 1986, <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> criticized the council as exclusionary and divisive, and he charged it was trying to weaken the influence of the party's basic constituency groups, including blacks. Noting those past differences, <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> said: `` I will not look back. We will look for forward. We will be there together.'' <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> said his campaign was successful because it appealed to mainstream values. To regain the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, Democrats must identify with the nation's concerns about crime and drugs, jobs, the environment, education and the desire `` to hold the line on taxes,'' he said. Although his candidacy was closely watched by black leaders, <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> deliberately kept liberal two-time presidential candidate <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> at arm's length and did not invite <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> to campaign for him. `` Mainstream values are the values of the overwhelming majority of the people of this country,'' <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> said. `` It's time our party began focusing on such values at the national level.'' <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, whose razor-thin victory is subject to a recount requested by his <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> opponent, campaigned as a moderate in the tradition of his two predecessors, Gov. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Baliles </PERSON> and Sen. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Robb </PERSON>, a former governor and president of the <ORGANIZATION> DLC </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>'s call on the party to embrace mainstream values as the key to regaining the White House used a common buzz-word for the council. <PERSON> Robb </PERSON>, in a morning address to the group, used the word `` mainstream'' no fewer than 21 times, and the inaugural issue of the group's new magazine was distributed bearing the title `` The Mainstream Democrat.'' `` Stand pat with liberal fundamentalism, or build a new agenda on mainstream values _ that is the choice,'' <PERSON> Robb </PERSON> said. Speaking to reporters later, <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> lavished praise on the council but stopped short of saying he would join. The party's other top elected black, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Majority Whip <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, is a co-chairman of the council and has urged <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> to join <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> praised <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> before the group, saying, `` He will change the course of American politics, not because he is black, but because of what as a black American he will do.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0105EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-StabbingDeaths     11-14 0192</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stabbing Deaths,0199</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Children Slain; Mother Takes Own Life, Police Say</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PROVIDENCE, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman whose marriage had recently broken up apparently slashed the throats of her three sons with a pocketknife and then took her own life, police said. The woman's mother, who had talked with her daughter about her problems late into the night Sunday, found the bodies Monday morning in this <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> suburb, police said. The body of <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Warwick </PERSON>, 36, was found in a bathtub with both wrists slashed, and a <LOCATION> Swiss </LOCATION> army knife was found nearby, said police Cpl. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Doarnberger </PERSON>. The bodies of her sons, <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Warwick </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 5; <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON>, 4; and <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON>, 3; were found in bedrooms, their throats cut, he said. The two younger boys apparently were killed while they slept, but <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> had wounds on his hands, suggesting that he had tried to ward off the attack, police said. The case was classified a murder-suicide, police spokesman <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. Mrs. <PERSON> Warwick </PERSON> had been staying with her parents after separating from her husband of 13 years. She recently had been under medical supervision for depression, <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-EasternEurope     11-14 0731</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Eastern Europe,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Reacting Cautiously to Change in East Germany</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Despite prodding from Democrats, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is reacting cautiously to democratic reform in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, saluting the developments as momentous and irreversible while trying to avoid any appearance of gloating. It is a balancing act, intended to lend support and encouragement to the march toward freedom while guarding against doing anything that might provoke a crackdown in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> or slow the dramatic pace of reform. `` We are handling it in a way where we are not trying to give anybody a hard time,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said last week. He said he was responding in `` a rather measured way'' that was designed to encourage change and `` hopefully not contribute to an unforeseen disorder.'' Now, two well-placed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials say <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is considering a meeting with <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> leaders in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> after his summit next month with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. The aim of such a meeting would be to show Western unity on the future of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and to discuss new political and military strategy in light of the changes in Eastern and <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s initial approach to the opening of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s borders was so low-keyed that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> felt obliged to explain: `` I am not an emotional kind of guy. I'm very pleased.'' Questioned Monday about <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s restrained reaction, White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, `` I urge you not to mistake that for the personal enthusiasm for the freedom and the extension of values that are now going to the East German people.'' An administration official, discussing <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s approach, said, `` Things are going so well in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, why screw them up'' by saying something provocative. `` We do n't need to say, ` We won, they lost.''' Democrats have been attacking <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> all year as too timid and hesitant about changes in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and across <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, and they unveiled a new volley Monday. `` Even as the walls of the modern <PERSON> Jericho </PERSON> come tumbling down, we have a president who is inadequate to the moment,'' said <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democratic Leader <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>. `` The changes taking place in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> should galvanize our president into action,'' <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> said. `` But at the very time freedom and democracy are receiving standing ovations in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, our president is sitting politely in the audience with little to say and even less to contribute.'' <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> urged <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to go to <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> to hail `` the figurative and literal destruction of the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall.'' He also said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> should swiftly suspend trade barriers against the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and grant <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> observer status at international economic institutions. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said it was `` extremely unlikely'' that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would go to <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. `` It's our feeling that there are any number of policy reasons why that is probably not the right thing to do at this time.'' While cheering the developments in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, the administration acknowledges it has been surprised by the pace of change and is uncertain where events will lead. Preparing for his summit with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> on Dec. 2 and 3, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> met Monday with a panel of academic and government experts on the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The meeting focused on military developments in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Earlier sessions were devoted to the Kremlin's economic problems <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the changes in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, particularly in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, are putting a new focus on the summit. `` Certainly, the exodus from <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and the taking down of the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall, in terms of people's ability to move across the borders, adds a new sense of urgency and a new dimension to that whole discussion,'' the spokesman said. He said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would not be accompanied to the summit by a large number of arms control specialists, but that the talks should `` give a push'' to negotiations to reduce strategic nuclear arms and conventional weapons. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> turned up the rhetorical heat on developments in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> during an emotional ceremony Monday welcoming Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> to the White House. `` The iron curtain is fast becoming a rusted, abandoned relic, symbolizing a lost era and a failed ideology,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` The change is everywhere,'' the president said. `` <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>. And ladies and gentlemen, the week that brought <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, is the week the headlines proclaimed, ` And the Wall Comes Tumbling Down.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-StelloNomination     11-14 0438</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stello Nomination,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Urged to Drop Controversial Choice for Nuclear Weapons Post</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic senators from five states that have federal nuclear weapons facilities want President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to withdraw his nomination of <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Stello </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> to head weapons production, saying he's unqualified for the sensitive post. In a letter made public Monday, the senators said the poor condition of the nation's 12-state nuclear weapons complex makes it crucial that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> find someone of undisputed credentials for the job of assistant secretary for defense programs. `` Unfortunately, based upon his record of circumventing health and safety regulations and obstructing investigations while at the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, we strongly believe that Mr. <PERSON> Stello </PERSON> is not the proper candidate for this responsibility and that the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> should reject his confirmation,'' the letter said. Stello's confirmation hearing is scheduled for Wednesday in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. His nomination was announced July 24 by the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. The letter opposing the nomination was signed by <PERSON> Sens </PERSON>. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Brock </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state. <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON> is on the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, the four others are not. <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON> is the only member of the committee to openly oppose <PERSON> Stello </PERSON>'s nomination, so it is not clear how other members might vote. Stello's critics contend he is poorly suited to ensure health and safety at the nuclear weapons plants, but <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials contend his broad experience in commercial nuclear power regulation makes him a good choice. <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, the deputy energy secretary, said the senators' letter was `` not news'' to him because the five already had informed the department of their opposition to Stello He said he knew of `` one or two'' other <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> opponents but added, `` we think the votes are there'' to gain full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approval this month. Stello has been working as a special assistant to Energy Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> since July. The weapons complex, including 17 major plants and laboratories in 12 states, is beset by mechanical, safety, environmental and management problems that <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> has said must be corrected soon to assure the nation's nuclear defense. Stello had been chief of staff at the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> since 1986, ranking directly under the five commission members. The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> regulates commercial nuclear power. In a move interpreted by some as a sign that <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> may doubt <PERSON> Stello </PERSON>'s chances of winning <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation in the current session of the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> late last month told one of his top aides to temporarily take charge of the weapons office.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Thatcher'sCrisis Bjt   11-14 1013</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Thatcher's Crisis, Bjt,1041</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thatcher: Suddenly Britons Contemplate Life Without Her</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY8</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MAUREEN JOHNSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, who only six months ago looked unassailable, is suddenly looking vulnerable and defensive. An economic slump, culminating in the Oct. 26 resignation of her treasury chief, has confronted her with possibly the worst crisis of her decade in office. The combative determination that wrought a revolution is looking more like authoritarianism _ a trait she may have exercised once too often in forcing the resignation of Chancellor of the Exchequer <PERSON> Nigel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawson </PERSON>. And for the first time, she has given Britons a glimpse of a future without her all-embracing presence, saying she is likely to step down sometime after the next election, which must be held by mid-1992. `` I think people would think it was time for someone else to carry the torch,'' she told the Sunday Correspondent newspaper. At 64, midway through a third five-year term, her comment should n't have been all that surprising. The fact that it triggered a furor is testimony to the profound impact she has had on British life. Her supporters insist that Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> will triumph, that she thrives on adversity as she showed in waging war for the <LOCATION> Falkland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, facing down <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s militants and, most recently, at last month's <ORGANIZATION> Commonwealth </ORGANIZATION> conference resisting a united front seeking tougher sanctions for <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. `` In a country where every other politician seems to change postures every opinion-poll time, <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> _ irritating as she frequently is _ does not do that,'' wrote <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> MacRae </PERSON> in The Sunday Times. Says Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>: `` A leader must lead firmly ... How can I change <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>? I am what I am.'' But her admission of political mortality is likely to intensify the war of succession that began to stir last month at her Conservative Party's annual convention. Contenders such as former <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Heseltine </PERSON> and Deputy Prime Minister Sir <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> were already sending out veiled challenges. With inflation above 7 percent, interest rates at an eight-year high of 15 percent and the trade deficit hitting new records, the gloss had gone off the Thatcherite boom and the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> was averaging a 10-point lead in opinion polls. Then came <PERSON> Lawson </PERSON>'s bombshell, depriving Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> of the man she herself had credited with turning <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s economic fortunes around. Thus her interview, published Nov. 5, became something of a starter's pistol in the race to succeed her. <PERSON> Lawson </PERSON> said he resigned because Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> ignored his ultimatum to sack Sir <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Walters </PERSON>, her part-time economic adviser, whom <PERSON> Lawson </PERSON> accused of undermining his policies. His resignation forced a shuffle in which the three senior ministries changed hands. In the view of many commentators, it gave the 22-member Cabinet more power over Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, if only because she ca n't afford to lose another senior minister. `` ... The world has changed for her. Changed utterly ... the fear has gone out of those formerly timid men who surrounded her Cabinet table,'' commented the pro-Thatcher <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION>. At the heart of the crisis are two issues: Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s personal style and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s place in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> _ the political issue set to dominate the British political agenda in the 1990s The style issue is an old one: Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> as the nanny-prime minister, convinced she alone is right; Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> the hectoring bully; Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> the crusading free-marketeer, whose hatred of socialism leads her to savage everything from organized labor to the cherished <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>; Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> the handbagger, a term drawn from the popular caricature of an Iron Lady who slaps down critics with her handbag. The <PERSON> Lawson </PERSON> dispute was, on the face of it, about whether <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> should join the currency-stabilizing exchange rate mechanism of the European Monetary System, which links nine of the 12-nation <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION>'s currencies <PERSON> Lawson </PERSON>, who had already been trying to steady the economy by tying the pound to the powerful West German mark, wanted to join as soon as possible. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, under pressure, has agreed in principle to join under strict conditions. But she sounds unenthusiastic and <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> called the European Monetary System a `` half-baked'' idea. Many observers believe her attitude is symptomatic of an island nation's `` persistently ambiguous attitude toward European integration,'' as commentator <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mauthner </PERSON> put it in <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Financial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s foreign policy has swum along on her warm relationship with former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, allowing her to project <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> as a world power. But President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> seems more interested in the Continent than its islands, and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> is far better placed than <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> to meet the economic challenge of a transformed Soviet bloc. Meanwhile, the Thatcher Euro-bashing of the 1980s, caricatured as the Britain-vs. - foreigners approach, has given way to worries Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> will miss the boat and end up marginalized in both <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> ` Two years ago she was arguably the most respected statesperson in the world,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dobbs </PERSON>, a former senior <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> official. `` Yet in just a few months her simply unrestrained enjoyment of a good punch-up has left her virtually friendless on the diplomatic scene.'' A Harris poll for the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> in October showed 62 percent disapproval of Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s attitude toward <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> allies. `` The poison is at the heart of this government in that its leader is unable to command the support of the best men in Conservative politics,'' commented <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> biographer and columnist in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s liberal Guardian newspaper. <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> has shaken the government before. In 1986, a battle was waged in the <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> over whether to sell an ailing British helicopter company to an American company or a European consortium. <PERSON> Heseltine </PERSON>, who favored the European option, lost out and resigned. He is now Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s likeliest successor. <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> is heading toward greater unity, bringing the corporate, mildly socialist doctrines prevalent on the Continent into growing confrontation with the robust individualism espoused by the Thatcherites. So for British politics, <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> looks like a drama that will run and run.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugPlane     11-14 0551</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Plane,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>DeConcini Warns About Buying More Radar Planes Until Problems Solved</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The chairman of a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> appropriations panel is warning the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> not to sign a contract for a third sophisticated radar plane until electronics problems are resolved in two existing aircraft that detect drug-smuggling flights. `` I'm very interested, being the chairman of the funding committee, in not letting a new contract when we do n't have one that works,'' Sen. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON> said Monday, demanding corrections in the computerized electronics in the <ORGANIZATION> Lockheed </ORGANIZATION> P-3 airborne early warning aircraft. The <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> Democrat, who heads the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations subcommittee on <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and General Government, is urging that the problems be fixed by March, a month before the <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> is scheduled to sign a contract with <ORGANIZATION> Lockheed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for its third flying radar platform. `` They have to tell us it will be corrected by March. If they do n't fix it, I'm going to come down on them hard,'' <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON> said. `` If they do n't adhere to the suggestion I'll have a hearing and it wo n't be pleasant.'' <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> documents _ and sources _ show that the aircraft have experienced trouble pinpointing the location of targets and following their course and speed; faulty on-board communications for the crew; and problems with a spinning, metal radar dome. Most documents were written by crewmen at the <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Surveillance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Support </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Corpus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, where the agency has based the P-3 <ORGANIZATION> AEW </ORGANIZATION>'s, the frontline equipment in detection of airborne drug smugglers. In the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, Rep. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> English, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said he expected committee Chairman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Conyers </PERSON>, D-Mich., to ask the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> to investigate problems with the P-3 AEW <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Kendig </PERSON>, acting director of the <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> surveillance center, has acknowledged there are a `` few glitches'' in the computer systems, but said the aircraft `` works and it works great.'' He said the two planes now flying were mainly responsible for detections leading to 36 arrests from Jan. 1 to Aug. 10, seizures of 37,000 pounds of marijuana and 8,300 pounds of cocaine as well as vessels, aircraft and vehicles. <ORGANIZATION> Lockheed </ORGANIZATION>'s airborne early warning program manager, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McGinnis </PERSON>, has said he hopes `` anomalous behavior'' in the tracker will be fixed by `` the first of the year.'' `` The airplane and the tracker are very capable and doing their job'' despite the discrepancies, <PERSON> McGinnis </PERSON> said. The first P-3 airborne early warning aircraft was delivered in June 1988 at a cost of more than $ 27 million, and the second arrived in April at a price of $ 30.6 million. The third plane will cost $ 35 million, money already appropriated by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Lockheed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> P-3 </ORGANIZATION> is a four-engine turboprop built to detect enemy submarines, but two airframes were outfitted with the most sophisticated electronics available and sold to the <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> to detect airborne drug smugglers. The major electronics problem documented in <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> memos _ and in interviews with agency sources _ is the computerized tracker. The equipment is designed to automatically plot the course and speed of a suspect aircraft, but is sometimes so inaccurate that the P-3 can not reliably guide interceptors to the suspected smugglers, the sources and documents said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ParkwayShooting 4thLd-Writethru a0775 11-14 0769</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Parkway Shooting, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0775,0788</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Detectives Shot to Death By Inmate From Back Seat of Car</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf with 2 grafs to UPDATE with possible arrest; picks
up 3rd graf, ``Killed were ...''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL GEITNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A murder suspect being driven on a busy highway to a city jail Monday pulled out a gun and fired from the back seat at two detectives, killing them both, authorities said. The convict, identified as <PERSON> Stoney </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, 25, ran from the scene, according to Police Commissioner <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Condon </PERSON>. Around midnight, about 10 hours later, police brought in for questioning a man believed to be <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, who was found in a home in the borough of <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>, said police Sgt. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Berry </PERSON>. Killed were Detectives <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, 34, of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Guerzon </PERSON>, 46, of <PERSON> Merrick </PERSON>, said Sgt. <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON>, a police spokesman. The shooting, the first to claim the lives of two city police officers in more than 11 years, occurred on the Grand Central Parkway in the borough of <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> LaGuardia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. The detectives had driven <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> from the city's <LOCATION> Rikers </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> jail to the <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION> district attorney's office earlier in the day to take a lie detector test and discuss a plea bargain, police said. He was being taken back to <LOCATION> Rikers </LOCATION> in one of the detectives' personal cars when the shooting occurred <PERSON> Condon </PERSON> said both officers carried pistols in ankle holsters, but neither had been fired. The weapon with which they were shot was not recovered, and <PERSON> Condon </PERSON> said it was unclear where <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> got a gun. The seating of detectives and inmate _ them in front, him alone in back _ violated procedure, <PERSON> Condon </PERSON> said. Police said it was not against police guidelines to transport prisoners in personal cars. <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> was handcuffed when he was in the car, but was not when he fled, according to witnesses. A pair of cuffs was found in the front seat. Police said it appeared the car pulled over to the side of the highway before shots were fired. Both detectives appeared to have been shot once in the back of the head. Police said <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, a resident of <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION>, has an extensive criminal record dating to 1984, including drug and assault charges. In 1985, he was sentenced to 364 days in jail for biting off a girlfriend's ear. He was arrested in July for allegedly strangling another girlfriend after a night of partying and drug-taking. In October, he and his mother were arrested for conspiring to murder a witness against him in the July slaying. He allegedly had his mother offer $ 2,000 to a hit man who turned out to be an undercover detective. <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Officer <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> said three men were arrested near the airport shortly after Monday's shooting, but each was released. An hour after the shooting the detectives' bodies, in white bags, were on grass near the parkway. The sedan they were driving was parked nearby. There were bullet holes in the windshield, and the wipers were on. Another car, its front end smashed, also sat in the road. Police Capt. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said the driver of the second car was not involved in the shooting. Westbound traffic on the parkway was limited to one lane. Officer <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulvey </PERSON>, the first officer on the scene, said he found `` one police officer face down on the ground and the other officer on the passenger seat shot and killed.'' At least seven witnesses were being interviewed. `` It was a pretty bloody scene,'' <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> said. Asked where the officers had been shot, he said, `` There was so much blood it was hard to tell.'' The officers were members of the <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION> district attorney's detective squad, <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> said <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, who leaves behind a wife and a daughter, was appointed to the Police Department in 1981 and earned two police awards. <PERSON> Guerzon </PERSON>, who had a wife and two children, was appointed in 1969 and earned 13 awards, <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON> said. Rewards totaling $ 40,000 were offered for information leading to the officers' killers: $ 10,000 from a group of city businessman called COPSHOT; $ 10,000 from the city; and $ 20,000 from the <ORGANIZATION> Detectives </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endowment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which represents detectives. The last time two police officers were killed in the same incident was April 2, 1978. Officers <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Cerullo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Christie </PERSON> <PERSON> Masone </PERSON> were killed in a gunfight with two occupants of a car they stopped in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>. The officers shot Monday became the fourth and fifth ones killed in the line of duty this year. Fourteen others have been wounded.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Fed-InterestRates     11-14 0665</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fed-Interest Rates,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Economists Predict Interest Rates Will Continue Falling</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In what would be good news for consumers and business borrowers, many private economists are looking for interest rates to continue falling over the next six to nine months. The analysts are looking for further rate declines as the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> tries to keep a sluggish economy from toppling into a recession. But while economists are looking for future rate cuts by the central bank, they do n't expect to see any further action in that direction over the next month or so, given the fact that <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> policymakers moved to ease credit conditions slightly just last week. Those comments were the prevailing view as top <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> officials gathered in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> today for a meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Open </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Market </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, the panel of <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> board members and regional bank presidents that meets eight times a year to map monetary strategy. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyss </PERSON>, an economist with <PERSON> DRI-McGraw </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, said he was looking for a variety of consumer and business borrowing rates to edge lower through next summer, reflecting sluggish growth during this period and <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> easing moves. <PERSON> Wyss </PERSON> predicted that the benchmark prime rate, to which one-third of all business and consumer loans is tied, will be cut from 10.5 percent to 10 percent before Thanksgiving with another cut to 9.5 percent in the first half of next year. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinai </PERSON>, chief economist of the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, predicted that the national average for fixed-rate mortgages, currently at a three-month low of 9.79 percent, would fall to around 9.5 percent in coming months with adjustable rate mortgages declining by a somewhat larger amount. `` I believe we will see additional easing on the part of the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> over the next three to nine months because the economy will keep on weakening, but I do n't think the central bank is planning to make a one-fourth percentage point cut in rates every few weeks,'' <PERSON> Sinai </PERSON> said. Analysts were still puzzling over the timing of the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>'s easing move last week. Members of the <ORGANIZATION> FOMC </ORGANIZATION> reportedly held a telephone conference call Nov. 6, deciding to push a key interest rate, the federal funds rate, down from 8.75 percent to 8.5 percent. Manipulation of this rate, which is the interest banks charge each other for overnight loans, is the primary lever the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> uses to control short-term interest rates. Private economists wondered why the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> decided to act last week instead of simply waiting to discuss the matter at today's regularly scheduled <ORGANIZATION> FOMC </ORGANIZATION> meeting `` There was no need for them to panic because I do n't see any sign that the economy is falling off a cliff,'' <PERSON> Wyss </PERSON> said. Some analysts wondered whether the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> felt pressured by the pointed comments being made by the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration that if the country does go into an economic nosedive next year, it will be the fault of the central bank for keeping interest rates too high. Others suggested that the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> may have moved when it did as a way of reducing the government's cost of raising funds at several huge debt auctions held late last week after <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> raised the debt ceiling. But whatever the reason, economists were generally optimistic that the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>'s move will succeed in keeping the current record peacetime expansion, which is entering its eighth year this month, going for some time to come. Many analysts believe that growth will slow significantly from now until next summer, as the economy responds to efforts the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> made last year to clamp down on credit in an effort to battle inflationary pressures. But starting next summer, these analysts are looking for a rebound in growth in response to a series of credit easing moves the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> has made beginning last May. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> is trying to bring the economy from a fast-track growth path to a moderate-growth path without inducing a recession,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Diely </PERSON>, an economist at <ORGANIZATION> Northern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-IndianMuseum     11-14 0322</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Indian Museum,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Ready to Consider Compromise Indian Museum Bill</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Lead prospects uncertain. Afternoon Senate action expected</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KIM I. MILLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is within arm's length of establishing a National Museum of the American Indian in the nation's capital, and in the process, settling some longstanding feuds. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> was expected to take up a bill today to transfer a priceless collection of Indian artifacts from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s Museum of the American Indian to the <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>, which would display them in a national museum on the Mall and a satellite facility in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> passed the measure by voice vote Monday. A similar bill passed the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on Oct. 3, but because of slight differences in the two bills' language, Sen. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>, planned to ask the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to approve the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> version today, said <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Zell </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Indian Affairs, which <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON> chairs. The measure may at long last make peace among diverse factions, first by resolving a 10-year-old dispute in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> over how to display and preserve the <ORGANIZATION> Heye </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> collection of more than 1 million Indian artifacts. Second, it stipulates that the <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION>, where possible, return some 18,000 Indian remains to their original tribes for burial. The question of the remains had been the last obstacle to crafting a passable bill, and compromise came in September when <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> reversed the museum's long-held policy that the bones were necessary for study Indians nationwide, seeking to bury their ancestors, heralded his decision as a watershed that will influence other museums. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> called Monday's <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> action `` a wonderful moment.'' `` It opens new horizons for the <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION> and the world,'' he said in a statement. `` We'll be working with Native American communities in ways we've never done before, and it's a model for working with other communities.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GOPGovernors 630   11-14 0604</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-GOP Governors, 630</SECOND>
<HEAD>GOP Advice: Don't Hedge on Abortion</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WALTER R. MEARS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HILTON HEAD ISLAND, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Next season's Republican campaigners are being advised to take firm, early positions on the issue of abortion and run on them without hedging or compromising. Party leaders said Republicans lost votes in the off-year elections because they equivocated on abortion, not necessarily because they opposed it. In addition, they said, Democrats claimed the middle ground on the issue in defeating Republican candidates for governor of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> a week ago. `` Lesson learned,'' said <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, the Republican national chairman. `` Never let your opponent define you or control the terms of debate.'' <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> said that despite the 1989 defeats, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> prospects are good heading into next year's campaign for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and 36 governors. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, head man in the war on drugs, turned to politics to advise <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> governors Monday that hedging on abortion could cost the votes and doom candidates in 1990. `` I believe that Americans have a much higher degree of tolerance for honest differences, deeply held differences, than they have for trimmers and opportunists,'' <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said Republicans should take their positions on the basis of principle. `` Once you articulate that viewpoint, do not start changing just because political winds may appear to be shifting,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. That meshed with <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>'s counsel. Candidates, he said, must decide what they believe about the issue, state that position clearly and refuse to equivocate, no matter the campaign pressures. `` Our party is a big tent,'' <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> said. `` We can house many views on many issues. Abortion is no exception.'' The party platform of 1988 opposes abortion, but <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> leaders said party candidates do n't need to heed it. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> is not a single-issue party,'' said <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, an abortion foe. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said there are many pro-choice GOP leaders, in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and among the governors. Long term, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said he doubts the issue will help or hurt either political party. Party policy, and President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s veto-enforced opposition to abortion, align the party against the abortion rights activists who demonstrated in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and elsewhere Sunday. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> challenged them to demonstrate next time against drugs and the birth of cocaine-addicted babies. `` I do n't think that the record suggests that the pro-life position is political suicide,'' he said. `` It was n't political suicide for <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> when he ran. It was n't political suicide for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> when he ran. ... `` We now have a situation ... where <PERSON> Molly </PERSON> <PERSON> Yard </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION>, stands up and says to us if you dare to run people who are pro life we will get someone else up against you and beat your brains out,'' <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said. `` How dare she say that.'' <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said that `` as long as people are marching ... for rights and freedoms and protections, I would like to see a march on <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to protest the birth of cocaine babies.'' He said people of all parties and persuasions could join that demonstration, suggesting it should include `` some of the folks from <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> and elsewhere'' who march for abortion rights. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said the demonstrators claim to be concerned about the poor, so they ought to be protesting drugs. `` Whatever number of people have been hurt in back-alley abortions, it is a small number compared to the number of people who have been hurt by back-alley drug sales,'' he said. The governors were winding up their annual conference today with an education discussion featuring <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s assistant for economic and domestic policy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MilitaryJetCrash     11-14 0321</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Military Jet Crash,0330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Catastrophic Engine Failure Caused Jet Crash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MARIETTA, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> jet crashed last week because its engine suddenly failed, The Atlanta Constitution said in a report on the accident that destroyed 12 apartments and killed two people in this <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> suburb. Investigators have pinpointed which engine parts caused the sudden, catastrophic failure of the A-7E Corsair II's engine Thursday, the newspaper, quoting an unidentified source close to the investigation, reported in Tuesday editions. The source, however, declined to say exactly what went wrong. Air traffic controllers said engine and radio failure may have occurred about two minutes before the crash, the time of the tower's last contact with the pilot. They said there was no indication the plane was in trouble before it hit the apartment complex. An investigation of the crash is expected to take at least 30 days. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> on Monday said it would pay the funeral expenses of the two people who were killed when the jet slammed into their apartment complex: <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Dick </PERSON>, 24, and <PERSON> Margie </PERSON> <PERSON> Padovani </PERSON>. <PERSON> Padovani </PERSON>, 28, who was two months pregnant, died of burns Friday. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON>'s body was transported to <ORGANIZATION> Meridian </ORGANIZATION>, Miss. Ms. <PERSON> Padovani </PERSON>'s body will be transported to her hometown of <LOCATION> Hempstead </LOCATION>, N.Y Her 5-year-old daughter, <PERSON> Jacquelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Padovani </PERSON>, 5, remained in critical condition at <ORGANIZATION> Grady </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> with burns over about half of her body. The jet's pilot, Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Conlyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 37, was listed in serious condition at <LOCATION> Kennestone </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Marietta </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Conlyn </PERSON> was the only person aboard the unarmed attack plane when it crashed. The jet was returning to the <ORGANIZATION> NAS </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Dobbins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, about two miles from the apartments and 15 miles from downtown <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, when it went down. The crash destroyed 12 of the 76 units at the <ORGANIZATION> Pine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Village </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> apartment complex and heavily damaged another 20, said <PERSON> Kathie </PERSON> <PERSON> Barton </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Smyrna </LOCATION>'s director of community relations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Berlin-Turks     11-14 0664</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Berlin-Turks,0684</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Great Weekend, A Worrying Future for Turks in Berlin</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-East Germany, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BARR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The opening of the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall showered cash on Turkish merchants down the road from Checkpoint <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON>, but <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s largest minority community still feels enclosed by discrimination. `` The newsstands, the vegetable shops, the electronics stores had the business of a lifetime this weekend,'' said <PERSON> Mehmet </PERSON> <PERSON> Elmasgunes </PERSON>, an officer at <LOCATION> Bamukbank </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s predominantly Turkish <LOCATION> Kreuzberg </LOCATION> district. It was an unexpected payoff, he said, for people who years ago moved into a rundown neighborhood where not every apartment had a toilet. Behind the Wall, however, is a potential flood of competition for the low-paid jobs once reserved for immigrants. There may be even more demand for scarce housing, an issue already turned against foreigners by right-wing extremists. On the Turkish side, there is frustration about being barred from the civil service and the legal profession, about the difficulty in becoming German citizens and the red tape that keeps families separated. `` We have begun with taking down the worst wall, the biggest wall, and we want to work with the <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> people to take down these other walls,'' said <PERSON> Husnu </PERSON> <PERSON> Ozankli </PERSON>, chairman of the Turkish community organization in <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. `` The Turkish people have been here 25 years, 35 years now and we consider ourselves part of this society.'' Of the 755,000 workers in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, according to government statistics, 47,000 are Turks, mostly employed in factories or low-paid service jobs. Yugoslavs, who hold 15,000 jobs, are the next largest immigrant group. These `` guest workers'' were welcomed in the 1960s, but since 1973 immigration has been restricted to spouses or children of workers already here. `` If I married a woman in <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> today, she could not come for at least a year,'' <PERSON> Ozkanli </PERSON> said. `` There are so many application procedures that are just harassment.'' In local elections in January, the right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> blamed immigrants for <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s ills. One poster accused Turks of taking apartments needed by Germans. The party's share of the vote, though only 7.5 percent, was a green light for bigotry. `` Careful, stinking Turkish pack! Get out of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, you pigs,'' said one note <PERSON> Ozkanli </PERSON> received after the election. `` It is better if you pack your suitcases now and finally get out of the city before it is too late. 7.5 percent _ that's just the beginning,'' said another. <PERSON> Alaaddin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ozmert </PERSON>, a Turkish attache in <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> who deals with employment and benefit issues, contended that Turkish workers have little to fear from the opening of the Wall. `` The Turkish workers living here are qualified, skilled workers, and they are ... acclimatized to the life here and to the market,'' said <PERSON> Ozmert </PERSON>. `` The refugees from the East bloc countries are not yet familiar with Western technology. They would have to be re-educated to have a chance in the job market.'' At <LOCATION> Bamukbank </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Elmasgunes </PERSON> said he believed most East Berliners would be content to visit and would not settle permanently in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. The merchants will be happy to see them return. Even in the more subdued, workaday atmosphere that settled over <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> on Monday, there was hardly room to squirm among the shoppers at Ocak Import. A clerk said at least 2,000 radio-cassette players were sold over the weekend, and the store hired a truck Monday to go to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> to replenish stocks. `` We did n't think people would come here, but it was like a carnival in the streets,'' said <PERSON> Mahmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Balli </PERSON> at Selcuk Photo. He held up an empty cassette tape rack to show how good business had been. <PERSON> Ozkanli </PERSON> emphasized that he shared in the jubilation that gripped the city, and he offered visitors pieces he had chipped off the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall the night before. For now, he said, `` we do n't mind stepping back a bit.'' `` Everyone has to step back,'' added <PERSON> Dundar </PERSON> <PERSON> Atalay </PERSON>, a math teacher who dropped by the office. `` Even the Germans.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-Pay 520   11-14 0504</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Pay, 520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Foley Says House Will Pass Pay Raise Despite Nader Opposition</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Consumer advocate <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Nader </PERSON> is starting a campaign against it, but Speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> says he's confident the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> will approve a 33 percent pay raise and ethics reform package <PERSON> Nader </PERSON>, at a Monday news conference, said he was gearing up the same kind of effort that defeated a proposed 51 percent congressional pay raise earlier this year. The fact that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> was offering to reform its ethics this time in exchange for increasing its $ 89,500 salary and the salaries of federal judges and top executive officials does n't mean the public should support it, he said. `` I do n't think people in this country like the idea of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> telling them that they will reform themselves only if they get a pay increase,'' <PERSON> Nader </PERSON> said. `` That smells bad. `` Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are in the public service, not the profit service. If they want to make more money, they can quit and go across the street and join a corporate law firm that will pay them far more than they deserve,'' he said. <PERSON> Nader </PERSON> said he was contacting talk radio hosts and others to block what he said was another case of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> trying to slip one past the public, a statement <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> vehemently denied. `` As usual, Mr. <PERSON> Nader </PERSON> is wrong,'' <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> said. Thursday's scheduled vote `` wo n't be coming up in the dead of night, snuck through without a vote,'' he said However, <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> said he would n't release details of the package until Wednesday, the day before the vote. While no official version has been released, the outlines of the plan are widely known. It includes a 7.7 percent pay raise labeled `` cost of living adjustment'' that would take effect Jan. 1. A year later, a 25 percent raise would be combined with a new rule banning lawmakers from accepting fees for speeches. The package also includes tighter ethics restrictions on other outside income, including gifts and free trips. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Wertheimer </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Common </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cause </ORGANIZATION>, a group that pushes for tighter government ethics rules, praised the proposal. It `` will help ensure that the nation's top public officials are fully compensated by the public, without supplements of private interest influence money,'' he said Monday. It appeared Monday that <PERSON> Wertheimer </PERSON>'s scenario was only half right _ as the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seemed pleased to keep taking the speaking fees. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said Monday that he did n't have the votes to pass the package in his chamber, but it was possible the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> would allow the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to go its own way. There is less incentive to approve the plan in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. Its rules allow members to supplement their salaries up to 40 percent with speech honoraria, compared with 30 percent in the House. In addition, senators on the average have much more personal wealth than their <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> colleagues. Congressional salaries were last increased in 1987, when members' pay was raised from $ 77,400.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lite     11-14 0216</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lite,0224</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NANAIMO, British Columbia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A New Zealander is betting that British Columbians will pay to jump off a bridge. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> wants to bring `` bungie jumping'' to western <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, and thinks he's found the ideal location, the <LOCATION> Nanaimo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> gorge on <LOCATION> Vancouver </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. In the first year of bungie jumping in <LOCATION> Queenstown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>, about 17,000 thrillseekers paid to leap off a bridge with a thick rubber cord attached to their ankle, said <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, a veteran of more than 300 such jumps. `` There's been absolutely no injuries,'' he said. A bungie jumper leaps headfirst toward the water. The cord, or bungie, slows momentum after about a 45-foot freefall. The momentum is all but stopped by the time the jumper reaches the water _ but then comes the rebound. The bungie pulls the jumper back skyward at almost the same speed as the descent, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said. `` The initial plunge is the big thrill but you pull about three Gs -LRB- gravity-force -RRB- coming back up and you get three or four good bounces,'' he said. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said he's working on a long-term lease of the site and hopes to start building a bridge for people to jump from early next year. He said he expects to charge around $ 70 a jump.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WalterMears     11-14 0699</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Walter Mears,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING to include designation as Washington Today column</HEAD>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Budget Feud Shaping up as 1990 Campaign Theme</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WALTER R. MEARS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As a campaign slogan, sequestration is not going to make it. Too long, almost a tongue-twister, it is four syllables of bureaucratic jargon. Besides, as one Democrat observed, most voters probably think it is an Olympic event having something to do with horses. No such luck. What it is is the government code for automatic spending cuts, jargon masking the fact that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the White House have n't managed to put together a budget that fits their own deficit rules President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has delivered a simple, Republican translation that is likely to be built into the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> campaign of 1990: `` <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is to blame.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has the better pulpit, but the Democrats are n't about to plead guilty. So the budget feud will become a theme of the contest for <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seats next year, by which time the mess may be worse than it is now. The sequester system of spending reductions has been in effect for just short of a month, triggered by budget failure. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is threatening to leave it in place, unless <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> devises and delivers spending cuts of about $ 14 billion. `` Sequestration is a drastic action, but neither the administration nor the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> must flinch from our obligation to keep this nation's deficit moving down and ultimately to reduce the debt,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in self-appraisal of his presidency so far. But they've already flinched _ the deficit has n't been moving down. The sequester system of spending reductions is part of a process of deadlines and ceilings that are supposed to rein in deficit spending and start trimming it. The automatic cuts that now are in effect, and become more drastic if they stay, are to reduce spending by an estimated $ 16.1 billion, although the final figure may turn out to be somewhat lower. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> now says that unless <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> can slice the deficit by at least $ 14 billion in a bill that still is being negotiated, he'll veto the bill and leave the automatic cuts in place `` We are prepared to manage the government under sequester,'' he said. The president said the bill will have to produce real reductions in red ink without new taxes, without pushing off spending in a fashion that will push the deficit up in future budgets, and without gimmicks. He did n't define gimmicks, perhaps because the original administration plan for deficit reduction included savings to be realized by pushing up the date of a $ 3 billion military payroll, and dropping postal costs from the budget numbers. But there also is an advantage for the administration in keeping the current cuts _ <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> must send <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> a new federal budget, for the year beginning Oct. 1, 1990, only two months from now. With the automatic cuts in place at least into the winter months, it will be easier to produce a budget meeting next year's deficit ceiling, $ 74 billion. That also would strengthen his hand in opposing future tax increases. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he still wants to work with the Democrats in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for a bipartisan budget settlement that will bring down the deficits, and that politics can wait until the fall of 1990. But budget pronouncements on both sides are taking on a political edge. `` The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people know why this deficit is n't down,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said last Tuesday `` They see, 4 to 1, that the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is to blame.'' It's not a new argument. When he signed a 1981 debt ceiling bill that pushed the limit past $ 1 trillion, <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said the measure `` can stand as a monument to the policies of the past which brought it about, policies which as of today are reversed.'' The government has had to triple the limit since then. Last week, just before a default deadline, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> passed and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> signed a bill increasing the debt limit to $ 3.12 trillion.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Baker-OAS     11-14 0568</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Baker-OAS,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baker Suggests Central America Could Dominate Summit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> is raising the possibility that reported Soviet arms deliveries to <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> may be the most contentious issue at the Soviet-American summit meeting in three weeks. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> foreign ministers Monday evening that the Soviet shipments to that region remain the `` biggest obstacle'' to a genuine superpower accommodation. `` The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> bears a special responsibility because its arms and money, moving through <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, continue to support violence destruction and war,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. In previous statements, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> has said he does n't challenge the Soviet claim that it has ceased direct weapons shipments to <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> as of this year. But he has contended that Soviet shipments to the region through third countries and deliveries by the Soviet bloc have meant that the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>'s allies in the area continue to be well-stocked. His remarks Monday reinforced the notion that regional conflicts _ particularly in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> _ could produce fireworks when President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> hold their summit meeting in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> starting Dec. 2. The <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> meeting, featuring about 25 foreign ministers, was continuing today after a hectic opening session Monday that included: _ A sharp exchange in which Panamanian Foreign Minister <PERSON> Leonardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Kam </PERSON> accused the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> of pursuing `` fascist'' policies after <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> called <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> an `` outlaw regime'' that should be spurned by `` self-respecting democracies. _ The introduction by <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> of a resolution calling on all OAS member states to withdraw their ambassadors from <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> until a democratic process is under way there The human rights commission of the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> released a report Monday accusing <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> of widespread abuses. _ The admission of <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, amid numerous expressions of support, as the 32nd active member of the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> _ A demonstration by several dozen <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> employees outside the headquarters demanding higher pay The <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> is undergoing a cash flow crisis that has resulted in numerous layoffs and declining employee morale. _ A call by Nicaraguan Foreign Minister <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Escoto </PERSON> for an <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> appeal to the government of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> `` to cease immediately the bombing of the civilian population. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> held the leftist rebels responsible for the outbreak of fighting over the weekend, calling their attacks `` acts of terror, pure and simple.'' Shortly before foreign ministers opened their afternoon session, representatives of the leftist <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> government and the Nicaraguan Contras reconvened peace talks here after two days of discussions last week at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. There was no report on the meeting, but <PERSON> D'Escoto </PERSON>, in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, said there was minimal progress at the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> talks because the Contra delegates were n't interested in discussing the demobilization of their forces Central American presidents last summer called for the demobilization of the rebels by Dec. 5. Both the Contras and the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration regard that deadline as essentially meaningless because the presidents specified that the demobilization had to be voluntary. <PERSON> D'Escoto </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> could speed the peace process by converting the humanitarian aid being received by the rebels to demobilization aid. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration has insisted that the rebels must continue to receive <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> food, clothing, shelter and medical supplies until after the Feb. 25 national elections in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. That, the administration says, will give the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> additional incentive to hold free and fair elections.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891114-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-14-89 0152EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HUDSued     11-14 0552</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-HUD Sued,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>HUD Lender Sues, Alleging Unfair Audits Tainted Its Reputation</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
