<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Swaggart     02-02 0490</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Swaggart,0506</SECOND>
<HEAD>Swaggart Says Somebody Else Is Out To Get Him</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN SAYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BATON ROUGE, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 TV evangelist <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON>, who has threatened a libel suit for a stripper's story of an alleged sexual liaison with him, said Wednesday that he knows of another effort being planned to discredit him. Speaking to about 600 people at his Family Worship Center, <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> again accused Penthouse magazine of scheming to destroy his ministry with a story in which <PERSON> Catherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Kampen </PERSON> said she performed sex acts for him while he watched. Without revealing any details, <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> said his ministry had uncovered another move against him. <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> said the plan involved different people. `` There's another effort afoot, as preposterous as this one ... If you have enough money you can get anyone to say anything,'' <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kampen </PERSON>'s allegations are similar to those raised last year by a prostitute, <PERSON> Debra </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphree </PERSON>, which led to <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON>'s ouster from the Assemblies of God, a Pentecostal denomination, and reversed the fortunes of <ORGANIZATION> Jimmy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Swaggart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministries </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Kampen </PERSON>'s employer labeled the stripper's allegations, detailed in Penthouse's current issue, `` a pornographic fairy tale.'' The magazine said Monday that it was standing by its article. On Monday, <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> said there was `` not one shred of truth to these allegations. I have never met or seen the woman.'' <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON>'s attorneys said they had evidence the story was a hoax, but refused to discuss specifics Wednesday night, <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> said the ministry was approached by a man in December who knew of <PERSON> Kampen </PERSON>'s allegations `` and spilled his insides ... he said he believed it was a hoax.'' <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> also said a woman he identified as <PERSON> Kampen </PERSON>'s employer also called the ministry and said she knew the story was false. <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> did not reveal the caller's name. <PERSON> Rhonda </PERSON> <PERSON> Shear </PERSON>, co-owner of a `` strip-o-gram'' service that employs <PERSON> Kampen </PERSON> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, said Monday that her sister, <PERSON> Nona </PERSON>, told her <PERSON> Kampen </PERSON> made up the story after seeing the Penthouse story on <PERSON> Murphree </PERSON>'s relations with <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON>. Shear's sister, contacted in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, said a lawyer had advised her not to comment. Efforts to reach <PERSON> Kampen </PERSON> for comment have been unsuccessful. <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> said the man who revealed <PERSON> Kampen </PERSON>'s story to the ministry had told him Penthouse publisher <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Guccione </PERSON> was angry because of <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON>'s work in pressuring convenience stores to discontinue carrying the men's magazine. A telephone call after business hours Wednesday, seeking comment from Penthouse's spokesmen at their <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> offices was not answered. <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> said that during the past year, he had `` learned not to judge people. I've learned that I'm not God.'' He also advised his congregation not to `` get to the point where it's ` us' and ` them.''' His ministry would continue with expanded television programming to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> said. `` We are going to go forward to tell the story of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> as we have never gone forth before,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Ortega-US     02-02 0555</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ortega-US,0573</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ortega Meets Carter, Says Bush Telegram Pledged Peace</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 12 grafs to UPDATE with Ortega peace plan. Pick up
11th pvs, `Azcona said...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARRIE FIGDOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CARACAS, Venezuela (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in a telegram to Nicaraguan President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> that he was `` willing to work for peace,'' <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> said Wednesday. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> also met on Wednesday with former President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> and President-elect <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> and <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> both are in <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> for <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>' inauguration ceremonies this week. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> brought with him a new peace proposal which he showed to <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> and others. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> declined to discuss specifics, but told reporters it dealt with <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and its neighbor, <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, which the U.S.-backed Nicaraguan rebels have used as a base for some operations. A source close to Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, who is in <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> for <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>' inauguration, said the plan had to do with resettlement of rebels in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> once peace is achieved. Contra leader <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> said that Socialist international leaders familiar with the plan told him it also contained provisions for political prisoners in <LOCATION> Nicaraqua </LOCATION> and for granting civil liberties in the country. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> said in a live interview on <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> television that he sent a letter of congratulations to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> after the new <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president's inauguration, and that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sent him a telegram in response `` in which he said he was willing to work for peace.'' <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> said he reminded <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> of the time they shook hands at the inauguration of Brazilian President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> in 1985, when <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was vice president, and how `` all the leaders of the world applauded this unanimously.'' In a press conference after the interview, <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> said that `` the conditions are not yet ripe for a direct dialogue'' between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> said he would be meeting with Honduran President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Azcona </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyos </PERSON> and other Central American presidents this week in <LOCATION> Caracas </LOCATION> to discuss regional problems. `` This will give us an opportunity to talk about common problems -LRB- including -RRB- the -LRB- peace -RRB- plan, its advances, and a meeting of Central American presidents,'' he said. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>'s meeting with <PERSON> Azcona </PERSON> on Wednesday would be before a meeting <PERSON> Azcona </PERSON> plans to hold with <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> on Friday. <PERSON> Azcona </PERSON> said this week that the five <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> presidents have agreed to a summit on Feb. 14-15 in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> to discuss the peace plan, adopted in August 1987. The presidents are expected to be in <LOCATION> Caracas </LOCATION> for the Perez inauguration. After meeting with <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> and <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> said in a communique that the meeting was `` a great step towards the solution to the problem of <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>,'' although it did not elaborate. It emphasized that <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> was not acting as a representative of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government during his stay here. The former president moderated a forum on the Latin American foreign debt and noted in his brief comments that last year alone poor nations transferred $ 35 billion to rich countries in debt payments. `` We must seek solutions to the crises of nations, desperately poor and suffering, who spend sometimes half their export earnings just to pay interest on their debt and in the process the debt continues to increase,'' <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said. `` This reunion of world leaders is a wonderful opportunity to assess this crucial problem,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ColdRdp 2ndLd-Writethru a0761 02-02 1123</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cold Rdp, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0761,1145</SECOND>
<HEAD>Alaska Blaster: Cold Wave Brings Big Chill to Ever-Widening Area</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 9 grafs to UPDATE weather conditions in Western region,
Minnesota death; picks up 5th graf: `As the cold ...</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto PD1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By POLLY ANDERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Schools were ordered closed for the rest of the week in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> amid warnings that temperatures would go to 40 below, as the Alaska-born cold blast pushed south and east, stretching the big chill from the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>. Closed roads and icy highways took their toll as at least one motorist was killed in a 17-vehicle pileup in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, a tour bus crashed on an icy stretch of <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> interstate and 100-car string of accidents occurred near <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. `` February is going to be quite different from January,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Snider </PERSON>, a meteorologist at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Arbor </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>. Midwesterners who chuckled at the weather in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> over the weekend while polishing their golf clubs got their comeuppance as winter set in with a vengeance The normally rainy Pacific Northwest got a rare snowfall, and Easterners counted the waning hours of springlike weather as the cold front moved their way. <LOCATION> Bellingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, reported gusts over 100 mph early Wednesday and 60 mph by midday, knocking out power to as many as 15,000 customers. Snow caved in the roof of <PERSON> Everett </PERSON>'s soccer center, causing $ 250,000 damage, officials said. At least 20 people were injured when a tour bus carrying about two dozen passengers overturned on icy, wind-swept Interstate 80 in the <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, and six people were hospitalized, the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Highway Patrol reported. The big winter storm, with 60 mph gusts, knocked out electrical power to a `` big chunk'' of <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> on Wednesday night, with blackouts extending 40 miles to <LOCATION> Ogden </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Light </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Eskelsen </PERSON>. <PERSON> Eskelsen </PERSON> said engineers believed the outage was the result of `` dirty rain'' coating insulators on power poles and blowing fuses, and some crews had reports of burning power poles. In northern <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, authorities blamed a night of minus 20-degree temperatures for the hypothermia death of a 31-year-old woman whose frozen body was found on a sidewalk in Coleraine. As the cold pushed into the country Wednesday, temperatures fell 18 degrees in one hour at <LOCATION> Ardmore </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, which shared the nation's high of 84 degrees Tuesday afternoon, had readings in the lower teens a day later and wind chills in the 30-below-zero range. With <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>'s wind chills expected to dip as low as 80 degrees below over the next several days, Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinner </PERSON> ordered all schools to close until Monday. `` The weather forecast for the next two days calls for bitter cold to the extent that our young people are at risk, particularly those being transported to school,'' Sinner said. A wind-chill reading of 90 below was recorded Wednesday morning at <LOCATION> Tioga </LOCATION>, in northwestern <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>. The wind chill reading at mid-afternoon was 67 below at <LOCATION> Williston </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, where high winds and chill temperatures forced the closing of many roads, crews worked to clear wreckage from a pileup on Interstate 84. Eight semi trucks and nine other vehicles were involved, and at least one person was killed, said Lt. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Neal </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Idaho </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Twin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>. Not counting <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, was the nation's icebox at midday Wednesday, with a reading of 31 below zero, and temperatures in the state were forecast to dip below 40 below by Thursday morning. Electric power in <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, a city of 57,000, and several smaller towns in north-central <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> was knocked out for nearly an hour Wednesday morning when the <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eagle </ORGANIZATION> hydroelectric dam broke down. `` We do n't know what caused it,'' said <PERSON> Cort </PERSON> <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Montana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. `` There's a lot of things that can happen in weather like this.'' In <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, where it all began as the thermometer went as low as 60 below over the weekend, temperatures moderated Wednesday over much of the state except for the area near the Canadian border. While <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION> was reporting just 11 degrees below zero and no wind, <LOCATION> Northway </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> Highway near the Yukon had a 7 a.m. reading of 59 below. <LOCATION> Northway </LOCATION> posted an extreme of another sort when the barometric pressure reached 31.85 inches late Tuesday, a record high-pressure reading for the North American continent. The reading there eased off Wednesday morning but was still a high 31.31 inches. It was the effects of the high pressure system on the jet stream that created the unusual weather pattern. The barometric pressure was so high that the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Adminitration </ORGANIZATION> early Wednesday issued an order restricting instrument and night flights over <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, saying that altimeters that use barometric pressure might not calculate a plane's altitude accurately at that high pressure. The snowfall at <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> was enough to shut all runways at <LOCATION> Seattle-Tacoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> for nearly an hour Wednesday morning. The snowfall at the airport, 2 inches and counting at midmorning, plus temperatures in the teens made it the worst wintry weather in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> in more than three years. In the Plains, agriculture experts said the cold snap could reduce the evaporation from farm fields, already dry from last summer's drought and the dry winter. But that was the only good news for farmers in the forecast. Fruit growers worried that trees had begun to bud in the warmth and would now be in danger; the thirsty winter wheat crop in the southern Plains faced new stresses without the blanket of snow that usually keeps it safe during the winter; and ranchers across the Plains worked Wednesday to shelter cattle from the sudden cold. `` Now we've got something that's unbelieveable _ record highs, and suddenly within one day we go to cold temperatures,'' said <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Baenziger </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nebraska-Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> agronomy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> department </ORGANIZATION>. But in the East, record highs continued to topple Wednesday. In <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, normally known for its wintry weather, the record high for the date of 53, set just last year, was broken at 3 a.m. with a reading of 56 degrees. There was no snow on the ground, and <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION> was not frozen. It was 66 in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>; 67 in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>; 67 in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>; 59 in <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>; and 70 in <LOCATION> Roanoke </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, all records for the date. As winter swept toward the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> region, ski operators said it could n't come soon enough. `` The crowds just do n't see snow, and it stops them from coming out,'' said <PERSON> Sherry </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerych </PERSON>, ticket office manager at <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brighton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ski </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Area </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. `` As soon as it hits, we'll get ourselves fixed up again.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SouthAfrica     02-02 0297</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-South Africa,0303</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anti-Apartheid Guerrillas Reject Lawyers For Treason Trial</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four African <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas have refused legal representation for their treason trial. They said they did not recognize the court's authority and would not enter a plea. The four black men, in a statement read by one to the <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Delmas </LOCATION> on Wednesday, said <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s judicial system `` is founded on injustice and oppression.'' The defendants, who could face the death penalty if convicted, are charged with treason, terrorism, murder, attempted murder and other offenses in connection with a mine blast that wounded 17 people in 1986 and the killings of two policemen, a black politician and a black woman. The four, who said they have been tortured during eight months in solitary confinement, are <PERSON> Obed </PERSON> <PERSON> Masina </PERSON>, 56; Ting-ting <PERSON> Masango </PERSON>, 28; <LOCATION> Neo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Potsane </LOCATION>, 26, and <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Makhura </PERSON>, 26. In their statement, read by <PERSON> Masina </PERSON>, they acknowledged their membership in the military wing of the <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and described themselves as soldiers who should not be tried in a civilian court. Dozens of supporters in the courtroom raised clenched fists and cheered when <PERSON> Masina </PERSON> said the four would not enter a plea. The guerrilla group was outlawed in 1960 after decades of non-violent political activity and has been waging a bombing and sabotage campaign since 1961 aimed at ending white minority rule. <PERSON> Delmas </PERSON> is a farming town about 30 miles east of <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>. The country's longest treason trial, involving senior anti-apartheid leaders who last year received long prison terms, began there in 1985 before shifting to <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION>. Under the country's apartheid system, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s 26 million blacks have no vote in national affairs. The 5 million whites control the economy and maintain separate districts, schools and health services.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Taiwan-Gambling     02-02 0706</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Taiwan-Gambling,0727</SECOND>
<HEAD>Taiwan Officials Concerned Gambling Will Disrupt Booming Economy</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SHIRLEY LAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TAIPEI, Taiwan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With money pouring from a booming export business, a lust for gambling has taken hold and turned this Nationalist Chinese island into a massive underground casino. Officials say it threatens to disrupt the economy. The gambling craze is attributed to the flood of idle cash created by <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s economic success and of limited investment opportunities. `` It's worse than a huge casino,'' said a dismayed <PERSON> Jaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Shao-kang </PERSON>, a legislator of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. `` We do n't even have fair gambling rules and decent bookies.'' Gambling is illegal in <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, but an estimated 2 million people, or roughly one-tenth the population, play an underground game based on results of a twice-weekly lottery in nearby <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. They are lured by the chance to win 10 to 500 times their bets, which typically are 500 <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> dollars -LRB- $ 18 -RRB- or more. Only a tiny fraction of players, about 6,000 people, were arrested or fined last year. The game became a favorite with farmers, factory workers and market vendors after the government suspended its own lottery in 1987 to break up underground gambling based on the drawing. On Tuesdays and Thursdays, when the <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> lottery is held, <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s telephone lines are jammed by people calling bookies for results. Gamblers pray to folk gods for winning numbers and often celebrate at <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> temples when they win. `` The lottery gamblers have gone too far,'' fumed <PERSON> Ching </PERSON> <PERSON> Mei-hsien </PERSON>, principal of <LOCATION> Taipei </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Fu </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Primary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, which is near such a temple. `` Their noisy celebrations often disrupt our students in class.'' <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s two largest cities, <LOCATION> Taipei </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kaohsiung </LOCATION>, recently proposed running their own lotteries to raise funds for social welfare programs. Cabinet approval is needed for the drawings to begin later this year. Meanwhile, tens of thousands of Taiwanese have turned to gambling on futures prices on commodity markets in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. An estimated 500 local companies, including jewelry shops and investment firms, accept daily bets totaling about 5 billion <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> dollars -LRB- $ 179 million -RRB- based on the movement of futures prices on the overseas markets, according to <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Tsai </PERSON>, a financial consultant with the <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, which advises businesses and government agencies. Newspapers estimate each company has about 160 clients, meaning about 80,000 people gamble on commodity prices. Even the local stock exchange is widely viewed as little more than a legal form of gambling. Many inexperienced players such as housewives, office clerks, retired servicemen and college students view the market solely as a way to make quick money through speculation. The exchange reported in January that about 1.66 million people have opened accounts with stock brokers. Trading volume totaled the <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> dollar equivalent of about $ 280 billion last year, the third largest in the world after <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. On average, each of the total 34 billion shares changed hands nearly three times last year, even though roughly two-thirds of the shares were closely held and not for sale. <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> Chien </PERSON>, chairman of the state-run <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Planning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, believes the gambling craze has changed traditional values that helped <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> improve its economy dramatically, with per capita annual income in 1988 of 157,400 <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> dollars -LRB- $ 5,512 -RRB-, a 56 percent increase from 1983. `` So many people are obsessed with speculation,'' <PERSON> Chien </PERSON> said. `` They want to become rich overnight, and they no longer work so hard for the money.'' In a recent speech, Economics Minister <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> <PERSON> Li-an </PERSON> said the trend could eventually erode <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s economic achievement. He complained that businesmen increasingly prefer the pursuit of quick profit through gambling and speculation over productive investment. <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> <PERSON> Shou-hsiang </PERSON>, an economics professor at <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Culture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Taipei </LOCATION>, said the lack of channels for investment is a major reason behind the upswing in gambling. Most bonds are purchased by banks, real estate is too expensive and only a few mutual funds are allowed. The government has taken some steps to help open up new investment opportunities in recent years, easing foreign exchange controls to stimulate overseas investment. Some Taiwanese still fear overseas investments as an unknown risk, however, and have been reluctant to diversify.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0017EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-GuardianHusband 1stLd-Writethru a0775 02-02 0456</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Guardian Husband, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0775,0466</SECOND>
<HEAD>Husband Seeks Abortion For Wife To Save Her Life</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf, `Herbert Klein's ..., to CORRECT husband's name
to Martin, sted Herbert; picks up 3rd graf: `Klein, 34, ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAT MILTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MINEOLA, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man whose pregnant wife has been in a coma for seven weeks urged asked a judge Wednesday to appoint him her legal guardian so he can authorize an abortion that he says will save her life. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>'s 32-year-old wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>, was critically injured in a car collision on Dec. 13 and is in a coma at north <ORGANIZATION> Shore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Manhasset </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>, 34, a self-employed accountant who lives in <LOCATION> Upper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brookville </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, told the court that physicians have advised him that an abortion is necessary to save his wife's life and assist in her recovery. His petition is opposed by anti-abortion activists <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Short </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Broderick </PERSON>, who have asked the court to be appointed legal guardians of the fetus, which is about 16 to 18 weeks old. The case, considered unprecedented by legal and medical experts, is being heard by Justice <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> McCaffrey </PERSON> of the trial-level state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>'s parents, <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> and <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> Zusselman </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Delray </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, attended Wednesday's hearing and said they too were in favor of ending their daughter's pregnancy. Mrs. <PERSON> Zusselman </PERSON> told the court that her daughter and son-in-law, who have a 3-year-old daughter, had been looking forward to having a second child. Asked if she agreed that ending the pregnancy was in her daughter's best interest, Mrs. <PERSON> Zusselman </PERSON> replied: `` Absolutely.'' Three physicians, called to testified by <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>'s attorney <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Schutz </PERSON>, said that a continued pregnancy could endanger Mrs. <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>'s well-being Dr. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, a professor of obstetrics and gynecology at <ORGANIZATION> Albert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Einstein </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>, said he felt strongly that ending the pregnancy was necessary to save her life and should be done immediately, he said. `` A continuation of this pregnancy would push her over the cliff,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Carras </PERSON>, chief of neurosurgery at <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Shore </LOCATION>, said that the prognosis for Mrs. <PERSON> Klein </PERSON> was guarded because of the pregnancy and other conditions. The <LOCATION> Nassau </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> district attorney's office was allowed to monitor the proceedings to `` ensure that there is no criminal violation of law,'' according to Assistant District Attorney <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiernan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Schutz </PERSON> objected to the prosecutor's involvement. `` What is this nonsense of a criminal statute?'' he said. `` We are doing nothing criminal here. We are only asking the court to appoint an guardian for the welfare of a woman in a coma.'' The case was continued to Thursday, at which time the judge was expected to consider the petitions of the two Right-To-Life advocates.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Poland-Romania     02-02 0214</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Romania,0220</SECOND>
<HEAD>Protesters Detained In Anti-Romania Rally</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police arrested about 20 people during a protest against <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s alleged repression of ethnic Hungarians and its campaign of demolishing villages, a spokeswoman for the activists said. The demonstration outside the Romanian Embassy was organized by members of the <ORGANIZATION> Polish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and Solidarity trade union movement, said the spokeswoman, <PERSON> Zuzanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Dabrowska </PERSON>. Both organizations are banned. Ms. <PERSON> Dabrowska </PERSON> said a small group of protesters on Tuesday gathered in front of the embassy and shouted `` We are in solidarity with the Romanians.'' The group distributed leaflets to about 100 people across the street from the embassy before police began making arrests. `` We would like Feb. 1 to become the day of solidarity with the Romanian nation. The situation there has not changed and it's important we establish such a tradition,'' <PERSON> Dabrowska </PERSON> said Romanian leader <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>'s plan to demolish up to 7,000 villages in his Soviet bloc country and replace them with huge agro-industrial complexes has been widely criticized as a flagrant violation of human rights. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> is particularly concerned that many of the villages to be razed are inhabited by ethnic Hungarians, and last year the official Polish press pointed out that a few of the villages are populated by ethnic Poles.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-PLO     02-02 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-PLO,0664</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israelis Debate The Once-Unthinkable: Talking To The PLO</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP Extra</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By RONI RABIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Spurred by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> decision to open talks with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, Israelis have embarked on a serious debate about a subject once virtually taboo here: talking peace with the Palestinian organization. The subject is debated almost daily on radio shows and in newspaper columns. At least two members of the left-leaning <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, Cabinet Minister <PERSON> Ezer </PERSON> <PERSON> Weizman </PERSON> and ex-Minister <PERSON> Abba </PERSON> <PERSON> Eban </PERSON>, have called for talking to <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s representatives. The broad-based Peace Now movement recently changed its position to support talks with the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. `` We must speak with them, we must listen, we must exchange words ... We have to talk to those we want to make peace with,'' said <PERSON> Galia </PERSON> <PERSON> Golan </PERSON>, a leading Peace Now figure. She and <PERSON> Eban </PERSON> are attending a conference on the Israeli-Palestinian conflict in <LOCATION> Amsterdam </LOCATION> along with <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> officials, despite an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> law against meetings with members of `` terrorist'' organizations. For many Israelis, accepting the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> is not just a political but a psychological hurdle. For years, they have associated it with atrocities, such as the 1972 massacre of 11 Israeli athletes at the Olympic Games in <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION>. But a public opinion poll late last year indicated 54 percent of Israelis support talks with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, provided the organization renounces terrorism and accepts <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s right to exist. The change in opinion is due in part to the Palestinian uprising in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> and in part to <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s statements in December renouncing terrorism and accepting <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s existence. Strong tactics aimed at quelling the 13-month uprising, or intefadeh, have brought international criticism of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. At least 370 Palestinians and 15 Israelis have died in the rebellion. `` Before the intefadeh, we saw the Palestinians in the occupied territories as construction workers, and Palestinians outside were terrorists,'' said <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Amirov </PERSON>, who was kicked out of the right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> bloc for holding talks with pro-PLO figures two years ago. `` Now there is a whole new image: the image of a 14-year-old boy who throws stones, and who can not be beaten by our army.'' The <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> chief's new moderate stance has isolated <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> agreed to open a dialogue with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> in December, and several European nations are urging <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to do the same. Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, leader of the right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> bloc, repeated Tuesday he would never speak to the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. His party's coalition agreement with <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> takes that stand, but dovish members of <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> are starting to call for changes At least two Labor members are among the four Israeli legislators who have attended meetings along with <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> officials in the past month. <PERSON> Weizman </PERSON>, a former air force officer and defense minister, said in an interview with the <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> last week <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> should drop the ban on talking to the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. `` Today the only party able to deliver what it promises in the territories _ able to bring about an end to the rioting _ is the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said But opponents _ including <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION>, which won the most votes in November elections _ say the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> has not changed, despite <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s statements `` The bottom line is they want a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state in <LOCATION> Judea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Samarea </LOCATION> just as a down payment to throw us out of here,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> member <PERSON> Tzahi </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanegbi </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Judea </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Samarea </PERSON> are the biblical names of the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>. Security risks are a persuasive argument. Even Israelis who support talks with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> are aware of the risk a Palestinian state might pose to the Jewish state. Israelis have fought five wars with <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> states in 40 years and still remember the vulnerable narrow borders before <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> captured the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> in the 1967 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Elephant     02-02 0475</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Elephant,0489</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pachyderm With Proper Posture To Take Up Burden Of Buddha's Tooth</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEXTER CRUEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLOMBO, Sri Lanka (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It takes a special tusker to carry <PERSON> Buddha </PERSON>'s tooth. That task will fall to <LOCATION> Indiraja </LOCATION>, a 4,884-pound elephant from <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> named in honor of the late Prime Minister <PERSON> Indira </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>. But <PERSON> Indiraja </PERSON>, who will be shipped to <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> next week to begin years of training in the sacred service of <PERSON> Buddha </PERSON>, has a tough act to follow. The new elephant will replace <PERSON> Raja </PERSON>, a popular pachyderm who served for half a century at the Temple of the Tooth in <LOCATION> Kandy </LOCATION>, according to <PERSON> Neranjan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wijeratne </PERSON>, the temple's chief custodian. <PERSON> Raja </PERSON> was long in the tooth himself, reaching the age of 82 before dying in July. The 13-year-old Indiraja, also a male, was selected for his proper posture so that he may carry the sacred tooth of <PERSON> Buddha </PERSON> in one of <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>'s most colorful pageants. `` It will take couple of years to train the elephant,'' <PERSON> Wijeratne </PERSON> said Wednesday. He picked out <LOCATION> Indiraja </LOCATION> during a visit to <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> after Prime Minister <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> announced plans to donate an elephant to the temple in <LOCATION> Kandy </LOCATION>, 50 miles east of <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>. The death of the beloved Raja, whose name means `` King'' in the Sinhalese language, plunged Sinhalese Buddhists into grief. <PERSON> Raja </PERSON> was so popular that former President <PERSON> Junius </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jayewardene </PERSON> declared him a national treasure. <PERSON> Indiraja </PERSON>, who will arrive in <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> on Feb. 8, measures 7 -LCB- feet from head to toe and has a flat back. Both his tail and trunk touch the ground in the arc deemed proper for elephants. The main task for Indiraja will be carrying the sacred tooth, revered as coming from <PERSON> Buddha </PERSON>'s own mouth, at the annual <LOCATION> Kandy </LOCATION> pageant, which is held for two weeks in July and August. Because Indiraja still will be in training at the time of this year's festivities, the <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committe </ORGANIZATION> is trying to find a local male elephant _ only males can carry the tooth _ for the task. Efforts are on either to reduce the amount of fireworks and noise so that the untrained elephant wo n't panic, or have an elephant who is unaffected by noise and fireworks in the tooth-carrying ceremony. According to historians, the tooth was smuggled into <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> in the 4th century for safekeeping during a war. The tooth is kept in a golden casket at the temple at <LOCATION> Kandy </LOCATION>. During the festival, it is paraded around the town on an elephant's back Buddhism was founded in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> about 500 B.C. when <PERSON> Siddhartha </PERSON> <PERSON> Gautama </PERSON>, born a prince, achieved enlightenment. He later came to be known as Lord <PERSON> Buddha </PERSON>. Sinhalese Buddhists make up about 75 percent of <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>'s 16 million people. There are about 5 million Buddhists in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HostageSchool     02-02 0720</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hostage School,0740</SECOND>
<HEAD>School Seige One Year Later: `I'm Glad The Children Didn't See Blood'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOYT HARWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TUSCALOOSA, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Teacher <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON> has received honors from law officers for trying to fight off a gunman who invaded her school a year ago. But she is proudest that no children were harmed in the 12-hour ordeal. `` I thought about that when I heard of children getting killed and wounded at other schools in the country recently,'' she said. `` I was glad our children did n't have to see any blood. Blood is life.'' Recent shootings at schools in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, `` made me realize how thankful I am that it was n't our school,'' said <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Carden </PERSON>, headmaster of the <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> End </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. `` We do n't want to turn our schools into prisons, but we've got to do something to protect our children.'' West End <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> is planning to build another campus, he said, `` and the first thing we thought about is security.'' Last Feb. 2, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>, wearing denim clothes, a baseball-type cap and carrying several guns, entered the school's elementary building at 8:30 a.m., accompanied by an unwitting accomplice, and took more than 80 children hostage. <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> allowed his companion to leave in the middle of the day but he remained until 8:30 p.m., when officers subdued him as he emerged after hearing a videotaped fae pardon sent from <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> by Gov. Guy Hunt. As the hours of the seige crept along, <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> at times allowed groups of hostage children to go free, but at the end Mrs. <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON>'s and another class _ 26 people in all _ were still in their rooms <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> pleaded guilty in October to charges he kidnapped 110 children and adults at the private school, and was sentenced to a life term and five 20-year terms, with the judge recommending psychiatric help. Two of <PERSON> Carden </PERSON>'s children, <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON>, were in the third and first grades. <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Carden </PERSON> said, does n't seem to show any after-affects but <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> has developed a fear of being left alone at times. When <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> was freed that night, <PERSON> Carden </PERSON> said, the child's only complaint was, `` I did n't get to eat my lunch.'' When released, most children tended to react to their parents' emotions, he said `` The reason some kids were crying was because their parents were crying.'' <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodwin </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rivers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> who was called in that day to try to alleviate concerns of parents, said he believes the children have bounced back remarkably. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> of the psychology department at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION> is working with colleagues in other cities where gunmen have appeared at schools to develop ways to help children. `` It's amazing, but there have been very little psychological studies of such things,'' <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> said. `` We're trying to come up with a network to study long-range effects.'' When <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> entered Mrs. <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON>'s room, she attacked him with a Bible story book before he ordered his accomplice to tie her up with tape. `` I feel like when the children are at school they are my children and I have to take care of them,'' she said. After <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> pleaded guilty, the Madison County Sheriff's Department made Mrs. <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON> an honorary member, and last week the <ORGANIZATION> Tuscaloosa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fraternal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Order </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> gave her a certificate signifying she had done more for law enforcement in <LOCATION> Tuscaloosa </LOCATION> in 1988 than anyone other than officers While in the school, <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> demanded to see an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reporter, and told the reporter he was trying to make a statement on behalf of the nation's homeless and hungry. <PERSON> Carden </PERSON>, 35, said in an interview this week that he had expected enrollment to drop because of the takeover, `` but we did n't lose a single student. We have 410 enrolled now compared to 360 then.'' Meanwhile, with the elementary building separate from the rest of the school, <PERSON> Carden </PERSON> has taken steps to try to prevent any recurrence. An inter-com and a telephone line have been installed in the building, and the school's athletic director, `` a big, burly man,'' spends a lot of time there. In addition, `` panic doors'' have been installed, so no one can enter without a key or without being admitted from the inside.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AIDSCoach     02-02 0648</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS Coach,0665</SECOND>
<HEAD>AIDS Patient Fired From Volunteer Coaching Job</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PATTY REINERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANDERSONVILLE, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> has been barred from coaching his 10-year-old daughter's intramural basketball team because he has AIDS, but <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> hopes he wo n't be benched for long. <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> was dismissed last week after only one game as a volunteer coach at <ORGANIZATION> Laurel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. Already, he has launched a petition drive to get himself reinstated and to protest the <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Community Schools policy dealing with AIDS. `` The next step may be to keep me out of the school altogether,'' <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` My daughter will be there for four more years and if we let them defeat us now, I might not ever get to go to the school.'' <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>, 37, contracted acquired immune deficiency syndrome from tainted blood products during open-heart surgery in 1984. The disease, which attacks the body's immune system, is transmitted primarily through bodily fluids, such as during sexual contact, intravenous drug use and blood transfusions, but not through casual contact. <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> volunteered to coach the team of fourth -, fifth - and sixth-graders when his daughter <PERSON> Dande </PERSON> decided to play at the school, 60 miles southeast of `` I have no physical contact with them at all,'' <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said. `` I might throw a basketball to them, but if they're going to get it that way, we're all in trouble.'' Principal <PERSON> Odell </PERSON> <PERSON> Calihan </PERSON> and Superintendent <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Jobe </PERSON> refused to comment, saying only that they are following the school district's policy `` I know the situation, but I ca n't comment and I wo n't confirm any names,'' <PERSON> Jobe </PERSON> said when asked about <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>'s dismissal. `` It's just ignorance,'' <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said. `` They have n't educated themselves on AIDS and how it's transmitted. But the way the disease is spreading, they ought to start getting educated. Four or five years ago, I did n't think I'd ever come down with something like this either.'' A similar argument was made after school authorities in <LOCATION> Kokomo </LOCATION> barred young <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> from his classes because he has AIDS. His family later moved to another town and his story was told recently in a television movie. Under the <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> school district's AIDS policy approved in September, employees suspected of carrying the AIDS virus must submit to a medical examination by a doctor selected by the school board. If an employee tests positive for the virus, a committee decides whether the employee is an immediate public health threat. The superintendent serves on the committee and selects its members, which include a public health physician and school officials. `` If it's not discrimination, I do n't know what is,'' <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said. `` The superintendent chooses who he wants on the committee, so he can select people who support him. I ca n't even go to the meeting to defend myself.'' <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said many of the basketball players' parents have signed a petition to reinstate him as coach. `` I'd like to fight it and win it. But at this point in time, we've been struggling just to make ends meet and we're not going to be able to put out a lot of money,'' said <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>, whose family lives on his Social Security payments and the salary from his wife's factory job <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Theresa </PERSON>, has agreed to coach the team in the meantime, but school officials say she first must be tested for the AIDS virus. Until his case is resolved, <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> plans to attend games as a spectator. `` My daughter is on the team and they ca n't keep me from going to the games,'' he said. `` What I do n't understand is what's the difference if I'm sitting on the bench with the team as their coach, telling them when to go in and when to come out, or sitting in the bleachers as a parent with the other kids all around me, eating my popcorn?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--FloatingBillboards     02-02 0128</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Floating Billboards,0130</SECOND>
<HEAD>Billboards In Seine Drive City Crazy</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Parisians are calling on the national government to pull the plug on a flood of boat-borne billboards that are pitching products on the <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Seine </LOCATION>. The floating advertisements began popping up last month on the river that run through the city's center. <PERSON> Alain </PERSON> <PERSON> Juppe </PERSON>, a deputy to Mayor <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Chirac </PERSON>, wrote to <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarre </PERSON>, in charge of river transport in the Socialist government, demanding to know `` the measures he intends to take to remedy the situation.'' In a letter dated Tuesday and made public on Wednesday, <PERSON> Juppe </PERSON> said the city bans advertising on the banks of the <LOCATION> Seine </LOCATION>, one of the world's most romantic urban settings, but has no authority over boats on the river.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0203EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--IraniansBrawl     02-02 0156</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Iranians Brawl,0160</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iranians Attack Anti-Khomeini Students</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PERUGIA, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Iranian fundamentalists burst into a student center and attacked with knives and chains Iranians who were giving a presentation critical of <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, an Italian news agency reported. Four people were taken to a hospital in the northern Italian city for knife wounds, cuts and bruises, the <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported. About 30 people were watching a documentary about <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Perugia </ORGANIZATION>'s student center on Wednesday when the group of pro-Khomeini activists burst in, <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION> said, quoting witnesses. Several students kicked out part of a locked door and fled, while others were assaulted, the agency said. The assailants fled before police arrived, according to <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION>. The injured included three Iranian students and a representative of an Iranian group opposed to <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION> reported. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> on Wednesday began celebrating the 10th anniversary of the Islamic revolution that brought <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> to power.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0230EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     02-02 0049</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0049</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Wednesday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 05; 08; 12; 22; 23; 30.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 03; 09; 19; 40; 42; 54. Supplementary 52.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 8-1-0; 4-0-2-2; 8-3-1-8-1; 4-3-0-8-4-6.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Yeutter     02-02 0265</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Yeutter,270</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yeutter Attended Philip Morris Party</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>, outgoing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade representative and President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s nominee be agriculture secretary, was the guest of honor at a reception costing thousands of dollars sponsored by <ORGANIZATION> Philip </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the food, brewing and tobacco conglomerate, according to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>, whose confirmation hearing for the agriculture post is scheduled Thursday, did not check with his agency's ethics officer to see whether it would be appropriate to accept the hospitality of <ORGANIZATION> Philip </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morris </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolton </PERSON>, a spokesman for the trade office. `` He considered such approval unnecessary in light of his imminent departure from the office,'' <PERSON> Bolton </PERSON> was quoted as telling the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> in its Thursday editions. Earlier, the paper said, <PERSON> Bolton </PERSON> said that when the idea for the reception first arose, <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> was planning to return to private life and the reception was `` viewed here as a thank you for his efforts on behalf of the tobacco industry at large while he was <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade representative.'' If he is confirmed as secretary of agriculture, as expected, he will oversee an agency whose policies directly affect <ORGANIZATION> Philip </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morris </ORGANIZATION>' business interests <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, deputy director of the Office of Government Ethics, told of the situation but not <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>'s name or the specific executive posts, said, `` I've got problems with that,'' the newspaper said. Then told who it was who had accepted his hospitality from a major corporation with whom he did business as a government official, <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> should have sought an opinion from his agency ethics officer, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0244EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CockroachEar     02-02 0262</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cockroach Ear,0269</SECOND>
<HEAD>Got a Bug in Your Ear? Docs Say Suck It Out</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The patient with the bug in her ear screamed, `` Get that sucker!'' That rang a bell for her doctors who failed to nab the critter with had been considered the best roach approach. The doctors were excited when the woman came to the hospital with a cockroach in her ear. It was their long-awaited chance to try out a squirt of the anesthetic lidocaine, which a report four years ago said was the best way to remove a bug from an ear. `` With hurried anticipation, we sprayed the drug briskly into the ear canal and quickly jumped back, fully expecting the beast to come hurtling forth at first contact with the noxious substance,'' they told their colleagues in a letter in today's New England Journal of Medicine. Alas. Nothing happened. They tried again, this time dousing the intruder with a bigger dose. Still nothing. `` Get that sucker outa my ear!'' the patient screamed. `` What a brilliant idea,'' the doctors agreed. They hooked up a wall suction device and gently slipped the tip into the young women's ear. With a satisfying `` schloop!'' they nabbed the roach. `` Got him!'' the doctors wrote. `` Sure enough, there he was, plastered to the suction tip like a fly to flypaper.'' The doctors, <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> and <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rotello </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Syracuse </LOCATION>, conclude with this advice for physicians faced with a stuck bug: If all else fails, try sucking it out.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TampaDisturbance 3rdLd-Writethru a0424 02-02 0056</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tampa Disturbance, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0424,0054</SECOND>
<HEAD>Suspect Dies in Drug Arrest</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Fixes typo in lead.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TAMPA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rock-and-bottle throwing erupted in a housing project Wednesday night after a suspect died during a drug arrest, and more than 100 police officers turned out to quell the disturbance, police said.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>A 22-square-block, 2nd graf.</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0247EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-deKooning     02-02 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-de Kooning,0275</SECOND>
<HEAD>Artist Dies of Lung Cancer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SOUTHAMPTON, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Artist and teacher <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Kooning </PERSON> died Wednesday of lung cancer. She was 70. In November, she was diagnosed as having cancer after she entered <LOCATION> Jefferson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> to be treated for Lyme disease. She had been hospitalized here the past two weeks and died around 4:30 a.m. Wednesday. Her works are in the collections of the Museum of Modern Art and the <ORGANIZATION> Guggenheim </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and are featured in other institutions throughout the country. `` I always say I'm an escape artist,'' she once told art critic <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Slivka </PERSON> when asked to describe her style. `` Style is something I've always tried to avoid. I'm more interested in character.'' She was married to <PERSON> Willem </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Kooning </PERSON>, a renowned abstractionist. Although she established herself as an art commentator and held professorships at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mexico </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. She was born <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Catherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Fried </PERSON> in 1920. She attended <ORGANIZATION> Hunter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> then switched to the <ORGANIZATION> Leonardo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> da </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vinci </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> where she found friends active in the abstract and realism movement. At about this time, she met de Kooning and they were married Dec. 9, 1943, about five years after she had become his private student. Her first solo exhibition was in 1952 at the Stable Gallery in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Her most recent work was inspired by paleolithic cave paintings of <LOCATION> Lascaux </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Altamira </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>. In addition to her husband and sister, survivors include two brothers, <ORGANIZATION> Conrad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fried </ORGANIZATION>, of <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Fried </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Freeport </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0243EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     02-02 0945</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0981</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTA MONICA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress-singer <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON> and actor <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Penn </PERSON> apparently have reached an amicable agreement to end their stormy three-year marriage and divide their property, court records show. A divorce petition filed in <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> cited irreconcilable differences and seeks restoration of the pop singer's former name, <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON> <PERSON> Ciccone </PERSON>. It also said community property and financial obligations shared by the couple `` have been disposed of by written agreement.'' No details were disclosed in the two-page petition filed Jan. 25. <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON> publicist <PERSON> Liz </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenberg </PERSON> said last week <LOCATION> Penn </LOCATION> would get the couple's <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION> home and the singer would keep their <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> apartment. <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON> recently bought a $ 2.9 million <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> home. `` That's it,'' <LOCATION> Penn </LOCATION> publicist <PERSON> Lois </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said Wednesday. `` She kept one and he kept the other.'' The divorce action follows a Dec. 28 incident in which <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> deputies were called to the couple's <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION> home after the hot-tempered <LOCATION> Penn </LOCATION> allegedly beat <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON>. No charges were filed.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former heavyweight boxing champion <PERSON> Muhammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> is taking on <ORGANIZATION> K </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> mart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and another company for knockout stakes over an order of shoe polish. <ORGANIZATION> Muhammad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ali </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Champion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, owned by the ex-fighter, is suing K mart and <ORGANIZATION> Melville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> for allegedly balking on a contract for shoe polish and failing to sell the polish in 500 stores, according to motorcycle stunt driver <PERSON> Evel </PERSON> <PERSON> Knievel </PERSON>, a spokesman for <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> and senior vice president of his company. `` They only put it in about 60 stores. That's a breach of promise,'' said <PERSON> Knievel </PERSON>. `` I do n't know why they would do that.'' The lawsuit, filed Tuesday in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, seeks $ 550 million in damages, as well as $ 30,000 for attorney's fees and money owed to creditors. <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, the attorney for <PERSON> Ali </PERSON>'s company, said K mart and <PERSON> Melville </PERSON> backed out on their order when the <PERSON> Muhammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> shoe polish was delivered. <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON>, general counsel for <PERSON> Melville </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Harrison </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, refused to comment. <PERSON> Orren </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Knauer </PERSON>, director of investor relations at K mart's Troy, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, home office, said nobody was available to comment.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Given the choice to hear talks by <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON> or the woman who oversees the Playboy empire, crowds at an elite international seminar chose <PERSON> Christie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON> by a 2-1 margin. <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON> spoke Tuesday about `` The Nation State of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'' at the annual World Economic Forum in <LOCATION> Davos </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>, while just next door the chairwoman and chief executive of <ORGANIZATION> Playboy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION> was speaking about `` Leisure Life in the 90s.'' Ms. <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON>, who inherited the reins of Playboy from her father, <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON>, spoke to a standing room only crowd of about 160 on the changing tastes of the baby boom generation, family values and grown-up toys, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. `` The governor of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> is concerned because our seminar is scheduled opposite of his,'' she said. `` As someone who does a lot of business in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, I am sympathetic, but ...''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PORT ARTHUR, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A sculptor is preparing to unveil the life-size likenesses of rock legends <ORGANIZATION> Buddy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Holly </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Ritchie </PERSON> <PERSON> Valens </PERSON> and <PERSON> J.P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, a.k.a. the <ORGANIZATION> Big </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bopper </ORGANIZATION>, 30 years after they died in a plane crash. `` It looks good,'' <PERSON> J.P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, the Bopper's son, said of photos he's seen of the sculpture by <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arthur </LOCATION> artist <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>. <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, 29, of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, and other members of the <PERSON> Holly </PERSON> and <PERSON> Valens </PERSON> families were invited to a reception Thursday night to get their first look at a sculpture of the Bopper, who sang the classic `` Chantilly Lace,'' and a companion bronze of <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> with his arms around <PERSON> Holly </PERSON> and <PERSON> Valens </PERSON>, of `` La Bamba'' fame. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said the latter work is intended to show the trio as if they were standing for a picture just before boarding the fateful flight on Feb. 3, 1959, from <LOCATION> Clear </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, to <LOCATION> Fargo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Jiles </PERSON> <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> gained fame in southeast <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> as a disc jockey in nearby <LOCATION> Beaumont </LOCATION> and as a club performer.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HILLSBORO, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An attorney for <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Paycheck </PERSON> has asked for a delay in the country singer's resentencing for the 1985 tavern shooting of another man. Paycheck, 50, was convicted May 17, 1986, of aggravated assault and tampering with evidence in the Dec. 19, 1985, shooting of <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON> in a <LOCATION> Hillsboro </LOCATION> tavern. Wise was grazed in the forehead, recovered and testified against Paycheck. The singer, best known for his song, `` Take this Job and Shove It,'' has remained free while appealing his conviction and has been doing concerts, lawyer <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Buss </PERSON> said Wednesday. <PERSON> Buss </PERSON> said he asked the <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday to forbid lower courts from taking any action in the case until the high court rules on Paycheck's argument that a mandatory three-year prison sentence for use of a firearm during a crime was imposed improperly. If the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> agrees, it would delay Paycheck's resentencing scheduled for Monday in <LOCATION> Highland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Common Pleas Court
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SAN ANTONIO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mayor <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Cisneros </PERSON> will team up with country star <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> in a music video to woo country music fans to this south <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> city. The video, which will feature scenes of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> performing, will be shown Feb. 16 on the country music talk show `` <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> Now,'' along with a live appearance by <PERSON> Cisneros </PERSON>. The mayor is not scheduled to sing in the video, which will be shot Monday, but he said he would be willing to join <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> in a duet. `` If it involves hamming it up, I'll do it,'' <PERSON> Cisneros </PERSON> said Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0248EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PregnancyTests     02-02 0191</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pregnancy Tests,0195</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Says People Often Misinterpret Home Pregnancy Test Results</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Home pregnancy tests are frequently misinterpreted by ordinary people, says a report that questions whether the kits should stay on the market even though they are accurate when interpreted by lab workers. In a letter in today's <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>, Drs. <PERSON> Jocelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON> of Children's Hospital in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Mariet </PERSON> <PERSON> Iosefsohn </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> said they asked secretaries, clerks, messengers and janitors to analyze 200 urine samples using two brands of home pregnancy kits. Ten percent of the results of one test and 13 percent of the results of the other were wrong. However, when a lab technician used the kits, one was 100 percent accurate. The other kit gave no false results, although the results were indeterminate in four cases. The researchers noted that the manufacturers claim the home kits are 90 percent accurate. `` It seems clear from our observations that the discrepant results produced by laypersons were due more to difficulties in using the home test kits and interpreting results than to problems with the kits themselves,'' they wrote.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0794 02-02 0310</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0794,0314</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: ADDS de Kooning; A separate moved for AMs as a0429.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Bob Dunn</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEWARK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, a cartoonist and writer for the syndicated comic panel `` They'll Do It Every Time'' died Tuesday. He was 80. <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> was a founding member and former president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cartoonists </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, the world's largest organization of professional cartoonists. In 1975, he received the society's <PERSON> Elzie </PERSON> <PERSON> Segar </PERSON> Award and in 1976, its Reuben Award, better known as the comic world's Oscar. <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> also hosted one of the first television quiz shows, `` Quick on the Draw,'' and wrote more than 12 books. <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> joined The Star-Ledger of <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION> in the early 1930s and started selling his cartoons to magazines. He joined the <ORGANIZATION> Hearst </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in 1933, where he worked first as a reporter and then as an artist in the comic art department of King Features Syndicate, a division of <ORGANIZATION> Hearst </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Elaine de Kooning</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SOUTHAMPTON, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Kooning </PERSON>, an artist and teacher died Wednesday of lung cancer. She was 70. <PERSON> Mrs </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Kooning </PERSON>, who's first solo exhibition was in 1952 at the Stable Gallery in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, has works in the collections of the Museum of Modern Art, the <ORGANIZATION> Guggenheim </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and other institutions throughout the nation. In 1962, she was commissioned to do a portrait of President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> for the Truman Library in <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>. As was her manner, she immersed herself in the project, producing hundreds of sketches and about two dozen finished canvasses. One of the finished portraits hangs in the Truman Library and the other is in the <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> F. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Cambridge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. Mrs de Kooning also held professorships at such institutions as the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mexico </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BundyCelebration     02-02 0186</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bundy Celebration,0189</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officers Who Celebrated Bundy's Execution Cleared Of Wrongdoing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Twenty off-duty <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION> police officers who celebrated <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s execution outside <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> State Prison Jan. 24 did not violate departmental conduct policies, an internal investigation showed. The investigation began after newspaper reports said a group of officers celebrated <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s death Jan. 24 by singing songs like `` On Top of Ol' Sparky'' at a gathering that had the spirit _ and alcohol _ of a tailgate party. The investigation confirmed that one officer had been drinking, but found that he was not acting maliciously when he told reporters and others that he was <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION>'s chief of police, a spokesman said Tuesday. Investigator <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Crew </PERSON> said he thought the media overplayed the incident. `` I do n't think there was any malicious intent. Police officers are held to a higher standard of behavior, and that's not always fair.'' According to police spokesman <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiracofe </PERSON>, interviews with seven police officers and five civilian employees found that none of the officers at the prison near <LOCATION> Starke </LOCATION> were intoxicated, which would have violated police policy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0250EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Asthma     02-02 0341</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Asthma,0350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Concludes Allergies To Blame for All Asthma</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A study today concludes that virtually all asthma attacks are triggered by allergies, challenging a widely held belief. Experts have long believed that asthma attacks in children and young adults were usually caused by allergies, while in grownups they were usually thought to have other causes. The study, based on tests of 2,657 people, suggests that all asthma victims have the allergic variety, regardless of age. `` This helps us to understand better why allergic and non-allergic asthma look so much the same,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Burrows </PERSON>. `` It's all the same disease.'' <PERSON> Burrows </PERSON>, a researcher at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>, published his results in the New England Journal of Medicine. His team's conclusions were based largely on measurements of an antibody called immunoglobulin E, or IgE, which plays a key role in the allergic response that leads to asthma. Youngsters with asthma have high amounts of IgE, but these levels drop as people get older. The study found that even though older asthmatics' IgE levels seem low compared to children's, they are still higher than those of grownups who are free of asthma. The doctors concluded that because of the adults' relatively high IgE levels, their asthma was caused by allergies. They noted that routine skin tests that are used to pinpoint the cause of allergies frequently fail to show anything wrong. <PERSON> Burrows </PERSON> said this is probably because the tests do not include the specific substance _ called an allergen _ that is triggering the attacks. `` The message is pretty simple,'' said <PERSON> Burrows </PERSON>. `` For many years, people thought there were two different kinds of asthma, only one of which was an allergy problem. Even when it's not easy to demonstrate what the allergen might be, the immunoglobulin in the blood suggests that virtually all asthma has an allergic basis.'' The finding, if true, may have little effect on how doctors deal with asthma, since allergic and non-allergic asthma are usually treated with the same drugs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0253EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FishOil     02-02 0324</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fish Oil,0334</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Finds Effect of Fish Oil on Inflammation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fish oil's ability to lower the body's production of two important substances that cause inflammation may explain why it sometimes seems to relieve arthritis and other diseases, researchers reported today. The researchers studied the effects in the blood when nine healthy people took 18 fish oil capsules a day for six weeks. `` We found a very dramatic reduction in the ability of their white blood cells to make tumor necrosis factor and interleukin-1,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinarello </PERSON>, who reported his study in the New England Journal of Medicine. `` This is the first time that any dietary manipulation has been shown to change the production of these inflammatory compounds.'' Doctors have long noticed that <PERSON> Eskimos </PERSON> and others who eat lots of oily ocean fish have less heart disease than other people. They also are less likely to get arthritis, juvenile diabetes and other diseases that involve overactive inflammatory responses. Some studies suggest that fish oil supplements can lower blood cholesterol, protecting the arteries from damaging buildups. <PERSON> Dinarello </PERSON>, a researcher at <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, said the latest work implies that fish oil also protects the heart by reducing inflammation in the arteries that may lead to thickening of the artery walls. Ten weeks after they stopped taking fish oil, the volunteers' production of interleukin-1 had fallen 61 percent and tumor necrosis factor had dropped 40 percent <PERSON> Dinarello </PERSON> cautioned that the study did not include a comparison group, and said other kinds of oil supplements could have similar effects. While tumor necrosis factor was first noticed for its ability to shrink tumors, doctors believe its most important role in the body is causing inflammation in response to injury. Tumor necrosis factor has failed to work as a cancer treatment, and <PERSON> Dinarello </PERSON> said there is no evidence that reducing its levels in the body would increase susceptibility to cancer.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-North'sJurors Bjt   02-02 0759</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North's Jurors, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Search for Jurors Capable of Judgment But Ignorant of History</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> courtroom, a judge is looking for that rarest of creatures _ the person who barely knows anything about <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>. The judge selecting jurors to try <PERSON> North </PERSON> is making some progress, but the question arises: Will the jury that results be a cross-section of the community, capable of rendering an informed judgment? In the legal sense, it will be a jury of North's peers. The law only requires that it be a cross-section of citizens from which no one has been excluded by reason of sex, race or other arbitrary criteria. It need not be people comparable to North in any other way. What Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> seeks is a jury `` ignorant'' of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>'s activities _ people so removed from world affairs during the summer of 1987 that they were unaware that <PERSON> North </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> he had lied to it, believing his duty to his country required such deception. Such searches are conducted to ensure that jurors do not enter a case prejudiced either for or against a defendant. But in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>'s case, it means the exclusion of an enormous number of potential jurors who, at one point or another, read or heard something about him Sen. <PERSON> Howell </PERSON> <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON>, D-Ala., who served on the <ORGANIZATION> Iran-Contra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and is a former state judge, said the exclusion of knowledgeable people as jurors `` has inherent problems in it and raises real questions,'' but he does n't know the answers He said some people simply do n't watch television out of choice or because they are too busy. `` On the other hand, you have the chance they did n't have any interest and you would think they're lacking in the necessary intelligence to serve on it,'' he said `` Whether they will differ from normal, average jurors remains to be seen,'' he said. `` If a man never saw anything of it, what type of individual is he?'' Others go further. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Moffitt </PERSON>, a well-known criminal defense lawyer, questions whether a fair verdict can be rendered by people who knew nothing about the Iran-Contra affair before stepping into <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON>'s courtroom. `` I would n't want people who lived in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the seat of government, on that jury who were so uninformed,'' said <PERSON> Moffitt </PERSON>. `` Are they going to be interested in what goes on inside the courtroom if they were so uninterested for so long on what went on outside it?'' <PERSON> Moffitt </PERSON> said justice would be better served if six of the jurors could be drawn from the uninformed and six from those who followed the Iran-Contra affair, though he concedes that is not practical. On the other hand, say some legal experts, the jury system works well even with jurors who, for whatever reason, arrive innocent of knowledge of the case. `` Jurors are asked to bring a certain common sense into the jury room and try to determine whether a particular story makes sense and look witnesses in the eye to tell who is telling the truth,'' said <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Lacovara </PERSON>, a former prosecutor in the Watergate trial, another case drenched in publicity before it reached trial. `` It is not necessary for people to be highly educated or current in world affairs to make that assessment,'' <PERSON> Lacovara </PERSON> said. `` It's a burden to find qualified jurors, but I'm not saying it ca n't be done,'' added <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> LaFave </PERSON>, a criminal law expert at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION>. `` Do n't forget that all the pre-trial publicity has n't been unfavorable,'' added <PERSON> Neal </PERSON> <PERSON> Sonnett </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, president-elect of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Criminal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lawyers </ORGANIZATION>. `` Do n't forget the movement to pardon North. Not many people facing serious felony charges are asked to speak in support of the re-election of members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. So the government has to be as careful about prejudiced jurors as the defense.'' The jury's ignorance of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>'s activities is crucial because he was compelled to talk to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' Iran-Contra committees. In exchange, he was given limited immunity, a promise that his testimony would not be used against him in court. Prosecutors developed their case independently and charged <PERSON> North </PERSON> with obstructing presidential and congressional inquiries, lying to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and shredding evidence. For all the attention focused on North, <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON>, before the trial started, expressed confidence that an unknowing jury could be found to hear the facts and draw its own conclusions. He said the same questions were raised in the Watergate case, but a jury was found, a verdict was rendered and justice was done.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Condors Bjt   02-02 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Condors, Bjt,0695</SECOND>
<HEAD>Captive California Condors Court; Eagles Divebomb Andean Condor</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE SIEGEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Love is in the air at two zoos where scientists hope the world's last 28 <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> condors will mate themselves away from the brink of extinction, a biologist says. Meanwhile, one of seven Andean condors freed into the wilderness chickened out of a dogfight with two golden eagles half her size. `` We've got all sorts of great things happening with the Andeans and some equally exciting things happening with the captive <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> condors. We're very encouraged,'' <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Dowhan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> condor recovery coordinator, said Wednesday. Only 28 endangered <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> condors remain, 14 in captivity at the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Zoo and 14 others at the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diego </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Escondido </LOCATION>. Scientists hope the vulture-like creatures, which are <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s largest land birds with 9 -LCB- - foot wingspans, will reproduce enough so that some can be returned to the wild in five to 10 years Courtship started in early January among four pairs of the birds at <LOCATION> Escondido </LOCATION> and two pairs in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dowhan </PERSON> said during a phone interview from his office in <LOCATION> Ventura </LOCATION>. One of the courting pairs in <LOCATION> Escondido </LOCATION>, male condor AC-4 and female UN-1, started mating early in January, he added. Last April, the same pair produced a female chick named <PERSON> Molloko </PERSON>, the first <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> condor conceived and hatched in captivity. Scientists believe condors lay eggs 30 to 35 days after fertilization, but mating does n't necessarily result in fertilization, <PERSON> Dowhan </PERSON> said. The seven Andean condors, donated by zoos across the nation, were freed into rugged mountains 50 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> in an experiment meant to help biologists learn the best way to handle, release and monitor <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> condors once they reproduce in adequate numbers. About 1,000 to 2,000 of the wild Andean birds remain in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The most recent release was Jan. 21, when biologists removed netting from a roost box and feeding platform that housed four Andean condors in the Sespe Condor Sanctuary. On the same day, a hostile encounter occurred between two golden eagles and one of three other Andeans, which had been freed Dec. 17 from the nearby <ORGANIZATION> Hopper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mountain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refuge </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Dowhan </PERSON> said. The 10-month-old Andean, condor Y1, flew from <LOCATION> Hopper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> onto the eagles' turf, where `` the eagles made several ` stoops,' or aggressive drives, toward the condor and forced it to the ground,'' said a Fish and Wildlife Service news release. <PERSON> Dowhan </PERSON> said the condor soon returned to the air and `` made a beeline to the security of its home -LRB- roost box -RRB-. It was intimidated by the eagles,'' which have 5-foot wingspans. The Andean condors, which will be recaptured and re-released in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> when the experiment ends next year, will encounter a number of other birds in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s mountains and `` recognize some will be territorial and others may serve as pilots to where food is present,'' he said. There has n't been much flight activity among the four Andeans released Jan. 21, <PERSON> Dowhan </PERSON> said. Condor R4 immediately flew 120 feet into a brushy thicket and could n't figure out how to get back to her roost box. Biologists caught her Tuesday and returned her to the box, where <PERSON> Dowhan </PERSON> said `` she ate right away _ carcasses of stillborn calves.'' <PERSON> Dowhan </PERSON> said it will be months before the biologists place food for the carrion-eating condors away from their roost boxes in an effort to teach them to forage. Two of the three Andeans freed from <LOCATION> Hopper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> in December flew about three miles on Tuesday and passed over the Sespe roost box, but the four condors there `` did n't notice them. They were sleeping,'' <PERSON> Dowhan </PERSON> said. Back at the zoos, the six males court the females by arching their necks, looking at the ground, and trying to encircle the females with their outstretched wings. <PERSON> Dowhan </PERSON> said each female `` will try to come up under the male and nibble at his beak. That's a positive reaction. <PERSON> Dowhan </PERSON> said the breeding season runs from January to April.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890202-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-02-89 0211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DolphinDeaths Bjt   02-02 0566</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dolphin Deaths, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Origin Of Dolphin-Killing Red Tide Puzzles Experts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
