<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 2328EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PTLTrial 2ndLd-Writethru a0703 07-24 0585</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-PTL Trial, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0703,0594</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jury Begins Deliberations in Tax Trial of PTL Aides</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 1-2 to UPDATE with jury deliberating three hours
before leaving.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL NOWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLOTTE, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON> lied when they said <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> founder <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> authorized them to take ministry money they used to buy property and jewelry, a prosecutor said Monday before deliberations began in the Taggarts' tax evasion trial. The jury started deliberations just after 5 p.m. on the 12th day of the trial. Jurors left after three hours and were to resume Tuesday. `` In a nutshell, this case is about power,'' prosecutor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said in his closing statement in the brothers' trial. `` The power <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON> and his brother exercised at <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> to line their own pockets.'' The Taggarts are charged with evading $ 525,000 in income taxes after spending nearly $ 1.2 million in <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> money on personal luxuries such as condominums, jewelry, expensive cars and designer clothes. The trial began July 5. If convicted, each brother could be sentenced to 25 years in prison and face fines of more than $ 1 million. The defense rested Thursday following two days of testimony from the Taggarts, who began at <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> as piano players. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Potter </PERSON> gave no reasons for then postponing Friday's session Within a few years of joining <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> in the late 1970s, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON>, 32, was <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s top personal aide. <PERSON> James </PERSON>, 35, was the interior designer at <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> retreat just south of <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>. Before his closing remarks, defense attorney <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Cotten </PERSON> placed items from such exclusive <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> stores as <ORGANIZATION> Cartier </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Gucci </ORGANIZATION> on a bench in front of the jury. `` If what is on trial here is a lifestyle you do n't like, then we did n't need a trial at all,'' he said. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> told the jury that the government's case was made more difficult by some of the witnesses _ including the two defendants. `` If you're not offended by the evidence of how they spent the money they took from <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> ... you should be offended by the fact that both defendants got on the stand and lied,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said. He said there was ample evidence to support the government's case <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON> showed `` audacity and greed'' when he testified he was entitled to be paid at a level similar to <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> never authorized it, never, not once. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON> took the stand and lied to you and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON> conspired to take money from <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> and not pay taxes on it,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said. He referred to <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON>'s testimony that he had authority from <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> to take large cash advances and use PTL blank checks. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON> testified last week that his way of accounting for the $ 1.2 million was to submit documentation to justify it, receive a tax form from <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> that called the cash advances income or that the cash advances would be considered a loan which would be converted into a bonus. <PERSON> Cotten </PERSON> used his closing arguments to return to testimony about a verbal agreement he said was reached between <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> in 1983. He asked the jurors not to dismiss the agreement simply because it was an oral contract. <PERSON> Cotten </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> agreed to give <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON> access to the same resources he enjoyed. `` The intent was not to beat the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> out of money. It was to have <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> shoulder the burden,'' <PERSON> Cotten </PERSON> said.'
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 2335EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Britain-Cabinet 3rdLd-Writethru a0772 07-24 0818</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Britain-Cabinet, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0772,0842</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thatcher Names New Foreign, Defense Secretaries</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 5th graf, `Mrs. Thatcher...' to CORRECT title of social
security secretary.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MAUREEN JOHNSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> appointed new foreign and defense secretaries Monday, fired two Cabinet ministers and switched around others in the biggest government shake-up since she won power 10 years ago. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> named <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Major </PERSON>, one of the least-known members of her 22-member Cabinet, as the new foreign secretary, making him a prime contender to succeed her. He replaces Sir <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Howe </PERSON>, who was moved to a vacant post as deputy prime minister. <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> will also lead the governing <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION>. The prime minister, battling to halt her government's slide in popularity, also put new appointees in an array of major posts including the portfolios for <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and the environment. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> fired her harassed <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Channon </PERSON>, who had been accused of bungling bomb warnings before <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> Flight 103 was blown up over <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> on Dec. 21, and Social Security Secretary <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>. The two other Cabinet ministers to depart _ <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Younger </PERSON> and Trade and Industry Secretary Lord Young _ said they were resigning to resume business careers. Northern Ireland Secretary <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> was named defense secretary in an apparent reward after four years as <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s top official in the embattled province. The appointment of Major as foreign secretary was a big step up from his former <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> post as chief secretary to the treasury, the No. 2 financial official. The 46-year-old son of a circus trapeze artist was raised in poverty in south <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s rundown <LOCATION> Brixton </LOCATION> district, never went to university and worked as a building laborer before making a career in banking. He entered Parliament in the May 1979 general election that brought Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> to power and ousted a socialist <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> government. His appointment underlined the transformation of the hierarchy of the <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, once the preserve of the British upper classes, since Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, a grocer's daughter, took over. `` We now know, without the need for guesswork, who her chosen successor will be,'' <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s liberal Guardian newspaper commented Tuesday. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, 63, is widely expected to retire some time after bidding for an unprecedented fourth successive term at the next election. It must be held by mid-1992. The move of <PERSON> Howe </PERSON>, 62, to deputy prime minister was widely regarded as a demotion from one of the most prestigious jobs in the Cabinet. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> also brought into the Cabinet another member of the class of 1979, <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Patten </PERSON>, a rising star from the party's liberal wing, as the new environment secretary. Reflecting anxiety at the government's drop in the polls and its drubbing in elections for the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> last month, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> shifted Education Secretary <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> to the chairmanship of the <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Party chairman <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooke </PERSON> was named <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> Secretary, a tough job that effectively removes the incumbent from day-to-day contact with party political issues in mainland <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. Energy Secretary <PERSON> Cecil </PERSON> <PERSON> Parkinson </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> favorite whose political career was interrupted after a scandal over an extramarital liaison six years ago, was named transport secretary. He resigned from the <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> in 1983 after news broke that his ex-secretary, with whom he had an affair, was carrying his child. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> brought him back into the Cabinet when she won a third term in May 1987. The shake-up, announced after Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> summoned government ministers to her Downing Street office for private meetings, appeared aimed primarily at freshening the government's image. Beset by rising inflation, a revival of labor union militancy and facing a much tougher challenge from the revived <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> has trailed <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> seven to 15 points in polls since the spring. <PERSON> Patten </PERSON> succeeded <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Ridley </PERSON>, a chain-smoking scion of an aristocratic family, who was named trade and industry secretary. <PERSON> Ridley </PERSON>, accused by critics of mishandling the current passage through Parliament of a controversial new tax, is deeply unpopular with many party members, who blame him for worsening the government's poll standing. But Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, who has the sole power to appoint <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> ministers, has repeatedly defended him. The dismissal of <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Channon </PERSON>, an heir to the Guinness brewing fortune and reputedly the richest member of the Cabinet, had been predicted. In the aftermath of the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> disaster, his department was accused of being tardy about passing on detailed bomb warnings to airlines. Critics also said he mishandled current strikes by employees of <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rail </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> Underground. Other new Cabinet appointments announced were <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamont </PERSON> as treasury secretary and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Gummer </PERSON> as Agriculture Minister. Both previously held government jobs outside the Cabinet. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Wakeham </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader in the Commons, became the new energy secretary, and <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Newton </PERSON>, former trade minister, the new social security secretary.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ActressSlain     07-24 0353</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Actress Slain,0364</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Accused of Killing Actress Said to Have Gone to Samantha Smith's
Hometown</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TUCSON, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The man accused of killing actress <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaeffer </PERSON> reportedly traveled to the <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> hometown of <PERSON> Samantha </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, the young girl whose 1983 visit to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> drew international attention Police investigators were told that <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bardo </PERSON>, now 19, ran away and traveled to <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> four or five years ago to be near the <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> girl, the <ORGANIZATION> Tucson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citizen </ORGANIZATION> reported Saturday. In July 1983, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, then 11, went to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> for a two-week tour at the invitation of the late Soviet leader <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Andropov </PERSON>. She had written a letter to <PERSON> Andropov </PERSON>, asking the world leader whether he favored war. In an unusual move, he responded to her letter, telling her the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> people had peaceful intentions and inviting her to visit his country. Two years later, on Aug. 25, 1985, she and her father were killed in a plane crash near <LOCATION> Auburn </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> homicide detective, said he heard the <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> story from an acquaintance of <LOCATION> Bardo </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON> would not identify the acquaintance. Detective Sgt. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Armijo </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bardo </PERSON>'s father, <PERSON> Phillip </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, told <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> police detectives after his son's arrest that the son had developed the obsession for <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> and had run away to find her. <PERSON> Armijo </PERSON> said detectives were told <PERSON> Bardo </PERSON> had gotten within several blocks of the <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> home but was picked up by police when he asked for directions. <PERSON> Bardo </PERSON> was returned to his parents. <PERSON> Bardo </PERSON> was arrested in <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> last Wednesday, one day after Ms. <PERSON> Schaeffer </PERSON> was gunned down at her apartment building in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. He is jailed in lieu of $ 1 million bail, and his lawyer has said <PERSON> Bardo </PERSON> will fight extradition to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Neither <PERSON> Armijo </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON> indicated they thought <PERSON> Bardo </PERSON> was thinking of harming the young girl. <PERSON> Bardo </PERSON>'s father, <PERSON> Phillip </PERSON>, declined to comment on the Smith matter. `` We're not discussing anything with anyone,'' the elder <PERSON> Bardo </PERSON> said. `` Later on we'll release a statement, but we're kind of sorting it out ourselves right now.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 2351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BusShooting 1stLd-Writethru a0716 07-24 0564</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bus Shooting, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0716,0572</SECOND>
<HEAD>Homeless Man Charged in Bus Shootings</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 5 grafs to UPDATE with suspect charged. Picks up
4th graf, `Witnesses said...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILL LESTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police issued a murder warrant Monday for a 44-year-old drifter accused of killing two people aboard a county bus and wounding another motorist while stealing his car. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Besaraba </PERSON> was charged with two counts of murder, one count of armed robbery, one count of attempted murder, said <ORGANIZATION> Hollywood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Det </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Darron </PERSON> <PERSON> Cansiglione </PERSON>. Police circulated a photo of <PERSON> Besaraba </PERSON> among homeless men at the food program of the <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lutheran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION>. The man reportedly used the program as an address. `` The police contacted us early yesterday because they said they had this address,'' First Lutheran Pastor <PERSON> Robb </PERSON> <PERSON> Grimm </PERSON> told The <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION>. Late Monday, police announced they had signed a warrant for <PERSON> Besaraba </PERSON>, known by the nickname `` Crazy Joe'' to other homeless men at the shelter. `` He was wild and spontaneous,'' said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, who knew <PERSON> Besaraba </PERSON> from the shelter. Witnesses said the gunman had been drinking wine at the stop in front of a supermarket in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, a suburb north of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. He stepped into the door of the bus after it pulled up and opened fire at the driver and sprayed bullets through bus windows. `` The door opened. He stood up, reached under his shirt and pulled out a gun,'' said <PERSON> Devin </PERSON> <PERSON> Oppy </PERSON>, 28, a passenger in the rear of the bus. `` The driver looked at him and he shot him three times in the head. He did n't say a word. People were screaming and jumping on the floor. I kept saying, ` Get down!''' <PERSON> Sydney </PERSON> <PERSON> Granger </PERSON>, 43, a driver for the <ORGANIZATION> Broward </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION>, was killed. An immigrant from <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION> with several children, he was making his last round and had about 30 minutes left on his shift. The passenger on the bus had been identified but his name was not released by midday Monday until next of kin could be told. No special safety procedures were planned after the shooting, because it appeared to be a random incident, `` nothing that could be deemed a vendetta against bus drivers,'' said <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Volinski </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Broward </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transit </ORGANIZATION>. He said two bus drivers who knew the victim stayed out of work Monday, but most drivers had shown `` a surprisingly stable reaction.'' `` We've tried to have our own supervisors and superintendents keep a greater visibility and availability to the operators,'' he said. `` They might be at transfer locations or in their car where certain buses are scheduled to stop.'' After the initial shootings, the gunman walked through the supermarket parking lot to an intersection and banged his gun on the window of a car, witnesses said. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Yaguda </PERSON>, 31, a tourist from <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, surrendered his car and was walking away when the gunman shot him three times in the lower left leg and twice in the back, witnesses said. `` The -LRB- gunman -RRB- seemed like he did n't have a care in the world,'' said <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, 40, who ran to call police. `` He just lifted his arm and bang, bang, bang.'' She said <PERSON> Yaguda </PERSON> `` was backing away. He had no reason to shoot him.'' <PERSON> Yaguda </PERSON> was in Memorial Hospital in critical but stable condition Monday, hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Wine </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 0043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HUD-Coors     07-24 0225</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-HUD-Coors,0232</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Coors Letter Allegedly Cleared Way For Denver Project's Approval</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Coors </PERSON>, the wealthy <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> brewer and a friend of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, wrote <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> to endorse a request for more than $ 16 million in rent subsidies for <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> housing projects, according to a published report. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Monday editions that the endorsement two years ago by <ORGANIZATION> Coors </ORGANIZATION> came as the request appeared headed for rejection. The Times based the information on <ORGANIZATION> Coors </ORGANIZATION> on internal government documents. It also quoted former senior housing official <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> as saying a <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> selection committee was told that <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, then the department's secretary, wanted the <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> application given `` very careful consideration, which it was.'' The newspaper said the finding followed other revelations that during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> was more likely to approve projects endorsed by prominent Republicans, former <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> aides and friends of <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>. Documents showed the <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> proposal was originally left off a list of 1987 applications to be recommended for financing. On Aug. 12, 1987, <ORGANIZATION> Coors </ORGANIZATION> wrote <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> urging him to `` look into this matter and give it your favorable approval.'' One week after the letter was written, the selection panel met in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and approved the <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> request, the Times said documents showed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     07-24 0452</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0469</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NORCO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kayla </PERSON> <PERSON> Mull </PERSON> raises petite potbellied pigs that skateboard, squeal and sit up for their supper. One pig plays `` Swine Lake'' on the piano; a swimming pig has been known to perform the `` swine dive.'' `` They are new and marginally hip,'' said <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, a writer for Pet Care Report. `` They are friendly, relaxed, and you can housebreak them, which are the big three as far as I'm concerned.'' The little swine are selling big in <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>. `` Yes, it's a trend. If you have your BMW, you have to have a pig now,'' said an owner of two little pigs who wanted his name withheld because of zoning violations. -LRB- The mini-pigs, originally bred in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, can be raised legally only in areas zoned for livestock. -RRB- `` They make really darling pets,'' said <PERSON> Gwenna </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackmore </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Rolling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hills </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estates </ORGANIZATION>. `` They are clean, smart, and they are fun.'' `` They are easier to potty train than a dog,'' said <PERSON> Micky </PERSON>, Ms. <PERSON> Blackmore </PERSON>'s daughter, who bought a male pig when it was one month old. `` He sits on command. Of course, you have to give him a treat, which is just about anything.'' Ms. <PERSON> Mull </PERSON>, a 37-year-old microbiologist, is leading the pack of pig breeders. Prices for the pigs start at $ 1,500 each. `` Everyone who has ever owned a pet pig, even for a week or two, will tell you how much fun it was,'' she said. `` Even if it ended up as dinner in six months.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>KEY WEST, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man sporting a scruffy white beard and macho persona swaggered off with top honors in the <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Hemingway </PERSON> Look-alike Contest as this city ended a weeklong tribute to the author. The Hemingway Days Festival attracted more than 6,000 visitors to celebrate what would have been `` Papa's'' 90th birthday. The festival also included fishing and writing contests, as well the dedication of the Hemingway postage stamp. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Royston </PERSON>, a 55-year-old investor from <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, beat out 47 other entrants Sunday. `` I know right now half my English professors from college are jubilant and the other half are turning over in their graves,'' <PERSON> Royston </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Mize </PERSON>, from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, placed first among 607 entrants in the festival's short story contest. His work, entitled `` The Blooding,'' is a Midwestern folk tale of how people become hardened to life. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Shacochis </PERSON>, a writer for <PERSON> Harper </PERSON>'s magazine and one of several judges, described the adventure as `` a story as <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> as Thanksgiving dinner'' and `` crystal clear.'' <PERSON> Hemingway </PERSON> wrote classics such as `` For Whom the Bell Tolls,'' `` A Farewell to Arms, `` `` The Snows of Kilimanjaro'' and `` Green Hills of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>,'' while living in <LOCATION> Key </LOCATION> <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> in the 1930s.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 0051EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Obit-Auchincloss     07-24 0254</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Auchincloss,0262</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mother Of Jacqueline Onassis Dies At Age 81</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEWPORT, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Auchincloss </PERSON>, the mother of <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON>, died following a lengthy illness. She was 81. Mrs. <PERSON> Auchincloss </PERSON>, who died at her home in <LOCATION> Newport </LOCATION> on Saturday, was considered an accomplished horsewoman. She won the hunter championship three times at the National Horse Show at Madison Square Garden aboard the mare `` Daneuse.'' She married <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bouvier </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> on July 7, 1928. The couple's other daughter was <PERSON> Caroline </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Radziwill </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> The marriage ended in divorce in 1940. She married <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Auchincloss </PERSON>, the father of three, on June 21, 1942. The couple had two children, <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Auchincloss </PERSON> <PERSON> Rutherford </PERSON>, who died in 1985, and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Auchincloss </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Auchincloss </PERSON> died Nov. 26, 1976. Mrs. <PERSON> Auchincloss </PERSON> married <PERSON> Bingham </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> on Oct. 25, 1979. She was on the board of the <ORGANIZATION> Newport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Historical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Redwood </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Library </LOCATION>, and was honorary director of the <ORGANIZATION> Robert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> E. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Stratford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, at the time of her death. Her death occured on the same day that <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, mother of the late President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, turned 99. The exact cause of death was not known. A spokeswoman answering the telephone at <ORGANIZATION> Hammersmith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION>, the family home, refused further comment. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Tuckerman </PERSON>, a spokeswoman in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> for Mrs. <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON>, did not return a message left on her telephone answering machine. Mrs. <PERSON> Auchincloss </PERSON> is survived by her husband, three children, three step-children, 14 grandchildren and step-grandchildren and one great grandchild.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Mexico-Debt 6thLd-Writethru a0405 07-24 1009</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mexico-Debt, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0405,960</SECOND>
<HEAD>Deal Reached in Mexican Debt Talks</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: INSERTS 2 grafs after 4th graf pvs, bgng: ``However, the...''
to add statement by Mexican president; picks up 5th graf pvs, bgng: ``The
successful...''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> reached agreement with its creditor banks late Sunday on a package that is expected to make significant reductions in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s foreign debt burden, the second largest in the developing world. The agreement, which provides banks with three options to chose from in providing assistance to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, marks the first breakthrough for the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's Third World debt strategy. Officials involved in the talks estimated that the package had the potential of reducing by up to one-third the $ 4.5 billion in payments <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> must make annually to service the $ 54 billion it owes to commercial banks. However, the exact benefits of the plan will not be known for many months until the individual banks holding the loans make decisions regarding the extent to which they will participate in the debt reduction package arrived at Sunday. Mexican President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> hailed the accord in a nationwide television and radio address in that country. He said it answered `` the cry of Mexicans to return to growth'' and `` opened a breach'' for other countries with similar debt problems. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> described the negotiations as `` difficult, complex and tense.'' The successful conclusion of the negotiations came after <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Treasury Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> joined in the final stages of the marathon discussions. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, emerging after the talks ended late Sunday, said, `` You see a lot of smiles around here,'' but he refused to discuss specifics of the final agreement. However, another official, who spoke on condition that his name not be used, said the final package offers banks two ways to provide debt relief to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. They can agree to reduce the principal on the old loans by 35 percent or they can agree to reduce the interest being charged on the loans to 6.25 percent. A third option commercial banks will have is providing new loans to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Those banks willing to reduce principal or cut the interest charged will be able to get guarantees on the remaining debt from the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monetary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, the two multinational lending agencies that are backing the administration's debt strategy. In a statement, <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> called the <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> agreement `` a major step forward in the implemenation'' of the administration's debt reduction initiative. `` The agreement between <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and its creditor banks will provide significant debt and debt-service reduction for <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, as well as new money, to support <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s economic growth,'' <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> said. He said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, working with other countries, was willing to offer <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> short-term financing of up to $ 2 billion until <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> began receiving the new money agreed to in the plan. The negotiating teams for the final agreement were led by <ORGANIZATION> Mexican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Pedro </PERSON> <PERSON> Aspe </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Citicorp </ORGANIZATION> and the head of the committee representing commerical banks in the talks. Both men were smiling when they emerged from the talks, held in <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>'s office and various conference rooms on the third floor of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>. The official Mexican new agency, <ORGANIZATION> Notimex </ORGANIZATION>, said there were last-minute negotiations over a `` readjustment clause'' that would increase debt payments once the Mexican economy got moving again. But the official who discussed the talks said that both sides had agreed to tie increased debt payments to any improvements in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s export sales after the year 1996. The so-called `` readjustment clause'' has reportedly been a sticking point in the talks, with <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> maintaining that raising debt payments at a later date might block an economic recovery that the cuts are designed to foster. The fact that <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> and <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> were both participating in the talks was an indication of the high priority the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has placed on completing a deal with <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, the country which is considered the test case for the administration's new initiative to reduce debt. Last March, <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> unveiled the strategy which sought to reduce a portion of the $ 1.3 trillion debt burden being carried by Third World nations by offering various inducements to persuade commercial banks to forgive a portion of their loans. The administration had hoped to have a finished Mexican debt package to present during the seven-nation economic summit held week in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. To help move the talks along, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> held a hurriedly scheduled meeting with Mexican President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON>. While the talks between <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and its creditor banks failed to arrive at a breakthrough before the summit ended, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was successful in winning backing for the strategy in the final economic communique. The administration also announced in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was prepared to put up between $ 1 billion and $ 2 billion as an emergency `` bridge'' loan to supply money until funds start arriving from the commercial banks. `` With this accord we have achieved our goal of reducing from 6 to 2 percent -LRB- of the gross national product -RRB- our net transfers abroad,'' an anonymous source close to the talks said, according to <ORGANIZATION> Notimex </ORGANIZATION>. The $ 54 billion owed to private banks represents about half of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s $ 107 billion foreign debt, the second largest in the developing world after <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s. Reducing the crushing debt is the centerpiece of President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON>'s policy. It is seen in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> as the key to getting the nation's stagnant economy moving again. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s debt crisis began with a borrowing spree during the oil boom years of the late 1970s. When the bottom fell out of the oil market in 1982, the <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> economy went into a tailspin that has seen the average worker's buying power fall by half. The economic crisis sparked fears of political instability as unhappy Mexicans began turning against the party that has ruled for 60 uninterrupted years. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>, a Harvard-educated economist, was held to the smallest margin of victory in party history in last year's presidential elections.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-NewspaperDivorce     07-24 0221</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Newspaper Divorce,0228</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wife Takes Space In Newspaper to Tell Hubby: We Are Divorced</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Steel company boss <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, 41, sold his business four years ago and walked out on his wife and their three children to sail around the world. His wife, <PERSON> Marie </PERSON>, said she learned what he had done only by reading the local newspaper. Now, Mrs. <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> has a newspaper message for her millionaire husband: We're divorced. Mrs. <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> put an advertisement in <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> on Friday that said: `` Mrs. <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>. Should anyone know the whereabouts of my husband, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, ex-chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Cooper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> PLC. </ORGANIZATION>, would they please inform him that I divorced him today and was granted sole custody of our children. Thank you.'' But on Sunday night Mrs. <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, also 41, was quoted as telling the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION> newspaper she would remarry her husband `` if he ever gets this out of his system and comes back to us.'' The report said <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> was believed to be living on his luxury yacht off the Spanish island of <LOCATION> Majorca </LOCATION>. The Sun newspaper quoted Mrs. <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> as saying at her home near <LOCATION> Wolverhampton </LOCATION> in the English Midlands: `` I still love <PERSON> John </PERSON>. My only worry is that he might get snapped up on his travels by some smart bimbo.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 0115EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Namibia-Economy     07-24 0784</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Namibia-Economy,0814</SECOND>
<HEAD>Namibian Economy a Potential Success but Problems Loom</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP Extra</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By GREG MYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WINDHOEK, Namibia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a continent littered with economic disasters, <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> heads toward independence as a potential success if it can meet the demands of poor blacks without alienating wealthy whites and foreign investors. The desert territory has profitable mining, fishing and farming industries and one of the best infrastructures in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, much of it built with money from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. White-controlled <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> has administered <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, also known as <LOCATION> South-West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, for 74 years under a mandate from the defunct League of Nations. <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s per capita income of about $ 1,000 annually is among the highest in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. But economists say its independence could bring a sharp economic decline and they list these reasons: _ <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, which has provided up to 25 percent of <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s $ 750 million annual budget, is expected to cut virtually all aid after independence, expected early next year _ Thousands of <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s whites, concerned about the future under a black-led government, are expected to leave the country or move their assets to neighboring <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. _ Leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> South-West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Africa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, the guerrilla group expected to win pre-independence elections in November, have virtually no hands-on economic experience. They proclaim socialist policies associated with crumbling economies elsewhere in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. `` SWAPO does not conceal its belief in the moral superiority of socialism over capitalism,'' the organization said in an election manifesto. `` The state will have ownership of a significant part of the country's economic resources,'' it said. `` Egalitarianism forms the basis of -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION>'s -RRB- vision of a just social order.'' Such promises are popular among the black majority in a territory where the unemployment rate is estimated at 25 percent and few blacks own homes or businesses. Will it work? All the southern African nations that have relied heavily on state control of the economy _ <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Zambia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tanzania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION> _ have suffered economic declines or fallen short of their potential. <LOCATION> Botswana </LOCATION>, the one black-ruled country in the region to pursue a market-oriented economy, has prospered. `` <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> has raised expectations that will be difficult to meet regardless of their policies,'' said <PERSON> Rainer </PERSON> <PERSON> Ritter </PERSON>, a private economist in <LOCATION> Windhoek </LOCATION>. The organization has promised major improvements in education, health care, housing and jobs. But <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> has not said how it will finance the programs. The territory now has a budget deficit of about $ 180 million and a foreign debt of more than $ 300 million. <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> will have to try to prevent a recession in the northern towns and villages of the <LOCATION> Ovambo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> tribe </LOCATION>, where the organization draws its strongest support. An estimated 50,000 South African soldiers have left <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> since the year-long independence plan took effect April 1. Most were stationed in the north, where Namibians fought them but relied on their money. Hundreds of small general stores, known as cuca shops, are central to economic life in the north and are likely to suffer. Thousands of Namibians employed by the military in jobs ranging from soldiers to maids are now out of work. <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> has softened its hard-line socialist language in recent months in an effort to encourage whites to stay and to attract foreign investors. `` We will invite foreign investors to develop our economy,'' <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nujoma </PERSON> said recently in <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>. `` We do not think the present moment is the time for nationalizations.'' <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> also has made it clear it will accept a mixed economy and needs the skills and capital of <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s 75,000 whites, who make up 6 percent of the territory's 1.3 million people. Whites own an estimated 65 percent of private property in <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> and earn at least 10 times more than blacks on average, according to <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION>'s main opponent, the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Turnhalle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION>, says <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION>'s moderate tone will vanish if the organization comes to power. <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> remains committed to `` an outdated and demonstrably unsuccessful ideology _ that of doctrinaire socialism _ an ideology that has already destroyed the economies of most African states,'' said the alliance, a multiracial coalition that favors a market-oriented economy. The Namibian government, under South African control, already accounts for more than half the territory's $ 1.3 billion gross domestic product. Large diamond and uranium mining companies, owned by firms in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, make up the largest chunk of the private sector. Consolidated Diamond Mining of <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, owned by <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Beers </PERSON> of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, recently said <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION>'s economic views contain `` some inaccuracies and a certain lack of realism.'' But the company also said it was `` encouraged by -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION>'s -RRB- apparent willingness to negotiate'' and that willingness `` offers scope for reconciliation between government and the private sector.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 0133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TalkingTransportation Bjt   07-24 0532</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Talking Transportation, Bjt,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Wants Ideas for Better Transportation Network</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Meeting begins 10 a.m.; lead prospects uncertain</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Stuck in traffic? Tired of waiting for the bus? Fed up with rising air fares? Transportation Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> is trying to find out what Americans want to do about it. But <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON>, in starting today a series of nationwide public hearings aimed at coming up with a national transportation policy, is asking for ideas, not complaints. `` You should n't go if you're just going to say, ` We've got gridlock, somebody ought to do something about it,' because we know that,'' said <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> in an interview. `` These are needs and idea sessions.'' <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON>, who carries a regular <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Metrorail card in his wallet and drives to work on the same jammed roads as this region's other commuters, said the nation has been taking transportation for granted And he makes it clear this includes the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> is a former federal prosecutor and <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> area transit chief brought to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` We've had a policy, but there has n't been a coordinated national policy,'' he said. `` There was an absence of planning, and I happen to be a planner.'' <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> said the nation's airports, highways, bridges, waterways and mass transit system are simply wearing out. `` We're going to have to rebuild it and replace it, or we're not going to be able to rely on it anymore,'' he said. Among the most critical problems are a lack of planning for new airports, <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> said, and $ 80 billion worth of work on the country's deteriorating bridges. The <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has scheduled 33 meetings in cities ranging from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Meetings are to be moderated by department experts in various fields, with sessions focusing on different subjects according to the location. In <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> on Wednesday, for example, it's rural needs, including health care delivery, intercity buses and rail transport. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on Sept. 8, it will be drug and alcohol use in the commercial transportation system and federal research and development. The last meetings will be Sept. 11-12 in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> has asked for expert testimony at the hearings as well as comments from anyone interested in improving any aspect of highway, rail, air, or water transportation. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> has some of the most wide-ranging responsibilities in the administration. He is <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s point man in the Alaskan oil spill because his department oversees both the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> and pipelines. He's also issued key decisions affecting issues ranging from automobile mileage standards to air terrorism. The department is accepting written suggestions until Sept. 1. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> said he hopes to have a new set of transportation policies in place before the end of his first year in the Cabinet. What will it all amount to when the policy is set? <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> sees ambitious results affecting every American: `` Maybe it will eliminate gridlock. Maybe it will make it easier for you to get to work. Maybe it will hold down air fares. Maybe it will make you more productive in your job by making it easier to get to various places in the country.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 0134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BushBouncesBack Bjt   07-24 0881</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush Bounces Back, Bjt,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Bush a `Late Bloomer'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, rebounding from negative reviews early in his presidency, is now winning good marks after two successful trips to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and a general sense of economic well-being at home. The president is `` a late bloomer,'' says one analyst. At the 100-day point, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was criticized as being too cautious, unimaginative and unwilling to compete with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. After six months in office, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> basks in praise for winning support at a <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> summit for a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> plan to reduce conventional arms in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, and for traveling to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> to encourage democratic reforms. `` He's actually done well after a halting beginning,'' said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronin </PERSON>, a presidential scholar at <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Cronin </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was `` aided enormously by the fact that the Democrats in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> were in disarray'' as House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Whip <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> struggled with ethical problems and then resigned. `` There was no challenge to his leadership.'' After losing a battle with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for confirmation of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> as secretary of <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> came back with a decisive victory on his veto of a $ 1.20 increase in the minimum wage. `` He's obviously in a lot better shape than he was at 100 days,'' said <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hess </PERSON>, a presidential scholar at the <ORGANIZATION> Brookings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>. `` He's had two awfully good trips abroad and when a president travels abroad, he gets an awful lot of attention.'' <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Sabato </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> political scientist who called <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a late bloomer, said, `` It's as though there's a second honeymoon at the six-month point. `` It's tied to real successes, particularly in the foreign sphere, and things are going reasonably well abroad and at home,'' <PERSON> Sabato </PERSON> said. `` The economy may be slow but it's not in recession. There's no war or threat of it, and things appear to be going in our direction.'' <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Ornstein </PERSON>, a political analyst at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s foreign travels `` tilt the balance away from the notion that the guy who was making things happen was <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was asleep at the switch. `` It erases the notion of a passive president who's doing nothing,'' <PERSON> Ornstein </PERSON> said. At the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s chief of staff, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON>, said, `` It's nice to see the beginning of a response that everybody hoped there would be.'' Polls show <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has a positive rating of 66 to 73 percent, which puts him ahead of <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> at this point in his presidency. <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohut </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Gallup </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opinion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s approval rating was slipping in April and May but then began to turn around `` Between May and July, he's been dealing with international problems and the country tends to rally around a president who's dealing with rather clear-cut international issues,'' said <PERSON> Kohut </PERSON> On the other hand, <PERSON> Kohut </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is `` still an enigmatic character to many people. That's where he's weak.'' He said the category of people classified as `` do n't know'' or `` no opinion'' about <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is higher than with other presidents, running at about 26 percent. Countering that criticism, <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> said `` vision does n't fit on a bumper sticker.'' He said the president is defining his agenda with specific proposals to balance the budget, bail out the savings and loan industry, clean up air pollution and combat crime. <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has demonstrated `` a willingness to do his homework, to spend the time examining the details, then to make a decision not in haste.'' Asked what <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> should have done differently, <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> replied, `` Honest, in terms of the big issues and timetable and the agenda and the approach, not a heck of a lot.'' <PERSON> Ornstein </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> should be more aggressive, establish a long-term agenda and take some risks. Beyond that, he said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was losing `` an awful lot of direction and momentum'' by the fact that hundreds of top-level appointments have not been made. `` He could plummet the next six months if we slipped into a recession,'' cautioned <PERSON> Sabato </PERSON>. `` There's a little too much basking in the glow of a 70 percent approval rating, not capitalizing on it,'' <PERSON> Ornstein </PERSON> said. `` If you're up around 70 percent early on, it's a good time to let it drop down to 60 percent by pushing some things through that may be a little controversial.'' There is widespread agreement that much of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s popularity is due to his personal style, his high energy level and obvious relish for the job. `` I think we've grown used to him, like an old, comfortable shoe,'' said <PERSON> Hess </PERSON>. `` Some of the rough edges from the campaign have rubbed off. He has n't forced himself on us.'' <PERSON> Ornstein </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` is not the kind of guy who's going to fall asleep with the pope'' _ alluding to an occasion where <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> nodded off while meeting with <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> said, `` I think people right off the bat perceived a different style'' from the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> days. `` They have really begun to feel comfortable and appreciative of the style. I think that is very important for a president to do _ to give his mark to the office that he probably will be occupying for eight years.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 0134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BatCave Bjt   07-24 0563</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bat Cave, Bjt,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Holy Batroots! Are Bats Related to Humans?</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Holy Batroots! Is it really true, as some scientists suggest, that human beings and bats might be distant cousins who share the same primeval ancestors? Is there a Batman or Count Dracula lurking in each of us? In the heat of this summer's batmania, with <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> moviegoers breaking box-office records to see `` Batman,'' anything seems possible. The National Zoo's bat expert, Dr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Seidensticker </PERSON>, says it's an intriguing theory, one you could sink your teeth into, but he's not sure he believes Other scientists at the <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION> scoff at the idea. <PERSON> Seidensticker </PERSON> says brain studies have yielded evidence that certain kinds of large bats found in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> may be descendants of prehistoric primates akin to lemurs or mouselike shrews. `` The theory is that these bats are really flying primates,'' he says, and connected somehow in the evolutionary chain to the early primate ancestors of monkeys, apes, gorillas _ and humans. But Dr. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Handley </PERSON>, a leading authority on bats and other mammals at the <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> History </ORGANIZATION>, says this theory is a `` hot potato'' of scientific controversy that has won few adherents. `` We do n't know what the ancestors of bats really were,'' <PERSON> Handley </PERSON> said. The 160 fluttering bats in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zoo </ORGANIZATION>'s new Bat Cave are n't talking. In fact, they do n't display the slightest familial interest in their supposed two-legged cousins who stare intently through a glass wall into their dimly lighted hideaway of damp rocks and hollow tree trunks. One recent visitor was Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> and his children, who attended the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> premiere of `` Batman'' at a nearby movie theater and then joined a post-screening party for 1,200 guests in a tent outside the Bat Cave. <PERSON> Seidensticker </PERSON>, the zoo's associate curator of mammals, illuminated the cave for <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> with a flashlight. He said the vice president was `` very interested'' in the bats and lingered for seven minutes, much longer than the average tourist. <PERSON> Seidensticker </PERSON> said bats `` are not mice with wings, they are bats,'' and people should n't be afraid of them. `` They actually are nice, fun, incredible animals,'' he says. `` They're great little guys.'' Keeper <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Prima </PERSON>, who wears a Batman baseball cap, says the bats have never bothered her. `` They're not aggressive,'' she said. `` If anything, they're just curious.'' They hover watchfully while she scrubs the cave walls or delivers their meals. The bats, three species of fruit eaters, consume 30 pounds of grapes, melons, bananas and a gruel of peach nectar and vitamins every day. The rest of the time they fly back and forth, socialize in their `` harems'' and just hang out. Or, more precisely, hang down. They also have active sex lives. `` They're continuously producing babies,'' <PERSON> Seidensticker </PERSON> says. Ms. <PERSON> Prima </PERSON> says she's never felt threatened working in the Bat Cave. `` They never touch me, and they've never flown into my hair,'' she said. `` They keep their distance. They know you're there, but they are n't interested in coming near you. They are n't accepting you as a bat.'' `` There's no need to fear these little guys,'' she says, although some visitors have been seen anxiously sprinting past the Bat Cave without a glance. The public's most frequently asked question, says <PERSON> Seidensticker </PERSON>, is `` Where's the Batmobile?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 0135EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CongressRdp     07-24 0709</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress Rdp,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Races Toward Summer Vacation</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Action on Capitol Hill reaches a frenzied level this week as lawmakers seek to pass a flurry of money bills, grapple with how much to spend on the stealth bomber and clear other legislative tangles before going on summer vacation. Leading the agenda in both the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is legislation laying out <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spending priorities for the coming year. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will be lobbying House members against an effort to either freeze production of the B-2 bomber, known as the stealth because of its radar-eluding capabilities, or cut the number to be built from eight per year to two. Meanwhile, a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee is pushing ahead with its investigation of the scandal at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>. The House Government Operations housing subcommittee summoned <PERSON> Lynda </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, a former career <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> employee, to testify today about dealings with her friend, <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>, a former top <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> official. The administration contends that the stealth bomber, built to penetrate Soviet airspace, is a key to future <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nuclear deterrence. But members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> wrestling with serious deficit problems are shocked at its cost _ more than half a billion dollars each. Also to be fought is the perennial debate over how much to devote to the administration's `` Star Wars'' Strategic Defense Initiative and how much money to give to rail-mobile MX missiles versus the single-warhead Midgetman. At the same time, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> is seeking to complete work on the 13 basic spending bills needed to run the government in the next fiscal year, which begins Oct. 1. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> also is pushing ahead on legislation from child care to clean air and budget cuts. Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> was executive assistant to former <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, but numerous witnesses have described her as almost a surrogate Cabinet member who was heavily involved in funneling department money to well-placed Republicans. `` Miss <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> has chosen to take the Fifth Amendment, and we very much hope that she will change her mind,'' said subcommittee chairman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, D-Calif. `` But we will need to get at her role, if she's unprepared to testify, through individuals who had close contact with her. On Tuesday, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> plans to hold a drafting session to deal with responses to last month's <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s decision that burning the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> flag is a protected form of political expression. The panel's subcommittee on constitutional rights completed hearings last week on the issue. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is divided over whether to seek a constitutional amendment banning flag desecration or to address the matter through a simple change in the law. After working behind closed doors most of last week, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiators on a $ 166 bailout plan for the savings and loan industry will meet Tuesday with hopes of nailing down a final package. The major remaining disagreement is how to raise the $ 50 billion needed immediately to cover the loss of federally insured deposits in some 500 S & amp; Ls at or near insolvency because of poor and often fraudulent lending. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> want to raise the money through 30-year private bonds in order to prevent the bailout from swelling the federal deficit. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and Democrats would borrow the money directly through the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>, but exempt the amount from annual deficit reduction targets. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> could vote as early as Thursday on the nomination of <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> to be <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s assistant attorney general for civil rights at the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The black former sheriff of <LOCATION> Wayne </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, is opposed by many civil rights groups for lack of experience, but <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> contends he will be a tough enforcer of anti-discrimination laws. And the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> continues work on a tax bill, with members apparently divided almost down the middle on a proposal favored by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to reduce taxes on capital gains. The panel also will try to find a way to change the surtax that finances the catastrophic health insurance program for older Americans. Higher income retirees who pay most of the cost of the program have been lobbying the committee to spread the cost among all taxpayers, not just older citizens.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-VDTs-Health     07-24 0604</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-VDTs-Health,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Targets Video Display Terminal Users</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARTON REPPERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new federally funded study on 8,000 women office workers aims to resolve persistent questions over whether video display terminals can harm the health of people who use them. Rep. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, whose House Government Operations subcommittee has held hearings on VDTs, said the two-year, $ 2 million study by <ORGANIZATION> Mount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sinai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> is long overdue. <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> said he had urged the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> for several years to fund research `` that could determine whether VDTs cause serious harm, especially for pregnant women who use them.'' `` They have been terribly slow to respond, partly due to encouragement by several large corporations to avoid this kind of research,'' he said. `` Meanwhile, the potential harm has increased dramatically as the number of VDT users has multiplied.'' <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> calls the <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sinai </LOCATION> epidemiological study _ being funded by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Child </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, a unit of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> _ `` an important first step'' toward resolving the health issue. The study comes in the wake of a report issued last month by the congressional <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assessment </ORGANIZATION>, saying more research is needed to explore the potential health risks of power frequency electromagnetic fields _ particularly their effects on the nervous system and possible role in promoting cancer. The <ORGANIZATION> OTA </ORGANIZATION> report said that while most public concern has focused on high-voltage transmission lines, more attention should be paid to exposure to such fields from other sources such as household and office wiring, appliances and other electrical equipment, including VDTs. `` It is now clear that 60 Hz -LRB- cycles per second -RRB- and other low frequency electromagnetic fields can interact with individual cells and organs to produce biological changes,'' it said. `` The nature of these interactions is subtle and complex. The implications of these interactions for public health remain unclear, but there are legitimate reasons for concern.'' <PERSON> Michele </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcus </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sinai </LOCATION> study's principal investigator, said it will be conducted in four cities _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> and an as yet undetermined city in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Both union and non-union workplaces will be included. Dr. <PERSON> Marcus </PERSON> said a major difference between the <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sinai </LOCATION> project and previous epidemiological studies in this country is that in addition to gathering health-history data through questionnaires, `` we are going to be looking at reproductive effects prospectively. That is, we're going to be following women forward in time.'' `` We'll be identifying their exposure or their use of video display terminals, and then seeing whether or not they get pregnant and following the course of the pregnancy,'' she said. Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, D-Tenn., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on science, technology and space, said `` there are still many unanswered questions about the potential health effects of VDTs and of electromagnetic fields generally, but there is no longer any doubt that this form of radiation can cause some biochemical changes. `` The decision by <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> to support <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sinai </LOCATION>'s study is an important step, but more is needed,'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said. `` Government must expand its research program and do more to ensure that private industry is preparing solutions should the evidence warrant it.'' Also welcoming the study was Rep. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaydos </PERSON>, D-Pa., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on health and safety, which plans to hold further hearings on the VDT issue early next year `` I am concerned about the health hazards faced by office workers, especially those who use video display terminals for long periods of time during the working day,'' <PERSON> Gaydos </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 0147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AbortionPoll Bjt   07-24 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion Poll, Bjt,0667</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poll Finds Opposition to Anti-Abortion Candidates</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Americans by nearly a 2-1 margin are inclined to oppose anti-abortion candidates for their state legislatures and to support legal abortion in their states, a national poll has found. As lawmakers across the country prepare to take up new abortion laws, 38 percent of respondents to the <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General-Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> poll said they would be less likely to vote for a candidate who firmly opposes abortion. The same number said abortion would n't matter much in their vote, while the smallest group _ about two in 10 _ said they would be more apt to vote for a candidate who took a strong anti-abortion position. Moreover, 63 percent of the 1,163 adults polled said they would want abortion to be legal in their state if the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> reversed its 1973 ruling that made abortion a constitutional right and let each state make its own abortion laws. That support for legal abortion was up slightly from 57 percent in an MG-AP poll in March. Similarly, support for the 1973 ruling in the <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> case was up to 59 percent, from 53 percent. While those increases were within the poll's margin of error, similar movement in several questions indicated a slight rise in pro-choice opinion since the high court decision July 3 that permitted states to increase restrictions on abortion. The new survey, conducted July 7-16, had a margin of error of plus or minus three percentage points. While most respondents expressed general support for legal abortion, they were split on specific restrictions permitted in the recent <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling. Among those findings: _ Sixty-five percent said abortions at public hospitals should be legal, but that fell to 51 percent when respondents were asked specifically about abortions that are not required to save the mother's life The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> said states can ban such abortions from public hospitals. _ Respondents split about evenly on whether it should be legal for public health employees to perform or assist in abortions The court said that, too, can be barred by the states when the mother's life is not at risk _ Respondents strongly supported mandatory pre-abortion tests to see if fetuses that are at least 20 weeks old can survive outside the womb, with 62 percent in favor The high court said such tests can be required. _ By 54-38 percent, with 8 percent undecided, respondents said it should be legal to use public funds to counsel women about the availability of abortion The court left that issue undecided. Overall, 48 percent said they opposed the July 3 ruling, 43 percent favored it and 9 percent were unsure. That was a split in opinion given the margin of error. As in previous polls, general questions on abortion produced divided views, reflecting public discomfort with an issue that pits the rights of pregnant women with concern for their fetuses. Sixty-seven percent said a woman should be allowed to have an abortion if she wants one and her doctor agrees to it; 25 percent said not, and 8 percent were undecided. On the other hand, 42 percent said they would support a constitutional amendment to ban most abortions. Fifty-three percent opposed such an amendment and the rest were undecided. Younger, more educated and wealthier people were more apt to support legal abortion, as were residents of the <LOCATION> Northeast </LOCATION> and the West and big-city dwellers. People who called themselves conservatives were far more likely to oppose abortion: Just 42 percent of conservatives supported the 1973 ruling, compared with 66 percent of moderates and 80 percent of liberals. <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a communications company based in <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, publishes the Richmond Times-Dispatch, The Richmond News Leader, the <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Winston-Salem </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal, and operates TV stations <ORGANIZATION> WXFL </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, WCBD in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> WJKS </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 0147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AbortionPoll-Method     07-24 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion Poll-Method,0655</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poll on Abortion Reached 1,163 Nationwide</HEAD>
<UNK>With PM-Abortion Poll, Bjt</UNK>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General-Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> poll is based on telephone interviews July 7-16 with 1,163 adults in the continental <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Phone numbers were selected randomly and interviews were conducted with the adult who had the most recent birthday, a random phenomenon. The results were weighted to adjust for variations in the sample. The poll has a three-point margin of error, meaning that 19 of 20 times its findings should be within 3 points of the result if every adult American were asked the same questions. The error margin is larger for subgroups; it is five points for people who called themselves conservatives, for example. There are other sources of potential error in polls, including the wording and order of questions. These are the questions in this poll; because of rounding, sums may not total 100: 1. If a woman wants to have an abortion and her doctor agrees to it, should she be allowed to have an abortion, or not? Yes: 67 percent. No: 25 percent. Do n't know or no answer: 8 percent. 2. Would you vote for or against a candidate just on the basis of that candidate's position on the abortion issue? Yes: 32. No: 61. DK-NA: 7. 3. If a candidate for your state legislature is firmly opposed to abortion, would that make you more likely to vote for that candidate, or less likely, or would n't it matter much? More: 21. Less: 38. Would n't matter: 38. DK-NA: 3. 4a. Should it be legal or illegal for abortions to be done at public hospitals? Legal: 65. Illegal: 26. DK-NA: 9. b -LRB- If legal -RRB- Does that include abortions that are not necessary to save the mother's life? Yes: 78. No: 18. DK-NA: 4. 5a. Should it be legal or illegal or public health employees to perform or assist in abortions? Legal: 44. Illegal: 43. DK-NA: 13. b -LRB- If legal -RRB- Does that include abortions that are not necessary to save the mother's life? Yes: 90. No: 9. DK-NA: 2. 6. Should it be legal or illegal to use public funds to counsel women about the availability of abortion? Legal: 54. Illegal: 38. DK-NA: 8. 7. If a woman who is at least 20 weeks pregnant wants an abortion, should the doctor first be required to determine whether the fetus can survive outside the womb, or not? Yes: 62. No: 21. DK-NA: 17. 8a. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> this month gave the states more power to restrict abortions. Do you favor or oppose that ruling? Favor: 43. Oppose 48. DK-NA: 9. b -LRB- If oppose -RRB- Is that because you wanted the court to do more to restrict abortions, or because you think the court did too much to restrict abortions? Wanted more: 8. Too much: 86. DK-NA: 7. 9. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled in 1973 that a woman can have an abortion if she wants one at any time during the first three months of pregnancy. Do you favor or oppose that ruling? Favor: 59. Oppose: 36. DK-NA: 5. 10. If the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> reversed its 1973 ruling and let each state make its own abortion laws, abortion could become legal in some states and illegal in others. Would you want abortion to be legal or illegal in your state? Legal: 63. Illegal: 31. DK-NA: 7. 11. If abortion was illegal in your state, do you think that would stop most women there who want abortions from having them, or would most of them go to another state where it was legal? Stop: 7. Go: 87. DK-NA: 6. 12. Would you favor or oppose a constitutional amendment that would make abortions illegal nationwide, except in cases of rape, incest or to save the life of the mother? Favor: 42. Oppose: 53. DK-NA: 6.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 0153EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PsychiatristVideos Bjt   07-24 0539</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Psychiatrist Videos, Bjt,0556</SECOND>
<HEAD>Psychiatrist Puts Expertise Into Videos</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RAY FORMANEK Jr.</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MORGANTOWN, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When it comes to teaching medical students about mental illness, <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Fidler </PERSON> does n't go by the book. He makes movies. `` A lot of the videotapes I make are designed to make people feel like they really are in the patient's shoes,'' said <PERSON> Fidler </PERSON>, an adolescent psychiatrist at <ORGANIZATION> Chestnut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> and an associate professor of psychiatry at <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` Like, what does it feel like to be psychotic. The audience gets confused. They really begin to take on some of the feelings that are being portrayed.'' <PERSON> Fidler </PERSON>, 40, has produced more than 100 features since he began using videotapes as a teaching tool a decade ago while at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Chapel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. About half are for sale to medical schools throughout the country. The videos range from 8 minutes to two hours in length and cost from $ 50 to $ 1,200. A year and a half ago, <PERSON> Fidler </PERSON> began working on a new educational series called `` Medicine Playhouse'' at <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. Each episode presents an emotional, medical or philosophical problem typically faced by health professionals. A question-and-answer session with an expert in the field is held after each show. `` It's sort of a <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wobegone </LOCATION> approach to medical education,'' <PERSON> Fidler </PERSON> said, referring to the mythical place made famous by humorist <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON> <PERSON> Keillor </PERSON> on his radio show, `` A Prairie Home Companion.'' Students say the videos are a good learning tool. `` It's much more helpful for a medical student to observe a patient,'' said <PERSON> Kellie </PERSON> <PERSON> Gooding </PERSON>, 24, a third-year student at the medical school. `` It stays in your mind much longer if you can actually see a schizophrenic or whatever, rather than just reading about it. You might just remember something a couple of days if you read it. If you see it on the screen, you might remember it for the rest of your life.'' `` The videos show a really comprehensive picture,'' said <PERSON> Sloane </PERSON> <PERSON> Blair </PERSON>, 23, also a third-year student. `` It shows you as it is _ real people in real life. In a book, they would break a subject down into one component and then another.'' Some of the videotapes, <PERSON> Fidler </PERSON> said, make medical students squirm. In one video, shot in black-and-white and titled simply, `` Depression,'' a loud clock ticks in the background as cameras close in from different angles on the troubled face of an actor. `` It's just 15 minutes long but it seems like it runs for an eternity,'' <PERSON> Fidler </PERSON> said. `` I've had people actually come up and tell me they feel suicidal after watching it, even though the word is never mentioned.'' In another, called `` Paranoia,'' a man grows more and more anxious as passengers riding on a city bus turn around in their seats and begin staring at him. He admits his videos may not be right for everyone. `` About 10 or 15 percent of the students do n't learn well using the videotapes,'' <PERSON> Fidler </PERSON> said. `` They'd be better off with books or a lecture. Some people just are n't good visual learners. `` But that's OK. I do n't think many lectures in medical school reach 85 percent of the students,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 0155EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     07-24 0720</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Considers Duty on Imports of Canadian Pork</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A prospective <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> levy on imports of unprocessed fresh, chilled and frozen pork from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> could add further to a growing number of live hogs coming across the border, according to an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> analysis. Last week the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> ruled in a `` final determination'' that <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s pork is being subsidized. The ruling now goes to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, which has 45 days to decide whether the imports are hurting American hog farmers. If the commission agrees with the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> ruling, the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> will be ordered to collect countervailing duties on imports of Canadian pork to offset the benefits of the subsidies. The Commerce investigation did not include processed or preserved pork products such as canned hams, bacon, sausage or ground pork. Countervailing duties have been levied on imports of live hogs from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> the past four years. Overall, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is the world's largest pork importer, with about 1.14 billion pounds, carcass weight equivalent, imported last year, approximately 7 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> consumption, according to the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> supplied almost 45 percent of the 1988 pork imports; <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>, 29 percent; and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, 11 percent. The remainder comes mainly from other Eastern European countries. Pork imports during the first four months of this year totaled about 333 million pounds, down 17 percent from January-April 1988, the report said. Imports from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> were `` substantially below'' the year-earlier level, while shipments from <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> were up slightly. `` Canadian hog and pork prices remain below last year, which has encouraged domestic consumption and diverted some supply from the export market,'' the report said. `` Despite near-record year-ago hog slaughter, Canadian statistics indicate that total exports of pork through the end of May were about 8 percent below 1988 levels.'' Earlier this year there was a wide spread between western Canadian hog prices and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> prices, the report said. That provided a strong incentive for western Canadian producers to ship live hogs to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> market. The spread narrowed in April, and imports of live hogs from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> declined to less than half of their March level _ but still were 18 percent more than a year earlier. Hog imports from all sources for the January-April period totaled 475,845 head, the report said. That was 125 percent above the same period in 1988. Canadian production this year is expected to be down about 2 percent from 1988 because of herd liquidations prompted by lower hog prices. `` The addition of a countervailing duty deposit on fresh, chilled and frozen pork imports from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> is expected to reinforce the existing shift towards imports of Canadian hogs,'' the report said. <PERSON> Shayle </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shagam </PERSON>, an economist in the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> agency, said in another report that the world pork trade is small relative to total production and that a handful of countries are involved. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is the largest pork producer, accounting for almost a third of the world's total last year, but the country's huge population requires most of the production, <PERSON> Shagam </PERSON> said. Last year <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> was the fourth largest pork exporter, with live hogs and pork going to <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, and frozen pork to <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. On an individual country basis, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is the second largest pork producer but ranks fourth when the 12-nation <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> are included. As well as being the leading pork importer, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is sixth in the world as an exporter. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is the biggest market for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pork. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> is another large buyer. <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> ranks seventh in the world as a pork producer, turning out much more than it requires domestically, <PERSON> Shagam </PERSON> said. Exports currently are about 22 percent of <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s production. Almost 90 percent goes to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and 9 percent to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> was third as an exporter last year. `` As a result of large domestic pork supplies, imports by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will remain fairly steady, with <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> increasing its relative share of the market,'' <PERSON> Shagam </PERSON> said. But <PERSON> Shagam </PERSON> added that the mix between hogs and pork from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> will depend on relative wage rates in the meatpacking industry and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> countervailing duties on imports from there.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890724-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-89 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CampusTrends     07-24 0717</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Campus Trends,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Colleges say Minority Recruiting Results Fall Short</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
