<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 0148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TankerSpill 3rdLd-Writethru a0593 04-02 1276</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tanker Spill, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0593,1309</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Shifting Oil Causing Headaches; Skipped Charged</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 3 grafs after 1st to UPDATE with newspaper report of
captain admitting drinking before and after boarding vessel, picks up 3rd
graf pvs, `The bulk...'; INSERTS 6 grafs after 12th pvs, `Police in ...'
to ADD background from prosecutor, picks up 13th graf pvs, `FBI officials
...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserColor VDX5</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HAL SPENCER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VALDEZ, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities issued an arrest warrant for the tanker captain suspected of drinking before his ship ran aground, causing a 1,000-square-mile oil slick that expanded Saturday under shifting wind and currents. A prosecutor said the captain admitted drinking on board the tanker before it went aground, according to court papers obtained by The Oregonian of <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION> newspaper. One of the first investigators to board the Exxon Valdez asked <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> what the problem was, and the captain replied, `` I think you're looking at it,'' the newspaper reported in its Sunday editions. Meanwhile, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s governor threatened to close the Trans-Alaska Pipeline if the oil industry fails to protect against future spills. The bulk of the 10.1-million-gallon slick began moving toward <PERSON> Cordova </PERSON> about 50 miles southeast of here, threatening the home waters of fishermen who have struggled to save endangered fish hatcheries. About 800 miles of beach have been tainted so far in the biggest oil spill in the nation's history, officials said. Gov. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowper </PERSON> said the state will require `` absolute proof that equipment is in place'' to combat future oil spills. `` If it's not done, we're authorized to close the pipeline,'' he said Some 85 percent of the state's $ 2 billion budget comes from the pipeline, and although the state has a $ 10 billion savings account, oil production on <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s North slope accounts for 25 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production. <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> Attorney General <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Baily </PERSON> said Saturday that criminal charges were filed late Friday against <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>, 42, captain of the tanker that crashed into <LOCATION> Bligh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reef </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Prince </LOCATION> <LOCATION> William </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sound </LOCATION> on March 24. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> fired <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> on Thursday, the same day the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> revealed blood and urine tests taken about nine hours after the accident showed he had been under the influence of alcohol. Charges filed in <ORGANIZATION> Valdez </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> accuse <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> of operating a motorcraft while under the influence of alcohol, reckless endangerment and the negligent discharge of oil, all misdemeanors. The three offenses carry combined maximum sentences of two years and three months in prison, and fines totaling up to $ 10,000. District Attorney <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Weeks </PERSON> said if convicted, <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> would have to spend at least 30 days in jail because he has two prior drunken driving convictions in the past five years. Valdez Magistrate <PERSON> Tracee </PERSON> <PERSON> Schnell </PERSON> signed the arrest warrant for <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>, and set bond at $ 50,000. Authorities believe he left the state several days ago, but <PERSON> Baily </PERSON> said the state would seek his extradition. Police in <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>'s hometown of <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, said Saturday they did not know his whereabouts. The Oregonian said two crewmen told authorities they saw <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> drinking in <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION> before the ship left port. A statement filed by <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Linton </PERSON>, an assistant district attorney in <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION>, said one crewman saw <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> consume four alcoholic drinks while still in port. <PERSON> Linton </PERSON>'s affidavit said two other unidentified witnesses said they smelled alcohol on <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>'s breath when the captain was on the bridge, the newspaper reported. `` One witness said that <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> appeared to be under the influence of intoxicating beverages and that his balance was not good,'' <PERSON> Linton </PERSON> said in the affidavit. However, all crewmen interviewed by <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> state troopers have said <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> `` did not appear to be intoxicated,'' <PERSON> Linton </PERSON> wrote. <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> apparently told investigators he drank one beer before leaving port and a couple of bottles of `` moussy,'' a beverage containing 0.5 percent alcohol, after he returned to the ship, <PERSON> Linton </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> officials in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> say they're investigating possible felony violations of the Clean Water Act, which prohibits the `` negligent discharge of a pollutant into navigable waters.'' Exxon is liable for millions of dollars in fines under state law if it is proven to be negligent in causing the spill and cleaning it up. Shifting wind drove the main body of the slick east toward <LOCATION> Hinchenbrook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, which forms the primary boundary between the sound and the Gulf of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. The movement of the oil toward the rich fishing grounds at the mouth of the <LOCATION> Copper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> stirred fear in <LOCATION> Cordova </LOCATION>, which lies on the east side of the sound. Some <PERSON> Cordova </PERSON> fishermen, who had mounted a bold effort to protect the hatcheries on the west side, headed back toward their home port to battle the oil there. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Dietrick </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> praised the <PERSON> Cordova </PERSON> fishermen as the `` backbone'' of the cleanup and containment effort so far. Leaders in the fishing and tourist town of <LOCATION> Seward </LOCATION>, the first community downstream from Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> to the west, also went on the offensive, deploying 10,000 feet of boom the town ordered from a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> manufacturer to protect salmon river habitats. `` We're not going to let it happen,'' said <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Gieseler </PERSON>, mayor of the town 125 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION>. `` We're taking our own initiative.'' At the Kenai Fjords National Park, near <LOCATION> Seward </LOCATION>, a team was sent out to survey wildlife and evaluate the state of the park before oil reaches the rocky shores, spokeswoman Dixie Dies said. The park will count on the city of <LOCATION> Seward </LOCATION> for boom and other protective measures, she said. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> rejected a plea from oil producers to ease restrictions placed on tanker traffic into <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> following the spill. The <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Richfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> said tanker movement from the marine terminal of the trans-Alaska oil pipeline needs to be stepped up to ensure adequate supplies on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>. On Friday, wholesale gasoline prices surged as commodities traders speculated that the squeeze in oil supplies caused by the disastrous spill wo n't ease soon. Gas prices at the pump jumped by as much as 10 cents a gallon in parts of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Normally three to four loaded tankers leave <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION> daily. Since the spill, only five have made it out. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> has ordered tugboat escorts until the tankers pass the grounded <PERSON> Exxon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON>. Local harbor pilots are required to accompany the tankers for longer distances than usual. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said the restrictions would not be lifted until the <PERSON> Exxon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> is refloated and moved to a safe anchorage, possibly next week. Workers continued Saturday to pump oil from the crippled tanker onto the Exxon <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. Biologists walking beaches have counted 520 oiled birds representing 20 species, fish and game officials said. Ten sea otters and 27 oiled birds were taken to <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION> for cleaning, and federal bird experts said more than 1,000 tainted birds _ some alive, some dead _ had been spotted on a single island. They expected the number to increase dramatically. Wildlife experts also were considering the possibility of sending some sea otters to other states for care and rehabilitation. Biologists say they expect to be inundated by otters, the marine mammal most vulnerable to oil contamination because of the loss of insulation and buoyancy of their fur. A sablefish harvest set to open today was canceled because of the spill. Officials previously halted the shrimp harvest, which was open for about two weeks before the spill and was to have run until mid-April. Meanwhile, another in a series of class-action lawsuits was filed Friday. A class-action complaint by <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Belli </PERSON>, on behalf of area fishermen, asked for $ 2 billion, half of it in punitive damages.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 0214EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Namibia 4thLd-Writethru a0580 04-02 0889</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Namibia, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0580,0915</SECOND>
<HEAD>South Africa Threatens To Remove U.N. Force After Guerrilla Attack</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: LEADS with 16 grafs to UPDATE with revised casualty toll in
fighting; U.N. team sent to investigate; pickup graf 15 pvs `Fewer than...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURINDA KEYS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WINDHOEK, Namibia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> reported major clashes with guerrillas hours before <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> began its transition to independence Saturday and said it may ask the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> force monitoring the process to leave. Government-run radio said early Sunday that 36 guerrillas were killed and two captured in fighting Friday night with <LOCATION> South-West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> African </LOCATION> police, who suffered two deaths and nine injuries. The figures, attributed to a spokesman for territorial Administrator-General <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Pienaar </PERSON>, slightly revised those given Saturday by South African officials. Foreign Minister <PERSON> Pik </PERSON> <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> said Saturday that 38 guerrillas and two territorial policemen were killed when guerrillas of the <ORGANIZATION> South-West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION>, infiltrated from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> on Friday evening. `` This is a most serious development,'' said <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>. The reported attack came hours before a formal cease-fire took effect and a 20-nation <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeeping force began overseeing the end of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s 74-year rule over <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. Police blocked thousands of <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> supporters who tried to march in the capital to celebrate the transition. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> accused the rebels of a flagrant violation of a pledge to halt hostilities and said he had complained to <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON>. Unless there is a satisfactory response from the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> said, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> would feel compelled to ask the peacekeeping force to leave `` until <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> can be brought to its senses.'' In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Nadia </PERSON> <PERSON> Younes </PERSON> released a statement from <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> saying: `` The secretary-general is greatly concerned that such incidents have been reported. He has told Mr. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> that UNTAG -LRB- the U.N. Transition Assistance Group -RRB- is immediately sending a team to investigate the reports.'' <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Special Representative <PERSON> Martti </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahtisaari </PERSON> sent four senior <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> military, civilian, and police personnel to northern <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> to investigate the South African report. He was expected to make his report by Sunday evening. An official of <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION>, which has waged a war for independence since 1966, said the organization would need a day or so to determine what had happened but added that <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> `` has gone out of its way to avoid conflict.'' According to <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> indicated he might agree that <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> could reactivate its troops to guard against <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> operations. But the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman said the secretary-geeneral would have no comment on <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>'s remarks. Later at a news conference, <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> said <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> African </LOCATION> troops will be allowed to leave their bases to search for the guerrillas involved in the fighting if police ca n't control the situation. South African and <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> forces were confined to their bases as of Saturday under the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> plan but <PERSON> Pienaar </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> units had not complied. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> interrupted his airport news conference to take a call from <PERSON> Pienaar </PERSON>. He then said that <PERSON> Pienaar </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ahtisaari </PERSON> and Gen. <PERSON> Prem </PERSON> <PERSON> Chand </PERSON>, the UNTAG commander, said certain South African units would be released from their bases to provide support to the police and the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> group would monitor the South African movement. Fewer than 800 of the 4,500 military personnel assigned to the UNTAG have arrived in <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. There had been no fighting since September between South African and <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> forces, which were supposed to be restricted to their bases as of midnight Friday under U.N. Resolution 435. The resolution establishes a process for elections in November leading to independence early next year for <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s last territory. British Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, completing an African tour, flew into <LOCATION> Windhoek </LOCATION> to meet with <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> officials and British members of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> monitoring force. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said a special session of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> should be called to consider the alleged SWAPO incursion. `` This a most serious challenge to the authority of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> and the agreement, and we condemn it totally,'' she said. There was a tense 30-minute standoff outside the capital when about 100 policemen confronted up to 20,000 <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> supporters marching to <LOCATION> Windhoek </LOCATION> from the black township of <LOCATION> Katatura </LOCATION>, seeking to celebrate the start of the independence process. Church leaders persuaded the marchers to return to <LOCATION> Katatura </LOCATION>, where celebration rallies by rival political factions were held during the day. About 400 <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> supporters reached downtown <LOCATION> Windhoek </LOCATION> and held a rally across from a luxury hotel. About 30 policemen watched but did not interfere as the crowd chanted, `` SWAPO, we win!'' Until independence, administration of the territory and responsibility for law enforcement will remain in the hands of <PERSON> Pienaar </PERSON>, appointed by <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> has ruled <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> since it captured the territory from the Germans in World War I. <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeepers will monitor the election in November of a constituent assembly. The assembly will later set up a black majority government. Of <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s 1.3 million residents, about 70,000 are white. <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> is favored in the pre-independence elections, but whether it can gain the two-thirds support needed to have complete control over the drafting of a constitution is uncertain. The <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africans </LOCATION> agreed to a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> independence plan for <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> in December as part of a southwestern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> accord that also calls for <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> troops to be withdrawn from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 0254EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-ShipIntercepted     04-02 0193</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Ship Intercepted,0199</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cargo Ship Crew Notifies Coast Guard That Captain Appeared Drunk</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONG BEACH, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> intercepted a 728-foot cargo ship Saturday after the crew told the agency the captain appeared drunk and was piloting the ship erratically, officials said. A <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> patrol boat intercepted the Japan-bound `` Century Hope'' near the <LOCATION> Channel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> about 100 miles off the coast of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. The captain, who was not identified, submitted to a blood alcohol test and turned over command to the first mate, said Petty Officer <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. Results of the test were not available late Saturday. `` The vessel is anchored in <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> and has been detained by the Captain of the Port until the situation is resolved,'' Lt. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruzdzinski </PERSON> said. Another captain was flying from <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> to take command. The Century Hope, registered in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and flying the British flag, was carrying soy beans to <LOCATION> Yokohama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bruzdzinski </PERSON> said. The incident closely followed allegations that the captain piloting the oil tanker <PERSON> Exxon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> was drunk when the tanker rammed into <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Bligh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reef </LOCATION> on March 24th, creating the nation's worst oil spill.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 1627EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People-Kelly     04-02 0154</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People-Kelly,0159</SECOND>
<HEAD>Entertainer Gene Kelly Returns Home After Bout With Pneumonia</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hollywood song-and-dance man <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> was released from the hospital Sunday after a bout with pneumonia. `` He's at home now, resting,'' said <PERSON> Beebe </PERSON> <PERSON> Kline </PERSON>, a publicist for <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>, 76, had been admitted to <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION> hospital Wednesday under a pseudonym. `` He came in quietly,'' said hospital spokesman <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON>. `` His physicians did n't want him to be bothered by phone calls or visitors.'' The illness forced the entertainer to cancel a weekend performance of his one-man show, `` Evening with <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>'' at the <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mirada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. Theater spokeswoman <PERSON> Beverly </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamlin </PERSON> said the performance was not rescheduled and refunds would be given to 1,300 fans. <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> starred in such films as `` An <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>'' and `` Anchors Aweigh,'' with <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON>. He is probably best known for his splash dance in `` Singin' in the Rain,'' which he also co-directed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 2044EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People SUB a0671 04-02 0308</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People, SUB, a0671,0315</SECOND>
<HEAD>People In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS Los Angeles-dated item to CORRECT spelling of Sidney Pollack,
sted Sydney Pollock; SUBS Miami-dated item to fix spelling of Tippi Hedren,
sted Hendren.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY44</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hollywood stars turned out by the hundreds to honor director <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON> at a gala to raise money to build the American Cinematheque arts complex. <PERSON> Faye </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunaway </PERSON>, <PERSON> Victoria </PERSON> <PERSON> Principal </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Travolta </PERSON>, <PERSON> Goldie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawn </PERSON>, <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Matheson </PERSON> and directors <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollack </PERSON> joined studio executives, agents and publicists Saturday night at the fourth Annual Moving Picture Ball at the Century Plaza Hotel. `` <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON> has truly put the heart back into film and the audiences back into theaters,'' said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Essert </PERSON>, Cinematheque Founder and Artistic Director. The Cinematheque, a non-profit, viewer-sponsored cultural organization, is building an arts complex of theaters and galleries next door to <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>'s Chinese Theater in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>. Proceeds from the fund-raiser were not announced.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With <PERSON> Sophia </PERSON> <PERSON> Loren </PERSON> as the guest of honor, about 750 people attended a dinner and musical extravaganza that raised an estimated $ 550,000 to house an AIDS research program. `` Working Girl'' star <PERSON> Melanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> and her mother, <PERSON> Tippi </PERSON> <PERSON> Hedren </PERSON>, were hosts of `` An Extraordinary Evening with <PERSON> Sophia </PERSON> <PERSON> Loren </PERSON> and Friends'' Saturday on <LOCATION> Williams </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> in north <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Loren </PERSON> has a home. Actors <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cliff </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Goulet </PERSON> were among about 50 celebrities attending. Organizers said proceeds will go toward building a $ 5 million facility for the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION>'s Comprehensive AIDS Research Program. Dr. <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Fischl </PERSON>, the university's AIDS program director, praised Ms. <PERSON> Loren </PERSON> for helping fight stigma and apathy toward acquired immune deficiency syndrome. `` It's a terrible thing that's happening in our century,'' Ms. <PERSON> Loren </PERSON> said. She said fund-raising was like an ocean `` made up of many drops and every little drop helps.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 2145EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Cambodia-Sihanouk     04-02 0383</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cambodia-Sihanouk,0395</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sihanouk Says Would Meet Vietnamese-backed Cambodian Leader</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prince <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>, leader of a <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> resistance coalition, said Sunday he has agreed to meet <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON>, prime minister of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>'s Vietnamese-backed government. In a statement released from his residence in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> said he had been informed by a <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> diplomat that <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON> was ready to make `` two concessions in regard to the problem in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>.'' He did not reveal the nature of the concessions. He said the meeting of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>'s four warring factions could take place as early as May 2 in <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION> or in September in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. Last month <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON> sent a letter to <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> saying `` there are elements that show that a fundamental agreement is possible'' between the government and resistance groups. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> invaded <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in December 1978, drove out the radical <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> regime that defeated the U.S.-backed government in the spring of 1975, and installed another communist administration. Hundreds of thousands of Cambodians were killed during the nearly three years the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> was in power as it purged opponents and drove people out of the cities to impose a harsh form of agrarian communism. <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>, who was deposed in 1970, now leads a resistance alliance of his supporters, the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> and Cambodians loyal to anti-communist <LOCATION> Son </LOCATION> <LOCATION> San </LOCATION>. The three alliance members met in March in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and formed a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, which they said would unify their guerrilla forces. <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON> criticized the council, saying it was part of a <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> plot to regain power. On Sunday radio broadcasts by the resistance coalition denied that allegation and said the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> would not seek exclusive control of the future government and the council would not allow any faction to harm the others by force. Representatives of the resistance groups and <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> government met in February in <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>. The meeting ended without results when no agreement could be reached on the formation of a transitional government to be established following a withdrawl of the Vietnamese troops from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. They also disagreed on how to monitor the Vietnamese withdrawal. An estimated 70,000 Vietnamese military personnel are in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> has said it will withdraw its troops by September if the Cambodian factions can agree on a political solution.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 2136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BridgeCollapse 2ndLd-Writethru a0713 04-02 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bridge Collapse, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0713,0660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bridge Collapse Leaves At Least Seven Dead</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 1 graf to UPDATE with 7 bodies recovered; INSERTS
4 grafs after 8th graf, `We've got ..., to UPDATE with inspectors meeting
Monday, high water not considered cause. Pick up 9th graf, `The highway
...</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos MX1,2,3,4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WOODY BAIRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COVINGTON, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Divers pulled seven bodies from a murky, rain-swollen river Sunday where at least that many people died when a 50-year-old <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> highway bridge collapsed. The search for more victims continued but was hampered by bridge debris and muddy waters, said state <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> Lt. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Durham </PERSON>. The cause of the collapse was unknown. Searchers did not know how many victims might be in the river, said <PERSON> Leroy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bledsoe </PERSON>, team director for nine divers working at the site. Authorities said they had found a tractor-trailer rig and four cars which plunged into the river when a large chunk of the two-lane roadway fell 25 feet into the river about 8:45 p.m. CST Saturday. They planned to continue to search `` until we're sure there are no other vehicles or victims in there,'' <PERSON> Bledsoe </PERSON> said. The collapse left a 60-foot gap in the two-lane, northbound bridge carrying <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Highway 51 over the <LOCATION> Hatchie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> five miles north of here and about 45 miles north of <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>. A companion, two-lane bridge for southbound traffic was unaffected. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said bridge-building experts planned to study the bridge to try to find out why it collapsed. `` We've got the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> here. Their bridge survey team is going to survey the pilings of both bridges and do some soundings and we'll just have to go from there,'' he said. State bridge inspectors plan to meet Monday morning with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, according to <ORGANIZATION> Covington </ORGANIZATION> Fire Chief <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Craig </PERSON>. The river is slightly swollen from heavy rainfall last month, <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> said. `` We've had an unusual amount of rainfall last month. The river is out of its banks, and there's backwater all over the place. But this happens twice a year, every year, and has for the past 100 years,'' <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> said. `` The river is actually just barely out of its banks. We do n't feel it had any bearing on the collapse,'' said <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> The Highway Patrol closed the southbound roadway shortly after the collapse and traffic was routed around the area. One victim was identified as <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Herron </PERSON> Sr. of <PERSON> Ripley </PERSON>, believed to be 49 or 50, said <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Pugh </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lauderdale </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ripley </LOCATION>. The names of the other six were withheld until relatives were notified. The bodies of three victims, a man, a woman and a child, were recovered Saturday night. They apparently had been riding together in one car, <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> said. The Hatchie, which runs generally east to west across the middle of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, was at 14.7 feet, 2.7 feet over flood stage, about where the accident occurred, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported. It was not raining at the time of the collapse, but it had been raining in previous days. <PERSON> Bledsoe </PERSON> said swift currents and the dark water were hindering the search. `` It's pitch black in there,'' he said. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Prater </PERSON> of <PERSON> Covington </PERSON> said residents have been concerned for some time that the bridge was getting old. <PERSON> Prater </PERSON> said three of his relatives were in a pickup truck that drove over the bridge not long before it collapsed. `` I was telling my wife the other day, saying ` That bridge with as much water as we've had is a dangerous thing,''' he said. Aging highway bridges have collapsed in other states in recent years. In April 1987, an upstate <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> span collapsed, killing 10 people. In 1983, part of the <LOCATION> Mianus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> collapsed, killing three people.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 2145EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-IsraeliSpy     04-02 0171</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israeli Spy,0175</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spy Jailed in U.S. Still on Israel's Payroll</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> is paying $ 5,000 a month to an American serving a life sentence in federal prison in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> for stealing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> secrets for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, according to a published report. Each month $ 5,000 is put in an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> bank account for former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence analyst <PERSON> Jonathon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON>, according to the April 10 issue of Newsweek magazine. Newsweek attributed the information to `` Territory of Lies,'' a forthcoming book by <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> correspondent <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Blitzer </PERSON>. <PERSON> Blitzer </PERSON> suggests <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON> will eventually make a deal to be deported to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, where he'll get the cash, but no intelligence work. `` He'll get some money and probably even a nice apartment. But that's it,'' an unidentified Israeli official told <ORGANIZATION> Newsweek </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Blitzer </PERSON> found no evidence that <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON>'s activities were authorized at the highest level in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, but said <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> investigators told him some cabinet ministers `` probably suspected'' they had a spy in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> `` but were willing to shut their eyes to it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 2146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-WhatTime?     04-02 0588</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-What Time?,0603</SECOND>
<UNK>Does Anybody Really Know What Time It Is?</UNK>
<DATELINE>UNION CITY, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It will be another summer of confusion in <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, where the time of day is strictly a matter of opinion. Residents of this city divided by the <LOCATION> Indiana-Ohio </LOCATION> state line are victims of the time change that annually splits <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> into what residents call `` slow and fast time.'' When daylight-saving time went into effect nationwide at 2 a.m. Sunday, most citizens of <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, went along. They are on fast time. But those who live in <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, stay on Eastern Standard Time year-round, as do <ORGANIZATION> Hoosiers </ORGANIZATION> in 76 of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>'s 92 counties. They are on slow time _ most of them. `` Most people have adjusted to it, but there's still confusion,'' said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Stahl </PERSON>, mayor of <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Leroy </PERSON> <PERSON> Stentzil </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, has lived in <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, since 1930 but still sets his clocks on <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> time. `` It's a nuisance until you get used to it,'' <PERSON> Stentzil </PERSON> said. A few years ago, <PERSON> Stentzil </PERSON> had clocks in his house labeled `` <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> Time'' or `` Ohio Time.'' `` I do n't do that anymore,'' he said. `` But it does cause confusion. I've been late lots of times. Now if I'm invited to something in <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and I do n't think about it, I'm there an hour early. I keep reading material in my side pocket all the time.'' In fact, most <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, residents will experience the anxiety of being an hour late for something during the coming months, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, mayor of the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> side of Union City. `` But they'll make up for it by being early for something else.'' The time change affects families who work on one side of the state line but live on the other and merchants who must cater to customers on both times, <PERSON> Stahl </PERSON> said. `` In some instances there are stores that stay on slow time no matter what,'' <PERSON> Stahl </PERSON> said. `` The <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> stores go on fast time. There are some stores that might split it down the middle. It just gets confusing. `` If they're normally open until 5 o'clock fast time, that would be 4 o'clock slow time. So maybe they'll move it a half hour and close at 5:30. That way it would be 4:30 slow time.'' <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> said most of the larger industries in <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, run on fast time despite being in <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>. Those include <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Body </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which produces step vans, and <ORGANIZATION> Sheller-Globe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which makes auto trim. `` Most of the businesses in cities such as <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> expect them to be following those hours,'' <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> said. However, <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, schools and government stay on slow time. As a result, some parents are leaving for work while their children are just beginning to prepare for school. `` Part of the people in <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> go on the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> time, just like I do,'' <PERSON> Stentzil </PERSON> said. `` And part of them do n't. I used to laughingly say: ` I do n't care if they put ABCs on the clock. I'll get along.' But I'm an old man now, and it just is n't so easy to adjust.'' <PERSON> Stentzil </PERSON> said if <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> legislators lived in <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, they'd think again about the wisdom of exempting <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> from daylight-saving time Exemptions from daylight-saving time are <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Samoa </LOCATION> and part of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, according to The World Almanac. Daylight-saving time starts the first Sunday in April and ends the last Sunday in October.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 2147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-AustraliaFloods     04-02 0214</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Australia Floods,0220</SECOND>
<HEAD>Floods in Eastern Australia Claim at Least Two Lives</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SYDNEY, Australia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Torrential rains along <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>'s east coast have caused flooding that that has claimed at least two lives, police said Sunday. Two other people were missing and presumed drowned when a bridge collapsed, the police said. Officials said a water department employee perished Saturday when floodwaters overturned his boat in the <LOCATION> Murrimbidgee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> at <LOCATION> Casurina </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sands </LOCATION>, west of <LOCATION> Canberra </LOCATION>. A man died in <LOCATION> Queensland </LOCATION> state because of the flooding, police said, but no details were available. Seven people were swept away when the rampaging <LOCATION> Tweed </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> collapsed a bridge at <LOCATION> Murwillumbah </LOCATION> in northern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION> state. Police said five people were rescued early Sunday but two are missing. Helicopters were sent to <LOCATION> Murwillumbah </LOCATION> to rescue victims of the flooding that followed 48 hours of rain.. One helicopter lifted 15 people from rooftops in the town and navy helicopters rescued five schoolchildren stranded in the <LOCATION> Murwillumbah </LOCATION> area, officials reported <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Pickering </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION> minister of police and emergency services, advised thousands of people living near the <LOCATION> Nepean </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hawkesbury </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Georges </PERSON> rivers in the <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION> region to prepare for possible evacuation. The <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Highway </LOCATION>, the main road link between <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Brisbane </LOCATION>, was flooded in several places.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 2224EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AbortionMarch 1stLd-Writethru a0730 04-02 0595</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Abortion March, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0730,0609</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thousands Participate In Abortion Rights March Through San Francisco</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 4 grafs after 5th graf, `The march ..., to UPDATE with
New York demonstration. Pick up 6th graf, `Activists on ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER McNULTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At least 20,000 people marched through downtown on Sunday in a noisy abortion rights demonstration that organizers called the largest pro-choice gathering ever held in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Area </LOCATION>. Police estimated the crowd at about 20,000, but organizers of the `` March for Women's Lives'' said more than 30,000 people participated in the march and rally at City Hall. <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Connell </PERSON>, 59, of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION>, marched with her 85-year-old mother and 30-year-old daughter. They carried a sign that said `` Three generations for choice.'' `` I think what's before us is a choice of whether abortion is safe and legal or whether abortion is unsafe and illegal,'' said <PERSON> Connell </PERSON>. `` It's not whether there's going to be abortion.'' The march, which was expected to attract supporters from as far away as <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state, was held in conjunction with a scheduled April 9 abortion rights rally in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> D.C </ORGANIZATION>. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, about 400 abortion rights activists, some hoisting giant clothes hangers, pushed against anti-abortionists in a demonstration in front of St. Patrick's Cathedral. In a rare show of civil disobedience marking what a rally leader called `` a turning point'' in the abortion rights movement, nine activists were arrested for trespassing on church property and disorderly conduct. `` Cardinal <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, we know your position, you are the head of the new Inquisition!'' shouted the protesters, who say that Cardinal <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> hierarchy are endorsing violence against women by supporting radical anti-abortionists. Neither <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> nor his spokesman returned messages seeking comment on the protest. Activists on both sides of the issue have been galvanized by a recent <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision to hear a case that could overturn legal protections for abortion that were guaranteed by the court's 1973 <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> decision. Many participants said that threat prompted them to gather in the streets to publicly express their views. `` It's the timing with the court,'' said <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, 43, of <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>. `` Our position does n't mean we're telling people to have an abortion, because there's nothing worse than a child that's unloved and unwanted ... It's a matter of respecting opinions.'' The rally also comes at a time when several anti-abortion groups, including Operation Rescue, have held numerous protests at clinics around the nation. In <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, a suburban abortion clinic was blockaded for more than an hour Saturday by anti-abortion demonstrators. Police arrested 137 people on trespassing charges. On Friday, 83 people were arrested for blocking access to an abortion clinic in <LOCATION> Boca </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Raton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, and an arson fire early Friday caused $ 65,000 damage to an abortion clinic in <LOCATION> Ocala </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. Sunday's <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> march brought a sharp reaction from anti-abortion activists `` Although the marchers purport to represent the women of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, I think they are deluded by their own sense of self-importance,'' <PERSON> Carole </PERSON> <PERSON> Hieatt </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jose </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pro-Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement. In its most recent poll on the subject, the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported on March 19 that 74 percent of the respondents in a nationwide survey said they believed that abortion was `` morally wrong,'' but also believed that it was a decision best left to the individual. More than 100 organizations sponsored Sunday's demonstration, including NOW, <ORGANIZATION> Planned </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parenthood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abortion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 2233EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Namibia 3rdLd-Writethru a0737 04-02 0800</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Namibia, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0737,0821</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police: 44 Guerrillas Killed On Second Day Of Transition</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 17th pvs, `SWAPO urged..., to ADD dropped
graf on terms of agreement. Pick up 18th pvs, `Botha, in...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURINDA KEYS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WINDHOEK, Namibia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Territorial police reported killing 44 guerrillas Sunday in widespread fighting that shattered a cease-fire and threatened <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s day-old transition to independence from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. South Africa accused the rebel <ORGANIZATION> South-West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> of infiltrating from neighboring <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, but <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> said its guerrillas were defending themselves <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> agreed to give up control of <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> under a U.N.-monitored process that began Saturday. Since late Friday, 120 guerrillas and six police officers hade been killed, territorial police Lt. <PERSON> Kierie </PERSON> du Rand said Sunday night. <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> president <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nujoma </PERSON> told a news conference in <LOCATION> Harare </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>, that group officials told him at least 48 civilians also had been killed in the confrontations, and many others had been wounded. He said he could neither confirm nor deny the reports of guerrilla deaths. Namibian police said there were more than 30 confrontations between officers and guerrillas during the day Sunday, and that the fighting continued into the night. No details about the clashes were released. <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> officials, including Gen. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Opande </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>, deputy commander of the peacekeeping troops, said the soldiers had neither participated in nor seen the battles. Territorial police said the fighting was in <LOCATION> Owamboland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s northernmost tribal area, where the guerrillas have had the most support during their 23-year bush war against <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> African control of <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. The territorial army, due to be dismantled in mid-May as part of a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> accord, suspended its demobilization process Sunday because of the fighting and began reassembling some units. South African's foreign minister, <PERSON> Pik </PERSON> <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, accused <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> of ordering hundreds of insurgents to cross into <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> in violation of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> agreement, reached in December. On Saturday, <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> said his government might order the 1,000 <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> troops in <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> to leave if it was not satisfied with a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> response to the fighting. <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> accused <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> of initiating the clashes and said its guerrillas `` fired only in self-defense after being hunted down and attacked.'' `` It is the earnest desire of <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> to scrupulously observe the terms of the cease-fire agreement,'' <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement from its headquarters in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. It did not explain why its fighters were inside <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Nujoma </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Zimbabawe </LOCATION> for a conference on <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, said he was `` dismayed and shocked'' that the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> would allow the territorial police to be redeployed. He told the semi-official <ORGANIZATION> Zimbabwe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inter-African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> that the guerrillas were under strict instructions to abide by the cease-fire but that alleged violations were being investigated. Until Friday, there had been no fighting between <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> for more than six months as both sides observed an informal truce. <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> urged the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> to deploy more peacekeeping troops to monitor the truce. A total of 4,650 U.N.-sponsored troops are to be sent to <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> during the transition to independence. A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> force, <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Eckhard </PERSON>, said <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION>'s guerrillas were supposed to stay at least 100 miles inside <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> as of midnight Friday He said it was unclear whether the Namibian police, who remain in charge of law enforcement until independence, were entitled to operate against the guerrillas. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, in a statement Sunday issued in <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, said some of the guerrillas were armed with surface-to-air missiles, and that the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> should hold an urgent meeting on the matter. Four <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> officials Sunday inspected the scene of the initial fighting and returned to <LOCATION> Windhoek </LOCATION> to report to the top <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> official in the territory, Special Representative <PERSON> Martti </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahtisaari </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>. They declined to comment on their findings, saying the situation was too sensitive. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> issued a statement Saturday expressing alarm over the clashes. He said <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> officials in <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> had confirmed an incursion by scores of guerrillas. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s white-minority government has ruled <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> since World War I. In December, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> agreed to the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> independence plan as part of a regional accord that also calls for withdrawal of Cuban troops from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. Until independence, administration of the territory and responsibility for law enforcement will remain in the hands of a South African-appointed official, <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Pienaar </PERSON>, who is required to oversee the government and elections impartially. <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> is the size of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> combined, but it has a population of only about 1.3 million, including roughly 70,000 whites. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> on Sunday recognized <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s independence from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, and expressed hopes that the Namibian people would establish a `` truly popular government,'' the official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 2245EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Gorbachev 5thLd-Writethru a0753 04-02 0782</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gorbachev, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0753,0804</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gorbachev Arrives in Cuba For Talks With Castro</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 5th pvs, `Hundreds of, to UPDATE with
Gorbachev quotes. Pick up 6th pvs, `Formal talks...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL PUTZEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HAVANA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> received a warm welcome Sunday as he arrived in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> for talks with President <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, who has criticized the Soviet leader's new pragmatic brand of communism. <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, wearing the green fatigue uniform that has been his trademark for three decades, walked onto the rain-soaked tarmac after <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s <PERSON> Ilyushin </PERSON> 62 jetliner landed and threw his arms around the Soviet leader. It was the third meeting of the communist chieftains but <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s first visit to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, the island nation that for nearly 30 years has stood as a symbol of Soviet influence 90 miles off the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> coast. <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> kissed <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON>, on both cheeks before escorting <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> on a review of the presidential honor guard. Hundreds of thousands of Cubans mustered by local neighborhood committees packed the arrival area at <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Marti </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> and lined a 10-mile route through downtown <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION> to the official guest house where <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will stay during his four-day visit. `` Everything is clear in our friendship, in our hearts, in our soul, in our faces,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said in a brief comment to <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Latina </ORGANIZATION>, the Cuban news agency, upon his arrival at the guest house. `` Now the only thing left is to talk, and we do have somethingg to talk about,'' he said. Formal talks between the Soviet and <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> leaders were to begin Monday. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> rode to the capital standing side by side in an open, Soviet-built parade car. They waved to the cheering, flag-waving crowd stacked several deep on both sides of the road. Although <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> is known for his ability to turn out thousands of people in this city of 2 million, the welcome for <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> appeared genuinely warm. Official media in both countries have papered over ideological differences to stress the closeness of Cuban-Soviet relations. But the contrast between <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>'s doctrinaire Marxism and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s new-style openness and determination to modernize the Soviet economy is evident just below the surface. `` <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> needs perestroika and glasnost,'' one female church-goer said Sunday when asked what she thought of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s visit. `` God has put <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in the world, and we are grateful.'' The woman, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said she hoped <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> would encourage <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> to permit more freedom in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. Cuban security agents called a number of local dissidents to suggest they stay away from the welcoming celebrations for <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, said one source in the dissident community, which remains largely underground. Political activity interpreted by the Communist regime as `` counterrevolutionary'' is punishable by lengthy prison terms. During his visit, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is to hold several hours of private talks with <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, who has been openly critical of the Soviet leader's pragmatic reforms for borrowing too much from capitalism. Soviet officials have suggested the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> may reduce its massive economic and military aid to the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> nation as it seeks to rebuild the Soviet domestic economy. `` We are going to discuss <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>'s performance, just as he is going to discuss our own performance,'' Soviet spokesman <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> earlier Sunday in an interview from <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION>. `` We will exchange views and experiences.'' Before flying to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> stopped in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and met with Prime Minister <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Haughey </PERSON>, who suggested the next U.S.-Soviet summit be held in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s first summit with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will be held in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> later this year if the two nations follow the pattern set during <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s presidency. However, no Bush-Gorbachev meeting has been scheduled. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s two-hour stop to the politically neutral, staunchly Roman Catholic <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> was the first by a <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leader. It was <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s first overseas visit since a December trip to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He was scheduled to do some sightseeing and address the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> before leaving <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION> to fly to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> on Wednesday for meetings with Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>. He is to speak to financial and business leaders in a nationally televised address Friday and will have lunch with Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> before returning to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. During their meeting in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Haughey </PERSON> were photographed holding glasses of stout, the country's favorite beverage. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has championed an anti-alcoholism campaign in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and has severely restricted sales of vodka. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Haughey </PERSON>, surrounded by their foreign ministers and aides, met in a VIP lounge. Outside hung a vast oil painting of the late <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> that commemorated a 1963 visit by the Irish-American president shortly before his assassination.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 2248EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-GiraffeDeath     04-02 0230</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Giraffe Death,0234</SECOND>
<UNK>Giraffe At Evansville Zoo Dies After Falling on Side</UNK>
<DATELINE>EVANSVILLE, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Evie </PERSON>, an 8-year-old female giraffe, died Sunday about 11 hours after falling on her side, zoo officials said. `` She passed away at 2:30 a.m.,'' said <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Grannon </PERSON>, operations curator for the Mesker Park Zoo. The body was taken to <ORGANIZATION> Purdue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION> for an autopsy to determine the cause of death, he said. Zoo director <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said <PERSON> Evie </PERSON> fell flat on her side Saturday about 3:15 p.m., but he was not sure what caused the accident. `` She was kind of running around in the sun when all four feet went our from under her and she landed on her side,'' <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said. `` We do n't know if the wind was knocked out of her or whether she hit her head.'' <PERSON> Evie </PERSON> had been on her back since the accident, and attempted about every 30 minutes to get back on her feet, zoo officials said. Zoo veterinarians Dr. <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> and Dr. <PERSON> Stan </PERSON> <PERSON> Epperson </PERSON> treated <PERSON> Evie </PERSON> Saturday night with relaxants, pain relievers and fluids, and even took X-rays of her neck and her legs but found nothing broken, <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Evie </PERSON>, worth $ 12,000 to $ 20,000, came to the zoo in 1982 from <LOCATION> Abilene </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Her mate, <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON>, came from the <LOCATION> Cheyenne </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zoo </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, in 1981, <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 2250EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-DebtTalks 5thLd-Writethru a0751 04-02 1103</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Debt Talks, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0751,950</SECOND>
<HEAD>Third World Debt Relief Plan Gets Major Boost from Industrialized
Nations</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 11th graf pvs, bgng: ``The $1.3 trillion...'' to make riots
in February sted last month; picks up 12th graf pvs, bgng: ``The endorsement...''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's new plan to provide debt relief for Third World countries received a major boost on Sunday when it won endorsement from the world's leading industrialized countries. The endorsement was contained in a joint communique adopted by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. It was issued following almost eight hours of closed-door discussions conducted by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Treasury Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> and his foreign counterparts. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> proposal was not mentioned by name in the three-page joint statement, but the discussion of the changes needed in current policy showed that the finance ministers were in general support of the proposals outlined by <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> in a March 10 speech. `` Debt strategy should be strengthened by placing greater emphasis on voluntary debt relief and debt service reduction in agreement with the commercial banks as a complement to new lending,'' the finance ministers said. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> said that he was pleased with the endorsement contained in the joint statement, saying it was unusually detailed on what approaches now need to be taken and very specific on the need for prompt action by the international lending agencies. `` There was broad support for strengthening the debt strategy along the lines of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> proposals,'' <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> told reporters after the meeting had ended. Canadian Finance Minister <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> called the new debt strategy an important step forward in solving the seven-year-long debt crisis. `` We have a good agreement and we have good support demonstrated for the proposal,'' he told reporters. A senior <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> official, who briefed reporters, said that while the communique did not mention specific support to be provided by other countries, he expected such announcements would be made later in the week. The administration is looking for countries running large trade surpluses, such as <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, to offer to support the debt reduction effort by providing money for new loans. The <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> plan represents a major departure from the debt approach pursued by the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, which had repeatedly rejected proposals for broad-based debt forgiveness. The $ 1.3 trillion burden of Third World debt has crippled the economies of developing nations and sparked economic and political unrest in many emerging democracies in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. Riots left at least 270 people dead in <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> in February after the government announced a new austerity program to please that country's creditors The endorsement by <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s major allies was the first step in a sales strategy the administration has put together. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> now takes the proposal before meetings on Monday and Tuesday of the steering committees of the 151-nation <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monetary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>. The two major lending organizations have key roles to play in implementation of the new debt relief approach, which the administration hopes will shave the current debt burden by 20 percent. In other comments, the seven industrialized countries reaffirmed their commitment to stabilize the dollar, saying either a sharp increase or decline in the greenback's value would be seen as harmful to worldwide economic growth and would trigger joint intervention by the nations to buy or sell dollars. The countries also told the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> that it needs to do more to reduce its huge budget deficits and said countries, such as <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, which were running large trade surpluses should continue to promote domestic demand in order to provide markets for foreign goods. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> allies have been complaining that <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s expected $ 170 billion federal budget deficit this year threatens worldwide growth by driving up interest rates, a situation which also adds to the debt payment burden of poor nations. The discussions took place at <ORGANIZATION> River </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION>, an estate on the <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> which once belonged to <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>. Under the <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> debt plan, commercial banks would be asked to forgive voluntarily a portion of the loans they have made to poor nations. In return, the <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> would provide assurances that the remaining debt would be repaid. The administration has estimated that over the next three years the plan could wipe out about $ 70 billion of the $ 340 billion in debt owed by 39 of the most heavily indebted countries. The <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> would be expected to contribute together between $ 20 billion and $ 25 billion to back the debt reduction effort with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> looking to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and other countries running large trade surpluses to assist in the effort by making new loans. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have indicated that <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> likely would be among the first beneficiaries of any debt relief strategy. But the debtor nations are already complaining that the plan does not go far enough to provide relief. Some experts have said that any attack on the problem will have to write off 50 percent or more of the debt. Large <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> banks, who hold 30 percent of the outstanding Third World loans, have reacted cautiously to the proposals, fearing that they could cause a stampede by debtor nations demanding debt forgiveness. Already, officials of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> have indicated that they will ask their bank creditors in upcoming negotiations to either provide new loans or slash the value of outstanding loans or the interest rates being paid by half. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, which owes $ 107 billion, is the Third World's second largest debtor, behind the $ 110 billion owed by <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>. The <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> plan represents a major departure from the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration approach, which emphasized new lending and opposed any broad-based proposals for debt forgiveness. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> approach was crafted by then-Treasury Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, who is secretary of state in the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, said in a speech last week that the new policy of debt forgiveness would be negotiated on a country-by-country basis with the relief going to those debtor nations willing to adopt necessary economic reforms. At the <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> meetings on Sunday, debtor nations issued a statement attacking the Baker approach to Third World debt while welcoming the new approach outlined by <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jean-Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Lemboumba-Lepandou </PERSON>, finance minister of <LOCATION> Gabon </LOCATION> and chairman of the committee representing developing countries, said the <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> plan was `` an important initiative and we are convinced that it will bear fruit.'' However, the <LOCATION> Gabon </LOCATION> finance minister sidestepped questions about whether the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> proposal went far enough to reduce the debt burden, saying the specifics of the proposal still needed to be worked out in upcoming meetings.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 2254EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Gallaudet-Zinser 1stLd-Writethru a0657 04-02 0426</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gallaudet-Zinser, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0657,0435</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Year After Gallaudet Protests, Elisabeth Zinser is Heading For
Idaho</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Rewrites throughout to CORRECT spelling of Elisabeth, sted Elizabeth,
Zinser.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Gallaudet-A Year Later</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto CH1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL NOWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GREENSBORO, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Elisabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Zinser </PERSON>, who was forced to resign last year as the incoming president of the nation's only university for the deaf, looks back on the incident without bitterness and says she's ready for a new challenge as president of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Idaho </ORGANIZATION>. `` I'm a pioneering person,'' she said. `` I feel I have to be part of something that is poised for development.'' In March 1988, Ms. <PERSON> Zinser </PERSON> became the focus of a national controversy when she was selected over two deaf finalists to become president of <ORGANIZATION> Gallaudet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> For the previous five years, Ms. <PERSON> Zinser </PERSON> had been vice chancellor for academic affairs at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Greensboro </LOCATION>. She stayed at that post when the protest over the <LOCATION> Gallaudet </LOCATION> job led her to withdraw before she took office. But now she's going to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, where she'll start July 1 as the first woman president of the <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>'s 9,500-student flagship state university. She said she hopes to strengthen that school's research efforts and its ties with the business community, and will work with <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>'s Indian and Hispanic communities. And in an interview last week, she wondered aloud if her interest in public service was enhanced by her experience with the deaf students. `` I've got an intense desire to make my life count for something,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Zinser </PERSON>, 49. `` That's why I ca n't just work for any institution.'' Her selection at <LOCATION> Gallaudet </LOCATION> touched off an immediate protest by thousands of students, faculty members and their supporters at the school _ which had never had a deaf president in its 124-year history. The protesters shut down the university, marched and burned Ms. <PERSON> Zinser </PERSON> in effigy. After three days, she resigned, citing a `` unique civil-rights movement in history.'' `` One of my objectives as president of <ORGANIZATION> Gallaudet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> was to be succeeded by a deaf person,'' she said with a smile. `` I accomplished that, perhaps more quickly than I had planned. `` I never felt I quit,'' she continued. `` It was n't a battle between the students and <PERSON> Elisabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Zinser </PERSON>, but an effort to reach a common bond.'' Ms. <PERSON> Zinser </PERSON> said farewell to the <LOCATION> Gallaudet </LOCATION> students by flashing them the `` I love you'' sign. The students later gave her a personal sign-language nickname: an `` E'' for <PERSON> Elisabeth </PERSON>, held over the heart.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 2259EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Panama-Drugs     04-02 0343</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-Drugs,0355</SECOND>
<HEAD>Five Arrested in Money Laundering Investigation</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALINA GUERRERO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two bank executives and three other people were arrested in the investigation of a Colombian-owned bank accused in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> of participating in a money laundering operation, officials said. Attorney General <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Villalaz </PERSON> on Saturday identified the bankers as <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Guarin </PERSON>, a Colombian who is manager of the <ORGANIZATION> Banco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Occidente </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Clara </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, a Panamanian who is the bank's operations manager. He said the others arrested were Colombian pilots German <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> and <PERSON> Alonso </PERSON> <PERSON> Correa </PERSON>, a Colombian who was on the plane that also carried <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> is one of 127 people charged in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> case that involves more than a billion dollars in alleged drug trafficking and money laundering. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, eluded capture Wednesday by hiding in a bank and then escaping after troops from the Panamanian Defense Forces surrounded the building, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> justice officials said. <PERSON> Villalaz </PERSON> did not say when the arrests were made. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sessions </PERSON> announced Wednesday that authorities had broken up an operation that had laundered $ 1.2 billion in drug money the past two years. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said the operation was linked to <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> drug cartel, which purportedly accounts for 80 percent of the cocaine entering the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> It was not clear if the pilots were the same ones <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said had been detained Wednesday in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> with <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>' private plane. The defense forces are headed by Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, the country's leader, who is under indictment in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> on illegal drug charges. <PERSON> Villalaz </PERSON> said authorities had searched intensely for <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> but `` unfortunately we have n't been able to locate him.'' <PERSON> Nivaldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Madrinan </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investigations </ORGANIZATION>, said Saturday that <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> escaped `` because of the lack of coordination between the capture in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and the release of the news in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, where there was a news conference that was heard by the fugitive.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890402-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-89 2309EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Nicaragua-Protest     04-02 0262</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua-Protest,0273</SECOND>
<HEAD>Workers Protest Government Policies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MASAYA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 1,000 union members on Sunday protested the high cost of living, the military draft and what they called a lack of labor rights. The Workers' Permanent <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> organized the demonstration in this city, 17 miles east of the capital of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Eli </PERSON> <PERSON> Altamirano </PERSON>, secretary-general of the <ORGANIZATION> Nicaraguan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, called the protest the beginning of `` a huge mobilization against the Sandinista regime.'' One sign carried by protesters said `` Next year the nine leave,'' referring to the governing directorate of the left-wing <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>. In February 1990, <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> is to hold general elections in accordance with a peace plan the five <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> presidents agreed to two months ago. `` The elections will not legitimize the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>. Rather, they will be beaten,'' said <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarquin </PERSON>, a Social Christian labor leader. The government has devaluated the currency several times this year and slashed spending in the face of soaring inflation and rising unemployment. There was no immediate reaction by the government to the <PERSON> Masaya </PERSON> <PERSON> demonstratin </PERSON>. The workers' congress is a federation of unions including centrist, socialist and communist members. Last June the congress called a strike that lasted several months. Dozens of union leaders were detained but later freed. Some of the protesters Sunday tried to attack a cameraman from government-run television and a photographer for the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> newspaper Barricada. Neither was injured and no other incidents were reported. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Duran </PERSON>, the Barricada photographer, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that the demonstrators tried to take his camera but foreign correspondents came to his aid.
</TEXT>
</DOC>