<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0135EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Quayle-APMeeting     04-06 0119</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Quayle-AP Meeting,0121</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush, Quayle To Address AP Publishers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> are scheduled to address the annual meeting and luncheon of The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in separate appearances in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> on April 24. <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> announced the appearances by the president and the vice president at opening day events of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> annual convention. Never before have a president and a vice president addressed the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> meetings on the same day. Some 2,000 AP member publishers and spouses are expected to attend the two events. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will appear first at the annual meeting of the news cooperative. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> will follow at the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> annual luncheon.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0205EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TheSellingofSouthfork     04-06 0611</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-The Selling of Southfork,0632</SECOND>
<HEAD>Meanwhile, Back At The Ranch Featured in `Dallas'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto DN1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE PEGO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARKER, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Trippet </PERSON> has done his best to make certain visitors to his world-famous <LOCATION> Southfork </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ranch </LOCATION> can see everything they believe <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> has to offer. He has installed a 183-foot-tall oil derrick. He has stocked lush pastures with a longhorn cattle and championship racehorses. And as for a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> millionaire? Well, he says, he just walks around the grounds as often as he can. <PERSON> Trippet </PERSON>'s ranch about 25 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> is the model for the Ewing spread in the television series `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>.'' The ranch, with its stately white two-story ranchhouse and immense outbuildings, is sometimes incorrectly placed in neighboring towns. But <PERSON> Trippet </PERSON> prefers the townname of <LOCATION> Southfork </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ranch </LOCATION>, and he lets everyone know it's all his. `` I'm the mayor and I'm the city council and I'm the building inspector,'' he says, wearing a sly grin that's shaded by a $ 3,000 cowboy hat. `` That's the only way I could have gotten all these things built around here.'' What was once a fairly nice country ranch is becoming an international tourist attraction. <PERSON> Trippet </PERSON> says you can stand on any part of the ranch and hear about 10 languages spoken in one hour. It sounds like an idle boast until the next group of tourists strolls by. A camera-snapping couple is from <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. A young family with two children is from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. And a woman who rolls into <PERSON> Trippet </PERSON>'s path and levels a camera lens at his head has a British accent `` You look just like <PERSON> J.R. </PERSON>, coming down there,'' she says, as she shoots. He does resemble <PERSON> J.R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ewing </PERSON>, who raises the ire and interest of millions of TV fans worldwide. On this day, the tall Texan is wearing a leather vest, western shirt, a pair of sharply pressed jeans and ostrich-skin boots. Like <PERSON> J.R. </PERSON>, the 44-year-old <PERSON> Trippet </PERSON> is fond of that disappearing <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> pastime _ making money. And he made his through _ you guessed it _ oil. `` You want to know the most expensive souvenir around here,'' he says, then points at himself. `` Me _ that's what. And I'm not cheap.'' <PERSON> Trippet </PERSON>, who bought the ranch in 1984 for a `` very big'' price, says if <ORGANIZATION> Southfork </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ranch </ORGANIZATION> looks a bit commercial, that's because it's meant to make money From the $ 1.75 chili dogs to the ranchhouse, which he rents for $ 2,500 a night for overnight visitors, the showplace is meant to be a money-making proposition. `` Besides,'' he says. `` That $ 2,500 is nothing. A good penthouse is going to cost you that much to rent. ... `` But anything you see here is for sale. You want to buy those shrubs and I'll go dig them up myself.'' His latest enterprise could be the start of something very big. This Friday, Saturday and Sunday, <PERSON> Trippet </PERSON> is holding the <ORGANIZATION> Southfork </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Antiques </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Spectacular </ORGANIZATION>. More than $ 3 million worth of antique furniture, chandeliers, carpets and jewelry will be offered for sale. The auction will include a <ORGANIZATION> Louis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> XV </ORGANIZATION> dining room transferred intact to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> from a Scottish castle. It's being offered by <PERSON> Priscilla </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> socialite. For the occasion, <PERSON> Trippet </PERSON> is selling the contents of his ranchhouse. He says he will then refill the house and sell all those items at the next auction. As <PERSON> Trippet </PERSON> ambles back to the ranch office to check calls before roaring off in a gold Mercedes, he does n't miss a step when asked about his favorite part of the ranch. `` My cash register,'' he says. `` And those tour buses parked over there. I love to see those dollar bills walking in.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0736EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--DiaperService     04-06 0147</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Diaper Service,0152</SECOND>
<HEAD>Berkshire County's Last Diaper Service To Fold</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ADAMS, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The diaper business has hit bottom, forcing the last remaining diaper service in <LOCATION> Berkshire </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> to call it quits. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Holzer </PERSON>, vice president of <LOCATION> Aladco </LOCATION>, said that with more parents using disposable diapers his customers have dropped from 400 a decade ago to a mere 60 scattered across the county. `` We ca n't operate at that low a volume,'' he said Tuesday. <PERSON> Holzer </PERSON> said he had hoped negative publicity about disposable diapers choking landfills would slow the trend, but that did n't happen Toward the end, he found that he could n't even give away his business. People declined, even when diaper service was offered as a gift, <PERSON> Holzer </PERSON> said. And so, in May, the Adams company, which also operates a laundry, dry cleaning and linen and uniform rental business, is dropping its diaper division.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0207EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SexAid     04-06 0233</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sex Aid,0239</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sex Aid: ``We Just Want Their Money''</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sex Aid. Keep a little tin box by the bed, and donate 25 pence every time, uh, you know, whenever you do. Wink wink, nudge nudge. The campaign announced by <ORGANIZATION> Marie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stopes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, a charity which supports family planning in the Third World, sounds like a publicity stunt. It is a publicity stunt. <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Hindmarsh </PERSON>, fund-raising manager for the charity, said Wednesday that it has been working away quietly for 20 years, `` talking earnestly to people _ and it has n't done the trick.'' `` We now realize that we need more hype like Band Aid and Comic Relief to draw people's attention to the problem, so we are asking people to make love and save the world.'' At the suggested rate of 25 pence -LRB- 43 cents -RRB-, Ms. <PERSON> Hindmarsh </PERSON> said the average British couple could give 12.50 pounds -LRB- about $ 21.25 -RRB- a year. `` They can save it up or write us a check every six months or put it in a little tin by the bed,'' Ms. <PERSON> Hindmarsh </PERSON> said. `` We do n't really care how they do it,'' she confessed. `` At the end of the day we just want their money.'' There is a serious point too: `` I think it will help people focus on the fact that they have the freedom to make love without producing another mouth to feed,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lenin     04-06 0215</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lenin,0221</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lenin's Body Still OK After 65 Years, Scientists Say</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The body of <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON> still is well-preserved after 65 years on lying in state in <LOCATION> Red </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, Pravda reported, and is in no immediate danger of decomposition. The <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> newspaper quoted <PERSON> Sergei </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Debov </PERSON>, head of the laboratory overseeing the body, as confirming long speculation that scientists at first did not think they could preserve the remains of the Soviet founder, who died in 1924. He said they considered a refrigeration system, but instead decided on `` anatomical-biochemical methods,'' the paper reported Wednesday. <PERSON> Debov </PERSON> did not go into details on how the body is maintained, but disclosed that the fight against decomposition was so intense at first that scientists had to work around the clock to preserve it. He said the preservation process still requires `` daily vigilant observation'' and that the body `` is guaranteed for an extended period of time.'' The body lies beneath glass in a special marble-and-granite mausoleum in Red Square. Five days a week, visitors are hustled past the body in a dimly lit room where no photographs are allowed. Mass demand that <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON>'s body lie permanently displayed prompted the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leadership to overrule <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON>'s widow, <PERSON> Nadezhda </PERSON> <PERSON> Krupskaya </PERSON>, who opposed having her husband embalmed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0213EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ScrippsHowardAwards     04-06 0266</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scripps Howard Awards,0280</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scripps Howard Foundation Honors Journalists At Banquet</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Scripps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> has honored print and broadcast journalists in 13 categories ranging from editorial writing to public service. Representatives of eight newspapers, three television stations, one radio station and one college newspaper were recognized at the foundation's National Journalism Awards Banquet Wednesday night. About 400 people attended. The winners include: _ <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Kalb </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Haven </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, in the college cartoonist category; _ <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Daly </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodwin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paul </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- Pioneer Press Dispatch, for editorial writing; _ The <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- Gazette, for environmental journalism in the under-100 ,000 circulation category; _ <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paul </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pioneer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dispatch </ORGANIZATION>, for environmental journalism in the over-100 ,000 circulation category; _ <ORGANIZATION> KOCO-TV </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> ity </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>, for commitment to literacy, broadcast division; _ <ORGANIZATION> Lesher </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION>, based in <LOCATION> Walnut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, for commitment to literacy, newspaper division; _ <ORGANIZATION> Anchorage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, for public service in the under-100 ,000 circulation category; _ The <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Inquirer </LOCATION>, for public service in the over-100 ,000 circulation category; _ <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kifner </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, for human interest writing; _ <ORGANIZATION> KTAR-AM </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, for excellence in local broadcast journalism in the large market radio category; _ WBRZ-TV, <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, for excellence in local broadcast journalism in the small market television category; _ <ORGANIZATION> WFAA-TV </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, for Eagle-Tribune, for service to the First Amendment. The <ORGANIZATION> Scripps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> was established in 1962 by <ORGANIZATION> Scripps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION>. The Cincinnati-based company is one of the country's largest media communications companies with interests in newspaper publishing, broadcasting, cable television, syndication and other media-related fields
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--PresidentialPrankster     04-06 0167</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Presidential Prankster,0170</SECOND>
<UNK>Student Punished For Actions During Bush Visit</UNK>
<DATELINE>LANCASTER, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A high school student was barred from some school activities after he reportedly mouthed obscenities at television cameras during President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s visit to the school. The student, 17-year-old <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Petersheim </PERSON>, was in `` preferential seating'' in bleachers behind the president at <ORGANIZATION> Conestoga </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> on March 22, Principal <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON> said. Some of his antics, which included blowing chewing-gum bubbles and waving a `` <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in'92'' sign after <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s anti-drug speech, apparently were aired by at least one <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> area television station, <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON> said. `` In this situation he did n't know how to act,'' said the principal, who decided to ban the senior from certain events. <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON> said the student had been barred from activities `` where we ca n't control his behavior.'' Those include school assemblies, the senior prom and graduation exercises. A school secretary logged several calls from television viewers the day of the president's visit complaining about the student's behavior, <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON> said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0215EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lebanon-Life     04-06 0803</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon-Life,0832</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lebanese Huddle In Bunkers During Shelling Duels</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RODEINA KENAAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The murderous bombardment in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, the worst in four years, has squeezed people's daily lives to four hours of scurrying about their business and 20 hours underground. When Syrian and Christian artillery gunners rest at daybreak, thousands of trapped residents cautiously emerge from bunkers. Their first order of business is to hurriedly buy fresh supplies of food, water, candles, gas lamps, decks of cards and sleeping pills. Just before the antagonists resume the deadly duel that began three weeks ago, they rush back to shelters on both sides of the Green Line that divides the city into Moslem and Christian sectors. Most nightclubs, bars, restaurants, cafes and movie houses are closed. So are schools and universities. Banks operate haphazardly for two or three hours a day, depending on the ferocity of the shelling. `` The only thing that matters nowadays is self-preservation,'' said <PERSON> Amin </PERSON> <PERSON> Trad </PERSON>, a pharmacist in <LOCATION> Christian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Ashrafiyeh </LOCATION> district. `` Survival is the name of the game.'' He did not recall a similar stampede for sleeping pills in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s 14-year civil war. `` I do n't have statistics. But if this continues, we will soon run out of tranquilizers,'' said Trad, whose pharmacy is shielded by tall sandbag walls. There are no severe shortages at present. Wholesalers try to monopolize goods in order to raise prices, and stores order new stock during lulls in the fighting. Some residents manage to joke about the shelling. `` Tell my friends in west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> not to worry about me,'' said <PERSON> Bahjat </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaber </PERSON>, a police reporter who lives in east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s Maameltein suburb Like many others, he commuted between <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s two sectors before the latest round of fighting `` I have all the fireworks. Some 200 shells explode around my apartment nightly. The house is always shaking like a swing, and I am swinging,'' quipped <PERSON> Jaber </PERSON>, 55. A Greek Catholic bachelor, <PERSON> Jaber </PERSON> does not use the basement shelter of his seaside apartment building because his 92-year-old mother can hardly move. `` I simply ca n't leave her alone.'' When a missile detonated a large gas storage tank at <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> port, winds blew the flame and smoke in the direction of his house, 10 miles north of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. `` I'm lik a roasted chicken,'' he joked to friends on the telephone. The fighting pits army commander Gen. Mily Christian units against an alliance of Syrian troops and Druse Moslem militiamen. It was touched off by an air-and-sea blockade <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> clamped on militia-run illegal ports on March 6 in a bid to reinstate government authority. <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> heads a <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> in the fractured nation's dual government. The Syrians and <LOCATION> Mosmilitia </LOCATION> allies, who recognize the rival Moslem Cbinet of former Prime Minister <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoss </PERSON>, retaliated by sealis to the Christian enclave and blockading its 1 million inhabitts with their bato the sea. Ensuing bouts of savage bombardment have blown hundreds of houses, wrecked power plants, destroyed city water pipes and threatened to crush the nation's infrstructure. Police statistics show an average of 3,000 shells fell on the city and its environs every day of the past three weeks, killing more than 150 people and wounding 500. Mor than 90 have been killed and 300 wounded in easnd the adjoining Christian hinterland. The other casulaties were in the city's Moslem sector and Druse-controlled hills. <PERSON> Nabil </PERSON> <PERSON> Haddad </PERSON>, 38, a <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> grcer, said he has been surviving with his wife aong with 40 neighbors in the candle-lit basement of their 6-story apartment building. `` I death so close. I give up,'' he said at the doorstep of their shelter in east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s poor <LOCATION> Einrict </LOCATION>. `` We're suffocating. I do n't think we're e.'' <PERSON> Haddad </PERSON> opens his store only during morning lulls in shelling. <PERSON> Shukri </PERSON> <PERSON> Lahhoud </PERSON>, a banker who lives posh, hilltop <LOCATION> Rabieh </LOCATION> district on east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s northern flank, was more optimistic. `` We ` to make it,'' he `` I do n't think the world is going to al the annihilation of 1 million Christians. Thisng to stop.'' <PERSON> Lahhoud </PERSON> said he and his neighbors while away the hours in running games of poker and backgamloor underground shelter, which houses a power generator. The city's Moslem sector is virtually a ghost town. Tens of thousands of residents have fled to relative safety in east and south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. Those who stayed behind also spend nights in shelters as soldiers with multibarreled mobile rocket launchers roam around, firing off a barrage, then moving quickly before retaliatory fire comes. Civilians take the punishment. `` It's a dirty trick but no one dares protest it,'' ident who requested anonymity.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ChildDeath     04-06 0204</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Child Death,0208</SECOND>
<HEAD>12-Year-Old Indicted in Murder of Half Brother, Beating of Half Sister</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 12-year-old girl who says she broke under the strain of daily baby-sitting was indicted as an adult Wednesday for allegedly killing her 2-year-old half brother and beating her 15-month-old half sister. After two hours of deliberations, a <LOCATION> Broward </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> grand jury indicted fifth-grader <PERSON> Arva </PERSON> <PERSON> Betts </PERSON> on adult charges of second-degree murder and aggravated child abuse. Investigators were initially baffled on March 14 when they found 2-year-old <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON> strangled to death and his 15-month-old half sister <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON> severely beaten and strangled, but still alive. Two days later, the suspect, who was 11 at the time, was brought into custody. Police said the child confessed to the strangling and beating, saying she was overwhelmed by the responsibility of baby-sitting every day from the time she got home from school untill 11 p.m., when her mother returned from work. <PERSON> Arva </PERSON> did not testify before the the grand jury despite the panel's invitation to appear on her own behalf, said <ORGANIZATION> Broward </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Attorney </ORGANIZATION>'s spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>. Second-degree murder carries a maximum penalty of life in prison. The maximum penalty for aggravated child abuse is 15 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ThinBlueLine 1stLd-Writethru a0838 04-06 0369</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Thin Blue Line, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0838,0376</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prosecutor Who Led Fight Against Adams' Release Is Fired</HEAD>
<UNK>Eds: LEADS with 3 grafs to UPDATE with district attorney confirming
report; INSERTS 1 graf after 12th graf pvs, `Vance said ...' No pickup.</UNK>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The assistant district attorney who led the fight to keep `` The Thin Blue Line'' defendant <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> behind bars was fired Wednesday. <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> was dismissed for violating policies, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Vance </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> was the third prosecutor involved in the case to leave the office this week. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> did not return repeated calls from The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. Other officials at the office declined comment. Over <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>'s objections, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> was released from prison March 22, a few weeks after a state court overturned his conviction for the 1976 slaying of a <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> policeman. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> had spent more than 12 years in prison. The case was examined in <PERSON> Errol </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>' 1988 documentary, `` The Thin Blue Line,'' which questioned evidence in the case. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, who served as an assistant district attorney in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> for 21 years, participated in the original prosecution of <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> was ordered released after the <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Criminal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> said evidence had been suppressed and at least two witnesses lied on the stand. In fighting <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' release, <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> said state District Court Judge <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Baraka </PERSON> and eight of the nine appellate judges were biased in <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' favor. He asked that <PERSON> Baraka </PERSON> be removed from the case. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>'s arguments held up <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' release for one night before another state judge ruled in <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' favor. The day after <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' release, <PERSON> Vance </PERSON> said evidence to retry him was lacking, and the murder charge was dropped. <PERSON> Vance </PERSON> said he'd investigate <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>'s behavior as a personnel matter. In his remarks Wednesday night, <PERSON> Vance </PERSON> said he had nothing but admiration and respect for <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>. `` I found we had a conflict regarding current office policies that simply could not be resolved any other way,'' <PERSON> Vance </PERSON> said. Earlier this week, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Creuzot </PERSON> and <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> resigned. Both had been with the office about six years and worked on <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' case Neither would specify their reasons for resigning, but said they planned to go into private practice.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Shoreham     04-06 0243</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Shoreham,0248</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shoreham Nuclear Power Plant A Step Closer To Dismantling</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELIZABETH EDWARDSEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALBANY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday approved an agreement allowing the state to buy the $ 5.4 billion <LOCATION> Shoreham </LOCATION> nuclear power plant for $ 1 and dismantle it. In approving the deal, worked out earlier this year by Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> and officials of the <ORGANIZATION> Long </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lighting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which owns the plant, the commission authorized rate increases that could result in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> residents paying the highest electric rates in the nation. The panel made permanent a 5.4 percent rate increase granted earlier this year, approved a 5 percent rate increase to go into effect in December, and authorized another 5 percent increase for December 1990. The agreement to close <LOCATION> Shoreham </LOCATION> still must be be approved by the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Long </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> by April 15. Then it is subject to approval by the utility's shareholders and board of directors The higher rates would give <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> Lighting a shot at regaining the financial stability it lost in recent years because of the burdens imposed on it by the ill-fated <LOCATION> Shoreham </LOCATION> project. <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> members, who approved an earlier agreement worked out by <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> and the utility only to the see that deal die because of state legislators' refusal to approve it, said they hoped they were putting the controversial plant behind them.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0224EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Hungary-Romania     04-06 0141</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Hungary-Romania,0144</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hungarian TV Crew Banned From Traveling Through Romania</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Hungarian television crew was barred from traveling through <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the state news agency <ORGANIZATION> MTI </ORGANIZATION> reported. Relations are strained between the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact neighbors over <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s alleged discrimination against its 1.7 million ethnic Hungarians. <ORGANIZATION> MTI </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday that the four-man crew from state television had planned to do a report in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moldavia </LOCATION>, which borders <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Alajos </PERSON> <PERSON> Chrudinak </PERSON>, leader of the crew, reportedly said that he and the others waited for more than an hour Tuesday at the Romanian border station of <PERSON> Bors </PERSON> before they were told they could not enter the country. <ORGANIZATION> MTI </ORGANIZATION> reported that border station commander Maj. <PERSON> Gavril </PERSON> <PERSON> Ardelanu </PERSON> said all staff members of Hungarian television's foreign affairs department were not welcome because of TV programs criticizing Romanian policy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0221EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CastleHeir     04-06 0368</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Castle Heir,0377</SECOND>
<HEAD>Adopted Baron Misses Deadline For Keeping Castle</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FERRYSBURG, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There was no happy ending to the fairy tale-like life that <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Hemmelsbach </PERSON> has lived since being adopted last summer by a childless West German baron. On Wednesday, <PERSON> Hemmelsbach </PERSON> missed a bank's deadline for coming up with $ 3 million to keep the baron's 1,429-year-old castle in the family. The West German bank that has a lien on the 150-room castle and 970-acre estate plans to put the property up for sale. As the adopted son of 76-year-old <PERSON> Baron </PERSON> <PERSON> Freiherr </PERSON> <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> vonLiebieg </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hemmelsbach </PERSON> stood to inherit the castle and surrounding vineyards on the <LOCATION> Mosel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> at the foot of the <LOCATION> Eifel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> in southwestern <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. The value of the castle and estate is estimated at $ 10 million. But <PERSON> Hemmelsbach </PERSON> said he has something more important than a castle. `` I still have this wonderful birthright and a wonderful father and I plan to be a good baron and good son,'' <PERSON> Hemmelsbach </PERSON> said Wednesday. `` I think we're all disappointed, but the baron has never asked about the castle. He only wants to know when I am coming back to visit.'' VonLiebieg selected <PERSON> Hemmelsbach </PERSON>, in part because of his German heritage, from more than 10,000 people worldwide who responded to the baron's televised plea for an heir on the syndicated show `` A Current Affair'' last June. <PERSON> Hemmelsbach </PERSON> did n't know at the time that he would be asked to save the family's deteriorating estate, which was taken over by the bank when a German businessman who had purchased the castle from vonLiebieg defaulted on a loan. The baron has not lived in the castle for more than a dozen years. He lives with his wife in a nearby villa. <PERSON> Hemmelsbach </PERSON>, a 57-year-old businessman, said he will continue to work to purchase the castle for as long as it remains for sale, but about 18 private and corporate investors, including a German hotel chain have lined up to purchase the estate from the bank. `` I've been a rainbow chaser all my life,'' said <PERSON> Hemmelsbach </PERSON>, who lives in the <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Ferrysburg </LOCATION>. `` I guess I'll always continue to do that _ I'm too old to do otherwise.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0224EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-06 0837</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0870</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BIRMINGHAM, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Duchess of <PERSON> York </PERSON> said eating veggies helped her lose weight, and she made the revelation in, of all places, a chocolate factory filled with temptation. The 29-year-old wife of Prince <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, who in August gave birth to their first child, Princess <PERSON> Beatrice </PERSON>, said losing weight has been a nightmare. The staff at the <ORGANIZATION> Cadbury </ORGANIZATION> chocolate plant in <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION> had praised the duchess for the weight she had lost. `` I eat raw vegetables _ lots of raw vegetables. I am still trying but it is very hard,'' the former <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> said. Confronted with wall-to-wall chocolates during her five-hour visit to the factory, the duchess refused to give in to temptation. She did take home a box of cream eggs and some handmade chocolates called Royal Household. Royal aides refused to speculate on who would eat them.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CONCORD, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cartoonist <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Larson </PERSON> has drawn his first album cover _ for jazz guitar legend <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON>, who paid for the art with a few music lessons. `` I've drawn so many ` Far Side' cartoons while listening to <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> ... that I probably owe him a credit line on most of my work _ let alone a cover,'' <PERSON> Larson </PERSON> wrote in a note on the `` Doggin' Around'' album Released Wednesday by independent <ORGANIZATION> Concord </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION>, the album has a cover showing the inside of a nightclub called `` The Stuffed Cat.'' Inside, upright-standing dogs, common characters in <PERSON> Larson </PERSON>'s wacky cartoons, are being served drinks by poodle waitresses and listening to two dog musicians on stage On the tables, a sign reads: `` Please keep table barking to a minimum.'' A sign with a fireplug and an arrow hangs on one wall. <PERSON> Larson </PERSON> agreed to do the cover if <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> offered to teach him a few tricks of the trade, said company spokeswoman <PERSON> Merrilee </PERSON> <PERSON> Trost </PERSON>. The record company, 45 miles east of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, flew <PERSON> Larson </PERSON> to <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON>' home in <LOCATION> Fairfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ark. </LOCATION>, where the two spent two weeks playing together.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rock' n' roll promoter <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> won a major legal round when an appeals court threw out attempts to revive a 22-year-old lawsuit over the management of the Jefferson Airplane music group. The state Court of Appeal on Wednesday rejected arguments by <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> that a lower court was wrong to dismiss <PERSON> Katz </PERSON>'s 1967 case. <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> contended that <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> had agreed to an indefinite extension to bring the case to trial. The issue involved <PERSON> Katz </PERSON>'s claim that <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> had improperly replaced <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> as manager of the group. <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> alleged inducement of breach of contract and improper interference. After a 1975 trial to determine the status of the contracts, the court set a second phase of the trial for 1979. That phase continued with an open end while <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> tried to settle damage issues. The damage talks were unsuccessful and the action was dismissed in 1987. Members of the Airplane, which had its heyday in the late'60s and early 70s, are considear to record an album.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 D <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Leary </PERSON>, the psychedelic drug guru of the 1960s, says pons _ not activists like himself _ represented two decades ago. <PERSON> Leary </PERSON>, 68, joined'60s activists <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Seal </PERSON> <PERSON> Abbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> in a panel discussion at <ORGANIZATION> Vanderbilt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> oesday night. He said the three were not part of the countere but worked for beliefs the majority of <LOCATION> Americon </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> were the counterculture,'' <PERSON> Leary </PERSON> said, referring to the presidents at the time.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SOUTH BEND, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> says he has n't gotten over the fear of being arrested for his protests against homelessness and nuclear weapons testing in the <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> desert. `` I'm the biggest rd I know,'' he told 400 <ORGANIZATION> Universof </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Notre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dame </ORGANIZATION> students at a lecture Tuesday. `` I get so ... scared that I weep. I do n't know what else to do.' The actual arrest comes as a rebecause you know you have done all you can do non-violently as ng,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> remembered an old friend and adviser an presented an award in his memor <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> cardiologist. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> awarded <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurst </PERSON> the third-annual <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Theodore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> E. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cummings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prize </ORGANIZATION> for Outstanding Contributions in Cardiovascular Disease. The honor included a gold medal and $ 25,000 award. <PERSON> Hurst </PERSON>, an author, professor and former chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> of the <ORGANIZATION> Emory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, made <ORGANIZATION> Emory </ORGANIZATION> `` one of the world's great centers of cardiovascular research,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told about 350 people at <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION> for the ceremony Wednesday. <PERSON> Hurst </PERSON>, 70, considered an expert in electrocardiography, served as cardiologist to President <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> for several years. <PERSON> Cummings </PERSON>, who died in 1982, was a <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> businessman and philanthropist who served as a friend and adviser to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> when was governor. <PERSON> Cummings </PERSON> also served as ambassador to <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> in 1981.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0228EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Smoking-Weight     04-06 0503</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Smoking-Weight,0534</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cigarette Smoking Boosts Metabolism, Burns 100 Calories a Day</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL Q. HANEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Smoking makes the body burn more calories, according to a study that helps explain one of life's biological injustices: why people put on weight when they give up cigarettes. The research publi care of about 100 calories a day for the typical smoker. Smokers typically weigh five to 10 pounds less than non-smokers, and they usually put on that much weight when they break the habit. The question has been why this happens. Part of the reason is that folks often eat more when they stop smoking, and some studies have shown they are more likely to crave sugar. While preliminary evidence suggested that they also burned calories more slowly, many experts thought this effect was small. In the past, scientists have studied this by watching changes in metabolism when people smoke while sitting still. In the lastest work, researchers decided to see what happened to metabolism when people smoked while moving around, just as they do in real lifeought it was conceivable we would n't see any effect,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>, who directed the <ORGANIZATION> Universityrgh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> study that's published in the New England Journal of Medicine. `` To our surprise, whe opposite, that it was much more enhanced. It reversed our thinking. The implication is that the metabolic eing -RRB- is much more important than everyone else has considered.' When staying ng increases metabolism by about 5 percent. But it raises it by about 12 percent. Among other things, this could help explain hy some people balloon when they quit cigaretteothers manage to hold their weight steady. `` If people tenn coffee breaks or while relaxing at home watching TV, they wo n't gain as much weight'' when they quit, said <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>. `` Those who smoke while active are likely to be thinnero begin with because of their smoking.'' So they risk putting on more when they stop smoking.. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rigotti </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> noted that some people, especiall keep smoking because they are afraid of gaining weight. `` Until our cultural obsession wih slenderness abates,'' she wrote, `` we must pay more attention to the way weight gain impedes efforts to stop smoking if we are to continue the progress of the past quarter century toward a smoke-free society.'' Exprts note that while obesity is dangerous, smokers should not leof gaining weight keep them from quitting. `` Your health risk is immeasurably improved whestop smoking, no matter how much weight you gain,'' said <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>. He also pointed out that people can offset their newly slowed metabolisttle extra exercise. `` All you would need to do is walk about a mile extra er that,'' <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> said. `` That' hard as it sounds.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0249EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WhereFDRSat Bjt   04-06 0621</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Where FDR Sat, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Glitter, Elegance of White House Past is Displayed at Smithsonian</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nearly forgotten mantelpiece that formed the backdrop for <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>'s famous `` fireside chats'' is the surprise feature of a new <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION> exhibition recreating the glitter and elegance of the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> in a bygone era. The permanent installation in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> History </ORGANIZATION>, entitled `` The Ceremonial Court,'' shows the front hallway of the White House as it appeared from a 1903 restoration until 1952. The 1903 restoration, conducted by <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> architect <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Follen </PERSON> <PERSON> McKim </PERSON>, took six months and cost about $ 500,000. The Smithsonian display required more than four years of planning and eight months to install, at a cost of nearly $ 1 million. The project was underwritten largely by a grant from <ORGANIZATION> Sears </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Roebuck </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> `` This is a permanent statement of the highest and most elegant reaches of American craftsmanship,'' said museum director <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. The White House, he said, represented `` a courtly life, a life of high style. It's always opening night at court ... the night for grand occasions, for getting out the very best china.'' Among the items in the exhibition, which opens today, is the mantelpiece from the fireplace in the Diplomatic Reception Room that was the scene of <ORGANIZATION> FDR </ORGANIZATION>'s radio broadcasts to a Depression-weary public in the 1930s. When <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>'s successor, <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>, undertook a major renovation of the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> in 1952, the mantelpiece and other unwanted objects were donated to the <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION>, which crated them for storage in its sprawling warehouses in suburban <LOCATION> Suitland </LOCATION>, Md. There the mantelpiece gathered dust, its existence recorded only on a Smithsonian catalog card, until the pile of crates marked `` White House'' was discovered nearly 30 years later by <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Carrigan </PERSON>, the museum's newly appointed assistant director for exhibits. In that moment, <PERSON> Carrigan </PERSON> envisioned a permanent museum exhibition of historic White House treasures drawn from the <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION>'s vast collections. The centerpiece of the resulting display is a recreation of the front hallway, stretching from the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Room </LOCATION> to the State Dining Room, as it appeared beginning with <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>'s presidency. While the hallway reflects the formal, chandeliered elegance of the turn-of-the-century White House, there are hints of the boisterous Teddy Roosevelt household. Just outside a trompe l'oeil painting of the State Dining Room is the family elevator. Inside is a mannequin of one of <ORGANIZATION> Roosevelt </ORGANIZATION>'s six children with their pet pony, <PERSON> Algonquin </PERSON>, which once was smuggto greet a bedrivelt At the other end of the hall is a second trompe l'oeil painting of the main stairway, with <PERSON> Archie </PERSON> and brother <PERSON> Kermit </PERSON> playing at the bottom with a paint set and their pet macaw, one of a menagerie that also included three rats, a terrier, a kitten, a flying squirrel and a green snake named <PERSON> Emily </PERSON> <PERSON> Spinach </PERSON>. Among the objects in adjoining rooms is a gold Steinway grand piano that was donated to the White House in 1930 and used until 1939. The piano, still being restored by <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION> conservators, was richly decorated brtist <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dewing </PERSON> with an allegorical painting, acanthus garlands and scrollwork. The exhibit features cases of White House children's dolls and toys, inaugural gowns worn by first ladies since <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> china and silver used by first families sinceeorge and <PERSON> Martha </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>. Presidential leisure-time memorabilia on display include <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s leather dispatch case and English-made telescope, a chess set used by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Quincy </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Hardin </PERSON> and balls monogrammed `` WGH,'' <PERSON> Chester </PERSON> <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON>'s silver cigar cutter, <PERSON> Ulysses </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>'s well-chewed <PERSON> Meerschaum </PERSON> pipe and a life preserver from <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s yacht, `` Honey Fitz.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0248EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     04-06 0400</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0415</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAPEER, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A dead rat might not be worth a rat's whisker in <LOCATION> Lapeer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> soon, or even the 10-cent bounty allowed by an obscure state law The 1915 law provides the bounty to anyone who kills a rat and turns it over in a state of `` good preservation'' to their municipal clerk. The clerk is to burn the rat's head and authorize payment through the county. But the law also allows county boards of commissioners to rescind the bounty, a move that <LOCATION> Lapeer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Clerk <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Thick </PERSON> said in a recent interview that she would welcome. `` I'm sure they have not done that, but we'll be doing that soon,'' she said. `` It'll be presented to the Board of Commissioners immediately.'' The bounty law surfaced recently during the celebration of Marathon Township's 150th anniversary of incorporation. Township Clerk <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Ring </PERSON> recalled receiving an anonymous letter in 1985 from a resident who said he had killed 76 rats and wanted to know whether he had to cut off their heads before receiving his $ 7.60 bounty. `` I went to the board meeting wearing surgical gloves that month,'' Ring said. `` I actually had visions of a sack of rats appearing on the front doorstep.'' But the rat slayer never has come forward. Marathon Township, meanwhile, also has on its books a $ 5 bounty for wolves, in effect since 1839.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SHARON, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Want a stop sign of your very own? Tired of replacing stolen traffic signs, this town has decided to put them up for sale. `` If we made them available, people might chose to buy them rather than requisition them at midnight,'' said Public Works Superintendent <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sulik </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sulik </PERSON> blames teen-agers for the epidemic of disappearing signs. Despite efforts to put them high enough to be out of reach, more than 70 signs were stolen last year, costing the town more than $ 3,000, he said. <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON>, located about 15 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, makes its own street signs and will charge sign buyers $ 20 each. The town buys its traffic signs from a <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> company and will sell the popular stop signs for $ 27 and speed limit signs for $ 20, <PERSON> Sulik </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Sulik </PERSON> took out an ad in a newspaper and plans to buy another in the high school newspaper. So far, though, only one adult has ordered a sign.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0253EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Gorbachev     04-06 0501</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Gorbachev,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Skeptical of Gorbachev Position</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, disappointed that <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is not withdrawing military support from <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, is accusing the Soviet president of empty rhetoric regarding Central American peace. `` While his words about not exporting revolution are welcomed, they are not matched by deeds which would give those words credence,'' White House Press Secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said Wednesday, referring to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s denunciation of the export of revolution. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s comments in his speech in <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION> on Tuesday conflicted with the policy of Cuban President <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, who supports the spread of revolutionary movements. But, in a written statement read by <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> called on <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to back up his statements about wanting demilitarized peace zones in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, by discontinuing military assistance to the leftist government of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. `` Today, we call upon the Soviets to cut off their half-billion-dollar annual military aid to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. The Soviets continue to pour arms into <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, a country whose army is already larger than those of all their neighbors combined,'' he said. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said continued Soviet activity in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> will affect U.S.-Soviet relations, but declined to specify how the administration might express its displesure. `` We've never made linkage threats,'' he said. `` But we have always said these are the kinds of things that influence the relationship between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.'' A day earlier, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> had said Soviet spokesman <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON>'s statements against the export of revolution appeared to be a positive sign. But on Wednesday he was more resng, `` We can hold out a little optimism on the basis of the words,'' but that the administration is looking for deedsto back them up. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials looked to the Soviet leader's visit to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> as an opportunity for him to change direction in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had written him urging Soviet withdrawal of military support from the leftist Nicaraguan government, and a halt to Cuban and Nicaraguan support for leftist guerrillas in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. But <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, in his Tuesday speech to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION>, said <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> will not has support for <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> as long <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> continues military assistance to other governments in the region. Fitzwatert comparable to the Soviet assistance because the U.S.-backed nations `` are not involved in subversion of their neighbors.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials estimate the Soviets shipped more than $ 500 million in military aid last year to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and gave <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> the same amount in economic asse the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has bankrolled the Contra rebels fighting to oust the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s shift to a diplomatic course means <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to the Contras is now non-military. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> this decade totals some $ 3.5 billion, and the administration accuses the Soviets of supporting the Salvadoran rebels through <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. Critics of the administration policy, meanwhile, cite widespreder the U.S.-backed regime.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0308EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HeartStudy     04-06 0344</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Heart Study,0353</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Rules Ban Conflict of Interest in Medical Study</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Doctors participating in a major study of treatment after coronary bypass surgery will be barred from owning stock in the companies whose medicines are being tested, according to guidelines released today. The rules are intended to prevent any conflict of interest that might sway researchers when they analyze the results. Doctors who drew up the guidelines note that there are no widely accepted standards to prevent conflicts of interest for scientists doing research with products that have commercial value. `` We believe that a defined conflict-of-interest policy will protect the integrity of the study and the credibility of investigators as the trial is scrutinized by the scientific community and the public,'' the organizers wrote. The rules were drawn up by Dr. <PERSON> Bernadine </PERSON> <PERSON> Healy </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clinic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> and colleagues from the <ORGANIZATION> Montreal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Baylor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. They were published in today's <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>, along with an editorial by its editor, Dr. <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Relman </PERSON>. `` These are laudable voluntary guidelines, which for the time being other clinical investigators would do well to adopt,'' he wrote. The seven-year, federally funded study is called the Post Coronary Artery Bypass Graft Surgery Clinicial Trial. It will examine the effects of drug therapy and cholesterol lowering for people undergoing heart bypass surgery. During this surgery, doctors reroute blood around clogged heart arteries. However, the detours often become plugged after a few years, and the study is intended to see if treatment can keep this from happening. The study will test drugs produced by three companies. According to the new rules, all key researchers will be prohibited from owning stock in the drug companies or working for them as paid consultants. The ban also will extend to their spouses and dependents. Authors of the rules note that the outcome of this study could affect the care of millions of Americans undergoing bypass surgery.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0309EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PollClosings     04-06 0501</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poll Closings,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Uniform Poll Closing Time Clears House by Broad Margin</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Polling places across the nation would close at a uniform time in presidential elections under a plan on its way to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> after winning House approval. The bill, approved 238-154 on Wednesday, is designed to reduce the effect of outcome projections made hours before the polls close in the Wet and in some late-closing states elsewhere. `` The importance of Western votes for president is being diminished just because of where we live,'' Rep. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyden </PERSON>, D-Ore., declared The measure has passed the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> twice before only to languish in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, but lawmakers say <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> prospects are better this year. The bill calls for closing times of 9 p.m. EST, 8 p.m. CST and 7 p.m. MST. In presidential election years only, the switch from daylight-saving time to standard time in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> time zone would be postponed a maximum of two weeks. Polls there would close at 7 p.m. PDT. Under the timetable, polling places would shut their doors simultaneously, making it impossible for results from some states to indicate a winner and influence turnout elsewhere. Only presidential years would be covered by the bill, which would take effect in 1992 and would not apply to <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. The plan is designed to dovetail with a 1985 agreement under which major television networks said they would voluntarily refrain from projecting election results within a state until the polls close there. It is unclear if local races are actually affected by early projections. House Rules Committee Chairman <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., however, said Tuesday that he believed the phenomenon may have contributed to the 1980 defeat of Rep. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON>, D-Ore., then chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> Either way, lawmakers say voter frustration because of such projections is basically unhealthy. `` It's unfair to either party that the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> would announce the final result of an election to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> before the final votes are counted,'' Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Quillen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Tenn </LOCATION>., told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> The only critic of the bill to take the floor, Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Frenzel </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Minn </LOCATION>., described it as `` a <PERSON> Rube </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> device that will louse up the states, cause them a great deal of confusion and travail. He said it actually could reduce turnout by shortening voting hours on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> and possibly prompting <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> states to open the polls at later hours than they do now. Rep. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Swift </PERSON>, D-Wash., the measure's sponsor, said studies have shown an earlier poll closing will prompt voters to vote earlier and thus the fear of a drop in turnout `` is simply not substantiated by the facts. The extension of daylight-saving time in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> zone would take place only in presidential election years. It would last for a maximum of two weeks and apply to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> as well as the <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> panhandle but not the rest of <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0301EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Stroke-Cholesterol     04-06 0357</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stroke-Cholesterol,0366</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Links Low Cholesterol and High Blood Pressure with Strokes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The risk of bleeding strokes is significantly higher than usual among men who have very low cholesterol levels but high blood pressure, a study published today concludes. The research found that men with blood cholesterol levels under 160 were three times more likely than those with higher cholesterol levels to suffer bleeding strokes. But this increase appeared to be explained entirely by a substantially higher risk in those with high blood pressure. The researchers said the findings should not be taken as an excuse to stop trying to lower cholesterol to prevent heart disease. Of the 350,977 men studied, 3,986 had unusually low cholesterol levels _ under 160 milligrams per deciliter of blood, and diastolic blood pressures above 90, which is considered to be elevated. In this group, there were nine bleeding strokes, a rate that works out to 23 strokes for every 10,000 men. By comparison, among men with low cholesterol but low blood pressure as well, there were just under two bleeding strokes per 10,000 people, the same as for all men with low blood pressure. The men with low cholesterol levels did not face any unusual risk of strokes resulting from blood clots inside the brain. These are more common than bleeding strokes. The men with low cholesterol also had a sharply lower risk of dying from all kinds of cardiovascular disease. For those with cholesterols between 140 and 160, there were 46 cardiovascular deaths per 10,000 people, compared with 83 cardiovascular deaths for the total group. The study was based on the Multiple Risk Factor Intervention Trial. The latest analysis, by Dr. <PERSON> Hiroyasu </PERSON> <PERSON> Iso </PERSON> and colleagues at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION>, was published in today's New England Journal of Medicine. `` Our findings should not be taken as a reason to defer the establishment of programs to lower serum -LRB- blood -RRB- cholesterol levels in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> population in order to prevent coronary heart disease,'' the researchers concluded. They speculated that very low cholesterol may weaken the walls of arteries in the head, while high blood pressure makes them break.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0309EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Budget     04-06 0433</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Budget Talks Stuck on Capital Gains</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> says President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s insistence on cutting the capital gains tax is a `` thorn in our negotiations'' as <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and congressional bargainers try to complete a budget agreement. `` I think we're confused,'' Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ill </LOCATION>., said Wednesday night, after a meeting with <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> `` We're a room of good intentions,'' he said, but, `` there's a difficult thorn in our negotiations and that's capital gains.'' <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> and <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> have been meeting with key members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to craft a plan for meeting the goal of a $ 100 billion deficit in fiscal 1990, which begins Oct. 1. About $ 28 billion in either new revenues or spending restraint would be needed to meet that goal, according to White House estimates. As part of the deficit reduction plan in his fiscal 1990 budget, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposed cutting the tax rate on capital gains to 15 percent, about in half. The president contends the rate cut would raise about $ 4.8 billion in revenue. However, congressional estimates show the reduction would be a big revenue loser in the long run and, Democrats contend, the rich would benefit the most from the tax break. Although his own budget included several billion dollars in tax increases and new user fees, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> contends those did not violate his campaign pledge against any new taxes. With Democrats opposing the capital gains scheme, coming up with a deficit-reduction plan has proven difficult since alternative tax revenues or more spending cuts would be needed. Rep. <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, D-Calif., the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> chairman, has proposed in the talks that half the deficit reduction, about $ 14 billion, come from revenues _ a combination of taxes, sales of government assets, and new user fees <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s revenue proposals produced about the same amount, but included the claimed capital gains influx He said Wednesday that resolution of the tax issue is crucial to the success of the talks. <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON> said he was not discouraged, but it would be difficult. `` We're going to continue to talk ... but I do n't know that we're going to meet any of the deadlines,'' he said. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has an April 15 deadline for completing the budget. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> and <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> declined to comment on the specifics of the meeting. `` It's just part of the budget process,'' <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> said. Asked if he had brought something new to discuss, he said, `` I did n't bring a thing.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0325EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TransportationPosts     04-06 0340</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Transportation Posts,330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Transportation Chiefs Selected</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An academician and a mass transit administrator are President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s choices to become the respective heads of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, sources say. The White House has told the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> and lawmakers that it intends to appoint <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Larson </PERSON>, 60, a professor who was secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> under former Gov. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>, to run the <ORGANIZATION> FHWA </ORGANIZATION>, department and congressional officials said Wednesday. Meanwhile, the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> has told the same lawmakers and <ORGANIZATION> DOT </ORGANIZATION> officials that <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Clymer </PERSON>, vice chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Southeastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION>, will be named administrator of UMTA. <PERSON> Clymer </PERSON>, 41, an accountant in <LOCATION> Swarthmore </LOCATION>, is on the policy-making board of <ORGANIZATION> SEPTA </ORGANIZATION>, which oversees buses, trolleys, subways and commuter lines for an average daily ridership of 1.2 million passengers in the five-county <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> area. <PERSON> Larson </PERSON> was <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> transportation secretary for eight years under <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>, now the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney general. Responsible for the nation's fourth largest highway system, <PERSON> Larson </PERSON> oversaw an agency with roughly 12,500 employees and a $ 3 billion annual budget. A favorite of <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>'s, <PERSON> Larson </PERSON> began a $ 1 billion bridge repair program and used merit hiring and a goal-oriented management style to try to rebuild a department scarred by scandal from the administration of former Gov. <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Shapp </PERSON>. <PERSON> Larson </PERSON> left state government with <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> in 1986, and is now a special assistant for economic affairs to the president of <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, where he had previously been a faculty member and administrator for 17 years. <PERSON> Larson </PERSON> declined to comment on the federal post, and <ORGANIZATION> SEPTA </ORGANIZATION> officials said <PERSON> Clymer </PERSON> was in a board meeting and unavailable for comment. The highway administration monitors the federal aid program for highway construction, administers a bridge replacement program, and oversees safety programs. <ORGANIZATION> UMTA </ORGANIZATION> assists state and local governments in improving mass transportation systems. <ORGANIZATION> FHWA </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> UMTA </ORGANIZATION> are the last two major federal transportation posts to be filled. The announcement is expected within a week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0326EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Gorbachev-MilitaryAid     04-06 0717</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gorbachev-Military Aid,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Analysts Disappointed by Gorbachev Speech</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s call for an end to the `` export of revolution and counterrevolution'' to <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> disappointed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> analysts who were hoping for a stronger sign that the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> would curtail its military aid to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration officials, pursuing a more conciliatory Central American policy than President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, agreed with congressional leaders last month not to seek military aid for the Contra guerrillas of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. They hoped that in response, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> would curtail the estimated $ 6 billion in aid the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> sends to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, the $ 1 billion in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> aid to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc assistance to leftist guerrillas in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. `` While his words about not exporting revolution are welcome, they are not matched by deeds which would give his words credence,'' <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said Wednesday. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, meeting in <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION> with <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, scolded Western media for reporting a Cuban-Soviet rift and gave no indication that the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> would be cutting its aid to the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> island, estimated at about $ 6 billion a year. `` As in the past, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> have a common approach to the key problems of international affairs,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said. `` The most immediate task is to solve so-called regional conflicts. `` We are resolutely against any theories and doctrines justifying the export of revolution or counterrevolution, and all forms of interference in the affairs of sovereign nations,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said. On Tuesday, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> had said that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would welcome `` the reduction of Soviet military support in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> or if they mean that Soviet surrogates would cease supporting'' insurgents in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. Instead, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> condemned <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> `` meddling in Afghan affairs.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has been sending an estimated $ 500 million a year in covert aid to the anti-communist guerrillas of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, helping secure the negotiated withdrawal of Soviet troops last February. Many Americans have engaged in `` wishful thinking,'' hoping that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> would seek to ease economic problems at home by curtailing aid to revolutionary movements abroad, particularly <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiarda </PERSON>, a political scientist at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION>. But `` there is no evidence whatsoever that the Soviets have started to reduce military aid to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> or to the rebels in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Wiarda </PERSON>. Although <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> may be pressuring <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> in private meetings to tone down his revolutionary rhetoric, and may ultimately curtail Soviet aid to leftist insurgencies, `` I think it unrealistic to expect <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to change those policies quickly,'' said <PERSON> Wiarda </PERSON>. The chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> applauded <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s statement on the export of revolution, while at the same time criticizing <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>'s past policies. `` I hope <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> follows <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s advice,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION> `` Certainly, much of our trouble in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> comes from <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> activities. If they can be closed down, this will help peace to come to that troubled region.'' A former Cuban diplomat now living in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Benemelis </PERSON>, said <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> `` expectations were too high for this meeting.'' `` I think there is definitely conflict between <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, but that it will take some time'' to become public, said <PERSON> Benemelis </PERSON>, who worked in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> for <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> before defecting in 1980. <PERSON> Benemelis </PERSON> has seen hints that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will reduce aid to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> as well as pressure <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> to curtail military interference in other countries, but does n't think the trend will become obvious until both countries enter their next five-year economic period in 1991. `` Since <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> took power, the Soviets have been asking the Cubans to fulfill their annual trade agreements. <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> has had problems, for example, filling his sugar quota. He has not been doing it,'' he said. <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, who opposes the type of political reforms <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is pressing in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, said Tuesday that no such changes are needed in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. `` But if Soviet aid was reduced, <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> would face a political crisis,'' said <PERSON> Benemelis </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> leader, who has developed strong ties to the Soviet military and intelligence agencies over the decades, may be biding his time, hoping that conservatives in those organizations will force <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> from power, said <PERSON> Benemelis </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> is betting on the opposition,'' said <PERSON> Benemelis </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Brumley </PERSON> covers national security affairs for The Associated Press.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0703EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Visas     04-06 0701</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Visas,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Seeks Change in Law to Ease Soviet Emigrant Surge</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is seeking changes in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> law to allow up to 150,000 Soviets to immigrate to this country over the next five years after a flood of visa applications caught the government off guard. The adminstration has been the target of criticism from <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> for its tangled approach to the flood of applications, coming primarily from Soviet Jews. More than 4,000 Jews were allowed to leave the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> last month, the highest total in 10 years. For years, the administration has demanded that the Soviets loosen their stranglehold on emigrant applications, but once the flood began under Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, the exodus appeared to overwhelm <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials. In order to remedy the situation, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> announced on Wednesday that the agency had sent legislation to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to allow 30,000 immigrant visas per year over a period of five years for those people `` whose admission would be in our foreign policy interest,'' said spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON>. While the spokesman said the primary beneficiaries of the new legislation `` are likely to be Soviet citizens,'' the law could be used for other nationalities. `` We're trying to make sure we take care of everybody from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> who wants to come in,'' <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> said. But Rep. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, D-Conn., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on immigration, refugees and international law, said the administration proposal does n't deal adequately with the problem of Soviet Jewish refugees `` It creates an unprecedented ` pick and choose' immigration policy,'' <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. `` It allows the president to choose people from different areas who are not immigrants or refugees.'' After his subcommittee holds a hearing today on Soviet refugees, <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> said, he plans to introduce legislation that would deal with the Soviet Jewish refugee situation `` narrowly, expeditiously and with adequate resources for resettlement.'' <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> says that in order to help clear up the backlog of Soviet visa applicants in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, he is sending additional inspectors to both cities to help speed up the processing. More than 19,000 Soviets are waiting to be interviewed at the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> for permission to enter the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as refugees, and another 7,000 are waiting in temporary quarters near <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>. The current rate of Soviet applications has been running about 4,000 a month. At that rate, the allocated refugee slots were due to run out shortly. Those being denied access under the refugee quotas were offered parolee status, but that did not give them government funding, nor did it allow the applicants to apply eventually for citizenship. Last summer, the backup problem was exacerbated by a change in the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> policy that ordered <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> to determine refugee status for Soviets case-by-case rather than as a group. That is true for other refugee applicants. As a stop-gap measure, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> in January shifted 7,000 unused slots meant for Vietnamese refugees to accommodate the Soviet overflow. Although some estimates project about 40,000 Soviet applicants this year, the administration had budgeted for only half that number. In a statement, Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said the legislation was not specific to nationality in order to provide the president with some `` flexibility'' in case he wanted to apply it to another nation at some other point. He pointed out that the law could apply to <LOCATION> Vietnamese </LOCATION> people who obtained exit visas from their homeland but do not qualify for refugee status under current immigration law. All immigrants have to prove that they would not become a ward of the state by showing that they had a job offer or some other means of financial support, <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> said. The new legislation does not contain any request for funding for the additional immigrants, although the White House has requested $ 100 million from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in supplemental funding for migration and refugee assistance. <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> said the administration also hoped that voluntary agencies would be able to help make up the shortfall. As well, he added, `` We're hopeful that friends and relatives in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would be able to provide such assistance.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FatalFish Bjt   04-06 0554</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fatal Fish, Bjt,0571</SECOND>
<HEAD>Death-Defying Dining Is Here _ Fugu Comes To America</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American diners with a death wish can now risk sushi-cide with fugu, a seafood delicacy that becomes the last supper for 100 Japanese each year. The raw fish arrived in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> last week, appearing on the menus of seven <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> restaurants and making the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> the only country outside <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> where fugu is found. But the man who brought the gourmet delight stateside promised Wednesday this fugu could n't hurt a fly, unlike the badly prepared fugu that's fatal to half the people who eat it. Every year about 100 Japanese eat a fatal fugu meal. `` There is no danger at all,'' said a confident <PERSON> Nobuyoshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuraoka </PERSON>, owner of Restaurant Nippon in midtown <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>. `` In the 50 years since the war, there is no single instance of poisoning from the tiger puffer fish prepared by a licensed chef in the city of <LOCATION> Shimonoseki </LOCATION>.'' With that in mind, all 265 pounds of fugu flown frozen into <LOCATION> John </LOCATION> <LOCATION> F. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> was prepared for delivery in that Japanese city. <PERSON> Kuraoka </PERSON> stressed its safety, but tales of fugu past provide another picture. Fugu has been a taste treat in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> for more than 2,000 years. There are 15 different kinds of fugu, all prepared from puffer fish. If not properly cleaned, the fish can be fatal _ its entrails, liver and ovaries contain the deadly toxin tetrodotoxin. The removal of the dangerous organs is handled by special chefs in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> with at least 13 years' experience. To insure smooth sailing with this first fugu shipment, <PERSON> Kuraoka </PERSON> had a chef with 53 years experience, <PERSON> Sakae </PERSON> <PERSON> Hata </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Shimonoseki </LOCATION>, handle inspection in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and upon arrival here. `` No other fish is treated as strictly as this fugu today. Inspectors at <LOCATION> Shimonoseki </LOCATION> observed the whole process,'' said <PERSON> Kuraoka </PERSON>. The go-ahead for importation was given in November 1988 after a year of intense negotiations between the two countries, said <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Lecos </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. Fugu now will be allowed into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> up to three times per year between September and March when the fish are in season. Fugu had been on the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION>'s automatic detention list for eight years, <PERSON> Lecos </PERSON> said. The ban made <PERSON> Kuraoka </PERSON> a man with a mission: bringing fugu to this country. `` I was asked by three or four food critics in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to bring it in, and by the Japanese people staying in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Kuraoka </PERSON>. `` They miss fugu so much.'' Why would anyone miss raw fish that much? `` It has a very mysterious taste, profound and unforgettable,'' explained <PERSON> Kuraoka </PERSON>, who charges between $ 35 and $ 60 per person for a fugu sashimi platter, $ 50 a plate for fugu hors d'oeuvres. His opinion was not exactly echoed by two women in the restaurant who'd tried the dish and lived to tell about it. `` Bland,'' offered one. `` Somewhere between squid and fluke,'' said the other. Nevertheless, <PERSON> Kuraoka </PERSON> was confident fugu would find its place in the American market. `` The tiger puffer fish is the best delicacy in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` It's a huge fish, a beautiful fish. This is our very best and also our most expensive. ... I'm very happy and very proud.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0333EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Airline-Pot     04-06 0388</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Airline-Pot,0400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Air Jamaica Jet Seized With 3,600 Pounds of Pot</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD COLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Customs officials warned <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> to intensify its anti-drug efforts after the agency seized an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jamaica </ORGANIZATION> jetliner with nearly two tons of marijuana. `` Security procedures on <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jamaica </ORGANIZATION> are dismal at best,'' <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheehan </PERSON> said Wednesday. `` We hope -LRB- this -RRB- seizure will attract their attention.'' Inspectors found 3,595 pounds of marijuana packed into two unlisted containers in the cargo hold of the Airbus A-300 that had flown from <LOCATION> Kingston </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Sheehan </PERSON> said. `` You could smell it from 50 feet away,'' he said. `` We just can not comprehend how the Jamaicans could not have discovered it, and allowed it to leave the country.'' Under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> law, the plane was seized and government-owned <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jamaica </ORGANIZATION> could be liable for a fine of $ 28.7 million. Impounded aircraft usually are released after payment of a small percentage of the penalty. Larger marijuana shipments have been intercepted on ships and cargo planes, but Tuesday's seizure was the most within memory aboard a scheduled commercial airliner, <PERSON> Sheehan </PERSON> said. As customs officials Wednesday were announcing that find, three men carrying shoulder bags with a total of 60 pounds of pot were nabbed on another Air <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> flight here, <PERSON> Sheehan </PERSON> said. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Heavey </PERSON>, customs regional director, said the plane seizure marked the 130th time since 1980 that shipments were stopped on <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jamaica </ORGANIZATION> flights. Agents have intercepted a total of almost 9 tons of the drug. `` Customs is very concerned that _ despite the rhetoric and the propaganda that we've been receiving from <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> _ the security is almost totally ineffective,'' <PERSON> Heavey </PERSON> said. `` We've got to do more to stop the use of <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jamaica </ORGANIZATION> aircraft as conveyances to smuggle marijuana.'' He said theency was particularly incensed that the two large cargo containers were not not on the flight manifest. Inside the containers, agents found 88 cardboard boxes, including 29 filled with clothes and the rest stuffed with marijuana. Inspectors did not immediately grab the drug, owing it to be picked up at the airport. They then followed a rental truck carrying the pot to south <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, stopping it and arresting the driver, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Muller </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, after he appeared to be taking evasive maneuvers, authorities said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0337EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Turtles     04-06 0215</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Turtles,0220</SECOND>
<HEAD>Malaysian Legislature Enacts Law Against Eating Turtle Eggs</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In an anti-extinction effort, a state legislature has enacted a law under which anyone caught with the eggs of leatherback turtles can be fined up to $ 363 or sentenced to six months in jail. Many Malaysians eat the eggs as a delicacy, believing they increase sexual prowess. The law passed Wednesday by the <LOCATION> Trengganu </LOCATION> state assembly in <LOCATION> Kuala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Trengganu </LOCATION>, 180 miles northeast of Kuala Lumpur, says the only lawful purpose for keeping the eggs is for hatching by the <ORGANIZATION> state </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> fisheries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> department </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Rashid </PERSON> <PERSON> Ngah </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fisheries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said he proposed the law because the number of leatherback turtles laying eggs in Rantau <PERSON> Abang </PERSON>, near <LOCATION> Kuala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Trengganu </LOCATION>, had declined to about 500 in recent years and measures were needed to prevent their extinction. The turtles, measuring as much as five feet in diameter and weighing up to 900 pounds, range the seas as far as <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> but return to the beaches of Rantau <PERSON> Abang </PERSON> each June to August to lay their eggs. Scientists say the turtles, which live as long as 100 years, return each year to the exact beach where they were born to lay up to 70 eggs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890406-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-89 0338EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AtwoodConfirmation     04-06 0522</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Atwood Confirmation,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Deputy Defense Nominee Makes `Extraordinary' Stock Divestment</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
