<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-JetEngines     07-07 0229</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jet Engines,0235</SECOND>
<HEAD>Base Reports At Least One F-16 Engine Missing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HILL AIR FORCE BASE, Utah (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At least one jet engine designed to power the F-16 fighter has apparently been stolen, an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said Thursday. At least one <ORGANIZATION> Pratt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Whitney engine was discovered missing Wednesday morning by maintenance crews returning to work after the Independence Day holiday, said Staff Sgt. <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Arana-Barradas </PERSON>, a base spokesman. <ORGANIZATION> KSL-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, quoting unidentified sources, reported that three of the 20-foot-long engines were taken out through two or three unmanned security gates over the weekend. The locks on the gates were cut, the station said. Investigators from the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Special </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investigations </ORGANIZATION> were trying to determine how many of the $ 2 million engines were taken from the base nearly 30 miles north of <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Arana-Barradas </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>'s 388th Tactical Fighter Wing and the <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> 419th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tactical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fighter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wing </ORGANIZATION>, both based at <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, fly the F-16. The engines also are shipped to <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> from other bases for maintenance at the nearby <ORGANIZATION> Ogden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Logistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Arana-Barradas </PERSON> said it had not been determined whether the engine known to be missing belonged to one of the Hill wings or had been sent from another base for maintenance. <PERSON> Arana-Barradas </PERSON> declined to provide other details of the theft.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 2343EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Nixon-China 240   07-07 0225</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nixon-China, 240</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nixon Planning China Trip: Report</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, who reopened ties with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in the 1970s, is planning to visit <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in September, according to a published report. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials and diplomatic sources were quoted in Saturday's editions of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> as saying that <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> and former Secretary of State <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> were likely to be among the first prominent Americans to visit <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> since the bloody crackdown on pro-democracy demonstrators last month <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> did not respond to inquiries about his <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> plans, the newspaper said. <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>, who served under <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> and helped forge relations with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, was quoted as saying he was considering a `` long-standing invitation'' to visit <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in October to take part in a government-sponsored investment conference. `` I wo n't conduct foreign policy on my own,'' <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> said. `` I would n't do anything without consulting the administration.'' President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has barred high-level official trips to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> as a sign of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> displeasure with the massacre in Tiananmen Square. The order extends only to executive branch officials. <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s trip to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in February 1972 re-established Sino-American relations for the first time since the 1949 communist revolution. He has made three other trips to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> has expressed disapproval of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sanctions, saying that messages should be sent through private channels asking the Chinese to show restraint.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 2348EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-ExiledGovernment 1stLd-Writethru   07-07 0568</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Exiled Government, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0707,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officials Appealed To Panamanian Government In Exile For Drug Bust</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS grafs 11-13 bgng: `In Panama,'' with reaction in Panama</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYNA BRENNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration appealed to a powerless government in exile for permission to board a Panamanian freighter off Key West and was readily accommodated, leading to the seizure of 3,359 pounds of cocaine, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> explained Friday. `` Can you tell us which government gave the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> permission, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s or the Panamanian government we recognize in exile?'' a reporter asked during the daily <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> briefing. `` The Department of State requested permission from the <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> government through the <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> and Ambassador <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, and permission was granted,'' spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> responded. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> recognizes <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> as the legitimate president of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> was ousted from the office in February 1988 at the urging of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s de facto ruler, Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, indicted by a grand jury in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> on drug trafficking charges, also overturned the results of the May 7 election, which showed an opposition candidate as the winner. <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> was not a candidate. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> responded to the election fraud by sending in American troops to bolster the 10,000 or so soldiers already there, withdrawing the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador and cutting the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy staff. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> boarded the Panamanian freighter Thursday night and found the hidden sacks of cocaine. Transportation Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> put the street value of the drugs at $ 129.5 million. Adm. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> boarded the 162-foot captured freighter at <LOCATION> Key </LOCATION> <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> on Friday and praised the interception, saying: `` What this means is that we have begun to coerce the smuggler back out on the sea, and out of the air.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said the ship's position, off the direct route to the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, aroused suspicion. But an initial search of ship failed to turn up anything, officials said. `` The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> went to the <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, and we were given approval to go ahead and board the ship,'' <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Lt. <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Karonis </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, government authorities said Friday they were satisfied that the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> had captured a drug-running vessel but were upset that <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> had gotten permission from the <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> government. `` We are very happy that the Americans have made this capture,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Carrera </PERSON> of the prosecutor's office. He added, `` We are annoyed about the manner'' that they sought permission. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> have had an anti-drug agreement since 1976 which mandates cooperation from both sides. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, a reporter at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> briefing pressed the issue: `` Is the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' view that the <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> government in exile has the authority to grant permission for interception of a ship? Is the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' view that the <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> government in exile has the authority to grant permission for any sort of military or paramilitary activity such as the use of <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> forces to stop shipping to and from <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>?'' <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> said: `` If we decide we're going to try to board the vessel, we go to the government and get permission. We certainly do recognize the <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> government as the government of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, and we recognize, therefore, that they have the authority to give us permission, and then we board the vessel.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0011EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-LifeinEasternEurope-Recreation     07-07 0529</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Life in Eastern Europe-Recreation,0543</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eastern Europeans Working To Make Ends Meet Have Little Free Time</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report; Last in a five-part series.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TEDDIE WEYR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's not exactly all work and no play, but many who live in the Soviet bloc nations of <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> say they rarely have either the time or money for recreation. `` It is hard to have free time in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>,'' said a woman who held a child in each hand as she left a market hall in central <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>. `` We have to stand on line and there is nothing in the stores.'' Romanians often spend up to five hours a day waiting in line for food because much of the food produced there is exported. `` Practically, I have no leisure time _ with work, the home, the kids,'' a <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> businessman said. Some Eastern Europeans work as many as three jobs. An air traffic controller in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> might also work as a nightclub bouncer, or a university teacher might moonlight as an exterminator. While stores and markets in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> are well-stocked with fresh produce and meat, other consumer items and appliances are in short supply. Hungarians have grown accustomed to working as long as 16 hours a day to provide needed services. <PERSON> Ibolya </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuzsel </PERSON>, a Hungarian woman with a 12-year-old daughter, has run her husband's workshop since he died last year. Kuzsel rises at 5:30 each morning to do her chores before work; her evenings are spent on the accounting. Saturdays, she goes to the cemetery. `` I have little time for my daughter,'' she said. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will spend four days in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, the first visit to the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact nations by an American president since 1977. Many Eastern Europeans find inexpensive recreation in television or weekend trips to the country. And statistics show that alcohol is a popular escape, despite attempts throughout the bloc to curb its use. Hungarians spend an average of one month's salary on alcohol each year. That nation has the highest alcohol-related cirrhosis mortality rate in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> is second. Western television, especially popular detective series, provides diversion. Those in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> who can afford it can buy satellite dishes to pick up Western stations. Soviet television provides variety for some residents of <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION>. Weekend houses or bungalows are popular for residents of <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. But even weekends mean work. `` We just harvested 100 kilos -LRB- 220 pounds -RRB- of cherries and 400 kilos -LRB- 880 pounds -RRB- of green beans,'' said a young Hungarian entrepreneur who spends her work week in her tiny toy shop in <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION>. She will can the garden produce for the winter. Real vacations are often too costly for most Eastern Europeans to even consider. A week's vacation in a modest setting for a Polish family of four could cost three times the average monthly salary. Liberalized travel laws are allowing Hungarians more access to the West, with reasonably priced bus tours to <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> costing about $ 210. The state travel agency also offers more exclusive trips, such as a three-week vacation to <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> for $ 4,840.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0026EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Abortion-Elections     07-07 0684</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion-Elections,0702</SECOND>
<HEAD>Abortion Upheaval Shakes '89 Elections</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Abortion advocates have staked out <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> for the first true test of their punch at the polls, saying they'll hit the hustings and slug it out on the airwaves in an all-out effort to elect a pro-choice Democrat as governor. `` Abortion is going to be smack dab in the middle of this election,'' said <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowker </PERSON>, state chief of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION>. With so few political races this year, `` we are going to be the target state,'' she said. This week's upheaval in abortion law has jarred other 1989 campaigns, particularly the <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> gubernatorial and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> mayoral elections. But it is in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> that the issue has risen quickly to the political fore. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>'s race, like <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s, pits an anti-abortion Republican against a pro-choice Democrat. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, pro-choice Democratic Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> is attacking the neutral stand of Republican <PERSON> Rudolph </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON>. `` People who believe in a woman's right to abortion ... ought to be fearful of <PERSON> Rudy </PERSON> <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> has said. A <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON> aide on Wednesday accused the mayor of fearmongering. <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> began his attacks on the issue months ago, but abortion gained new prominence as a political issue Monday, when the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> approved of greater abortion restrictions by the states. Pro-choice groups promptly pledged to fight new anti-abortion laws and to work for the election of candidates who favor legal abortion. `` In every race, we will attempt to make the right to abortion the major issue,'' declared NOW President <PERSON> Molly </PERSON> <PERSON> Yard </PERSON>. The outcome is uncertain. National polls have indicated that few voters cast their ballots solely on the issue of abortion, and those who do split about evenly on both sides of the debate. However, given the court's ruling, `` We're dealing with a whole different environment,'' said <PERSON> Janice </PERSON> <PERSON> Ballou </PERSON>, polling director for the <ORGANIZATION> Eagleton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rutgers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brunswick </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> `` All those people in the middle are the ones that this change might impact.'' In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Eagleton </PERSON> polling before the ruling found 23 percent support for more restrictions on abortion _ and 68 percent opposing restrictions. Moreover, many more abortion supporters held their views strongly. That is promising for Democratic gubernatorial nominee <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Florio </PERSON>, who has pledged to veto any abortion restrictions. And it may trouble Republican <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Courter </PERSON>, who has favored outlawing abortion except in most cases. `` If we can have a big win for <PERSON> Florio </PERSON>, that makes a big statement,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Bowker </PERSON>. `` And if we can do well in the Assembly races, that makes an even bigger statement.'' Her plan of attack: A hit list of abortion opponents in the state Assembly, a series of pro-choice rallies across the state, radio advertising criticizing <PERSON> Courter </PERSON> on the issue _ and two new telephone lines at NOW state headquarters in <LOCATION> Trenton </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Courter </PERSON>, for his part, is playing down abortion's significance, with an aide saying Wednesday he does not see it as a central issue in the November election. In <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, pro-choice advocates say Democratic gubernatorial nominee <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>'s support for legal abortion has been equivocal; for example, he opposes public funding for abortion in most cases. <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> faces Republican <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, who opposes legalized abortion. `` It seems to me that if <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>'s going to win he has got to be much stronger on the issue of women's reproductive rights,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Yard </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` I think he's been scared by it. Nobody wins by being scared.'' In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, the issue has been raised mainly by <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> against <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON>, the front-runner in the polls. <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> has had the city pay for abortions for poor women who have no other source of funds. He says <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON>, who opposes abortion personally, can not be trusted to continue the program. But <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>, <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON>'s spokesman, said <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON> would continue the abortion funding despite his personal beliefs. Said <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>: `` The mayor is spreading disniformation to try to heighten the fears of women.'' Abortion, he said, `` is not a mayoral issue.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0028EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-YellowstoneWolves     07-07 0741</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Yellowstone Wolves,0760</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wolf Awareness Program Draws Fire from Ranchers</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM ANGELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YELLOWSTONE NATIONAL PARK, Wyo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Howling wolves have n't been heard in Yellowstone National Park for decades, but even talk about them is enough to rile the ranchers and others surrounding the park The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>'s program to educate students across the country about the role of the wolf in the wild has raised fears by some that it could lead to the predator's return to <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s 2.2 million acres `` Wolves are fascinating animals and when you talk to people about them, you never get a ho-hum reaction. They always have a strong reaction one way or another,'' said <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Zarki </PERSON>, a ranger in <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s Naturalist Division. `` They come with quite a bit of emotional baggage. We are trying to put some information in the hands of teachers and students: what -LRB- wolves -RRB- do, what their behavior is and what sort of role they have in the ecology,'' he said. `` It is not designed to sell a particular point of view, it is supposed to give them information so they can make up their minds on their own.'' Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>, R-Wyo., is among those who see the wolf awareness program as a way to drum up support for the wolf's return to <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> `` There is no other purpose for it but to promote reintroduction,'' <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said. `` There are guys in there who are so -LRB- heated -RRB- up and so obsessed they ca n't even see.'' Turn-of-the-century eradication efforts by ranchers drove wolves from <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, and in recent years there has been a drive to return the animals to the park. <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> and the rest of the <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> congressional delegation long have opposed the plan, which has the support of <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> officials. Those who want to return the wolves say they would prevent big-game herds from growing too large and overgrazing. <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> and other foes fear the wolves would stray from <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> and prey on livestock on surrounding ranches. Rep. <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Utah </LOCATION>, has sponsored legislation that would force the <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> to study how returning the wolves to the park would affect the environment. The <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> delegation is trying to derail that effort, too. <PERSON> Owens </PERSON> brought a 13-month-old female wolf to the lawn outside the Capitol in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> last month to dramatize his campaign. The wolf awareness program is being financed by donations from the <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> History </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, several large corporations and one unidentified donor. It is meant to mesh with the park's `` Expedition Yellowstone'' program that prepares students for visits to the park. The financing bothers <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>. `` Forget the wolf aspect,'' he said. `` The issue is it is a bad precedent for interest groups to round up the money to do anything -LRB- through the Park Service -RRB-.'' <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said the arrangement amounts to federal government endorsement of a program that he says unfairly stresses the benefits of having wolves in the park without examining the impact of their presence as predators. The program, launched at the urging of former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Penn </PERSON> <PERSON> Mott </PERSON>, is designed to teach students about the wolf and its habits, not to promote their return to <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, park officials say. The program teaches elementary and high school students about wolves and urges them to mimic the animals through classroom activities such as howling, which wolves use to communicate. Students also can join in the debate over the plan to return wolves to <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> by staging a mock public meeting. `` They assume the positions of various special interest groups with parts in the debate,'' <PERSON> Zarki </PERSON> said. Not overlooked by the program is that wolves no longer lope through <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>. `` It's not like we hide from the kids the fact the wolves are not here,'' he said. `` We try to deal with that and why. Most kids know animals are not as widespread as they used to be and people are in many cases responsible for that.'' <PERSON> Zarki </PERSON> conceded that the program may result in letters in favor of wolf reintroduction, but stressed it is not designed to do so. `` I'm not suggesting in the activities that they do that,'' he said. `` But if you look in the past ... there are many incidents where students focus on wildlife issues and write to legislators and action is taken. All we are trying to do is help kids learn a little bit more about wolves.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0022EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ArtsAppointment     07-07 0257</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Arts Appointment,0265</SECOND>
<HEAD>Oregon Lawyer to Head National Endowment for Arts</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has selected <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, lawyer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Frohnmayer </PERSON> to head the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endowment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported. The arts agency dispenses $ 170 million a year in grants. <PERSON> Frohnmayer </PERSON>, 47, is being checked by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and would have to be confirmed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, the Times reported in its Friday editions. He would succeed <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodsoll </PERSON>, who left in February to take a post at the Office of Management and Budget. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> passed over several candidates, including <PERSON> Schuyler </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapin </PERSON>, former dean of the school of the arts at <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Barnabas </PERSON> <PERSON> McHenry </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Empire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plaza </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said. The <ORGANIZATION> NEA </ORGANIZATION> recently has faced criticism from members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for some of its projects. Most recently, an NEA-supported photographic retrospective, `` <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mapplethorpe </PERSON>: The Perfect Moment,'' an exhibition that some lawmakers said was pornographic, was canceled before it was to have opened at the Corcoran Gallery in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Other lawmakers have criticized the <ORGANIZATION> NEA </ORGANIZATION> for supporting the work of artist <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Serrano </PERSON>, who depicted in a photograph <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> on a crucifix submerged in the artist's urine. <PERSON> Frohnmayer </PERSON> is married and has two teen-age sons. He is a lawyer with a <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION> law firm and has spent years working in arts organizations in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>. A native of <LOCATION> Medford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, he attended <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-HongKong     07-07 0984</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hong Kong,1014</SECOND>
<HEAD>Crackdown in China Clouds Hong Kong's Future</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 The business of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> has been business, not politics, so when <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> agreed to return the crown colony to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, the residents did not object as long as capitalism was protected. After <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> cracked down on the student pro-democracy movement, much of that changed. Here is a report from a correspondent who was in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> when the army arrived.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By DAN BIERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The crackdown on dissent in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> has multiplied fears that this vibrant capitalist enclave may wither under the Communist Chinese rule scheduled to begin in 1997. <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> residents watched in horror as <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> soldiers stamped out the pro-democracy movement in June, and many responded by applying for passports and demanding that <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> offer them refuge. `` It's a tragedy we have here,'' said <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Y.S </PERSON>. <PERSON> Cheng </PERSON>, a political scientist. `` To most of my friends, there are only two ways out. One is to emigrate; the other is to keep quiet, keep your fingers crossed and hope for the best.'' <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> agreed five years ago to return <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in 1997, when the lease on much of the crown colony expires. In return, the Chinese said <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> could keep its capitalist system and enjoy a `` high degree of autonomy'' for 50 years under a policy of `` one country, two systems.'' Since then, the people of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> have busied themselves with what they have always done best: making money. The economy achieved impressive growth that reached 13.5 percent in 1987 and brought great prosperity to many of the 5.7 million people. Economic links with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> strengthened dramatically. Legions of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> entrepreneurs started factories in adjacent <LOCATION> Guangdong </LOCATION> province and hundreds of Chinese companies set up shop in the territory. Such bonds increased the importance of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s policy of modernizing and opening itself to the world, a process widely seen as the best guarantee of the `` one country, two systems'' policy Then came the night of June 3-4 in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, when the army attacked and the government acknowledged that hundreds of people were killed. The assault, and mass arrests that followed, caused hundreds of thousands in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> to shed their political apathy and take to the streets in protest. `` It has shown very clearly that there's no guarantee from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. They are capable of doing anything,'' said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Chan </PERSON>, a researcher at the Center of Asian Studies at the University of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. Many people are leaving the colony and companies are evaluating their future, said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Broadfoot </PERSON>, managing director of a business-risk consulting group. A surge in the emigration of skilled workers would cause a loss of the local investment and personnel needed for the city to grow. The government estimates 45,000 people emigrated in 1988, up from an average of 20,000 in each of the previous five years. Sharp increases in immigration inquiries and applications were reported last month by consulates of such popular destinations as <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. Even smaller countries like <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Belize </LOCATION> found interest growing. <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, personnel manager of a <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> shipping company, said three of its 170 employees had resigned to move abroad, four were planning to leave and 17 had started the emigration process. `` Everybody is worried about the future,'' she said. People without the money, skills or connections to go where they choose are asking <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> to provide refuge as an `` insurance policy.'' Officials in the colony say granting the right to live in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> is essential to restoring confidence among residents, many of whose families fled Communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> has refused. `` There is simply no way that the British government could grant to several million people the right to come and live in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>,'' Foreign Secretary Sir <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> said on a recent visit to <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. He said <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> would take all measures possible to safeguard the colony, and urged the people not to `` underestimate your ability to build that future.'' `` <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> has seen hard times before,'' <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> said. `` You've always shown the resilience and the resourcefulness to live through such times and emerge from them stronger than ever before. A recent poll indicated only 6 percent of residents would move to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> if given the right, and that most people had no intention of leaving <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Chan </PERSON> said the pro-democracy movement had caused many to rediscover their Chinese identity. The political awakening in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> touched all levels of society. In addition to huge street demonstrations, a television personality organized seminars on democracy and activists collected volumes of signatures for various protests. Revulsion about the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> crackdown was widespread, from newspapers long supported by <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> to taxi drivers who attached tiny black flags to their antennas. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, which some residents say has not done enough for the colony, appeared likely to speed democratic reform so the people would have a greater voice in their future. The legislature is dominated by government officials and appointed members. <PERSON> Cheng </PERSON>, the political scientist, has fought a long battle for more democracy but now says: `` What guarantee will it offer? If <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> is ready to crush the students with tanks and machine guns, what's the point of having a democratic system in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>? Others believe continued support in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s dissidents might be dangerous `` <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> leaders could perceive a political threat in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> that outweighs economic benefits,'' <PERSON> Broadfoot </PERSON> said. `` If <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> refuses to keep out of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s political affairs, it could be extremely damaging.'' Observers say the fall of the hard-line leadership in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, or enacting a bill of rights and redrafting the post-1997 constitution for <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> could help the territory's success extend well into the 21st century. But for now, <PERSON> Cheng </PERSON> said, `` almost everyone is very depressed.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-HongKong-People     07-07 0847</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hong Kong-People,0872</SECOND>
<HEAD>China's Conduct Raises Question of Whether to Stay in Hong Kong</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Hong Kong</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kwang </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON> left a pharmaceutical plant, a five-story home and the good life behind in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> when the communists won the war 14 years ago and he fled to this British colony. He thought he had found a home. Then Chinese soldiers crushed pro-democracy demonstrations in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and he started searching for a new haven. <PERSON> Nansun </PERSON> <PERSON> Shi </PERSON>, a TV producer, was `` just too busy for politics'' before the crackdown. Now she heads a group teaching <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> residents about democracy and human rights. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is to assume control of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> in 1997 under an agreement with <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, but the heavy-handed suppression of dissent has shocked this colony of 5.7 million and is changing the attitudes of its people. Since the Chinese army assaulted Tiananmen Square the night of June 3-4, hundreds of thousands of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> residents have put aside political apathy and taken to the streets in protest. More than 650,000 signed a petition for democratic reforms and a bill of rights, and demanding that <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> residents be given the right to live in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. Callers to radio talk shows have proposed independence for <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, while others say it should buy some islands to accommodate its people. Some residents have started an `` underground railroad'' to get dissidents out of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Zhang </PERSON> <PERSON> Xuexin </PERSON>, a waiter at the Good Taste Restaurant in the <LOCATION> Happy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> district, expressed the feelings of many: `` I'm terrified of what will happen when the Communists come. My whole family is; neighbors, too. `` I fled <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> during the Cultural Revolution. I swam here and risked my neck. After 1978 and <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>, I had a little hope. Then there was the massacre on <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION>. Now I know Communists will never change.'' Fear is not confined to Chinese residents. Many of the 100,000 Westerners in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> also worry. `` This is home,'' said <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, 44. `` I've spent half my married life here. I had one of my sons here. This is where I want to be, but if we do n't leave now and it collapses around us after 1997, we might just be too old.'' Under the 1984 agreement between <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> promises to keep <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>'s capitalist system intact for 50 years after 1997. It also agreed to an unspecified degree of political `` autonomy,'' currently being negotiated. After the bloodshed in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and ensuing mass arrests, many people in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> lost faith that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> would keep its word. Thousands want to emigrate, but some like Ms. <PERSON> Shi </PERSON> say they are willing to stay and fight. Educated in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> as a member of a well-off <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> family, she spent her teens `` wearing bobby socks and reading Seventeen magazine.'' She returned to <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> in her 20s, got a public relations job and soon began reporting on high society for television. Later, she moved to producing movies and TV shows. `` I never was political at all,'' she said. `` I had a sense of what was right, but that covered all spheres. I just did n't think about politics. That's not what we were taught to do.'' When <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s army attacked the students, she said, `` I was ... shocked so I could n't speak, possibly because it was such a simple issue, which is so rare these days. It's so black and white. It's so clear who was right and who was wrong.'' After taking part in demonstrations, organizing a concert and working on a song for the pro-democracy movement, Ms. <PERSON> Shi </PERSON> said, it seemed to her that people knew well enough what they were protesting but not what they were fighting for. `` We were shouting ` democracy,' ` freedom,' ` human rights,' but nobody knew what that meant,'' she said. `` I figured I had to find out.'' The result was a series of seminars on the topic by leading <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> academics. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lau </PERSON>, a nurse who attended a recent Sunday of lectures at the <ORGANIZATION> Hong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said the program opened her mind. `` It made me want to educate myself,'' she said, holding a filled notebook. `` Our system teaches us how to be good workers, but not good thinkers.'' <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Qiao </PERSON>, a 65-year-old taxi driver who fled <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> in 1954, said the crackdown in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> `` woke people up. It taught the young people about the Communists.'' `` They said the same thing in <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> in the 1950s: ` You can stay capitalist; we need your help,' all that stuff,'' he said. `` Then they came in and took the factories away and locked up the capitalists. It's going to be the same story here.'' Tan, the pharmacist, said his South Vietnamese passport will make moving more difficult. `` It gets so maddening,'' he said. `` I struggled here for 10 years and finally am making a little money in real estate. Then this happens, the market goes soft and my wife starts telling me it's time to find a new country.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Haiti-BankFraud     07-07 0482</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Haiti-Bank Fraud,0494</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Candidate for Haitian Presidency Arrested in Bank Scam</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RONALD POWERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Haitian exile who ran for president of his island nation in 1987 was arrested Thursday on charges he operated a bogus bank that may have bilked customers out of tens of millions of dollars, a federal prosecutor said. <PERSON> Clemard </PERSON> <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, who was granted asylum in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> nine years ago, and three others purported to run the <ORGANIZATION> Banque </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerciale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> D'Haiti </ORGANIZATION> from a home in <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION> and a mortgage company from a luxury apartment overlooking Central Park in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, authorities said. Neither concern was authorized to operate in the state. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Maloney </PERSON> said the victims of the scheme, which ran for about two years, ranged from drug dealers to international financiers. `` What makes this operation so unusual was the brazenness, the chutzpah,'' <PERSON> Maloney </PERSON> said. `` They never moved out of a location, they never left town. That makes it a little extraordinary.'' Investigators will not know how many people and financial institutions were cheated and how much money the scams earned until records seized by <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents during raids Thursday are examined, <PERSON> Maloney </PERSON> said. The bank apparently cheated its customers out of tens of millions of dollars, said Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerber </PERSON>, adding `` we do n't really have a handle on it.'' In one complex transaction, the bank recently issued bogus multimillion-dollar letters of credit payable to the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> and the economic ministries of <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Maloney </PERSON> said. The letters of credit for $ 2 million each from the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> and the two countries were used to finance the campaign of a politician from the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s neighbor on the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> island of <LOCATION> Hispaniola </LOCATION>, according to <PERSON> Maloney </PERSON>. According to court papers, the scheme began to unravel last October when <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Westminster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> attempted to regain losses on a $ 5 million letter of credit issued by <ORGANIZATION> Banque </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commercial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> D'Haiti </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Maloney </PERSON> said he could not yet explain how the phony bankers had managed to continue to operate without detection or retaliation. Authorities said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, 66, came to this country in 1980 after he was freed from a Haitian jail where he spent 10 years for opposing former President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> `` Papa Doc'' <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON>. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> was one of 35 presidential candidates in the violently aborted Nov. 29, 1987 general elections. If convicted of bank fraud and other charges, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> and the others would face at least 10 years in jail, heavy fines and forfeiture of property purchased with their earnings, <PERSON> Maloney </PERSON> said. He identified the other suspects, all listed as officials of the bank, as <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Aye </PERSON>, 74; <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>' son, <PERSON> Victor </PERSON>, 43, and <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, 50. All are from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Aye </PERSON> was freed on a $ 100,000 secured bond, but <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Magistrate <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Bagley </PERSON> <PERSON> Amon </PERSON> ordered the others held pending a hearing on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PhotoRescue     07-07 0243</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Photo Rescue,0249</SECOND>
<HEAD>Newspaper Photo Session Nearly Results in Tragedy</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto ATN1</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANNISTON, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A weather-related photo session for an <LOCATION> Anniston </LOCATION> newspaper nearly turned into tragedy when rushing waters swept a woman through a flooded 50-foot culvert and her would-be rescuer was trapped by the current. Neither <PERSON> Angie </PERSON> <PERSON> Shockley </PERSON>, a 24-year-old employee of the <ORGANIZATION> Golden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Springs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Anniston </LOCATION>, nor <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, 32, of <LOCATION> Anniston </LOCATION> was seriously injured Wednesday. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was treated at <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> and released. Miss <PERSON> Shockley </PERSON> was posing for a rain-related feature for <ORGANIZATION> Anniston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> photographer <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Motes </PERSON> when she stepped into a flooded ditch. She was swept under the water when she attempted to reach higher ground. `` You could n't tell how deep the water was,'' Motes said. `` She fell in up to her shoulders and was smiling, then she disappeared.'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, who was watching the photo session, jumped in after Miss <PERSON> Shockley </PERSON>. `` When he jumped in, I noticed she'd washed up on the other side -LRB- of the culvert -RRB-,'' Motes said. `` It just happened so quickly.'' By then, <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> had been slammed against the culvert and was pinned by the current. A group of basketball players left the community center's gymnasium to help free <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. But it took the <ORGANIZATION> Anniston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Squad </ORGANIZATION>, a chain and bystanders' help to save him At one point, <ORGANIZATION> Anniston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> personnel attached a breathing apparatus to <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> so he could be lowered temporarily under water during the rescue operation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     07-07 0328</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0338</SECOND>
<HEAD>NBC Extends Its Winning Run to 54 Weeks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY BUCK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> extended its winning streak in the Nielsen television ratings to 54 weeks as the network's `` Cheers'' tied <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne'' for first place. Altogether, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> captured seven slots in the Top 10. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> had three shows at the top. CBS was squeezed out. In the week that ended July 2, the two top-rated shows were closely followed by another <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> comedy, `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' which placed third. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> ratings with an average of 11.9, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> had 8.5 and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> had 8.3. For the season to date, since Sept. 19, the ratings are <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 15.2, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 12.2 and CBS 12.1. The rating is a percentage of the estimated 90.4 million homes in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> with television. The share is a percentage of sets in use. The Top 10: <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Cheers'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne,'' tied for first; <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' third; <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Different World'' and `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' tied for fourth; <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Night Court,'' sixth; <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Cosby Show,'' seventh; <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Empty Nest,'' eighth; <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Wonder Years'' and `` Coach,'' tied for <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> did have two shows in the next 10, `` Murder, She Wrote'' in 16th place and `` 60 Minutes'' tied for 19th place with <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>. `` Doctor, Doctor,'' a CBS summer series was 37th in the ranking. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> tied for first among the nightly news shows. Each had a rating of 8.7. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> was third with 8.2. <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>'s `` Married ... With Children'' was in a three-way tie for 46th place and its `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted'' series was in a two-way tie for 52nd. The lowest-rated network show was <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Have Faith,'' which collected a lower rating than five shows on <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>. The bottom network shows were CBS' `` Paradise'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s Thursday Night Baseball, tied, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` B-Men,'' CBS' `` Tour of Duty,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Great Circuses of the World'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Have Faith.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0110EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     07-07 0672</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0752</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of June 26-July 2. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.4 rating, 16.6 million homes. 1. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.4, 16.6 million homes. 3. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.2, 15.5 million homes. 4. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.6, 14.1 million homes. 4. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.6, 14.1 million homes. 6. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.0, 13.6 million homes. 7. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.9, 13.5 million homes. 8. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.6, 13.2 million homes. 9. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.1, 12.7 million homes. 9. -LRB- 62 -RRB- `` Coach,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.1, 12.7 million homes. 11. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.0, 12.6 million homes. 11. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` Doing Life'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 14.0, 12.6 million homes. 13. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.8, 12.5 million homes. 13. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.8, 12.5 million homes. 15. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.6, 12.3 million homes. 16. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 13.3, 12.0 million homes. 17. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` In the Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.0, 11.8 million homes. 18. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.9, 11.7 million homes. 19. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7, 11.5 million homes. 19. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7, 11.5 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` Midnight Caller,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.3. 22. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 12.1. 23. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.6. 23. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS, 11.6. 25. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 26. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.2. 27. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.1. 27. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.1. 29. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Vice,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.0. 30. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` Mad Max: Beyond Thunderdome'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 10.8. 30. -LRB- 44 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 10.8. 32. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.7. 33. -LRB- 44 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.6. 33. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.6. 35. -LRB- 46 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 36. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.7. 37. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` Doctor, Doctor,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.4. 38. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.3. 38. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Circus of the Stars,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.3. 40. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Monte </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carlo </LOCATION>,'' Part 1, _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 9.2. 41. -LRB- 79 -RRB- `` Paternity'' _ `` Movie of the Week-Friday,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.1. 41. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.1. 43. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Koppel Report: Tragedy at <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.0. 43. -LRB- 60 -RRB- `` Pleasures'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movie,'' 9.0. 45. -LRB- 71 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: Illegal Immigrants,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.8. 46. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 8.6. 46. -LRB- 81 -RRB- `` Twilight Zone: The Movie'' _ `` CBS Friday Movie,'' 8.6. 46. -LRB- 77 -RRB- `` Heartland,'' CBS, 8.6. 49. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` Silkwood'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 8.5. 50. -LRB- 97 -RRB- `` Highway to Heaven,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 50. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` The Equalizer,'' CBS, 8.3. 52. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 8.0. 52. -LRB- 62 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.0. 54. -LRB- 41 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.9. 55. -LRB- 97 -RRB- `` West 57th,'' CBS, 7.8. 55. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` Hooperman,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.8. 57. -LRB- 79 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Guillaume </PERSON> <PERSON> Show </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.7. 58. -LRB- 59 -RRB- `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 7.2. 59. -LRB- 77 -RRB- `` I-Man'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> Magical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.0. 60. -LRB- 113 -RRB- `` Cavanaughs,'' CBS, 5.8. 60. -LRB- 82 -RRB- `` Supergirl'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Saturday Night Movie,'' 5.8. 62. -LRB- 74 -RRB- `` Beauty and the <LOCATION> Beast </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 5.7. 62. -LRB- X -RRB- `` A Man Called Hawk Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.7. 64. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` Coming of Age,'' CBS, 5.6. 65. -LRB- 94 -RRB- `` Hard Time on Planet Earth,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 5.5. 66. -LRB- 75 -RRB- `` Paradise,'' CBS, 5.4. 66. -LRB- 109 -RRB- `` ABC Thursday Night Baseball,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.4. 68. -LRB- 114 -RRB- `` B-Men'' _ `` CBS Summer Playhouse,'' 5.3. 69. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.9. 69. -LRB- 87 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 4.9. 71. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.3. 72. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.2. 73. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Great Circuses of the World Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 3.9. 74. -LRB- 47 -RRB- `` Have Faith,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 3.7. 75. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.5. 76. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` The Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.2. 76. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Duet,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.2. 78. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AnselAdams     07-07 0470</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ansel Adams,0482</SECOND>
<HEAD>Estate Attorneys Argue False Advertising</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDA DEUTSCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Attorneys for photographer <PERSON> Ansel </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' estate argued in federal court Thursday that publishers of a book of <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' pictures taken for the federal government during World War II engaged in false advertising They sought to ban the sale of a calendar and desk reference book based on the same material, which is entitled, `` The Mural Project'' and said the book publishers wrongly used <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' name to sell their book. Attorney <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Mustin </PERSON>, representing the trustees of the <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> estate, said the trustees did not publish the pictures in question because they felt the quality was not representative of <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' work. The publishers `` are in it for the money,'' <PERSON> Mustin </PERSON> argued. `` The trustees are in it for the reputation of <PERSON> Ansel </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>. My clients want to preserve the integrity and quality of the work. But attorney <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallen </PERSON>, representing <ORGANIZATION> Day </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dream </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION>, said the only reason the quality of the pictures is not good is because the negatives are unavailable. The authors of `` The Mural Project'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Armor </PERSON> and <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, claim the negatives are being hidden by the trustees. The pictures themselves are in the public domain and can be purchased from the government for about $ 10 apiece. They were shot in 1941 and 1942 when <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> was working for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, photographing park scenes to be blown up for murals in public buildings. The murals were never made. <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Ickes </PERSON> had hired <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> for $ 22.22 a day plus expenses, and the photos became government property. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Keller </PERSON> said there is no dispute that the photos are in the public domain and <PERSON> Mustin </PERSON> said the trustees are not challenging publication of the book itself. `` We are not challenging the book in these proceedings because we understand it is already in the stream of commerce,'' he said. `` The toothpaste is out of the tube.'' But they seek to stop distribution of the calendar and datebook and further use of <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' name in advertising. The ad in question described the photos as `` The finding of an unknown body of work by <PERSON> Ansel </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>'' and compared it to the discovery of `` an unknown play by <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>, an unknown symphony by <PERSON> Beethoven </PERSON>.'' The trustees claimed this was misleading. But the judge disagreed. `` The fact is that this was and is a commissioned body of work and it was not available until the ferreting out by Armor and <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>,'' he said. `` I'm not inclined to believe from a practical standpoint that this is misleading advertising.'' The legal arguments on further points of dispute were continued until Friday afternoon. The judge said he would take the matter under submission before issuing a ruling.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AbsentConviction     07-07 0226</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Absent Conviction,0233</SECOND>
<HEAD>No-Show Defendant Convicted of Murder</HEAD>
<DATELINE>UPPER MARLBORO, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man who asked to be excused to use the restroom and disappeared before the start of his murder trial has been convicted in absentia. Prosecutor <PERSON> Claudia </PERSON> <PERSON> Koenig </PERSON> said sentencing will be put off until the defendant, <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Howell </PERSON>, is found. Defense lawyer <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Houlon </PERSON> said he will base an appeal on Circuit Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> McCullough </PERSON>'s insistence on proceeding with a jury trial. `` I told the judge I did n't have a prayer of getting a not-guilty verdict because the jury would n't look kindly on his absence,'' said <PERSON> Houlon </PERSON>. <PERSON> McCullough </PERSON> ruled that only the defendant could waive his right to a trial by his peers. In <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, trials in absentia are `` extremely rare,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>, chief of criminal trials in the state attorney's office `` There have been a few minor cases, but I'm not aware of any murder cases.'' <PERSON> Howell </PERSON>, a Jamacian citizen who lived in <LOCATION> Glenarden </LOCATION>, was convicted of killing <PERSON> Collin </PERSON> <PERSON> Phelmin </PERSON> <PERSON> Branford </PERSON>, 31, in a dispute over drugs. <PERSON> Howell </PERSON>'s trial on murder and handgun charges began June 28, one day after he fled. He was convicted last week after five hours of deliberations and is sought by the Prince <PERSON> George </PERSON>'s County Sheriff's <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> `` He said, ` I have to go to the bathroom,' and he kept on going,'' <PERSON> Houlon </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     07-07 0936</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0972</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GASTONIA, N.C., (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Aykroyd </PERSON> went from ghostbuster to speedbuster when he was stopped for driving 83 mph, but his demeanor would have made Sgt. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> Friday proud. <PERSON> Aykroyd </PERSON> knew the routine from his role in the movie `` Dragnet.'' Just the facts, please. `` He said he'd become hypnotized by the road after driving so long,'' said state Trooper L.J. <PERSON> Pitula </PERSON>, who stopped <PERSON> Aykroyd </PERSON> about 6:40 a.m. Thursday, for exceeding the 65 mph speed limit on Interstate 85 in <LOCATION> Gaston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Aykroyd </PERSON>, one of the stars of `` Ghostbusters II,'' was one his way from <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, where he was filming a movie, to his home in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> in his gray 1984 Mercedes. He told the trooper he had been driving for most of the night. <PERSON> Pitula </PERSON> said when he realized the driver was <PERSON> Aykroyd </PERSON>, he got a small case of stage fright himself. `` He was absolutely 100 percent a gentleman,'' <PERSON> Pitula </PERSON> said. `` He used no influence whatsoever.'' After <PERSON> Aykroyd </PERSON> autographed the ticket, the actor followed the trooper on the 10 minute drive to the <LOCATION> Gaston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Courthouse </LOCATION> where he posted a $ 56 bond, promising to appear when his case comes up.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Readers' Guide to <ORGANIZATION> Periodical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Literature </ORGANIZATION> has more listings for <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON> than any other living <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> woman, but many of her friends say most of what's written about her is inaccurate. Mrs. <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON>, who turns 60 on July 28, is most often portrayed as `` snooty, spiteful, greedy ... the original material girl,'' wrote <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>, who interviewed more than 60 of her friends for a profile in the August issue of Vanity Fair magazine. `` The <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> they know has managed to preserve her dignity through an ordeal by the press such as no other woman in this century has had to undergo, and she has also _ whatever her faults _ triumphed as a mother and as a professional person.'' <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>, who has known Mrs. <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON> for 12 years, wrote that she is still concerned about her appearance: She exercises, has her own private yoga instructor, and had a face lift last April. He also said she has amassed a fortune estimated at close to $ 200 million.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Jordanaires </ORGANIZATION>, whose harmonic voices backed <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ricky </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> and others on thousands of recordings, are among 10 finalists for induction into the Country Music Hall of Fame. The Country Music Association announced Thursday that the four-man quartet will be joined in the open category by <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> <PERSON> Ernie </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Louvin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brothers </LOCATION>, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>. Nominated in the non-performing category are <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Law </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Stapp </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cliffie </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> and <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> <PERSON> Waugh </PERSON>. One from each category will be inducted Oct. 9 during the nationally televised Country Music Association awards show. The Jordanaires were formed in <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, in 1948. Initially a barbershop quartet performing mainly gospel material, the group began a long and extremely successful association with Presley in 1956. <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, `` The Ol' Peapicker,'' is known for his hit record `` Sixteen Tons'' and his long-running TV program. The Louvin Brothers were country music's top brother act from 1951 to 1963, when they broke up. <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, who died in 1975, was a Grand Ole Opry star known for his hit `` Candy Kisses.'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> sold more than 30 million records, including his top hit, `` The Wild Side of Life.'' Inductees will be chosen by a panel of about 350 people who have at least 10 years of experience in the country music industry.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON>, the religious leader revered by most Tibetans as a living <PERSON> Buddha </PERSON>, celebrated his 54th birthday with a party in <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION>. The exiled Tibetan religious leader is on a 17-day visit to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> to address followers of the 2,500-year-old faith and conduct religious ceremonies. Though respected by all Buddhists, to some followers he carries no religious authority. A group of <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monks and others celebrated his birthday on Thursday with birthday cake, a tree planting ceremony, luncheon and traditional Tibetan dancing in <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION>. `` We even sang ` Happy Birthday' to the <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON>, although they do n't do that in <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the religious leader's trip to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TORONTO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s queen mother, it was deja vu. She rededicated the same highway, made a royal departure in the identical <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> <PERSON> LeBaron </PERSON> convertible, and was presented again Thursday to the youngest reporter to cover the royal tour across <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> in 1939. Reliving a part of the first tumultuous visit by a reigning monarch and his consort on a five-day trip that began in <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION> on Wednesday, the 88-year-old Queen <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> expressed disbelief that half a century had passed. `` When I arrived at the International Airport yesterday evening, I could hardly believe that it is some 50 years since the royal train pulled into north station, and the king and I had our first sight of this exciting city,'' a beaming queen mother told hundreds gathered on the lawn at the <ORGANIZATION> Ontario </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer-songwriter <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dylan </PERSON> has been awarded the highest cultural honor <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> can bestow upon an individual. The minister of culture informed <PERSON> Dylan </PERSON> last week that he has been awarded the title of `` Commandeur Dans L'Ordre des Arts et <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lettres </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Dylan </PERSON>'s publicist, <PERSON> Elliot </PERSON> <PERSON> Mintz </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dylan </PERSON> has been touring in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, performing in nightly shows that draw from his collection of more than 600 songs, said <PERSON> Mintz </PERSON>. Joining him on stage in <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION> was U-2's <PERSON> Bono </PERSON>. <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> joined him in <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HUD-Alabama Bjt   07-07 0641</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-HUD-Alabama, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Agency Reformed Rules After Funds Went For Cars, Boat, Jewelry, Furs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KENDAL WEAVER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MONTGOMERY, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prosecutors are considering possible criminal action in the loss of $ 2 million of federal housing funds in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> that apparently were used to buy luxury items such as a Mercedes, a speedboat, jewelry and furs. <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> documents obtained by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> allege that <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> real estate broker <PERSON> Cy </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> spent the money over a three-year period by using a stack of blank wire transfer authorization forms. <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION> office, without a system to double-check on the receipt of funds from <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> closings, thought the $ 2 million from 63 sales closings went to its central office account, according to agency records. In fact, the money was in a <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> account controlled solely by <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, according to a <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> audit. Housing officials in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> tightened controls over <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> money on Nov. 9, 1987, after they discovered the money was missing. That same day <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> closed out the First <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> account, withdrawing the last $ 136.54. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> has turned its investigative file over to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney for possible prosecution. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said he plans to meet with <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> officials this month to discuss possible criminal cases. Officials with <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> declined comment on specific allegations in the case. However, bank official <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> said it appeared that <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION> `` has done nothing wrong, nothing out of the ordinary.'' AP interviews and <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> records, including canceled checks, show some of the money was spent by <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> for the following purchases: _ A $ 50,000 Mercedes <PERSON> Laurens </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Jack </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ingram </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>, said salesmen recall that <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> bought a Mercedes 560 SL convertible. The <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> audit listed nearly $ 180,000 in checks written by <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> to car dealers. _ An $ 18,870 speedboat from <LOCATION> Kowaliga </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Marina </LOCATION> The office manager at the marina said <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> bought a Stingray _ `` the Cadillac of speedboats,'' she said. _ $ 21,000 was paid to High School Video Memories, a business enterprise in which <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> hoped to sell video yearbooks to high school pupils across <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>. The venture apparently folded. Also, he is accused of spending $ 5,246 on jewelry, $ 8,255 on furs, $ 9,571 on travel and $ 2,200 for a saltwater aquarium and accessories. <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> is trying to recover the money through administrative procedures. A <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> audit covering August 1984 to November 1987 indicated some of the money in <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>'s account also was spent on HUD-related expenses such as grass-cutting and maintenance on foreclosed homes, as well as attorney's closing fees. The wire transfer forms were provided by an apparently unwitting bank employee, according to documents. A memo written by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lunsford </PERSON>, acting manager of the <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> office in November 1987, said the forms led the office to believe the bank had wired the money properly to the agency's central office. At the time, the agency had no procedure in place to check whether it had received the money or not. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> handled sales of <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s foreclosed homes in the <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> area while he was an associate broker for <PERSON> Rick </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Lind-Davis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Real </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. The firm was sold in 1986 to <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Portis </PERSON>, who closed business operations last year. His attorney said <PERSON> Portis </PERSON> was not aware of what <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> was doing with the <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> money. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> did not return a phone call made to the recording device on his beeper telephone. The number listed for his residence phone has been disconnected and <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> has moved from the apartment listed in the current phone book. <ORGANIZATION> Montgomery </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Real </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> records show that he still has a valid real estate license, but it is listed as `` inactive status'' because he has not been associated with a real estate firm since Nov. 14, 1988.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush Bjt   07-07 0743</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush, Bjt,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Won't be Drawn Into More Nuclear Talks by Gorbachev</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is rejecting Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s latest proposal for reducing nuclear arsenals in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, saying he does n't `` want to get off track'' and challenge hard-won <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> unity. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says he will stand by a <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> plan, which he orchestrated, that calls for conventional troop reductions first. Talks with the Soviets on cutting short-range nuclear warheads would come later, under the formula endorsed by the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> in May. As he prepared for next week's trip to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, the president told reporters on Thursday he was not concerned with the Soviet leader's popularity in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, declaring: `` We're not going to get into the international poll business. Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported today that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has decided to propose a 25 percent pay increases for top career government employees, with as much as a tripling for a small number of key specialists. He has endorsed a similar raise for federal judges. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said Thursday night the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> expected to announce the president's decisions today, although he could not confirm the figures. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Thursday issued a fresh challenge to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to remove <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> troops from <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s initial call, made last week in an interview with Polish reporters, was dismissed by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> as political propaganda. `` It's not political; it's a visceral feeling I have on the question,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. He conceded <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> had voiced `` a lack of enthusiasm'' toward his troop withdrawal proposal. But he added, `` He's just taken troops out of <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. And who would have said two years ago that would happen? We salute that ... I think it would be nice to aspire to that kind of situation where he would n't feel troops were necessary.'' In his meeting with reporters, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also: _ Said he was `` happy'' that former White House aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> was not sentenced to prison, but declined to comment further on <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s sentence Wednesday to a $ 150,000 fine, a three-year suspended sentence, two years' probation and 1,200 hours of community service for his role in the Iran-Contra affair _ <LOCATION> Challenged </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and other Soviet bloc countries to follow the lead of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> in moving toward more democracy, saying: `` come along with the flow. _ Said he would press for a `` broad tactics'' international effort to clean up the environment at next week's economic summit in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, saying efforts should be focused on `` preventing pollution at the outset, rather than cleaning it up afterwards. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will travel to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> on Sunday as he begins a four-nation visit to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> that also will include stops in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> for the seven-nation summit of industrial democracies, and in the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, in a speech Thursday in <LOCATION> Strasbourg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, said the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> would make unilateral cuts in its nuclear missiles pointed toward western <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> if the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would agree to speedy talks on reducing short-range nuclear weapons on both sides in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration officials suggested the <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> offer was designed to test <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> unity. In May, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> won allied support for a proposal for reducing both <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact conventional forces to 275,000 per side. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> went along after initially resisting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> efforts to deal with troop reductions before grappling with the nuclear issue. `` I do n't want to get off track by reopening the <ORGANIZATION> SNF </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- short-range nuclear forces -RRB- issue when we have a good package that has wide support,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. The president said he has no plans to `` go one up'' with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> when he visits eastern <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> or to `` try to establish a popularity level in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. That's not what sound foreign policy is about.'' `` I am delighted that he enjoys popularity in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. I am delighted when he goes to <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. I am pleased when he goes to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. It is good for world peace when he takes those trips. And I expect he will be delighted when I go to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and when I go to <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, for we will be well received in those countries.'' Later Thursday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told a White House symposium on <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> he will urge <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> allies to join in an aid package for the Polish and Hungarian economies. However, he indicated <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> resources are limited, and that the two nations must primarily help themselves by reforming their own economies.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-EastGermany Bjt   07-07 0673</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-East Germany, Bjt,0695</SECOND>
<HEAD>East Germany's Hard-Line Leadership Increasingly Isolated</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GIRARD C. STEICHEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was heralding improved East-West relations in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> recently, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> was exhorting its young people to defend socialism `` with weapons'' if necessary. <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s aging leadership is growing increasingly uneasy over the momentum of reforms in other <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact countries, and over the warming of relations between the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. `` <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s leaders are n't having a very good time right now,'' said <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON> <PERSON> Timmermann </PERSON>, a foreign affairs expert at <LOCATION> Cologne </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> European and International Studies `` Everywhere they look there are changes going on that threaten them,'' <PERSON> Timmermann </PERSON> said, referring to political and economic reforms in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s state media gave scant attention to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s June visit to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, where he was enthusiastically received by citizens Better relations between <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> mean more headaches for <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, which has suffered for years from an identity crisis in the shadow of its prosperous western neighbor. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s popularity in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> also has posed increasing problems as public dissatisfaction mounts over the lack of reforms in the nation. Many East Germans look to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in the hope that he can help bring change to their rigidly controlled society. But <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, once the <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION>'s staunchest ideological ally, has begun a campaign to reinforce its orthodox communist views and has vehemently attacked advocates of change at home and abroad. While <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was being feted in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Margot </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s education minister and the wife of the party <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>, urged the nation's youth to be prepared to fight for socialism. `` This is a time of struggle,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> told delegates attending an education congress in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. `` The times need a generation of young people who are willing to struggle to defend socialism ... with weapons in their hands if necessary.'' East German leaders promptly defended <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s June 3-4 crackdown on the pro-democracy movement, saying violence was necessary to stop a `` counterrevolutionary overthrow of people's power in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>.'' Security forces beat and detained demonstrators who tried to deliver petitions to the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> to protest the crackdown. In a rare public attack against a fellow <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact nation, East German officials denounced political and economic reforms in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Joachim </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrmann </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s policy-making <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` The developments in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> fill us with great concern.'' `` Under the flag of ` renewing socialism,' forces are at work that strive for the removal of socialism,'' <PERSON> Herrmann </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and opposition groups have agreed to hold multiparty elections by next summer, and the country has embarked on bold economic reforms, including more cooperation with the West. <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> is equally troubled by political developments in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. State media have largely ignored Solidarity's stunning victories last month over Communist candidates. The ruling Politburo also has stepped up its campaign against would-be reformers in the East German party's ranks. In one of the sharpest official rebukes in a decade, the Politburo denounced <LOCATION> Dresden </LOCATION>'s party leadership as `` ineffective in controlling hostile bourgeois activities.'' <LOCATION> Dresden </LOCATION>'s party chief, <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Modrow </PERSON>, is considered sympathetic to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s program of economic reforms and glasnost. There also are signs the East German government fears that public dissatisfaction over the lack of changes in its society could lead to violent street protests. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Morgenpost </ORGANIZATION> newspaper reported on June 30 that <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> had nearly doubled the strength of its elite riot control force. Travel restrictions, long in force for visits to the West, also are being imposed for trips to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. West German news reports have said <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> is increasingly reluctant to extradite East Germans if they flee to <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>. The Hungarians have begun dismantling some border barriers with <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, making it easier for East Germans to flee to the West than over the heavily fortified border between <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Italy-Politics     07-07 0142</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Italy-Politics,0146</SECOND>
<HEAD>De Mita Gives Up on Forming New Government</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> entered its eighth week without a government today after Premier-designate <PERSON> Ciriaco </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Mita </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrat </ORGANIZATION>, gave up efforts to form <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s 49th government since World War II. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Mita </PERSON>, whose government collapsed in May, told President <PERSON> Francesco </PERSON> <PERSON> Cossiga </PERSON> on Thursday that `` political conditions were not present'' to form a new coalition. His efforts apparently were blocked by <PERSON> Bettino </PERSON> <PERSON> Craxi </PERSON>, whose Socialists were the second-largest party in the former coalition after the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Cossiga </PERSON>'s office said the president `` intends to press for a solution to the government crisis and solve it as soon as possible.'' <PERSON> Cossiga </PERSON> was scheduled to start negotiations with party leaders Saturday. The state-owned <ORGANIZATION> RAI </ORGANIZATION> television quoted unidentified sources as saying he would choose another <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrat </ORGANIZATION> to try to form a coalition.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890707-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-89 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Mideast Bjt   07-07 0673</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Mideast, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Plan For Talks Faltering</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
