<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 2348EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Guatemala-Riot 2ndLd-Writethru   03-26 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Guatemala-Riot, 2nd Ld-Writethru,a0737,0416</SECOND>
<HEAD>Inmates Seize Guatemalan Prison Farm, Hold Hostages; Deaths Reported</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS throughout, UPDATING with additional reports of dead and
wounded, eyewitness account. No pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GUATEMALA CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Inmates took over a prison farm Sunday and seized guards and visitors as hostages, news broadcasts said, with as many as five people killed and up to 20 injured. Television station <PERSON> Notisiete </PERSON> said Easter was a visiting day and about 250 prisoners were holding an estimated 400 people hostage, including guards, other inmates and visiting families with children. Notisiete broadcast reports, which were not confirmed by officials, said three guards and two inmates were killed. A private radio station, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasters </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, reported that at least two guards and two inmates were killed and 20 people were injured. Neither report gave any indication of the cause of the uprising at the <LOCATION> Pavon </LOCATION> prison farm 12 miles east of <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. The takeover began early Sunday afternoon and continued into the night, local television and radio stations reported. Witnesses said firefighters and <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> workers were seen entering the prison with five stretchers. Prison officials and the national police refused to comment on the situation. Television newscasts showed the prison farm surrounded by police and soldiers sent from the capital. An air force helicopter hovered overhead. <PERSON> Notisiete </PERSON> said additional army units were on standby. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasters </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> broadcast an interview with a man identified as <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> who said he and his wife <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> were waiting outside to visit a family member when the revolt began. <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> told the radio station his wife was among about 20 people who were wounded in a gunfight between inmates and guards. He said his wife was taken to a police hospital and he did not know the extent of her injuries. He said he took his wounded wife into a nearby prison chapel where many other visitors sought refuge and where other injured were being cared for. Reports said officials tried to bargain with prisoners to get them to surrender rifles they grabbed from prison guards, and then most of the weapons were recovered after a gun battle. The reports said negotiations were continuing. Notisiete quoted Fire Department Cmdr. <PERSON> Alejandro </PERSON> <PERSON> Giammattei </PERSON> <PERSON> Falla </PERSON> as saying the inmates demanded to talk with federal human rights director <PERSON> Gonzalo </PERSON> <PERSON> Mendez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> la </PERSON> <PERSON> Riva </PERSON> and that journalists and medical workers be allowed to enter the prison.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 2354EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Spain-CivilWar Bjt   03-26 0868</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spain-Civil War, Bjt,0886</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fiftieth Anniversary of War's End Generally Goes Unmarked</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSAN LINNEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN LORENZO DE ESCORIAL, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The sweeping esplanade and the giant granite cross thrusting up from the surrounding mountains dwarf the schoolgirls and conscripts on an outing at the Valley of the Fallen. The visitors giggle, shout and strut. They appear oblivious to the presence in the crypt behind them of the bones of 40,000 people who died fighting on both sides in the Spanish Civil War, which ended 50 years ago on April 1, 1939. Neither the monument _ built by <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> prisoners-of-war defeated by the forces of Gen. <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Franco </PERSON> _ nor the memory of the three-year war itself seem to weigh very heaviliy on the spirit of a modern <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>. The government of Socialist Prime Minister <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> has planned no public observance for April 1, the day a half-century ago that ushered in a 36-year <PERSON> Franco </PERSON> dictatorship that outlawed the Socialist and all other political parties. Socialists, Communists, liberals, anarchists, Masons and free-thinkers all suffered in the harsh repression that followed <PERSON> Franco </PERSON>'s victory, which marked the end of his July 1936 uprising against the forces of the Second Spanish Republic. Many who fought on the side of the Republic perished from hunger and ill treatment while hacking away at the granite mountains to build the Valley of the Fallen, 30 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>. `` The Socialists try to distinguish themselves from the Francoists by not keeping alive the memory of the Civil War,'' British historian <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Preston </PERSON> explained. `` There's nothing good to remember. It was n't really the end, it was the beginning of very difficult times for many, many people.'' A member of the Friends of Former Spanish Refugees said the government had agreed to help with their project to have as many indigent, elderly exiles as possible return to visit <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> this year _ as long as no mention was made of the end of the Civil War that drove them away in the first place. <PERSON> Jordi </PERSON> <PERSON> Corral </PERSON> <PERSON> Morales </PERSON>, a 21-year-old corporal in the army's elite Brunete armored division, knows that <PERSON> Franco </PERSON> lies buried beneath a plain, marble slab in the basilica, but he says he could care less about the man whose crusade for a righteous, rightist <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> was falling apart by the time the young conscript was born. The Valley of the Fallen _ which <PERSON> Franco </PERSON> designed as his final resting place _ has been administered since 1982 by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrimony </ORGANIZATION> in hopes, according to some, that it will gradually lose its fascist connotations and slip into the vast collection of old castles and monuments that dot the Spanish landscape. Historian <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Tusell </PERSON> and Culture Minister <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Semprun </PERSON> are both concerned about Spaniards' reluctance to confront their past and their lack of historical memory. On the eve of the 50th anniversary and 14 years after <PERSON> Franco </PERSON>'s death, `` it is striking that our country, which has gone through a peaceful transition from dictatorship to democracy, has not, however, developed a shared historic conscience,'' <PERSON> Tusell </PERSON> wrote recently in a <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> newspaper `` It's not a banal issue,'' he continued, `` because the image that a group projects of itself on the past indicates its willingness to live in harmony in the present and the future.'' <PERSON> Pedro </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> remembers the day 50 years ago when he and a group of other 12-year-olds joined the crowds in downtown <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> that hurried to put out the appropriate flags as the remaining Republican troops fled and <PERSON> Franco </PERSON>'s victorious Nationalist forces approached the Spanish capital. `` We rushed into a barracks the ` Reds' had abandoned and stuffed our pockets with potatoes and carrots,'' he recalled. `` Hunger was everywhere in <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> during the war, and we were happy it was over.'' `` The war did n't really end in 1939, the hardships and conditions of war continued well into the late 1940s,'' said sociologist <PERSON> Amando </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON>. `` People did n't marry very much, a great sense of depression set in, there was a terrible shortage of food, and then, the guerrilla warfare against <PERSON> Franco </PERSON> went on into the 1950s.'' <PERSON> Semprun </PERSON>, who wrote the screenplay for <PERSON> Alain </PERSON> <PERSON> Renais </PERSON>' 1964 film, `` La guerre est finie'' -LRB- The War is Over -RRB- as a <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> exile in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, warned attendants at recent academic conference that <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> will be in trouble without a historical memory. To fill the gap, many of the country's leading newspapers plan special supplements dealing with the end of the war and its relevance today. And a surprising success of the current literary season has been a novel entitled `` Luna de Lobos'' -LRB- Wolves' Moon -RRB-, by 31-year-old poet <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> Llanzamares </PERSON>, the sparse tale of three men in the anti-Franco guerrilla movement who try to get to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> through the mountains of northern <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>. The late Spanish historian <PERSON> Claudio </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON> <PERSON> Albornoz </PERSON>, who exhorted his countrymen not to forget the Civil War, wrote that during the 1931-39 Second Republic, Spaniards tried to carry out religious, political and economic revolutions that their European neighbors had taken centuries to realize. French historian <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Vilar </PERSON> says it will be possible to date the real end of the Spanish Civil War to the time when the three revolutions have been carried out.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 2356EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BRF--IceRescue     03-26 0185</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Ice Rescue,0189</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boy Clings To Life After 20 Minutes Underwater</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ERIE, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 7-year-old boy who fell through ice and was submerged in 40-degree water for nearly 20 minutes was in critical condition, and authorities said his prognosis was good. <PERSON> Dwayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Millcreek </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION> was in the intensive care unit at <ORGANIZATION> Saint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vincent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> Sunday night. The boy was fishing on <LOCATION> Presque </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Isle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> with his father Saturday morning when he fell into the bay and through the ice. Witnesses said another young boy tried to pull him out but stopped when he nearly fell in. The boy's father also tried, but could not find the youngster. <PERSON> Dwayne </PERSON> was eventually pulled from the bay by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Wronek </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Erie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Search </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> SCUBA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Team </ORGANIZATION>, who said the water was about 18 feet deep and very dark. The child had no heartbeat. <PERSON> Wronek </PERSON> said the cold water may help the boy's fight for survival because it tends to slow down body functions and defer the effects of being underwater for a period of time, <PERSON> Wronek </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 0024EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0582 03-26 0262</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0582,0266</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: ADDS Langdon obit; AMs separate on Mufti moved as a0577.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Said Al-Mufti</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AMMAN, Jordan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Said </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Mufti </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> Jordanian </LOCATION> prime minister who helped his country become an independent kingdom, died Saturday, state-run <ORGANIZATION> Jordan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> reported. The report did not give the cause of death or the age of one of <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s leading citizens throughout the country's 68-year history as an emirate under British protection and later as an independent monarchy. He served repeatedly in Jordanian cabinets from 1929 until the early 1960s, often as deputy prime minister and as interior minister. As prime minister from April to December 1950, <PERSON> Mufti </PERSON> opposed King <PERSON> Abdullah </PERSON>'s negotiations with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. He was a major figure in the regency council that governed <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> between the abdication of King <PERSON> Talal </PERSON> in 1952 and the 1953 accession of King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>, then a teen-ager. He served a second term as prime minister in 1956.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Thomas Langdon</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TUCSON, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Langdon </PERSON>, 84, a retired editor of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, died Friday of congestive heart failure and pneumonia. <PERSON> Langdon </PERSON> worked for newspapers in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> before becoming city editor of the <LOCATION> McKeesport </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal in 1925. He later was managing editor of the Journal before joining the Press in 1926. He left the Press after six months to become managing editor of the <ORGANIZATION> Altoona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>, but he rejoined the Press in 1929 and stayed for 40 years. <PERSON> Langdon </PERSON> worked on the newspaper's telegraph, city, copy and features desks and was assistant news editor for 16 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Laos-Elections     03-26 0360</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Laos-Elections,0371</SECOND>
<HEAD>Laos Holds First Elections for Ruling Council</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MOLLY YONG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VIENTIANE, Laos (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Laotians voted to elect their ruling national council for the first time Sunday in polling that some foreign analysts described as a public relations exercise by Communist leaders. A senior <LOCATION> Laotian </LOCATION> official said no major changes will be made in the Communist autocracy that has governed the country for 13 years. Hundreds were already lined up at polling places at schools, <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> temples and government offices in this capital city when the polls opened in the morning. The 1.8 million eligible voters of this impoverished Southeast Asian nation of 3.8 million people were electing the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, the highest state body. Officials said 121 candidates, mostly <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> members, are running for 79 seats on the body. The council was established when the Communists seized power in December 1975. Some foreign analysts said the election is intended to convince the world <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION> was stable and an attractive country for foreign investment, trade and foreign aid. In an interview last week, <LOCATION> Thai </LOCATION> political scientist <PERSON> Sirichai </PERSON> <PERSON> Sirikai </PERSON> said the election is designed only to consolidate the power of the Communist hierarchy and convince the world of <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION>' political stability As he arrived at a temple to cast his ballot, <PERSON> Sisomphon </PERSON> <PERSON> Lavansay </PERSON>, the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, was asked by journalists about reports of major government changes following the election. `` There will be no changes,'' he replied, adding that the council will not select a new premier. <PERSON> Sisomphon </PERSON> refused to reply when asked if he would be retiring. <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>'s ambassador to <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Thai </LOCATION> media had quoted reports that some elderly officials may retire after the election, including Prime Minister <PERSON> Kaysone </PERSON> <PERSON> Phomvihane </PERSON>, 68; acting President <PERSON> Phoumi </PERSON> <PERSON> Vongvichit </PERSON>, 80; and <PERSON> Sisomphon </PERSON>, 72. However, <PERSON> Somsavath </PERSON> <PERSON> Lengsavad </PERSON>, permanent secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, had called the election `` another step toward socialist democracy.'' He said results from the country's 4,153 polling stations would be counted by hand, and the final tally would not be known for a week to 10 days. The first nationwide district and provincial elections were held last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 0724EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Soviet-Election     03-26 0425</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Soviet-Election,0436</SECOND>
<HEAD>Millions of Soviets Vote in First Contested Elections</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN-THOR DAHLBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Millions of Soviets filled out ballots providing a choice of candidates for the first time Sunday in parliamentary elections that President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> called a triumph for his vision of democracy. However, maverick candidate <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>, running to represent <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in the new <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION>, claimed many people are worried about the possibility of vote fraud and ballot-box stuffing. He complained that the elections were n't completely democratic <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> polling stations, brightly lit and festooned with red banners and Soviet flags, opened at 7 a.m. Observers reported light voter turnout in the morning, but the official <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency said more people were heading for the polls later in the morning. Voters will elect 1,500 deputies of the new 2,250-member congress, which later will choose the country's president and elect from its own ranks delegates to a new full-time Supreme Soviet legislature. The congress itself will meet once a year. Official public organizations, ranging from the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> to a national association for book lovers, are directly electing 750 delegates to the new assembly. In Sunday's voting, hundreds of races were being contested for the first time in 70 years, a major change in Soviet politics. In the past, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> has allowed only one approved candidate to run for each seat. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, who voted with his wife <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON> at a polling station at <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Physics </ORGANIZATION>, told reporters afterward the sometimes boisterous campaign was just what the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leadership wanted. `` The electoral law that we passed has justified our hopes,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said. `` It has advanced the political thought and social activity of the people, and this is what we wanted to achieve.'' While it was still Saturday evening in the capital, voters in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> began casting ballots in voting stations 11 time zones away. Aboard the orbiting Mir space station, cosmonauts <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Volkov </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sergei </PERSON> <PERSON> Krikalev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Valery </PERSON> <PERSON> Polyakov </PERSON> were also among the first to vote, radioing their choice to <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said. The Soviet voting age is 18, and about 190 million of the 285 million Soviets are eligible to vote, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. Voting is not mandatory and ballots are secret, <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said. Nearly 180,000 polling stations nationwide opened Sunday morning and will close at 8 p.m. local time. According to <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION>, the first election results are expected Sunday night, but full returns will not be known for about 10 days.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 0732EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Pope-Easter     03-26 0347</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Pope-Easter,0360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pope Says Easter Gives Strength to Often Oppressed World</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FRANCES D'EMILIO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VATICAN CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> proclaimed an Easter Sunday message of hope tinged with sadness, recalling those persecuted for their faith, the breakup of families, and sectarian strife. About 100,000 pilgrims, tourists and Romans jammed into Saint <PERSON> Peter </PERSON>'s square to hear the pope say mid-morning Easter Mass on the steps of Christianity's largest basilica. He later moved to the balcony to deliver his speech and Easter greetings in 55 languages. By then, the crowd had nearly doubled, spilling over into narrow and cobblestone streets surrounding <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Keeping with Easter tradition, the <PERSON> pope </PERSON>, who is head of the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> and titular bishop of <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, delivered his Easter message `` Urbi et Orbi,'' Latin meaning `` to the city and the world.'' On Easter, Christians celebrate their belief in the resurrection of Christ from his tomb following his death on the cross on Good Friday. Calling Easter `` the new Passover,'' in reference to the night the Jews were miraculously saved in <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, the <PERSON> pope </PERSON> said: `` God continues to pass -LRB- through the world -RRB- through the resurrection of his son, the son of man ...'' `` God passes and frees from the fear that oppresses so many of our brothers and sisters,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> said. `` He passes where there do not exist conditions worthy of a truly human life,'' the <PERSON> pope </PERSON> added. He cited poor housing, broken marriages, prostitution, and countries where people can not freely worship. He did not name any country. `` God passes where ... the longed-for peace is not yet to be seen,'' the <PERSON> pope </PERSON> said, singling out sectarian strife in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. `` God still passes and sets free the whole of creation ... In his blood all is reconciled: man with God, with himself, with nature,'' the <PERSON> pope </PERSON> said. `` At this point, the responsibility of man gains new strength and awareness ... `` This is the truth which Easter proclaims to today's world, which is so many ways seems to be rushing headlong towards self-destruction and death,'' the <PERSON> pope </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Bhutto-Baby     03-26 0180</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Bhutto-Baby,0186</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bhutto Expecting Second Child</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KARACHI, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Benazir </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>, the first woman to lead a modern Moslem nation, is expecting her second child in October, family sources said Sunday. Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>'s first child, a boy named <PERSON> Bilawal </PERSON>, was born last Sept. 21. A month later, Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> propelled her left-of-center <ORGANIZATION> Pakistan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> to a victory in the country's first free elections in more than a decade. The prime minister's marriage in December 1987 was reported to have been arranged in line with strict Moslem tradition. She married <PERSON> Asif </PERSON> <PERSON> Zardari </PERSON>, a prominent landowner from <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s western province of <LOCATION> Baluchistan </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>, 35, was pregnant with her first child last year when <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s military leader, <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> <PERSON> ul-Haq </PERSON>, announced elections. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> overthrew Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>'s father, <PERSON> Zulfikar </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>, in a bloodless coup in 1977, and <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> was convicted of conspiracy to murder a political rival and executed in 1979. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> died in a plane crash in August. Investigators suspect that sabotage brought down the plane, but they have never found a definite cause or suspect.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-DebtTroubles Bjt   03-26 0830</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Debt Troubles, Bjt,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>It's Crunch Time For Brady Third World Debt Relief Plan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's heralded plan to relieve the staggering Third World debt burden faces its first big test this week when <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> tries to sell the proposal to finance ministers from around the world. The sales talk will come at the spring meeting of the 151-nation <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monetary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, the two major lending organizations, and at a separate strategy session attended by officials from the seven largest industrial countries. The sessions should be lively. Already, the <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> plan is being viewed as a crucial watershed for the 7-year debt crisis, which has at various times threatened financial calamity for major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> banks and turned <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> into a political time bomb as struggling democracies in the region tried to cope with growing debt repayments. The <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> plan, as the new initiative is being called, seeks to encourage commercial banks to voluntarily forgive part of the $ 1.3 trillion in debt owed by poor countries in return for guarantees backed by the <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> that the remaining pool of debt will be repaid. The new administration received high marks for abandoning what many considered to be the failed policies of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, which repeatedly refused to endorse any broad-scale effort at debt forgiveness. But critics, including many of the largest debtor countries, complain that the <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> proposal does not go far enough, especially in view of the economic and political pressures building in much of <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. Riots in <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> last month left more than 300 people dead after the government announced a new austerity program implemented to please the <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> and other creditors who hold $ 33 billion of that country's debt. The administration is hoping to come out of the <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> session with a general endorsement of the principles of the new debt approach when the meetings wrap up on April 4. But many of the debtor countries are pushing for quick debt relief to accompany the rhetoric. <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>'s President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> has termed the <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> proposals `` very timid'' and officials in that country are already saying they may have to defer debt repayments if they do n't get help soon. Similar warnings have come from <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Some observers say that the <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> plan, while attempting to resolve the debt crisis, may initially lead to a greater period of instability as debtors balk at meeting obligations on their old debt while they wait to see the details of the debt relief packages. Former <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Volcker </PERSON>, who played a leading role in the initial <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> response to the debt crisis in 1982, has warned that debt reduction could end up hurting both creditor and debtor countries if not properly managed. Most observers believe the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> must come up with concrete results quickly, at least with new initiatives for <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>, or risk more turmoil because of dashed expectations. `` It is important that debtor nations not get their expectations too high. The <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> proposal represents measured improvement, not radical relief,'' said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Cline </PERSON>, an economist with the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economics </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> think tank. Assistant Treasury Secretary <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulford </PERSON>, the key architect of the <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> plan, says the administration's goal is to reduce the total debt burden of 39 heavily indebted countries by 20 percent over a three-year period with a similar 20 percent reduction in interest payments. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> believes that commercial banks can be enticed into writing off a portion of their Third World loans by getting the <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> to earmark an unspecified amount of funds to essentially guarantee the payments on the remaining level of debt. Officials of the lending organizations, while generally supportive of the <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> proposals, said they need to see details on just how much money they will be expected to put up. In addition to trying to line up support with the two major lending organizations, <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> faces the task of selling his proposals to officials of the world's largest industrial countries. Finance ministers and central bank presidents of the so-called Group of Seven, composed of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, will hold daylong discussions which are expected to focus on the debt plan. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> used a similar get-acquainted session in February to sound out <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> allies to the debt proposal the administration was crafting. Based on initial comments, many observers expect the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration will win at least general agreement from the debtor and creditor countries and officials at the world lending organizations that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> proposals are worth pursuing. `` The less-developed countries are now expecting something to be done and that means something has to be done,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyss </PERSON>, chief financial economist at <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, consulting firm. `` <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> has clearly signalled the direction in which things will move.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Israel-Begin     03-26 0784</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel-Begin,0811</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rejection Of Begin Play Highlights Ambivalence Toward Leader</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Peace-Anniversary, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KARIN LAUB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a new play about <PERSON> Menachem </PERSON> <PERSON> Begin </PERSON>, the enigmatic former <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> leader fantasizes about bombing <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> to retaliate for the Holocaust and imagines being mobbed by admirers after ending his self-imposed seclusion. The one-man play was written for the <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> Festival in May but was rejected by festival officials who feared such free-wheeling treatment of the 75-year-old Begin was too controversial. The rejection highlights the ambivalence and strong emotions Begin still generates among Israelis nearly six years after he unexpectedly resigned as prime minister and shut himself in his two-story apartment at the edge of the <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> pine forest. `` To the nationalists, Begin is a sacred man, a symbol of everything that is pure and good. To those on the left, he stands for everything they despise,'' said <PERSON> Ehud </PERSON> <PERSON> Sprinzak </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Hebrew </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> professor and expert on right-wing Israeli politics. Begin became prime minister in 1977, the first from the right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> bloc to hold the post. Two years later, he signed the historic peace treaty with <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, sharing the Nobel Peace Prize with President <PERSON> Anwar </PERSON> <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>. He resigned in 1983 at the height of the war in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. Today, Begin's life is shrouded in mystery, frustrating biographers and heightening curiosity among Israelis. He ventures outside his apartment for a public appearance only once a year to attend a memorial service for his wife, <PERSON> Aliza </PERSON>, who died in 1982. Begin breaks his silence rarely, usually to comment briefly on the radio about history. He refuses to discuss his resignation, commonly attributed to depression over the death of his wife and the <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> war, in which more than 600 Israelis died. On Sunday, Begin commented on the 10th anniversary of the Israel-Egypt peace accord, taking the unusual step of speaking about current politics and criticizing the new American dialogue with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> as `` a negative, harmful phenomenon.'' He spends his days reading books, mostly biographies and history, said longtime Begin aide <PERSON> Yehiel </PERSON> <PERSON> Kadishai </PERSON>. He said Begin keeps up with news programs, reads <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> and foreign newspapers, and answers several dozen letters a week. Once an avid movie-goer, he now watches videos in the evenings. `` He likes Westerns,'' said <PERSON> Kadishai </PERSON>, adding that the former prime minister also used to watch the American soap opera `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>.'' American oil magnate <PERSON> Armand </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammer </PERSON> offered to donate $ 750,000 to Begin's favorite charity if the former prime minister wrote his autobiography, but <PERSON> Begin </PERSON> has declined, <PERSON> Kadishai </PERSON> said. His family, aides and friends refuse to talk about Begin in what <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> journalists have described as a wall of silence. Justice Minister <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Meridor </PERSON>, a longtime friend, visits Begin every Friday to talk politics. When asked for details about the talks, <PERSON> Meridor </PERSON> balked. `` I've never spoken about my conversations with Begin.'' <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> journalist <PERSON> Amnon </PERSON> <PERSON> Dankner </PERSON> tried to skirt these obstacles and probe the former prime minister's psyche in his one-man play, titled simply `` Begin.'' In one scene, <PERSON> Begin </PERSON> imagines ending his seclusion. `` People will see me and will be amazed,'' he says, dreaming of a crowd cheering and shouting `` long live Begin.'' But then he stops himself and asks: `` What would be the point of all those years? All the silence, the self-imprisonment?'' In another scene, Begin fantasizes about ordering a strike against <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in retaliation for the Nazi Holocaust in which 6 million Jews, including Begin's parents and brother, were killed. `` On that day, bodies would pile up at the entrances of towns and squares, like they were piled up at the entrances of the camps,'' says the Begin character. <PERSON> Dankner </PERSON> said he and many other Israelis share these revenge fantasies, adding that Begin's ability to articulate such emotions was at the root of his popularity. `` In every Israeli, there is a little Begin,'' he said. `` He expressed our fears, our nightmares, our delusions of grandeur.'' Even today, the mention of Begin sparks strong reactions. During an election rally last fall, <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> followers listened politely to speeches by party leaders, but at the mention of Begin's name worked themselves into a frenzy, clapping and shouting the name of the former leader for several minutes. But anger toward Begin has remained just as strong. While Begin celebrated his birthday last summer, a crowd gathered outside his apartment, including a <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> woman whose son was killed in the June 1982 <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> invasion. `` This man caused dozens of young men not to reach even their 20th birthdays,'' said the woman, <PERSON> Raya </PERSON> <PERSON> Harnik </PERSON>. `` In the middle of the war he just said he could n't go on any longer. The bereaved parents never had such a privilege.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1203EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Soviet-Checklist     03-26 0191</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Checklist,0204</SECOND>
<HEAD>Candidates in Soviet Election at a Glance</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Soviet-Election, Bjt</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Here are some key contested races for Sunday's national parliamentary elections in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> MOSCOW </LOCATION>: <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>, former <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief and former non-voting member of the ruling Politburo, vs. <PERSON> Yevgeny </PERSON> <PERSON> Brakov </PERSON>, head of the ZIL automobile factory.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> LITHUANIA </LOCATION>: Premier <PERSON> Vytautas </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakalauskas </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Jonus </PERSON> <PERSON> Kubilus </PERSON>, head of <ORGANIZATION> Vilnius </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and a member of the Sajudis grassroots political movement. President <PERSON> Vytautas </PERSON> <PERSON> Astrauskas </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Oleka </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Sajudis </ORGANIZATION> candidate.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> ESTONIA </LOCATION>: <PERSON> Edgar </PERSON> <PERSON> Savisaar </PERSON>, a leader of the grassroots political movement <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, vs. <PERSON> Allik </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaak </PERSON>, a local <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief in <LOCATION> Viljandi </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Marju </PERSON> <PERSON> Lauristen </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> leader, vs. <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Toots </PERSON>, editor of a Russian-language newspaper in the university town of <LOCATION> Tartu </LOCATION>. Ants Paju, editor of <ORGANIZATION> Eesti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loodus </ORGANIZATION>, a nature magazine, vs. <PERSON> Gustav </PERSON> <PERSON> Tonspoeg </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION>'s top official for agriculture. Rein Vederman, editor of the Raduga literary magazine, vs. <PERSON> Georgi </PERSON> <PERSON> Alyoshin </PERSON>, the No. 2 official in the <ORGANIZATION> Estonian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and seven others, including members of a <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> nationalist organization.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> UKRAINE </LOCATION>: <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Drach </PERSON>, head of the grassroots political movement <PERSON> Narodni </PERSON> <PERSON> Rukh </PERSON>, vs. six other candidates.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Nepal-Bus     03-26 0089</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Nepal-Bus,0090</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fourteen Killed In Bus Accident In Nepal</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KATMANDU, Nepal (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bus traveling in western <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION> went out of control and plunged 200 feet down a cliff, killing 14 people and injuring 60, the national news agency RSS reported Sunday. The bus was driving from <LOCATION> Dhangadhi </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Dadeldhura </LOCATION>, 310 miles west of <LOCATION> Katmandu </LOCATION>, when the accident occurred Saturday. The news agency said police arrested the bus driver and his assistant, but it did not say if they were charged or say what caused the accident.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Greece-Quake     03-26 0090</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Greece-Quake,0093</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tremor Jolts Central Greece</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAMIA, Greece (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A moderate earthquake shook this central Greek town early Sunday but caused no injuries or damage, police said. The tremor, which measured 4 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, struck at 1:20 a.m., the <ORGANIZATION> Athens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seismological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> said. The quake's epicenter was 105 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>, the institute said. A quake measuring 4 can cause moderate damage. The Richter scale is a guage of the energy released by an earthquake, as measured by the ground motion recorded on a seismograph.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Pakistan-Bus     03-26 0096</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Pakistan-Bus,0097</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bus Plunges Into Ravine Killing Nine</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bus plunged into a ravine near the old British garrison town of <LOCATION> Abbottabad </LOCATION>, and a newspaper reported Sunday that nine people were killed and two critically injured. Police said the bus driver was trying to negotiate a bend in the road when he lost control. The accident occurred Saturday about 40 miles north of <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION>, according to the Nation, an English-language newspaper. It said the bus was overcrowded with people returning from vacations, but it did not say how many were aboard.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--GeneralKilled     03-26 0131</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--General Killed,0133</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rebels Claim To Kill Cambodian General</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Cambodian army division commander was killed earlier this month when his jeep ran over a land mine planted by guerrillas, a radio station they control claimed Sunday. Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Hul </PERSON> <PERSON> Savoan </PERSON>, commander of the 196th division and the 4th military region, was killed in the explosion in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>'s northwestern province of <LOCATION> Battambang </LOCATION> on March 11, the broadcast said The mine, planted by the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, also killed a general staff officer and the driver of the jeep, the broadcast said. The claim could not immediately be verified. The front is allied with two other guerrilla groups in fighting the forces of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and of the government <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> installed after invading <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in 1978.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Avalanche     03-26 0138</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Avalanche,0141</SECOND>
<HEAD>Avalanche Kills Woman, Child in Norwegian Ski Cabin</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SIRDAL, Norway (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A girl found alive 3 -LCB- hours after her family's mountain cabin was buried by an avalanche has died, police said Sunday. The girl, <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON> <PERSON> Gloppen </PERSON>, 4, was one of six people who were rescued Saturday from the cabin 30 miles east of <LOCATION> Stavanger </LOCATION>, police said. A seventh person, <PERSON> Berit </PERSON> <PERSON> Kristensen </PERSON>, 35, was found dead at the scene. <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON> died Saturday night at <LOCATION> Stavanger </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, officials said. The survivors, including an infant and two other children, were located quickly and were not seriously hurt, said police spokesman <PERSON> Leif </PERSON> <PERSON> Helge </PERSON> <PERSON> Eskeland </PERSON>. The people were on an Easter skiing vacation when the first avalanche ever to hit the popular Hunnedalen cross-country ski area destroyed their cabin and damaged another, the <LOCATION> Norwegian </LOCATION> news agency, <ORGANIZATION> NTB </ORGANIZATION>, reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--BridgeCollapse     03-26 0109</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Bridge Collapse,0110</SECOND>
<HEAD>Up To Three People Killed In Bridge Collapse</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LISBON, Portugal (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A section of a pontoon bridge collapsed in southern <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>, killing up to three people, news reports said Sunday. A 260-foot span of the 700-foot bridge fell in Friday as a tractor and a truck were crossing it, the <ORGANIZATION> Lusa </ORGANIZATION> news agency said in a report from <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Lusa </ORGANIZATION> said the bridge over the <LOCATION> Limpopo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> province had been poorly maintained. It said three people were killed and several injured. The Mozambican news agency, AIM, said two people died in the accident. The AIM report was monitored in <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-TaxesByStopwatch Bjt   03-26 0802</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Taxes By Stopwatch, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Time Flies When You're Having Fun Doing Your Taxes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After a five-year, $ 1.9 million study, the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> has concluded that the average taxpayer should be able to fill out Form 1040, the dreaded individual income tax return, in exactly 3 hours and 7 minutes. But if it's past midnight, and you're lost in a thicket of deductions, exemptions, credits, exclusions and exceptions, you've got a splitting headache, the clock is ticking away and you're getting angrier by the minute, the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> would like to hear your This year, for the first time, <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> instructions for more than 350 tax forms includes an estimate of how long it takes to complete each one. Time estimates also appear on the thousands upon thousands of forms required by every other federal agency _ all under a new rule issued by the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> to implement the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980. The notices also include the name and address of an official to contact if someone wants to complain about a form or dispute a time estimate. The idea is that if enough people complain, bureaucrats will feel pressured to simplify the forms _ or perhaps to shorten some or eliminate them altogether _ in the interest of easing the burden of government paperwork. Altogether, the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> says, the total time the average taxpayer should spend on Form 1040 is 9 hours and 17 minutes. That includes 3 hours and 7 minutes of record keeping, 2 hours and 28 minutes to learn about the form, 3 hours and 7 minutes to actually fill it out and 35 minutes to assemble the documents, copy them and send them to the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION>. If the taxpayer itemizes deductions, add 4 hours and 34 minutes for completing Schedule A, which lists deductions. That makes a total of 13 hours and 51 minutes. The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> man with the stopwatch was <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Iocozzia </PERSON>, a statistical researcher who helped develop the computerized time-motion study conducted by a private management consultant, <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> B </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Little </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Cambridge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. The exhaustive study, which began in 1983 and ended last summer, included sending 10-page questionnaires to 6,200 individuals and more than 4,000 businesses and tax preparers. A separate group of 750 taxpayers kept yearlong diaries recording the time they spent on all tax-related activities, such as tossing receipts into a shoebox. When he figured his personal taxes recently, <PERSON> Iocozzia </PERSON> said, `` I kept track of my time spent, and I came pretty close to what is listed here.'' The new <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> rule is the brainchild of <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Transeau </PERSON>, chief paperwork manager at the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, who estimates that Americans probably spend 12.7 billion hours a year filling out forms for the federal government. If their time is worth, say, $ 10 an hour, that means a $ 127 billion annual loss to the national economy, <PERSON> Transeau </PERSON> says. It's such a staggering task, he said, that the entire <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> armed forces _ all 2.2 million men and women on active duty _ could be kept busy all year doing nothing else but completing government forms. And they'd need an additional half-million people to finish the job. This bothered <PERSON> Transeau </PERSON> enough to call a meeting of fellow paperwork managers in other agencies to talk about it. When he suggested printing time estimates on every form, he recalled, the room fell silent. Then the bickering began. Someone protested that blank spaces on the forms would be eaten up. `` You mean to tell me that we do n't want to change federal forms to preserve doodling space for the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people?'' <PERSON> Transeau </PERSON> responded. `` If we do this, people will write in and complain,'' a fellow bureaucrat said. `` Then we'll have to change the damned forms.'' `` That's the idea!'' <PERSON> Transeau </PERSON> replied. He said the new <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> rule, which he championed over the strenuous objections of most federal agencies, already has had `` an enormous impact'' in solving a problem that he believes shackles <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s competitive strength in world markets `` Before anything happens in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, you've got to get to the true magnitude of the problem,'' <PERSON> Transeau </PERSON> said. `` We now know that the paperwork burden is far greater than we reported before.'' The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION>, for example, has boosted sevenfold its previous estimates of how long it takes taxpayers to complete its forms. -LRB- <PERSON> Iocozzia </PERSON> says that's because the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> formerly ignored such activities as record keeping, which consumes 50 percent of a taxpayer's time. -RRB- <PERSON> Transeau </PERSON> is still struggling to finish his own tax return before the April 17 deadline. He laughs ruefully at the new <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> time estimates. `` It's taking so long, I need professional help,'' he said. `` I ca n't get through it. There's no way I'm going to finish in that amount of time.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1222EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SouthAfrica     03-26 0546</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-South Africa,0560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hunger Striker Suspends Fast After 37 Days</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GREG MYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A detainee in critical condition after 37 days on a hunger strike said Sunday he would suspend his fast and hinted he may soon be released. In a separate development, Anglican Archbishop <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> told residents of an impoverished township that black faction fighting remains an obstacle in their struggle for political rights. Hunger striker <PERSON> Sandile </PERSON> <PERSON> Thusi </PERSON>, who has been fasting to protest his detention without trial, said he decided to resume eating following a Saturday meeting with anti-apartheid leader Rev. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Chikane </PERSON>. <PERSON> Chikane </PERSON> also spoke Saturday to Minister of Law and <PERSON> Order </PERSON> <PERSON> Adriaan </PERSON> <PERSON> Vlok </PERSON> about <PERSON> Thusi </PERSON>, who has staged the longest fast of the estimated 600 detainees who have participated in a hunger strike since January to demand their freedom. <PERSON> Thusi </PERSON> said the negotiations between <PERSON> Chikane </PERSON> and <PERSON> Vlok </PERSON> were the key to his decision to resume eating. His comment suggested there has been some progress toward his release, but he would not say if the government had given him any assurances that he will be freed. The government has said it would not consider <PERSON> Thusi </PERSON>'s release until he resumed eating. <PERSON> Chikane </PERSON>, meanwhile, said he will meet <PERSON> Vlok </PERSON> this week for additional talks on the status of Thusi and other detainees. <PERSON> Thusi </PERSON>, who is in the intensive care unit at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aidan </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Durban </LOCATION>, said in a statement he would begin eating Monday after meeting with his family. The 26-year-old university researcher reportedly has lost 57 pounds, or about one-third of his weight, during his fast to protest his nine-month detention without trial. Doctors have described his condition as critical and said he risks blindness and brain damage if he continues to fast. The government says it has authorized the release of 580 people in custody since the hunger strike began. Human rights groups say several hundred activists remain held without charge. An estimated 30,000 people have been detained for varying lengths of time during the 33-month-old state of emergency. <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> delivered his Easter Sunday sermon to 600 people, including dozens of uniformed policemen, at an Anglican Church service in <LOCATION> Mbekweni </LOCATION>, a township about 45 miles east of <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION>. `` There is no doubt that it is God's intention for us -LRB- blacks -RRB- to be free in our land,'' said <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON>. `` For we do not want to oppress anyone, we just want to live in peace and harmony and happiness.'' Several hundred township residents, including a band and drum majorettes, sang and danced while they waited for the arrival of <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON>, the 1984 Nobel Peace Prize winner and the head of the <ORGANIZATION> Anglican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. `` I pray that we in this township will know that we are oppresed because we are black,'' <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> said. `` Therefore, we will be united and not allow ourselves to be divided into warring factions. The day we are so united there will be nothing to stop us.'' There have been numerous black-on-black faction fights in recent years, including 1986 battles in <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION> between anti-apartheid activists and pro-government vigilantes. Under apartheid, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s 28 million blacks have no vote in national affairs. The 5 million whites control the economy and maintain separate districts, schools and health services.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1233EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-FatFight Bjt   03-26 0794</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fat Fight, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>Where There's Smoke There's Hot Grease</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY MASSEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A dispute over cooking oils is heating up as farm state lawmakers and consumer groups join ranks on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> in what they say is literally a fight for the hearts of Americans. But underlying it all is a battle that has gone on for months between agricultural producers. The fight matches <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soybean farmers against foreign palm and coconut growers. `` It's a symptom of increased international competition that we have today for all products,'' says <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Reuwee </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Soybean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. So far, the dispute has produced legislation as well as a war of words in advertisements by both sides. At issue in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is a proposal by Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON>, D-Kan., and Sen. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Iowa </LOCATION>, to require more nutritional information on food packages to help consumers know what vegetable oils are used in products and how much cholesterol-raising saturated fats they contain At issue for producers is their share of the multi-billion-dollar <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and international markets for edible oils, which covers everything from salad dressings, cooking oils to margarine. According to the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, soybean oil accounts for more 70 percent of the edible oils used in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> while the so-called tropical oils _ palm, <LOCATION> palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> kernel </LOCATION> and coconut oils _ represent 4 percent. But internationally, tropical oils dominate and the industry worries that worldwide sales could suffer if the current health scare moves overseas from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm group, by its own admission, helped start the fight by persuading lawmakers to introduce legislation in 1987 targeting tropical oils as sources of cholesterol-raising saturated fats. `` We'd be lying if we said we have n't taken advantage of the health issue here to market our crop,'' says <PERSON> Reuwee </PERSON>. `` But it's what any good marketing organization does. Palm growers from <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>, the leading producer of the oil, are striking back with a campaign to promote their product. `` We think we're getting a pretty bum rap from statements that palm oil raises cholesterol when there is n't any evidence whatsoever that this is true,'' says <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Phipps </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Malaysian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Growers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. The latest development came this month when <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON> introduced a new version of the legislation. The lawmakers complained that some products claim to have `` no cholesterol'' or are made with `` 100 percent vegetable shortening'' although they contain cooking oils with high levels of saturated fats. The American <ORGANIZATION> Heart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which supports the legislation, says consumers can reduce the risk of heart disease by lowering the amount of saturated fat in their diet. Lard is 41 percent saturated fat by weight. Palm oil contains 51 percent saturated fat; coconut oil, 92 percent; sunflower oil, 11 percent; corn oil, 13 percent; olive oil, 14 percent; and soybean oil, 15 percent. In general, the legislation would require food labels to clearly list all cooking oils contained in the product or disclose detailed nutrition information, including the amount of total fat, cholesterol and saturated fat. The previous bill would have required labels to identify tropical oils as a `` saturated fat.'' <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON> dropped that provision in an effort to avoid continued opposition from tropical oils producers, who blocked the original bill by arguing it represented an international trade barrier. However, <PERSON> Phipps </PERSON> contends the new legislation still will hurt tropical oil producers. `` It is safe to say that it does not really help their predicament. Forcing a food company to put palm oil, coconut or palm kernel oil down as a sole source oil probably would be somewhat of a deterrent for food companies,'' says <PERSON> Phipps </PERSON>. He contends that negative publicity already has hurt the industry. In fact, a group called the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, led by a millionaire from <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, is conducting a national advertising campaign against tropical oils using banner headlines of `` The Poisoning of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' Already nearly a dozen large food companies such as General <PERSON> Mills </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Pillsbury </ORGANIZATION> have announced they have stopped or are phasing out the use of tropical oils from their products. Some products now carry labels that say they contain no palm or coconut oils. Palm growers have countered with full-page ads of their own in some of the nation's largest newspapers, decrying the `` smear campaign'' against tropical oils. The industry also has commissioned 30 scientific studies, including several at <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> universities, on the health effects of palm oil. Last year, the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> opposed labeling legislation, saying tropical oils contribute less than 8 percent of saturated fat intake by American consumers. In contrast, 70-75 percent of saturated fats in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diets come from consumption of meats, poultry, milk, cheese, butter and eggs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1240EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Gorbachev     03-26 0505</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gorbachev,0523</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gorbachev Says One-Party System Can Ensure Democracy</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Soviet-Election, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARK J. PORUBCANSKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said on Sunday the parliamentary election, which offered Soviets a choice of candidates in many cases, can ensure democracy while preserving the one-party rule of the communists. The Soviet president spoke after he and his wife <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON> voted at a gold-and-white building in the <LOCATION> Lenin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> area that houses the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associatedion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemists </ORGANIZATION> and part of the <ORGANIZATION> Semyonov </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Physics </ORGANIZATION>. They chose between <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>, a popular maverick who <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> ousted as <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> Communist Party chief, and <PERSON> Yevgeny </PERSON> <PERSON> Brakov </PERSON>, the director of the giant ZIL automobile factory, for a seat representing <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in the new 2,250-member <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION>. For a second seat, representing their <LOCATION> Oktyabr </LOCATION> region of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, they chose between two relatively young and lesser-known candidates: <PERSON> Ilya </PERSON> <PERSON> Zaslavsky </PERSON>, a 28-year-old scientific worker at the <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Textile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Krutov </PERSON>, a Soviet televison commentator. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> would n't say for whom he voted in either case. He told Soviet and foreign correspondents gathered in a cold mist on the steps of the building that he voted `` for a candidate who was nominated.'' `` This is a secret ballot,'' he reminded them. The president said his policies of pressing for more democracy and openness in Soviet society, while not permitting any legal opposition to the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, are `` the key to opening the potential of our socialist society, with the purpose of taking into account the various interests of people and harmonizing them on the basis of consensus or a majority.'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said political pluralism is `` not a panacea for solving problems and expressing a plurality of opinions.'' Despite calls by some protesters for a multiparty system, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said he was confident most Soviets supported his views. The <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> has launched an investigation into charges that <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> advocates a multiparty system, which is not permitted under the law. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said he was satisfied with the election law approved in December, saying it `` advanced the political thought and social activity of people.'' Officials knew when they wrote the law that it would need perfecting and that the experience of the three-month campaign would help them make corrections, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said. But he did not say what changes he would support. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was not a candidate in Sunday's balloting, having already been elected to the new parliament on March 14 as one of 100 deputies picked directly by the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Voters elected 1,500 deputies Sunday to represent various geographic districts throughout the country. For the first time in decades, Soviets had a choice of candidates for many of the seats. The other 650 were being chosen from the party, its affiliates, social, professional and trade union organizations. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said he supported competition at all levels of the election campaign but saw no contradiction in the party's nominating only 100 candidates for 100 seats He said many more candidates' names were considered before the nominations were announced.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1247EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BackgroundChecks Bjt   03-26 0625</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Background Checks, Bjt,0640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Virginia Law Aimed At Healing State's Image As Exporter Of Guns To
Crooks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOE TAYLOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RICHMOND, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Legislators who passed the nation's first law requiring instant background checks on people wanting to buy certain guns say they hope to end <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s reputation as a supplier of firearms to drug dealers. The deadline for signing the bill is midnight Monday; Gov. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baliles </PERSON> has said he supports the measure and is expected to sign it. It would take effect Nov. 1. Debate on the bill saw weapons drawn in the halls of the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. The sponsor of the measure took a Soviet-designed AK-47 assault rifle to a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committee hearing, saying he wanted to show that dangerous guns can be sold to anyone who has the money. Sen. M.E. `` Sonny'' <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON> said the gun was similar to one that was used to wound him when he served in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. The measure awaiting <PERSON> Baliles </PERSON>' signature is designed to keep assault rifles and handguns with barrels 5 inches long or less out of the hands of convicted and wanted felons. It sets up instant background checks on resident purchasers; non-residents may have to wait up to a week while the checks are made before they can take home a gun. The system will be similar to that used by merchants checking the validity of a credit card. Gun dealers, after checking a purchaser's identification, will call a toll-free number operated by the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>. In minutes, an officer at a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> computer terminal will determine if the purchaser has a criminal record. At present in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, there are no identification requirements or other state restrictions on gun purchases. Gun owners who want to carry a concealed weapon need a permit, but for others, no license is required and no registration files are maintained. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> referred to the state's reputation as a gun exporter a week ago when he put some of the blame for his city's high murder rate on <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> guns. The impetus for the measure came in December when a student at a school in <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON>' hometown of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> was charged with killing a teacher and wounding another with an assault gun. The final measure, which passed the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> 33-6 and the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delegates </ORGANIZATION> 81-15 in February, was a carefully crafted compromise to satisfy gun dealers, gun control advocates and firearms owners. `` What we basically have is a win-win situation from the standpoint of everyone concerned,'' said <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cahen </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> and Revolver Association. Gun owners lobbied for the instant-check provision because they did not want gun buyers to have to wait for days before taking home their purchases. They also won a provision preventing information in criminal background checks from being used as registration files. Gun dealers lobbied to make sure they would not be swamped with paperwork. The law places most of the record-keeping burden on <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>. Advocates of gun control wanted an outright ban on sales of military-type rifles and small handguns but accepted background checks as a first step. State Delegate <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranwell </PERSON>, who wrote most of the compromise language, said his aim was to fix <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s reputation as an exporter of guns to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> drug dealers. `` I want to make sure those people buy their firearms somewhere else,'' he said. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Cunningham </PERSON>, state liaison with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> is the first state to have an instant background checks law, although the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is looking into such a requirement nationwide. <PERSON> Cunningham </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> wants instant checks to replace waiting periods or license requirements in states that have such laws.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1249EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i NewCabinetEndorsesPeacePlan     03-26 0471</FIRST>
<SECOND>New Cabinet Endorses Peace Plan</SECOND>
<BYLINE>With Sudan-Famine, Bjt ^By MOHAMED OSMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KHARTOUM, Sudan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new coalition Cabinet on Sunday endorsed a tentative peace agreement with southern rebels, calling for an immediate cease-fire to a six-year civil war that has created a severe famine. The peace plan was the first act of the Cabinet of the war-weary country. The war costs the faltering economy $ 1 million a day, and the famine has killed hundreds of thousands of southerners. The peace plan calls for a controversial suspension of Islamic laws _ a rebel demand that has kept <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>'s Moslem fundamentalist <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> from joining a Prime Minister <PERSON> Sadek </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahdi </PERSON>'s coalition government, which includes all other parties and interest groups An immediate cease-fire also is called for in the agreement. Information and Culture Minister <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu-Saleh </PERSON> told reporters the Cabinet has decided to form a committee headed by Foreign Minister <PERSON> Sidahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> to start contacts with the rebel <ORGANIZATION> Sudan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. `` The Cabinet has agreed on the peace initiative,'' <PERSON> Abu-Saleh </PERSON> told reporters. `` The committee will be in continued session as from now to see ways for contacting the -LRB- rebel -RRB- movement.'' Rebels led by Col. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Garang </PERSON> signed the agreement Nov. 16 with the centrist <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unionist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, then the senior partner in <PERSON> Mahdi </PERSON>'s Cabinet. It calls for lifting the state of emergency in effect since President <PERSON> Gaafar </PERSON> <PERSON> Nimeiri </PERSON> was overthrown in April 1985, and a constitutional conference to negotiate peace. Initially, <PERSON> Mahdi </PERSON> refused to sign the agreement, maneuvring to deprive the Unionists of credit for reaching a settlement where his own party failed. This prompted the Unionists to quit the government in December. <PERSON> Mahdi </PERSON> replaced them with the <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>. That move, coupled with a successful rebel offensive to capture a number of strategic garrison towns, led the army to intervene and issue an ultimatum for <PERSON> Mahdi </PERSON> to resign or form a broad-based Cabinet to bring peace. Political parties and trade and professional unions supported the army's demands. <PERSON> Mahdi </PERSON> finally complied and, after repeated delays, swore in his new Cabinet on Saturday. If the government succeeds in starting peace talks and calling a cease-fire, it would greatly help an international relief operation coordinated to send 100,000 tons of food and supplies to the south before the rainy season starts May. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> has warned that 100,000 to 600,000 people could die in southern <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION> this summer if the operation fails. <PERSON> Garang </PERSON>'s rebels have been fighting for economic reforms, more autonomy and end to the Islamic laws decreed by <PERSON> Nimeiri </PERSON> in 1983. They were suspended when <PERSON> Nimeiri </PERSON> was ousted in 1985. But the <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> had been debating alternative laws based on the same harsh criminal punishments that include amputating limbs of thieves, flogging those who drink alcohol and stoning adulterers regardless of their religious affiliation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1313EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Wright Bjt   03-26 0730</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wright, Bjt,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Speaker Walks Delicate Line</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> seems keenly aware that he's walking a fine line in leading the Democrats while besieged by an ethics committee probe of his personal finances. `` If you are unyielding, an absolutist, you're criticized for being a tyrant. And if you're cooperative and conciliatory, you're criticized for being so weak you had to make concessions,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> mused last week The subject was Democratic concessions on the minimum wage bill, but the speaker's comment could have applied to any issue that comes his way these days. The ethics investigation places the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Democrat, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> for 34 years and its speaker since 1987, in the worst danger of his political career. If the panel's judgment is harsh, he could become the first speaker ever forced to resign the leadership post. As everyone waits for the verdict there is unease among the Democrats. At a news conference Friday following announcement of a new bipartisan agreement with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on a Central American policy, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s top deputies made a point of praising the speaker's efforts. Rep. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, D-Calif., the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Majority Whip, grabbed the microphones to make sure reporters knew the plan was the direct descendent of a 1987 effort by <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> had stuck to his guns despite skepticism even among his colleagues, and showed `` a willingness to take the heat, to give peace a chance,'' he said. `` If the speaker did not take the action at that point, we would not be here today,'' said Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Obey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Wis </LOCATION>. Until proven otherwise, most House Democrats are operating under the assumption that <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> will be cleared by the ethics committee `` I think the speaker has an enormous margin of wait-and-see support,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, D-Mont., although `` a damaging report would be very difficult for the speaker. `` My sense is a majority of Democrats do not expect the report to be damaging, but recognize the report will be used by the speaker's detractors and could be turned into a damaging tool,'' said <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, one of <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s close allies. Most Democrats, many of whom were reluctant to discuss the matter, echoed <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' sentiments. The party is unlikely to abandon its speaker unless the ethics committee, which resumes its deliberations next month, recommends disciplinary action. `` If a majority of members thought that a person ought to be reprimanded, I believe that's inconsistent with the speakership,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, D-Mass. `` The unknown bothers people,'' said <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, the chief Democratic vote-counter. But <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s power as speaker has not been diminished, he said. `` His support is solid. I do n't see any lessening of support.'' There has been much less legislative activity in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> this year than two years ago, when <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> first became speaker and had an active agenda. In this <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> has repeatedly said the House was awaiting an agenda from the president. Two years ago, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> was faced with a presidential proposal for a congressional pay raise and was able to maneuver so the raise took effect. This year, when a larger raise was proposed, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> took a political black eye while the raise was killed. Last week, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s most vocal opponent, Republican <PERSON> Newt </PERSON> <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, was elected the House Minority Whip. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> said one of the reasons he won was his attacks on <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, including the filing of the complaint that launched the ethics probe. To Democrats, <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> represents the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>'s hard-line approach toward politics, aimed at wresting away control of the House for the first time in more than three decades. But, curiously, many Democrats feel better about <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> since <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>'s elevation. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> himself is controversial and, in a leadership position, a much better target for the Democrats. `` It has sort of taken some of the sting out because people can go after him,'' <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> said. Rep. <PERSON> Beryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>., the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, called <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> `` a gold mine'' for the Democrats, who are threatening to make him a target of an ethics probe But <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> said he was not sure attacking <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> would provide much political cover for Democrats to protect <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. `` I think the Wright -LRB- situation -RRB- is separate and apart, and it has to be judged on its own merits, based on the findings of the committee,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1326EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-PeaceAnniversary Bjt   03-26 0747</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Peace Anniversary, Bjt,0771</SECOND>
<HEAD>Begin Critcizes U.S.-PLO Dialogue On Egypt Treaty Anniversary</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY21</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALLYN FISHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Prime Minister <PERSON> Menachem </PERSON> <PERSON> Begin </PERSON> broke his silence on political affairs Sunday by using the 10th anniversary of the Israeli-Egyptian peace treaty to criticize the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for opening talks with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. Begin and the other surviving architect of th historic treaty, former President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, praised the pact but expressed regret that it did not lead to a comprehensive settlement of the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> conflict. Islamic fundamentalists opposed to the pact assassinated Egyptian President <PERSON> Anwar </PERSON> <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON> four years after he signed it. There were no official ceremonies marking the occasion, reflecting the chilly relations between the two former <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> adversaries, mainly over the lack of a solution to the Palestinian problem. Israeli students did, however, sponsor a `` peace party'' at a convention center in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> to mark the occasion of the signing of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s only peace treaty with an Arab state. No official ceremonies were held in <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> either, and only one government - controlled newspaper mentioned the anniversary Columnist <PERSON> Anis </PERSON> <PERSON> Mansour </PERSON> wrote in the <ORGANIZATION> al-Ahram </ORGANIZATION> newspaper that although Arab countries accused <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> of treason when the treaty was signed, they now agree on the need for negotiations to peacefully end the conflict. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> broadcast interviews with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> and Egyptian politicians and even played Egyptian music and <LOCATION> Hebrew </LOCATION> peace songs that led the pop charts a decade ago. The 75-year-old <PERSON> Begin </PERSON> took issue with <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s latest peace move, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dialogue with the <ORGANIZATION> Palestinian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION> that broke a 13-year American boycott of <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s organization. `` This is in my opinion a negative, harmful phenomenon,'' he said in his characteristically hoarse voice. `` The Americans, our friends, are in essence asked to reconsider this matter.'' Begin said he opposed formation of a Palestinian state in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> as `` a danger to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and the entire <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>.'' He complained that Palestinians persisted in clashing with <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers in the occupied lands and sending guerrillas to raid northern <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. `` If this is n't terror, it is difficult to know what terror is,'' he said, referring to <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s renunciation of terror and recognition of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s right to exist that led to the Americans opening up a dialogue with <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. The uprising in the occupied lands is now in its 16th month and more than 400 Palestinians have been killed in the revolt, most by army gunfire at stone-throwing youths. Eighteen Israelis also have been killed. Referring to the treaty with <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Begin </PERSON> said: `` I have the feeling we achieved something very important, peace.'' Begin, who shared the Nobel Peace Prize with <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON>, reportedly became depressed over the death of his wife <PERSON> Aliza </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s losses in the <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> war He resigned suddenly in 1983 and has lived in seclusion ever since. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> was one of a half-dozen international figures connected with the 1979 treaty interviewed on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio on the anniversary. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, 64, applauded the peace agreement's survival through persistent <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> violence, noting especially that it was not upset by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 1982 invasion of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. `` Both sides have courageously complied with the terms of the peace treaty,'' said <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, who negotiated the accords at Camp David in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> between Begin and <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON> in September 1978. The following March 26, the three men signed the Israeli-Egypt peace treaty on the White House lawn. But <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said he regretted that the peace pact did not spur other accords with Palestinians and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> neighbors. `` My expectations and hopes and dreams were that building upon the principles established in the Camp David accords, that we would see a fairly rapid series of bilateral talks or negotiations between <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and her neighbors, including the Palestinians,'' <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said in an interview broadcast on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION>. The Camp David accords offered a wide-ranging framework for settling the <LOCATION> Arab-Israei </LOCATION> conflict, calling on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> to help negotiate a resolution of the Palestinian problem. They called for a five-year period of autonomy for Palestinians in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> as an interim solution before a final settlement was negotiated. `` That principle has not changed. I think it is still a good prescription for the future,'' said <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>. Palestinians rejected the plan at the time because it failed to guarantee them an independent state or a negotiating role for the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, still key issues in the dispute today.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1337EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-YellowstoneTourism Bjt   03-26 0710</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Yellowstone Tourism, Bjt,0728</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yellowstone Park Fights Fire Aftermath: Drop in Tourism</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KURT J. REPANSHEK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YELLOWSTONE NATIONAL PARK, Wyo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>, its image hurt by fires, starving elk and the slaughter of bison, is the focus of a high-powered public relations effort to restore the gleam to the national park system's crown jewel. Nature is slowly healing the wounds left from the summer of 1988's forest fires that burned nearly 1 million acres of the 2.2-million-acre park. But <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s magical lure is being crippled by vivid images of 200-foot-tall walls of flame that were projected into <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s homes by television last year. `` The more sensationalistic coverage led the public to believe that <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> simply burned up, that there was nothing left,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Anzelmo </PERSON>. `` That's very far from the truth. The park is open, it's alive, it's well.'' Thick blankets of snow are slowly melting, uncovering in the park a new landscape. In some areas, where visitors once could not see beyond the green needles on the first phalanx of pines, the eye can now scan up hillsides of charred tree trunks. Lining sections of the Grand Loop that circles through <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s interior are blackened skeletons of once-majestic lodgepole pines. But in other areas, grass and wildflowers are sprouting along with lodgepole seedlings that got their start when the fires seared open pine cones, scattering seeds. Higher than usual numbers of winter deaths of elk and <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>'s hunting of bison that roam north of the park's boundary have also hurt <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s image Park biologists agree some of the elk deaths can be traced to starvation stemming from the fire damage. But they also point out that recent mild winters and lush summers let some elk live beyond their normal years and so this year's more typical Yellowstone winter was bound to kill large numbers. As for the buffalo, there are killed when they wander outside the park because of the fear they may bring disease to livestock. <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> defenders stress that the park is intended to be a natural environment, with death and fire as natural as regrowth and rebirth. `` The very simple solution to all of this would be to put up a 12-foot high cyclone fence around Yellowstone National Park, and we can now keep the buffalo in,'' said <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Shimek </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Travel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Montana </ORGANIZATION>, a branch of that state's <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. `` And then we bring in the hay trucks and we feed all the elk and we keep them nice and fat, and then we put out all the pesky fires. `` As a tourism product, we compete with a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> zoo,'' said <PERSON> Shimek </PERSON>. `` <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> is not interested in competing with a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> zoo. <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> is interested in competing on the level of a wild, natural place.'' Getting the public to understand that concept and return to <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> is costing <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> hundreds of thousands of dollars. Surveys taken in recent months found that many people said they were less likely to come to <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> and many tourism counselors foresaw a falloff in trips there. <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON>, director of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Travel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, is sending media kits to 3,000 travel writers throughout the world. Those kits contain a fact sheet on what the fires did and did n't do, a story on the park's recovery program and an outline of the rehabilitation work. Also outlined are the projects the <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> is putting together to explain the ecological role of fire. Those projects will include an exhibit center and `` wayside exhibits'' along <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s road system that will describe where the fires roared and what they did. Also planned are nature trails that will lead visitors through burned and unburned areas. In the weeks to come, TV stations in the nation's major markets will receive videotapes depicting <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s rebirth. Tour operators also will be escorted through <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> to show them the park is still an attractive destination. The goal behind <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>'s decision to spend roughly $ 600,000 on the tourism campaign is to reverse the dip in advance bookings for the coming season, which at one point were running 33 percent behind normal for this time of year. `` Bookings are still down,'' <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> said, `` but there's a definite trend upwards.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890326-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-89 1337EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Reagan'sSubpoena     03-26 0910</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Reagan's Subpoena,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Last President Subpoenaed Less Than 15 Years Ago</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
