<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 2332EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PlaneCrash 2ndLd-Writethru a0742 08-13 0383</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Plane Crash, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0742,0387</SECOND>
<HEAD>Seven People Die in Two Small Plane Crashes</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 5th graf, `A 46-year-old...,' with 4 grafs to UPDATE with
second crash killing 3, CORRECT ages referred to in Florida crash. Picks
up 6th graf, ```This was...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ST. PETERSBURG BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> plane crashed into the Gulf of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> during a training flight Sunday afternoon, killing the pilot and three teen-age cadets, authorities said. The single-engine <ORGANIZATION> Cessna </ORGANIZATION> 182 was reported down shortly before 2:00 p.m. three miles off the southernmost point of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Petersburg </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, which is across <LOCATION> Boca </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ciega </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Petersburg </LOCATION>. `` We sent a cutter and a helicopter out to the scene and all they found was debris on the surface of the water,'' said Lt. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Vaughn </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Petersburg </LOCATION> station. `` Divers later found the wreckage in about 25 feet of water with the bodies of four people inside.'' The plane had taken off from a small <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Petersburg </LOCATION> airport. The cause of the crash was not known. A second small plane crash Sunday near <LOCATION> Mound </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, killed a St. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, couple and their 16-year-old granddaughter, authorities said. The single-engine <PERSON> Mooney </PERSON> crashed into a field 5 -LCB- miles north of <LOCATION> Mound </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> at about 1 p.m., said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Grayson </PERSON>, a dispatcher for the <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION>. The victims were identified as <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Worley </PERSON>, 66, who was the pilot; his wife, <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Worley </PERSON>, 57, and their granddaughter, <PERSON> Angela </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Procella </PERSON>, 16, of <LOCATION> Kirbyville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. In the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> crash, a 46-year-old pilot was at the controls, and three cadets aged 14 to 18 came along on the training flight, said Cmdr. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sportell </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Pinellas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> squadron. `` This was what is known as a <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> cadet orientation,'' Sportell. `` These young people were n't familiar with flying and this was just to give them a chance to get up in the air with a senior pilot. They were not flying the plane.'' The civilian organization, which helps search for downed aircraft, often enlists young people interested in aviation careers. The dead were identified as pilot <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> McNight </PERSON>, <PERSON> Shawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON>, 18, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Flythe </PERSON>, 17, and <PERSON> Damion </PERSON> <PERSON> Weber </PERSON>, 14, all of the <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Petersburg </LOCATION> area, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PhoneTalks 2ndLd-Writethru a0741 08-13 0777</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Phone Talks, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0741,0794</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ameritech Employees Strike; Two Other Baby Bells Reach Agreement</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 7th, ```We're pleased...,' to UPDATE with
details of Southwestern agreement. Picks up 8th graf pvs, `Southwestern
Bell...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Some 35,000 Midwestern telephone workers walked out Sunday, joining 150,000 <ORGANIZATION> Baby </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> employees on strike in the East and West. But two of the seven regional telephone companies reached a settlement with their workers Sunday, averting a walkout by 83,000 employees. Members of the <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> struck <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION>, which serves 12.3 million customers in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, after a midnight CDT deadline passed. The strikers at <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION> joined fellow <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> members and <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brotherhood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electrical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> members at three other `` Baby Bells'' _ <ORGANIZATION> NYNEX </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION>, and <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Telesis </LOCATION> _ who walked out a week earlier. But the <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> U </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION>, based in the <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> area, extended talks after a midnight MDT strike deadline and reached a settlement nine hours later, keeping 42,000 workers on the job. In <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, negotiators with <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and its union reached a tentative agreement at about 7:15 p.m. Sunday, averting a strike by some 41,000 telephone workers in five states. `` We're pleased with it,'' said <PERSON> Gaye </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for District 6 of the <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. `` We're very pleased that we were able to avert a strike, especially.'' Union spokesman <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> <PERSON> Wooldridge </PERSON> said the company had agreed to a 5.25 percent increase in base wages for the first year, plus a $ 1,000 bonus, and a 2.25 percent increase in the second and third years, as well as an increase in cost-of-living allowances. The company also dropped its attempt to make employees pay a portion of health insurance premiums for dependents, <PERSON> Wooldridge </PERSON> said, but there were some increases in certain health care costs. <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> confirmed that the two sides had reached an agreement, but released no details. The company has 11 million customers in <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The strike had been put on hold as negotiators continued talking past the midnight Saturday deadline. The bargainers broke off the talks at 6 a.m. and resumed Sunday evening. The regional companies already on strike have said that most direct-dial calls were going through normally on automated equipment. Some union jobs were filled by management employees, but the walkouts disrupted installations and repairs, operator-assisted calls and inquiries to directory assistance. The chief issues in most of the talks have been wages and efforts by several companies to get workers to pay part of their health insurance costs. At U S West, spokeswoman <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said bargainers would continue working to `` resolve details and complete other formalities.'' Union spokesman <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Frazee </PERSON> said he expected the document to be completed in a few days and brought to a vote by members within weeks. <PERSON> Frazee </PERSON> said the new pact `` retained basically the same health-care program'' and provides a 5 percent immediate raise, plus smaller wage increases in the second and third years, a $ 600 bonus and a wage increase based on productivity. The company would not immediately release details of the contract. <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> Vice President <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Maulis </PERSON> said union members at U S West were `` proud to have negotiated an agreement that secures a fair share of the company's outstanding profits for the workers who made their financial success possible.'' US West services 11.8 million customers in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION> has 35,000 <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> workers on strike, said company spokesman <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION>'s 18,000 members of the <ORGANIZATION> IBEW </ORGANIZATION> settled previously with the company's subsidiaries, <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> said. Strikes by <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> IBEW </ORGANIZATION> members began a week ago at New York-based <ORGANIZATION> NYNEX </ORGANIZATION>, which serves <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>; Philadelphia-based <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION>, which serves <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>; and San Francisco-based <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telesis </ORGANIZATION>, which serves northern <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> and all of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. No formal talks were scheduled in those strikes over the weekend, but <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> and union representatives met for about an hour informally Sunday. One of the Baby Bells settled Aug. 5 with all its workers _ Atlanta-based <ORGANIZATION> BellSouth </ORGANIZATION>, which serves nine Southeastern states. The Baby Bell companies were created in 1984 by the breakup of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION>. Scattered instances of vandalism have been reported. During the weekend, a telephone cable was cut with a hacksaw in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, disrupting service to about 600 customers in <LOCATION> Auburn </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China 1stLd-Writethru   08-13 0223</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0574,0228</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Orders New Work Rules for Students</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf `The new...' with 1 graf to add dropped word `attempt.'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government has ordered that this year's college graduates must work for one or two years before pursuing graduate studies, an official report said Saturday The new rules appeared to be another attempt to prevent a recurrence of this spring's popular, pro-democracy student movement that was crushed by troops on June 3-4. About 3,500 students planned to start master's and doctoral degree programs this fall, the official <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> newspaper said. But a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> circular said students, especially those in the social sciences, must first gain work experience. The new order does not affect students who already have work experience, the paper said. The government already has cut the number of incoming college freshmen nationwide by 30,000 to 610,000 students in an apparent effort to curb student unrest. The paper quoted an unnamed education commission official as saying the new regulation was part of the government's efforts to reform university enrollment and job assignment systems. He said the new order would significantly improve the backgrounds of people in the fields of applied and social sciences. The report said more than half of this year's new graduate students worked before continuing their studies.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Iran-Toxins     08-13 0307</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iran-Toxins,0315</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Iran Tried to Buy Toxins</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has tried to buy poison-producing strains of fungus from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>, according to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. The disclosure that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> was seeking the toxins renewed concerns that the country is trying to develop a weapon from the substances, Western intelligence officials said in Sunday editions of the Times. American officials said the efforts could be part of a research program to develop a defense against biological weapons. But, an American official, speaking about the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's decision to urge the Canadians and Dutch to block the sale, said: `` There are enough bad vibes that we want to stand in the way of it We're bending over backwards to be careful.'' The Iranians were seeking to buy types of fungus found on wheat and grass that produce toxins called mycotoxins which can harm humans and animals by inhibiting the ability of cells to synthesize proteins, the newspaper said. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1982 asserted that mycotoxins were used in a weapon that sprayed `` yellow rain'' on the Hmong tribespeople in <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION> by communist forces. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> began trying to buy the fungus last December when a man identified in intelligence files only as Mr. <PERSON> Moallem </PERSON> got in touch with Dr. <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON> <PERSON> Schiefer </PERSON>, director of the toxicology research center at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Saskatchewan </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Schiefer </PERSON> thought it unusual because the purchase of such fungus is usually from one of many laboratories around the world and not from one scientist to another, the paper said. So <PERSON> Schiefer </PERSON> contacted the Canadian government and he subsequently declined to sell them the fungus. Soon after that, the <ORGANIZATION> Iranian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> tried to buy 11 types of fungus from the Fungus Cultures in the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>, the paper said. The Dutch rejected the offer.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 0125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-StonesConcert     08-13 0354</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Stones Concert,0366</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stones Open Tour at Tiny Club</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRENT LAYMON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW HAVEN, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Rolling Stones launched their 1989 tour Saturday night when they pulled into a tiny <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Haven </LOCATION> nighclub for a tuneup that thrilled 700 fans who paid $ 3 apiece for the impromptu gig. `` Welcome to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Haven </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Mick </PERSON> <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> shouted as the band took the stage at <ORGANIZATION> Toad </ORGANIZATION>'s Place. `` This is our debut show of the 1989 tour.'' The Stones, who have been rehearsing for the last six weeks in the tiny northwest <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, brought the house down with an 11-song, hour-long set. The tour is the Stones' first in eight years. The band opened the set with `` Start Me Up,'' and played several songs from their new album, `` Steel Wheels,'' which is to be released Aug. 29. The show featured the classic songs that have made the Stones one of rock's most enduring bands including, `` Jumpin' <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Flash </PERSON>,'' `` Honky Tonk Woman,'' `` <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> <PERSON> Sugar </PERSON>,'' and `` It's Only Rock' n' Roll.'' <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON>, who wore a T-shirt promoting the 1989 North American tour underneath a blue shirt, traded licks on the guitar on several songs with Stones guitarists <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wood </PERSON>. The Stones have traditionally tried to opened new tours with impromptu shows at small venues. Word that the Stones were going to play at <ORGANIZATION> Toad </ORGANIZATION>'s leaked out over the last several days, said <PERSON> Storm </PERSON> <PERSON> Norman </PERSON>, music director at WEBE-FM in <LOCATION> Westport </LOCATION>. Fans lined up outside the club and hundreds were turned away before the Stones took the stage at 10:45 p.m. Saturday. The audience, included a number of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, residents who worked for the Stones during their stay at a former girl's boarding school in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Almquist </PERSON>, 39, who runs an art gallery in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, worked for the last six weeks as <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON>'s housekeeper. <PERSON> Almquist </PERSON>, who attended her first Rolling Stones concert in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> in 1964, said she enjoyed her job. `` I just spent the last 30 days being his housekeeper and it changed my life,'' <PERSON> Almquist </PERSON> said. Also in the audience was singer-songwriter <PERSON> Daryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 0129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TexasElection 7thLd-Writethru a0604 08-13 0865</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Texas Election, 7th Ld-Writethru, a0604,0884</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ballot-Counting Starts in Race for Wright's Seat, Several Other Issues</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 4th graf, `Democrat Jim ...,' to UPDATE
with Geren reaction; picks up 5th graf, `Shortly after ...'. </HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto FW4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PATRICE GRAVINO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican Dr. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Lanier </PERSON> will meet Democrat <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Geren </PERSON> in a runoff for a congressional replacement for <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, the former <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> speaker toppled by ethics charges, <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth-area </LOCATION> voters decided Saturday. <PERSON> Lanier </PERSON>, host of the nationally syndicated TV health show `` 60 Second Housecall,'' garnered 21,978 ballots, or 39 percent of the vote, to 17,751 votes, or 32 percent, for <PERSON> Geren </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> lawyer and former aide to Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>. That made a runoff necessary, since one candidate had to garner more than 50 percent of the vote to win. Democrat <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> came in third with 12,308 votes, or 22 percent. The remaining five candidates _ two Democrats, two Republicans and a Libertarian _ trailed far behind. The highest vote-getter of the five was Republican <PERSON> Laraine </PERSON> <PERSON> Bethke </PERSON>, who had 1,313 votes, or 2.4 percent. <PERSON> Geren </PERSON> immediately predicted a runoff victory, pointing out that Saturday's combined Democratic vote topped the total achieved by Republican candidates. `` Well, the Democrats won tonight,'' <PERSON> Geren </PERSON> said at a victory party in west <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>. `` It took us four candidates to do it, but when you total it up, we got nearly 60 percent of the vote. I call that a victory.'' Shortly after the results came in, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> endorsed <PERSON> Geren </PERSON>. `` He's a good man I think he will be a good congressman,'' said the former congressman, who had not endorsed anyone running in the special election. <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> said he also would lend his support to <PERSON> Geren </PERSON>. <PERSON> Lanier </PERSON> said he was n't surprised <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> had come out for <PERSON> Geren </PERSON>, and said it was `` a formidable endorsement.'' But <PERSON> Lanier </PERSON> predicted he, too, would win the runoff. Under state law, candidates from both parties run in a single special election, with a runoff between the two top vote-getters if no one gets a majority. The law requires the governor to schedule the runoff 20 to 30 days after the votes are officially counted, which usually occurs within a week of the election. In an emotionally charged referendum in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, voters approved 2-to-1 a proposal to reorganize the city council to equalize voting power between whites and minorities. The proposal received 41,456 votes to 20,823 against. Voters in the <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> suburb of <PERSON> Coppell </PERSON> faced suspension of bus service at midnight Sunday after voting to withdraw from the <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rapid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION>. The suburbs of <LOCATION> Carrollton </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Irving </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Plano </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Rowlett </LOCATION> decided to keep the service. At the American Legion post where <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON>, cast ballots earlier Saturday, a steady stream of voters turned out during an overcast, 80-degree morning. Turnout had been expected to play a large part in the election because few issues divided the candidates, and many residents remained angry that they had to vote for anyone other than the popular <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. In the congressional race, <PERSON> Lanier </PERSON> and <PERSON> Geren </PERSON> had been the front-runners in a recent opinion poll. Each man had his party's endorsements, but <PERSON> Lane </PERSON>, who stressed a pro-choice stand on abortion, had endorsements from labor groups and <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s son. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> did not endorse anyone. Also on the ballot were Democrats <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Petrovich </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, Republicans <PERSON> Bethke </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, and Libertarian <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckingham </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>. After the 1988 election, the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> congressional delegation had 20 Democrats and nine Republicans The Democrats had a 34-year lock on the 12th District under <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, who was revered for his talents at serving constituents and bringing federal money and jobs to <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, resigned his <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> seat June 30 after an ethics investigation turned up 69 instances of alleged rules violations. Democrats went into the election controlling the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> by an 80-seat margin, but faced embarrassment if they lost in a district where registered Democrats predominate. In special elections earlier this year, Democrats held a seat in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> and won one in <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, and Republicans held a seat in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, the 10-4-1 proposal called for expanding the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> from 11 members to 15, with 10 elected from single-member districts, four elected from overlapping `` super districts'' and the mayor elected citywide. Currently, eight members of council are elected from single-member districts and three _ including the mayor _ are elected at large. Proponents said the plan would give minorities a greater voice in city government. Opponents said it would dilute minority voting power. Others said the plan would n't substantially change the ethnic makeup of council districts. The transit referendum on whether five <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> suburbs would withdraw from <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rapid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transit </ORGANIZATION> bus service could affect the long-range fate of a $ 2.45 billion plan to crisscross the metropolitan area with 66 miles of light rail by 2010. The plan also called for 18 miles of rail connecting downtown to the <LOCATION> Dallas-Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> and 37 miles of bus and car pool lanes for suburban commuters. Opponents said the plan would cost the suburbs a lot more than the bus service would be worth.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 0242EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PhoneTalks 7thLd-Writethru a0609 08-13 0912</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Phone Talks, 7th Ld-Writethru, a0609,0932</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bell Workers Strike in Five States as Walkouts Loom Elsewhere</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 10 grafs to UPDATE with details on U S West negotiations,
reports on some workers leaving jobs at midnight. DELETES 10th graf, `We've
been ...,' which is outdated material; picks up 11th graf, `The so-called
...' Strike deadlines were midnight local time: CDT for Ameritech and Southwestern
Bell, MDT for U S West.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By POLLY ANDERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Telephone workers in five Midwestern states went on strike early Sunday, but negotiations between unions and regional telephone companies serving 19 other states continued past midnight deadlines in an effort to avert walkouts. Week-old strikes continued to disrupt service in another 15 states. Strikes began at 12:01 a.m. local time Sunday against <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION>, all subsidiaries of <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenthal </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. But <PERSON> Rosenthal </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Belkin </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said early Sunday that progress had been made in negotiations with <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> and U S West. Talks continued past midnight deadlines. `` We've passed the deadline,'' <PERSON> Belkin </PERSON> said just minutes past midnight Sunday. `` Reports from the negotiating table are that there is progress being made. There has been a call for an extension of the contract. However, we understand large numbers of workers are walking out of buildings and not abiding by the extension.'' U S West spokeswoman <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said, `` What we've heard is that they've stopped the clock ... and they're going to continue bargaining. Obviously, the assumption is that they must be close or else they probably would n't continue to bargain.'' In the <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> negotiations, company spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said the company gave the union a new proposal about 15 minutes before the strike deadline, which had 41,000 union employees in five states poised to walk out. `` I think we're still hopeful we can get a contract,'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said. He said the issues still on the table dealt with wages and health benefits. But negotiations with the Chicago-based <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION>, which serves 12.3 million customers and has nearly 40,000 <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> workers, collapsed late Saturday. `` We were unable to reach a fair agreement with the -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- companies,'' <PERSON> Rosenthal </PERSON> said. `` We are prepared to continue to negotiate, but at this point we are on strike.'' The three so-called `` Baby Bells'' met with or exchanged proposals and counterproposals Saturday with representatives of the <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brotherhood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electrical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>. The unions set a midnight deadline for walkouts, local time. Strikes by the two unions against three other regional telephone companies _ <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Telesis </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> NYNEX </ORGANIZATION> _ began last weekend. A seventh Baby Bell, Atlanta-based <ORGANIZATION> BellSouth </ORGANIZATION>, was the only one to reach a tentative settlement last weekend. The Baby Bell companies were created by the 1984 breakup of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION>, which was not directly affected by this month's walkouts. <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T settled with the two communications unions earlier this year. Officials at the regional companies already on strike said last week that most direct-dial calls were going through normally on automated equipment, but the walkouts disrupted repair services, operator-assisted calls, and inquiries to directory assistance. Those strikes affected 15 states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Rosenthal </PERSON> said the key issues dividing the unions and the phone companies were wage increases and management efforts to make workers help pay health insurance costs. Various local issues are also being discussed. In some cases, the talks involve <ORGANIZATION> Baby </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> subsidiaries as well as the main regional companies. Companies made strike preparations, including briefing management employees on filling union jobs. U S <PERSON> West </PERSON> said it planned to pull its advertising from various media outlets Monday if there is a strike, in order to reduce demand for services. `` Normally, we advertise to stimulate business,'' said U S West spokeswoman <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>. `` If we get in a strike situation, we would not want to overload our business offices.'' The regional companies that faced Saturday strike deadlines were: _ <LOCATION> U </LOCATION> <LOCATION> S </LOCATION> <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>, based in <LOCATION> Englewood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, serving 11.8 million lines in 14 states: <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. It has 42,000 <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> workers and 2,000 <ORGANIZATION> IBEW </ORGANIZATION> workers, according to <PERSON> Rosenthal </PERSON>. _ <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION>, based in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, serving 11 million customers in <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. It has 44,000 <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION>, no <ORGANIZATION> IBEW </ORGANIZATION> workers. _ <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION>, based in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, serving 12.3 million customers in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>. It has 39,500 <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> workers, who are continuing talks, and 18,000 <ORGANIZATION> IBEW </ORGANIZATION> workers, most of whom have reached a separate settlement with one <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION> subsidiary, <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION>. Walkouts continued at San Francisco-based <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telesis </ORGANIZATION>, which provides service in northern <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> and all of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>; Philadelphia-based <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION>, which serves <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>; and New York-based <ORGANIZATION> NYNEX </ORGANIZATION>, which serves all or parts of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>. No formal talks were held Saturday in those walkouts. However, informal talks were held in the <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> strike, and <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> officials told the compnay they were prepared to bargain around the clock, <PERSON> Rosenthal </PERSON> said. The one Baby Bell that settled, Atlanta-based <ORGANIZATION> BellSouth </ORGANIZATION>, provides service in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>. A contract with its 64,000 <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> workers late Aug. 5 averted a walkout.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 0246EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-SatelliteLaunch     08-13 0241</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Satellite Launch,0247</SECOND>
<HEAD>Navigation Satellite Launch Postponed by Lightning</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lightning forced the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> early Sunday to postpone the launch of a military navigation satellite for the fourth time in a week. As rain fell on the launch pad and lightning crackled nearby, the countdown on the Delta rocket continued down to the 4-minute mark and was held there as officials hoped for a break in the weather. The launch team had only a 21-minute period starting at 2:11 a.m. in which to place the Navstar satellite into a desired 11,000-mile-high orbit. When the weather did not clear in time, the effort was called off. The official reason for the scrub was `` lightning within five miles of the launch pad.'' The launch was rescheduled for no earlier than Friday. Officials said the long delay is necessary because of other launch activity in the next week. A schedule conflict with last Tuesday's launch of space shuttle <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> and thunderstorms resulted in three earlier postponements. The $ 65 million Navstar satellite is to join a network of navigation spacecraft that can tell <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and allied military forces where they are anywhere in the world - on land, sea or in the air, and in any weather. The satellite is the third of 21 improved <PERSON> Navstars </PERSON> that the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> plans to orbit to complete a global system by 1992. The first two were launched in February and June.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 0339EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-SriLanka     08-13 0186</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Sri Lanka,0191</SECOND>
<HEAD>TV Editor Assassinated by Gunmen on Bicycle</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLOMBO, Sri Lanka (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two bicycle-riding Sinhalese gunmen on Sunday assassinated the government television's chief news editor, the third prominent broadcast official to be killed in the past 24 days, military officials said. <PERSON> Kulasiri </PERSON> <PERSON> Amaratunga </PERSON>, 62, was shot in the neck Sunday morning at his home in <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lavinia </LOCATION>, a seaside resort town 6 miles south of <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>, according to the officials, who under briefing rules can not be identified. The assassins cut the telephone lines at <ORGANIZATION> Armatunga </ORGANIZATION>'s house and escaped on their bicycles, the officials added. They blamed the killing on the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, a Sinhalese extremist group accused of killing two other broadcast personalities last month as part of its violent campaign against the Sinhalese-dominated government. More than 4,000 people have been killed in the past two years after the front condemned the government for its peacemaking efforts with the Tamil minority. All three government broadcasters who were killed were Sinhalese. The Sri Lankan military officials reported 13 other killings in other violence during a 24-hour period ending at 8 a.m. Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 0538EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Lebanon     08-13 0361</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Lebanon,0374</SECOND>
<HEAD>Syrians Reportedly Overtake Strategic Mountain Town; Rocket Duels
In Beirut</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FAROUK NASSAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Syrian troops reportedly overran a Christian-held strategic mountaintop town Sunday, tightening the noose around the Christian heartland as savage rocket and artillery duels raged in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. There was no immediate casualty report from the confrontation in the town of <LOCATION> Souk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> al-Gharb </LOCATION>, but police said at least four people were killed and 27 wounded in the indiscriminate exchanges across the capital Sunday. A police spokesman acknowledged that the count did not include many civilians trapped under blazing buildings in Christian east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. `` No one can reach them because of the intensity of the shelling,'' said the spokesman, who can not be named in line with standing regulations. The new casualties brought the overall toll to 626 killed and 1,660 wounded since March 8 when the latest confrontation erupted between army commander Gen. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s 20,000 predominantly <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> troops and <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s 40,000 soldiers and their Moslem militia allies. The siege started one week after <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> blockaded illegal ports run by Moslem militias south of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> in an effort to recoup $ 100 million in customs dues lost annually. A spokesman for <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> said the mainly Christian units controlling Souk al-Gharb foiled an attempt to capture the town and mounted a counterattack, engaging Syrian, <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> and Druse forces in fierce close-quarter combat. But an official of Druse warlord <PERSON> Walid </PERSON> <PERSON> Jumblatt </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Progressive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> said the Syrian army's 41st brigade, led by Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Hashem </PERSON> <PERSON> Moallak </PERSON>, overran Souk al-Gharb and surrounding hilltop hamlets Sunday. It was the first major ground thrust reported since the current round of fighting erupted in March. The Druse official, who refused to be named, said Druse militiamen and <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> dissidents opposed to <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>, took part in the tank-led attack on <LOCATION> Souk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> al-Gharb </LOCATION>, 15 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. Police said they could not confirm or deny either of the conflicting claims but reported heavy fighting in <LOCATION> Souk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> al-Gharb </LOCATION>. Since September of last year, <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> has headed a Christian government rivaled by a Moslem Cabinet that is led by <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoss </PERSON> and backed by <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 0625EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Britain-Israel 1stLd-Writethru   08-13 0488</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Britain-Israel, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0612,0497</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Israel Concludes Two Captured Soldiers Are Dead</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 7 grafs to UPDATE with Israeli, families' comment,
CORRECTS spellings of soldiers' names. Pickup 6th graf `After questioning...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Sunday Times reported that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> believes two <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers held captive by an Iranian-backed Shiite Moslem group died shortly after being ambushed in southern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> in 1986. In <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, the army's chief spokesman, Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Ephraim </PERSON> <PERSON> Lapid </PERSON>, refused to confirm or deny the report but said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> considers its prisoners of war to be alive unless it has documentary proof to the contrary. `` By proof, we do not mean through the British media or other media, but through the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. The weekly, quoting unidentified senior sources in the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> government, said Sunday that intelligence officers interrogating Sheikh <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Karim </PERSON> <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> have concluded the soldiers died from wounds after being ambushed near <LOCATION> Beit </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yahoun </LOCATION> in February 1986. Israeli commandos captured <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>, the reputed leader of <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, or Party of God, in southern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, in a daring raid inside the Lebanese border July 28. Israeli officials have said they were willing to exchange <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> for three captured <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers including the two cited in the Times story. The newspaper also said the parents of the soldiers were informed by the military that their sons were dead, but both families told the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> daily <ORGANIZATION> Yediot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ahronot </ORGANIZATION> that they received no such report. The family of one of the soldiers, <PERSON> Yosef </PERSON> <PERSON> Fink </PERSON>, refused to comment when contacted by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The newspaper said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> had long been aware that the soldiers, <PERSON> Fink </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rahamim </PERSON> <PERSON> Alsheik </PERSON>, were injured when they were captured Feb. 17, 1986, but believed that at least one of the soldiers survived. After questioning <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>, the Israeli government believes one of the soldiers died 15 minutes after the ambush and the other died hours later, the weekly said. Security officials said they believed last week that neither <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> nor <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> knew that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> had learned its soldiers were dead, the weekly reported. The newspaper said the third Israeli missing in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, air force navigator <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Arad </PERSON> whose fighter jet was shot down over <LOCATION> Sidon </LOCATION> in Oct. 16, 1986, is believed to be alive but is being held by <LOCATION> Lebanese </LOCATION> militia with closer ties to <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> than <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. The weekly, quoting security sources in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, said Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> has told his Cabinet not to publicly discuss the matter of the two ambushed soldiers and has tried to keep it secret from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to offset <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pressure to free <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> in exchange for Western hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. `` Israeli leaders know that agreeing to such an American request would help mend the recent strains in Israeli-American ties; but they fear that <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>'s release would prompt criticism at home that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> risked the lives of its soldiers for an operation that solely benefited <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' the newspaper said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 0847EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-NorthernIreland     08-13 0270</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Northern Ireland,0276</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rioting Follows Protestant March in Northern Ireland</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BARR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDONDERRY, Northern Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police were attacked with gasoline bombs early Sunday in rioting that followed a <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> parade celebrating a 300-year-old victory over the forces of a Roman Catholic king. Police used batons to disperse the crowd of 200 gathered in an area of the city where disturbances are common after the annual Apprentice Boys' Parade. `` Officers were attacked by petrol bombs thrown by a riotous mob of 200,'' said a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constabulary </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> police force. No injuries were reported, he said on condition of anonymity. Twenty years ago, the Apprentice Boys' Parade caused riots in Roman Catholic districts of <LOCATION> Londonderry </LOCATION> and led to the dispatching of British troops to <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> three days later on Aug. 14, 1969. Catholics plan their own march Monday to mark the anniversary, followed by a speech by <PERSON> Bernadette </PERSON> <PERSON> Devlin </PERSON> <PERSON> McAliskey </PERSON>, a prominent figure in the republican movement in the 1960s. On Saturday, four hours before thousands of Protestants marched peacefully along city streets banging drums, security forces found a bomb in a bar near a gate to the Catholic section of <LOCATION> Londonderry </LOCATION>, known as Bogside. The bomb went off as it was being defused by British army experts. It shattered glass in the Apprentice Boys Memorial Hall, but no one was injured. The <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> later claimed responsibility and said in a statement that the bomb was timed to go off while security forces toured the area to demonstrate the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> could strike in spite of tight security.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 0936EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-PhoneTalks 1stLd-Writethru a0633 08-13 0508</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Phone Talks, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0633,0516</SECOND>
<HEAD>Talks Continue Past Deadline at 2 `Baby Bells'; Ameritech Union Strike</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 5th graf, `We're apart...', to CORRECT spelling of Wooldridge.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Telephone workers and regional phone companies serving 19 states continued talks past a strike deadline Sunday, but nearly 40,000 workers in five <LOCATION> Midwestern </LOCATION> states walked out when negotiations broke down there. Communications Workers of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> members walked out at Chicago-based <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION> and its subsidiaries shortly after 1 a.m. EDT -LRB- midnight CDT. -RRB- In <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> U </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> representatives bargained through the night, while in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, negotiators for the union and <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> broke early Sunday morning to get some rest but planned to resume their talks later in the day. No strike was called at those two companies. `` All of our people are still working, and we hope we can keep everybody at work today while we negotiate this afternoon and get a settlement late this afternoon or early this evening,'' said <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> <PERSON> Wooldridge </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, referring to the Southwestern Bell situation. `` We're apart on some major items that are on table,'' he said. `` There are some things we ca n't accept, things we need to work out.'' <PERSON> Wooldridge </PERSON> would not specify what issues remain unresolved. In a telephone recording on the U S West talks, <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> local president <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Blue </PERSON> said that as of 8 a.m. EDT, `` intense negotiations are still continuing. we are not officially on strike at this time. everything is on hold. But it could go either way.'' U S West spokeswoman <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> also said the two sides are `` still talking.'' The walkout at <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION> brings to four the number of so-called `` Baby Bells'' affected by strikes. <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION> and its subsidiaries serve 12.3 million customers in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>. Strikes by <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brotherhood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electrical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> members began a week ago at New York-based <ORGANIZATION> NYNEX </ORGANIZATION>, Philadelphia-based <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION>, and San Francisco-based <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Telesis </LOCATION>. Together, they serve 15 states. No formal talks were held Saturday in those walkouts. The chief issues in most of the talks has been wages and company efforts to get workers to pay part of their health insurance costs. The walkouts have disrupted operator and repair services, but most direct-dial calls are not affected. The Baby Bell companies were created in 1984 by the breakup of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION>. The only regional company to settle so far is Atlanta-based <ORGANIZATION> BellSouth </ORGANIZATION>, which provides service in nine states. <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION> has 39,500 <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> workers on strike, and 18,000 <ORGANIZATION> IBEW </ORGANIZATION> workers, most of whom have reached a separate settlement with one <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION> subsidiary, <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> has 11 million customers in <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, and has 44,000 <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> workers and no <ORGANIZATION> IBEW </ORGANIZATION> workers. U S West, based in <LOCATION> Englewood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, serves 11.8 million customers in 14 states: <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. It has 42,000 <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> workers and 2,000 <ORGANIZATION> IBEW </ORGANIZATION> workers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 1027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Ethiopia-Leland 5thLd-Writethru a0637 08-13 0732</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Ethiopia-Leland, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0637,0749</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wreckage of Leland's Plane Found, No Survivors Reported</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Inserts 2 grafs after 7th pvs, ``Leland, a...'' to UPDATE with
comment from President Bush. Pickup 8th pvs, ``The twin-engine...''</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ADDIS ABABA, Ethiopia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rescue workers on Sunday located the wreckage of a plane that crashed six days ago with Rep. <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> and 15 other people aboard. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said no survivors were found. The plane crashed in <LOCATION> Gambela </LOCATION>, a town in southwestern <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> 30 miles from the Sudanese border and 60 miles from the refugee camp where the aircraft was headed, said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Haley </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Addis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ababa </LOCATION>. The plane went down in rugged highlands near two dirt airstrips the pilot may have been trying to reach because of bad weather near the refugee camp. `` The crash site was located. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> helicopters put down. They have confirmed 13 dead, and the presumption is that the other three are also dead,'' <PERSON> Haley </PERSON> said in a telephone interivew. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> issued a statement saying <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> helicopters discovered the crash site, `` <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> jumpers jumped out of a UH-60 helicopter and ... they confirmed there were no survivors at the site.'' However, spokesman <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Sudin </PERSON>, who read the statement, also said the jumpers accounted for only 13 people and that it appeared that three were missing. <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Democrat who heads the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hunger </ORGANIZATION>, was accompanied by eight Americans. They included three members of his staff, a friend of the congressman, three workers for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, and the wife of one of the AID officials. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, `` <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> and I were truly saddened to hear that the discovery of <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>'s aircraft revealed that apparently there were no survivors of this tragic accident. <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> and the other members of his traveling party, both Americans and Ethiopians, were engaged in a noble cause _ trying to feed the hungry. `` I have known, admired and worked with <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> for many years. His sense of compassion and desire to help those in need has aided millions of people from <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Addis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ababa </LOCATION>.'' The twin-engine Twin Otter vanished Aug. 7 in bad weather. The rescue workers did not immediately speculate on the cause of the crash. However, <PERSON> Gambela </PERSON> and the village of <LOCATION> Dembidola </LOCATION> just to the north had been an early focus of the search because there are two rough, dirt airstrips nearby. The pilot may have diverted to one of those strips because of heavy clouds and low visibility at <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>'s intended destination. The Ethiopian government said peasants had heard a light plane circling one and possibly two other dirt strips 90 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Gambela </LOCATION> on Monday. Since the plane disappeared, an aerial and ground search by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ethiopian </LOCATION> personnel had been carried out daily. At one point, weather satellites detected what appeared to be airplane distress signals far from the intended flight path, but a search of those areas turned up nothing. The seven others on board were all Ethiopian. They included a three-member crew, an officer with the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>, an officer of <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rehabilitation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, another official and an employee of AID. Earlier Sunday, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ethiopian </LOCATION> rescuers had extended their search for <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>'s Twin Otter airplane into eastern <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>. On Saturday, searchers had concentrated their efforts on valleys and mountains in a 100,000-square-mile area about the size of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. Another Embassy spokesman, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Guerra </PERSON>, said four <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Blackhawk </ORGANIZATION> helicopters and six other aircraft searched Sunday along the path the plane was to take to the camp in <LOCATION> Fugnido </LOCATION>, 480 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Addis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ababa </LOCATION>. Ethiopian authorities said it was cloudy in the search area and visibility was poor Sunday. Bad weather had dogged the operation since it began Tuesday. Fugnido is the site of one of four refugee camps in southwestern <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> run by the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> High Commissioner for Refugees. Fugnido houses more than 300,000 Sudanese who have fled famine and a civil war in their own country. A C-141 Hercules aircraft with additional personnel and equipment arrived Saturday to help in the search. The reinforcements, including 100 more searchers, were sent mainly to relieve fliers of two Hercules already involved in the effort. They had been flying from dawn to sunset since they arrived from <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 1055EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-SpaceShuttle 4thLd-Writethru a0636 08-13 0694</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Space Shuttle, 4th Ld - Writethru, a0636,0707</SECOND>
<HEAD>Space Shuttle Lands Safely In California After Secret Mission</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 4-7th grafs, bgng `Earlier, sonic...', with 5 grafs to
UPDATE with inspection, a few tiles missing, and to recast. Picks up 8th
graf pvs, `The weather...'.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE SIEGEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>EDWARDS AIR FORCE BASE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Space shuttle <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> swooped out of orbit and landed safely in the <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Desert </LOCATION> on Sunday at the end of a secret mission in which the astronauts released a superspy satellite to photograph military targets around the globe. Air Force Col. <PERSON> Brewster </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>, commander of the five-man crew, guided the 97-ton winged spaceship to a touchdown on a hard clay runway at 6:37 a.m. PDT after a flight that covered more than 2 million miles in five days, one hour. `` A super team and a great machine _ welcome home, <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Culbertson </PERSON>, an astronaut who served as the spacecraft communicator at <ORGANIZATION> Mission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, told the crew as the spacecraft rolled down the runway after a perfect landing. After securing systems aboard the spacecraft for nearly an hour, the astronauts left the vehicle and did a walkaround inspection. They found a few of the 30,000 heat protection tiles missing, a normal condition. Then they were driven to a nearby facility for physical exams and showers. An hour before landing, <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> fired twin braking rockets to drop the shuttle out of orbit and start it on a fiery dive through the atmosphere and into this desert air base 80 miles north of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. Mission Control lifted its curtain of silence to report the successful firing. `` All parties here report a good deorbit burn; all systems aboard <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> are clean,'' <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON>, the control center commentator, reported. Sonic booms cracked overhead as <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> descended through a clear sky and made its sweeping approach to runway 17 on <LOCATION> Rogers </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dry </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>. The weather here was ideal, with clear skies, unlimited visibility and mild temperatures. Although as many as half a million people have flocked to the desert air base to watch previous shuttles land, Sunday's touchdown was closed to the public because of the classified nature of the mission. Most news about the flight has been blacked out on <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> orders since an overhauled <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> lifted off from <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canaveral </LOCATION> last Tuesday on its first flight in 3 -LCB- years. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> was allowed to make only periodic statements that spacecraft and crew were fine and to disclose the landing day and then the time. Sources close to the project said the main goal of the flight was the deployment of a sophisticated, 10-ton spy satellite designed to snap highly detailed photographs of military installations, troop movements and other targets of interest around the world. It would help the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> verify Soviet compliance with arms treaties, just as Russian satellites do over the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> confirmed Wednesday that a satellite was deployed by the astronauts during their first day in orbit, but he would n't discuss its purpose. To prepare for the trip back to <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> commander <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> and pilot <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON> conducted a series of tests Saturday to make certain the shuttle's computers and control jets were ready. In addition, mission specialists <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Leestma </PERSON>, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Adamson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> stowed several experiments. Some of those tests were believed to be connected with the `` Star Wars'' missile defense project, while others involved determining how people can serve as military observers from space. <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, the oldest shuttle, last flew in January 1986, landing 10 days before the Challenger explosion that killed the crew of seven. After the accident <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> concentrated on making safety modifications to the two newer shuttles, Discovery and Atlantis, before turning attention to <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. Discovery and Atlantis each has made two space trips since flights resumed last September. <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>'s return restored the shuttle flight to three vehicles at a time when the launch rate is increasing, with three more flights planned this year and nine in 1990. Another orbiter is being built as a replacement for Challenger and is scheduled for its first launch in early 1992.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 1136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--RamsteinProtest     08-13 0170</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Ramstein Protest,0172</SECOND>
<HEAD>Protesters Demand End to NATO Warplane Flights Over Germany</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RAMSTEIN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nearly 1,000 peace activists, politicians and relatives of victims of last year's <LOCATION> Ramstein </LOCATION> air disaster marched Sunday to protest exercises by low-flying <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> warplanes. <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Georg </PERSON> <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON>, an opposition Social Democrat from the <LOCATION> Saarland </LOCATION> state legislature, said the exercises over populated regions of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> amounted to acts of `` terror,'' and he demanded an immediate end to the practice. It was at the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Air Base at <LOCATION> Ramstein </LOCATION> that three Italian aerobatic jets performing in an air show collided on Aug. 28, 1988, falling in ball of fire into the crowd of spectators. Seventy people were killed in the accident. The <LOCATION> Ramstein </LOCATION> disaster led to widespread protests against low-flying exercises by national and <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> defense forces. Public opposition intensified after a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> fighter plane crashed into a row of apartment houses in the city of <LOCATION> Remscheid </LOCATION> on Dec. 8. Six West Germans and the American pilot died in that accident.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 1359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Pierce-PenPals Bjt   08-13 1093</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pierce-Pen Pals, Bjt,950</SECOND>
<HEAD>HUD Secretary Got Tons of Letters Seeking Favors</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD L. VERNACI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The elderly man decked out in his Sunday best posed proudly in the sunlight of a liquor store parking lot, hoping the new <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> secretary would see a family resemblance in that dignified profile. He wrote to <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, the secretary of <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, that his mother's maiden name, too, was <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, and she was from <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> wrote back that he was from <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, and he was sure they were n't kin. That letter was one of hundreds amassed by <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> during the eight years he served at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. Normally, a housing secretary's government files would be packed off to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Archives </ORGANIZATION> where they would receive scant attention from historians, who would find sexier things to write about than the tenure of a man who managed to remain in obscurity throughout his time in office. But the $ 2 billion scandal of influence peddling and outright theft that pervaded the department during the <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> years has changed all that. For a time during the past couple of weeks, the crowd of reporters wanting to thumb through his files was so big the public affairs office at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> was taking reservations. One theme comes through the 48 boxes of speeches, letters, bureaucratic jargon, `` grip' n' grin'' photographs and mind-numbing meeting minutes: Many of <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s pen pals were on the make. The vast majority wanted a job, some money, some time. They tugged at every string they could find, a chance meeting at a cocktail party, a handshake at a graduation ceremony, a family friend in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, a seat in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, a seat at the Cabinet table. `` Dear <PERSON> Sam </PERSON>,'' began the 1981 letter from the late <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>, trying to boost the fortunes of the son of a deceased law partner. `` He's had a lot of experience in <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>, is a GS-14, is a proven Republican, has philosophical credentials, and is the kind of fellow who ought to be brought up from the bureaucracy into policy work,'' <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> wrote of his friend's son. While the letters were as different as the people who composed them, one thing all of the writers had in common was the probability that they would be horrified at the thought of their letters being dug out of the files by squads of chortling reporters. Finding the word `` CONFIDENTIAL'' across the top of a letter discovered in these files now has an effect entirely opposite from the one intended. Instead of `` keep this to yourself,'' it now means `` Xerox me.'' One such confidential memorandum was written in 1985 by <PERSON> Bernice </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, who at the time was director of the office of small and disadvantaged business utilization. Ms. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> had gotten into a spat with <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>, who was <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s executive assistant and now is a central figure in the investigations of influence peddling. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> himself had said that Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> enjoyed power and was not reluctant about using it to flatten people in her path. While the files do not show what started the tiff, the incident that brought it to a memo-writing fury was when Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> sent <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> employees to Ms. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' office to cart away the furniture. After leading off with Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>'s `` lack of sophistication and immaturity,'' Ms. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> went on to call her a liar and say, `` I am not intimidated by your threats.'' `` It is my hope that attitudinal vindictiveness be put aside in the interest of effectively carrying out the secretary's goals and objectives,'' Ms. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> wrote. A formal reply to Ms. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> was not found in the files, but the fact that someone had marked her errors of spelling and grammar gives some indication of what the tone must have been. Some of the papers in the files are dripping with irony, such as the note <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> sent to all <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> employees four years ago, urging them to report any `` knowledge of waste, fraud and mismanagement.'' `` The law provides broad protection from any reprisal being taken against you for making such reports, and I give you my personal assurance that I will not tolerate any such reprisal,'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> wrote. On the back of <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s memo was typed a three-paragraph letter from <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kieren </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> employee from <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>, who blew the whistle on wrongdoing in the department, got fired and spent 18 months in court to get his job back. `` My experience to report fraud, waste and mismanagement was a horror story that I for one do not want to experience again,'' <PERSON> Kieren </PERSON> wrote. Other letters, now viewed with the 20-20 vision of hindsight, might make their authors squirm. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> received a pair of thank-you letters from <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Dempsey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, both of whom have served as the agency's top investigators and have been instrumental in exposing fraud and waste in <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s department. `` I've told you previously how much I appreciated your support and backing,'' <PERSON> Dempsey </PERSON> wrote in thanking <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> for attending his 1985 retirement party as the department's inspector general. In his own note, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, who succeeded <PERSON> Dempsey </PERSON>, wrote that <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> made the event `` an evening neither <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> nor the others who were there will soon forget.'' Some of the paper in the files gives a glimpse of what <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> himself was like. It seems that rarely did anyone he know experience an illness or a death in the family that <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> did n't write a thoughtful note In one case he wrote a letter of condolence over the passing of `` Muffin,'' apparently a family's pet He also was mindful of the perks of his office, once inquiring as to the free use of a restored presidential yacht, and demanding in his extensive travels that he be accorded treatment befitting a member of the president's <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION>. In 1987, that trait nearly provoked an international incident at <LOCATION> Dulles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> outside <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, when <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s first-class reservations on a flight to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> were loused up. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> demanded an aisle seat in the first-class cabin, and an airline employee, <PERSON> Sami </PERSON> <PERSON> Asfahani </PERSON>, went aboard to find a place for the secretary to sit. `` In the course of events, Mr. <PERSON> Asfahani </PERSON> politely requested members of a <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabian </LOCATION> prince's party to rearrange their seating so that I could secure the type of aisle seat I had requested,'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> wrote in a letter to the chairman of the board of <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>. `` Certain members of the prince's party overreacted in my opinion,'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> wrote.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 1139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-China-Taiwan     08-13 0284</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Taiwan,0293</SECOND>
<HEAD>Taiwan Shipping Company Loses Suit Against China</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Chinese court has ruled against the first company from <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> to sue <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, rejecting the claim that a Taiwanese ship captain was intimidated into confessing to smuggling, a pro-Beijing newspaper said Sunday. The Chinese-language newspaper <PERSON> Wen </PERSON> <PERSON> Wei </PERSON> <PERSON> Po </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Zhuhai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intermediate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Saturday upheld the action of Chinese customs officials and ordered the captain to pay $ 5,770 in court costs. On March 6, a <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> patrol boat seized the 1,963-ton Taiwanese ship, Kuang Ta No. 2, near <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> while it carried 31 crew members and 4,760 cartons of cigarettes. Authorities released the ship and crew several days later after captain <PERSON> Tsai </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheng-Hsiung </PERSON> signed a confession that he was smuggling cigarettes. On April 11, the captain filed suit in <LOCATION> Zhuhai </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> port about 40 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. In the suit, the <ORGANIZATION> Kuang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hwa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ship </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> argued that the confession was signed under `` threat, tiring interrogation and the acute desire to release the ship and crew.'' It demanded $ 4.3 million in compensation and return of the confiscated cigarettes. In its decision, the court rejected the company's argument that the confession was extorted and that ship was in international waters, the paper said. The Chinese had said the ship was in Chinese waters and its crew planned to sell cigarettes to Chinese fishermen, a violation of <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> customs laws. Both the Nationalist government in <LOCATION> Taipei </LOCATION> and the Communist government in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> have claimed to be the sole legitimate ruler of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> since 1949, when Communist forces drove the Nationalists from the Chinese mainland. Recently, the two countries have relaxed restrictions on Taiwanese visiting <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 1358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-NIreland-Liberties Bjt   08-13 0753</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-NIreland-Liberties, Bjt,0775</SECOND>
<HEAD>British Liberties: Among The Casualties Of Northern Ireland</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MAUREEN JOHNSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Behind the lives destroyed in 20 years of violence in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> lies another casualty: the corruption of civil liberties in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> itself. In its attempts to crush the <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, a nation that ranks among the world's older democracies has adopted laws which opponents say would look more at home in a dictatorship. Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> defends the practice of detaining suspects for a week without charging them or banning British radio and television stations from broadcasting interviews with <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> members as part of the price for fighting terrorism. `` To beat off your enemy in a war you have to suspend some of your civil liberties for a time,'' she said after last October's imposition of the broadcast ban, which also covers members and sympathizers of 10 other militant groups `` None of us can be neutral as between the terrorist and the law-abiding citizen,'' added Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, who survived an <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> hotel bombing in 1984 that killed five people, including two senior <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> figures. Her critics, however, detect a gradual warping of democratic freedoms since `` the troubles'' flared and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> dispatched troops on Aug. 14, 1969 to keep <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s Protestants and Catholics apart. Twenty years later, the troops remain. The Financial Times of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, in an editorial in December, commented on `` a lengthening list of recent government decisions each of which has given greater weight to reasons of state than to the civic rights of the individual. Most, but not all, arise from the troubles in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>.'' However, the most controversial legislation, the Prevention of Terrorism Act, is a legacy of a <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> government _ enacted in 1978 after 21 civilians were killed by an <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> bomb in an English pub. The act, which applies throughout what is known formally as the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, includes police powers to detain suspects for up to a week without charge. In the decade of rule by Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s Conservative government, <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s death toll climbed past 2,700 and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> has been cited 21 times _ the most by any country _ for violating the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION>. Her government imposed the broadcast ban on paramilitary groups and limited, or proposed limiting, the right of a suspect to remain silent. Since last fall, courts in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> have been able to interpret an accused's silence after arrest as an indication, in some circumstances, of guilt. Those circumstances are: _ Failing to mention during interrogation any fact offered in defense at trial. _ Refusing to be sworn or answer questions at trial. _ Failing to explain any possessions or marks on the defendant's clothing or person at the time of arrest _ Failing to give an account for being at a particular place at the time of arrest. The courts themselves, which are convened without juries which might be intimidated or split along sectarian lines, are also an extraordinary step taken in 1973 to combat terrorism. Last month, a government advisory panel proposed limiting the right of silence for ordinary criminals in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION>. Regulations under the anti-terrorist act have been used to compel photographers and television stations to hand over material to help police investigations. TV networks complained their crews were put in added danger after being compelled last year to hand over unscreened footage of an <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> funeral march in which two British soldiers were murdered by a mob. `` We'd been pushed another step down a road with an uncertain ending,'' commented <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolton </PERSON>, an executive with <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Thames </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> station, after giving police tape of an interview with a suspected terrorist. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s run-ins with the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> are partly due to the fact that this country has no written bill of rights or constitution and thus issues are automatically transferred to the court in <LOCATION> Strasbourg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, instead of being filtered through domestic courts. Last November, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> refused to implement a ruling by the 19-judge court that the anti-terrorism act's detention powers violate the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> and should be repealed. The case was brought by four <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> men who were held for between 4 -LCB- days and a week in 1984 and then released. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> invoked an article of the convention that says the ruling need not be accepted `` in time of war or public emergency threatening the life of the nation.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 1146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-USWestAgreement     08-13 0330</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US West Agreement,0337</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>US West, Union Reach Contract Agreement, Avert Strike</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> announced Sunday that they had agreed on a three-year contract, nine hours after a strike deadline at the regional phone company had passed and been extended. Details of the verbal agreement were not immediately released. U S West spokeswoman <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said the bargaining teams would continue working throughout the day to `` resolve details and complete other formalities.'' `` We're really pleased we got the settlement,'' she said. `` We think it's going to be beneficial to the employees and to the company and to the union, and also to our investors. `` And the customers will benefit as well because <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> employees will be able to remain on the jobs.'' <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> Vice President <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Maulis </PERSON> said the union was `` proud to have negotiated an agreement that secures a fair share of the company's outstanding profits for the workers who made their financial success possible.'' <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> represents 42,000 <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> workers in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>. `` We here in District 7, while pleased to have reached a tentative agreement with U S West, stand in solidarity with our <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> brothers and sisters who are currently on strike,'' <PERSON> Maulis </PERSON> said. Strikes by <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brotherhood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electrical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> members began a week ago at New York-based <ORGANIZATION> NYNEX </ORGANIZATION>, Philadelphia-based <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION>, and San Francisco-based <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Telesis </LOCATION>. Together, they serve 15 states. Workers struck Chicago-based <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION> at midnight CDT Saturday. In <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, talks with <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> broke early Sunday morning so negotiators could get some rest, but they planned to resume their talks later in the day. The contract expired at midnight Saturday. The previous <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> contract also expired at midnight, but negotiators extended the deadline in an effort to reach the settlement. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said the mood at company headquarters was `` tired and relieved.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 1147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Soviet-Grain     08-13 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Grain,0275</SECOND>
<HEAD>Grain Farmers Get Easy Targets in Foreign Currency Experiment</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet authorities have set relatively easy targets for collective farms in an experiment designed to increase grain production by paying for excess crops in convertible currency, a newspaper said Sunday. The newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> said farms will be paid in dollars and other world currencies for any high-quality grain they produce above their average for 1981-85. The entire <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> produced an average of 180 million metric tons of grain during that period, far less than the 210-211 million metric tons produced in the record years of 1986 and 1987. Soviet authorities hope to stimulate domestic grain production enough to reduce purchases of grain on the world market. Farms will be allowed to spend their hard currency as they wish to obtain Western combines, food-processing equipment and other items, the newspaper said. It was not clear if the farms could choose to buy consumer goods. For peas and oil crops, the standard will be more difficult: the average production of 1986-88, which were fairly good years. The two-year experiment will apply to collective and state farms, the newspaper said. Authorities are still debating whether to allow farmers on the new leasing program to join. American economist <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldman </PERSON>, commenting on the program when it was proposed in June, said it could undercut the attempt to convert farms to individual leaseholds. He predicted that collective farms seeking to break previous records to obtain foreign currency will be unwilling to allow individual farmers to break out on their own and lease part of the farm's land.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 1151EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BubbleBoySchool     08-13 0389</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bubble Boy School,0400</SECOND>
<HEAD>School Pays `Bubble Boy' Tribute</HEAD>
<DATELINE>THE WOODLANDS, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new school is being named after <PERSON> David </PERSON> `` the bubble boy,'' the youngster unable to fight disease who died at the age of 12 after spending most of his life in a series of bubble-like sterile isolators. <PERSON> David </PERSON>'s parents were joined Friday by relatives and officials of the <ORGANIZATION> Conroe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> during ground-breaking ceremonies for <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Elementary </PERSON> in this community north of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. `` He inspired all of us,'' said his mother, <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON>. `` I want students to be inspired by his experiences as well.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON>, who died 5 -LCB- years ago, lived all but the last two weeks of his life in sealed, sterile surroundings. The news media throughout that time and since have upheld an agreement not to disclose his family's last name. School district Superintendent <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> said schools are rarely named after students, but <PERSON> David </PERSON> deserved it because his life typified `` the courage so important to the American character.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON>'s life will be remembered in a selection of material in a reading room of the school's library, <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> said. He said the school also will have an outdoor education center because district officials `` felt that would please <PERSON> David </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> attended elementary school through the fifth grade in The Woodlands and developed a `` wonderful interest'' in education, his mother said. He also had a keen interest in the outdoors and dreamed of `` running through the grass barefooted,'' she said. `` It's fitting that the school would be here, in the forest,'' she said. <PERSON> David </PERSON>'s isolation was needed to keep out germs because he was born with a condition known as severe combined immunodeficiency disease. About 30 to 50 children are born with this disorder in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> each year, and they have little or no natural resistance to infections. Doctors tried to construct his immune system by giving him healthy bone marrow, the source of disease-fighting blood cells, donated by his sister. The transplanted cells did not survive, but they apparently infected him with a common virus which caused runaway cancer of his white blood cells, and he died Feb. 22, 1984. It was the first conclusive evidence of cancer developing in a human after infection by a virus, said Dr. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shearer </PERSON>, <PERSON> David </PERSON>'s physician at <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Children's Hospital in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890813-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-13-89 1154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Israel-Soviets     08-13 0248</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel-Soviets,0254</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israel, Soviet Union Create First Joint Enterprise</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
