<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 2357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Philippines 5thLd-Writethru a0841 03-08 0722</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0841,0741</SECOND>
<HEAD>Renegade Officer Sought As Coup Plotter Seized in Philippines</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 7 grafs to UPDATE with Dumlao saying Cabauatan tried
to get away but was captured. Pickup 8th pvs, `Dumlao said...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT H. REID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A leading renegade military officer sought in coup plots against President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> was arrested early hursday as he left a restaurant in a <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> suburb, officials said. Former Lt. Col. <PERSON> Reynaldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cabauatan </PERSON>, wearing civilian clothes and a disguise of eyeglasses and a goatee, was unarmed when military agents took him into custody in <LOCATION> Pasay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> shortly after midnight, according to Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Pantaleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Dumlao </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dumlao </PERSON> said <PERSON> Cabauatan </PERSON> tried to get away and urged officers to shoot him. But he stopped when one of them placed a gun to his head and threatened to shoot, <PERSON> Dumlao </PERSON> added. He said earlier that <PERSON> Cabauatan </PERSON> offered no resistance. Cabauatan's brother, <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON>, and a friend were detained with him outside the <LOCATION> Japanese </LOCATION> restaurant but were released, officials said. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> praised the military for the capture and told reporters the arrest `` will lead to greater stability in this country.'' <PERSON> Dumlao </PERSON> said agents surrounded the restaurant and waited outside for five hours for Cabauatan to leave after getting a tip he was at a party there. He said they were not certain it was Cabauatan because of his disguise, so agents approached him and saluted. <PERSON> Dumlao </PERSON> said they grabbed <PERSON> Cabauatan </PERSON> when the former colonel returned the salute. <PERSON> Dumlao </PERSON> said <PERSON> Cabauatan </PERSON>, a former Philippine Constabulary officer, was taken to Constabulary headquarters at Camp Crame for interrogation. He said <PERSON> Cabauatan </PERSON> faced three possible criminal charges, but he did not specify the charges. <PERSON> Cabauatan </PERSON> was the most prominent anti-Aquino military figure seized since the December 1987 capture of former Lt. Col. <PERSON> Gregorio </PERSON> `` Gringo'' <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON>, leader of an Aug. 28, 1987, coup attempt that left at least 53 people dead. <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> escaped last April from a prison ship in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> and remains at large. <PERSON> Cabauatan </PERSON> was sought after a January 1987 coup attempt, when renegade soldiers stormed military and news media facilities in the capital. The government called it an attempt to restore ousted President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to power. <PERSON> Cabauatan </PERSON> also took part in an abortive putsch at The <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> Hotel in July 1986 and was believed to have been linked to an attack on the stockade at <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bonifacio </LOCATION> in April 1987. Cabauatan went underground and was later dropped from military rolls as absent without leave. In statements to reporters, he claimed to have organized the <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> to continue his struggle against Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>. Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Montano </PERSON>, commander of the Philippine Constabulary, told reporters Thursday there were `` very strong indications that the money being used by this group came from ex-President <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>.'' He did not elaborate. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> identified <PERSON> Cabauatan </PERSON> as one of the major military figures sought in armed attempts against the president. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>, a right-wing lawyer, said he spoke by telephone with <PERSON> Cabauatan </PERSON> minutes after his arrest and said <PERSON> Cabauatan </PERSON> `` will cooperate so the truth will come out.'' <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON> said <PERSON> Cabauatan </PERSON> opposed violent attempts to overthrow the government but sought change `` through peaceful, democratic and legal means.'' He said <PERSON> Cabauatan </PERSON> supported a campaign by former Lt. Col. <PERSON> Rolando </PERSON> <PERSON> Abadilla </PERSON> to forge `` genuine reconciliation'' between Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> and <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> has refused to allow <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to return from exile in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, where he fled after a popular uprising toppled his administration three years ago. <PERSON> Abadilla </PERSON>, former intelligence chief of the <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> area, was also charged in the January 1987 coup attempt but was acquitted by a military court in December. In another development, a relative of Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> charged Wednesday that an American consulting firm was hired by Vice President <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> <PERSON> Laurel </PERSON> to undermine the government. But a spokesman for the company, <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, <PERSON> Manafort </PERSON>, Stone and <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said it was simply helping the opposition organize a political party before the 1992 presidential election. During a speech to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION>, Rep. <PERSON> Emigdio </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanjuatco </PERSON>, said the company `` monitored activity in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and in the executive branch relevant to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>'' as part of an effort by <ORGANIZATION> Laurel </ORGANIZATION> to discredit the government. Laurel broke with Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> last year and announced he was organizing an opposition movement.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Vanuatu     03-08 0353</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Vanuatu,0368</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ex-President Gets Six-Year Jail Term for Trying to Replace Prime
Minister</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PORT VILA, Vanuatu (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ex-President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Sokomanu </PERSON> was sentenced Tuesday to six years in jail after being convicted of trying to install his nephew as prime minister of this <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> island chain. <PERSON> Sokomanu </PERSON>, who has been president since 1980, was dismissed from office in January for plotting against Prime Minister <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Lini </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sokomanu </PERSON>'s nephew, <PERSON> Barak </PERSON> <PERSON> Sope </PERSON>, and opposition leader <PERSON> Maxime </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlot </PERSON> were given five-year prison sentences and former member of Parliament <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> was sentenced to two years. The charges against <PERSON> Sokomanu </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sope </PERSON> and <PERSON> Carlot </PERSON> carried maximum sentences of life imprisonment. Three defendants were acquitted. <PERSON> Sokomanu </PERSON> was convicted of inciting mutiny within <LOCATION> Vanuatu </LOCATION>'s paramilitary forces last December in an attempt to replace <PERSON> Lini </PERSON>'s elected government with an interim administration headed by Sokomanu and the other defendants were taken into police custody just before Christmas. At the time of of his arrest <PERSON> Sokomanu </PERSON> acknowledged his action was unconstitutional, but he said <PERSON> Lini </PERSON> was unable to govern after suffering a stroke. He said he tried to install <PERSON> Sope </PERSON> as prime minister to restore economic power. <PERSON> Sope </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lini </PERSON> had been engaged in a power struggle for more than a year. Acquitted by British-born Judge <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> were former member of Parliament <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Naupa </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sokomanu </PERSON>'s private secretary <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kalititi </PERSON> and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Spooner </PERSON>. Those three and <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> had been charged with lesser counts of conspiracy to overthrow the government and with administering and making unlawful oaths and statements at a Dec. 18 swearing-in ceremony. <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> was brought in from the <LOCATION> Solomon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> to hear the most controversial case in <LOCATION> Vanuatu </LOCATION>'s brief history and to pass judgment. His decisions are subject to appeal. <PERSON> Sokomanu </PERSON> was removed from office in January by the <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> which accused him of gross misconduct. <PERSON> Sokomanu </PERSON> had served as head of state and <PERSON> Lini </PERSON> as head of government since <LOCATION> Vanuatu </LOCATION> became independent in July 1980. <LOCATION> Vanuatu </LOCATION>, formerly the Anglo-French <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hebrides </LOCATION>, had been jointly administered by <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> since 1906. It has a population of about 130,000 and is 1,395 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0238EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Wayans     03-08 0845</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Wayans,0861</SECOND>
<HEAD>Turning `Blaxploitation' Upside Down</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HILLEL ITALIE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In 1980, 50 stand-up comics tried their luck on `` Audition Night'' at <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s Improv. Two were <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Townsend </PERSON> and <PERSON> Keenan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ivory </PERSON> <PERSON> Wayans </PERSON>. They quickly became friends and ended up co-writing `` Hollywood Shuffle,'' a film largely financed by <PERSON> Townsend </PERSON>'s credit cards that turned into one of last season's surprise movie hits Now <PERSON> Wayans </PERSON> is showcasing his own talents by writing, directing and starring in `` I'm Gon na to Git You Sucka,'' a takeoff on the `` blaxploitation'' films of the 1970s. `` A few years ago, me and some friends were sitting around and talking about the movies we used to go see,'' <PERSON> Wayans </PERSON> said in a recent interview. `` The conversation went from, ` remember this movie' to ` remember this scene.' We started laughing and that was when ` Airplane' was coming out and that was kind of a blueprint for me.'' Starting with the death of <PERSON> Junebug </PERSON> <PERSON> Spade </PERSON> from an overdose of gold chains -LRB- `` He was ready to die!'' the preacher boomed -RRB-, `` I'm Gon na to Git You Sucka'' takes on such movies as `` Superfly'' and `` Shaft'' and turns them upside down. <PERSON> Wayans </PERSON>, who also co-wrote and co-produced the <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> concert film, `` Raw,'' plays <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Spade </PERSON>, who helps capture those responsible for his brother <PERSON> Junebug </PERSON>'s death. Assisting <PERSON> Spade </PERSON> are an aging band of tough guys played by ex-football stars <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bernie </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> and musician <PERSON> Isaac </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, who wrote the theme to `` Shaft.'' `` That was the coolest thing,'' <PERSON> Wayans </PERSON> said. `` To be able to work with those guys and then to watch them get up there and be totally uninhibited. That's because they got it. They did n't take themselves seriously. They were having a good time. In retrospect, they could see where the humor was.'' Fans of `` National Lampoon's <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'' will recognize <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON>, the dreaded <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Wermer </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Faber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> is the villain again in `` I'm Going to Git You Sucka.'' He plays Mr. Big, the man behind the proliferation of gold chains. `` My first choice was <PERSON> Shelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Winters </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Wayans </PERSON> said. `` Initially, it was still going to be ` Mr.' Big but you would n't have ever seen her face.'' <PERSON> Wayans </PERSON>' project took a long time to get to the screen. When the film was conceived in the early 1980s, he was a relatively unknown stand-up comic and actor. It was a time when <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> studios were not interested in financing an all black film. They were, however, willing to reconsider if Wynans would agree to make a few `` minor'' changes. `` I went to <ORGANIZATION> Vestron </ORGANIZATION> and they kept coming up with the most bizarre ways to integrate the cast they could think of. ` How about if I get <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> -LRB- ` The Breakfast Club,' ` Sixteen Candles' -RRB- to be my younger brother _ a kid that was left on the doorstep of my house and act black for the entire film?' `` ` And how about if we make one of the guys like <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Bronson </PERSON>.' They wanted so desperately to integrate it they did n't care if they undermined the picture.'' But the success of `` Hollywood Shuffle'' and <PERSON> Spike </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s `` She's Got ta Have It'' made the studios more receptive to <PERSON> Wayans </PERSON>' project and he ended up getting <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Artists </ORGANIZATION> to distribute the film `` It was a lot easier to go in and sit down and really talk. Before we did ` Hollywood Shuffle,' if it was an all black act, no one wanted to touch it.'' <PERSON> Wayans </PERSON> grew up in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION> section of <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, one of 10 children. He was trying to make people laugh as far back as he could remember and had plenty of time to display his talents at the family dinner table. `` There was always an audience and we were always competing,'' he said. `` Dinner time was sitting at a long table with my parents at each end. The objective was making the person across from you spit food.'' His early heros were <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON> and the late <PERSON> Freddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Prinze </PERSON>, who also grew up in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION>. But while those comedians had traumatic and tragic lives -LRB- <PERSON> Prinze </PERSON> committed suicide just as he became a star -RRB-, <PERSON> Wayans </PERSON> has no interest in being a `` tortured artist,'' `` It was n't a psychological thing where I had a horrible family life and I wanted the audience to love me,'' he said. `` There are those who just find humor in almost anything, who have warped senses of humor, which I'm a victim of. I just find everything funny and I like being funny.'' Although Mr. <PERSON> Big </PERSON> mutters ominously at the end of the movie that `` there will be no sequel,'' <PERSON> Wayans </PERSON> is anxious to continue making films and also to help other blacks break into the business. `` The recognized pool of talent is so small that the opportunity is tremendous,'' said <PERSON> Wayans </PERSON>, who found roles for <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Fargas </PERSON>, <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> and his brother <PERSON> Damon </PERSON> among others. `` There's a building pool of talent right now.'' But <PERSON> Wayans </PERSON> could n't help adding, `` I used them all in the movie.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0238EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AIDSRuling     03-08 0339</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-AIDS Ruling,0347</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Overturns Murder Convicted Tainted by AIDS Scare</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM STUCKEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANNAPOLIS, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Court of Appeals on Tuesday overturned a murder conviction because sheriff's deputies were allowed to wear rubber gloves in court to protect them in case the defendant was infected with the AIDS virus. The opinion by Judge <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Orth </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> said it was likely the sight of deputies sitting behind <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiggins </PERSON> wearing gloves led jurors to believe he had AIDS and should be `` withdrawn from public circulation and confined in an institution with others of his ilk.'' `` The specter of the dread disease AIDS hovered over the trial,'' <PERSON> Orth </PERSON> said in the unanimous ruling by the seven-member court. `` The trial judge refused to exorcise it'' despite `` <PERSON> Wiggins </PERSON>' persistent and vehement protests.'' The court returned the case to Prince <PERSON> George </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> for a new trial. <PERSON> Wiggins </PERSON> was convicted in November 1987 of the murder of <PERSON> Bjorn </PERSON> <PERSON> Haug </PERSON>, whom he had met at a bar in his hometown of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. He is in the <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penitentiary </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>. According to trial testimony, <PERSON> Haug </PERSON> returned to <PERSON> Wiggins </PERSON>' apartment, where he was knocked unconscious and loaded into the trunk of a car by <PERSON> Wiggins </PERSON> and three friends The group drove into <LOCATION> Prince </LOCATION> <LOCATION> George </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Haug </PERSON>, who had regained consciousness, was killed by <PERSON> Wiggins </PERSON>, according to testimony. Prosecutors told Judge <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> that <PERSON> Haug </PERSON> had been diagnosed as having AIDS, that a codefendant and roommate of <PERSON> Wiggins </PERSON> carried the AIDS virus and that <PERSON> Wiggins </PERSON> and his roommate were homosexual. Although <PERSON> Wiggins </PERSON> had not been tested for the virus, <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> said there was `` a strong possibility or probability'' that he had it, and denied a motion by defense attorneys that the guards not be allowed to sit behind <PERSON> Wiggins </PERSON> while wearing gloves. The appeals court also ruled Tuesday that <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> should have granted a defense motion not to admit items stolen from <PERSON> Haug </PERSON>'s apartment that were found in <PERSON> Wiggins </PERSON>' apartment because they were not listed in a search warrant
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Ericat19     03-08 1007</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Eric at 19,1034</SECOND>
<HEAD>Autistic Youth Seeks Life's Work Through Numbers</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VERN ANDERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOUNTIFUL, Utah (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tell <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> the date you were born and he'll immediately give you the day of the week you first drew breath. Same with dates in the future. He's a human calendar. Yet it's only weeks since the 19-year-old autistic savant mastered buttoning his own clothes, allowing him to trade elastic-waisted trousers for his first button-up <PERSON> Levis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> will graduate June 2 from a special education program that has taught him the joy of work in an alien world. By the time he earns his diploma, <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> hopes to have found a life's work in numbers. A recent issue of the <ORGANIZATION> Viewmont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> newspaper dubbed <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> the school's `` Rain Man.'' He shares many traits with the movie's title character, but there are important differences <PERSON> Eric </PERSON>'s calendar calculations and aptitude for figures do n't make him a prodigious savant like <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON>, played by <PERSON> Dustin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>. But unlike <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON>, <PERSON> Eric </PERSON>'s mania for numbers and improving social skills let him hold down a job. They loved him in trials at a video store and the school library. Tests show <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> to be mildly retarded as well as autistic and a savant, a mix that puts his promising quest for work in a post office or city library on a very uncrowded plane. `` They are usually so incapacitated in other ways that their skill wo n't help them,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ritvo </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> UCLA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>, one of the country's leading authorities on autism. Indeed, those who knew <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> when he was younger are surprised at his blossoming sociability. Greetings in the corridors are returned with a not-so-nervous `` Hi,'' and he has somewhat relaxed the obsessive routines and rituals that govern an autistic life. `` I was worried because I had heard that they got worse as they got into adolescence and families had to decide what to do with them. With <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> just the opposite happened. He just seemed to improve,'' said <PERSON> Candace </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, his mother. `` He's just a huge success story for parents with autistic kids who normally feel isolated, frustrated and believe ... it's a burden that will never let up,'' said <PERSON> Cindy </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Eric </PERSON>'s special education teacher. Years ago, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s first autistic student spoke only in the second-person and was prone to unpredictable rages that injured herself and others. <PERSON> Eric </PERSON>, her third autistic pupil, is the first savant and the only one to shine at the community vocational opportunities <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> arranges. `` I think he's trying to understand people's feelings,'' she said. `` It's a very rote process, a very mechanical process.'' Autism, absorption in self-centered, subjective mental activity, is a severe disorder present in four of 10,000 births, an overwhelming majority of them males. Its cause is unknown, but evidence suggests chemical or structural abnormalities in the brain. Among its characteristics is a profound disability in forming normal human attachments, or in showing or receiving affection. <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> stiffens up when hugged, even by his parents, and wo n't let on if he's sick or in pain. A study by <PERSON> Ritvo </PERSON> and others published in February's <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychiatry </ORGANIZATION> shows about two-thirds of those with autism have some degree of mental retardation, scoring below 70 on standardized IQ tests. Only about 10 percent of autistic people fall into the savant category, and far fewer of those are mentally retarded, other studies show. Mrs. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> believes her son, who hoards bus schedules and loves to read the phone books he gets at Christmas, performs his calendar gymnastics by visual rather than mathematical means. `` I used to wonder if he was calculating dates, but I really believe it's a matter of having a photograph in his mind of our 100-year calendar. I asked him dates in the 1800s the other day and he could n't do it,'' she said. That's <PERSON> Eric </PERSON>'s explanation, too, elicited in what is typically a one-sided conversation with a stranger. He nervously checks his watch every few seconds. How do you figure out what day somebody was born? `` I have a good memory.'' What do you want to do after graduation? `` Have a job.'' Something with numbers? `` Yes.'' He's a whiz at simple math and his memory for numbers is as convenient as it is vast. `` He makes a great phone directory,'' says brother <PERSON> Dan </PERSON>. `` I think about anything he sees he's likely to remember,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, who spent hours a few years ago making flash cards of multiplication tables, only to have <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> render them useless by memorizing the answers the first time through. <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, manager of <LOCATION> Video </LOCATION> <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> in this <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> suburb, accepted <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> for an hour a day's training on a two-week trial basis. He stayed for 1 -LCB- years, quickly memorizing the shelf code for every videocassette in the store and eventually mastering the computer to check in movies. `` He was amazing with numbers,'' <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> said. But it took him six months to routinely talk to other employees and much longer to pass time with customers. `` I used to stand by the door and say, ` <PERSON> Eric </PERSON>, you ca n't leave until you say goodbye to everybody.' He would finally mumble goodbye.'' `` The emotional connection is the last to be made by an autistic child,'' <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said. `` It's so difficult to make people understand the excitement you feel when they finally start making that connection.'' An earlier stint shelving books at the school library gave <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> command of the Dewey Decimal System and friendship with the once-skeptical librarian. He was far less avid about custodial and landscaping jobs, and <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> believes absence of social interaction as much as numbers accounts for that today. `` He reaches out to people. His social habits are much more appropriate,'' she said, citing <PERSON> Eric </PERSON>'s response to the death of a school administrator's wife. As expected, <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> affably recapitulated for the bereaved husband the obituary information from the newspaper. But then he added, `` I'm so sorry about your wife.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0242EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Satanic-Stevens     03-08 0309</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Satanic-Stevens,0320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cat Stevens Endorses Rushdie Death Sentence Again</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former pop singer <PERSON> Cat </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> reiterated his support for the <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s death sentence against <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>, saying the author's treatment of Islam was `` as good as stabbing Moslems in the heart.'' <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, who changed his name to <PERSON> Yusuf </PERSON> <PERSON> Islam </PERSON> when he became a Moslem in 1979, said Tuesday that threatening to kill <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> was the equivalent of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> using an atomic bomb. `` It's got to be seen as a deterrent, so that other people should not commit the same mistake again,'' <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> said in an interview with the television show `` World Monitor,'' produced by The Christian Science Monitor. Last week, <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> denied endorsing the death sentence after his statements received harsh criticism in <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>'s novel `` The Satanic Verses'' has generated worldwide outrage among Moslems and support for the Moslem author in the West In Tuesday's interview, <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> also said negative reaction in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to his comments is a bit ironic, considering his former record company recently refused his request to stop producing his records. `` All I can see is that God works in mysterious ways,'' said <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, who was interviewed from a mosque near <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, where he lives. `` Some of my records are being destroyed.'' Several radio stations have refused to play <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>' records because of his earlier remarks. A <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> station offered copies of `` The Satanic Verses'' to people who brought their <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>' records to the station. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, who said the novel's treatment of Islam was `` as good as stabbing Moslems in the heart,'' suggested that <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> should repent writing the book. `` If he manages to escape -LRB- the death sentence -RRB- he still has to face God on the day of judgment,'' he said. `` So I would recommend to him to sincerely change his ways right now.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-London'sStreetKids Bjt   03-08 0886</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-London's Street Kids, Bjt,0912</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tougher Welfare Rules Spawn Legion Of Young Drifters</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY10</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BEN DOBBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Shellie </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> begs for money in the subway, gets valium from a friend and sometimes spends the night with other teen-agers on a littered sidewalk by the <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Thames </LOCATION>. At 17, she is one of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s army of homeless youths whose numbers, critics of Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> claim, are being swollen by the Conservative government's radical shakeup of the welfare system. The government is determined to wean Britons off what it calls `` the dependency culture.'' To do this, it is paying 16 - and 17-year-old high school dropouts $ 50 - $ 60 a week to become job trainees and cutting off welfare payments to those who do n't sign More than 400,000 now work for their benefits each year and gain job experience in the process. But those who do n't register for a one - or two-year `` YTS,'' or Youth Training Scheme, have been barred since Sept. 12 from `` signing on'' for $ 33 a week in state aid Exemptions are available to youths who suffer `` severe hardship'' such as disability or a violent home, and of 4,500 applications for hardship status, nearly 3,000 have been accepted. But critics, including some members of Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s own <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, have forced an acknowledgment from Social Security Minister <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> that the reform is causing problems, and he has hinted he will broaden his discretionary powers to help those worst hit. Conservative lawmaker <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Squire </PERSON> supports this Thatcherite concept of `` workfare,'' but opposes cutting welfare payments. `` People who have no real home should be properly looked after until they are able to get a job or a YTS course,'' he says. Their only alternatives are to `` either resort to crime or to begging gifts or to prostitution,'' he said in an interview. Some see the issue as a test of how far Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s crusade can go in revamping the 43-year-old welfare system. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, who runs the New Horizon day hostel near Covent Garden in the heart of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, said young homeless often regard job training as `` slave labor. They do n't think they should be forced to do it.'' Many come from unemployment-stricken northern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, or are fleeing broken homes, and can not afford accommodation. The YTS has 135,000 unfilled places, yet some youngsters have difficulty finding the right slot, and others get fired because they do n't get on with their employers. `` There's no transition,'' <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> said. `` Either it works or it does n't work ... Any other way you can think of to make money, they do it. Most cope very well. Of course, some go under.'' <PERSON> Austin </PERSON>, stepping out of the rain to meet friends in the hostel's dingy pool room, said she left home in September because `` me and me dad did n't get on. She say she has since slept in doorways, under railroad bridges and on sidewalks in the so-called `` cardboard city'' along the <LOCATION> Thames </LOCATION>. Lately, she has found shelter in an abandoned house in <LOCATION> Camden </LOCATION>, north <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. She says she gave up a trainee mechanic job after four days because `` it was too underpaid and it was n't worth it.'' She says she can earn up to $ 50 a day begging in subway stations. `` I'm better off how I am now than I was when I was living at home,'' <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> said, her voice wavering. `` There ai n't no one telling me what I should do.'' Her eyes are unsteady; her face flashes a smile, then becomes a grimace. `` People who are homeless now are all like brother and sister,'' she said. `` All they're worried about is when is their next money going to come to buy food, if they've got enough blankets, if it's going to rain tonight. Drugs and violence are endemic. Illnesses such as scurvy, scabies and tuberculosis are common. The government says <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> has 23,000 homeless, but welfare groups say the total is closer to 40,000 and growing. Last year, the government ended housing subsidies for nearly 1 million poor. Grants for buying stoves and beds were changed to interest-free loans. Unemployed people under age 25 now are allowed only two to six weeks welfare if they remain in the same region. The government allocated $ 36 million last summer to help <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> authorities renovate empty public housing and pay for homeless hostels. New Horizon still must raise $ 128,000 in voluntary aid this year. `` We're professional beggars,'' jokes <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, 17, from <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION>, said he was forced off the dole into becoming a trainee decorator, but his job consisted mainly of running errands. He quit in frustration. `` You try to sleep in toilets or park benches,'' he said. `` There's nowhere warm. You're shaking all night and all the next day you're shaking. Your stomach's empty. You feel dead weak.'' He now earns $ 182 a week working in a grocery store, and is moving into a working men's club where the weekly rent is $ 107. `` Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> did me good really _ she made me find work,'' said <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, a gaunt figure with spiked hair. `` People who've got something in them, they're going to benefit out of this,'' he said. `` But for every one person that does get a job, 10 people will go homeless and go on the streets.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0152EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-KosherMoscow     03-08 0242</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Kosher Moscow,0248</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israeli Chef Says Soviets Approve Kosher Eatery</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> chef says Soviet authorities have given him approval to set up a kosher restaurant in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Shalom </PERSON> <PERSON> Kadosh </PERSON> said Tuesday that he discussed the idea last week in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> with city officials and tourism and trade representatives. `` The Soviets are showing a great readiness to help us create the restaurant as quickly as possible,'' he said on <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>, though they have imposed `` some limitations on the signs'' of the future restaurant. The Israeli daily <ORGANIZATION> Yediot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ahronot </ORGANIZATION> said the eatery will be funded by <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jewish </ORGANIZATION> activists and its prices will be subsidized. Kadosh, chef at <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>'s Sheraton-Plaza Hotel, said the menu would be based on Israeli cuisine and that some products would be imported from <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. He said the kosher certificate will be given by the chief rabbi of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kadosh </PERSON> said he plans to travel to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in the near future to help organize the restaurant and will supervise it through short visits. `` The aim is not making profit but creating a kosher food place for Jews and tourists,'' <PERSON> Kadosh </PERSON> said. `` My best profit would be a contribution to the <LOCATION> Soviet-Israeli </LOCATION> ties.'' The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> cut ties with the Jewish state following the 1967 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war. In recent years, the two countries have exchanged consular missions. Last month, the first Jewish community center in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in 50 years opened in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--NunPunished     03-08 0144</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Nun Punished,0145</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nun Sentenced To Day In Court</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WITHAM, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Dominican nun who painted peace slogans on the runway of a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> base was ordered to sit through a court session as punishment for refusing to pay a fine. Sister <PERSON> Mair-Colette </PERSON> <PERSON> Ludden </PERSON> was fined $ 232 Tuesday by magistrates in this town 40 miles northeast of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> who convicted her of criminal damage at <LOCATION> Alconbury </LOCATION> base. She said she would not pay because the money would go toward a system which supports nuclear weapons. Under an obscure regulation, court chairman <PERSON> Dolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Claydon </PERSON> ordered the nun to stay within the court precincts for the rest of the day. The sister said later: `` It was a great relief when they let me stay in the court. I was told later it was equivalent to spending a day in the cells.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Officer'sFuneral     03-08 0320</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Officer's Funeral,0330</SECOND>
<HEAD>5,000 Police Turn Out For Slain Policeman's Funeral</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VIRGINIA BYRNE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Five thousand police officers lined bitterly cold streets outside a <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> church Tuesday for the funeral of the first <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> police officer killed on duty in the city this year. Officer <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Machate </PERSON> was shot to death March 3 while struggling with a suspect in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>. Two men, both illegal aliens, were arrested shortly afterwards. At the funeral Mass, Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> and Police Commissioner <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> expressed hope the state <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> would override Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>'s promised veto of bill to reinstate the death penalty. `` What's required here is that every criminal in the street know that you're gon na be apprehended, that you're gon na be prosecuted, that you're gon na be jailed and where appropriate, executed,'' a visibly angry <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> told mourners packing <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mark </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. The state Assembly in <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION> passed a death penalty bill Monday, and <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> promised to veto it. Outside St. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON>'s, the police officers, most from metropolitan area forces, formed a four-block long blue line. As <PERSON> Machate </PERSON>'s coffin was carried out of the church by an honor guard, three police helicopters in a `` missing man'' formation swooped over the church. Officer <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>, who was paralyzed when he was shot while on duty, attended the services in his wheelchair. Machate, was was 25, had been baptized and married in the same church. His wife, <PERSON> Grace </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON>, seven months pregnant with the couple's only child, wore a miniature version of her husband's shield around her neck during the service <PERSON> Machate </PERSON> had earned 13 awards since joining the force in 1986. `` <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Machate </PERSON> was intensely proud to be a police officer,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Gerard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Arella </PERSON>, noting that the slain officer came from a police family. `` He and his family were all proud to be servants of the people.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0154EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--ShipFire     03-08 0151</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Ship Fire,0152</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Fishing Vessel Sinks; Five Dead and 31 Missing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Chinese fishing vessel caught fire in heavy seas off the south <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> coast, and at least five crewmen died and 31 were missing, an official report said today. One survivor was picked up by a passing oil tanker two hours after abandoning the ship, which caught fire Saturday about 44 miles southeast of the coastal city of <LOCATION> Xiamen </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Fujian </LOCATION> province, the <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported. According to an account from the survivor, <PERSON> Cai </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuyin </PERSON>, a fire broke out at the back of <LOCATION> Minxia </LOCATION> Yu 0173 and within 20 minutes spread to the bridge, forcing the 37-member crew to abandon ship, the agency said. Chinese authorities the following day sent eight fishing vessels and two navy craft to search for survivors, but by Monday evening had found only five bodies, the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0155EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Japan-Shipwreck     03-08 0134</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Japan-Shipwreck,0138</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Dead, One Missing After Tanker Overturns</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two crew members were killed and one was reported missing early today after a Japanese tanker capsized in rough waters off the western coast, local police said. Six others aboard the 1,000-ton Shoryu-maru were rescued by helicopter while skipper <PERSON> Sadao </PERSON> <PERSON> Arata </PERSON> swam to safety, said police official <PERSON> Hideo </PERSON> <PERSON> Miyajima </PERSON>. The vessel went down in <LOCATION> Toyama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, 160 miles west of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Miyajima </PERSON> said by telephone from nearby Toyama-kia. He said the tanker was anchored slightly under a mile off shore when it was rocked by high waves and then smashed into a breakwater early Wednesday. The ship was to have loaded gasoline in the same port today before leaving for <LOCATION> Mikuni </LOCATION>, another western port along the Sea of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Miyajima </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Argentina-Politics     03-08 0832</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Argentina-Politics,0856</SECOND>
<HEAD>With Elections Near, Many Argentines Still Undecided</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED McCULLOUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As national elections move closer, the biggest bloc of voters remains undecided, despite months of feverish campaigning by the main presidential contenders. Analysts say the undecided voters are mainly supporters of President <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Radical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> angry at five years of economic stagnation and social unrest; Peronists unhappy with their party's candidate, the center-right <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Menem </PERSON>; and center-left voters who feel none of the candidates speak for them. `` I do n't feel represented by any of them,'' said <PERSON> Virginia </PERSON> <PERSON> Dardalla </PERSON> <PERSON> Rute </PERSON>, 33, the owner of a small public relations company. `` None of them will make a good president.'' Real estate agent <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Reymann </PERSON>, 25, voted for <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> in 1983 but has been disappointed and would rather not vote for a Radical in these elections, set for May 14. But at the same time, she would never vote Peronist or socialist and does n't think a conservative could win. `` I'm not uninformed,'' Miss <PERSON> Reymann </PERSON> said. `` I read the papers. I listen to the radio.'' But no candidate stands out, she said, and the ballot she casts _ voting is mandatory in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> _ may be blank. At state in the elections are the presidency, some <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seats, half the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION>, and provincial legislatures. Three surveys conducted over the past two months have put undecided voters at 39 percent, 32 percent and 32.5 percent. <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> is 7 to 10 points ahead of the Radicals' <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Angeloz </PERSON> in those polls and others, but the gap has narrowed considerably. <PERSON> Alvaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Alsogaray </PERSON> of the rightist <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> trails a distant third, followed by <PERSON> Nestor </PERSON> <PERSON> Vicente </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Left </ORGANIZATION>. Under the constitution, <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> can not seek a second consecutive term. <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> and <PERSON> Angeloz </PERSON>, both provincial governors and lawyers, have traversed the country and made the requisite swing through <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> to demonstrate their statesmenship abilities. Positions have been staked out on how to restart the economy, balance the budget, curtail urban crime, provide housing, pay the foreign debt, and ease relations between the military and human rights groups. <PERSON> Menem </PERSON>, 53, and <PERSON> Angeloz </PERSON>, 57, are both center-right, but their parties are movements that defy political labeling. Their parties, along with the armed forces, have provided <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>'s presidents for most of this century. <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> has tried to play down the <ORGANIZATION> Peronists </ORGANIZATION>' `` black legend'' of violence and administrative incompetence, which preceded military coups in 1955 and 1976. The latter has tried to distance himself from an unpopular government without losing the support of <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON>, a veteran campaigner, and resources like access to state media. Now and again, the two snipe at one another. <PERSON> Angelos </PERSON> says <PERSON> Menem </PERSON>'s proposals are `` simplistic. <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> says <PERSON> Angelos </PERSON> represents a government `` that fulfilled only 5 percent of what it promised.'' But each for the moment seems more interested in polishing his own public image _ <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> as the charismatic champion of organized labor and the downtrodden, and <PERSON> Angeloz </PERSON> as the honest administrator and family man _ than in demolishing the other. `` I wo n't let you down'' is the slogan on Menem posters, which show the candidate with his hair to his shoulders and sideburns covering most of his cheeks. `` It can be done!'' is <PERSON> Angeloz </PERSON>'s slogan. He usually appears on posters and in person in a blue blazer and open-necked shirt, wearing thick-framed black glasses and a broad smile. <PERSON> Vicente </PERSON>, a lawyer and several times a losing candidate for the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION>, lacks a nationwide constituency and is little known outside the capital. What he really is aiming to do is increase the number of leftist legislators in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Alsogaray </PERSON>, for the same reasons, has little chance of winning. But the 75-year-old military engineer and former economy minister and ambassador to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is a potential kingmaker. In a scenario that frustrates <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> and makes <PERSON> Angeloz </PERSON> credible despite any poll, no candidate will win enough votes to guarantee victory in the <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, and the 600 electors pick a president, or failing to do that, pass the decision onto <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. In either case, the conservative <PERSON> Alsogaray </PERSON> may trade his electors for political concessions, and his party has much more in common with the Radicals than the Peronists. In 1983, <PERSON> Alsogaray </PERSON> supported <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON>, reluctantly, to prevent a <ORGANIZATION> Peronist </ORGANIZATION> victory. <PERSON> Angeloz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Alsogaray </PERSON> insist their electors will vote for them. More importantly, both have rejected Peronist suggestions that the runners-up support the candidate who gets the most votes. <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Julia </PERSON> <PERSON> Alsogaray </PERSON>, a national deputy and key adviser to her father, in an interview published in the <ORGANIZATION> Buenos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aires </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> acknowledged that in the end, either in the <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> or <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, her party might provide the winning margin. She set no specific concessions the party would demand but insisted that `` any candidate wishing to get our votes would have to adhere'' to the party's platform, which calls for the privatization of state industries and minimal government, among other things.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Tibet-History     03-08 0809</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tibet-History,0833</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tibetans, Chinese Remember 30 Years Since Uprising</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Tibet, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tibetans and Chinese this week commemorate different sides of a bloody 1959 Tibetan rebellion against <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> rule. For Tibetans, Friday marks 30 years since they repudiated Chinese rule and surged into the streets to shield their spiritual leader, the <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON>, from an alleged kidnapping plot. Hundreds and perhaps thousands died when <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> put down the revolt. For the Chinese, it marks the start of three decades of socialist `` democratic reform'' in the remote Himalayan region. Even before the anniversary date this week, more blood was shed when Tibetans shouting `` Free Tibet!'' clashed with police. At least a dozen people were killed when Tibetans marched behind their banned pre-communist flag and then attacked Chinese-owned businesses and government buildings. There is fear of more violence on Friday. Exactly what happened on March 10, 1959, and in the following weeks remains a subject of great controversy and there are few non-partisan accounts. A new generation of Tibetans said they do n't know who to believe `` Each side abuses the other,'' said a young Tibetan woman in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. `` If you read what is written by the exile -LRB- Tibetan -RRB- government in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, then the Chinese were invaders and the Tibetans were right to fight them. `` But if you read what <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> says, you think, ` They are right, the Tibetans were wrong,''' she said. `` I can only judge the things I see now.'' But she and others of her generation expressed bitterness over the legacy of the 1959 rebellion: <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> has become an armed camp, and hatred runs deep between the native people and dominant Han Chinese. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> claims its sovereignty over <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> dates to the 13th century, when the <ORGANIZATION> Mongols </ORGANIZATION> who ruled <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> sent an army into <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION>. But until <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> marched into <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> in 1950, there were long periods of virtually no contact between the two. Actual power lay with <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monks under the leadership of the <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON>, revered as the reincarnation of <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION>'s protector god. Eastern Tibetan clans began armed revolt against the communists in 1956, but <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION> remained calm until 1959. Violence was touched off when the local Chinese general invited the <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON> to attend a theatrical show. A rumor spread that the army planned to kidnap the <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON> to force him to attend a legislative session in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. On the day of the show _ March 10 _ tens of thousands Tibetans surged around the <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON>'s palace to prevent him from attending. Some attacked Chinese targets. Secular Tibetan leaders seized the moment to declare independence, and monasteries seconded the call. A long standoff began, with the <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON> inside his palace urging both sides to stay calm. Finally on March 17, the Chinese allegedly fired two mortar shells into the palace grounds. The <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON> and his family fled that night, eventually reaching <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. Unaware of this, the crowd stood guard around the palace until March 20, when the Chinese army began steady shelling. After three days, the last resistance in <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION> was quelled. Rebel attacks on Chinese forces in remote areas continued for years, but to little effect. The Chinese blamed the revolt on the disgrunted former ruling class and moved to weaken it by dividing up the land and forming communes after the pattern set elsewhere in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. They also began a campaign to suppress <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION>'s traditional Buddhist culture, peaking in the 1966-76 far leftist Cultural Revolution when thousands of monasteries were destroyed and monks were jailed or forced into labor. The small communities of monks and nuns that have grown again in the past decade seem radicalized by the experience. They have held pro-independence protests repeatedly in the past 18 months. Four violent clashes with police, including this week's, have left dozens dead and hundreds injured. The Chinese show no sign of yielding their hold on the region. <PERSON> Ren </PERSON> <PERSON> Yinong </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nationalities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> said the government is in constant contact with the exiled <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON>, mainly through the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. But he said the two sides are unable to agree on terms for starting talks. `` Except for independence, anything can be discussed,'' the official <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> newspaper said last week. `` As for Tibetan autonomy, the Chinese government absolutely can not make any concessions.'' The <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON> has said he is willing to accept less than full independence and that his priority is to improve living conditions for his people. Speedy agreement is needed if Tibetan culture is to be preserved, he said last year. A recent broadcast by the official <ORGANIZATION> Lhasa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> was not optimistic. The struggle against separatists, it said, is an `` arduous and complex affair,'' and all involved `` must be mentally prepared for a long-term struggle.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-US-SovietSurvey     03-08 0353</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Soviet Survey,0362</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S.-Soviet Women Surveyed About Family Life</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Seventy-nine percent of Soviet women and 43 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> women think alcoholism is a chief cause of divorce, a poll shows. Poor communication wrecks most marriages, 77 of the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women said in the survey. They ranked alcoholism second, while 39 percent of <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> women ranked parental interference second. The survey, based on an unscientific sampling, was conducted by Woman's Day, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> magazine geared toward suburban women, and <PERSON> Krestyanka </PERSON>, a Soviet magazine whose name translates as, `` Peasant Woman,'' although 54 percent of its respondents identified themselves as white-collar. `` This survey reveals there's nothing foreign about domestic difficulties,'' said <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON>, Woman's Day editor in chief. `` Soviet and <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women have more in common than they may have thought: too much work, troubled marriages, husbands who wo n't help, and alcoholism. `` Stress is the great equalizer,'' said <PERSON> Ethel </PERSON> <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>, associate professor of political science at <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, who interpreted the poll for Woman's Day. `` Women have hit a strong stress point in both societies.'' Fifty-six percent of the Soviet women surveyed said an ideal husband should be faithful and a good head of the family. More than 63 percent of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women mentioned `` communicative,'' `` emotionally supportive'' and `` faithful'' as the virtues of the ideal husband. Only 2 percent of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women thought good homemaking skills make an ideal husband. Still, 61 percent said <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> men must assume more responsibility for housework and 50 percent wanted men to help more with child care. Twenty percent of the Soviet women said men should do more at home and 13 percent said men should spend more time raising their kids. The surveys were conducted by mail so that rural <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> women without phones could be included. Women's Day received about 30,000 responses from women with a median age of 41; more than three-quarters are married and almost 90 percent have children. <PERSON> Krestyanka </PERSON> got back about 200,000 responses, with a median age of 30, three-fourths married and 78 percent with children. The <PERSON> Yankelovich </PERSON> <PERSON> Clancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Shulman </PERSON> polling firm tabulated the Woman's Day results
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0303EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--MarkedCars     03-08 0104</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Marked Cars,0105</SECOND>
<HEAD>Familiar Police Cars May Be Replaced For Undercover Work</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FLINT, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The city's unmarked police cars are so well known that a drug raid turned up a computerized list of them, prompting police to request $ 75,000 for new cars. <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>'s finance committee was considering the request. The new vehicles would allow the department to sell or replace undercover cars every six months, Police Chief <PERSON> Fay </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Peek </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> said. Drug dealers' familiarity with the unmarked cars not only hampers undercover work but may endanger officers' lives, police said. The computerized list included makes, models and license plates.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-AnthonyConvicted     03-08 0363</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Anthony Convicted,0377</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jury Convicts Senator's Ex-Aide</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By THOMAS J. SHEERAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal jury Tuesday convicted a former aide to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> of accepting $ 1,300 in illegal payments from two <LOCATION> Polish </LOCATION> immigrants who had sought the senator's help <PERSON> Ladd </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON>, 47, of <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> sat impassively, with one elbow on the defense table, when the verdict was read in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> said, `` No comment,'' to reporters as he left the courtroom. His attorney, <PERSON> Elmer </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON>, said it was too early to say whether there would be an appeal. In a statement distributed in the federal courthouse after the verdict was read, <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, said the decision was `` the end to a sad episode that began in November 1986,'' when he asked the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to investigate allegations that <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> had been acting improperly with his constituents. It is illegal for federal employees to accept money or any thing of value in return for performing their official duties. `` Those who are sworn to uphold the law should expect no leniency when they break the law,'' <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> said. No date was set for sentencing. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> was convicted of accepting $ 300 from <PERSON> Irena </PERSON> <PERSON> Boc </PERSON>, who testified last week that she gave <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> the money in an envelope in 1983 to help her with an application for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizenship. <PERSON> Waclaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Pietrzykowski </PERSON> testified that <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> solicited $ 2,300 from him in 1985 to help the daughter of his landlady, <PERSON> Anni </PERSON> <PERSON> Wojcieszko </PERSON>, with her application to the <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterinary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Pietrzykowski </PERSON> and <PERSON> Wojcieszko </PERSON> testified they gave <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> $ 1,000 and that he later returned $ 500. The trial began March 1. In closing arguments, <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON> tried to shift blame for the alleged payoffs to others and to point up discrepancies in testimony. But prosecutors blamed the discrepancies on time lapses and the difficulty Polish witnesses had with the English language. `` The truth is <PERSON> Ladd </PERSON> <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> is the one ripping off these people,'' said <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a lawyer with the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Integrity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Section </ORGANIZATION>. `` <PERSON> Ladd </PERSON> <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> is the one who took advantage of some of the most vulnerable people in our society,'' <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MusicalChocolate     03-08 0639</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Musical Chocolate,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Julia Child Recipe Set to Music</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX9</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Attention, dieters. The musical recipe for a wickedly delicious chocolate cake by <PERSON> Julia </PERSON> <PERSON> Child </PERSON> is being cooked up at the Kennedy Center tonight. It takes about 20 minutes to devour, and it does n't contain a single calorie. But composer <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoiby </PERSON> warns that his `` Bon Appetit!'' a new musical monologue performed by actress <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Stapleton </PERSON> with <PERSON> Hoiby </PERSON> at the piano, may tempt chocolate lovers to break their vows of abstinence. `` I am tempted not only by the lyrics but by the cake itself,'' confesses <PERSON> Hoiby </PERSON>, who is trying to observe a diet of such macrobiotic foods as cabbage, brown rice and fish with seaweed. `` I often give in to temptation and say I'll make up for it later,'' he said during a prerehearsal interview. `` I love chocolate cake. The things that are out of reach are what we love in this world.'' <PERSON> Hoiby </PERSON>'s piece is based on the videotape of a 1961 television cooking lesson by <PERSON> Julia </PERSON> <PERSON> Child </PERSON>, and will be served as the dessert course for an evening of <PERSON> Hoiby </PERSON>'s music at the Terrace Theater. After its world premiere here, <PERSON> Hoiby </PERSON> and <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Stapleton </PERSON> will perform the work at <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, on March 31 and at <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, on April 9. On stage, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Stapleton </PERSON> sings and pantomimes her way around an imaginary kitchen, using lyrics taken from Miss Child's tape, as she prepares a `` very special, ve-e-ery choc ` late-ly, bittersweet, loooovely cake'' called <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Gateau </PERSON> au Chocolat, l ` Eminence `` What I love is her wonderful sense of theater,'' the actress says. `` She's not just a cook. She's a character, very rich and very humorous.'' Miss <PERSON> Stapleton </PERSON> makes the most of the TV chef's comic touches, tapping an invisible cake pan and instructing her audience to `` knock out the flour on the floor, if you have a self-cleaning kitchen like mine.'' And she engages in a fast-paced musical race with an electric mixer, as she beats egg whites in an unlined copper bowl. `` We're going to see who wins,'' she sings, `` and I think maybe I'll win ... because I'm bigger. <PERSON> Hoiby </PERSON> says `` Bon Appetit!'' _ which takes its title from Miss Child's familiar closing line _ was composed as a concert curtain-raiser for a longer work he wrote in 1984, his operatic version of the late <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Draper </PERSON>'s monologue, `` The Italian Lesson.'' <PERSON> Hoiby </PERSON> and associate <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Shulgasser </PERSON> came up with the idea of using the script of a Julia Child cooking lesson as a vehicle for Miss <PERSON> Stapleton </PERSON>, a veteran of Broadway musicals who is better known as <PERSON> Archie </PERSON> <PERSON> Bunker </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Edith </PERSON>, on the `` All in the Family'' TV series. Miss <PERSON> Stapleton </PERSON> wrote Miss Child for permission. Miss Child happily agreed, and sent a batch of her tapes for viewing. <PERSON> Hoiby </PERSON>, who watched them for four full days, became intrigued by the chef's `` rhapsodic phrases'' and musical metaphors `` Her speaking patterns really grab you, the phraseology, the unexpected little interjections,'' he said. `` There is a kind of musical cadence in her speech which one is n't aware of unless one starts to set it to music, and then there it is.'' Is there something musical, too, about chocolate cake? `` Well, you see, chocolate cake, it's a very special moment,'' <PERSON> Hoiby </PERSON> replied. `` It's an indulgence, something you do n't want to do too much of. It's like a reward _ you ate all your spinach, now you can have your reward. It's put in a very special category as a treat.'' Getting hungry? After tonight's concert, members of the audience will gather at a reception to nibble on the real thing, <LOCATION> Le </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gateau </LOCATION> au Chocolat, l'Eminence <PERSON> Brune </PERSON>, prepared from Miss Child's recipe by the <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> chef. `` The cake is going to be the icing,'' says <PERSON> Shulgasser </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-OvernightVisits     03-08 0474</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Overnight Visits,0488</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court: Divorced Mother Can't Let Boyfriend Stay Over While Kids Are
Home</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KIMBERLY M. SHEARIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PROVIDENCE, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The boyfriend of a mother of three can not spend the night while the children are home, the state's highest court has ruled. The state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday upheld a lower court decision to bar the boyfriend, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> DiPippo </PERSON>, from staying overnight, saying the ruling raised no major constitutional issues. Civil libertarians expressed surprise at the decision and found the remark that the case raised no constitutional questions disturbing. `` I think that the state of <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> has made a very poor statemeent about women, divorced women, single parents and their children, and their collective rights to privacy in their own homes,'' said <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurst </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> attorney for <PERSON> Carla </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Parrillo </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Parrillo </PERSON> and her husband, <PERSON> Justin </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, were divorced in May 1986, and Ms. <PERSON> Parrillo </PERSON> was given custody of her children, two daughters and a son, ages 8 13 at the time. <PERSON> Parrillo </PERSON> was given visitation rights. In June, the <PERSON> Parrillos </PERSON> returned to <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, and Ms. <PERSON> Parrillo </PERSON> wanted her ex-husband to see the children in a location away from her home. <PERSON> Parrillo </PERSON> wanted his ex-wife restrained from having any `` unrelated males'' stay overnight at her house. Ms. <PERSON> Parrillo </PERSON> contended that her ex-husband began to harass her upon learning that she was dating DiPippo. DiPippo stayed overnight once or twice a week, Ms. <PERSON> Parrillo </PERSON> said, and it caused no harm to her children, who were in separate bedrooms. She told the court that her children liked <PERSON> DiPippo </PERSON>, but she had no plans to marry him in the near future. <PERSON> Parrillo </PERSON> began reducing his support payments when he learned <PERSON> DiPippo </PERSON> was visiting, the high court said. The children told the lower court's judge in a private meeting that they all got along well with <PERSON> DiPippo </PERSON>, although the son said there were times he disliked the man. But the judge ruled the overnight visits `` in the presence of the children, were not conducive to their general well-being, at least in terms of their psychological welfare,'' the high court said. The judge also had noted that if Ms. <PERSON> Parrillo </PERSON> married DiPippo, the issue would become moot. Ms. <PERSON> Parrillo </PERSON> appealed, saying the judge erred because no evidence existed that her sleeping with DiPippo psychologically harmed her children. But the high court upheld the <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision, saying that ruling `` was without question directed at <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON>. ... <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> may still visit the marital domicile overnight, with the exception of those times when the children are with their mother.'' <PERSON> Hurst </PERSON> said she hoped Ms. <PERSON> Parrillo </PERSON> would appeal the decision. `` The practical effect on <PERSON> Carla </PERSON> <PERSON> Parrillo </PERSON> is that she is precluded from conducting her private activities in the privacy of her own home at her discretion,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NavyDeaths     03-08 0597</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Navy Deaths,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Navy Recruit's Death Blamed on Safety Neglect</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The death of a 19-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> recruit during training a year ago resulted from the service's neglect for safety procedures and pressure on the training system from higher-ups, according to a congressional investigation. In a report released Tuesday, the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Appleton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, died at the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Swimmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in part because of `` an intimidating, non-volunteer atmosphere and inadequate controls at the school and its superior commands.'' Some of the flaws remain uncorrected, the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said. And it found that of 16 other <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> training deaths between Jan. 1, 1986, and the end of last year, safety problems contributed to five of the fatalities. `` The bottom line is that <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> instructors still are not trained to conduct high-risk training and that students still are not screened to make sure they can handle the dangers,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Toby </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wis </LOCATION>., who requested the investigation along with the other members of the state's congressional delegation <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> called <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON>'s death `` a tragedy waiting to happen,'' pointing to <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> findings that he was unqualified for the swimming rescue course, had untrained and unsupervised instructors and was prevented from dropping out because of pressure on the school to increase the number of graduates it turned out. `` This <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> report is a catalog of failures by the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, which led to <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON>'s death and others,'' <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> said at a news conference. He vowed to follow up to see that remaining problems are resolved and asked Vice Admiral <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Disher </PERSON>, head of the service's training system, to contact families of recruits who died in training `` to tell them what really happened.'' The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said it had discussed its findings with the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and reported that officials `` generally agreed'' and `` were receptive to suggestions on how to improve training safety'' and accident investigations. <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON> panicked during a swimming-pool drill known as `` sharks and daisies,'' in which swimmers must free themselves from an instructor who grabs them from behind, simulating a drowning person. After counseling and medical examination, he was found `` not physically qualified'' for the course because of a phobia of being held under water. But despite the findings, he was re-enrolled in the class and forced to undergo the drill again. <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON> left the pool and clutched an equipment rack, shouting such things as `` I quit'' and `` Please do n't put me back in the water,'' but was dragged back to the pool by instructors. After a struggle in the pool, he was removed unconscious and could not be revived. An autopsy found that <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON> probably died of heartbeat irregularity caused by extreme fear, fatigue and decreased oxygen. The lead instructor was found guilty by a general court martial of negligent homicide and sentenced to a demotion and 90 days' confinement Eight others associated with the class were given various administrative punishments, including demotions and reprimands. Some improvements have been made, <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said. The `` sharks and daisies'' drill has been dropped, instructors are given better training and safety equipment is kept on hand at the swimming pool. There also is a clearer policy regarding students' rights to drop out of a course, the investigators said. But the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said there remains great pressure on students not to drop out of a course because it is made clear to them that doing so will adversely affect their careers, and that there still is no system to alert instructors to students with a history of problems.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Raisa     03-08 0501</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Raisa,0521</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Media, in Switch, Report on Raisa Gorbachev's Views</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELIZABETH SHOGREN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> did not go into loving detail on what <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> wore or who did her hair, but it did report on what the first lady was thinking about some world and domestic issues _ an unusual turn for Soviet media. Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, wife of the president and <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief, <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, spoke at a a reception she gave Monday in honor of International Women's Day, a Soviet holiday that is being celebrated today. She talked about her husband's reform policies and about how the world's women have improved prospects for peace, and <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION>, the official Soviet news agency, reported her views. State-run television frequently shows the stylish <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> first lady and Western journalists interview her. But it is rare for fellow Soviets to be let in on her thoughts. `` If people currently are more confident of a peaceful future, we know that much of the credit goes to women actively working on all continents for friendship, cooperation and profound mutual understanding of nations,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said at the reception, as reported by <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION>. For <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> to be covering the reception itself _ for wives of ambassadors and other diplomats in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, wives of members of the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Politburo </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> women in various fields _ was unusual. Before <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> came to power four years ago, <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> wives almost invariably were kept backstage. Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> changed that. The attractive, 57-year-old former teacher of Marxist-Leninist philosophy has taken a role somewhat resembling that of the wife of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president. Not all Soviets are delighted with the change. Many are taken aback by her wardrobe, large and glamorous by Soviet standards. Others grumble that she is too involved in her husband's work. On Monday, Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> gave the grumblers some ammunition by going public with some of her views. Speaking of her husband's reforms, she said, `` Soviet people are putting into practice plans of revolutionary restructuring. We are connecting to it the destiny of our country, of our nation. We want our public life in all aspects _ socio-economic, political, moral, ecological, and in the sphere of human rights and freedoms _ to be worthy of a human being. `` By transforming and renewing our society on a socialist basis, on the principles of humanism and democracy, we are making our country more open for all the nations of the world.' She greeted her guests individually and gave each a bouquet, reported <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON> <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>, wife of <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>. `` She's a very attractive, intelligent and vocal woman. If they let her speak more often, everyone would benefit,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON> told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The Gorbachevs later attended a televised celebration held in the <LOCATION> Bolshoi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Theater </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to mark International Women's Day. This time, things were a little more typical. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> sat on the dais with other Politburo members and dignitaries. His wife was in the audience.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Whistleblowers     03-08 0323</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Whistleblowers,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Whistleblower Bill on the Move Again in the Senate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bill to protect so-called `` whistleblowers'' who expose government waste, fraud and abuse is back in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> after a compromise between sponsors and the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration. `` This very well might be the first bill to be signed by the president this year,'' Sen. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Grassley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, said at a news conference Tuesday in which sponsors unveiled a revised version of the measure. The bill would ease the way for federal employees to win reinstatement if demoted or fired after disclosing mismanagement. Then-President <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> blocked the measure by a pocket veto, meaning he refused to sign the bill and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> was out of session at the time. He said it could result in the government fighting legal battles against itself. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s move received heavy criticism in a surprised <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and from Democratic presidential nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. Lawmakers agreed under the compromise to give up a provision of last year's bill that would have allowed a special counsel representing employees to go to court, said Sen. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, D-Mich. In turn, the administration agreed to a provision barring the special counsel from opposing whistleblowers in any action before the <ORGANIZATION> Merit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, the agency that enforces civil service safeguards. The administration also agreed to greater privacy protection under the bill, while the senators approved a minor rewording under which employees are deemed whistleblowers if their exposure of waste, fraud or abuse was `` a contributing factor'' in the decision to discipline them. The change inserted the word `` contributing.'' Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> promised in a letter to <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> `` our cooperation to discourage any amendments, in either body of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, that might in any way interfere with this agreement.'' `` None of the changes to which we have agreed detracts in any way from the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' intent to strengthen whistleblower protections,'' the letter said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0103EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-StLouisElection     03-08 0250</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-St Louis Election,0254</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mayor Wins Democratic Primary In St. Louis</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ST. LOUIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mayor <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schoemehl </PERSON>, seeking to become only the third mayor in city history to gain a third term, easily won the Democratic primary on Tuesday against two oppponents. In final, unofficial results, <PERSON> Schoemehl </PERSON> had 36,743 ballots, or 61.5 percent of the vote, to former <PERSON> Alderman </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, who had 20,581. A third candidate, retired businessman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Noel </PERSON>, had 2,382. <PERSON> Schoemehl </PERSON>'s nomination would be tantamount to a third four-year term in the heavily Democratic city. The general election will be held April 4. `` This has been a tremendous day for <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Schoemehl </PERSON> said. `` We in fact have a very bright future in the track that we are on.'' In the Republican mayoral primary, auto repair shop owner <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Elking </PERSON> edged <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lang </PERSON>, who owns a pet grooming shop, by 31 votes. <PERSON> Elking </PERSON> had 928 votes to 897 for <PERSON> Lang </PERSON>. <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lang </PERSON>, a used tire dealer who is not related to the other candidate, had 138 votes. Voters also cast ballots for aldermen in 10 of the city's 28 wards. Election commissioner <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wamser </PERSON> had predicted that fewer than a third of the city's 216,500 voters would participate in the wake of a late winter storm that dumped 11 inches of snow on the area Sunday and Monday. By late Tuesday, that estimate was downgraded to possibly only 25 percent in spite of temperatures that rose to the low 30s.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0309EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-VoterTurnout     03-08 0725</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Voter Turnout,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Voter Turnout Again Down Except Among the Elderly</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Older Americans flexed their political muscles last November, while interest in choosing a new president flagged among other age groups, the <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> reports. Some 68.8 percent of people aged 65 and over reported going to the polls last fall, the only age group to show an increase from the election four years earlier, according to the analysis released on Tuesday. Senior citizens voted at a 67.7 percent rate in 1984. `` The elderly have been getting a lot of attention and have become a great deal more active then ever before,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> statistician <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON>. `` They are becoming a much more self-conscious group than before and are beginning to recognize their power.'' While the over-65 group was tops in turnout, the 45-to-64 age segment was n't far behind at 67.9 percent last November. But that was down from 69.8 percent four years earlier. Turnout by voters aged 25 to 44 fell from 58.4 percent to 54.0 percent, and in the 18 to 24 group it dropped from 40.8 percent to 36.2 percent. Overall, the Census analysis found voter turnout down 3 percentage points from 1984 and _ at 57 percent _ the lowest since the bureau began asking about voting in 1964. As usual, more people told the <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> they had voted than there were votes actually cast, a phenomenon which the bureau gently terms `` misreporting.'' The total vote amounted to about 50 percent of the number of people of voting age in the country, the post-election count found. But when the <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> surveyed about 55,000 households two weeks after the election, 57.4 percent reported having gone to the polls. Does that mean people lie to the census takers? `` Yes,'' said <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON>, `` That's the greater part of it.'' The purpose of the survey is not to find out how many people voted _ to do that you have to count the votes, <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> pointed out. The survey compares the turnout among regions and groups of people. That comparison is valid, he said, `` with one group misreporting about as much as another.'' Either way, it was a 3 percentage point drop from 1984 and the lowest turnout in many years. At 57 percent, the Census figure is the lowest ever recorded by that agency, while the national vote total has n't been as low as half in a presidential year since 1924, according to figures compiled by the private Committee for the Study of the American Electorate. The drop in turnout was greatest for blacks and Hispanics, the Census study found. `` By and large, when there is a change in voter turnout it is greatest in segments of the population which have the lowest turnout to begin with,'' <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> said. `` I suspect that is what is happening here.'' Only 51.5 percent of voting-age blacks said they had cast ballots, down from 55.8 percent four years earlier. For Hispanics the decline was from 32.6 percent to 28.8 percent. The white turnout fell from 61.4 percent to 59.2 percent between 1984 and 1988. Women held their lead over males in voting, 58.3 percent to 56.4 percent last year. In 1984 women had led 60.8 percent to 59.0 percent. As usual, the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> topped the nation last fall with 62.9 percent reporting they voted, a drop from 65.7 percent in 1984. The Northeast was second at 57.4 percent, down from 59.7 percent. Turnout in the West fell from 58.5 percent to 55.6 percent, while in the South it dropped from 56.8 percent to 54.5 percent between 1984 and 1988. Education seems to encourage voting, with 77.6 percent of college graduates turning out. Next were people with some college, 64.5 percent and then high school graduates, 54.7 percent. Only 41.3 percent of those who had n't finished high school voted, and turnout was 36.7 percent for people who had n't gone beyond grade school. People with jobs outvoted the unemployed, 58.4 percent to 38.6 percent. People who own their own home turned out at a 70.0 percent rate, while only 39.8 percent of renters reported voting. Because it is based on a survey the study can be subject to sampling error. The <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> estimates the margin of error for the overall turnout at four-tenths of 1 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0315EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Landsat     03-08 0456</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Landsat,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Promises to Spare Landsat</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Landsat earth-sensing satellites appear to be getting a reprieve, with an administration pledge to keep them running and a variety of federal agencies being asked to foot the bill. The two satellites had been threatened with a shutdown when funds ran out on March 31. But <PERSON> Thonas </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pyke </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> reported that while details remain to be worked out, the administration is committed to keep the satellite system running. A shutdown would have amounted to `` turning off the lights, closing the door and retiring from the field,'' of remote sensing, said Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Scheuer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on natural resources. The federal agencies that make the most use of the satellite data are being asked to contribute to keep the system operating after March 31, <PERSON> Pyke </PERSON> told the subcommittee. It will cost about $ 9.4 million to keep the system running for the rest of the fiscal year. <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roe </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, told the subcommittee that he has a meeting scheduled with Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> to discuss details of the funding. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has been coordinating the new Landsat funding as head of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. `` We've got to stop this damned nonsense,'' <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> said of the Landsat funding problem. Funding was a continuing battle under the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, which initiated the transfer of the system to private hands. That transfer, to the <ORGANIZATION> Earth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Satellite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>, is incomplete. Federal money is still used in operating the satellites, which measure land use, water flow, vegetation and mineral locations and provide detailed mapping information. The two satellites are currently beyond their original design lifetimes. A replacement, Landsat 6, is n't scheduled for launch until 1991. In the meantime, <ORGANIZATION> Landsats </ORGANIZATION> 4 and 5 continue to supply useful data. If they are turned off for lack of funds the only source for similar information would be the French SPOT-Image satellite system or the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Pyke </PERSON> told the subcommittee that the EOSAT company, the private firm handling the Landsat data, has been asked to contribute part of the funding to keep the satellites running, but no commitment has been received. Federal agencies that seem likely sources of funds, he said, include the <ORGANIZATION> Departments </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION>, Agriculture and Interior and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. Rep. <PERSON> Lamar </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>, urged that the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> be asked for assistance as well. `` It's an absolute shame that we've come to this juncture,'' concluded Rep. <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> McCurdy </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>. He termed threatening to shut down the satellites a `` pretty expensive game of chicken.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890308-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-08-89 0316EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-News     03-08 0631</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-News,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Bush News Conferences Abound</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
