<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 2325EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AuctionRecords     10-30 0293</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Auction Records,0299</SECOND>
<HEAD>Record Prices Paid for Complex Watch, Stieglitz Photos</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Bethe in 7th graf is cq.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A series of 21 photos of clouds by photographer <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Stieglitz </PERSON> brought $ 396,000 at auction Monday and a watch sold for $ 539,000, both setting records, auction houses said. The watch sold to a private collector for the highest price ever paid for a watch at auction in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>. The photo sale was a record price for a single lot of photography, a spokeswoman for <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s auction house said. The watch, with a face measuring 1.4 inches, was made by Swiss craftsmen and took three years to complete. It was designed and commissioned in 1927 by <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Schulz </PERSON>, who worked for <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>'s before opening his own business and who also designed watches for <ORGANIZATION> Cartier </ORGANIZATION> `` It was the most complicated watch of its size ever to be made,'' said <PERSON> Daryn </PERSON> <PERSON> Schnipper </PERSON>, a watch expert for <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>. In addition to a standard dial that tells time, the watch face has four smaller dials. One gives the month, one gives the day of the week, one registers the date and has a second hand, and another gives the phases of the moon. The previous record for a watch sold at auction was set earlier this year when a wristwatch went for $ 275,000. <PERSON> Stieglitz </PERSON>' `` Equivalents _ Three Series of Seven Each'' was bought by an anonymous collector, said <PERSON> Bethe </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, a publicist for <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s. The series consists of 21 different black-and-white photos of clouds, each measuring 3 -LCB- by 4 -LCB- inches, dating from the 1920s. <PERSON> Stieglitz </PERSON> signed the title page of the series, dedicating it to <PERSON> Alma </PERSON> <PERSON> Wertheim </PERSON>, a patron and friend. The series was sold by the <PERSON> Wertheim </PERSON> family, <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 2327EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Colombia     10-30 0248</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Colombia,0256</SECOND>
<HEAD>Grenade Goes Off in Terrorist's Hands, Killing Him and Policeman</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOGOTA, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A terrorist and a policeman were killed by a grenade that burst as the terrorist prepared to toss it at a passing police patrol Monday night, police said. They said an accomplice and a second police officer were wounded in the explosion in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Minuto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dios </LOCATION>, a northwestern suburb of this capital city of 6 million people. Two other bombs exploded late Monday in south and central <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, but no casualties were reported, authorities said. One bomb destroyed part of a bank front and neighboring buildings and the other caused minor damage at the social security building. The latest incidents, following violence late Sunday that wounded two journalists, apparently came in response to a decision by the government of President <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> to refuse to negotiate with drug traffickers. The government declared war against the drug lords and their hired killers on Aug. 19 after leading presidential candidate Sen. <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Galan </PERSON> was assassinated. Since then, at least 237 bombings and bombing attempts have taken place throughout <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, mostly in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Barranquilla </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cartegena </LOCATION>, resulting in the deaths of 33 people. Earlier Monday, eight people were killed and 30 injured when a bus sped off the side of a ravine near <LOCATION> Bordo </LOCATION>, 340 miles south of <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, police said. The bus was traveling north from Ipiales near the border with <LOCATION> Ecuador </LOCATION>. Police said the bus apparently was traveling too fast.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 2327EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-India-Clashes     10-30 0204</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-India-Clashes,0209</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Recover 48 bodies After Clashes in India</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Forty-eight more bodies were recovered on Monday in <LOCATION> Bhagalpur </LOCATION>, a remote town in <LOCATION> Bihar </LOCATION> state hit by Hindu-Moslem violence, and another person was killed when police fired at an angry mob, news reports said. Since Sunday, 171 people have died in <LOCATION> Bhagalpur </LOCATION> and in three villages stretching across a 125-mile swath of <LOCATION> Bihar </LOCATION> state, one of the poorest and most violent in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, news media said. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> said the official death toll in <LOCATION> Bhagalpur </LOCATION> stood at 145 since clashes began last Tuesday. Press Trust of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> put the Bhagalpur toll at 200. In a dispatch from the state capital of <LOCATION> Patna </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> UNI </ORGANIZATION> quoted <LOCATION> Bihar </LOCATION> Home Affairs Commissioner <PERSON> Jiya </PERSON> <PERSON> Lal </PERSON> <PERSON> Arya </PERSON> as saying police fired when the mob attacked homes. Police rescued at least 150 residents. Bhagalpur is on the <LOCATION> Ganges </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, which is sacred to Hindus. The town is about 110 miles east of <LOCATION> Patna </LOCATION> and 220 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Calcutta </LOCATION>. Some clashes coincided with processions by Hindu militants who are collecting bricks to build a temple at <LOCATION> Ayodhya </LOCATION>, in neighboring <LOCATION> Uttar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pradesh </LOCATION> state, where Hindus and Moslems lay claim to the same religious site.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 2337EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APAppointment     10-30 0218</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Appointment,0224</SECOND>
<HEAD>Slaughter Named AP Newsfeatures Director</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Slaughter </PERSON>, a general executive on the headquarters staff of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has been named director of <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newsfeatures </ORGANIZATION>. Slaughter succeeds <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Perkes </PERSON>, who is retiring after 32 years with the news cooperative. <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newsfeatures </ORGANIZATION> develops and markets syndicated features and books, including `` The Associated Press Stylebook'' and `` The Word,'' a guide to newswriting. <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boccardi </PERSON> announced the appointment on Monday. <PERSON> Boccardi </PERSON> said that in addition to his Newsfeatures duties, Slaughter will assist in development of <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s strategic plan under Vice President <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON>, who is director of strategic planning and <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> treasurer. Slaughter, 40, was transferred to the AP headquarters staff in August after four years as <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s chief of bureau in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. He went to <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> after five years as chief of bureau in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J </LOCATION>. He joined the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Topeka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, in 1973 and worked in <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> before being named correspondent in <LOCATION> Cheyenne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, in 1976. He was correspondent in <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, and assistant chief of bureau in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> before being named <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION> bureau chief in 1980. Slaughter is a native of <LOCATION> Salina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, and a graduate of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION>. He also holds a master's degree in business administration.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 2338EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MilitaryImpostor     10-30 0626</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Military Impostor,0645</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man's Identity Taken by Army Deserter</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BETH CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOUISVILLE, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> never learned how to salute or put on a military uniform properly, because the only time he spent in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> was after he was arrested as a deserter and threatened with court-martial. <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>, who has sued the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> for $ 5 million, says the whole mess began when someone `` stole his identity,'' by taking his name and Social Security number and enlisting. The Army admits the arrest was in error, but claims it was <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>'s responsibility to clear up the confusion before it got that far. <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> says he notified a recruiter, whose name he ca n't remember, several years before the imposter deserted. Now <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>, 35, of <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, is awaiting a judge's ruling in the case after a non-jury trial earlier this month in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Court here. The judge has not indicated when he will rule. After <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>'s arrest in June 1985, he spent two days in the <LOCATION> Jefferson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> jail and nine hours at <PERSON> Fort </PERSON> <PERSON> Knox </PERSON> before his wife, with the assistance of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Romano </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazzoli </PERSON>'s office, got him released. <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> said he was frightened when an officer said he was to be sent to a military prison at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Leavenworth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, for court-martial. `` All this was new to me,'' said <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>, who said when he was told to put on an Army uniform, he did n't know he was supposed to tuck his pants into his boots. `` And just because I did n't put it on right, they made me do push-ups.'' Failing to salute a lieutenant brought more push-ups, he said. The calisthenics, along with sleeping on a concrete floor at the jail for two nights, aggravated a back condition, he said. Besides physical suffering, <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> claims his reputation was damaged and he suffered emotional distress _ he spent a month in a <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION> psychiatric hospital this year _ and damage to his credit rating. He has had problems with the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, and demands for payment of the impostor's debts to the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> and others, he said. He claims he was hospitalized in February because he was paranoid and cautious of others. `` I used to even look at the telephone man and think he was spying on me,'' he said. A man calling himself <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> and using <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>'s Social Security number joined the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, in 1975. He was sent to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, where he eventually deserted, <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> said. The non-military <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> found out about the impostor in 1981 when the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> said he had not been paying taxes on military income. `` It still puzzles me right now,'' <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> said. `` I wonder why, and of all people, why me. I have enough problems. I do n't need any more problems. People do give the wrong Social Security number occasionally, either intentionally or by accidentally scrambling the numbers, said <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Higdon </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>'s district manager for <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Jefferson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. `` The best thing someone can do is check their Social Security record periodically'' and make sure the annual earnings match the figures on the income tax return for each year, <PERSON> Higdon </PERSON> said. The Army does n't deny the mix-up caused <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> trouble. `` There's no question that he had a rough time, spending 48 hours in jail and another day down at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Knox </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON>, the assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney who is handling the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s case. But <PERSON> Cox </PERSON> said the responsibility was <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>'s. `` He's the one who had the potential to be harmed by the mistaken records, so I think he had an obligation to follow up and make sure action was taken,'' <PERSON> Cox </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 2339EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-CharterRevision     10-30 0727</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Charter Revision,0748</SECOND>
<HEAD>Voters' Challenge: To Make New York City `Normal'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BILL STIEG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The cab drivers will still be surly. The Statue of Liberty will still light the harbor. The <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> will still be up, the Battery down, and the folks will still ride in a hole in the ground. But <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> is on the edge of a momentous change _ one that will alter the way the nation's largest city is governed. In a referendum that has drawn little attention in the midst of a tumultuous mayoral campaign, city voters this Nov. 7 will have an opportunity to approve or reject a charter that would strengthen the mayor and <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> while wiping out an entire governing body, the Board of Estimate. The board is arguably the most powerful segment of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s government, with final say over the budget. But the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has ruled that it is unconstitutional, so the city must change. `` I think one of the things we're doing is making <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> like normal governments in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> A.O </PERSON>. <PERSON> Schwarz </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, chairman of the commission that came up with the new, 393-page city charter. That means forming a bigger <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, changing the mayor's duties and responsibilities and creating new ways to award contracts, approve the budget and myriad other procedures Polls indicate the new charter will pass easily, despite considerable if disjointed opposition. The Board of Estimate dates back to 1901. It reflected a new <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>: In 1898, <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, the city of <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> and what is now <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION> joined <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> to become one consolidated city. Each of those five boroughs has a president, and those presidents sit on the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estimate </ORGANIZATION>, along with the three officials elected citywide: the mayor, comptroller and <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> president. For 89 years, the board has been approving contracts, deciding most land-use questions and approving the annual budget. The citywide officials have two votes each, while each borough president has one. So <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, with 350,000 residents, has the same voice as <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>, with 2.2 million. That, the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled last March, violated the principle of one-person, one-vote. The new plan is updated to suit a changing <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, where minorities account for more than half the population but only 25 percent of the council is black or Hispanic. `` We paid a lot of attention to making sure that minorities had fair representation,'' <PERSON> Schwarz </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> would be expanded from 35 to 51 members under the new plan, and the smaller districts are expected to produce more minority members, perhaps as many as 20, or 40 percent of the council. With the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estimate </ORGANIZATION> dissolved, the council will become a true legislature, with final say on the budget and most land use and zoning questions. The mayor will continue running executive agencies, appointing commissioners, proposing the city budget and estimating revenues _ a crucial element in spending debates. `` What the city's doing is moving from a unique, screwball form of government to one that looks a lot more like what other cities do _ that's a strong mayor, strong council form of government,'' said <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Russianoff </PERSON>, attorney for the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>. Supporters say the larger council and new requirements for public disclosure and a new independent budget office will check the mayor's power. But without the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estimate </ORGANIZATION>, critics contend, the mayor will be too powerful _ `` We will have an imperial mayor,'' said <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamberti </PERSON>, borough president of <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Lamberti </PERSON> and his fellow borough presidents stand to lose the most power under the plan, and are among its most outspoken opponents. The other opponents come from a variety of sources that do n't necessarily have much else in common. `` There's the far left and the far right and we're sort of the center,'' <PERSON> Schwarz </PERSON> said. `` These people are utterly strange bedfellows. They could n't possibly come up with a solution.'' Most city residents seem only vaguely aware of the proposed changes, which are n't, after all, going to revolutionize life in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. The average resident, <PERSON> Schwarz </PERSON> said, `` is going to find government more responsive, and that will be a plus. But will it pave the streets with gold? No.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 2352EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Flight103 2ndLd-Writethru a0735 10-30 0844</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Flight 103, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0735,0867</SECOND>
<HEAD>Investigators Check Maltese Link in Pan Am Bombing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: LEADS with 7 grafs to UPDATE with newspaper report of link
to Palestinian terror group established. Picks up 5th pvs, `London's Sunday
...' TRIMS thereafter. ^By KEVIN COSTELLOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FRANKFURT, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Investigators found a trail leading to <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> as the likely source of the bomb that blew up <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> Flight 103 over <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, killing 270 people, prosecutor's spokesman <PERSON> Jochen </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroers </PERSON> said Monday Authorities said a Libyan man may have played a role in the Dec. 21 bombing. Schroers, of the prosecutor's office, said a suitcase coming from <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> aboard an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Malta </ORGANIZATION> flight was the `` presumed'' container for the bomb. The suitcase was put aboard the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Malta </ORGANIZATION> flight on the tiny <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> island nation before being transferred to the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> flight at its originating point in <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>, officials reported. Other evidence recently uncovered by investigators in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> adds to suspicion that the bombing was carried out by the <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palestine-General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Tuesday editions. Sixteen members of the Palestinian group were arrested in raids in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in October 1988 and a bomb similar to the one believed to have destroyed the plane was seized in that investigation. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Talb </PERSON>, a Palestinian now being held on terrorism charges in <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, has told investigators he retrieved one bomb overlooked in the raids, and passed it to another person. Officials declined to identify to whom <PERSON> Talb </PERSON> said he passed the bomb. But they also said <PERSON> Talb </PERSON> was spotted in <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> in October 1988 in the company of <PERSON> Hafez </PERSON> <PERSON> Dalkamoni </PERSON>, a suspected leader of the Palestinian group who was arrested in the West German raids later that month. <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Sunday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> first disclosed the evidence of a possible Maltese connection. It said the bomb was placed in a suitcase containing clothing made and purchased in <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>. Citing British sources, the newspaper said the baggage list showed one suitcase was transferred to Flight 103 from <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Malta </ORGANIZATION> Flight KM180, which originated in <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> on the morning of Dec. 21. No passenger accompanied the bag on the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> flight, it said. All 259 people on the jumbo jet and 11 residents of <LOCATION> Lockerbie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, died as a result of the Dec. 21 bombing. In a statement sent by fascimile machine to news media, <PERSON> Schroers </PERSON> said West German investigators earlier informed <LOCATION> Scottish </LOCATION> investigators about suspicions regarding <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>. `` The suspicions were made more concrete, when the Scottish officials informed the Germans that clothing made in <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> was in the presumed bomb suitcase,'' the statement said. It said passengers on the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Malta </ORGANIZATION> flight were not under suspicion. The statement denied British news media reports of friction between West German and British investigators. <PERSON> Schroers </PERSON> said earlier in a telephone interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that West German investigators `` are in <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>, but the Scottish officials are taking the lead.'' `` It was possibly a man of Libyan extraction, but we ca n't say more than that,'' <PERSON> Schroers </PERSON> said of the person who investigators believe bought the clothes that were in the suitcase. `` The investigation into this lead has not been completed.'' Previous reports said the bomb was placed on board in luggage checked in at <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>. West German investigators repeatedly denied any evidence existed to substantiate those claims. Pan Am Flight 103 originated in <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>, taking on passengers and luggage flown in from other areas on international `` feeder flights.'' Passengers and bags were transferred to the doomed <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 at <LOCATION> Heathrow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Willi </PERSON> <PERSON> Fundermann </PERSON>, a spokesman for the federal criminal investigations office in <LOCATION> Wiesbaden </LOCATION>, said investigators have a `` hot trail'' leading to <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>. `` There are clues that a suitcase from <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> may have played a part,'' said <PERSON> Fundermann </PERSON>. `` There are also clues that someone from <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> _ or at least someone with a Libyan accent _ may have bought the items.'' The Flight 103 bomb was packed into a <ORGANIZATION> Toshiba </ORGANIZATION> radiocassette player, investigators have said. <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>, about 180 miles north of <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, enjoys good relations with the government of radical leader Col. <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, the chief investigator and head of the judiciary both refused Monday to disclose any details of the hunt for the bomber. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Esson </PERSON>, chief constable of <LOCATION> Dumfries </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Galloway </PERSON> who is leading the international investigation, issued a statement saying investigators are pursuing a number of `` encouraging lines of inquiry'' in a number of countries. <PERSON> Lord </PERSON> <PERSON> Fraser </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>'s Lord Advocate and its top judicial officer, said in a separate statement that `` the investigation continues to make encouraging progress.'' He said he feared that premature disclosure of the progress of the investigation `` could cause grave prejudice to the investigation itself.'' <PERSON> Esson </PERSON> said: `` Since the outset of this inquiry there has been a close liaison between the Scottish police, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> BKA </ORGANIZATION>. Information exchanged at regular meetings between these three agencies has contributed greatly to the ongoing and very active criminal investigation.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 2352EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--CrushedByElephant     10-30 0100</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Crushed By Elephant,0099</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pachyderm Kills Man For Beating Its Baby</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An elephant trampled to death a man who beat its baby for rampaging through his house in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bengal </LOCATION> state, a news agency reported. A herd of 40 elephants arrived in the area last week and caused havoc by trampling through houses and rice paddies, <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> quoted police as saying. The death occurred at <LOCATION> Salboni </LOCATION>, about 60 miles west of <LOCATION> Calcutta </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> added in Monday's dispatch. The day of death and the sex of the elephant were not given.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 2353EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-India-Violence Bjt   10-30 0818</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-India-Violence, Bjt,0840</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hindus vs. Moslems: Secular India Under Siege</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SHARON HERBAUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JAIPUR, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Stone-throwing mobs, blackened hulls of burned shops and the smell of gunpowder and smoldering ashes evoke dreaded memories of the bloodiest chapter in modern <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s history. Town after town in northern <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> is erupting in religious rioting. Even the former princely state of <LOCATION> Rajasthan </LOCATION> has become a victim of the frenzy and hatred it escaped during the birth of Hindu <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moslem </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> in the 1947 partition when an estimated 1 million people were killed. Hindu-Moslem riots and violence have claimed about 200 lives in the past six weeks. Against that backdrop, with Prime Minister <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s government and the opposition blaming each other for the renewed violence, next month's parliamentary elections could be the most divisive and violent in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 42 years of independence. `` The situation is so bad there might be a bloodbath before the elections. I feel it is the worst since independence,'' said <PERSON> Indrajit </PERSON> <PERSON> Gupta </PERSON>, deputy secretary-general of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION>. Nationwide, the communal caldron is on high boil. More than 500 people have died this year in sectarian violence in the Hindu heartland states _ <LOCATION> Bihar </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Uttar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pradesh </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rajasthan </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Madhya </PERSON> <PERSON> Pradesh </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Gujarat </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Maharashtra </LOCATION> _ more than double the number killed in the three previous years. `` Even for those of us who lived through the partition, there is no reason for this poison pill,'' said <PERSON> Shabir </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON>, a 63-year-old Moslem shopkeeper in <LOCATION> Jaipur </LOCATION>, the picturesque `` Pink City'' of <LOCATION> Rajasthan </LOCATION>. `` People now have blood on their hands, hatred in their eyes, revenge in their hearts, and their souls are ruled by rumors,'' he said. As the election draws closer, one right-wing opposition party is offering a different vision and fanning the communal flames. The <ORGANIZATION> Bharatiya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Janata </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and called <ORGANIZATION> BJP </ORGANIZATION>, has revived the idea of a Hindu <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, attacking the secular base on which modern <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> was created. It sees a groundswell of public support in this Hindu-dominated country _ particularly in northern <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> which has almost half the 542 seats at stake in the voting on Nov. 22, 24 and 26. The <ORGANIZATION> BJP </ORGANIZATION> contends Hindus have been discriminated against because of secularist policies dating back to <PERSON> Jawaharlal </PERSON> <PERSON> Nehru </PERSON>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s first prime minister and the current prime minister's grandfather, while minorities and particularly the Moslems have been pampered The <ORGANIZATION> BJP </ORGANIZATION> is not a major party but the main centrist opposition party, the <ORGANIZATION> Janata </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dal </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, has agreed to share seats with it in the north, largely because it sees no other way to defeat <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> and his <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. `` The obsession with vote banks seems to have driven out all rational thought,'' the conservative <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> newspaper said in an editorial. `` It's heads I win, tails you lose because brave words notwithstanding, the peril of communal animosity is still not taken seriously. It is all a game in which there is no prize beyond votes,'' the editorial said. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s religious and ethnic mosaic has been inhospitable to a Hindu party until now. Although Hindus comprise more than 80 percent of the population, they have long been divided along caste and class lines. Except in times of danger, they rarely vote as a bloc. Moslems, on the other hand, make up just 11 percent of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 880 million people but often wield pivotal electoral influence Yet they number more than 100 million, giving <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> the world's biggest Moslem population after <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>. Moslems traditionally have tended to vote as a bloc, making up more than 20 percent of the electorate in about 100 constituencies. But now the quest is for a new vote bloc, a consolidated Hindu vote cutting across caste lines. `` Never before have Hindus voted en bloc, and hence all political parties have ignored them, vitally affecting their interests,'' said <PERSON> Vishnu </PERSON> <PERSON> Hari </PERSON> <PERSON> Dalmia </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Vishwa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hindu </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parishad </ORGANIZATION>, or the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hindu </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>, a fundamentalist organization and a staunch <ORGANIZATION> BJP </ORGANIZATION> ally. `` The fundamental issue today is whether minorities are going to enjoy the status of a privileged class or are treated on par with their Hindu counterparts,'' <PERSON> Dalmia </PERSON> said. `` Thanks to the appeasement politics of the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> toward minorities for the last four decades today a Hindu in his own country is a second-class citizen.'' There are other undercurrents, but the primary reason for the sharpened hostility among Hindus and Moslems is the revival of a dispute over <LOCATION> Babri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Masjid </LOCATION>, a mosque in <LOCATION> Uttar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pradesh </LOCATION> that is believed built on the site of a demolished Hindu temple. The disputed site was locked in 1949. Neither Hindus nor Moslems could pray there until 1986 when a judge ordered the building unlocked for worship. The issue became a rallying cry for militant Hindu organizations that revived the call for building a temple and set Nov. 9 for the foundation-laying ceremony.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 2355EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PlantExplosion     10-30 0388</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Plant Explosion,0396</SECOND>
<HEAD>Memorial Service for Victims of Plant Explosion, Three More Bodies
Found</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL GRACZYK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PASADENA, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 25,000 people attended a memorial service Monday night for 22 workers who died in a series of explosions at a plastics plant last week, and three more bodies were recovered from the rubble. Among those attending the 45-minute service at the <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ray </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Harrison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> were 259 relatives of those who died in the <ORGANIZATION> Phillips </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> plant disaster last Monday. `` No one can really explain why happenings such as this occur,'' said S.R. `` Buddy'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, chairman emeritus of Bank One of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> here. `` I surely do n't know, but I do know this: a tragedy of this magnitude brings us all closer together and demonstrates the love, the care and the concern we have for one another.'' Sgt. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Cluck </PERSON>, chaplain of the <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, asked <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> employees to honor those who died by having the strength to return to work and live their lives `` the way they would want you to live.'' The recovery of three bodies brought the confirmed death toll to 17. The remains of five workers remain missing. The explosions injured 124 people. Despite thunderstorms and heavy rain, work crews continued moving tons of steel and concrete in hopes of recovering the last of the victims. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, whose district includes this city of 119,300, toured the plant and met with authorities. `` You really have to be here to see how absolutely devastating that blast was,'' <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON> said. `` Fully a quarter of the plant has been eliminated. There is still a safety factor at the plant site. There are still fires burning. It is an awesome sight to see.'' Much of the search has concentrated on the plant's control and finishing rooms, where debris is stacked as high as 40 feet, officials said. The polyethylene plant maufactured almost 20 percent of the nation's production of plastic pellets used to make milk jugs and grocery bags. <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> officials believe flammable hydrocarbon vapor from ethylene and isobutane gases escaped from a leaking chemical reactor, triggering the explosion. But company officials have said they do n't know how the gases were ignited and wo n't concentrate on finding a cause until all the missing victims have been found.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 2356EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     10-30 0479</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0497</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Look Who's Talking' Still No. 1, but `The Bear' Opens Strongly</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HORN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The comedy `` Look Who's Talking'' was the nation's favorite movie for the third straight weekend, making it <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>'s biggest hit of the season. The horror film `` Shocker'' and the nature drama `` The Bear'' opened to steady business, while actor <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Harmon </PERSON>'s `` Worth Winning'' bombed in its premiere. `` Look Who's Talking,'' starring <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Travolta </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kirstie </PERSON> <PERSON> Alley </PERSON> and the voice of <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON>, grossed $ 11.6 million last weekend. That raised its overall take to more than $ 45 million, more than any other movie this fall, according to figures released Monday by <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>. Director <PERSON> Wes </PERSON> <PERSON> Craven </PERSON>'s `` Shocker,'' a story about a television repairman whose execution does n't go quite according to plan, finished second last weekend, collecting $ 4.5 million in ticket sales `` The Bear,'' which chronicles three bears and two hunters struggling in the wilderness and broke several overseas box-office marks, opened to a $ 3.7 million gate in limited release. `` Next of Kin,'' the <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Swayze-Liam </PERSON> <PERSON> Neeson </PERSON> adventure movie, was in fourth place with $ 2.6 million. Next was the romantic thriller `` Sea of Love,'' with <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Pacino </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Barkin </PERSON>, which sold $ 1.84 million worth of tickets. The international cop drama `` Black Rain'' was sixth with $ 1.75 million. In seventh was `` Gross Anatomy,'' a look at the lives of students in their first year of medical school, with $ 1.74 million. `` The Fabulous Baker Boys,'' starring <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Pfeiffer </PERSON>, landed in eighth with $ 1.73 million. In ninth was the adoption drama `` Immediate Family,'' with <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> and <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Close </PERSON>, opening weakly with $ 1.68 million. In 10th was `` Worth Winning,'' starring <PERSON> Harmon </PERSON> in a game of sexual one-upmanship. The movie collected just $ 1.5 million in its first three days. Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION>. 1. `` Look Who's Talking,'' Tri-Star, $ 11.6 million weekend gross, 1,622 screens, $ 7,125 per screen, $ 45.4 million overall gross, three weeks in release. 2. `` Shocker,'' Universal, $ 4.5 million, 1,783 screens, $ 2,530 per screen, $ 4.5 million, one week. 3. `` The Bear,'' Tri-Star, $ 3.7 million, 858 screens, $ 4,285 per screen, $ 3.7 million, one week. 4. `` Next of Kin,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.6 million, 1,358 screens, $ 1,949 per screen, $ 8.8 million, two weeks. 5. `` Sea of Love,'' Universal, $ 1.84 million, 1,152 screens, $ 1,600 per screen, $ 49 million, seven weeks. 6. `` Black Rain,'' Paramount, $ 1.75 million, 1,202 screens, $ 1,458 per screen, $ 39 million, six weeks. 7. `` Gross Anatomy,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.74 million, 1,080 screens, $ 1,613 per screen, $ 5.3 million, two weeks. 8. `` The Fabulous Baker Boys,'' 20th <ORGANIZATION> Century </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.73 million, 782 screens, $ 2,213 per screen, $ 9.8 million, three weeks. 9. `` Immediate Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.68 million, 836 screens, $ 2,004 per screen, $ 1.68 million, one week. 10. `` Worth Winning,'' 20th Century <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, $ 1.5 million, 1,260 screens, $ 1,185 per screen, $ 1.5 million, one week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Devil'sNight     10-30 0318</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Devil's Night,0330</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Devil's Night' Period Begins in Detroit</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fires broke out on the first night of a three-night Halloween-time curfew Sunday as police, firefighters and citizen volunteers tried to keep `` Devil's Night'' arson under control. Asked how many fires had broken out, authorities said the mayor's office would compile figures and release them on Monday. No injuries were reported in any of the fires. Figures were also not available on the number of people arrested under the curfew, said Police Officer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Leavens </PERSON>. An abandoned home was set on fire twice within 90 minutes, radio station WWJ-AM reported. The second time, the blaze spread to an occupied home. Several fires were reported in garages on the city's lower east side, according to the station. Firefighters on the east side were so busy that firefighters were called in from the west side. Police found several cases of dynamite, blasting caps and radio control devices in the garage of a vacant home on the northeast side Sunday night, but were n't sure whether it was connected with Devil's Night, <PERSON> Leavens </PERSON> said. The police bomb squad took the explosives away for disposal. Fires are set during Devil's Night, which traditionally lasts three nights, in a destructive celebration of Halloween. The practice drew national attention in 1984, when 810 fires were set in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>. Since then, the number of fires has decreased each year. Last year, there were 229 fires reported, for an average of 76 per night. About 65 fires are reported on a normal night in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, fire officials have said. The curfew, which allows police to detain anyone under 18, went into effect at 6 p.m. and was to be in effect until 6 a.m. Monday In addition to police and firefighters, officials have said they expected 30,000 volunteers would help patrol streets. The Fire Department set up a special number for car phone callers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AgentOrange Bjt   10-30 0739</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Agent Orange, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Veterans' Administration to Reconsider Agent Orange Issue</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT GREENE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An advisory committee to the Department of Veterans Affairs this week may open the door a crack to disability benefits for <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans exposed to Agent Orange. Responding to a federal court decision in May, the 15-member Veterans' <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hazards </ORGANIZATION> will look again at scientific papers and studies on the herbicide used to clear dense foliage that hid the enemy. This time, however, the committee will use standards considered less strict than those used for determining other service-connected disabilities. No one is predicting the outcome. But there is agreement that <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> wants to resolve the issue quickly and in favor of veterans. `` I do n't think he's going to fool around very long,'' <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. `` He's so far exhibited a degree of willingness _ if not impatience _ to go along rather rapidly with this.'' Once the committee does its work <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> is `` kind of on his own as to how he wants to fly on this,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. He said <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> will make a final determination on the committee's recommendations within two weeks of receiving results of the meeting According to one congressional source, <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON>'s actions mean `` he's almost promised people'' that he will take some positive action for veterans. Veterans blame exposure to Agent Orange for cancers, skin diseases and genetic damage leading to miscarriages or birth defects. The committee will spend its first two days reviewing about 20 or 30 studies on the connection between exposure and non-Hodgkins lymphoma, one of the most frequently cited cancers, then study other diseases at later meetings. On Friday, it will issue recommendations on non-Hodgkins lymphoma and Agent Orange. The four-year-old advisory committee and government scientists have thus far rejected a link between Agent Orange exposure and health problems other than a skin condition known as chloracne. The American Legion, the prime veterans' group in this dispute, contends the committee has a longstanding bias against veterans. Not so, says <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Meadows </PERSON>, the disabled veteran and scientific layman in charge of the panel. `` Their greatest interest is their own integrity as scientists,'' he said. The government says the main problem with studies up to now is that there has been no way to verify exposure to dioxin. The American Legion and others say the government has detailed records on spraying activities that can be combined with equally detailed records on troop movements. Agent Orange, an orange-brown liquid that was shipped in orange-striped barrels, was sprayed in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> from January 1965 to April 1970. More than 230,000 veterans have registered with <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> claiming to have been exposed. More than 36,000 veterans have filed for disability benefits claiming Agent Orange exposure caused their problems, and two have been granted compensation _ for chloracne. Agent Orange is suspect because it contains `` phenoxy'' herbicides associated with certain cancers as well as dioxin, which has been found to cause cancer in laboratory animals. Dioxin's links to human health problems are disputed, although its links to human birth defects are more firmly established. A ruling in May by U.S. District Judge <PERSON> Thelton </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Henderson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> created a way out of the impasse over Agent Orange. A new administration and the elevation of the Veterans' Administration to cabinet status added another ingredient <PERSON> Henderson </PERSON> ruled May 2 that the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> imposed an `` impermissibly demanding test'' for linking Agent Orange with health problems. Although the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> has relied on a `` cause and effect'' relationship in determining service-connected disabilities, the committee was to use a different standard: `` a significant statistical association.'' <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> told Attorney General <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> on May 8 that he had decided against an appeal. New regulations for reviewing studies using the new standard, effective Wednesday, say a link will be deemed to exist if the studies associating Agent Orange with health problems outweigh the evidence that there is no association. The regulations say the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> secretary can give the `` benefit of the doubt to the conclusion that the association exists.'' In early October, <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> named Adm. <PERSON> Elmo </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Zumwalt </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> as a special adviser with a specific emphasis on Agent Orange. <PERSON> Zumwalt </PERSON> ordered spraying of Agent Orange during <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, and he lost a son who served in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> to a cancer linked with that spraying. <PERSON> Zumwalt </PERSON> is known as a veterans' advocate on this issue.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-FirstBlackGovernor     10-30 0518</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-First Black Governor,0531</SECOND>
<HEAD>First Black Governor Served A Month in Reconstruction Louisiana</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Va Governor</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOE TAYLOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RICHMOND, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's first black governor was a freed slave and a savvy politician who served a caretaker period of four weeks in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> after the Civil War, historians say. Interest in P.B.S. <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s governor from December 1872 to January 1873, has revived with the possible election in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> this year of a black governor, Democrat <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>. <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s lieutenant governor and a grandson of freed slaves, is running against Republican <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, a former attorney general who lost the state's 1981 election for governor. If <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> wins, he would be the first elected black governor of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> state. <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON> was not elected to the <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> office. <PERSON> Pinckney </PERSON> <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON> was `` the most intelligent, resourceful and dynamic of the black legislators during Reconstruction,'' said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carleton </PERSON>, a history professor at <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION>. `` He was a very able leader, a very persuasive speaker.'' The son of a <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> slave owner and a black slave, <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON> was freed by his father before the Civil War and was a captain in the <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. After the war, <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON> settled in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and joined the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> blacks </ORGANIZATION> and radical whites. He was elected to the <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1868 and was chosen as the chamber's president pro tempore When Lt. Gov. <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, who also was black, died in November 1871, <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON> moved by constitutional succession to the state's No 2 office under <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s carpetbag governor, <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> <PERSON> Warmoth </PERSON>. At the time, <PERSON> Warmoth </PERSON> was becoming a political maverick. A Republican, he was attempting to shift his power base to the Democrats, apparently sensing a revival of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s pre-war white power structure. In the 1872 election, <PERSON> Warmoth </PERSON> supported President <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>'s opponent, <PERSON> Horace </PERSON> <PERSON> Greeley </PERSON> But <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> won, and the next month the <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> legislature brought impeachment proceedings against <PERSON> Warmoth </PERSON>. During the trial, <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON> became acting governor. The impeachment case was still under way in January when <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s newly-elected <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> governor, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Pitt </PERSON> <PERSON> Kellogg </PERSON>, was sworn into office In his four weeks as governor, <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON> did nothing of consequence, said <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, a history professor at <ORGANIZATION> Tulane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. `` He was a colorful, very adroit and pragmatic politician who always seemed to manage to land on his feet,'' said <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>. `` In <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> during Reconstruction, that was no mean feat.'' <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON> later was elected to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> but was not seated because the vote was contested. He eventually moved to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, where he was a member of an informal Cabinet of black leaders involved in national political matters. He died in 1921. Before <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>'s campaign in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> this year, major parties have nominated two black politicans for governorships in recent years. In 1982 and 1986, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> ran as <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> candidate for governor, losing both times to Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON>. In 1986, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> Republican <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> failed to unseat Democratic Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Abortion-StateCourts Bjt   10-30 0595</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion-State Courts, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Availability of Abortion May One Day Hinge on State Courts</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD CARELLI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The availability of legal abortions for many women may one day hinge on rulings by their state's highest court, a key but often-overlooked battleground in the political fight over abortion. Public focus thus far has centered on state legislatures, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. But the role of state courts was dramatically underscored on Oct. 5, when the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled that the state constitution gives women a right to abortion. As a result, women in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> would be unaffected if the nation's highest court some day reverses its landmark 1973 decision and says the federal Constitution does not provide the right to abortion. If the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> merely passed a law criminalizing abortions, the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> surely would overturn it. Anti-abortion activists instead would have to try to amend the state constitution, an involved process not undertaken successfully since 1968. A state may never give its citizens fewer rights than those guaranteed by the federal Constitution, but it is free to provide greater rights. And the ultimate interpreter of each state's constitution is not the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> but that state's highest court For example, although governmental refusals to fund abortions for women on welfare have survived attacks based on the federal Constitution, such refusals were ruled invalid under the constitutions of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> court's broad ruling was not unprecedented. The <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> years ago found an abortion right in its state's constitution. Both state courts based their decisions on explicit statements guaranteeing the right of privacy. Although no other court has ruled directly on a right to abortion, at least five other state constitutions _ those of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> _ provide a right of privacy. In a few other states, most notably <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, rulings by the highest court have implied a state privacy right that could include the right to abortion. `` We have studied those state constitutions and are looking at the makeup of the highest court in each of those states,'' said <PERSON> Dawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnsen </PERSON>, legal director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abortion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>. Part of the abortion rights strategy will be to ask state, not federal, courts to overturn new restrictive laws based on state constitutional grounds. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Spaulding </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Right </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> to </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> says her organization began to focus on state constitutions long before the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> ruling. `` This battle will be in the states, and state court rulings on their constitutions therefore are included,'' she said. `` We know we have a problem in some states, and we are studying the matter.'' In those states in which there is no state constitutional right of privacy, challenges to restrictive abortion laws might be based on such legal notions as liberty, due process, equal protection and sexual equality. Such moves likely will be accompanied by efforts, on both sides of the fight, to amend state constitutions and to reshape the memberships of state legislatures and high courts. <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Ireland </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION> says getting more abortion rights supporters appointed to state high courts must be made part of `` the feminization of power'' her group seeks. `` State courts are part of the political package we are looking at,'' she said. `` They are present and future arenas.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EDITORS' NOTE: <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Carelli </PERSON> has covered the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> and legal affairs for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1976.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ForeignVoices Bjt   10-30 0815</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Foreign Voices, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Radio Free Europe-Poland Leader Gets Hero's Welcome</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Before Solidarity took power in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON> was the communist government's `` enemy No. 1'' because for 24 years he headed the Polish section of Radio Free <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, the U.S.-sponsored radio station that beams into the Soviet bloc. When <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON> returned to <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Aug. 28 for his first visit since 1945, he was stunned to find the airport crammed with senior Solidarity leaders. They took time out from forming the first non-communist government in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bloc </LOCATION> to welcome him as a hero. <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> called <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON>'s return `` a visible symbol of change,'' said <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON>, and his warm reception was symbolic of an improved status for Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty behind the crumbling Iron Curtain. The stations were created in 1950 and 1951 during the Cold War, and despite their ups and downs over the years, are thriving in the current thaw. <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON> headed the Polish section for 24 years starting in 1951. Official Polish television, which formerly condemned the so-called `` foreign voices'' that carried news censored from state-run media, not only reported <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON>'s triumphant return, it broadcast an interview with him. When <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON> stepped out the next day, `` to take a nostalgic walk through the city I had not visited for 45 years,'' a taxi driver veered over, took him around town, and refused to accept payment. `` The driver told me he had seen the airport arrival on television. He said, ` I listened to Radio Free Europe for so many years without paying anything. How can I take money from you?'' <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON>, 76, recalled during an interview after he returned to his home near <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Like <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Europe </ORGANIZATION> and its sister station, <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberty </ORGANIZATION>, are enjoying their new role not only in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> but in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and other countries of the communist bloc. `` It has become a very exciting place to be ... The radios are on the cutting edge'' of the changes underway in the Soviet bloc, said <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION> correspondent who now directs the twin radio stations. The stations were founded by the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, and in 1971, after revelations of <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> misdeeds, were separated from the spy agency and funded by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Congressional reports requested by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in 1984-85 criticized the stations for sometimes broadcasting material considered abusive of communist and government officials in the Soviet bloc. Since <PERSON> Pell </PERSON> took over in November 1985, said a foreign relations committee aide, `` he has done a fine job in curbing the problems we saw four years ago.'' But media in the Soviet bloc continued to depict `` the voices'' as branches of the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>, jammed their broadcasts to major cities, and bitterly condemned emigres like <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON> who worked for them. Nevertheless, the stations had an audience estimated at 50 million, according to the 1985 congressional report. Under the reforms launched since then by Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, the vituperation has ended and the audience has expanded. `` The major breakthrough was in November of last year, when they turned the jammers off,'' <PERSON> Pell </PERSON> said in a recent interview in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Taking advantage of the thaw, <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberty </ORGANIZATION>, which broadcasts to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, has hired reporters in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kiev </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Novosibirsk </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, who was the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> correspondent in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in the late 1970's, when most Soviets feared speaking with Westerners and could receive prison sentences of up to seven years for listening to <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Radio Free <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> _ which broadcasts to the rest of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> bloc </LOCATION> _ has received permission to open an office in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, and wants a bureau in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>. Official press criticisms have tapered off, and the weekly <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> last year praised <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberty </ORGANIZATION>'s coverage of the December 1988 earthquake in <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, calling it better than Radio <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s. `` In this case, we heard on a foreign band what we should have heard on our own,'' <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Ostrogorsky </PERSON> wrote in the Dec. 18, 1988, <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>. Although <PERSON> Ostrogorsky </PERSON> said the `` voices'' in the past had broadcast `` rumors, misrepresentations and outright lies,'' and had `` pushed their own ideological goods packaged as information,'' he praised the end of the jamming as testimony `` to the progress of glasnost'' or greater openness. <PERSON> Pell </PERSON> said, `` Simultaneously, another thing happened, the most significant of all. The place opened up. We could call people, they could call us.'' Broadcasters in <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION> tape reports from throughout the Soviet bloc, and transmit them back in. `` We now have a broadcast called ` at the kiosk,' in which our <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> correspondent reads excerpts from press reports the same day they are published,'' said <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>. The show is popular because the most interesting newspapers sell out quickly even in major cities, and may not be available at all elsewhere.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 0017EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PrisonDisturbances 3rdLd-Writethru a0807 10-30 0749</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Prison Disturbances, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0807,0767</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cleanup, Investigations in Wake of Week of Pennsylvania Prison Uprisings</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 6 grafs to UPDATE with new disturbance; picks up
4th graf, `Camp Hill's trouble ...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto HX1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL BLOOD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAMP HILL, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State police and guards kept watch Sunday over the remaining inmates at a riot-torn state prison, and investigations were planned to determine what caused two nights of bloody violence at the overcrowded penitentiary. In <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, a small fire broke out at a city prison Sunday night, forcing authorities to move about 100 inmates, said a police detective who spoke on condition of anonymity. No one was injured in the fire at <ORGANIZATION> Northeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, which came one night after a much more serious riot at another city prison and was the fifth disturbance to hit a <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> prison within a week. The 100 inmates were taken to a gymnasium as smoke from the fire cleared, the detective said. Four young men refused to return to their cells, and guards forced them to return, according to the officer. The prison near <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, where more than 100 people were injured in two nights of rioting last week, was calm Sunday, said <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>. The uprising there and at other prisons resulted in injuries to at least 183 people. Camp <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>'s troubles came between a disturbance at the <LOCATION> Huntingdon </LOCATION> state prison that left 48 injured last Monday and one at a <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> prison Saturday night, which resulted in serious injuries to three guards and the hospitalization of nine inmates. The Camp Hill uprising left at least 123 injured, almost half of the facility's buildings destroyed or damaged by fire, and hundreds of inmates without cells. Five people taken hostage Thursday were released Friday when state police stormed the prison, restoring order after a building-by-building assault. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said 744 Camp <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> inmates had been transferred to other state prisons since Friday. He said 200 more inmates would be sent to a new federal prison in <LOCATION> Bradford </LOCATION> in northwest <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, and as many as 600 others would be sent in groups of 50 to other federal jails. Hundreds of convicts had been forced to sleep on the ground at <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> under the eyes of guards and police officers. With the transfers and cleaning and repairing cells at <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, officials hoped to make cell space available for all inmates by Monday, <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said. `` We've got a lot of people in there cleaning up cellblocks as well as the kitchen buildings,'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said. The disturbance Saturday at <LOCATION> Holmesburg </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prison </LOCATION>, a county jail in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, was a `` copycat'' of the <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> riot, said city Prison Commissioner <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallagher </PERSON>. During the riot, which officials said began after an argument between several prisoners and a guard, inmates could be heard chanting, `` <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>.'' Forty-seven guards and 114 inmates were taken to hospitals, and nine inmates were admitted, three with head wounds, <PERSON> Gallagher </PERSON> said. Other convicts suffered broken bones and cuts, said hospital officials, who did not have an exact count. Three of the 47 guards suffered broken bones and deep cuts, but none were hospitalized, <PERSON> Gallagher </PERSON> said. Gov. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> said Saturday that he would appoint an independent commission to investigate why inmates rebelled at <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> on Wednesday and how they were able to get out of their locked cells to resume and escalate the violence Thursday. The state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and a state <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> subcommittee </ORGANIZATION> also planned to conduct their own reviews. At least one of the committees plans to study prison overcrowding, a problem at both state and county prisons. Officials say overcrowding may have been a contributing factor to the two state-prison problems as well as the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> disturbance. <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> said he also would back a criminal investigation of the riot, accelerate plans to replace the lost prison space and lessen overcrowding elsewhere, move to punish the inmates behind the uprising and review the need for more corrections officers. After the first day of violence ended Wednesday, <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> superintendent <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> said the prison did not have enough guards to deal with the prison population, which was 45 percent over capacity when the riots began. No damage estimate was available yet. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said four of the five hostages Thursday had been released from hospitals. The remaining guard was in fair condition. Three other prison staffers and six convicts also remained hospitalized Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     10-30 0829</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Looking Into Decline in US Oats Production</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A decline in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> oats production is prompting <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to look into the situation, and <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> analysts say consumer demand for oatmeal is one of the many factors for consideration. Some believe the government's price support program for oats should be modified to encourage farmers to plant more oats instead of turning to other feed grains such as barley, corn or sorghum. Whatever remedies are forthcoming, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> since 1982 has been a net importer of oats instead of an exporter. <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> are the major foreign suppliers. `` The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> market share of all world -LRB- oats -RRB- imports rose to an annual average of 44 percent in 1985-88, largest of all importing countries,'' says the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The agency, in a new staff report prepared as background for 1990 farm legislation, said oats are grown in most states but are concentrated in the North Central region, including the <LOCATION> Dakotas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>. In the 1950s, oats were grown on more than 40 million acres, and annual farm prices averaged 58 cents to 72 cents per bushel. In recent years, oats have been produced on 6 million to 10 million acres, with farm prices climbing from $ 1.21 per bushel in 1986 to $ 1.56 in 1987 and a record $ 2.67 in 1988. The value of oats production in 1987 ranked 16th among major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> field crops at $ 606 million. By comparison, corn was $ 14 billion; soybeans, $ 11.3 billion; hay, $ 9 billion; and wheat, $ 5.5 billion. `` The principal domestic use of oats is for livestock feed, although it has recently become a specialty feed for race and pleasure horses,'' the report said. Oats as human food includes the traditional oatmeal, along with oat flour, natural cereals, meat product extenders, cookies and breads, granola, oat bran and baby food. `` Recent medical research has shown that certain fibrous plant materials in the diet can lower serum cholesterol concentrations,'' the report said. `` The fibers, however, must be water soluble. Oat bran is water soluble, but wheat bran is not. Water-soluble dietary fibers also lower post-meal blood glucose levels in insulin-dependent diabetics.'' The report added: `` Thus, oat bran or whole oats is beginning to play a larger role in improving health through diet. Oats consumption by humans appears to be increasing, as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diets seem to be shifting toward cereal-based foods and away from fatty, high-protein animal-based foods.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> scientists say they have developed a new lethal snack for cockroaches, grasshoppers, crickets and fire ants that smells too yummy to resist. The bait includes corn mash left over from the manufacture of fuel-grade alcohol, ethanol, and a water-absorbent gel. The mixture is laced with a slow-release insecticide. According to the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, the new bait was initially designed to use against cockroaches. But researchers at the agencies insect laboratory in <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, found it attracted the other species, too. Entomologist <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brenner </PERSON> said the combination of corn mash and gel tends to retain moisture and `` remains aromatic under high temperatures and dry conditions.'' That makes it particularly attractive to roaches, which become hungry and thirsty when the temperature rises. The bait has been tested in the field as well as in the laboratory, and is waiting on approval by the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, he said. Although the mash-gel combination was developed by <PERSON> Brenner </PERSON> and an agency colleague, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON>, there are two other co-inventors: <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Pierce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, Cashier, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hult </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>. Air Vent and <ORGANIZATION> Pierce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> signed research agreements with the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> agency in February 1988 and hold first rights to license the bait when a patent is granted <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, to protect the bait's aroma and moisture during storage, suggested wrapping the bait in wax film that a hungry cockroach can open easily. <PERSON> Hult </PERSON> recommended using a bait holder, which would extend the shelf life of the mixture and protect it until ready for use. <PERSON> Brenner </PERSON> said that while the corn mash attracts roaches, hoppers, crickets and fire ants, it does n't attract warm-blooded animals as do baits of fruit, bread, raisins or beer.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The world's rice production is expected to rise slightly in 1989-90 but will fall short of meeting global demands, according to <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> projections. Significant harvest increases are expected in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, said the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s production may drop 6 percent from last year's record level but still would be the second-largest Total foreign rice production was forecast at 326 million metric tons, and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> crop at 4.93 million tons, milled equivalent. Analysts said that would be the fourth straight year that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> rice production has fallen short of total use, meaning another reduction in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> rice stockpile by next Aug. 1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names Sub a0426 10-30 0260</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names, Sub, a0426,0267</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS final item to CORRECT in 6th graf, `She was ...' that Morgan
was released one month ago from jail, sted two months ago.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Dr. <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> will have `` absolute control'' over a TV docudrama about her two years in jail for refusing to tell a judge the whereabouts of her daughter, an attorney says. The <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, D.C.-area plastic surgeon signed with <ORGANIZATION> Lansburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, makers of `` Adam,'' a television movie about a boy who was kidnapped and murdered, said <PERSON> Shelley </PERSON> <PERSON> Browning </PERSON>, an attorney who negotiated the deal for <ORGANIZATION> Morgan </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> has alleged that her former husband, Dr. <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Foretich </PERSON>, an oral surgeon, sexually molested their child, <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON>, now 7. <PERSON> Foretich </PERSON> vehemently denies the charges. <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> was jailed in 1987 for civil contempt of court by the judge presiding over their custody dispute. <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> refused to comply when the judge ordered her to allow <PERSON> Foretich </PERSON> unsupervised visits. She was released one month ago from the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, jail after <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> approved special legislation. Ms. <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> will be a consultant on the film and will wield `` final, absolute control over what appears,'' Ms. <PERSON> Browning </PERSON> said last week. When informed of the movie deal, <PERSON> Foretich </PERSON> said: `` I will absolutely sue them if my name or my daughter's name is used without my consent.'' Ms. <PERSON> Browning </PERSON> said she expects to win any lawsuit by <PERSON> Foretich </PERSON> because `` he has made himself a public figure.'' <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>'s fee, an undisclosed amount totaling less than $ 250,000, will go into a trust fund for <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON>, Ms. <PERSON> Browning </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 0042EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CarrierAccident 6thLd-Writethru a0813 10-30 0591</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Carrier Accident, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0813,0603</SECOND>
<HEAD>Accident on Flight Deck Leaves Five Dead, Two Injured</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 9th graf, `The Lexington ...,' to UPDATE with expected
time of arrival for ship.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY19</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BILL KACZOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PENSACOLA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A trainer jet crash-landed Sunday afternoon on the flight deck of the aircraft carrier <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, killing five people and injuring at least two, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said. The 3:30 p.m. CST crash of the two-seat T-2 <LOCATION> Buckeye </LOCATION> caused several fires on the World War II-era ship that sailors quickly brought under control, officials said. The <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s oldest aircraft carrier, was 30 miles south of its home port of <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION> when the accident occurred, said <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, a civilian spokesman at <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Naval </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION>. Officers on the ship said five people were killed in the crash-landing and at least two were injured, said White. The jet was assigned to <ORGANIZATION> Training </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Squadron </ORGANIZATION> 19, based at the <LOCATION> Meridian </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Station </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> White </PERSON> said. The victims' identities were being withheld pending notification of their relatives In addition to destroying the jet, the crash did major damage to two aircraft on the flight deck and minor damage to another, said Army Maj. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, a spokesman at the Pentagon. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> helicopters took the dead and injured to the <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION>, and to the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in Mobile, authorities said. One of the injured, <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>, 21, was in critical but stable condition at the Mobile hospital with second - and third-degree burns over 40 to 45 percent of his body, hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Monica </PERSON> <PERSON> Knight </PERSON> said <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> was the only sailor brought to that hospital, she said. <PERSON> White </PERSON> said he did not know <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>'s rank or hometown. The <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> was heading back to <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION>, and was expected to arrive at the city's commercial port around 10 a.m. Monday, officials said. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> sent a jet from Mobile to fly a team of ordnance experts in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Lt. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasper </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> apparently was concerned that fuel cells aboard the jet might explode after being damaged in the crash, <PERSON> Kasper </PERSON> said. The 46-year-old <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> is the only aircraft carrier used exclusively by the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> for training. It has 1,440 men and women assigned to it. The accident occurred a week before the 45th anniversary of a Japanese kamikaze attack that killed 47 crew members and injured 127 on Nov. 4, 1944. The original <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> crew plans to hold a reunion next weekend in <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION> that includes a day cruise on the carrier on Saturday, Nov. 4, to commemorate the attack. The <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> was commissioned on Feb. 17, 1943. Its planes sank or destroyed more than a million tons of Japanese shipping and 1,039 enemy aircraft. The carrier was dubbed `` The Blue Ghost'' by Japanese propagandist <PERSON> Tokyo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> during World War II because she had reported it sunk several times only to have it return to battle, painted a solid blue-grey color, unusual in wartime when ships are usually camouflaged. The <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> was mothballed after the war, but was reactivated in 1955. It reported to <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION> on Dec. 29, 1962, to serve as the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s training carrier. It is scheduled to continue that role after moving next September to <LOCATION> Corpus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The ship has been a favorite of movie producers with roles in the film `` Midway'' and the made-for-television mini-series `` War and Remembrance.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Scotus-KCDesegregation     10-30 0440</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus-KC Desegregation,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Supreme Court to Hear Arguments on Kansas City Desegregation Case</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Prenoon lead planned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY MASSEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> is being asked to decide whether a federal judge may impose a tax increase to pay for court-ordered school desegregation in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>. At issue in today's oral arguments is a federal judge's 1987 order doubling the property tax of residents in the <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> school district to finance a court-ordered plan for racially desegregating the public schools. Legal scholars and education officials say the court's decision could shape future school desegregation plans across the country and define the federal courts' power to remedy constitutional violations involving issues from prison overcrowding to fair housing. The state of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> is asking the justices to overturn a decision by the 8th <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> that upheld the property tax increase ordered by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>. The state contends that the federal courts lack the power to order higher taxes even to correct a constitutional violation such as racial discrimination in schools. The school district and a group of school children, who brought the original desegregation case in 1977, are urging the high court to uphold the tax decision. The district contends that state property tax law and local voters can not be allowed to frustrate the constitutional rights of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s minority schoolchildren to an equal educational opportunity. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> ordered the tax increase in September 1987 after the local school district was unable to pay its share of a more than $ 400 million desegregation plan he had approved for capital improvements in buildings and establishment of special `` magnet'' schools. State law says local property taxes may be raised only with voters' approval, and in some instances only with a two-thirds majority. District voters had not approved a levy increase since 1969, with four tax increase proposals rejected in 1986 and 1987 to finance the desegregation plan. In addition to doubling the property tax, <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> imposed an income tax surcharge on those people living or working in the school district. The appeals court struck down the income surcharge in August 1988, but upheld the district court's authority to order an increase in the property tax. However, the appeals court modified the procedure for imposing the higher tax levy. The appeals court found that state law had effectively prevented the school district from levying the necessary taxes to pay for the desegregation plan. It upheld <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>'s order as one that `` set aside levy limitations,'' and empowered the elected local school board to set the needed tax levels within certain limits.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891030-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-30-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Hugo-Tourism Bjt   10-30 0586</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hugo-Tourism, Bjt,0606</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tourism Reviving After Hugo, Rebound Expected in '90</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto CHT1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRUCE SMITH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
