<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0222EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TalkShowFest Bjt   06-10 0580</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Talk Show Fest, Bjt,0597</SECOND>
<HEAD>Talk Show Hosts Say They're Ignored Despite Their Influence</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ARLENE LEVINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Radio talk show hosts proved they're a force to be reckoned with during the congressional pay-raise brouhaha, deluging <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> with millions of tea bags from angry listeners. But they still feel ignored. So they're meeting in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> this weekend to do what other aggrieved minorities do: unite to demand more power. `` In the words of <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Dangerfield </PERSON>, ` We do n't get no respect,''' said organizer <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> radio station <ORGANIZATION> WRKO </ORGANIZATION>. `` The national media ... never took us very seriously. They think there's some conspiracy here.'' About 50 of the country's 225 radio talk show hosts began arriving Friday for the inaugural <ORGANIZATION> TalkRadio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>, a two-day gab confab expected to include consumer activist <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Nader </PERSON>, TV talk show host <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and political columnist <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, a 65-year-old talk jockey who's been in the business since 1950, said he hoped the gathering would give visibility to a national movement that has given ordinary people a chance to be heard. `` There's a huge void where people feel they do n't have a voice anymore,'' he said. The voices at the conference are deep and smooth. The smiles are big. The words are vehement and well-rehearsed. `` There is no more representative government in this country anymore. It's all special interests,'' said <PERSON> Mills </PERSON> <PERSON> Crenshaw </PERSON> of WTKK-AM in <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. `` The reason politicians are afraid of talk radio is we have the ability to allow private citizens to talk to their government.'' <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> took the first step toward unifying the talk show hosts in February, when he was able to persuade his colleagues to lead a national protest against proposed federal pay increases. Coaxed by their local hosts, listeners sent their congressmen a ton of tea bags bearing the message: `` Read my tea bag: no 50 percent raise.'' The public pressure helped halt a raise for lawmakers, judges and other people on the federal payroll. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said he was encouraged by the cooperation of his on-air brethren to try to formalize their connections through a conference. The session got going Friday with an open mike to <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> area listeners. Today, the talk show hosts planned to talk to each other, exchanging ideas and formally organizing, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said. Faneuil Hall, the venerable brick building where revolutionaries fomented independence from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and abolitionists railed against slavery, served as the stage for Friday's events. In the morning, <ORGANIZATION> WRKO </ORGANIZATION> host <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> leaned into one of the microphones and said, `` The people are sovereign, not the government,'' adding: `` Our elected representatives try ... to give Americans enough fat from the hog to keep people from rising up.'' His peers from across the country and about 125 listeners from around <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> took their seats. And in person, the talk show fans were as vociferous as their radio friends. `` I like to hear what the people say and not the politicians. We have a governor here who's a dictator,'' said <PERSON> Z. </PERSON> <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Czapski </PERSON>, 67, of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Andover </LOCATION>, his face turning red. `` You've got me going,'' the retired tool and die plant manager said happily. <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Wofsey </PERSON>, 36, of <PERSON> Quincy </PERSON>, who works for a department store, said she's a frequent listener and talker. `` It's the satisfaction of voicing my opinion, to express it over the airwaves. With letter writing, there's no response,'' she said. `` You can get a response from the talk show.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0319EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-MexicoSlayings     06-10 0477</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico Slayings,0496</SECOND>
<HEAD>Defendants Await Indictments in Matamoros Slayings</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CANDICE HUGHES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman described as the godmother of a gang of drug-smuggling ritual killers says she is innocent of any wrongdoing, including 15 slayings at a ranch near <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION>. But <PERSON> Sara </PERSON> <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> <PERSON> Villarreal </PERSON>, 24, of <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION>, also said Friday she expects to be indicted on murder charges. She scoffed at the claim by investigators that she was the `` madrina,'' or godmother, of the gang. Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> and <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Orea </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON>, 23, of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, were interviewed by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> at the Eastern Penitentiary. They have been held there since the May 6 shootout with police in which cult leader <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> and his associate, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Quintana </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, were killed. <PERSON> Orea </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON>, Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> and gang member <PERSON> Alvaro </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> were arraigned in the <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION> slayings earlier this week in the 9th Federal Criminal Court in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and were awaiting other indictments. They were indicted last month on various charges in connection with <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON>'s death in a <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> apartment and pleaded innocent. Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> and <PERSON> Orea </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> also said they were innocent of the Matarmoros killings and when they were captured May 6 they were fleeing, against their will, with <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON>. `` He threatened me,'' said <PERSON> Orea </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> of <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> said the man who forced her to accompany him was a different man from the charming fortune-teller she'd met a year and a half earlier. `` I thought I knew him, but I did n't,'' she said. <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> made her go with him when he fled <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> because he feared she would go to police, she added. Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> said <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> hit her and threatened her with a submachine gun. <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON>, <PERSON> Quintana </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, <PERSON> Orea </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> left <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION> after authorities began digging up mutilated bodies April 9 at the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Elena </LOCATION> ranch. Among the victims was <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON>, a 21-year-old <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> student. Authorities said <PERSON> Kilroy </PERSON> and several other victims were sacrificed in rituals to provide magical protection for the gang's drug-trafficking business Seven people in <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION>, including two fugitives, were charged last month in the slayings. Both <PERSON> Orea </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> said they knew nothing of the <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION> killings until they saw news reports. <PERSON> Orea </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> said he had never been to the ranch, and Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> said she was there only once for a birthday party. Ms. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON>, a former honor student at <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southernmost </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION>, said she spends her time in solitary confinement reading. `` If I knew I did something, I could say I was paying for it, but I did n't,'' she said. <PERSON> Orea </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> said he tries not to think about what will happen to him. `` The future is very black,'' he said. `` Something completely different from what I wanted.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0324EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Yellowstone-Hostages     06-10 0422</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Yellowstone-Hostages,0435</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gunman Surrenders After Releasing Hostages at Old Faithful</HEAD>
<DATELINE>YELLOWSTONE NATIONAL PARK, Wyo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A gunman who surrendered to park rangers after releasing eight hostages from a visitors' center will undergo a psychiatric examination, authorities said The man, identified as <PERSON> Brett </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, was taken into custody Friday night and transported to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, where he will be tested. `` He is a frustrated guy who has had a hard life,'' said park ranger <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, noting that <PERSON> Hartley </PERSON> once suffered from cancer. `` He was relatively calm the whole time.'' The hostage-taking `` was an expression of asking for help. Some people have a hard time asking for help,'' <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> said. Park spokesman <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hartley </PERSON>, 18, walked into the center at <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION>'s Old Faithful geyser complex shortly after 3 p.m. Friday, brandished a Ruger .30 - caliber revolver and told everyone inside to lie Women and children who were visiting were released a few minutes later, but <PERSON> Hartley </PERSON> held eight hostages about three hours, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. The hostages included five male visitors and three park employees, two of whom were women. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Painter </PERSON>, 34, of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, one of the hostages held for three hours, said the center was silent inside except for the sound of <PERSON> Hartley </PERSON> talking on the telephone with park rangers. `` I was just lying there on the floor watching him,'' Painter said. `` I was scared. I did n't know what was going to happen. He did n't say a word -LRB- to us -RRB-. He never said anything about why. He was real calm.'' Suddenly, at 6 p.m., <PERSON> Hartley </PERSON> yelled an obscenity into the telephone and told everyone to leave, <PERSON> Painter </PERSON> said. The hostages ran out the door. No one was injured and no shots were fired, park authorities said. Park ranger <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> said he conducted the telephone negotiations for nearly five hours with <PERSON> Hartley </PERSON>, who had a gun trained on the hostages throughout much of the period. <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hartley </PERSON> told him he planned the incident, and that `` it was a choice between the Grand Canyon and Yellowstone.'' <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hartley </PERSON> put the gun down about 8 p.m. and walked outside the center, where he was met by three park rangers in a car. After a short conversation, he was handcuffed and placed in the car, <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> said. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON> are scheduled to visit <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> on Monday to inspect damage from last summer's forest fires The center is not in an area the president planned to visit.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0325EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Bangladesh-Bus     06-10 0088</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bangladesh-Bus,0090</SECOND>
<HEAD>30 Feared Killed When Bus Falls in River</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DHAKA, Bangladesh (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> divers recovered 15 bodies and searched for 15 more believed trapped in a bus that fell into the <LOCATION> Daratona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> while driving onto a ferry in southern <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION>, police said today. The bus was carrying about 48 people Friday when it toppled into the river near <LOCATION> Bagerhat </LOCATION>, 85 miles south of <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bagerhat </LOCATION> police said. Eighteen people swam to safety, the authorities said. The bus was traveling from <LOCATION> Perojpur </LOCATION> to nearby <LOCATION> Bagerhat </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0342EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SewingSnag     06-10 0506</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sewing Snag,0520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pennsylvania Labor Department Orders End to Gift Concern's Home Labor</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID S. MARTIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MCCONNELLSBURG, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman struggling to keep her $ 1.7 million gift business alive says the state's enforcement of a law banning sewing work at home is unfair and has cost nearly 100 women their jobs. The state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION> has ordered <ORGANIZATION> Overly-Raker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> to stop using 100 or more homeworkers to piece together `` soft sculptures'' _ geese, cows, cats and other creations stuffed in cloth skins. <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Overly </PERSON>, the company's president, said she was unaware of the 1937 Industrial Homework Act and made no effort to hide the company's use of women sewing at home. The law prohibits anyone other than handicapped or those providing primary care for a handicapped family member from doing industrial work at home. Overly, a former teacher, founded the company in her basement 16 years ago with <PERSON> Freda </PERSON> <PERSON> Raker </PERSON>, a former secretary who handles the business' creative end. Since the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standards </ORGANIZATION> ordered the company to stop home production May 11 in response to a complaint, Overly said she began to hire the 30 or more seamstresses needed at a plant in a former dairy distribution building in southern <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>'s rural <LOCATION> Fulton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. `` The biggest hassle now is to find people who will come in,'' she said. Most of the women who had worked at home will lose their jobs because they have small children or can not get to the plant, she said. `` There's a lot of hardship going on because of this.'' One worker, <PERSON> Virginia </PERSON> <PERSON> Logsdon </PERSON>, said the $ 250 a month she earned supplemented her husband's income. She said she worked for almost two years, usually earning about $ 4 an hour based on the piece rate paid by Overly-Raker. `` It was very important. It takes what my husband makes to meet the expenses,'' she said. `` My money would take care of clothes, the dentist, medicines.'' <PERSON> Logsdon </PERSON> said she ca n't leave her 11-year-old daughter, <PERSON> Colletta </PERSON>, and 12-year-old son, <PERSON> Danny </PERSON>, to drive the more than 100 miles between her home in rural <LOCATION> Armstrong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> to the new Overly-Raker plant. <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> standards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> bureau </ORGANIZATION>, said the state was determined to enforce labor laws. `` We work to protect people's rights,'' she said. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, an international vice president for the <ORGANIZATION> Amalgamated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clothing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Textile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>, said homework provides an opportunity for companies to exploit workers. `` There is no control. There is no such thing as overtime. Their children help them. Before you know it, children under 12 have become helpers,'' <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> said. `` It becomes substandard conditions.'' During a recent interview, Overly said the company had more than 400 orders for more than 8,000 pieces of merchandise as it prepares for the Halloween to Christmas holiday season. She had hired only five full-time seamstresses and was worried about higher labor costs when the threat from low-cost imports from <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> is growing. Still, she said the company would survive.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0344EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-JewishEmigration Bjt   06-10 0581</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jewish Emigration, Bjt,0599</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Jews Being Asked to Finance Freedom of Their Soviet Brethren</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY SCHWARTZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For years, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Jews have set aside a special matzo each Passover and prayed for the emigration of their brethren in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Now that those prayers have been answered for many, Jews in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are being asked to set aside something more than unleavened bread _ the money required to resettle as many as 50,000 Jews who are expected to leave the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> this year. The United Jewish Appeal, the national fund-raising campaign for Jewish causes in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, has launched Passage to Freedom, an effort aimed at raising $ 75 million for Soviet emigres this year. Half will go to resettlement activities in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The rest will be split between Soviet Jews in transit to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, and those seeking to settle in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. `` We have worked for years and years to free them from <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>. Now that they are free, we ca n't deny them the freedom to choose where they are going to live,'' said <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Reider </PERSON>, director of public affairs for the <ORGANIZATION> Jewish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Greater </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. `` We really do n't know how long these doors will be open,'' said <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Lender </PERSON>, who is leading the national effort. `` We're looking at the third largest Jewish community in the world, and here's an opportunity to save them.'' The campaign, launched in April, already has raised more than $ 21 million. <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Tishman </PERSON>, president of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s UJA-Federation of Jewish Philanthropies, said one reason for the success is that many American Jews feel they did too little to save European Jews from <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>. `` The idea of not losing another Jewish soul is all-pervasive,'' she said. Programs to help Soviet Jews have been taxed to the breaking point by the flood of emigres, especially in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, the destination for more than half of the new arrivals. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> for New Americans, the biggest private resettlement agency that gets about two-thirds of its money from the <ORGANIZATION> UJA </ORGANIZATION>, has had to spread its staff among three offices to make room for more caseworkers. The association is operating as many as 70 English classes a day for immigrants. It also helps new arrivals find jobs and housing. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s UJA-Federation has taken a $ 100,000 advance from its Passage to Freedom money to finance scholarships to Jewish day camps so youngsters can adjust to life in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> while their parents learn English, get jobs and find places to live. Appeal money in other cities also will go to programs with proven track records. `` In four to five months, we can make them tax-paying members of the community,'' said <PERSON> Reider </PERSON>. About 18,000 Soviets, mostly Jewish, left the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in the first five months of this year and another 26,000 applicants are waiting to be interviewed at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. With only about 10 percent of the Soviet Jewish emigres choosing to go to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, some Zionists complain that too much money is going to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> resettlement programs. `` Given the choice, I'd rather see much more of the Passage to Freedom money go to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Lynne </PERSON> <PERSON> Abramson </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Long </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> for Soviet Jewry. Still, she said she has given to the appeal. `` I feel that we need very much to help them when they are here,'' Ms. <PERSON> Abramson </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Taiwan-China     06-10 0242</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Taiwan-China,0250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Military Chief Urges Chinese Troops to Support Democracy</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-China, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TAIPEI, Taiwan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s military chief has urged troops in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> to support the democracy movement and end their crackdown on demonstrators campaigning for freedom, a television station reported. `` We hope the mainland troops, especially the younger ones, will join the people to fight for freedom and democracy,'' Gen. <PERSON> Hau </PERSON> <PERSON> Pei-tsun </PERSON>, chief of the armed forces, said Friday night in a rare interview with the state <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> `` We urge troops on the mainland not to become accomplices to the suppression of democracy,'' <PERSON> Hau </PERSON> said. `` Mainland troops should play the leading role in establishing a new <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> under democracy.'' <PERSON> Hau </PERSON> spoke five days after Chinese troops swept through <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Tiananman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, killing hundreds, possibly thousands, to suppress the pro-democracy uprising that began in mid-April Hardliners in the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> leadership appear to have won a power struggle there, and reports from <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> say troops now are arresting supporters of the democracy movement. The Nationalists, defeated on the mainland in a civil war in 1949, are technically still at war with the Communists. They continue to claim they are <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s legitimate rulers. <PERSON> Hau </PERSON>, 69, born on the mainland and trained in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, heads <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s 500,000-man armed forces. <PERSON> Hau </PERSON> said the uprising suggests economic reforms initiated by senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> have failed. <PERSON> Hau </PERSON> said he now expects a lengthy purge of opponents of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s hardline leaders
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0432EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-HongKong-China     06-10 0402</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hong Kong-China,0414</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Hong Kong Preparing to Offer Asylum to Chinese Refugees</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> is preparing to offer asylum to political refugees from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s Guardian newspaper reported today. Quoting the British colony's secretary for security, the paper said trained personnel and screening procedures have already been set up at the border with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Guandong </LOCATION> province, `` even though it is recognized that this move will add to the growing tensions between <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>.'' The secretary, <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON>, was in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> with <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>'s governor, Sir <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, for talks with the British government `` In the volatile situation in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, nobody can rule out that a mass of refugees will attempt to cross the thin wire fence that now divides <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> from the New Territories,'' the report said. The colony consists of an island and a mainland area called the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Territories </LOCATION> adjoining the south of <LOCATION> Guandong </LOCATION> province. In <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, Chinese and diplomatic sources say police have begun arresting intellectuals accused of encouraging the protests and participants in the resistance to military intervention. The Guardian said <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> stressed that so far there had been no requests for asylum among the daily handful of Chinese who cross the border illegally. It said that in the past, illegal immigrants were sent back to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> within 24 hours. `` But now, in the light of events in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, political asylum will be granted and, unlike the Vietnamese boat people, whose presence is causing increasing friction in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, Chinese refugees are certain to be welcomed,'' the report said. The military assault on pro-democracy demonstrators in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> has hurt the <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> economy by raising anxieties over the period after July 1997, when <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> is to hand the colony back to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> under the terms of an agreement signed in 1984. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s upheaval already has dealt a serious blow to the <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> stock exchange and badly shaken confidence in the property market. Officials in the colony said today they fear a drop in its annual $ 4.3 billion tourism business as travelers cancel visits because of the upheaval. About 5.6 million people visited <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> last year and 28 percent of them coupled the trip with a visit to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Hong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tourist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Many people now canceling tours to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> also are dropping <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Woo </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Hong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotels </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0512EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador     06-10 0466</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador,0480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Leftists Blamed in Killing of Senior Cabinet Minister</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANNIE CABRERA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> blamed leftist guerrillas for the assassination of his closest adviser and said they were `` trying to provoke a reaction'' from his right-wing government. All major political groups condemned the submachine-gun killings of <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Porth </PERSON>, 73, and two bodyguards Friday outside the minister's home. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> issued a White House statement calling the assassination a `` vicious murder,'' and some Salvadoran politicans warned it could lead to new political polarization in the nation. <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Porth </PERSON>, a Cabinet member considered <PERSON> Christiani </PERSON>'s chief of staff, was the highest ranking official killed in the 9-year-old civil war between the U.S.-backed government and the rebels. The rebels as of early today had not claimed responsibility for the shootings. <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ungo </PERSON>, a Social Democrat and political ally of the rebels, said the slaying was `` an assasination in cold blood ... that does not contribute in any way to peaceful coexistence and dialogue.'' <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> called <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> `` one of the most illustrious men of our country'' and told a news conference his adminstration will not not allow more `` provocations that push our country farther down into the whirlpool of violence.'' <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> said his government is convinced the leftist <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- is `` trying to provoke a reaction from us, but we are not going to react outside of the law.'' Gunmen fired on <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Porth </PERSON>'s car after he left his home in the capital. He died shortly after he was taken at <ORGANIZATION> Zaldivar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, a nurse said on condition of anonymity. Police said the two bodyguards, one of whom was driving the car, died at the scene. <PERSON> Gerardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Chevallier </PERSON>, leader of the centrist <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, warned the assassinations could mark a new political polarization in the country. He said the attack was the result of `` the declarations of <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> that if the <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION> does not accept its peace proposal there could be a military response.'' The rebel front last week offered to halt attacks if the new right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> government eliminated death squads. The alliance, known as <PERSON> Arena </PERSON>, denies any involvement with death squads and spurned the proposal. Arena was founded in 1981 by cashiered army Maj. <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> d'Aubuisson </PERSON>, who has been linked to the squads that killed thousands of suspected leftists in the early 1980's. He denies the accusations. Also among the founders was <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, who was a vice minister in the 1940's, a member of the civilian-military junta in 1961 and foreign minister in 1978. Guerrillas have pledged to make the country ungovernable under the administration of <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON>, who won a presidential election in March. About 70,000 people, mostly civilians, have died since civil war broke out in 1980.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0515EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ForcedRepatriation 1stLd-Writethru a0413 06-10 0397</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Forced Repatriation, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0413,0401</SECOND>
<HEAD>Diverse Groups Protest Proposed Indochinese Immigration Measures</HEAD>
<HEAD>Ed: Leads with 3 grafs to recast and explain allusion to `Voyage
of the Damned.' Picks up 4th graf: `A spokesman ...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICH CARTIERE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Protesters rallied against the proposed forced repatriation of Indochinese refugees from <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, likening the move to the Voyage of the Damned in 1939. They demonstrated outside the British Consulate in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> on Friday as officials in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> urged that <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> send home most Vietnamese boat people. Demonstrators harkened back to the voyage of a German ship loaded with fleeing Jews who were refused entrance to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The 900 Jewish passengers aboard the SS <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> returned to various European ports and many later died at Nazi hands. The event was depicted in the 1975 movie `` Voyage of the Damned'' starring <PERSON> Faye </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunaway </PERSON> and <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Sydow </PERSON>. A spokesman at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>'s British Consulate said officials had no comment. But the colony's British secretary of security, <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON>, told reporters at a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> news conference that <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> `` has had enough.'' The refugee problem is creating a second crisis for the British colony deeply worried about coming under Chinese rule in 1997, he said. <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> has 42,766 Vietnamese boat people, one-third of whom arrived this year. <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> said all but 14,150 were simply seeking a better way of life, rather than political refuge. The protesters _ including Jewish representatives, <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> lawmakers and former Vietnamese boat people _ carried signs that read, `` Princess <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>. Do n't Let Them Butcher Us'' or that quoted <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>: `` When people are free to choose, they choose to be free.'' Dr. <PERSON> Toan </PERSON> <PERSON> Truong </PERSON>, who escaped from <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> just two days before the fall of <LOCATION> Saigon </LOCATION> in April 1975, told some 50 rally participants that forced repatriation was `` something that will be perpetrated by bloodless bureaucrats.'' `` This is a crime against humanity,'' said <PERSON> Truong </PERSON>, who was among two dozen protesters who began a five-day fast to call attention to their cause. Besides the British colony, protesters said countries that may be considering repatriation include <LOCATION> Brunei </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Malayasia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>. Demonstrators called on <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> to oppose repatriation and the screening of Southeast Asian immigrants. The issues will be discussed at the two-day <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> on Indochinese Refugees in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> beginning Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0516EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Marcos-Suit     06-10 0436</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Marcos-Suit,0450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prosecutors Seek Judgment Against Marcos Even in Event of Death</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN M. DOYLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal prosecutors want to guarantee they have a claim against the assets of former <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> even after he's dead. To that end, they filed a civil racketeering lawsuit against <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON>, on Friday. The critically ill, 71-year-old <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> and his 59-year-old wife are already under a criminal racketeering indictment in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, charged with siphoning millions of dollars from their homeland's treasury The latest lawsuit, filed under the civil aspects of the Racketeer Influenced Corrupt Organizations Act, closely parallels allegations in the 90-count criminal indictment. `` The civil complaint was filed in order to ensure that the interests of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as well as the interests of the victims of the racketeering enterprise will be fully preserved in the event of the death of <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>,'' said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Benito </PERSON> <PERSON> Romano </PERSON>. Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> LaBella </PERSON> said the victims include the <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> people and numerous <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> banks. The criminal charges against <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> and attending forfeiture claims against his alleged ill-gotten gains would be dismissed after his death, <PERSON> Romano </PERSON> explained. `` Conversely, a civil complaint filed by the government against an individual defendant continues against the estate of a deceased defendant,'' he said. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' lawyer, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hibey </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, said he would fight the civil case as well as the criminal charges. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tigue </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> attorney for Mrs. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, said: `` The lawsuit will be defended against vigorously, as is the underlying charge which essentially contains the same allegations.'' The Marcoses have lived in exile in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> since they were toppled in a popular uprising in February 1986. Mrs. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> pleaded innocent to the federal charges. Her husband's ill health kept him from making the trip from <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> for arraignment. In April he was separated from the case, although the charges were not dropped. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, who suffers from heart and lung ailments, has been hospitalized in <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> since Jan. 16. He underwent emergency surgery for kidney failure last month. His doctors and lawyers say he is near death. A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> grand jury indicted the Marcoses and eight others last October on various charges. Racketeering charges against the Marcoses accused them of looting more than $ 103 million from the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> to buy art and real estate in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. The indictment also said the Marcoses defrauded <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> banks and lending institutions of more than $ 165 million in buying and financing the choice <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> real estate.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0517EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Honduras-Panama     06-10 0277</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Honduras-Panama,0285</SECOND>
<HEAD>Honduras Warns Panama it Will Cut Electricity if Bills Not Paid</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> says it will cut the electricity it provides to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> if its Central American's neighbor does not pay a $ 4.2 million bill due since 1987. <PERSON> Reginaldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Panting </PERSON>, secretary of <ORGANIZATION> Economy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, told a news conference on Friday that `` our position is not to pressure the Panamanian government nor the chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>, Gen. <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. `` We are only trying to get pending bills paid ... and <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> has a bill with <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> it has to pay,'' Panting said. <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> provides <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> with about 10 percent of its electrical service. <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> has the largest electrical processing plant in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and also sells electricity to neighboring <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. Panting said he traveled to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> two months ago `` to remind the government of its debt with <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. `` At the time, we warned that we could suspend the energy at the end of the month if <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> does n't immediately proceed to pay the debt, but it has n't done it.'' He said <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> had discussed the possibility of repaying the debt with sugar exports to <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> but has not done so. `` Faced with what has happened, we are left with one other option: cut the electricity we send to <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>,'' Panting said. He said he will travel to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> again next week in a last attempt to resolve the problem. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is considered <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s de facto leader. He was indicted by two <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> grand juries in 1988 on drug trafficking charges, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has placed economic sanctions on the nation in effort to force him to step down.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0554EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-China-USRallies     06-10 0556</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-US Rallies,0575</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thousands Rally in U.S. To Support Chinese Student Movement</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos BX1, NY6</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-China, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Americans and Chinese across the country rallied, rang bells and held candlelight vigils to keep the flame of pro-democracy sentiment burning despite the brutal crackdown in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. `` We do n't want people to think that because it is quiet over there, all is over,'' <PERSON> J.D </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kuo </PERSON>, a Chinese-American research scientist with <PERSON> G.D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Searle </PERSON>, told about 1,500 people at a downtown <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> rally Friday. `` By adding our voices, the students in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> will know people are behind them.'' Church bells rang throughout <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> after a moment of silence, and in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Chinatown </LOCATION>, more than 5,000 people attended a memorial service followed by a mock funeral procession for the victims of the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> massacre. Marchers carried a figure inspired by the <ORGANIZATION> Statue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberty </ORGANIZATION>, similar to one displayed by the student protesters in <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> until it was destroyed last weekend. `` This has united the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> people for one cause _ to overthrow the government and establish democracy,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, one of the student organizers of the memorial service. `` We must never allow them to crush another body.'' Later, more than 15,000 people packed Dag Hammarskjold Plaza across from the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, many wearing white headbands bearing the word `` freedom.'' Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> drew cheers when he said, `` All these students wanted was a chance to speak with their own government about democracy.'' <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> also promised to rename the corner outside the Chinese Consulate as Tiananmen Square. Under a cold drizzle late Friday, about 100 Chinese students gathered by candlelight on the steps of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>'s City Hall to lay a wreath in honor of their fallen comrades back home. `` I wish there was more we could do, but at this moment we just do n't know what to do,'' said <PERSON> Yong </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, a 28-year-old graduate student at the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION>. `` We're all very deeply, deeply sad and shocked.'' Earlier, a rally by <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> students in <LOCATION> Northampton </LOCATION> was joined by <PERSON> Kui </PERSON> <PERSON> Xu </PERSON>, a graduate student and granddaughter of former <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Hu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yaobang </PERSON>, whose death on April 15 ignited the pro-democracy movement. Students facing final examinations took time out on other campuses to remember their slain peers in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, Hispanic students helped Asian-Americans organize an afternoon march, and friends circulated petitions on behalf of <PERSON> Tong </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonning </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, graduate mathematics exchange student who is missing after returning home with donations for pro-democracy protestors. Chinese students at <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> held a memorial service, and at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION>, students opened a multimedia exhibit tracking the pro-democracy movement in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. At the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, about 150 Chinese and American students sang <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>'s `` Imagine'' and other peace anthems at a mournful noon gathering. Sorrow abounded over the Chinese repression of the pro-democracy movement. `` We thought maybe the government was going to change,'' said S.Y. <PERSON> Cheng </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, professor originally from <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. `` Sometimes I think all of us are too naive.'' `` They should n't give up. They should continue. They do n't fear dying,'' <PERSON> Zhewu </PERSON> <PERSON> Wang </PERSON>, 31, a visiting scholar at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> from the northeast <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> city of <LOCATION> Harbin </LOCATION>, said in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0557EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Pope 2ndLd-Writethru   06-10 0691</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pope, 2nd Ld-Writethru,a0411,0709</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sparse Crowds, Frank Words Mark Scandinavian Tour</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS one graf for graf 5, `For a ...' to UPDATE with final Mass
today in Vadstena. Picks up graf 6 pvs, `I saw ...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VICTOR L. SIMPSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> made concessions in his tour of <LOCATION> Scandinavia </LOCATION>, but the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> pilgrim in the lands of Luther failed to excite a public already indifferent to its own church. From the fjords of <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>, to barren windswept <LOCATION> Iceland </LOCATION> to the high-tech affluence of <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>'s tour was unlike any of his previous trips to Christian countries, even those like <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> where <PERSON> Roman </PERSON> <PERSON> Catholics </PERSON> are a minority. Faced with some reluctance to the visit by <PERSON> Lutheran </PERSON> clergy, the leader of the world's 850 million Roman Catholics agreed to sit in silence in a Lutheran cathedral in <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>, referred to himself often as the `` bishop of <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>'' rather than as <PERSON> pope </PERSON> and listened to chiding by Lutheran bishops. Even to his own flock, in a region with marked differences on sexual morality with <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>'s teaching, he used more cautious language than usual when dealing with family issues. For a man used to drawing vast numbers of people, the crowds were tiny. In his final Mass today of the 10-day tour, in the Swedish city of <LOCATION> Vadstena </LOCATION>, about 2,500 youths attended. Roman Catholics represent less than 1 percent of the population of the five countries he visited. `` I saw the pope in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> -LRB- in 1987 -RRB-. I was very surprised there were so few people here,'' said <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Clemmons </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, as the <PERSON> pope </PERSON> stopped in <LOCATION> Trondheim </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>. She plans to marry a Norwegian. There were no protests, although a fundamentalist <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> demonstrator rushed toward <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> during an outdoor Mass Friday. Security stopped the man, who was unarmed, 30 feet from the pope. Police said he wanted to hand the pontiff a leaflet. The trip is scheduled to end today. <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> officials assured that <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> was highly pleased with his trip and said it helped move along Catholic-Lutheran relations. `` I do n't go to attract the masses, but to preach the gospel,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> said midway through the trip. `` I go to bring the gospel everywhere there are Catholics. But I also go to those who are not Catholics, especially here where there are Christians.'' The pope appeared to go out of his way to avoid offending. In a region where birth control is encouraged and abortion rates are high, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> used such codewords as `` respect for the gift of life in all its forms,'' rather than resort to explicit language. His frequent reference to himself as `` bishop of <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>'' was a sign of `` sensitivity for the people present,'' explained Australian Archbishop <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Cassidy </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> undersecretary of state. Other terms, such as supreme pontiff, would be `` quite alien,'' <PERSON> Cassidy </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iceland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> are overwhelmingly Lutheran although surveys have shown less than 10 percent regularly attend church on Sundays. One of the principal purposes of the trip was to further relations with the <ORGANIZATION> Lutheran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, dominant since the <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reformation </ORGANIZATION> swept away Catholicism four centuries ago. Some Lutheran bishops opposed the visit, and in <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> they insisted that <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> not participate in a prayer service in a Lutheran cathedral. The pope attended, sitting near the altar and following the service in a prayerbook without speaking. Afterward, in an exchange of speeches, <PERSON> Lutheran </PERSON> <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> <PERSON> Ole </PERSON> <PERSON> Bertelsen </PERSON> made no secret of differences between Catholics and Lutherans and told the pope `` nice words and smiling friendly church leader attitudes are not really what we need right now.'' <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> officials, however, viewed the ecumenical meetings as a success and emphasized it is better to air differing points of view than to pretend all are in agreement. `` After four hundred years of separation, time is needed for the process of reconciliation and healing to take place,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> said Friday in an ecumenical prayer service in <LOCATION> Uppsala </LOCATION>. `` Not everything can be done at once, but we must do what we can today with hope for what may be possible tomorrow.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0605EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WeatherpageWeather     06-10 0502</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Weatherpage Weather,0519</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eastern Seaboard Soaked By Lingering Storms; Winds Buffet Parts of
Florida</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Lingering storms drenched much of the eastern seaboard this morning and strong winds buffeted areas in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> after a fatal tornado whipped through <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. Thunderstorm winds gusted to 53 mph at Desert Rock, Nev. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arthur </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> Roswell </LOCATION>, was struck by golfball-size hail. Fierce thunderstorm winds caused damage at <LOCATION> Buckhead </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, about 50 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>. Elsewhere, the thunderstorms spawned locally heavy rains. Flood watches were posted early today in southeast <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, southern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and northern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. Flood watches also were posted in western <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>. Showers and occasional thunderstorms lingered through <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and northern <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> early this morning. Showers and thunderstorms also were scattered in south-central <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, northern <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> across eastern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, western <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, south-central <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> and from western <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> across eastern <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. On Friday night, a tornado packing heavy rains and winds up to 120 mph struck <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, leaving one person dead and one injured, after damaging homes and cars and ripping up trees. Heavier rainfall during the 6 hours ending at 2 a.m. EDT included 2 inches at <LOCATION> Islip </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, almost 2 inches at <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, and nearly 1 -LCB- inches at <LOCATION> Chicopee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. Clear skies and light winds sent temperatures dipping over the upper <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and frost advisories were posted today in northwest <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> and eastern <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. Today's forecast called for rain in much of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and western <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>; and showers and thunderstorms from <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> across <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, western <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, western <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> and north-central <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Predicted highs: 50s and 60s in much of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>; 60s from upper <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> across <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, and along <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s southern coast; 90s in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, the central Gulf of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> coast, much of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, southern <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and southern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, and the inland part of central and southern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>; 90s to near 105 degrees across the desert <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION>; and 70s and 80s in the rest of the nation. Temperatures around the nation at 3 a.m. EDT ranged from 38 degrees at <LOCATION> Hibbing </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, to 85 at <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>. Other reports: _ East: <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> 66 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> 54 rain; <ORGANIZATION> Buffalo </ORGANIZATION> 61 foggy; <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> 75 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION> 60 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> 61 foggy; <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> 57 cloudy; <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> 81 partly cloudy; <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> 71 foggy; <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> 61 fair; <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Maine </ORGANIZATION> 51 rain; <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> 70 fair _ Central: <PERSON> Bismarck </PERSON> 51 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> 59 cloudy; <PERSON> Dallas-Fort </PERSON> <PERSON> Worth </PERSON> 71 partly cloudy; <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION> 55 partly cloudy; <PERSON> Des </PERSON> <PERSON> Moines </PERSON> 52 partly cloudy; <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> 54 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> 62 partly cloudy; Minneapolis-St. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> 53 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Nashville </ORGANIZATION> 67 fair; <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION> 74 foggy; <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Louis </ORGANIZATION> 60 _ West: <ORGANIZATION> Albuquerque </ORGANIZATION> 64 windy; <ORGANIZATION> Anchorage </ORGANIZATION> 50 partly cloudy; <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> 83 partly cloudy; <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> 61 cloudy; <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> 85 fair; <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> 60 cloudy; <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diego </ORGANIZATION> 61 cloudy; <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> 54 partly cloudy; <ORGANIZATION> Seattle </ORGANIZATION> 53 fair _ <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>: <ORGANIZATION> Montreal </ORGANIZATION> 57 rain; <ORGANIZATION> Toronto </ORGANIZATION> 59 fair
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0630EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     06-10 0361</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0375</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HOLLAND, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The yellow brick road leads to <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION> this weekend, as four of the original munchkins join fans of `` The Wizard of Oz.'' Many believe the author who inspired the film classic, <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Baum </PERSON>, patterned part of <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON>'s travels to Oz after local sites and people because he had a summer cottage in this town. `` It really reminds me of the set,'' said <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Pellegrini </PERSON>, 65, who played one of the `` Sleepyheads'' who welcomed <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> to Oz. <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> apparently was modeled after a neighbor, <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Martindale </PERSON>, who wore her hair in pigtails and had a small dog, said festival organizer J.L. <PERSON> Landry </PERSON>. The Emerald Castle is said to be drawn from nearby Castle Park and a circle of houses called <ORGANIZATION> Perry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circle </ORGANIZATION> was the model for <LOCATION> Munchkinland </LOCATION>, she said. This year _ the 50th anniversary of the MGM classic _ will be especially busy, said <PERSON> Meinhardt </PERSON> <PERSON> Raabe </PERSON>, who played the coroner who pronounced the Wicked Witch of the East dead after she was crushed by <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON>'s house. Former munchkins <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Duccini </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Aubin </PERSON> also appear at the festival, which runs through Sunday in this southwestern community near <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FABIUS, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's no bull that state Sen. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Larraine </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffmann </PERSON> owns a stud that was named after the state's governor. Actually, <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> is a bull _ all 800 pounds of him. <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>'s odyssey began at the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fair </ORGANIZATION> two years ago, when 4H ` er <ORGANIZATION> Trista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parish </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, won the showmanship ribbon in the junior division for her cow, Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> presented her with the blue ribbon and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> was so moved she decided to name <PERSON> Phoebe </PERSON>'s first son after the state's favorite son Two months ago, <PERSON> Hoffmann </PERSON> was shopping for a breeding bull and bought <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>, unaware of the stud's name. `` As soon as we heard, we said, ` Oh, no,''' said <PERSON> Hoffmann </PERSON>, a Democrat. She thought the name would be disrespectful of the governor, also a Democrat. In the end, she decided to steer away from calling the animal after the governor and changed the bovine's name to <PERSON> Bubba </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0631EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Quotes     06-10 0123</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Quotes,0127</SECOND>
<HEAD>Current Quotations</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 `` The idea of not losing another Jewish soul is all-pervasive.'' _ <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Tishman </PERSON>, president of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jewish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeal-Federation </ORGANIZATION> of Jewish Philanthropies, referring to a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> campaign to raise money for emigrating Soviet Jews.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 `` I do n't go to attract the masses, but to preach the gospel.'' _ Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, after failing to draw large crowds on his tour of <LOCATION> Scandinavia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 `` The reason politicians are afraid of talk radio is we have the ability to allow private citizens to talk to their government.'' _ <PERSON> Mills </PERSON> <PERSON> Crenshaw </PERSON> of WTKK-AM in <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, speaking at a radio talk show host conference in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, which is looking for ways to win respect.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0652EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RockyFlats     06-10 0699</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rocky Flats,0720</SECOND>
<HEAD>FBI Affidavit Alleges Illegal Waste Burning at Nuclear Plant</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SANDY SHORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Workers at the Rocky Flats nuclear weapons plant dumped toxic chemicals into creeks that lead to water supplies for four <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> suburbs and illegally burned hazardous wastes at the site, according to an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> affidavit. Both the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION>, which owns the plant, and <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which operates it, covered up the contamination by stating that the plant was in compliance with environmental laws and regulations, the affidavit alleged. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Magistrate <PERSON> Hilbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Schauer </PERSON> unsealed the affidavit Friday after a newspaper challenged withholding of the information that led <PERSON> Schauer </PERSON> to issue a search warrant for a raid on the plant Tuesday by federal agents. The plant, which processes plutonium for nuclear weapons, is 16 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. The 116-page affidavit indicates the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> investigation into possible criminal violations of hazardous waste laws will focus on activities going back to November 1980. The affidavit also questions the <ORGANIZATION> DOE </ORGANIZATION>'s decision to award an $ 8.6 million bonus to <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> for excellent management of Rocky Flats. The Rocky Mountain News reported in Friday's editions that the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> also has launched an investigation of performance bonuses awarded Rocky Flats' managers. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> probe was the third blow sustained by the facility this week. On Tuesday, 75 <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> agents raided Rocky Flats in a move dubbed `` Operation Desert Glow,'' as part of the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> inquiry. On Wednesday, the <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> announced it had found 25 environmental violations at the plant. `` We need to check out every allegation that is in this document,'' Gov. <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Romer </PERSON> said of the affidavit. `` If it -LRB- the plant -RRB- ca n't meet criteria for health and safety, we close it down.'' The affidavit revealed that <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> aerial infrared surveillance of the plant in December found that an incinerator in a plutonium reprocessing building that was closed for safety violations was being illegally operated. The DOE closed the building in October after an outside warning sign was accidently covered up, and three DOE inspectors walked in without protective garb. The building reopened in January. The affidavit also alleged that since 1986, Rocky Flats has generated `` at least 35 to 40 hazardous or mixed wastes sent for final disposal to various on-site facilities'' that do not have permits or interim status under the 1976 Resource Conservation and Recovery Act. `` The knowing treatment, storage and disposal of hazardous or mixed wastes without a permit ... is an <ORGANIZATION> RCRA </ORGANIZATION> felony,'' the affidavit said. The illegal discharge of pollutants into <LOCATION> Walnut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> occurred Nov. 15 and 16, the affidavit alleged, adding that the discharges and subsequent efforts to conceal them violated the Clean Water Act. <LOCATION> Walnut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> drains into the reservoir for <PERSON> Broomfield </PERSON>, a city of 27,600 residents 10 miles north of <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> also detected liquid discharges into <LOCATION> Woman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION>, which flows into the lake supplying water to the cities of <LOCATION> Westminster </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Northglenn </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Thornton </PERSON>, just north of <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, which have a combined population of about 157,000. Testing of the creeks `` strongly suggests that the contamination is medical waste originating from a research laboratory or a pharmacy'' at Rocky Flats, the affidavit said. The affidavit went on to say that there was probable cause to believe <PERSON> Rockwell </PERSON> and DOE officials in November 1985 falsely certified that Rocky Flats was in compliance with all applicable groundwater monitoring requirements under the <ORGANIZATION> RCRA </ORGANIZATION>. `` In fact, various <PERSON> Rockwell </PERSON> and DOE officials were aware of serious contamination and were informed that the monitoring system was deficient and did not comply with the <ORGANIZATION> RCRA </ORGANIZATION>,'' the affidavit said. <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Sankey </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> DOE </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said agency officials had not had time to study the affidavit and had no comment. She also said she was unaware of the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> investigation. In a news release, the department said a special DOE investigation team has been at <ORGANIZATION> Rocky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Flats </ORGANIZATION> since June 6, but has not found `` any condition or situation which presents an imminent danger to the public's health or safety.'' <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurtt </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, declined to comment Friday. He said <PERSON> Rockwell </PERSON> attorneys were reviewing the affidavit.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0817EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-AmericanPOWs     06-10 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-American POWs,0663</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. to Interview Japanese Monk About American POWs in Vietnam</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARI YAMAGUCHI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An American military attache will interview a <LOCATION> Japanese </LOCATION> monk who has reportedly said he saw American prisoners in the re-education camp where he was held in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said today. The monk's daughter quoted her father as saying he shared a cell with three American prisoners for the last six years he spent in captivity. She said her father did not remember their names but described them as young and healthy. The monk, <PERSON> Iwanobu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yoshida </PERSON>, 65, reportedly suffers from mental disorders and a speech impediment. He has been hospitalized since January when he returned to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> after being released from 14 years of imprisonment in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. In the past week he has given his first interviews to the Japanese media, raising interest with claims he saw Americans held since the Vietnam War. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> denies holding American prisoners, and recently it has cooperated with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials searching for remains of Americans missing in action. <PERSON> Yoshida </PERSON>'s daughter, <PERSON> Keiko </PERSON> <PERSON> Takatsuka </PERSON>, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> today that her father communicated with the Americans in his cell through gestures. `` My father told me that when he asked them if they were Americans, they nodded,'' Ms. <PERSON> Takatsuka </PERSON> said during a telephone interview from her home in <LOCATION> Sapporo </LOCATION> on Hokkaido, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s northernmost island. She said the prisoners were not allowed to speak to each other. Her report differed from one earlier in the week on the <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in which <PERSON> Yoshida </PERSON> was quoted as saying he saw `` five or six'' American POWs but never spoke with them and had been held apart from them. The location of the re-education camp has not been disclosed. Ms. <PERSON> Takatsuka </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> the <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> reporter must have misunderstood because her father told her several times he had been held with the Americans. A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military attache will travel to <LOCATION> Sapporo </LOCATION> on Sunday to interview <PERSON> Yoshida </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said, speaking anonymously. He said Ms. <PERSON> Takatsuka </PERSON> met with a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> attache at the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> recently to report on her father's remarks and that the information was forwarded to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for analysis. Ms. <PERSON> Takatsuka </PERSON> initially refused to speak with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, saying her father was too ill, according to the embassy spokesman. <PERSON> Yoshida </PERSON> suffers from mental disorders and a speech impediment, said <PERSON> Hidenori </PERSON> <PERSON> Hareyama </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Shiraishi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tokushukai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> on Hokkaido where <PERSON> Yoshida </PERSON> is being treated. Only <PERSON> Yoshida </PERSON>'s daughter can understand what he says and his speech is at times incoherent, <PERSON> Hareyama </PERSON> said. He refused to elaborate. <PERSON> Yoshida </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monk, told the <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> that Vietnamese political prisoners also called the foreigners in the camp Americans. Ms. <PERSON> Takatsuka </PERSON> said her father does not remember the names of the three held in his cell but said they were still `` young and healthy.'' <PERSON> Yoshida </PERSON> told her he saw more American POWs, perhaps more than 10, before he suffered a stroke three years ago. `` My father is still afraid somebody will come and get him to throw him back in the Vietnamese prison,'' she said. <PERSON> Yoshida </PERSON>, formerly a city councilman in <LOCATION> Mibari </LOCATION> on Hokkaido, became a monk in 1966 and emigrated to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, where he set up a temple in <LOCATION> Saigon </LOCATION>, now called <LOCATION> Ho </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Minh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. He was granted South Vietnamese citizenship in 1973, then was arrested in 1975 after the takeover of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> by communist forces. On Jan. 20, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> released <PERSON> Yoshida </PERSON> for humanitarian reasons after appeals by international human rights groups including <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>. A total of 1,730 Americans are listed as missing in action in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, and 634 are missing in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, according to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> figures. The <LOCATION> Indochina </LOCATION> war ended in 1975 with communist victories over U.S.-supported governments in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0832EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Lebanon 1stLd-Writethru a0415 06-10 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0415,0702</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Dead as Syrians Shell Christian Coastline</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Inserts 5 grafs after 11th pvs, ``Details were...'' to UPDATE
with envoys arriving in Baghdad, add comment. Pickup 12th pvs, ``The plan...''
TRIMS.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MOHAMMED SALAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Syrian gunners shelled the coast north of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> today, killing four people and wounding six, as an <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> envoy tried to halt 12 weeks of bloodshed between Syrian and Christian forces. A police spokesman said about 200 shells and rockets fired from Syrian batteries in Moslem west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> exploded around the Christian ports of <LOCATION> Jounieh </LOCATION> and Byblos early in the day. He said the fatalities were `` civilians killed near <LOCATION> Jounieh </LOCATION> when a 107mm <LOCATION> Katyusha </LOCATION> rocket hit a residential district near the harbor.'' The latest casualties brought the overall toll to 367 people killed and 1,427 wounded since the current round of violence broke out March 8 between <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> army units and an alliance of Syrian-Druse forces. The escalation coincided with the arrival in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> of <LOCATION> Lakhdar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ibrahimi </LOCATION>, assistant <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> secretary general, in a renewed effort to stabilize a cease-fire. <LOCATION> Ibrahimi </LOCATION>, an Algerian, crossed <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s dividing Green Line for talks with <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> at the general's bunker office under the bomb-ravaged presidential palace of <LOCATION> Baabda </LOCATION>, east of the capital. Ibrahimi drove to Moslem west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Syrian </LOCATION> capital, Friday and held separate meetings with <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoss </PERSON>, who heads the <ORGANIZATION> Moslem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> in the nation's dual government, and <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> <PERSON> Husseini </PERSON>. The Arab envoy was dispatched to <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> by the leaders of <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> to seek compliance with a cease-fire called May 26. The committee of three Arab League heads of state was formed to find a solution to the 14-year civil war within six months. The three leaders also sent their foreign ministers on a tour of <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and the five permanent member states of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> to promote a proposed settlement for the <LOCATION> Lebanese </LOCATION> crisis. The ministers _ Prince <PERSON> Saud </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Faisal </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Abdel </PERSON> <PERSON> Latif </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Filali </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Bouallam </PERSON> <PERSON> Bsayeh </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> _ held a second, six-hour meeting Friday with Syrian President <PERSON> Hafez </PERSON> <PERSON> Assad </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>. Details of the discussions were not officially disclosed. The three foreign ministers today arrived in <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION>, where they were greeted by foreign minister <PERSON> Tariq </PERSON> <PERSON> Aziz </PERSON>. <PERSON> Al-Filali </PERSON> told reporters: `` We are sure we will find complete cooperation from <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> officials in trying to find a solution to the Lebanese crisis.'' Before leaving <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, the Algerian foreign minister said, `` We tried in <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION> to define the major subjects that could be achieved in the forseeable future.'' He said that `` the solution is, in the end, in the hands of the Lebanese, and we were able to see <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>' willingness to help <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>.'' The independent <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> daily paper An-Nahar said the three were soliciting support for a seven-point settlement proposal. The plan, according to the paper, calls for `` exerting international pressure on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to withdraw its forces from south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>.'' It also proposes the `` deployment of an Algerian force'' along a 75-mile stretch of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> coast to prevent the import and export of illegal material at the various ports. The coastal strip referred to in the plan extends from just above the southern provincial capital of <LOCATION> Sidon </LOCATION>, through <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, to the northern city of <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION>. The scenario also calls for `` lifting all sea, land and air blockades, reopening blocked roads between the sectors, including the Beirut-Damascus highway'' that runs across sections of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> controlled by warring <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> and Druse militias, the paper said. It said <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> military observers would be deployed at the crossings and along the Beirut-Damascus highway. The plan also calls for `` convening a session of the Lebanese parliament to consider a draft for political reforms and the election by parliament of a president who would pledge to implement the reforms.'' The last point in the plan calls for `` discussing the question of Syrian withdrawal from <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>.'' <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> controls a 6-to-10-mile deep strip of Lebanese territory along their border. It serves as a buffer against cross-border guerrilla attacks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0856EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Britain-Jaruzelski 1stLd-Writethru a0422 06-10 0575</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Jaruzelski, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0422,0595</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poland's Communist Leader Visits Britain</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 12 grafs to UPDATE with protest. Pickup 7th graf
pvs, ``Jarulzelski said...''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MAUREEN JOHNSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Polish leader <PERSON> Wojciech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> says the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s resounding defeat in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s freest postwar elections may have been only a passing phenomenon. At the <ORGANIZATION> Polish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> today, a small group of Polish emigres protested Gen. <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON>'s visit, with one banner declaring: `` From <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> to Peking, communism brings death.'' <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> arrived in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> today after a one-day visit to <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>, and he met for 25 minutes with Foreign Secretary Sir <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> at <LOCATION> Heathrow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> said the election results were `` a reflection not only of the attitudes but also of the emotions of the Polish people.'' `` But as you know, emotions are sometimes ephemeral,'' he said in an interview in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> with the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. He spoke in Polish, and his remarks were translated. Following a stop to lay a wreath at Polish war graves in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> today, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader was to meet with Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> for lunch at her country estate, <LOCATION> Chequers </LOCATION>. He plans to return to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> on Sunday. Members of Solidarity with Solidarity, a British-based group, organized their weekend vigil outside the embassy near a separate weeklong vigil outside the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. `` We are not saying that what happened in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> was as bad as the Chinese massacres,'' said protest organizer <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudewicz </PERSON>, referring to the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> army's attacks on pro-democracy protesters a week ago. `` But in 1981, it was Gen. <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> who brought out the tanks onto the streets of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, when several hundred people were killed during martial law.'' Solidarity was crushed at that time and later banned. It was legalized under an April pact with the government. In a statement released Friday, Solidarity with Solidarity described <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> as `` a man decisively rejected by his nation'' in Sunday's elections. In the Polish voting for the new 100-seat <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, Solidarity won 92 seats and the other eight were undecided. Independent candidates were allowed to run for only 161 seats in the existing 460-seat Sejm, or lower house, but they won 160 of them. Only two of 35 top <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leaders and their allies running on a special list of unopposed candidates gained a majority of `` yes'' votes, allowing them to take seats without a new election. <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> said in a British newspaper interview this week that he would stand by the results and suggested that his <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> could lose power in totally free elections in 1993. In the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> interview, <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> said the elections were not a `` football match ... it is a political process.'' He referred ruefully to his imposition of martial law in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> in 1981 and his banning of the free trade union Solidarity. `` Sometimes it takes a long time before the revolution becomes civilized,'' said <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON>. `` We could not avoid it either.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> invited <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> after she visited <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> last November and met with both government and Solidarity leaders. British officials said the prime minister was interested in talking with <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> about the elections and his plans for the future. <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON>'s visit is part of widening contacts between <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and Western government leaders, who have welcomed the Polish reforms. French President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> will visit <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> next week and President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is due to go there July 9-11.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0913EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Korea-Protests 1stLd-Writethru a0426 06-10 0454</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Korea-Protests, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0426,0466</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Battle Students, Arrest 1,000</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: New thruout to UPDATE with 1,000 arrests, new clashes. No pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KELLY TUNNEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of radical students today battled police with firebombs, rocks and clubs after protesters demanded the <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> government let them take part in a youth festival in communist <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. Police reported more than 1,000 arrests. About 2,000 students fought riot police at two campuses in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> after they were blocked from marching into the streets to denounce President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-woo </PERSON>'s government and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Thirty student leaders were seized trying to reach the North Korean border for talks with communist officials, police said. About 1,500 students fought police with iron pipes, clubs and rocks at <ORGANIZATION> Yonsei </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and about 500 students threw firebombs and rocks at police at nearby <ORGANIZATION> Sogang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. Police hurled rocks back at students but did not use tear gas. `` Crush the <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> Tae-woo regime!'' and `` Yankee go home!'' students yelled. Hundreds of students later battled police in central <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, hurling rocks and bricks. Riot squads used tear gas to break up the protesters and chased the students through the streets. Shoppers and pedestrians fled for cover. Troops and students were injured in the fighting, but the police had no figures on casualties. More than 1,000 students were arrested in the clashes or as they tried to reach the universities to take part in a second day of protests, police said. Police officials, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said 20,000 riot police were deployed in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> to block the university demonstrations. About 6,000 troopers in green combat fatigues and visored helmets ringed <ORGANIZATION> Yonsei </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Sogang </ORGANIZATION>, outnumbering the demonstrators. The protests came after students staged rallies at the two colleges to demand to take part in the 13th World Youth Festival next month in the North Korean capital of <LOCATION> Pyongyang </LOCATION>. Radical students are calling for unification with the communist North. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> has invited South Korean students to attend the youth festival, an athletic and cultural festival attended mainly by non-aligned and communist nations. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> has accused the North of attempting to incite domestic unrest to weaken the <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> government. Student leaders charge that <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> keep the <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> peninsula divided. They have called for the overthrow of <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> and expulsion of the 43,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops based in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. The two Koreas are bitter rivals. They have clashed frequently over the years. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> invaded the south in 1950 to start the Korean War. Radical students and dissidents have been calling for the fall of the <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> government, but they lack support because of their extreme views and violent tactics.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0923EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Pakistan     06-10 0271</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pakistan,0281</SECOND>
<HEAD>Six Sentenced to Death by Stoning for Adultery</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KHAIRPUR, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A lower court today convicted six people of adultery and sentenced them to death by stoning under an Islamic law. Judge <PERSON> Mirza </PERSON> <PERSON> Saeed </PERSON> <PERSON> Beg </PERSON> invoked the controversial `` Hadood Ordinance'' enacted in 1979 by former President <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> <PERSON> ul-Haq </PERSON>. It was the first such ruling since Prime Minister <PERSON> Benazir </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> came to power in December. The U.S.-eductated Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> has pledged to press for repeal of the Islamic law, which imposes harsh punishment for moral offenses and limits women's rights. Beg's court convicted <PERSON> Ghulam </PERSON> <PERSON> Qadir </PERSON> <PERSON> Sher </PERSON> and <PERSON> Noor </PERSON> <PERSON> Khatoon </PERSON> of marrying illegally because Ms. <PERSON> Khatoon </PERSON> failed to secure a proper divorce from her previous husband, <PERSON> Shaikh </PERSON> <PERSON> Anver </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Sher </PERSON>. The court found four of <PERSON> Qadir </PERSON> <PERSON> Sher </PERSON>'s friends guilty as accomplices for helping arrange his marriage with Ms. <PERSON> Khatoon </PERSON>. No date was set for the executions. Members of the <PERSON> Khatoon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Qadir </PERSON> <PERSON> Sher </PERSON> families said they would appeal to a <LOCATION> Sindh </LOCATION> province high court. Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>'s left-leaning <ORGANIZATION> Pakistan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> has called for the repeal of all discriminatory Islamic laws promulgated under <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>'s 11-year rule. As chief of the army, Gen. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> toppled Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>'s father, Prime Minister <PERSON> Zulfikar </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>, in a 1977 military coup and had him executed two years later. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> died in a plane crash in August. An inquiry found the plane was downed by saboteurs but was unable to identify them. Repeal of the laws passed under <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> would require majorities in both houses of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>'s sizeable right-wing opposition has said it will block any government move against the Islamic ordinances.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890610-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-10-89 0952EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SevereStorm 1stLd-Writethru a0421 06-10 0382</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Severe Storm, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0421,0388</SECOND>
<HEAD>Severe Storm Spawns Philadelphia Tornado; 1 Dead</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 5th graf, `The body...', to UPDATE with identity of victim,
CORRECT her age to 13 sted 15.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
