<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-IdahoFires 1stLd-Writethru a0763 07-29 0390</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Idaho Fires, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0763,0393</SECOND>
<HEAD>National Guard Joins Fight Against Forest Fires</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS lead to CORRECT that governor authorized use of, sted sent
in, military reinforcements; SUBS 2nd graf to CORRECT that 3,000, sted
15,000, people are involved in fighting 15,000 acres of fires.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOISE, Idaho (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Cecil </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrus </PERSON> declared a state of extreme emergency Friday, putting military reinforcements on call to help the battle against hundreds of forest fires burning out of control. The emergency proclamation, which allows the state to use the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, will last for 30 days or until the fire danger subsides. The <ORGANIZATION> Boise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interagency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> estimated about 3,000 people were working as firefighters or support personnel to battle 15,000 acres of <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> fires. The weather cooperated in northern <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> with high humidity that slowed the flames, while the opposite was true for the <ORGANIZATION> Boise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>. `` The humidity dropped considerably,'' said <PERSON> Lynette </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Boise </LOCATION> forest spokeswoman. `` When the air dried out, the fires got up and ran.'' A lightning storm earlier this week covered central <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> with 500 fires, some limited to just a burning tree. Firefighters concentrated on the larger blazes, while parachuting smokejumpers or helicopter-borne crews tackled the small ones. The containment of small fires and shuffling of crews Friday left it difficult to assess total acreage burned or manpower on the fire lines. The top-priority fire in the state was the 1,500-acre <LOCATION> Fleming </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> blaze near Banks, north of <LOCATION> Boise </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Pam </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON>, fire information officer for the <PERSON> Payette </PERSON> forest north of <LOCATION> Boise </LOCATION>. It burned on state and <LOCATION> Boise </LOCATION> forest land. The second fire of concern was the 600-acre Dollar Creek fire near the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fork </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> the </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salmon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> east of <ORGANIZATION> Cascade </ORGANIZATION> because of the chance its destruction of ground cover could lead to erosion into the river. Fire bosses in the <ORGANIZATION> Boise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> focused on the 6,500-acre <LOCATION> Deer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> blaze near <LOCATION> Mann </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> north of <LOCATION> Weiser </LOCATION>, which had tripled in size since Thursday and was burning in critical sharptail grouse habitat. In the <ORGANIZATION> Payette </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, about 500 firefighters from all over the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> had contained 70 of 130 fires and the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> erected a temporary tower at the McCall airport to monitor the scores of retardant bombers and smoke jumper planes in the region.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0213EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SwappAppeal     07-29 0343</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Swapp Appeal,0354</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Approves Polygamist Leader's Appeal Despite Missed Deadline</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PEG McENTEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SALT LAKE CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge ruled Friday that polygamist clan leader <PERSON> Addam </PERSON> <PERSON> Swapp </PERSON> can appeal his conviction for the bombing of a Mormon chapel, despite his attorney's failure to meet a filing deadline. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON> gave defense attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bucher </PERSON> an extension for `` excusable neglect'' in filing the appeal in the <ORGANIZATION> 10th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> a few days late last summer. Meanwhile, federal prosectors said they will appeal <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>' sentencing of Swapp and two of his three co-defendants in the Jan. 16, 1988, bombing and a subsequent standoff with authorities that ended in a fatal shootout The violence at the clan's compound ended a standoff with state and federal officials. Corrections Lt. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> House </PERSON> was killed and <PERSON> Swapp </PERSON> was wounded in the exchange. The impasse had begun 13 days earlier, when <PERSON> Swapp </PERSON> bombed a Mormon chapel near the farm. <PERSON> Bucher </PERSON> filed the appeal after <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON> sentenced the four last July, but the <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> appellate court returned the matter to <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON> so he could make a ruling on the late filing. <PERSON> Swapp </PERSON>, his brother <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON>, his mother-in-law <PERSON> Vickie </PERSON> <PERSON> Singer </PERSON> and her son, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Singer </PERSON>, were convicted of 20 counts of bombing, attempted murder and use of firearms. <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>, defying federal mandatory sentencing guidelines governing bombings and firearms which are much stiffer, originally sentenced <PERSON> Swapp </PERSON> to 15 years in prison, Mrs. Singer to five years, and <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Swapp </PERSON> and Singer to 10 years each. Prosecutors, however, appealed the sentences and the 10th Circuit returned the case to <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>, who added token additions to the terms of the Swapp brothers and Mrs. Singer. He added no time to Singer's term. Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lambert </PERSON> said the new appeal would ask for five-year `` firearm enhancement'' terms for Singer and the Swapps, but no additional time for Mrs. Singer, 47, who has dropped her own appeal. The Swapp brothers and Singer also were convicted of state homicide charges in <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s death.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TotTVDinners 1stLd-Writethru a0564 07-29 0573</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tot TV Dinners, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0564,0583</SECOND>
<HEAD>Enterprising Mothers Create TV Dinners For Tots</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: SUBS grafs 11-12, bgn `When she...,' to CORRECT `Margo' to
`Margaux,' restore dropped words. ^By CARRIE FIGDOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's nearly dinner time, the baby is crying and <PERSON> Mister </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> comes on in five minutes. What's a parent to do? Two <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> entrepreneurs hope the answer is the tot-sized TV dinner. Pop it in the microwave and presto: cod with creamed peas and squash. `` Babies love it and so do grown-ups. It tastes like real food,'' said <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Dootson </PERSON> <PERSON> Pigott </PERSON>, vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> Starting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Right </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and the mother of a 7-year-old. She and company President <PERSON> Cameon </PERSON> <PERSON> Ivarsson </PERSON> said the idea behind the frozen dinners is to start toddlers at 4 months with a balanced and nutritional diet, without exhausting their mothers in the process. The frozen minimeals are being produced and packaged in a <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> specialty-food factory while the entrepreneurs await specially adapted machinery. The meals, being test-marketed in Seattle-area groceries, contain items from the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> ranging from cod to vegetables. The only additive is a little water for consistency, Ms. <PERSON> Pigott </PERSON> said. The company is starting with four menus in three textures, from smooth to chunky with offerings such as semolina pasta and brown rice, Ms. <PERSON> Pigott </PERSON> said. There is also a vegetarian menu. Each bowl has a cartoon beneath the food to help encourage kids to finish the food so they can see the picture. In each tub, the foods are separate to allow mothers to introduce each item separately to the child. `` It's exactly as if a mom made her own baby food. ... We're not doing weird things, we're doing plain, simple things,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Ivarsson </PERSON>, a Swiss-trained neurophysiologist. In <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>, she fed two boys, now 5 and 8, her homemade baby food. She spent every other weekend cooking and freezing 40 mini-TV dinners. When she moved to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and gave birth to <PERSON> Margaux </PERSON>, now 15 months old, Ms. <PERSON> Ivarsson </PERSON> `` decided to do what every American mother does'' and bought a jar of commercial baby food. The strained carrots, she said, were flavorless. <PERSON> Margaux </PERSON> was n't enthusiastic about the food either, she said So, Ms. <PERSON> Ivarsson </PERSON> formed Starting Right with Ms. <PERSON> Pigott </PERSON>, who has a degree in finance and once owned and operated a restaurant. Doctor friends gave advice about nutrition, and Ms. <PERSON> Ivarsson </PERSON>'s husband, who runs a restaurant helped with business tips If the frozen dinners catch on, the company plans to incorporate regional foods, depending on where the meals are distributed, so babies start out eating foods they'll be served as they grow up. Suggested retail prices range from about $ 1.35 to $ 1.49. Ms. <PERSON> Pigot </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Ivarsson </PERSON> said they're trying to help women who get involved in the business. The board members are women and the majority of the company stockholders are women. `` I do n't know if you'd call it feminist, but our philosophy was that if we have the opportunity to help women, good,'' Ms. <PERSON> Pigott </PERSON> said. The company faces tough competition from other baby food manufacturers, particularly the Fremont, Mich.-based <ORGANIZATION> Gerber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Product </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which controls 70 percent of the baby food market, said <PERSON> Gerber </PERSON> spokeswoman <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Ivens </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gerber </PERSON>'s baby foods have no additives except water for making puree, Ms. <PERSON> Ivens </PERSON> said. Only the desserts have sugar added and some of the fruits have added vitamin C, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0314EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     07-29 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0026</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 03; 08; 19; 22; 28; 38.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     07-29 0082</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0086</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 03; 08; 19; 22; 28; 38.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 6-1-1-9.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 03; 04; 06; 16; 30; 33.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 11; 12; 15; 24; 33; 36. Bonus: 1-6-9-9-2.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto Game: 32; 35; 40; 44; 52; 53. Supplementary 27.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 9-8-7-4.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 0-2-7; 1-0-9-4; 5-3-5-0-6; 4-7-1-8-9-4.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0208EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ChurchKilling     07-29 0232</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Church Killing,0237</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Convicted in Killing of Church Volunteer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROLLA, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man was found guilty of first-degree murder Friday in the killing of a church volunteer, more than two years after he was captured in the longest manhunt in <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> history. The jury deliberated for 2 -LCB- hours before returning the verdict against <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, 35, in <ORGANIZATION> Phelps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. The penalty phase of the two-week trial is scheduled to begin at 9:30 a.m. Saturday, and the state is asking for the death penalty. The jury can recommend either death or life imprisonment. <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Finnical </PERSON>, an assistant attorney general and the lead prosecutor in the case, said testimony from ballistics experts showed the gun <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> had when he was arrested in <LOCATION> Ada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>, was the one that killed caretaker <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON> in a Doolittle church on April 1, 1987. `` Circumstantial evidence conclusively _ conclusively _ proves <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> murdered this man,'' <PERSON> Finnical </PERSON> told the jury. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON>, had questioned the validity of the ballistics results. `` What you have here is the state grasping at straws. They have to put someone in the church,'' <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> said. At the time Long was killed, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> was the subject of a massive manhunt after a man matching his description fled from a <LOCATION> Rolla </LOCATION> motel room a few days earlier. A police officer was wounded in that incident.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0743EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--BugFire     07-29 0122</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Bug Fire,0124</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boy Trying to Kill Bugs Sets Home Afire</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOULDER, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A teen-ager accidentally set fire to his family's home while trying to kill bugs on a porch, officials said. The fire started when the 14-year-old boy lit insect repellent after spraying it on the bugs, said <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff's Capt. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Epp </PERSON>. The flames ignited bushes, then shot up and covered the front porch and its roof and burned into the wall of a second-floor bedroom. Thursday's fire caused about $ 40,000 damage to the <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> McGehan </PERSON> home, said <PERSON> Epp </PERSON>. No one was injured. A cat, two dogs, a parakeet and a guinea pig were saved from the smoke-filled house, officials said. The boy was not identified.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0323EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MorganBicentennial     07-29 0351</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Morgan Bicentennial,0359</SECOND>
<HEAD>Show Celebrates 200th Anniversary of Morgan Horses</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TRUDY TYNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NORTHAMPTON, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 1,100 descendants of a little bay horse foaled 200 years ago trotted, danced or even popped out of a cake in honor of their breed. <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> breeder <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Sumner </PERSON>, manager of the 50th annual <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morgan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Horse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Show </ORGANIZATION>, said the six-day spectacle was a sort of homecoming for the first uniquely American breed of horse. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Morgans </ORGANIZATION> appeal is as universal as his versatility,'' said <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Frizzel </PERSON> of <PERSON> Davison </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, awarding a citation and bottle of champagne to a group of enthusiasts in straw hats and jeans who hitched a trio of high-stepping <ORGANIZATION> Morgans </ORGANIZATION> to a hay wagon and joined the fancy carriage parade through downtown Thursday evening. First prize went to <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> millionaire <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> E.I </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Dupont </ORGANIZATION> and his wife in an ornate antique hunting carriage, drawn by four coal black Morgans. As they rolled smoothly down Main Street one of the three grooms in top hat and tails sounded a cheery flourish on an long, brass hunting horn. Morgans, who are equally at home in hunt clubs, isolated cattle ranches or helping the police maintain order on city streets, reflect the all-around characteristics that endeared them to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> farmers. They wanted and got a horse strong enough to pull a plow, small enough to require little maintenance, and fast enough to ride. A bronze plaque on a granite boulder along a street in suburban <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION> a few miles down the <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> marks the beginning of what the inscription simply calls `` that useful breed'' in 1789. The small, dark horse, with black mane, tail and feet, who bestowed his characteristics on more than 100,000 descendants, originally was named Figure by <PERSON> Justin </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, the schoolteacher and singing master who raised and raced him in western <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>. His lineage is unclear, but some <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> historians believe he may have been sired by a Tory colonel's part-Arabian, part-English thoroughbred stallion `` liberated'' during the Revolutionary War by farmers in retaliation for raids on their livestock.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0243EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Guild-Post     07-29 0220</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Guild-Post,220</SECOND>
<HEAD>Washington Post, Union Reach Agreement</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> have reached a tentative five-year contract, three years after the last agreement expired, the newspaper reported Saturday. The contract covers 1,420 newsroom employees and white-collar workers. Management declared negotiations at an impasse two years ago. Members of the <ORGANIZATION> Washington-Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> will vote on the agreement Monday. The union bargaining committee has recommended ratification. The <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said the contract would increase weekly salaries between 4 percent and 6 percent, with lower-paid workers receiving a higher percentage increase along with an improvement in minimum-salary scales. Employees who make more than $ 50,000 a year, which includes most of the paper's news and editorial workers, will have increases of about $ 42.50 per week during the first three years of the contract, with similar increases expected in the final two years, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said. The agreement also calls for improvements in pension and disability-insurance plans and better medical and dental coverage. It provides several provisions for resolving worker-management disputes and a no-strike, no-lockout clause. The worker-management clause is believed to be the first such clause in the 51 years the Guild has bargained on behalf of <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> employees. The contract covers newsroom, accounting, advertising, circulation and data-processing employees, as well as some workers in other business departments.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0244EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush Bjt   07-29 0617</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush, Bjt,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Firm on Defense; Willing to Compromise on Capital Gains</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, facing battles with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on several fronts, says he's standing firm on his military spending plan but is willing to compromise on his proposal to cut the capital gains tax. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> insisted Friday that he will be able to have his way with the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on his defense package even after the House this week shredded it, slashing key components such as Star Wars, the stealth bomber, mobile MX missile and Midgetman missile. `` I am disappointed that the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> did what they did,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told a news conference, noting that the chamber restored money for some programs he wants to cut. `` Yesterday was not the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s most memorable moment, but we're going to keep fighting on for what we believe in. But <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he's willing to look at alternatives on his proposal to cut the 33 percent maximum capital-gains rate to 15 percent. `` If there's some compromise that can spur investment, spur jobs, increase employment _ the cause of new jobs starting up _ I'd be interested in it,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said `` I do n't think I should ever say it's got to be done just this way in terms of the bills up there in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> right now.'' On another topic, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> decried news leaks in the espionage investigation of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomat <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>. `` I do n't want to go into it while it is under investigation,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said when asked about specifics. `` I am very concerned about premature discussion and disclosure _ that means leaks _ on this matter, because I think you can jeopardize the case itself and perhaps the man's ability to get a fair hearing.'' No charges have been filed against <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>, but the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> revoked his diplomatic passport and put him on paid leave June 22. He is under heavy <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> surveillance. Regarding the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s slash of $ 1.8 billion from his $ 4.9 billion military spending request, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> reaffirmed his commitment to his `` solid strategic program.'' He said he will fight to win <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> support to counter the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> measure, and that he needs everything he's proposing to strengthen his arms control position in talks with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also said: _ He's confident his multibillion-dollar bailout plan for the savings and loan industry will prevail, despite a <ORGANIZATION> House-Senate </ORGANIZATION> conference agreement this week that rejected a key funding mechanism on which he has insisted _ Attacks on his nominee to head the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s civil rights division, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>, are `` pure gut politics. He said he staunchly supports <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>, who critics say is unqualified. _ He still wants a constitutional amendment to ban burning of the American flag, but did n't answer directly when asked if he would settle for a Democratic-sponsored effort, passed this week by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, to outlaw flag burning through a statute rather than amending the Constitution `` I will see what comes down here, but I will continue to push for the approach that I think is the best, given the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision,'' he said. _ He did not condone the kidnapping of a Shiite Moslem leader by <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> commandos in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and does n't know if it may lead to freedom for an American hostage _ He was frustrated over the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> inability to get Panamanian ruler <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> out of power _ He would not respond to harsh criticisms leveled by outgoing Customs Commissioner <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Raab </PERSON>, who said he saw a lack of commitment or interest in the departments of State and <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> on fighting the drug war <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the real question is, `` How do we do better.?
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0247EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BroadcastDeregulation     07-29 0465</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Broadcast Deregulation,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>FCC `Voodoo Priests' Not Helping Radio</HEAD>
<HEAD>For release 2 p.m. EDT. Time set by source</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAY ARNOLD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Radio is being ill-served by `` voodoo priests'' at the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> who seem to think just about anyone should be able to own a station, a broadcasting lobbyist says. A deregulation-minded <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> has been kind to broadcasters in many ways during the 1980s, but has sometimes gone too far in its rush to impose a free-market ethic, said <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fritts </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasters </ORGANIZATION>. `` If there were a modern-day <PERSON> Rip </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Winkle </PERSON> broadcaster who had gone to sleep in 1980 and reawakened this year, he would scarcely believe the changes,'' <PERSON> Fritts </PERSON> said in remarks prepared for delivery today at the <ORGANIZATION> Idaho </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasters </ORGANIZATION> meeting in <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. `` The entire communications landscape has changed,'' he said. `` Deregulation has come faster and gone farther than our industry ever asked or dreamed of.'' Under <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON> and his predecessor, <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON>, the Fairness Doctrine has been lifted and broadcasters received favorable improvements in the license-renewal process. <PERSON> Fritts </PERSON> said broadcasters were grateful for those victories, but that the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> has caused other headaches. Noting that the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> loosened rules for acquiring radio station licenses, <PERSON> Fritts </PERSON> said it appeared the commission had `` become so obsessed with regulation by marketplace economic theory that it seemingly is interested in providing every man, woman and child with their own radio station.'' `` Ole Rip would be surprised that the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> has no apparent concern for preserving the system of local service by financially healthy stations that has served the American public so well for the past 70 years,'' he said. `` Our awakening broadcaster would think his world was being ruled by voodoo priests. `` As a result of the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>'s Alice-in-Wonderland allocations policies, it is faced with a growing backlog of applications for new facilities and minor station modifications. <PERSON> Fritts </PERSON> said an <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> official acknowledged recently that a new ruling allowing increased power for small FM stations may increase the application backlog from six months to 18 months. And it was particularly galling to broadcasters, he said, that even as the backlog grows, a deficit-conscious <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> wants to increase application fees by 13 percent. <PERSON> Fritts </PERSON> lashed out at <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> proposals to hold lotteries, auctions and private negotiations to allocate and assign station licenses. `` How can the commission say with a straight face that is can choose broadcast applicants who will best serve the public interest by reading ping-pong balls or conducting lotteries?'' The <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Fritts </PERSON> said, `` has allowed so many new stations on the AM band that it has created destructive interference and undermined the financial health of many stations to the determinant of local service.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0249EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HUDProbe     07-29 0482</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-HUD Probe,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congressman Accuses Ex-HUD Official of `Cashing In'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KIM I. MILLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> official says he made recommendations that `` ultimately benefited'' people with whom he now works, and a congressman is calling for a <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> investigation. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Monticciolo </PERSON>, former <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> regional administrator for the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, was grilled Friday by members of a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee investigating allegations of wrongdoing at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>. He denied any wrongdoing during his seven-year <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> tenure, but was harshly questioned by Rep. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Shays </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Conn </LOCATION>., about a 1984 memo in which <PERSON> Monticciolo </PERSON> had made recommendations about a company he later joined `` I made recommendations to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> that ultimately benefited people who are now partners of mine,'' <PERSON> Monticciolo </PERSON> said, adding that the final decision came from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` I'm going to have people look at what you've done because there was a quid pro quo,'' <PERSON> Shays </PERSON> said. `` I'm hopeful and I would expect that the attorney general's office will look into what you've done because you've cashed in.'' Monticciolo is chief executive of <ORGANIZATION> Eagle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, a real estate development company with contracts in <LOCATION> Rockland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. Some of the partners were involved in a controversial 1983 deal in which they bought seven <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> properties in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> valued at $ 10.5 million price but put up only $ 550,000. The developers later sold the property, making a reported $ 17 million profit. <PERSON> Monticciolo </PERSON> said he had made recommendations to <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> that benefited the developers, who later hired him for a $ 125,000-a-year job and made him a 15 percent partner for no up-front cash. At one point, <PERSON> Monticciolo </PERSON> told the panel that <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s Section 8 moderate rehabilitation program was `` 50 percent political,'' with half the money going to developers who were <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> contributors or well-connected to the administration. <PERSON> Monticciolo </PERSON> also said he had never recommended a project for that program, which has been suspended. But when <PERSON> Shays </PERSON> confronted him with a <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> memo about several such projects in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Monticciolo </PERSON>'s region _ the former administrator admitted having discussed the projects with the public housing authorities. `` We ca n't rely on a thing you said,'' Rep. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., said `` You say one thing when you do n't have the document and when the document is in front of you, you say something diametrically opposed.'' <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, former executive assistant to then <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, was to have been the first witness Friday but he failed to show up. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> had asked for a postponement in his voluntary appearance because his lawyer was in the hospital. It was the third time <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> had asked for an extension. Subcommittee Chairman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, D-Calif., said the panel would vote Wednesday on issuing a subpoena for <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> to appear Sept. 27 and to produce `` all relevant documents and records.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0249EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DroughtDisaster     07-29 0549</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought Disaster,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dole Offers Compromise All-Crops Disaster Relief Proposal</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY MASSEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After a week of partisan bickering, farm-state senators are inching toward compromise on legislation to provide federal payments to producers suffering crop losses from drought and other weather-related damage. Senate Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> dropped his opposition Friday to an across-the-board disaster relief package and offered a proposal that a Democratic leader said could clear the way for a bipartisan agreement. `` Sen. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s flexibility will lead to an agreement on a final package that treats all farmers fairly,'' Sen. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said in a statement `` We are moving toward common ground that fairly covers all demonstrated crop losses within reasonable spending levels.'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> had been leading opposition to a Democratic-sponsored measure providing $ 955 million to cover weather-related crop losses. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s proposal, estimated to cost $ 891 million, would provide more assistance to farmers of the major grains who bought federal crop insurance and less to the hundreds of other commodities _ the so-called non-program crops _ because they are not covered by federal subsidy and price support programs. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration has said about $ 870 million in agricultural budget savings could be used for farm disaster relief. So far, the dispute in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has been over what crops should qualify for federal payments. But pressure is building on lawmakers to take action. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is scheduled to recess Aug. 5 for a month-long vacation, and most farm-state members do n't want to return home without having sent an aid bill to the White House. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> has complained that the Democratic measure, approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on a party-line vote earlier in the week, was potentially too expensive because it covered more than 500 crops. But he moved closer to the Democratic package Friday with his compromise proposal. Faring best under <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s proposal would be producers of wheat, cotton, rice, corn and other crops participating in federal commodity programs and those who bought federal crop insurance. They would be eligible for assistance on losses above 35 percent, with payments covering 65 percent of their lost income. Farmers without crop insurance, but enrolled in the federal farm programs, would have to suffer losses of at least 40 percent, under <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s plan. Peanuts, tobacco and sugar beet growers would be covered by the same provision. Soybean and sunflower farmers would be eligible for assistance if they suffered losses above 45 percent. Most crops not covered by government commodity programs, everything from peaches and cherries to dry edible beans and potatoes, must suffer losses exceeding 50 percent and would then receive payments covering 50 percent of the producer's lost income. The same 50-50 formula would apply to farmers who are not enrolled in federal commodity programs but grow wheat, corn, grain sorghum and other so-called program crops. Under the Democratic package, farmers with crops enrolled in government commodity programs would qualify for assistance if they suffered 40 percent losses. Farmers of other crops would have to show a 45 percent loss. The measure provided 65 percent payments for both. A $ 1 billion disaster relief bill passed by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> last month would require a minimum loss of 35 percent for any crop to receive assistance.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0330EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Soviet     07-29 0284</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Soviet,280</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Marshal Says USSR Can Keep Pace With Stealth</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A top military adviser to Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> says the B-2 stealth bomber wo n't give the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> an edge over the Soviets. `` For every action in life there is a reaction,'' Soviet Marshal <PERSON> Sergei </PERSON> <PERSON> Akhromeyev </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> on Friday. `` So if the creation, development and deployment of the B-2 is an action, in one way or another there will be some sort of reaction from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.'' The House this week voted to suspend production of the B-2 until the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> scales back the high-priced program, and said the administration must show the stealth can successfully evade radar detection and penetrate Soviet airspace before production resumes. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his defense officials have lobbied hard for the bomber as a highly advanced piece of technology that would outstrip Soviet radar capabilities. <PERSON> Akhromeyev </PERSON>'s speech and question-and-answer session was the first by a senior <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> official at the <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> since Premier <PERSON> Nikita </PERSON> <PERSON> Krushchev </PERSON> in 1959. <PERSON> Akhromeyev </PERSON> told an audience that included Adm. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Crowe </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION>, that the trip in which he gave historic testimony to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had encouraged him that Soviet relations with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will continue to improve. Still, he said that while the decrease in tension between <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact countries was `` a tremendous accomplishment ... the military threat, unfortunately, is still there.'' <PERSON> Akhromeyev </PERSON>, wearing his <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> uniform with 11 rows of ribbons, went from the <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> to a private White House meeting with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> and Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0310EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BatBan     07-29 0286</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bat Ban,0289</SECOND>
<HEAD>Holy Censorship! Film Board Bans Children Under 12 From Seeing Batman</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Batman'' is winging its way to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, but youngsters under 12 will have to stick to comic books to catch the Caped Crusader. The national film board says the popular movie is unsuitable for little kids. The British <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Classification </ORGANIZATION> applied its new `` 12'' category to the movie that opens Aug. 11 in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, with <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Keaton </PERSON> playing the title role and <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicholson </PERSON> starring as his evil nemesis, the Joker. The category bars youngsters under 12 from a film no matter what parents decide. In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the comparable PG-13 is only an advisory guideline for parents, while the R rating restricts minors from seeing a particular movie. A spokesman for filmmaker <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> said the British decision was `` quite in keeping with the nature of the film. It is for the producers to decide what kind of film they wish to make and what they have come up with is not like the old comic strip television series from the'60s. This <PERSON> Batman </PERSON> comes out at night.'' A film board spokesman, speaking on condition of anonymity in keeping with British practice, said the new designation was created because the old `` 15'' classification wound up keeping children between the ages of 12 and 14 out of movies that may be suitable for them. Early Times, a children's newspaper, said: `` We are concerned that many children under 12, in the light of the hype and publicity over <PERSON> Batman </PERSON>, will be bitterly disappointed over the rating of this film as 12 Certificate particularly as the impression has been created that it is a summer family film.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0311EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Turtles-Shrimpers     07-29 0347</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Turtles-Shrimpers,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Says Wildlife Case Strong, Orders Administration to Explain</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration has four days to explain why it suspended rules designed to protect endangered species of sea turtles after protests by shrimp fishermen in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Court Judge <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> on Friday refused to grant an order sought by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> to require the government immediately to enforce the suspended regulations for Gulf Coast shrimp fishermen. But <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> called the federation's case `` a strong one'' and said the government has until Tuesday to detail under what legal authority Secretary of Commerce <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> suspended the regulations. <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> scheduled another hearing for Thursday. <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> lawyer <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuruc </PERSON> said at a hearing that the basis for <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON>'s action was that public safety was endangered by the protests. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Irvin </PERSON>, a wildlife federation lawyer, said he was disappointed that the judge had denied the order, but was encouraged by his comments that the wildlife group had a strong case. The rules suspended Monday would have required the use of devices that keep sea turtles from becoming entangled in trawlers' nets Instead, <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> said shrimpers in 45 days would have to obey still another set of rules requiring them to lift their nets every 90 minutes or sooner so turtles can escape. Turtles can live that long if trapped, according to members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> supporting the shrimpers. Before the court hearing, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> and the Defenders of Wildlife called for a nationwide boycott of shrimp to protest the fishermen's tactics. The suit, filed Tuesday, said <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> was inflicting irreparable harm on five species of sea turtles that are listed as threatened or endangered. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fisheries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> estimates that 11,000 turtles die each year in shrimpers' nets. Last weekend, angry shrimpers used their boats to block ship channels along the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> coasts. Gunfire was reported in both states and four shrimpers were arrested in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Two recreational boaters were hospitalized briefly for minor injuries after trying to run the blockade Saturday in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0331EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-POWFamilies     07-29 0209</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-POW Families,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Says POW-MIA Issue Still `Highest Priority'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says the government will do whatever it can to find out if American servicemen are still being held in <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. `` We will do everything that a government can to recover the missing, and if we discover proof of captivity, we will take action to bring our men home,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Friday in a speech to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Families </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prisoners </ORGANIZATION> and Missing in <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. The league says 2,348 Americans remain missing or unaccounted for as a result of the conflict in <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. Most _ 1,714 _ are in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. The rest are in <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> called on <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> to `` shed light'' on the fate of the missing, and said the pace of restoring diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> could be impeded unless that country cooperates on the POW-MIA issue. Some of those attending the meeting sai they were discouraged. `` I do n't believe this is a top priority,'' said <PERSON> Lorene </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, 61, of <LOCATION> Rapid </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, whose son, <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON>, has been missing for 17 years. `` I think perhaps we are making progress, but, my God, after 20 years we ought to make a little,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0250EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AirlineSmoking Bjt   07-29 0476</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Airline Smoking, Bjt,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Airline Smoking Ban Permanent Under Committee-Passed Bill</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A ban on smoking aboard airline flights of two hours or less would become permanent under a bill sent to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor, but anti-smoking forces say they expect tougher restrictions in the final bill. Tobacco industry lobbyists ended up pushing for the permanent ban Friday after a 25-25 vote on a ban that would have covered all domestic flights indicated growing congressional support for proposals to broaden the airline smoking ban. The tie vote defeated the wider ban, but it was the closest a congressional vote has come to outlawing all smoking on airliners. The bill, passed on a voice vote by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Works </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, is one of several proposals to extend or expand the 1987 temporary smoking ban on flights of two hours or less. That ban expires in April. Opponents made tongue-in-cheek suggestions that liquor, cheap cologne and crying babies could also be banned because they offend some people. Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Clinger </PERSON>, R-Pa., who supported the permanent ban but opposed all proposals that would affect flights over two hours, joked that the committee might vote to `` install cheap cologne detectors and put crying babies in the hold. Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Oberstar </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Minn </LOCATION>., who pushed for a total smoking ban, said the committee's defeat of attempts to apply the ban to longer flights reflects strong lobbying by the tobacco industry <PERSON> Oberstar </PERSON> said a more far-reaching ban would likely pass the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> but he declined to predict what the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> might do. One of the measures to extend the smoking ban is in the form of an amendment to an appropriations bill. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> is expected to take that up next week. <PERSON> Oberstar </PERSON> described Friday's vote as a `` short-term gain'' for the tobacco industry, which at first opposed making the two-hour ban permanent. However, several tobacco lobbyists switched strategies as the committee was voting. In the end, pro-smoking forces supported a permanent ban while anti-smoking committee members voted for a four-year extension of the temporary ban in the hope of ensuring that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> again would have to consider a total ban. Anti-smoking groups have said they will continue to fight against smoking on any airliner. `` The two-hour ban is far from a perfect piece of legislation and very far from the solution needed to protect all airline passengers and all flight crews from the serious hazards created by tobacco smoke in the airline cabin,'' said <PERSON> Ahron </PERSON> <PERSON> Leichtman </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Against </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tobacco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Smoke </ORGANIZATION>. Rep. <PERSON> Gus </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>, D-Ill., who said his wife of 34 years died from cancer, called in-flight smoking a life-and-death issue `` On an airplane, you ca n't open the window when someone else smokes. In midair, you ca n't transfer planes,'' <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> said. `` Rights are for now, but death is forever.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel-Kidnapping Bjt   07-29 0672</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Kidnapping, Bjt,0694</SECOND>
<HEAD>Abduction of Shiite Leader Could Lead to Release of Hostages, Israel
Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LOUIS MEIXLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The kidnapping of a Shiite Moslem cleric by <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> commandos could put pressure on pro-Iranian terrorists to free some of the foreign hostages held in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, according to <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials. `` Clearly when you capture one of their top leaders it can deter terrorism and you have a certain amount of leverage in your hands,'' Army spokesman Col. <PERSON> Raanan </PERSON> <PERSON> Gissin </PERSON> said of Friday's raid by helicopter-borne commandos. Seized by the commandos were cleric <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Karim </PERSON> <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>, his cousin <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> and a friend, <PERSON> Majid </PERSON> <PERSON> Fahs </PERSON>, a Lebanese police spokesman told reporters. <PERSON> Gissin </PERSON> said <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> and two `` assistants'' were `` safely in Israeli hands and undergoing questioning.'' One person was killed in the assault on an apartment building in the village of <LOCATION> Jibchit </LOCATION>, 20 miles north of the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> border and 35 miles south of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, according to <LOCATION> Lebanese </LOCATION> and Israeli reports. Lebanese police said a neighbor, <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeid </PERSON>, opened the door of his apartment during the raid and was shot to death by the commandos. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio said <PERSON> Zeid </PERSON> was one of <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>'s bodyguards. Even before Friday's abductions, some <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials said the capture of a Lebanese Shiite leader supported by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> could influence the release of three <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> servicemen kidnapped in southern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> in 1986. Lebanese security sources suggested <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> may have been abducted in a plan to exchange him for <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> Lt. Col. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON> or other foreign hostages. The sources also have linked <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> with <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>' abduction. <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Danville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, was kidnapped in southern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> Feb. 17, 1988, while serving with an observer group attached to the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeeping force in southern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. Seventeen foreign hostages are held in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, including nine Americans and three Britons but not counting the Israeli servicemen. It is belived most of the hostages are captives of pro-Iranian terrorist groups affiliated with <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, or Party of God. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has been held the longest. He was kidnapped March 16, 1985, and a Shiite Moslem group, Islamic Holy War, has said it is holding him. <PERSON> Gissin </PERSON> called <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> the `` equivalent of the commander of the -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- terrorist organization in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>, 33, has denied involvment with the fundamenalist Islamic group but <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> have called him a member of <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> deplored the kidnapping, saying it could jeopardize the lives of the foreign hostages and called for his release. <PERSON> Gissin </PERSON> disagreed and said <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> leaders will `` now think twice before harming their hostages.'' `` They value the lives of their leaders far more then they value the lives of their suicide fighters,'' he added. <PERSON> Gissen </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas have attempted at least 20 cross-border raids into <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> this year. An <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman told reporters, `` <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> said many times in the past that when the fight against terrorism is at stake, it reserves the right to respond whenever it finds it suitable and effective.'' The three Israeli troopers believed held hostage in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> are soldiers <LOCATION> Rahamim </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alsheikh </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Yossi </PERSON> <PERSON> Fink </PERSON>, captured Feb. 17, 1986, when guerrillas ambushed their patrol, and air force navigator <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Arad </PERSON> seized Oct. 16, 1986, when his plane was shot down. Lebanese police, the Israeli news media and witnesses gave these accounts of the Jibchit raid: Three helicopters took part in the operation. About 12 commandos with silencer-equipped pistols surrounded <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>'s building and forced their way into his apartment. Israeli television said the troopers blasted the front door of <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>'s apartment with plastic explosives, seized <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> and the other men and rushed them to a helicopter that departed in the attack that lasted less then 30 minutes. <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Mona </PERSON>, was locked in a room with her hands tied and her mouth taped shut. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> issued a statment saying, `` This shameless act by the Zionist regime will not remain unanswered by the Moslem and combatant forces.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0252EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     07-29 0707</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0739</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LEXINGTON, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Y </PERSON>. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> no longer eats fried chicken, which made him a millionaire. At 55, with his heart mending, he said he intends to eat less, exercise more, condense his business interests and devote more time to his family. Coronary heart disease led him to quadruple bypass surgery this month. `` I feel like I've gotten a second chance. I'm really very happy, very optimistic,'' he said in a recent interview. `` I realized one thing. You ca n't cheat the system.'' For many years, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> worked hard and played hard. He drank, smoked, traveled and gambled. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said he has started walking for exercise and is often accompanied by his wife, <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, the former <LOCATION> Miss </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and TV anchorwoman. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> sold <ORGANIZATION> Kentucky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fried </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicken </ORGANIZATION> in 1971 but still has several restaurant ventures going.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former first lady <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> launched the latest phase of her anti-drug crusade with a visit to a drug rehabilitation center. After meeting with female clients and their children at the <ORGANIZATION> Via </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Avanta </ORGANIZATION> drug center, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said her foundation would distribute grants to similar centers in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area, although Via Avanta wo n't be considered for a grant this year. The grants will begin small and grow according to contributions, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said Thursday. The live-in center is one of a handful in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> that caters to women who have children or are pregnant. `` I've never seen this kind of a program before ... they tell me there are a couple of others,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. `` I think it's very important, especially for young mothers. Meanwhile, former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, accompanied by <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> agents and publisher <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON>, visited the all-male <ORGANIZATION> Bohemian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rosa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has been a member for years at the exclusive club, a 2,700-acre grove near the community of <LOCATION> Monte </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> about 15 miles west of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rosa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> arrived Friday. It was not known how long he planned to stay.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Academy Award-winning actress <PERSON> Audrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> has signed on for a part in the movie `` Always,'' a romance built around blazing forest fires. The <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON> work is being filmed in in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state. Others in the film are <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Dreyfuss </PERSON>, <PERSON> Holly </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. Miss <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> won a best actress <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> in 1953 for `` Roman Holiday.'' `` Always'' is an Amblin Entertainment production for Universal Pictures-United Artists and is to be released in December. Universal announced Miss <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON>'s addition Thursday.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> has become the first Strip headliner to halt his act because of a dispute between hotels and musicians. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said he canceled his act at <ORGANIZATION> Bally </ORGANIZATION>'s Hotel and Casino because of a musicians' strike over use of taped music in lieu of live musicians. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> was to open a weeklong engagement at <ORGANIZATION> Bally </ORGANIZATION>'s on Thursday night. It was the first time a Strip headliner has been affected in the two-month dispute. Several Las Vegas hotels have announced they are dropping live music for some production numbers. <ORGANIZATION> Bally </ORGANIZATION>'s said it would use musicians for headliners, but the musicians joined the picket lines. `` I'm saddened by the musicians' union strike which occurred today at <ORGANIZATION> Bally </ORGANIZATION>'s and by the effect it has had on many people. Any time people are out of work, it is personally upsetting,'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>RED BANK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Rocker </PERSON> <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Bon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jovi </PERSON> is seeing red over a summons he received for what police said was running a stop light. <PERSON> Bon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jovi </PERSON> said he wants his day in court to contest a $ 60 ticket issued March 1. The singer said he went through the light when it was amber. His father, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bongiovi </PERSON>, was following close behind in his own car and also was issued a summons. He pleaded guilty and paid his ticket. <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> lawyer <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> McOmber </PERSON> said Thursday that he submitted affidavits with <PERSON> Bon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jovi </PERSON>'s testimony. He said Municipal Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Himelman </PERSON> could make a decision based on those statements and the testimony of police, but his client wants to appear personally. A court date was set for Aug. 24.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Japan-Stress     07-29 0156</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Japan-Stress,0160</SECOND>
<HEAD>More than 50 Percent Of Japanese Feel Stress</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than half of all Japanese suffer from stress caused by work or relationships, but men are more likely to drink and women more likely to shop to deal with it, a government survey said today. According to the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welfare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>'s national survey, conducted June 1988 among Japanese over 12 years of age, almost 52 percent of 36,146 people said they feel stress in their daily lives. More than 70 percent answered they can handle stress, but 10 percent said they were overwhelmed, the ministry report said. While 49.2 percent of 17,692 men said they feel stress, 54.4 percent of 18,454 women said they do. The survey pointed out men and women try to release stress differently. While drinking, exercise, television and radio were major remedies for men, chatting, idle time and shopping were the top three remedies for women.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0103EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-China-Tiananmen Bjt   07-29 0588</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Tiananmen, Bjt,0603</SECOND>
<HEAD>Daily Flag Raising Now by Invitation Only</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The daily raising of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s scarlet flag in Tiananmen Square used to draw a motley audience of dozens and cause small, brief traffic jams in the bicycle lane adjoining the square. All-night food vendors, street sweepers, pedicab drivers, drifters _ anyone who happened to be up _ would gather at the flagpole to watch three soldiers goose-step out of the imperial palace and march into the square to raise the flag. These days, however, watching the national flag go up requires an invitation or advance permission. The square has been closed to the general public since June 4, when the crackdown on the pro-democracy movement began and soldiers backed by tanks drove student protesters from the square, the symbolic center of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. Bicyclists now are forbidden to stop along its edge. Today, about a dozen foreign journalists and more than 80 children from the <ORGANIZATION> Wangfujing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> had permission to watch the flag raising. The students wore the red kerchiefs of the <ORGANIZATION> Young </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pioneers </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> children's organization, and their teacher said they were there to `` learn to love the country and love the army.'' The children marched silently onto the 100-acre square, led by a half-dozen young soldiers who barked commands at them: `` Forward. Right face. Sit.'' Except for the soldiers and city buses that lumbered by, the still-dark square was silent. At the far end, on the monument to revolutionary heroes that the students had turned into a protest command post, two soldiers stood guard while six comrades napped, wrapped up in bedrolls on the stone pavement. At 5:30 a.m., the square's lights blinked off and the children sat silently on the pavement. At 5:52 a.m., 12 minutes later than scheduled, three soldiers emerged from the palace gate bearing the flag. The ceremony has been modified since June 4 _ two other soldiers stood guard with submachine guns. Upon order, the children raised their right arms in salute as the flag went up. The few without neckerchiefs stood with arms at their sides, apparently not allowed the honor of saluting their flag. A few silent minutes, and it was over. The children sat back down for a brief lecture by a white-gloved soldier on the history of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s flag. `` It is the color of fresh blood,'' he told the students, reminding them of the bloody civil war that preceded the Communist rise to power. A quick march around the square, and the children were off to school. Officers roused the sleeping soldiers with shouts of `` Hey.'' Bedrolls under their arms, they stumbled off the monument. Before June 4, sunrise was the signal for dozens of pedestrians to stream onto the square to take their morning exercise and enjoy the freshest air of the day. Today, more than 50 army trucks, each bearing about 36 soldiers, pulled up in rows on one side of the vast expanse. `` They are here to see the -LRB- Mao Tse-tung -RRB- memorial hall and the Great Hall of the People and <LOCATION> Zhongnanhai </LOCATION>,'' the party headquarters, said an officer, who refused to identify the unit. `` It's a good chance for them to see these things they would not otherwise see.'' The memorial hall, where revolutionary leader <PERSON> Mao </PERSON>'s preserved body is exhibited, has been closed to the public since the building underwent repairs over the winter. When will it and the square reopen? `` I do n't know. I'm sure sooner or later,'' the officer said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0306EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Exxon-Cleanup 1stLd-Writethru a0413 07-29 0593</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Exxon-Cleanup, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0413,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Says He'll Make Sure That Exxon Finishes Cleanup</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Subs 5th graf to add more info about Exxon Valdez spill</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says he'll do his best to make sure that <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> lives up to its responsibility to clean the oil-soaked shores of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. `` If I had the feeling Exxon was going to pull back on an agreement or fail to fulfill an agreement they'd made with us, with the government, or with the state of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, I would ... try my best to do something about it,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said at a news conference Friday. The president's remarks came hours after <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> executives told a congressional panel that the company will suspend cleanup operations for the winter by mid-September. However, company officials said they would agree to any `` reasonable'' continuation of the cleanup next spring. More than 700 miles of shoreline have been damaged as a result of the March spill of nearly 11 million gallons of crude oil from the tanker <PERSON> Exxon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> in the nation's worst oil spill. <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Vice Adm. <PERSON> Clyde </PERSON> <PERSON> Lusk </PERSON> told the interior subcommittee on water, power and offshore energy resources that he expected that there would be `` disagreements on what should be done,'' with differences in opinion as to what constitutes a clean beach. `` What is clean?'' <PERSON> Lusk </PERSON> asked. `` I do n't know how we're going to make that decision.'' <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s plans have been questioned since the disclosure earlier this week of an internal memorandum that said `` no commitment should be made'' on when to suspend or resume cleanup. <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> officials interpreted the July 19 memo as an indication <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> was preparing to pull out, even though the cleanup is far from completed. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, asked by reporters about the matter, said he expected <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> to live up to its commitment. The brouhaha prompted Friday's subcommittee hearing. The memo, written by the manager of <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s cleanup operation in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, `` suggests <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> is putting together its plan for demobilization without <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> approval,'' said subcommittee Chairman <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, D-Calif. W.D <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION>, called the wording of the memo `` unfortunate. The company, he said, will withdraw its equipment and estimated 10,000 workers from the region beginning Sept. 15 because of potential safety problems with rough seas and weather. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> will return `` in the spring of 1990 to reinspect the area, to assure that the job has been properly done, and if not, to put it right,'' <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> said. But when <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> pressed him about whether <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> will resume cleanup in the spring, <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> said he could n't give `` an unequivocal commitment.'' `` I think it would be naive to do that,'' he said. `` We will follow through on any reasonable request that is made'' by the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Lusk </PERSON> said federal and state officials, as well as scientists and <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> representatives, would participate in the inspection next spring. But the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> has no authority to require <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> to do additional cleaning at specific sites, he said. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> executives said Friday that about 600 miles of contaminated shoreline had been treated, but <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s chief environmental official put the figure at about 190 miles saying that in many cases oil has seeped back into the rocks and pebbles. `` We can not imagine how <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> can conclude 600 miles have been treated,'' said <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelso </PERSON>, the commissioner of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> `` If that statement were made in <LOCATION> Kodiak </LOCATION> or Homer the roof would rise. Maybe they're looking at a different gulf.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0310EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-EskimoRights     07-29 0409</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Eskimo Rights,0420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arctic Groups Plan Defense of Traditional Ways of Life</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COPENHAGEN, Denmark (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Eskimos from four nations, guarding a tradition of hunting and fur trading, criticized animal conservationists for threatening the culture of Arctic people. <PERSON> Rosemarie </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuptana </PERSON>, vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> Inuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circumpolar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>, urged delegates to force environmentalists and animal conservationists `` to answer our arguments,'' the <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION> newspaper Information reported Friday. `` Our opponents are much weeker when it is we who set the agenda,'' Ms. <PERSON> Kuptana </PERSON>, a Canadian, told the 500 Inuit delegates at a conference's meeting in <LOCATION> Sisimuit </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION>. It was the first time a Soviet delegation attended a general assembly of the conference, a non-governmental organization for Inuit from <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Anger is growing among Arctic natives toward conservationist groups such as <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION>, whose campaigns the Eskimos say have damaged hunting and the fur trade. `` It never ceases to amaze me how people can react so strongly against traditional hunting on the part of a little group of indigenous people _ people who during thousands of years of hunting never have threatened a single animal species _ while at the same time industrialized society has polluted the planet to such a degree that there is no way back,'' Ms. <PERSON> Kuptana </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Kirsten </PERSON> <PERSON> Sander </PERSON>, who attended the conference as an observer, admitted that the group's campaign against seal skins in recent years had done unintended harm to Inuit hunters. To counter future anti-harvesting campaigns, the conference unveiled a far-reaching Inuit conservation strategy. This policy, largely the initiative of conference members from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION>, embraces all aspects of environmental concern in the Arctic. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jull </PERSON>, a former Inuit adviser to the <LOCATION> Canadian </LOCATION> government, said the document calls for detailed research on the environment and wildlife, including all species that Inuits depend on for food and clothing. He said the plan was partly `` an expression that the environment is our interest and not just for the benefit of companies down south somewhere.'' The conference also compiled a guide of policy principles on issues including nuclear power, education and self-government for use at the regional and local levels. `` What we're basically saying is that we live in the <LOCATION> Arctic </LOCATION> and we know what happens when you mess it up,'' <PERSON> Jull </PERSON> said. About 40,000 Inuit live in <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION>, 28,000 in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and 11,000 in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. The Soviet Inuit comprise a small part of the 150,000 natives of the Siberian north.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0310EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtonInBrief     07-29 0815</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington In Brief,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>EPA Fines Companies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> levied $ 235,500 in fines against four companies for allegedly violating federal laws in connection with the use or manufacture of toxic chemicals. In two of the cases, the fines were reduced because the violations were voluntarily disclosed, the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said Friday. The penalties were: _ $ 112,500 against <ORGANIZATION> 3-V </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, of <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, for illegally importing chemicals not on the federal approved list, improper certification of a chemical, and failure to notify an intention to test a chemical. The fine was reduced by 25 percent because the infraction was voluntarily reported. _ $ 85,000 against <ORGANIZATION> Cavedon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, of <LOCATION> Woonsocket </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>, for failing to notify the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> of its intention to manufacture four chemical substances The company reported the violation and had its fine reduced by 50 percent. _ $ 28,000 against <ORGANIZATION> Surface </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coatings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, of <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, for failing to properly notify the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> of the manufacturer of seven chemical substances. _ $ 10,000 against <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cob </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, for illegally importing a chemical not on the federally approved list.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>FDA Will Study Changes in Food Labels</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> will consider major changes in the way foods are labeled. <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> aid Friday that the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> review will cover nutrition labeling, ingredient labeling, the format of labels as well as manufacturers' descriptions of foods and the health messages they put on their products The Nutrition Labeling and Education Act was introduced Thursday in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> amid criticism from lawmakers that the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> was moving too slowly on the issue. Hearings on the bill are expected to begin next week. The measure would make nutrition labeling mandatory, require disclosure of certain information such as the amount of fiber, fat and cholesterol and provide uniform standards for food descriptions such as `` lite'' and `` cholesterol-free.'' The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> said it will hold three or four public hearings across the country beginning in the fall `` to find out what consumers want and need on food labels.'' The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> is expected to propose new federal rules on food labeling early next year. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> requires certain food labeling, including such information as ingredients and net weight on packaged foods. About 55 percent of packaged foods include information on labels about the nutrition of the foods.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Company Issued License For Double Satellite Launch</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Martin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marietta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commercial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Titan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> will be allowed to launch two satellites in September aboard a single rocket. The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> said Friday that <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Marietta </PERSON> Commercial Titan was granted permission to launch a Titan III rocket from <ORGANIZATION> Cape </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canaveral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Station </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. Aboard the two-stage Titan III will be the <ORGANIZATION> Skynet </ORGANIZATION> 4A military communications satellite owned by the British government, and the <ORGANIZATION> JCSAT </ORGANIZATION> 2 communications satellite owned by <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Satellite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a joint venture of <ORGANIZATION> Hughes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> and two Japanese trading companies. The mission will be the first commercial launch by <ORGANIZATION> Martin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marietta </ORGANIZATION> Commercial Titan.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Bush Will Name Commerce Aide to New Job</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will name <PERSON> Shellyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Gae </PERSON> <PERSON> McCaffrey </PERSON>, an associate deputy secretary of commerce, as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> representative on the governing body of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>. The White House said Friday that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was nominating <PERSON> McCaffrey </PERSON> for the rank of ambassador in her capacity as head of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> delegation to the International Labor Conference. In the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, she worked as deputy executive secretary for the <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> and senior staff member in the Office of Policy Development.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Post, Guild Reach Tentative Agreement</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Members of the <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> will vote Monday on a five-year contract with <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, the newspaper reported today. The contract, which covers 1,420 newsroom employees and white-collar workers, comes three years after the last pact expired. Management declared negotiations at an impasse two years ago. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington-Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> bargaining committee has recommended that its members ratify the contract. The <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said the contract would increase weekly salaries between 4 percent and 6 percent, with lower-paid workers receiving a higher percentage increase along with an improvement in minimum-salary scales. Employees who make more than $ 50,000 a year, which includes most of the paper's news and editorial workers, will have increases of about $ 42.50 per week during the first three years of the contract, with similar increases expected in the final two years, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said. The agreement also calls for improvements in pension and disability-insurance plans and better medical and dental coverage. It contains several provisions for resolving worker-management disputes and a no-strike, no-lockout clause. The worker-management clause is believed to be the first such clause in the 51 years the Guild has bargained on behalf of <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> employees. The contract covers newsroom, accounting, advertising, circulation and data-processing employees, as well as some workers in other business departments.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0305EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MouseShortage Bjt   07-29 0583</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mouse Shortage, Bjt,0600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mouse Lab Risks Future to Resume Mouse Production</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RAEBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Editor</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BAR HARBOR, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The fire-damaged <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> <PERSON> Laboratory </PERSON> is taking on a crash program to replenish the nation's supply of rare research mice and gambling that tax money will keep it in business. The world's leading producer of unusual laboratory mice is using all its resources on mouse production rather than rebuilding, its director said. The fire two months ago at the <ORGANIZATION> Jackson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> crippled much medical research. By not using its insurance money to construct a permanent facility, the laboratory is facing the possibility that it will go out of business in as little as a year. `` Our responsibility was to get research animals out as fast as possible and worry about the financial problems later,'' the laboratory's director, <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Paigen </PERSON>, said Friday. The loss of the laboratory's mouse production facilities `` is currently creating very serious problems for research scientists all over the world,'' said Dr. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyngaarden </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION>, in a recent letter to the <ORGANIZATION> Jackson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION>. The laboratory is the world's leading center for the study of mouse genetics. The fire on May 10 destroyed the laboratory's mouse production facilities and killed 400,000 research mice. The laboratory was supplying 20 percent of the nation's laboratory mice, including many unusual strains unavailable elsewhere The mice `` are essential to research on arthritis, lupus, cancer, heart disease, AIDS, and some 4,000 hereditary diseases,'' said <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wexler </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Hereditary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, in a letter to the laboratory. <PERSON> Paigen </PERSON> said the laboratory's interim production facilities, to be housed in large trailers, could produce 24,000 mice a week by the fall. Before the fire, the laboratory was producing 40,000 mice a week. The <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hughes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, sent the laboratory an unsolicited check for $ 750,000. The <ORGANIZATION> Arthur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> K. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Watson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Charitable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> gave the laboratory $ 400,000. <PERSON> Paigen </PERSON> estimated losses from the fire at $ 40 million and said insurance will reimburse about $ 15 million. The laboratory has asked <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for $ 25 million. A bill is pending in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> that would give that amount to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> to help restore the nation's supply of research mice. <PERSON> Paigen </PERSON> is optimistic that much or all of that money, if approved by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, would be awarded to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> <PERSON> Laboratory </PERSON>. Jackson Laboratory mice have been used for 60 years to demonstrate the effectiveness of bone marrow transplants in treating some kinds of cancer, to understand the genetics of heart disease, the causes of diabetes and the basis of many inherited disorders. The fire is delaying much of that research. For example, the <ORGANIZATION> Mayo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clinic </ORGANIZATION> was set to begin testing a new arthritis drug with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> Laboratory mice this summer. The research has been put on hold until the mice are again available, <PERSON> Paigen </PERSON> said. Mice are useful for research because they can be bred to develop diseases similar to many human diseases. The fire began when a flammable adhesive being used by workmen ignited, <PERSON> Paigen </PERSON> said. `` Everybody who works at the lab mobilized to get as many animals out as they could,'' he said. `` We actually saved a hundred thousand animals.'' No strains of mice were permanently lost. A few animals of each strain, or in some cases frozen embryos, were stored outside the production facility as a safety measure. The problem now is to increase the numbers of those mice.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-RootSued 2ndLd-Writethru a0768 07-29 0517</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Root Sued, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0768,0525</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Orleans Group Claims Root Represented It Improperly Before FCC</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 5th graf, `Root is...', with two grafs to UPDATE with Root
at parent's Ohio home and no comment from his father. Picks up 6th graf,
`Root had...'.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Root </PERSON>, the lawyer who survived a mysterious gunshot and a plane crash near the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>, has been sued by investors who claim he cost them $ 125,000 in a case before the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. The suit was filed Thursday in federal court by a group of investors who tried to get an <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> license in 1987 to build an FM radio station. Root specialized in that type of litigation. But the lawsuit claims he committed legal malpractice by lying about some things, failing to attend to details associated with getting a license, and keeping the investors from getting a cash settlement from another group that ultimately got the license. <ORGANIZATION> Belle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chasse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Limited </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Partnership </ORGANIZATION>, the group represented by Root, and five other groups were trying to get the same license approval for the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> area, according to the suit. Root, of <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, is recovering from the bullet wound and other injuries stemming from the crash of a small plane he was piloting July 13. He is at his parent's home in <LOCATION> Plymouth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, about 50 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>. His father, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Root </PERSON>, contacted by telephone early Saturday about the suit, said, `` I'm not aware of it, and I would n't have any comment.'' The elder <PERSON> Root </PERSON> said his son was not available for comment. Root had set out on a business trip, flying from <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, to <LOCATION> Rocky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, and later told air traffic controllers he was having trouble breathing. He put his plane on autopilot and military planes kept watch on him until his plane ran out of fuel and ditched near the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>. Root says he was unconscious until his plane hit the water, but the military pilots said they saw his head move. He also insists he does not know how he received the gunshot wound to the abdomen, which was found after his rescue. The lawsuit claims that <PERSON> Root </PERSON> told his group's lead investor, <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> <PERSON> Clear </PERSON>, that the other competing groups would be willing to pay <PERSON> Belle </PERSON> <PERSON> Chasse </PERSON> a $ 125,000 settlement for dropping its license application. However, the suit alleges, <PERSON> Root </PERSON> subsequently told attorneys for the other groups that he had been having trouble locating his clients, and that Clear and <PERSON> Belle </PERSON> <PERSON> Chasse </PERSON> had decided to dismiss their application. The <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> filed an order of involuntary dismissal against the application and <PERSON> Root </PERSON> allowed it to go through without telling the <PERSON> Belle </PERSON> <PERSON> Chasse </PERSON> investors what he had done, the suit alleged. Attorney <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Waltzer </PERSON> said the group that eventually won the license paid settlements to all of the other groups except <PERSON> Belle </PERSON> <PERSON> Chasse </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> officials said last week that Root, who was paid about $ 50,000 by the <ORGANIZATION> Belle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chasse </ORGANIZATION> group, had been involved in many cases in which groups received settlements in exchange for dropping their applications.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890729-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-89 0317EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PrairiePagoda Bjt   07-29 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Prairie Pagoda, Bjt,0511</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eight-Story Pagoda Looms Over Prairie</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto BI1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PEG COUGHLIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PETTIBONE, N.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
