<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0031EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SpottedOwlRuling     02-09 0413</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Spotted Owl Ruling,0421</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Temporarily Halts Logging Near Spotted Owl Nests</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SALLY CARPENTER HALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PORTLAND, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge Wednesday temporarily halted logging on five timber tracts that is being contested by conservationists seeking to preserve the northern spotted owl in western <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Frye </PERSON>'s temporary restraining order came in response to a motion filed Tuesday by environmental groups fighting the federal <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION>'s plans to log mature forests near spotted owl nests. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivers </PERSON>, acting <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> state </ORGANIZATION> director, said its district representatives had been told to notify logging companies to cease operations as soon as possible. A sixth tract affected by the judge's order has not yet been awarded. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION>, in reckless disregard for the spotted owl, selected these six timber sales as a target of opportunity to make their point through chainsaw justice,'' said <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Wood </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, one of the plaintiffs. Rivers would not comment on <PERSON> Wood </PERSON>'s remarks. Meanwhile, in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, nine conservation groups sued the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> Wednesday to try to stop logging on publicly owned stands of old-growth timber that are habitat for the northern spotted owl. The environmental groups contend a <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> plan for spotted owls does n't protect the species. The plan, approved in December, said 374,000 acres of mature and old-growth timber in 13 national forests in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> should be designated as owl habitat. That is in addition to the wilderness areas and other tracts protected from logging. The northern spotted owl lives in the remnants of the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION>'s ancient old-growth forests. The Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> is being challenged in court over its 1987 refusal to designate the owl a threatened or endangered species. The 9th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> earlier this month lifted an injunction it earlier imposed on cutting timber near spotted owl nests on <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> land in western <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>. The appeals court sent the case back to <PERSON> Frye </PERSON>'s court. A request to reinstate the injunction is pending before <PERSON> Frye </PERSON>. On Wednesday, <PERSON> Frye </PERSON> set a Feb. 17 hearing on that motion. In response to the appeals court's injunction, the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> cut its projected timber harvest on the former <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Railroad lands it manages in western <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> by about 25 percent. The <ORGANIZATION> BLM </ORGANIZATION> announced the six timber tracts after the injunction was lifted.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-GuardianAngels     02-09 0410</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Guardian Angels,0421</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Subway Vigilantes To Go Ahead With London Chapter</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Guardian Angels say that with the backing of the director of two <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Bronson </PERSON> movies and a <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> businessman they will start training recruits in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> next week _ despite official opposition. <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sliwa </PERSON>, leader of the New York-based group that wants to send civilian patrols into the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> Underground, had threatened to abandon the plan unless the crime-fighting group could find training space. He said police and some government officials had `` dug their heels in'' and refused to allow the <ORGANIZATION> Angels </ORGANIZATION> to train in public places. Police and lawmakers have said law enforcement on the subways should be left to professionals, not civilians. After discussing the Angels' plight on a highly popular <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> television talk show, <PERSON> Sliwa </PERSON> said Wednesday that he had received two offers of help _ from <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Fagan </PERSON>, owner of a chain of public recital halls throughout <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, and from director <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Winner </PERSON>. Winner directed `` Death Wish'' and `` Death Wish II'', both starring <PERSON> Bronson </PERSON> as a tough vigilante who settles the score with cold-blooded criminals. <PERSON> Sliwa </PERSON> said <PERSON> Fagan </PERSON> offered the Angels the use of a hall evenings `` with no strings attached'' for a three-month training course and Winner guaranteed that if there were any problems, he would pay for a training facility. `` It gives us a mandate to continue,'' <PERSON> Sliwa </PERSON> said. The Guardian Angels had also received hundreds of calls from people who offered gardens, rooms, attics and backyards for training, <PERSON> Sliwa </PERSON> said. He said 60 young people, one-third of them women, had applied to become <PERSON> Angels </PERSON> and would on Monday begin a training program in basic self-defense, first aid, performing citizens arrests and `` human relations.'' `` We're going to give it a go for the three months of training, and hopefully by early May be able to produce a Guardian Angel unit of young men and young women from the greater <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> area to go down into the Underground and give you a permanent, regular presence of Guardian Angels,'' he said. Supporters of the Angels say a sharp rise in assaults and robberies in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s subway system indicate the 2.2 million passengers who use it every day ca n't be protected without deploying many more uniformed police. The Guardian Angels, who turn 10 years old on Monday, became famous for patroling <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s subways and have branched out into 60 cities in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Vietnam-Vets     02-09 0229</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Vietnam-Vets,0234</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Veterans Begin Building Medical Clinic for Vietnamese</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group of former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers, hoping to `` deliver an olive branch of peace,'' have begun to build a medical clinic in rural <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, information received today from the veterans said. Although a number of veterans groups have returned to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, the clinic at <LOCATION> Vung </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tau </LOCATION> in southern <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> is the first known development effort by former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> servicemen. A news release from the Veterans-Vietnam Restoration Project said a ground-breaking ceremony for the 10-room facility occurred Saturday with veterans <PERSON> Ruben </PERSON> <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> and Vietnamese medical official Dr. <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> van Rep taking part. Plans call for a dozen veterans, who include carpenters, electricians and architects, to spend about 10 weeks building the clinic with their own hands. The cost of the project is estimated between $ 60,000 and $ 100,000. At the ceremony, the veterans said they had begun `` to deliver an olive branch of peace to the people of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>.'' `` It is hoped the group's efforts may soften the hard edge of American policies towards <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, and eventualy lead to a better understanding and improved relationships,'' the release said. <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON>, a 47-year-old computer software technician from <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, served as a combat infantryman in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 38, of <LOCATION> Monterey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, saw <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> duty with the air force and is currently a building contractor.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Selenium     02-09 0795</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Selenium,0817</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scientists Criticize Newspaper Story</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SACRAMENTO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Several government and university scientists contend a recent series of newspaper stories exaggerated the threat to humans from selenium in food. Executive Editor <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Favre </PERSON> of The Sacramento Bee, which published the series on Dec. 4-5, said the newspaper was `` confident of the accuracy of our reporting and of our analysis.'' The critics are led by <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> Schrauzer </PERSON>, a chemistry professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, who said the Bee stories `` needlessly raised fears concerning the safety of the foods we eat ...'' The stories, summarized in an account distributed to papers nationwide by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, said selenium had been found in food from supermarkets across the nation at levels high enough to slowly poison millions of high-risk Americans such as the very young, the old and the chronically ill. <PERSON> Schrauzer </PERSON> criticized the stories for `` reporting doubtful data on the selenium levels of common foods'' and `` grossly exaggerating the toxicity of selenium ...'' Selenium, a natural element in soil, is essential to life in small concentrations but can be toxic at higher levels `` Reports contending that millions of Americans are at risk of selenium poisoning are unfounded and irresponsible,'' <PERSON> Schrauzer </PERSON> said, `` as are the claims that the foods regularly consumed by Americans contain unsafe levels of the element.'' The Bee reported that illnesses ranging from stomach upsets to death occurred in rural western residents who had been exposed to significant amounts of selenium. The newspaper said that at least one person, an <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> rancher, died of the disease, while others suffered paralysis, loss of hair, skin rashes, hypertension and other maladies attributable to selenium. <PERSON> Favre </PERSON> said the newspaper believes its stories were accurate and hopes `` that the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> and other government agencies will not turn their backs on a potential health hazard'' because of any dispute over the Bee's data. `` The laboratories the Bee used in the testing process are recognized by many states as among the finest labs for this type of test. We are confident that the results they found and which we published are accurate.'' The Bee said it hired private laboratories to study the selenium content in foods in `` dry weight'' form, with all moisture removed. The newspaper then figured average daily intake by translating the dry weights into equivalents of fresh foods as they would be consumed. The scientists criticizing those articles have focused principally on the calculations which the Bee used to translate the dry weights into average meals, rather than on the selenium levels found in tests conducted for the Bee. Bee reporter <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, who wrote the stories, defended the use of dry-weight calculations, saying there has been a `` dramatic evolution'' in the scientific community's opinions on which system to use, and that the once-universal wet-weight method is giving way to the more scientifically accurate dry-weight system. A major problem with wet-weight calculations, <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> said, is that they lead to underestimation of intake. But <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Jukes </PERSON>, a biophysics professor at <ORGANIZATION> UC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Berkeley </ORGANIZATION>, who says he participated in the discovery that selenium was essential to life, said the stories `` need to be scrutinized and revised based on the actual content of selenium in foods, which they miscalculated.'' <PERSON> Anna </PERSON> <PERSON> Fan </PERSON>, chief of the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>' office of food toxicology in <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, also said the Bee's assessment of dietary selenium intake `` is not consistent with scientific literature for the last 10 to 15 years <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON>, supervising chemist of the federal <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> office, said the Bee's conclusions were `` without scientific merit.'' `` There is no evidence to suggest millions of people are getting too much selenium in their diet,'' <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> said. The primary problem with the story, he said, was not the Bee's data, but its `` misleading'' interpretation of that data The story used an example of a person eating 6 ounces of dry eggs in a meal, implying that 6 ounces would be a normal serving, <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> said. But the fresh equivalent of 6 ounces is 11 extra-large eggs, a 10-fold exaggeration of what someone would consume at a typical meal, he said. `` Similar reductions in calculated intakes can be made for other foods from -LRB- the Bee -RRB- article ...,'' <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> said he based the formula for determining how much someone would consume in dry-weight equivalents on information gathered from several credible scientists and nutritionists, and that his data indicates that 6 ounces dry weight would equal 2 -LCB- to 3 extra large fresh eggs. However, nutritionist <PERSON> Joanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Ikeda </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> UC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Berkeley </ORGANIZATION>, who was not consulted by the Bee and is not among critics who have come forward, said that 6 ounces of dry eggs are equivalent to 12 extra-large fresh eggs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Beatles25th 2Takes   02-09 0993</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Beatles 25th, 2 Takes,1015</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Beatles Took America _ 25 Years Ago</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` They were doing things nobody was doing. Their chords were outrageous, just outrageous, and their harmonies made it all valid. ... Everybody else thought they were for the teenyboppers, that they were going to pass right away. But it was obvious to me that they had staying power. I knew they were pointing the direction where music had to go.'' _ <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dylan </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>By DOLORES BARCLAY</NOTE>
<NOTE>AP Arts Editor</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Plaza Hotel was in for a jolt when four mopheads from <ORGANIZATION> Liverpool </ORGANIZATION> settled in a 12th floor suite for a short winter's stay in February 1964. They dove into room service: J & amp; B Scotch with <ORGANIZATION> Coca-Cola </ORGANIZATION>. They binged on `` jam butties'' -LRB- butter and jelly sandwiches -RRB-, corn flakes and ice cream, and left bowls full of stubbed out `` ciggies.'' The first morning, 37 sacks of mail arrived. And girls. Lots of girls. Screaming, screeching, silly schoolchildren who would kill their grandmothers for a glimpse of <PERSON> John </PERSON>, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, <PERSON> George </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ringo </PERSON>. The lasses dressed as chambermaids and tried to sneak into the suite. They posed as record company representatives. Anything. They stormed the hotel's revolving doors only to be dumped unceremoniously on the street with legions of their shrieking sisters. It was the first magical mystery tour for The Beatles. They landed at <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> on Feb. 7 to make their legendary first appearance on `` The Ed Sullivan Show'' on Feb. 9. For 15 days, the country became inflamed with Beatlemania, and it would be years before the fever would die down. They were cocky and sure at their news conferences. At one, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON> was asked how much money he expected to earn during the tour. His response: `` About half a crown. Depends on the tax. How much have you got?'' And to what did they owe their success? `` Good press agent,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> replied. <PERSON> Ringo </PERSON> <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> was asked what he thought of <PERSON> Beethoven </PERSON>. His reply: `` Great. ` Specially his poems. It was a lark. No one at that moment realized the rich gift and legacy to emerge from the four musicians. They went on to sell more than any group in pop history. Indeed, after their appearance on `` The Ed Sullivan Show,'' the Beatles sold 2.5 million records in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in less than a month. <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON> is dead now, shot outside his <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> apartment building on Dec. 8, 1980. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> lives with his second wife, <PERSON> Olivia </PERSON>, and 9-year-old son, <PERSON> Dhani </PERSON>, in a fortress-like Gothic mansion with spires and turrets at <LOCATION> Henley-on-Thames </LOCATION> in western <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. He has lived out of the limelight for nearly 20 years, but reemerged somewhat in 1987 to give his first full concert in 15 years in July at <LOCATION> Wembley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arena </LOCATION> and to record a hit single, `` Got My Mind Set On You,'' which topped the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Cash Box music chart in January 1988. He also has recorded with <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dylan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Orbison </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Petty </PERSON> in a tongue-in-cheek group known as the Traveling Wilburys, and he is co-owner and an executive producer of the independent British film company, <ORGANIZATION> Handmade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Films </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- `` The Missionary,'' `` Life of Brian'' -RRB-. <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> spent five weeks in an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> alcoholism clinic last fall with his wife, actress <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bach </PERSON>. They live in a secluded estate near <LOCATION> Ascot </LOCATION> in southern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. He became the first Beatle grandfather when his 20-year-old son, <PERSON> Zak </PERSON> <PERSON> Starkey </PERSON>, eldest of three children from his first wife, <PERSON> Maureen </PERSON>, became a father on Sept. 7, 1985. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> is working on an album, which includes some songs co-written by <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Costello </PERSON>, to be released later this year. He has too many commitments to consider the 25th anniversary, his spokesman <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Doherty </PERSON> said. `` There have been a number of anniversaries in recent years. There will be lots of anniversaries coming up. He's still very busy making music. <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> said in a live radio phone-in on the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Russian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> last month that the Beatles will never be revived because `` to find a replacement for <PERSON> John </PERSON> is impossible.'' <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> has four children. His family lives on a fortified forest estate in <LOCATION> Sussex </LOCATION> in southeast <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. But in 1964, the Beatles had scarcely begun. Although wildly popular on the continent, the fabulous four and their records did not catch on in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> until Jan. 17 when `` I Want to Hold Your Hand'' hit No. 1 on the Cashbox chart. Within a year, they grossed $ 1.6 million in the first week's showing of their movie, `` A Hard's Day Night,'' and <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>'s kooky book, `` In His Own Write,'' climbed best seller lists overnight In rapid succession, they made six hit albums, including 1967's anthem to the Summer of Love, `` Sgt. <ORGANIZATION> Peppers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lonely </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hearts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION>.'' `` Sgt. Pepper'' sold 2.5 million records in its first three months and stayed on the charts for a staggering 113 weeks. Capitol Records estimates the album's worldwide sales at 15 million since 1967. This alternately melancholy, terrifying and exhilarating record captured as no other the complex textures of its time: a supercharged, corrosively contradictory summer when hippies grooved at the Monterey Pop Festival, black emotions exploded in riots in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION> and a war grew bloodier in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. Youthful listeners somehow heard all of this in `` Sgt. Pepper,'' an album whose themes included Eastern culture, sweet and terrifying psychedelic fantasies, the widening gulf between young and old and, above all, loneliness. `` To me, the Beatles created an excitement about being in the business itself,'' says songwriter and performer <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Cross </PERSON>. `` They stick out to me as the greatest thing in pop music. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> has always been, and remains, my biggest influence of all time because of song structure. He and <PERSON> John </PERSON> taught me how to write songs.'' Cross, who won four Grammy Awards in 1981 for his song and LP, `` Sailing,'' was 12 when he saw the Beatles on `` Ed <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Beatles-1stAdd     02-09 0447</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Beatles - 1st Add,0449</SECOND>
<HEAD>NEW YORK _ ``Ed Sullivan.''</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The CBS press release heralding the Beatles' first appearance in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was, in retrospect low-keyed. It identified them as `` The Beatles of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'' _ a `` wildly popular quartet of English recording stars.'' They were billed on the show with the comedy team of <PERSON> Mitzi </PERSON> <PERSON> McCall </PERSON> and <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brill </PERSON>, impressionist <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorshin </PERSON>, a tumbling act called the four Fays and 37 members of the cast from the Broadway musical, `` <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, more animated than usual, handled the squealing audience as a father would a hyperactive child. He gently shushed them and made the girls promise to stay in their seats. He told the audience <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON> had sent a wire wishing the Beatles `` a tremendous success'' in our country, introduced a commercial for Aero Shave and then swept his arm through the air as the curtain parted. There was <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, 21, wide-eyed and boyish, feverishly working the bass guitar and singing `` All My Loving'' at one microphone. <PERSON> George </PERSON>, 20, was on lead guitar. <PERSON> John </PERSON>, 23, on rhythm guitar, harmonized at another microphone. <PERSON> Ringo </PERSON>, 23, sat high above them on a platform, pounding out beats on the drums. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> soloed on `` Til There Was You'' from the Broadway show, `` The Music Man.'' Later, after a magician did card tricks and <PERSON> Georgia </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> sang songs from `` <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON>,'' the Beatles returned with the <LOCATION> Lennon-McCartney </LOCATION> song, `` She Loves You.'' They were fresh and school boy neat in their Edwardian jackets, shirts and ties. Their hair, considered outrageously long at the time, fell in agreeable bangs across their foreheads and stopped somewhere mid-neck. The Beatle hair style eventually became as conservative as a crewcut. After the <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> show, the Beatles played the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Coliseum in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> On Feb. 12, they played Carnegie Hall, where fans drowned their music in screams. Three years later, the Beatles began to show signs of weariness and drifting apart. Exhausted from years of concert touring, <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON> had each done some independent film work; <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON> met his future wife, <PERSON> Yoko </PERSON> <PERSON> Ono </PERSON>, in a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> art gallery in 1967, around the time they recorded `` Sgt. Pepper.'' <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> went off to <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> to study sitar under <PERSON> Ravi </PERSON> <PERSON> Shankar </PERSON>. Two months after `` Sgt. Pepper'' was released, <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Epstein </PERSON>, the Beatles' manager and stabilizing influence, died. With him went much of the spirit that had held the group together. In 1970, a year after the critically acclaimed `` Abbey Road'' was released, <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> came out with a solo LP and a self-interview critical of the other Beatles. The LP and movie, `` Let It Be,'' came out and by the end of the year, the group dissolved.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--NudeRobber     02-09 0142</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Nude Robber,0142</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Robs Woman And Undresses As People Chase Him</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man robbed a woman of a gold chain, a bangle, a piece of jade and cash but eventually left most of it behind and flung off all his clothes while people chased him, it was reported today. Mrs. <PERSON> Chong </PERSON> <PERSON> Yuk </PERSON> <PERSON> Yin </PERSON>, 54, was starting her car Monday night near a supermarket in <LOCATION> Kota </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kinabalu </LOCATION>, 900 miles east of the <LOCATION> Malaysian </LOCATION> capital, when the man robbed her of the valuables and $ 73, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bernama </ORGANIZATION> quoted local Police Superintendent <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Rauf </PERSON> as saying. <PERSON> Chong </PERSON> screamed for help and the man fled, pursued by several people who were passing by. As he ran, the man undressed himself completely, casting off all the clothes and valuables except the bangles, and disappeared, the agency reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bush-Networks     02-09 0064</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Networks,0067</SECOND>
<HEAD>Networks Will Carry Bush Speech Live</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Bush-Budget</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Television networks will pre-empt prime-time programming tonight for live coverage of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s address to a joint session of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The president is scheduled to speak at 9 p.m. EST. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> said they also will carry the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> response which will follow the president's address.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0250EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Armenia-Quake     02-09 1047</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Armenia-Quake,1077</SECOND>
<HEAD>2 Months After Quake, Children Study New Lesson _ Survival</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANDREW KATELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LENINAKAN, U.S.S.R. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bare light bulb throws rays of hope on the faces of some of <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>'s earthquake children who now study math and the virtues of communism inside a tent. For the 20 fourth graders in a green army tent that is now <LOCATION> Leninakan </LOCATION>'s School No. 7, school bells are ringing again. The corpses and the coffins are gone. So are sobbing relatives and the rescue workers who searched for the living amid the dead. A coal-fired furnace in the tent offers warmth. The children and other survivors do n't need to look far for reminders of Dec. 7, the day two months ago that the earth shook and introduced a new lesson _ one on survival. Their former school lies in ruins just over a hill. They are among tens of thousands of people who never left the area, or have returned since the earthquake smashed northwestern <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> with a blow measuring 6.9 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale. Of the half-million people left homeless, 100,000 women, children and the elderly were evacuated. Those who remain are trying to cope. Some complain the government is not doing enough to help them get clothes and solid roofs over their heads. Others doubt the reconstruction will be finished in two years, as authorities promise. Still others alleged that government officials were keeping donated relief goods for themselves. Those who remain live in tents, mobile homes and the few remaining habitable buildings. They shop for food in surprisingly well-stocked stores and receive government benefits. After recovering 25,000 bodies _ 15,000 in <LOCATION> Leninakan </LOCATION> alone _ workers have moved on to clearing and rebuilding. The <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> says the quake cost $ 16.1 billion. Broken concrete and twisted pipes have been dumped along roads leading to <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>'s second-largest city. `` We Will Build Up Our Native <LOCATION> Leninakan </LOCATION> in Two Years,'' vows a sign at one city entrance, placed under a bronze bust of <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON>, the founder of the Soviet state for whom the city was named. About 100 construction workers are building themselves temporary dormitories in <LOCATION> Leninakan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Akopyan </PERSON> said his Siberian brigade hopes to finish the dorms by the end of February, and start on homes for the general population. Among those hoping for permanent quarters are Asmik Tosunyan and three other people living in a one-room mobile home donated by <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. The 6-foot-by-18-foot room has just one mattress, two chairs and a propane stove, but no electricity or running water. <PERSON> Narina </PERSON> <PERSON> Ophsepyan </PERSON>, 18, was not so lucky. Since the earthquake toppled her nine-story apartment building and killed her parents, she has lived in an unheated tent with no water. `` I asked for a house but they said, ` Where are we going to find one?''' she said as she shivered on a Leninkan street. She and several other residents of <LOCATION> Leninakan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Spitak </LOCATION>, the city closest to the epicenter, complained they have received none of the millions of dollars' worth of clothing donated from abroad and other Soviet republics. She accused `` the bosses'' of keeping it for themselves, or selling it. <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Khodzhamiryan </PERSON>, a deputy premier of <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, said there is n't enough clothing to go around. Asked about the charges, he said: `` Everywhere there are bad people.'' Officials say 6 million square yards of housing must be built, more than 2 million in <LOCATION> Leninakan </LOCATION> itself. New schools and factories also are planned. `` They say it will be done in two years, but God knows when they actually will finish,'' said an angry <LOCATION> Spitak </LOCATION> man without a job and home who refused to give his name. <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reshitilov </PERSON>, a Soviet construction minister and head of the <LOCATION> Leninakan </LOCATION> branch of a government earthquake commission, said it is `` completely realistic'' to build minimal housing and social facilities in two years, but he acknowledged complete restoration will take longer. Officials insist construction will be monitored carefully to prevent shoddy workmanship, which officials says contributed to the death toll. A commission is investigating why many new buildings collapsed in the quake, while older structures were only damaged. New buildings will be no higher than four stories and located away from heavy seismic areas, said <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Krivov </PERSON>, deputy chairman of a committee on architecture and city building. More detailed building codes, like those in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, are being drawn and construction workers will be required to follow them scrupulously, he said. <PERSON> Norik </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Muradyan </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief in <LOCATION> Spitak </LOCATION>, lost 11 relatives in the disaster and said officials are taking no chances in reconstruction. `` We know now that quality, that's life,'' <PERSON> Muradyan </PERSON> said in his makeshift office, a trailer donated by the British. `` Because of that, we are obliged not only to rush, but also to inspect everything.'' Slipshod practices are evident, however. Along railroad tracks, wooden building panels and plasterboards are stacked high, warping in the weather and unprotected from rain and snow that could cause rot. Authorities have determined it wo n't be safe to rebuild on the site where <LOCATION> Spitak </LOCATION> stood, at the confluence of three quake faults. The city, where 23,000 lived and 3,200 died in the quake, will be rebuilt a few miles to the southwest. Today, the old city appears frozen in time, a museum of horror. Hundreds of collapsed houses lie where they fell, seemingly untouched since Dec. 7 in the shadow of beautiful, snow-covered mountains. Eventually the rubble will be cleared and a park, small factories and railroad station may be built there, officials said. But for now, all energy is being poured into the new location, a picturesque valley with fresh bulldozer tracks on recently cleared fields. A sign at a tent city for construction workers proclaims it `` our human duty'' to rebuild <LOCATION> Spitak </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Muradyan </PERSON> takes the proclamation to heart and says his work is good therapy. `` When you are left alone, there is always grief _ both in your soul and mind _ and tears in your eyes,'' he said softly. `` But when you are working for the sake of children and their future and for the sake of your homeland, you must put everything aside and work like a devotee to your people.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Budget Bjt   02-09 0988</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Budget, Bjt,980</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Budget Has Nod to Campaign Promises, but Defers Tough Decisions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> tonight unveils a budget plan keyed to his campaign promises of `` kinder and gentler'' programs without new taxes, but it leaves difficult decisions on reducing the federal deficit for later. The president, in a 9 p.m. EST speech before a joint meeting of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, will call for a nation more competitive abroad and more compassionate at home. To those ends, he will propose more federal spending in fiscal 1990 for clean air and clean coal technology, for science and space, for AIDS research and aid to the homeless, education and child care, according to administration and congressional sources. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> claims that those costs will be offset by about $ 4 billion in new revenue from a controversial cut in the capital gains tax _ another campaign promise _ and $ 2 billion by holding the expansion of the military budget to the rate of inflation. `` You will have a very detailed and precise descriptions of the priorities of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration,'' said <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, the White House press secretary. Left deliberately unclear, however, will be how much <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> embraces the many budget cuts he left unchanged from the first-draft spending plan former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> submitted last month. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will distance himself from any of the individual, unpopular cuts by inviting <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to help set each program level in accordance with his `` flexible freeze'' plan to limit overall spending in general categories. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> suggested terminating dozens of domestic programs and cutting back many others in order to reduce the deficit below the $ 100 billion maximum allowed by the Gramm-Rudman law. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s calculations include the total savings from those <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> cuts in contending that he, too, is meeting the deficit target. He may claim a deficit as low as $ 90 billion by including sales of government assets that do not count toward the Gramm-Rudman goal, said one source who spoke on the condition of anonymity. <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> lawmakers briefed Wednesday by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s budget director, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>, said the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plan proposes lumping programs together in `` boxes,'' within which some would have to be cut in order to expand others. Democrats did n't wait for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s speech to begin criticizing his plan to cut the capital gains tax, saying it is a tax break for the rich and will increase the deficit, not reduce it as the president claims. `` At a time when virtually every segment of our country is being asked to sustain a sacrifice of one form or another ... it is simply unacceptable to be considering tax breaks for the very wealthiest segment,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>, D-Tenn., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Many private economists dispute <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s claim that the rate cut will increase government revenues by spurring business investment and activity. Nonetheless, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> budget will claim about $ 4 billion in new revenue from the plan, which would be implemented gradually and eventually cut the rate to 15 percent for productive assets held for two years or more. Capital gains now are taxed at either 28 percent or 33 percent, depending on income. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> oil man, also will propose new tax breaks for the oil and gas industry. Additional energy production in selected offshore areas and in the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> wildlife refuge _ both opposed by environmentalists _ also are part of the plan, sources said. Other <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposals aimed at business and trade growth will include: _ Restoring a research and development tax credit for business _ Urban enterprise zones, using special tax breaks to lure companies to depressed areas _ Expanded support of research and science, including the space station and shuttle and the proposed superconducting supercollider physics laboratory <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will focus part of his speech and proposals on the environment, promising more spending on the Superfund program for toxic waste clean-ups, clean coal technology, clean water and wetlands programs, and a greater emphasis on global environmental problems such as the greenhouse effect. A few selected domestic programs in his budget would be increased as part of his `` kinder, gentler nation'' promise. Sources said they include: _ Increasing the <ORGANIZATION> Head </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Start </ORGANIZATION> preschool education program by $ 250 million _ A merit award program for schools, and increased subsidies for black colleges _ A renewed and expanded tax credit for adoption, two years after the 1986 tax bill eliminated a deduction to offset those costs _ Rejection of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s proposed $ 1.7 billion cut in the Medicaid health program for the poor _ A child care tax credit of $ 1,000 for low-income families _ Full funding of the <PERSON> McKinney </PERSON> homeless assistance act _ $ 25 million to start a national program for youth in public service. _ Increased spending for the battle against drug abuse, although not the full amount authorized by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> _ Increased spending on AIDS research The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> budget revisions will also reflect the $ 1.9 billion cost to the taxpayer next year of his program to bail out the ailing savings and loan industry. He'll also embrace <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s plans for upgrading aviation safety, and add $ 350 million to the $ 1.4 billion <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> sought for clean-ups needed at the government's nuclear plants, the sources said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> asked <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to increase military spending 2 percent over inflation in fiscal 1990. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will propose an inflation-only increase next year, with a 1 percent increase over inflation in 1991 and a 2 percent increase in 1993. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will revise <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s economic assumptions slightly to reflect his higher projection for short-term interest rates in 1989 than the 6.3 percent projected in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> budget. Since taking office, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his budget chief <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> have been urging <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> leaders to join in high-level budget talks to shortcut the balky congressional budget process. Under regular procedures, the president's budget gets modified by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> into a final budget resolution, which then serves as an overall guide for legislation produced later by the appropriations and tax-writing committees.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0250EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SoccerRiot     02-09 0192</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soccer Riot,0196</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cyprus Fans Attack Scots After Close Match, Injure Referee</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LIMASSOL, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 1,000 angry Cypriot soccer fans besieged the winning Scottish team after a World Cup qualifying match, stoning the <ORGANIZATION> Scots </ORGANIZATION>' locker room and injuring nine people, police said. Four Cypriot fans were arrested on rioting charges in the violence that erupted after the <ORGANIZATION> Glasgow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rangers </ORGANIZATION> scored a goal to clinch a 3-2 victory in the final 10 seconds of a see-saw game. A police spokesman said club-swinging riot squads broke up the mob after fans started hurling cans and stones at the locked metal doors of the Scottish team's locker room at <LOCATION> Tsirion </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION> in this southern port. The spokesman said the team later drove straight to <LOCATION> Larnaca </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> under police escort. Police said eight officers were injured and the East German referee was `` slightly injured'' when he was punched by a mental patient on parole as he followed the players off the field. One police car and a bus were damaged, witnesses said. There were no reports of injuries or arrests among an estimated 1,500 Scottish fans who flew in for the game.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0212EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     02-09 0939</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,940</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farmers Able to Borrow Again</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Farmers are able to borrow money again, and the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says it's a good sign that the battered agricultural economy is well on its way to recovery. `` The large paydown in farm debt held by major farm lenders appears to be over, and debt is expected to grow 1.5 percent to 3.5 percent in 1989,'' the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. `` Farm loan demand strengthened in the past year and should continue to expand in 1989.'' Moreover, the agency said Wednesday in a report, commercial banks that specialize in farm finance are doing well compared with the mid-1980s. By last summer, their returns on equity were up 40 percent from 1987 and more than 150 percent above 1986. `` The improving farm economy will save more agricultural banks from failure in 1989,'' the report said. `` Failures, after setting a post-Depression record of 75 in 1987, fell to 41 in 1988, and may be the same to sharply fewer in 1989.'' Total bank failures, including agricultural institutions, may `` be closer to 100'' in 1989 instead of more than 200 in each of the previous two years, the report said. At the height of the recent financial crunch, as plummeting land values cut sharply into assets, thousands of farmers owed so much that they could n't qualify for additional credit to pay bills. With the lid on further credit, farmers often liquidated or culled livestock herds, sold commodities held in storage and took other steps to reduce debts. As this paydown took effect, banks and other lending institutions have eased back. As a result, the report said `` creditworthy farmers should have ample access to operating credit'' for spring planting and other production expenses this year. `` Farm lenders are optimistic about financial conditions despite the -LRB- 1988 -RRB- drought and do not think it will sidetrack the farm recovery,'' the report said. Major farm lending groups reported stronger portfolios in 1988 and fewer farm loan delinquencies, loan charge-offs and foreclosures, it said. An exception was the department's <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, which makes loans to the least creditworthy producers, but `` indications are that it too is coming to grips'' with its problems, the report said. A major reason for the favorable farm financial outlook this year was said to be the continued strength in crop and livestock commodity sales. `` Better economic fundamentals also underlie long-run trends in agriculture,'' the report said. `` Farmland markets have improved and the farm sector balance sheet -LRB- of assets and liabilities -RRB- has stabilized.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Farm and ranch inventories of cattle and calves edged down again to a 28-year low of 99,484,000 head on Jan. 1 from 99,524,000 a year ago, according to new <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> estimates. But the decline has slowed and there were indications many beef producers have started rebuilding their herds. A year ago, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cattle herd was down 2.4 percent from the 102 million head that had been estimated Jan. 1, 1987. This year's decline was less than 1 percent. `` This slowed the recent downtrend in cattle inventories that began six years ago and was the second consecutive inventory below 100 million head since 1961,'' the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday. The estimate was in line with recent predictions of <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> analysts, who say the shrinkage in the overall cattle herd may be starting to rebound. As producers hold back breeding stock to rebuild herds, beef output is expected to decline in the short run. Overall, according to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> forecasts, 1989 beef production may decline 5 percent to 7 percent from last year to the lowest level since 1980. But large supplies of pork and poultry are expected and that could leave this year's total meat output at only slightly below the record level of 1988. Even so, retail beef prices are expected to set records this year. As of Jan. 1, the number of beef cows and heifers that have calved totaled 43.9 million head, up 1 percent from a year ago, the first increase following six consecutive years of decline. Beef cows were reported at 33.7 milion head, up 2 percent from Jan. 1, 1988, and dairy cows at 10.2 million head, down 1 percent. It was the smallest inventory of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> milk cows since 1872, the report said. The 1988 calf crop was estimated at almost 40.9 million head, up 2 percent from 1987. Analysts said the value of all cattle and calves as of Jan. 1 was estimated at about $ 60.4 billion, up 16 percent from $ 52 billion a year earlier. The average value was reported at $ 607 per head, compared with $ 523 the previous year.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An annual inventory report by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> shows that the nation's flock of sheep and lambs increased slightly in 1988 for the third consecutive year. The increase was only a small fraction of 1 percent, however, boosting the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> flock to an estimated 10,802,000 sheep and lambs on Jan. 1 from 10,784,000 on Jan. 1, 1988. Despite the recent gains, the Jan. 1 count was one of the smallest in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history, according to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> records going back for more than a century. In 1970, for example, there were 20.4 million sheep and lambs in the nation's flocks. And in 1867, when <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> began counting sheep, there were about 46.3 million head. The industry peaked in 1942 at 56.2 million. `` Primarily the decline stems from less demand for wool as more synthetics and cheaper substitute materials were introduced and the declining demand for lamb in consumer diets,'' the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0303EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Mozambique-Widow     02-09 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mozambique-Widow,0724</SECOND>
<HEAD>Illinois-Born Widow of African Revolutionary Hopes for Peace</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURINDA KEYS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MAPUTO, Mozambique (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondlane </PERSON>, educated in a one-room schoolhouse near <LOCATION> Downers </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grove </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, was 17 and dreaming of becoming a doctor in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> when she met an African revolutionary at a summer church camp. He changed her life. It was 1951, and <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondlane </PERSON>, who became the founder and first president of the <ORGANIZATION> Mozambican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, was 31 and lecturing at church camps as part of his scholarship to <ORGANIZATION> Oberlin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. `` I am a product of <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondlane </PERSON>,'' says his widow, 55, who heads the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>, still wracked by war and famine 14 years after independence from <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION> and 20 years after her husband's assassination. `` I grew up in this little town near <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. Until I was 7 I lived out in the country,'' the former <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Rae </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> recalled in an interview. `` Life was calm, very stable, not many ideas were passing through.'' She said, `` <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> was able to write on a blank sheet and he wrote on it until the time he died.'' On Feb. 3, 1969, <PERSON> Mondlane </PERSON> was killed by a parcel bomb at his office in <LOCATION> Dar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Es </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salaam </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tanzania </LOCATION>, where the revolutionary movement _ known by its <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> acronym, <ORGANIZATION> Frelimo </ORGANIZATION> _ was headquartered during the war against the Portuguese. `` During the whole long struggle every now and then you had to pick up the children and leave the house in the middle of the night because word came that someone was coming to attack,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Mondlane </PERSON> said. `` I'm not at all a violent person. As a matter of fact I'm rather a pacifist. But my life has been very much linked with war, unfortunately.'' Her work as head of the <ORGANIZATION> Mozambican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> involves providing emergency aid for millions of refugees displaced by fighting between the <LOCATION> Frelimo </LOCATION> government, which took power in 1975 under a Marxist constitution, and guerrillas of the Mozambican National Resistance, supported for many years by the white-minority governments of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and what then was <LOCATION> Rhodesia </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Mondlane </PERSON> said she is not a Marxist but is a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Frelimo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and a deputy in the People's Assembly, the national legislature. Today's <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION> is not what she had expected, she said. `` I never counted on so much war, that's for sure. We thought that it would be possible to develop the country. It has n't been.'' A major decision of her life was relinquishing her American citizenship. `` The rest of my family is in the States. It's a question of do you break these ties or do n't you, really throw in the lot or not? `` I decided yes, this is really my country. I really dedicated my life to this country since I met <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON>, and that's a long time ago. `` I went to the church camp in -LRB- <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, and there was <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON>. We students were supposed to go to a different lecture every day. I went to the lecture Monday on <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and stayed there. I was just mesmerized.'' She and <PERSON> Mondlane </PERSON> exchanged letters for the next 18 months. After high school graduation she went to <ORGANIZATION> Marianhill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> to be near him, then they both transferred to <ORGANIZATION> Northwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Evanston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> `` Blacks and whites did n't get married then,'' she said. `` The process took five years, trying to work through things with my family. There was a lot of hullabaloo from his missionary friends about marrying instead of going to the <LOCATION> Congo </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Mondlane </PERSON> went to work for the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> and did n't return to <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> until 1961. After nine months as a professor at <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Mondlane </PERSON> went to <LOCATION> Tanzania </LOCATION>, where three Mozambican exile groups united in 1962 under his leadership and began the guerrilla war. After her husband's death, Mrs. <PERSON> Mondlane </PERSON> helped fund schools and medical posts in the northern provinces that <ORGANIZATION> Frelimo </ORGANIZATION> controlled until independence came in 1975. `` What I'd like to do is go and work on my farm -LRB- in the countryside -RRB- but here I am still working here, doing the same thing I was doing all my life,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Mondlane </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0310EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Paraguay-Cult     02-09 0587</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Paraguay-Cult,0603</SECOND>
<HEAD>Posters, Statues &amp; Other Reminders of Deposed Ruler Come Down</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELIZABETH LOVE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ASUNCION, Paraguay (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soon after Gen. <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> was ousted in a coup, residents of the working class neighborhood `` Barrio Stroessner'' strung some rope around the neck of a statue of the dictator and pulled it down. <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>'s cult of personality, which in 34 years saw a city, international airport and even a popular polka named after him, is crumbling as Paraguayans try to erase remnants of the man who was ousted Friday by Gen. <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>. At President <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> International Airport, an employee using a spatula and bucket of warm water worked to remove the ubiquitous posters of the one-time president and `` Only Leader,'' as he often was described. Gone, too, is the large flashing neon sign that for years at night blinked out in red letters the message `` Stroessner: Peace, Work and Well-Being'' from atop the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industrial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> next to a downtown park. Government employees still slip and refer to `` President <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>'' instead of `` President <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>,'' but the ever-present photos of the stocky, shrewd ex-army commander-in-chief have disappeared from their offices. The newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Ultima </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hora </ORGANIZATION> offered a tongue-in-cheek sale of `` framed pictures and paintings in various sizes, poses and expressions of a known ex-military president.'' `` The offer is limited and will not be repeated,'' the phony ad said. The Roman Catholic Church-run Radio Caritas held a poll to determine what new name to use for the airport, the neighborhood `` Barrio Stroessner'' and the city <PERSON> Presidente </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>, located about 200 miles east of the capital across the <LOCATION> Parana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>. One caller suggested the airport be dubbed `` Freedom Airport''; another, `` February 3rd Airport'' to mark the day of the coup. Others suggested `` Barrio Stroessner'' become `` Barrio <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> II'' to commemorate the pope's visit to <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION> in May. Government officials are reluctant to criticize the <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> years too harshly, telling reporters they prefer to look to the future. <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> himself set the tone Monday by saying his former boss and friend `` was not a dictator.'' `` The <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> government had different stages and within those stages there were 32 or 33 years of a great government,'' says new Foreign Minister <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Argana </PERSON>. The public reaction is more varied and harder to gauge, but as opposition leader <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> <PERSON> Laino </PERSON> notes acerbicly, few in the army stood by <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> in his moment of need, no one rallied to his side while he remained a prisoner in <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION>, and the majority of people who saw him off at the airport were there to jeer. `` There's no doubt about it, the majority of the people are euphorically enchanted,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON>, who came from <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, 19 years ago to serve in <LOCATION> Colonel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oviedo </LOCATION>, a city 80 miles east of <LOCATION> Asuncion </LOCATION>. `` It will take a couple of weeks until they are over this.'' That view is not unanimous. A parking lot attendant said: `` He was a good man. We'll have to wait to see what comes next.'' But interviews with Paraguayans like <PERSON> Hilaria </PERSON> <PERSON> Sandoval </PERSON> indicated why the end of a 34-year authoritarian was almost an anticlimax. `` Now you can talk and nobody will arrest you,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Sandoval </PERSON>, a vegetable vendor who carries carrots, onions and spinach door-to-door on her head. `` I think Gen. <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>'s coup was a magnificent act,'' she said. `` I would like to vote for the general for president in the next elections.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0311EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-JerryBrown     02-09 0771</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jerry Brown,0788</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jerry Brown Back in Political Spotlight</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUG WILLIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SACRAMENTO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 To the delight of Republicans and discomfort of some Democrats, <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> is back in the political spotlight, campaigning for the once-obscure post of chair of the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Democratic Party. The political comeback of the former governor and two-time presidential candidate follows six years of self-imposed political exile _ part of it spent in seclusion writing in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and part working in <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON>'s hospital in <LOCATION> Calcutta </LOCATION> and on a CARE hunger project in <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s latest campaign will conclude with voting Saturday among the 2,800 delegates credentialed for the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Democratic Party's annual convention. Another liberal <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, is expected to be named chairman of the national <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> on Friday. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, 50, once dubbed `` Gov. Moonbeam'' by his critics, has lined up endorsements from an impressive array of party leaders and is regarded as the favorite over investment banker <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Westly </PERSON>, 32, of <LOCATION> Menlo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Westly </PERSON> is the current vice chair of the party and traditionally would be unopposed for chairman. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s critics note that as governor from 1975 through 1983, he shunned the party, and they contend he would use the chair's office not to serve the party but as a stepping stone to advance his own political career. They also say one of his weaknesses as governor was neglect of the sort of administrative detail that is a major part of the state chair's job, and that <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s election would give new life to what have become stale Republican attacks against controversial aspects of <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s governorship, from Medflies to his appointment of <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Bird </PERSON> as chief justice. Ms. <PERSON> Bird </PERSON> was recalled by voters in 1986, largely because of her opposition to the death penalty. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> acknowledges and dismisses such criticism, saying that the 18 primary and general election campaigns he has conducted over the past two decades give him the experience, contacts and fund-raising ability to revitalize the party. `` I think that issue of negative baggage is overstated. People do n't replay history forever,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> says, making jokes exaggerating his past political problems. `` I guess I feel a little bit like <PERSON> Typhoid </PERSON> <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>,'' he joked in one interview shortly after announcing his candidacy late last year. `` I walk in and people want to step back a little. Ohhhhh boy, it's going to be <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bird </PERSON>, <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, death penalty, <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON>, Farm Workers, Whewww! But <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s image is not a joke to some Democrats. `` He has too much baggage to help the party recoup,'' says Assemblyman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Vasconcellos </PERSON> of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>, a Democrat generally supportive of <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> during his governorship. And Assemblyman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Katz </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fernando </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> Democrat who has formed an exploratory committee for a race for lieutenant governor in 1990, does n't want <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> to become a fresh campaign issue. `` I do n't see any evidence that he's changed. What has <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> done in the last six years to show he's in touch with the people of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>? He seems to think he has to go to <LOCATION> Calcutta </LOCATION> to see people in need,'' <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> says. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> says his goals will be to rebuild what he describes as a decaying <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, particularly in fund-raising, and he says that goal, not his own career, will be his focus as chairman. But if he succeeds in strengthening the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, the people now criticizing his bid will want him to run for office, but he adamently declines to specify any future office. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> has gone out of his way in his comeback bid to admit past mistakes. In a long introspective article he wrote for The <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> Bee the week before formally announcing his campaign for chair, he specifically addressed his rocky relationship with the party he now wants to lead. `` One thing I did not do -LRB- as governor -RRB- is build a strong <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> or even an enduring political organization. I knew where I was going, but too often I was going there by myself,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> wrote. `` I had become so immersed in campaigning and running that I neglected the people around me.'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> acknowledges that his bid for the unpaid post of party chairman is his bid to re-enter politics, but he denies that his re-entry will be at the expense of the party. And he pledges to serve the full four-year term, which presumably would take him out of 1992 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> or presidential races. `` I'm back, back to build the party, and back to stay,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> told convention delegates in Red Bluff last week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0312EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TeenProfessor     02-09 0633</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Teen Professor,0647</SECOND>
<HEAD>Harvard among Top Schools Recruiting 17-Year-Old Math Whiz</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DIAMOND</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As thousands of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> teen-agers struggle with the complexities of basic algebra, a 17-year-old English girl is being wooed by <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> and several other universities to lecture and continue her mathematical research on such subjects as quantum groups and statistical mechanics. <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, is manipulating some of the most complex concepts in mathematics. Her work has taken her to the outer fringes of theoretical physics and mathematics, such subjects as knot and string theory, and the connections between the world of particle physics and mathematics. She entered <ORGANIZATION> Oxford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> six years ago and by age 13 had her degree. Today she is working on her doctorate and has long since caught the attention of the world's top mathematicians. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> has already taught students at <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION> on a tutorial basis. If she accepts a position at an American university it will be mainly to conduct research. But she said she might lead a seminar or deliver an occasional lecture. In addition to <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Study </ORGANIZATION> is interested in bringing <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> in for a year. It all began not in some exclusive British school but in <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>'s own home in <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION>, where her father, <PERSON> Harry </PERSON>, a computer consultant, gave <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> her entire pre-Oxford education. `` I was always dealing with adults so when I got to Oxford I fitted into the atmosphere. ... He did n't use any textbooks. He taught me totally himself,'' she said Wednesday while visiting Harvard with her father. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> got top scores on her <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION> entrance exam. It was at that point, her father said, `` it was obvious to me that she was a little better than most.'' Once at <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> studied under Sir <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Atiyah </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Professor </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION> and `` one of the great mathematicians of the world,'' according to <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Addison </PERSON>, chairman of the mathematics department at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, one of the schools recruiting <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> seems to have taken her rapid rise in stride. She is much more interested in talking about the vast unknown in the world of mathematics than dwelling on her accomplishments. `` When I was taught mathematics in the beginning I was interested in it. I just liked it. I did n't think it was anything special,'' <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> said. Now, <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> says, `` The age thing really does not matter for more than the first two seconds. ... I talk to mathematicians as mathematicians and I think they talk to me in the same way.'' <PERSON> Addison </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>'s math chairman, has been tracking <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>'s career for the past seven years `` Word was certainly getting around in the mathematical field that there was this very unusual prodigy,'' <PERSON> Addison </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> just spent four weeks in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> attending a prestigious mathematics conference at the <ORGANIZATION> Mathematical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, also in <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>. The discussion among scientists and mathematicians from around the world focused on the relationship between physics and mathematics, <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>'s area of concentration. <PERSON> Addison </PERSON> interviewed <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> for a possible research position at <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION> and found her `` a very nice person. Sometimes prodigies end up being kind of strange or egotistic. I did n't sense that.'' <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> said he taught his daughter at home so she could reach her highest potential. He is using the same method in teaching his other daughter, <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON>, 15, who is something of a piano prodigy, with one <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> concert under her belt. To the inevitable question of whether <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> feels she has missed out on childhood she answers unequivocally: `` I've had a very enjoyable childhood. I've had so many opportunities I would n't have had if I'd gone the ordinary route.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     02-09 1020</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1059</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTA MONICA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, who starred in the television series `` Diff ` rent Strokes,'' is suing his parents and former business adviser, alleging they took too big a share of his The lawsuit filed Tuesday in <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monica </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> also claims that W.G. and <PERSON> Edmonia </PERSON> <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> and the adviser, <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> DeThomas </PERSON>, caused his assets to be managed unwisely. It said <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> believes his parents were unduly influenced by Ms. <PERSON> DeThomas </PERSON>. His lawsuit did not specify what compensation he was seeking but stated that Ms. <PERSON> DeThomas </PERSON> got more than the 5 percent she was entitled to and his parents more than the 20 percent they should have received as his personal managers. The defendants could not be reached for comment because there were no telephone listings for them in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area. <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, who turned 21 Wednesday, started acting when he was 5 years old and portrayed lead character <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on `` Diff ` rent Strokes,'' a series designed for him in He also appeared in the movies `` The Kid from <LOCATION> Left </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Field </LOCATION>,'' `` On the Right Track'' and `` Playing With Fire.'' On Monday, <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>'s `` Diff ` rent Strokes'' 23-year-old co-star, <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON>, pleaded innocent to attempted murder for a Feb. 2 shooting that police described as a drug-related
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Virtuoso cellist and conductor <PERSON> Mstislav </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostropovich </PERSON>, who was stripped of his citizenship and expelled from the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Composers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> in 1978, has been reinstated in the professional union, the <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency said. <PERSON> Rostropovich </PERSON>, conductor of the National Symphony in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, and his wife, soprano <PERSON> Galina </PERSON> <PERSON> Vishnevskaya </PERSON>, emigrated from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> four years earlier in search of `` artistic liberty.'' <PERSON> Vishnevskaya </PERSON>, a former singer with the Bolshoi Opera, also was stripped of Soviet citizenship. <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> announced <PERSON> Rostropovich </PERSON>'s reinstatement Wednesday. The government newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> last month interviewed the conductor and suggested in the resulting article that returning the couple's citizenship would `` restore justice.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Givens </PERSON> and developer <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> each have donated $ 10,000 to send homeless children to a benefit concert featuring singer <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, comedian <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> and blues star <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>. The donations will allow 20 children to attend the $ 1,000-a-seat benefit concert Feb. 16 in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. `` This will be an evening that these children will always treasure,'' Miss <PERSON> Givens </PERSON>, who appears in <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s situation comedy `` Head of the Class,'' said in a statement. <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> said he decided to make his donation after watching <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s performance in the new Broadway show, `` Black and Blue. Proceeds of the benefit will go to <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'s Children's Health Fund, which provides health care to homeless children, and HELP, a non-profit organization that builds transitional housing for homeless families.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer-actor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> said he has agreed to perform in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> with The Chieftains in exchange for a benefit concert by the Irish folk group in <LOCATION> Wilkes-Barre </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa </LOCATION>. The Irish actor best known for portraying King Arthur in the movie `` Camelot'' said Wednesday he will sing Irish folk songs and read a poem of his during a St. Patrick's Day concert at Carnegie Hall. In return, The Chieftains will give a benefit performance in October in <LOCATION> Wilkes-Barre </LOCATION> to raise money for a scholarship foundation <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> started to honor his brother <PERSON> Dermot </PERSON>, who died in 1986 during a musical tour. <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> said he hoped the benefit would raise $ 50,000 for the <ORGANIZATION> Dermot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Harris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, which pays to send Irish students to the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scranton </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> established the fund for the Jesuit school because he and his younger brother had made many friends there and had attended Jesuit universities.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Filmmaker <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON> has donated $ 850,000 to help build a studio in the <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ballet </ORGANIZATION>'s new building, the school announced. The school, founded by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Balanchine </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirstein </PERSON> in 1934, will move in 1990 to a new building at <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> from existing studios in <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Juilliard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> at the Center. The <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON> Ballet Theater will be the only one of the five studios being built to have seating for viewers, the school said Wednesday.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PEORIA, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Performer <PERSON> Pinky </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> left for <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> to recover from a heart attack suffered during a performance of `` Sugar Babies,'' but vowed to return t take care of `` some unfinished business here.'' `` I owe the people here a show. I sure hope I can come back someday and perform,'' <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> said Wednesday before his release from St. Francis Medical Center. He left for his <LOCATION> Mission </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Viejo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, home with his wife, <PERSON> Bebe </PERSON>. The 72-year-old <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> _ a lisping, baggy-pants vaudeville veteran and early television comedian _ was stricken backstage Jan. 25 at the <ORGANIZATION> Peoria </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> during a road-company performance of the Broadway musical. `` If it was n't for the kindness I've received here in <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION>, I do n't know what I'd have done,'' <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> said. `` When I came here, I was dying. I had no pulse. Now, I'm coming along.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> has agreed to donate to a cancer charity 15 pounds sterling for every pound of body weight a 210-pound fund-raiser sheds, the prince's office says. <PERSON> Alma </PERSON> <PERSON> Whiteway </PERSON>, 59, whose husband, <PERSON> Les </PERSON>, died of cancer four years ago, said the crown prince told her when he opened <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Luke </PERSON>'s Hospice for cancer sufferers in her hometown of <LOCATION> Plymouth </LOCATION> that he would support any good idea to help it `` My doctor said I could do with losing four stone -LRB- 56 pounds -RRB-, so the hospice wrote to the prince and he kept to his word,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Whiteway </PERSON>, who raises funds for the hospice. `` It's fantastic _ as far as I am aware I am the first slimmer in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> to be sponsored by the prince,'' she said. `` He sent his best wishes to me for a successful slim and I wo n't let him down.'' Cmdr. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Aylard </PERSON>, the prince's secretary, confirmed Wednesday that <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> would sponsor Mrs. <PERSON> Whiteway </PERSON> at 15 pounds -LRB- $ 26 -RRB- for every pound she sheds. He agreed to donate up to 840 pounds, or nearly $ 1,500.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0324EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RocketAccident     02-09 0134</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rocket Accident,0140</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rocket Kills One During Test</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PUEBLO, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A rocket nose cone apparently being tested under high air pressure blasted through a factory building's ceiling Wednesday night and crashed in a parking lot, killing one employee, police said. The 17,000-pound nose cone went through the <ORGANIZATION> Kaiser </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerotech </ORGANIZATION> building at the Airport Industrial Park and lodged 4 feet into the parking lot, Police Sgt. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said. `` I'd never seen anything like that,'' he said. A 66-year-old man who worked at <ORGANIZATION> Kaiser </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerotech </ORGANIZATION> was killed, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said. An explosion occurred when the air pressure was released, but there was no fire, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said. `` From what I could determine ... they were testing a rocket cone under high pressure and something did n't jive quite right and it became disconnected,'' <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0326EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RiverFight     02-09 0466</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-River Fight,0481</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lawmakers Want Ban On Tennessee Liquor In North Carolina</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN FLESHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RALEIGH, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An environmental dispute between <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> took a new twist when two legislators here decided to `` fight fire with firewater'' by proposing a ban on <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> liquor. State Sen. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Winner </PERSON> said he wanted to let <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> leaders know that their decision to stop a <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> company from dumping wastewater into the <LOCATION> Pigeon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> would have economic ramifications in both states. `` I'm not trying to knock them to their knees,'' Winner said. `` The basic problem is they do n't think they have anything to lose.'' Winner and state Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Swain </PERSON> introduced a bill Wednesday that would ban the sale in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> of any liquor manufactured in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> or purchased from a <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> vendor. `` There's no revenge involved,'' said <PERSON> Swain </PERSON>, tongue in cheek. `` I just think ol' Tennessee liquor is bad for people.'' The bill is the latest salvo in an increasingly bitter feud between the states over <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>'s refusal to grant <ORGANIZATION> Champion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> a permit to discharge wastewater into the <LOCATION> Pigeon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> at its <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION> paper mill. The Pigeon flows from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> into <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, skirting the northeastern border of <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Smoky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> <LOCATION> National </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>. In response to concerns by residents of <LOCATION> Cocke </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, officials in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> announced Dec. 23 they would not grant a variance allowing the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> plant to continue dumping into the river. A Champion official announced this week that operations at the mill would be scaled back as a result of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>'s decision, threatening the jobs of 1,000 people. Nonetheless, a spokesman for <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Ned </PERSON> <PERSON> McWherter </PERSON> said the decision not to grant the variance is final. `` What <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> does, I guess, is <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>'s businesss,'' said <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Renner </PERSON>, the spokesman `` About the only similarity between <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> whiskey and <LOCATION> Pigeon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> water is they're about the same color.'' The liquor bill quickly inspired jokes and puns in the halls of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>'s Legislative Building, including talk of `` fighting fire with firewater.'' A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alcoholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beverage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> estimated that more than 1 million bottles of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> whiskey are sold in the state each year. Winner said he chose to target <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> liquor to avoid conflicting with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Constitution's provision forbidding states from restricting interstate commerce. The courts have ruled that the 21st Amendment allows states to regulate liquor traffic within their borders and that it supersedes the interstate commerce clause, he said. A spokesman for the <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON> distillery in <LOCATION> Lynchburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, said he was only vaguely familiar with the Champion controversy, but the proposed liquor ban was troubling. `` We're not too happy, I do n't guess,'' said spokesman <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Brashears </PERSON>. `` It do n't make us too pleased.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0326EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TreasuryAuction     02-09 0094</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Treasury Auction,90</SECOND>
<HEAD>10-Year T-Bills Down</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Yields on 10-year <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> notes fell to the lowest level since February 1988. The average yield was in Wednesday's auction 8.91 percent, down from 8.94 percent at the last auction on Nov. 9, 1988. It was the lowest rate since 10-year notes averaged 8.21 percent on Feb. 3, 1988. The notes will carry a coupon interest rate of 8 ~ percent with each $ 10,000 in face value selling for $ 9,977.10 A total of $ 9.5 billion in notes were sold out of bids totaling $ 22.7 billion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0327EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Terrorism     02-09 0595</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Terrorism,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Secret Program Protects US Energy Network</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Michehl, 2nd graf, is CQ</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAY ARNOLD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An anti-terrorist program is protecting the nation's electric power suppliers even though planners doubt a coordinated attack ever will be launched against the energy network, an industry official says. The program is about six months old and involves an `` ongoing working relationship'' with the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Michehl </PERSON> <PERSON> Gent </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reliability </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, told a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> hearing on Wednesday. He said the program, which was 2 -LCB- years in the making, was adopted even though `` skepticism was rampant'' among its creators that terrorists would carry out a multi-site attack on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> energy supplies. Natural events such as hurricanes present a greater threat to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> power systems, said Gent, whose organization represents virtually all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Canadian suppliers of electricity. The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> has been advising <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> companies privately of a growing threat of `` techno-terrorism'' attacks on vital domestic energy facilities and it is pressing them to fortify their defenses. <PERSON> Gent </PERSON> said his group had agreed with <PERSON> DOE </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> officials not to talk about the program because of fear of tipping off terrorists. He said his testimony before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> `` is the first, and I hope the last, public utterance of our program.'' He said he would be willing to discuss specifics of the program in a closed committee session, which <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, said could be done. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> said oil and natural gas pipeline representatives had declined to appear before the panel out of fear that sensitive security information would be revealed. The committee concluded two days of hearings on the vulnerability of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> telecommunications and energy resources to terrorism. In testimony Tuesday, the committee was told the increasing sophistication of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> telecommunications systems and their concentration at fewer sites made them more vulnerable to terrorist attack. The committee also was told the federal government was ill-prepared to deal with a terrorist assault on private communications. A DOE official Wednesday said that in the past two years his department `` has taken decisive steps to substantially strengthen and reorganize the nation's ability to respond to non-nuclear energy emergencies.'' Those steps include an Energy Emergency Management System within DOE and an <ORGANIZATION> Interagency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vulnerability </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Badolato </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> DOE </ORGANIZATION>'s deputy assistant secretary for energy emergencies. `` We filled a vacuum,'' <PERSON> Badolato </PERSON> said, adding that he wanted to ensure that `` we'd never have to go before this body or the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people and say that we had information, even general information, that something was being perpetrated by enemies of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on our energy infrastructure and we stood idly by and did n't do anything about it.'' He said <PERSON> DOE </PERSON>, like the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, put out `` several'' advisories in 1987 that there were foreign terrorist threats that could involve the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He did not elaborate. `` I take the threat seriously, the potential threat seriously.,'' <PERSON> Badolato </PERSON> said `` Since 1980 there have been approximately 8,000 attacks against energy systems around the world. We've been lucky in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. But the individuals who do this are only a plane ride away.'' Another witness, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mullen </PERSON>, said there had been 283 documented cases of sabotage against American energy systems since 1980. But <PERSON> Mullen </PERSON>, a terrorism expert, said he saw no evidence of an increasing terrorist threat in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and that most previous acts of sabotage had been incidents such as shooting at power lines or arson against gasoline station owners or operators.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     02-09 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0026</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Rise in Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 32,078.43, up 13.31 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Thursday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890209-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-09-89 0226EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;Ls-BudgetImpact     02-09 0585</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;Ls-Budget Impact,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush's Rescue Plan Juggles Numbers for Sake of Budget</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
