<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-07-20-89 2325EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Apollo-HoustonCelebration 1stLd-Writethru a0751 07-20
0387</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Apollo-Houston Celebration, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0751,0394</SECOND>
<HEAD>``Splashdown'' Party Celebrates Apollo 11 Lunar Landing</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 9 grafs to UPDATE with color from party; picks up
4th graf pvs, `On July...</HEAD>
<TEXT>
; ADDS byline.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>With AM-Bush-Space, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto HT2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH RENDON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SPACE CENTER, Houston (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The three Apollo 11 astronauts had another `` splashdown'' Thursday, this time in the form of a party with thousands of <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> employees celebrating the 20th anniversary of their lunar landing. Astronauts <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>, <PERSON> Buzz </PERSON> <PERSON> Aldrin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> arrived from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, where they had lunch with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` Twenty years ago, I sat in mission control when these guys came down and I would n't miss this for the world,'' said <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Mark </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Johnson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> director who is now chancellor for the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION>. The space center party was patterned after the informal celebrations that followed each Apollo mission. A crowd estimated at 10,000 attended the event. `` This is just like the splashdown party 20 years ago, except then they threw everybody in the pool,'' said <PERSON> Cookie </PERSON> <PERSON> Leisenring </PERSON>, a former employee of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, who was trying to take pictures of the astronauts. <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, <PERSON> Aldrin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> each got loud applause upon arrival. Separate outdoor areas were designated for different departments such as engineering and development, and recovery crew. Inside, a band played in a gym-sized room decorated with star-shaped ballons and blue balloons with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> flag on them. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> said the astronauts were very pleased to return and visit with old friends. Many of those in the crowd wore buttons showing <PERSON> Armstong </PERSON> on the moon and reading, `` July 20, 1969-1989 We Were There.'' On July 20, 1969, <ORGANIZATION> Armstrong </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Aldrin </PERSON> planted their footsteps on the moon while <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> circled above in the spacecraft that later carried the three men back to <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. The splashdown party is one of many events being hel???? z ~ 2to commemorate that historic After the party, the three former astronauts were to attend a private party where they would watch a light display on Clear Lake dubbed `` Thousand Points of Light.'' That celebration was to begin at 9:56 p.m. _ the moment <ORGANIZATION> Armstrong </ORGANIZATION> stepped on the <LOCATION> moon </LOCATION> two decades ago _ when a group of boats simultaneously switch on strings of lights.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-07-20-89 2327EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Senate-Cambodia     07-20 0546</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Senate-Cambodia,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Adopts Amendment that Opens Door for Military Aid to Cambodia</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted Thursday night to open the door to supplying military aid to the non-communist resistance forces in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. By a vote of 59-39, it adopted an amendment by Sen. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Robb </PERSON>, D-Va., opening the way for President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to make lethal aid available to the resistance forces allied with <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>'s Prince <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> in order to stiffen their ability to resist The amendment is to a $ 4.6 billion <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> authorization bill. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> earlier voted 97-1 for a more general amendment that held out the promise of substantial aid to a new Cambodian government, which is `` determined to prevent the return to power of the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Robb </PERSON> and other supporters of his amendment said it was essential to supply lethal aid because the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has a moral imperative to bar the return of the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>. That left-wing faction is blamed for the killing of more than 1 million Cambodians when it ruled the country in the 1970's. Opponents of the <PERSON> Robb </PERSON> amendment said opening the door to aid puts the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> `` on a slippery slope'' in <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> similar to the development of its involvement in the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> war. The amendment, similar to one already approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, does not specify the dollar amount of military aid or indicate what kinds of weapons would be supplied. <PERSON> Robb </PERSON> said it does not directly authorize military aid but does give the President the `` flexibility'' to ask authorization for it at a later time. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s action comes at a time when negotiations are opening in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> on the future of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> after the announced Sept. 30 withdrawal of the occupying Vietnamese army. `` The administration in my judgment needs that flexibility,'' <PERSON> Robb </PERSON> said. `` By aiding the non-communist resistance we advance the prospects for a successful outcome in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. But if we do nothing only heighten the prospects for a bloody civil war and the return of the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>.'' But Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, D-Calif., told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>: `` Military aid to the so-called non-communist resistance would derail a fast-moving peace process that promises real hope. Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, appealed in vain for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to take more time to consider the `` The president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has not asked for one dollar in military aid,'' he said. `` I may vote for military aid when the president makes a request for it, when he says, this is what we need, this is why we need it.'' `` I say we've got time to consider this issue,'' <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said. `` We do n't have to vote for it at this hour of the night.'' `` I stood on this floor when we slid into the war in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said. `` I think we should let history give us some guidance before we take sudden action here and write a blank check for the president.'' Other senators disagreed and Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Lieberman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, called the <PERSON> Robb </PERSON> approach `` measured involvement.'' `` This is our responsibility lest we be accused of forgetting the lessons of the first Asian holocaust,'' <PERSON> Lieberman </PERSON> said. `` Let us do what is required to keep a second one from occurring.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-07-20-89 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-HUD-SpaceSpending 1stLd-Writethru   07-20 0509</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-HUD-Space Spending, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0832,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Approves Spending Bill for Housing, Space and Veterans Programs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: CORRECTS $400 million to $400 billion in 10th graf: ``Schumer
estimated,'' ^By DENISE CABRERA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved a $ 65 billion spending bill for housing, space and veterans programs Thursday but decided to cut funding for a controversial program at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>. The bill, passed by a voice vote, provides no new money for a <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> program currently being investigated by four congressional panels and the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> for fraud and mismanagement. A <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> inspector general's report alleged several former <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> officials and Republican party fundraisers, including former Secretary of Interior <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Watt </PERSON> used political influence to get funding for projects on which they were highly paid consultants or developers. `` We did not want to fund a program which is having such difficulty,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations subcommittee that oversees funding for <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> and independent agencies. The bill also would reclassify all deputy assistant secretaries, administrators and directors at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> and other agencies covered by the legislation as career positions. Persons now in these positions are political appointees of the president. However, it was funding for a planned space station on the <LOCATION> moon </LOCATION> and expanded <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> exploration that dominated debate on the bill on Thursday, the 20th anniversary of man's first lunar landing. Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, attempted to transfer $ 714 million from the space station to veterans medical services, pollution control and research and low-income and elderly housing. `` The space station is not the way to go to space. It is the B-2 bomber of the space program,'' said <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>. <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON> estimated the space station and a proposal by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for a manned mission to Mars would cost $ 400 billion. `` I am a believer in space technology,'' said <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, `` but you ca n't have everything.'' `` As we reach for the stars, let us not forget those who live underneath them'' he added. While <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>'s proposal might save money in the short term, <PERSON> Green </PERSON> warned that decreasing spending for space by small amounts at a time would drive the overall costs up. `` The one thing that is going to drive the cost of the space station through the roof is to nickel and dime it,'' said <PERSON> Green </PERSON>. <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON> `` really saves a penny this year but he will be spending pounds and pounds in later years,'' added <PERSON> Green </PERSON>. <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>'s proposal was defeated by a 291-125 vote. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> appropriations bill earmarks $ 1.65 billion of <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s $ 12.2 billion budget for the space station The bill reduces the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration budget request for <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> by $ 1 billion. The bill also provides: _ $ 15.1 billion for <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>, including $ 9.1 billion for assisted housing and $ 456 million to fully fund programs under the <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> McKinney </PERSON> Homeless Act _ $ 29.5 billion for the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, including $ 820 million for veterans medical care _ $ 35.5 million for the <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Product </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> _ $ 5.4 billion for the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DC-10Crash-Engine 1stLd-Writethru a0402 07-20 0473</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-DC-10 Crash-Engine, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0402, a0405,0481</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Engine Suspected of Failing Had Past Problems</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Combines urgent series, clarifying that problems were with No.
on the jet that crashed. UPDATES with details of other problems, quotes
from passenger who said jet had problems earlier in the day.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-DC-10 Crash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OKLAHOMA CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal records indicate past major problems with the tail engine of a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> DC-10 that crashed Wednesday as it attempted to make an emergency landing with about 290 people aboard. The jet's tail engine, or engine No. 2, failed just prior to the crash, and the 15-year-old plane experienced `` complete hydraulic failure,'' <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrar </PERSON> said. However, it could not be determined Wednesday night whether the tail engine that experienced the previous problems was the same No. 2 engine that was on the jet when it crashed. Meanwhile, a passenger who rode same DC-10 from <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> Wednesday morning said the plane had been delayed because of technical problems. Mrs. <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinsmore </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Laurel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, said passengers boarded tha plane and and it began to leave the terminal at <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> shortly after 10 a.m., when `` everything sort of shut off.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Dinsmore </PERSON> said the pilot came on the PA system and said `` a little gizmo'' had gone wrong. She said the plane taxied back to the terminal, where the plane sat for about 15 minutes while the `` gizmo'' was being fixed. <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> records, obtained for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> by the <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Owners </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, indicate that on Oct. 7, 1988, the No. 2 engine overheated and shut down just after takeoff from <LOCATION> O'Hare </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. An inspection of the engine later revealed that a turbine blade had failed and broken free from the engine's platform. On Sept. 30, 1988, the No. 2 engine also reportedly quit operating at 16,000 feet because of `` extensive high pressure and low pressure turbine damage,'' the report said. The primary cause of the shutdown was a blade that separated at the blade root due to an `` ailing edge crack,'' the report said. On July 20, 1983, the report said, the No. 2 engine shut down due to `` vibration.'' An inspection revealed a broken turbine blade, the report said. The report also indicated problems with the other two engines on the plane. On Sept. 26, 1986, the plane's No. 1 engine was replaced after an inspection revealed a cracked second-stage blade. On Nov. 13, 1987, the report said, the flight crew reported that the No. 3 engine vibrated and lost power as the plane climbed to 4,000 feet after taking off from <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> An engine tear-down later revealed that an engine blade failed and caused additional bearing failure.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Poland-FoodAid     07-20 0277</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Food Aid,0282</SECOND>
<HEAD>EEC Takes First Steps to Provide Emergency Food to Poland</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Poland, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SALLY JACOBSEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BRUSSELS, Belgium (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> has taken the first step to supply emergency food to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, which was singled out for a helping hand at the economic summit of leading industrial nations. Officials of the 12-nation trading bloc put forward a proposal Wednesday for shipping surplus agricultural products to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, which is suffering from serious food shortages. The <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION>'s executive body, said the food will be provided to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> in a way that will ensure that the government begins to take measures to reform the country's devastated economy The plan must be approved by agriculture ministers of the 12 nations that belong to the trading bloc. They are scheduled to meet Monday and Tuesday. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the leaders of <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> agreed at their summit in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> last week to ship food to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> as soon as possible. They also called for a conference to coordinate support for reform measures in both <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, also known as the Common Market, was assigned to take charge of the tasks. In a statement, the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> announced it adopted a framework for urgently supplying food to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. The food will come out of the stocks the community has built up by its farmers. Officials said the commission was considering a plan that would allow the Poles to sell the community's food on the free market and use the money for economic improvements, such as improving the food distribution system.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0215EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     07-20 0408</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0419</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MARTINSBURG, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group that wants to improve the image of taverns in the state's eastern <LOCATION> Panhandle </LOCATION> elected a topless bar owner as president, and he says his job has n't been easy. `` I'm not interested in getting publicity about the fact that I own a topless bar. Luckily, it has n't blown up in my face, yet,'' said C.B. `` Butch'' <PERSON> Pennington </PERSON>, owner of the <ORGANIZATION> Opequon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lounge </ORGANIZATION> and president of the <ORGANIZATION> Tri-County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Tavern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Owners </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. The association was created following an April gambling raid on 33 bars in the Panhandle in which police confiscated 70 illegal gambling devices, including poker machines. `` The biggest mistake that people have is that all you go into a tavern for is to drink and gamble,'' <PERSON> Pennington </PERSON> said. `` That's just not so. You go in to talk to people. It's like going into a friend's house You relax and swap stories.'' <PERSON> Pennington </PERSON> said the owners were upset by the raid because the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> previously ruled that poker machines are legal. The group plans to lobby state and local government to improve business conditions for tavern owners. `` We just want to show them that we're in a legitimate business and, like everybody else, we deserve a fair shake,'' <PERSON> Pennington </PERSON> said. `` We know more than just how to mix drinks. There are some things we can do to help old folks, children, charities, things like that.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW BEDFORD, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The postman may always ring twice, but sometimes he rings 32 years too late. <PERSON> Mildred </PERSON> <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Onge </PERSON> received her mail as usual Tuesday only to find a post card addressed to Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> was her name in 1957, the year marked on the card. Her brother and sister-in-law had sent it while vacationing in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> 32 years ago. `` I did n't believe it. I really did n't believe it,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Onge </PERSON>, 67, who has been widowed twice. `` My brother has been dead since 1977 and my husband -LRB- <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> -RRB- has been dead since 1963.'' New Bedford Postmaster <PERSON> Antone </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> has seen three such late letter deliveries in his 24 years on the job. He said the card could have gone astray within the post office, or been misdelivered and mailed again years later. `` Thirty-two years is a long time,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Onge </PERSON>, who was 35 when the card was mailed. `` My husband would have laughed.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0217EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NudeSculpture     07-20 0222</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nude Sculpture,0227</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sculpture Gets a Second Unveiling at Arkansas Arts Center</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LITTLE ROCK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A nude sculpture got a second unveiling here when the <ORGANIZATION> Arkansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> heeded a protest from the work's owner and took down a cloth that had covered the piece. <PERSON> Townsend </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolfe </PERSON>, the center's director, said Tuesday the covering had been brought down after complaints were raised last week. The sculpture had been draped on occasion at the request of visitors leading groups of children younger than about 12, he said. <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldstrom </PERSON>, the New Yorker who owns the work that is on a three-year tour of the country, said earlier this week he thought it was small-minded to cover up the sculpture and he planned to write the center's board of directors about the matter. The artist, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> DeAndrea </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, also had expressed his displeasure with the draping. The work is a self-sculpture of <PERSON> DeAndrea </PERSON> seated in a chair looking at a nude woman. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldstrom </PERSON>, 14, son of the art collector and dealer, called the <ORGANIZATION> Arkansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION> Monday and said it was disrespectful, even criminal, to drape the sculpture. `` Who gives them the right to put that cover on the sculpture?'' he said. `` The board of directors obviously has no concept of the historical and artistic value of this work.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DC-10Crash 16thLd-Writethru a0424 07-20 1296</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-DC-10 Crash, 16th Ld-Writethru, a0424,1334</SECOND>
<HEAD>Airliner Crashes in Iowa with 298 on Board, Dozens Survive</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 4 grafs to UPDATE with three infants, sted one, cockpit
crew survived crash, 61 bodies found, search suspended due to darkness;
picks up 4th graf, `Nagin said ...'.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos SCX1,2,3,4,5; LaserColor SCX6; LaserGraphics NY57,66</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MELISSA JORDAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SIOUX CITY, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> DC-10 carrying 293 people crashed Wednesday in an explosive ball of fire and cartwheeled down a runway after the pilot tried to make an emergency landing. At least 178 survived the crash, officials said. A fire official initially estimated 185 to 195 were killed in the crash, but officials later backed off the figure. `` We simply do n't have an estimate we can rely on,'' Fire Captain <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmidt </PERSON> said at a news conference Flight 232, from <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> via <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, carried 11 crew members and 282 passengers, including three infants on laps, said <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Nagin </PERSON>. He said the three members of the cockpit crew survived the crash and were being treated for injuries. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Bohs </PERSON>, spokesman for Gov. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Branstad </PERSON>, said 61 bodies were found. The search for bodies at <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gateway </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> was suspended late Wednesday due to darkness and was to resume Thursday. <PERSON> Nagin </PERSON> said a list of the dead and survivors would be released as soon as possible. He could not confirm the number of dead. The plane crashed on an inactive runway at <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gateway </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> after circling for about a half-hour while pilots told passengers to prepare for a crash-landing, survivors said. The accident was one of the deadliest air disasters in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history. The 15-year-old plane had `` complete hydraulic failure'' before the crash just after 4 p.m., <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrar </PERSON> said. The tail engine failed, and this may have caused a hydraulic failure, said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Raynesford </PERSON>, another <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. <PERSON> Nagin </PERSON> said he did not know if hydraulic problems were a factor. A passenger who rode same DC-10 from <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> on Wednesday morning said the plane had been delayed in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> because of technical problems. <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinsmore </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Laurel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, said the plane began to leave the terminal at <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> shortly after 10 a.m., when `` everything sort of shut off.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Dinsmore </PERSON> said the pilot came on the PA system and said `` a little gizmo'' had gone wrong. It was 15 minutes before it was fixed, she said. Late Wednesday, City Manager <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinda </PERSON> said 185 people were taken alive to <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Luke </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Marian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, both in <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. He said seven had died at the hospitals. The search for bodies was difficult because they were scattered in a field of corn 4 feet tall. Rescuers continued to search the corn fields late Wednesday. Dr. <PERSON> Romaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Bendixen </PERSON>, clinic commander of <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>'s 185th tactical fighter group, said he was the first doctor on the scene, about three minutes after the crash He had just landed in another plane. He said the living were scattered among the dead. `` In one group of six seats, a woman sitting in the middle was barely injured, her husband beside her was dead and two behind her were dead,'' <PERSON> Bendixen </PERSON> said. He said rescuers pulled out three of the flight crew alive. Survivor <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Martz </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Castle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, said there was no panic after the pilot announced there was engine trouble. Then, just before landing, the pilot `` came on and said that this may be more than a rough landing, so do the best you can to assume the -LRB- crash preparedness -RRB- position.'' `` Suitcases, paper, mail, clothes, unfortunately people, were laying all over the runway,'' said witness <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Forst </PERSON>. Still, some people walked away from the wreckage. <PERSON> Melanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Cincala </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, a passenger on Flight 232, said there was a fire on the plane, and a fireball `` flashed past us.'' The plane burst into flames after she got off, she said. `` We could see the plane tumbling down the runway,'' said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, a witness who said he was working about 1,500 yards from the site. He said the plane broke into `` 15,000 different pieces.'' Maj. <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Sorensen </PERSON> with the <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said he had just landed his plane when the jetliner crashed. `` Shortly before touchdown ... the right wing began to dip or began to roll and the nose began to fall to a position of approximately 15 to 25 degrees right bank and possibly 10 degrees nose low,'' he told <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION>. `` It was very apparent at that moment that he could not make a safe landing. The only question would have been how disastrous a landing would it be. It was a very disastrous landing.'' <PERSON> Sorensen </PERSON> said that while he was in the air he heard radio traffic from the pilot. `` The suggestion ... was that he could turn only in one direction and he was not sure he could make the runway. Then he turned left and headed for the southwest runway ... and everything appeared to be somewhat about normal.'' Then, the right wing dipped. The plane `` bounced twice, flipped into the air and we were sitting there upside down and it began to fill up with smoke,'' said <PERSON> Cliff </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, a passenger returning home from <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. `` Then God opened a hole in the basement and I pushed a little girl out. I grabbed another, kept pulling them out until they did n't come no more. <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> said he thought he helped a half-dozen out and then he ran. Asked about a survivor who reported an explosion before the crash, <PERSON> Nagin </PERSON> said he knew nothing beyond the report and that talk about sabotage was `` only speculation.'' At <LOCATION> O'Hare </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, where the plane was due, people waiting for Flight 232 were in a room guarded by airline personnel and police. A clergyman was in the room. Among the passengers of the plane were the two top officials of the <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Basketball </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, a league spokesman said. Commissioner <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramsdell </PERSON>, 25, had not been accounted for early Wednesday evening, but deputy commissioner <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schemmel </PERSON> was among the survivors, the spokesman said. <PERSON> Lavonne </PERSON> <PERSON> Quirin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Alta </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Buena </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vista </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> said she and her husband found what appeared to be the plane's nose cone in a corn field at their seed corn business, 75 miles from the airport. The airport has two active runways, each 9,000 feet long, which can accommodate a plane the size of a DC-10. The area around the airport, which is seven miles from downtown, is crop land in corn, soybeans and pasture with some trees. The DC-10-10 was delivered to <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> in April 1974. Routine inspections had been conducted on the plane, <PERSON> Nagin </PERSON> said. No unusual weather was reported. Wind speeds were clocked to 30 mph. The nation's worst air crash happened 10 years ago and involved a DC-10. On May 25, 1979, <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> Flight 191 lost an engine on takeoff from <LOCATION> O'Hare </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, banked sideways out of control, slammed into a field and exploded. All 271 people on board died, as well as two people on the ground. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> cited `` maintenance-induced damage'' _ a 10-inch crack in the engine mount _ that caused the left engine to tear loose. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> also criticized <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION>' design as vulnerable to maintenance damage. <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> suspended production of the DC-10 airliner in 1983. DC-10 orders collapsed in 1979 because of the recession and the May 1979 crash. In all, 369 DC-10s were produced. The second-worst crash in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history killed 156 people on Aug. 16, 1987, when a <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jet crashed on takeoff at <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> Metropolitan Airport. One child on the plane survived.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0120EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CannibalismDig     07-20 0328</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cannibalism Dig,0341</SECOND>
<HEAD>Archaeologists Unearth Remains of At Least 2 Bodies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELLEN MILLER HADDOW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAKE CITY, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Archaeologists have uncovered the bones of as many as four people in a mass grave near the reputed site where self-proclaimed cannibal <PERSON> Alferd </PERSON> <PERSON> Packer </PERSON>'s victims perished, the scientists said Wednesday. The diggers, who found the bodies of at least two men and possibly four on Tuesday, said they also found burlap and a green suspender clip holding remnants of brown cloth. `` The cloth is most remarkable,'' said archaeologist <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Ayres </PERSON>. `` It could help us put a date on things.'' The scientists are part of an expedition formed by <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> law professor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Starrs </PERSON>, who is looking for clues to the truth about what occurred on the snow-packed mountain ridge in 1874. <PERSON> Packer </PERSON>, who formed a gold-hunting party with five other men, said the group became stranded on the ridge two miles south of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> during a bitter winter. <PERSON> Packer </PERSON>, the lone survivor, wandered into what is now <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> in April 1874. He told authorities that <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>, a member of the group, killed the other four gold seekers and that he was forced to kill <PERSON> Bell </PERSON> in self-defense. <PERSON> Packer </PERSON> said he consumed the remains of the five in order to survive. He was convicted of manslaughter and sentenced to 40 years in prison. The case has been a topic of debate ever since. The archaeologists' findings indicated the men's bodies were wrapped in burlap and buried in a mass grave, said <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Birkby </PERSON>, curator of physical anthropology at <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>. The bones were in a jumbled mass, forcing scientists to move slowly in uncovering them. As the scientists worked in the dig site, which <PERSON> Starrs </PERSON> calls the `` bone zone,'' residents and onlookers kept watch nearby. <PERSON> Ayres </PERSON> said the scientists would test the cloth, suspender clip and other artifacts to estimate their age. The scientific expedition began Monday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0257EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Nicaragua     07-20 0669</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nicaragua,0692</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ortega Campaigns During 10th Anniversary Rally</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DORALISA PILARTE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> gave a full-fledged campaign speech on the 10th anniversary of the Sandinista revolution, knowing his government's performance in the next seven months is more important than all the triumphs and failures of the past decade. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>, whose country has become the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION>'s poorest, promised better times ahead and said Nicaraguans are better off today than before July 19, 1979, when <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas marched victoriously into <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> He called on President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to dismantle the U.S.-backed Contra rebels, most of whom are in neighboring <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, and even praised some opposition leaders who joined the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> at the start of the revolution then left it, feeling betrayed. About 200,000 people gathered at a huge plaza along the shores of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> on Wednesday for a rally, the highlight of otherwise lackluster 10th anniversary celebrations. Observers who have been at other anniversary celebrations said most of those attending the 90-minute rally were either party loyalists or public employees afraid of losing their jobs if they did n't show up. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>, who estimated the crowd at more than 300,000, said the large number showed the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> have at least that many votes assured for general elections set for Feb. 25. The Sandinista show of strength at the rally might scare the opposition into abstaining from the ballot, <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> said. `` But let's all be very clear about this ... they can take or leave the elections, but there will be elections on Feb. 25, 1990,'' he said. `` And they will be clean and honest elections, like the ones in 1984.'' In a 50-minute speech, <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> said his government is controlling inflation, which `` is not smashing us as is happening in other countries.'' Inflation in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> surpassed 20,000 percent in 1988, but stiff austerity measures brought it down to a monthly rate of 12 percent in June. However, the cost has been high. The government has fired 35,000 public employees and tightened credit restrictions and public spending. Foreign aid has decreased. A 10-country European tour in April and May from which <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> hoped to get $ 250 million for the country to survive the year, produced just $ 50 million. Nevertheless, at the end of his speech, <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> proclaimed: ` Today the people are better off than before 1979. `` Better days will come,'' he added. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> did not elaborate and left the promises fluttering in the cool morning breeze from the lake. He accused the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> of continuing its `` imperialist aggression'' against <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> by maintaining a commercial blockade and blocking credit. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> still has n't decided to be respectful of the rights of the nations of the Third World ... and of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. `` If the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is for peace ... he should stop immediately his policy of war against the people of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and allow the Contras to be dismantled from Honduran territory.'' Most of the U.S.-backed rebels are known to have moved to jungle camps in neighboring <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> after their leaders and the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> signed a temporary truce in March 1988. Contra bands still roam northern and central <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and sporadic skirmishes still are reported. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> gave guarded praise to three members of the five-member junta that took control after dictator <PERSON> Anastasio </PERSON> <PERSON> Somoza </PERSON> fled the country on July 17, 1979. The three later left the junta, leaving only <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> and current Vice President <PERSON> Sergio </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>. <PERSON> Violeta </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrios </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Chamorro </PERSON>, a powerful symbol of upper-class unity with the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> against <PERSON> Somoza </PERSON> and now the leading contender for opposition presidential candidate, resigned April 19, 1980. She said the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>' goals were incompatible with her hopes for a democratic <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> said Wednesday that Mrs. <PERSON> Chamorro </PERSON>'s decision not to accept `` conditions that the gringos wanted to impose on the junta'' was `` firm and courageous.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Chamorro </PERSON>'s family owns the opposition newspaper <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION>, shut down several times during by <PERSON> Somoza </PERSON> regime and again by the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>. It did not publish on Wednesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0235EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     07-20 0872</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0902</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Sylvester </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> says he really is n't a macho, monosyllabic guy, although he admits he's played that role in so many films that he'd almost forgotten how to talk. `` It's not really me. It was a book that I interpreted,'' <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> said of his Rambo films. `` I inherited the mantle. I'm not monosyllabic. I'm not that quiet. I'm not a loner by nature.'' A clean-shaven, neatly dressed and bespectacled <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> met with reporters Tuesday in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> where he is filming scenes for a <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION> picture co-starring <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>. <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> plays an undercover policeman who is refined and articulate _ a man more inclined to wearing suits and dabbling in the stock market. His next film, `` Lockup,'' opens in early August, and <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> said he is more optimistic about it than he has been about any film since the first `` Rocky'' in 1976. `` It's an ensemble,'' he said. `` It is n't just me out there with a rifle, swinging from a tree for 2 -LCB- hours. At least I get to act, get to talk, which I'd almost forgotten how to do in the past few films. It's like the re-education of <PERSON> Sylvester </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>VICKSBURG, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Multimillionaire publisher <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON> and nine members of the biking club <ORGANIZATION> Capitalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tools </ORGANIZATION> rolled into this historic <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> town on a seven-day journey down the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION>. `` We began where the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> began, and we're going to where it ends,'' <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON> said of the 2,100-mile trek. The motorcyclists spent Tuesday night at a bed-and-breakfast inn and left Wednesday for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, their final destination. The 69-year-old publisher said he found the route more enjoyable than his normal commute. `` We've gone through 10 states and experienced less traffic than one hour of driving from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` You feel like you're really getting to the heart of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' The trip did have its wrong turns, though. `` We followed Highway 72 on a 1988 Rand-McNally map of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and the road got rougher and rougher ... the bridge was out,'' he said. The crew asked a farmer if it was possible to cross the river and he replied, `` If you can leap these bikes 40 feet you can cross,'' <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BIRMINGHAM, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Folk singer <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Baez </PERSON> sang a new song protesting the recent violence in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The performance was at a charity concert attended by Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> and Princess <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>. The 48-year-old <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> singer said she had thought about singing `` Lady Di,'' which she wrote eight years ago, but decided, `` It just would n't have been protocol.'' Instead, she sang the <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> protest song at the Prince's Trust Rock Gala at <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION>'s National Exhibition Center. Wednesday night's concert drew about 10,000 people and raised $ 800,000 for the trust, which helps young people. <PERSON> Baez </PERSON>, who met the royal couple before the show, said she was flattered to be invited. `` I am pleased that I can still enjoy performing,'' she said. `` I'll try to go on for another 10 years, but then I'll have to put my teeth in a jar.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HULL, Quebec (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Duke and Duchess of <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> thanked a crowd for a warm welcome after getting a rough reception a few days earlier on their Canadian tour. `` <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> and I are particularly touched by the warm welcome of Quebecers,'' Prince <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> told a gathering at a civic welcome Wednesday outside City Hall. `` Thank you for the most wonderful welcome.'' The thanks seemed intended, in part, to quiet some controversy fanned by the British press, which reported that <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> was shaken when the couple was booed Sunday at the closing ceremonies of a summer festival in <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. For his part, Mayor <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Legere </PERSON> offered a down-to-earth greeting, urging the royal couple to `` have a Hull of a good time.'' Later the duchess, the former <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>, visited a rehabilitation center in adjacent <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION> and spoke to victims of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis _ a degenerative neuro-muscular affliction also known as <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Gehrig </PERSON>'s disease.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former `` Hollywood Squares'' host <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> has sued actor <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> and game show host <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Convy </PERSON>, contending they broke a contract to hire him as host of a new quiz show. <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> claimed in Wednesday's <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> lawsuit that he was host of the successful pilot of `` 3rd Degree'' and was promised he would continue in that role for the 1989-90 season, said his lawyer, <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolpert </PERSON>. Although announcements were made that the former `` Hollywood Squares'' host would preside over `` 3rd Degree,'' he was told on June 30 that he would not get the job after all, the suit alleged. Soon thereafter, it was announced that <PERSON> Convy </PERSON> was not being renewed as host of `` Win, Lose or Draw'' and would replace <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> on `` 3rd Degree,'' the suit said. The suit seeks $ 1 million in compensatory damages and asks for punitive damages in an amount to be set by the court. `` 3rd Degree'' is produced by <ORGANIZATION> Burt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Bert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Productions </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Friends, <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. The suit accuses <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>' and <PERSON> Convy </PERSON>'s company and the other company of breach of contract and fraud by replacing <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0244EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CleanAir Bjt   07-20 0618</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Clean Air, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Clean Air Draft Plan Sets Ozone Cleanup Deadlines</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nineteen cities likely would be given 10 years to fix their ozone pollution problems, while severely polluted <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> would have two decades, according to a draft of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s clean air bill. The multibillion-dollar cleanup plan would set four new categories for cities with ozone problems _ severe, serious, moderate or marginal _ and require the most polluted communities to use the most stringent remedies. The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> obtained a draft of the proposal, and then applied the latest available <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> air monitoring data to determine which cities would fall into the two most serious ozone pollution categories. There could be some changes when new air quality information becomes available, probably next month, but <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> officials said the number of switches should be small. Ozone is a highly reactive gas that irritates and inflames sensitive lung tissues. This causes a host of adverse health effects, including chest pains, shortness of breath, coughing, nausea, throat irritation and increased susceptibility to respiratory infections. The current <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> data would place these areas in the `` serious'' category for a 10-year cleanup: Chicago-Gary, <LOCATION> Ind </LOCATION>.; <LOCATION> Cincinnati-Hamilton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Hartford-New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain-Middletown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>; Milwaukee-Racine, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Philadelphia-Wilmington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Del.-Trenton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>; Providence-Pawtucket, R.I.-Fall River, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>.; <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION>, La.; Beaumont-Port <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION>, W.Va.-Ashland, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Sheboygan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>.; <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>; and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> officials verified both the list of 19 areas that would be given 10 years to correct ozone problems and the three cities in the severe, 20-year cleanup category. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Becker </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> and Territorial Air Pollution Program Administrators, the organization of state and local air pollution officials, also said he did not expect many changes in the cities' classifications. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is expected to submit the bill to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> as early as Friday. The top 80 metropolitan areas in the country, and about 15 rural areas, are out of compliance with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> clean air standards under current law. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposal is only one way of attacking the ozone problem, and environmentalists and their supporters in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are expected to push for their own proposals. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> estimates that nationwide ozone cleanup efforts would cost $ 5 billion to $ 10 billion a year through the year 2000 and $ 8 billion to $ 12 billion a year afterward. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration legislation envisions the ozone cleanup as being financed largely by industries, including petroleum, automobile, paint and ink producers. Many of the costs would likely be passed on to consumers. The bill would order national measures including new controls on motor vehicle emissions, hazardous waste facilities, and smaller sources of pollutants such as consumer solvents. Oil companies would have to tighten volatility requirements for gasolines. The `` severe'' and `` serious'' areas also would need to have stricter inspection and maintenance programs for motor vehicles; capture emissions from refueling at the gas pump; and EPA-ordered controls on seven additional categories of industrial or commercial sources of pollution. These areas would be required to reduce ozone emissions at an average rate of 3 percent a year _ for 20 years, in the case of severely polluted areas and for 10 years for the serious areas. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plan includes a series of existing and new penalties that could be imposed on areas that fail to comply with the law. These steps, which have been applied sparingly by <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>, include a moratorium on construction of anything that would increase pollution, loss of federal highway funds, restrictions on new drinking water hookups, and withholding money to run clean air programs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0300EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NuclearPlants Bjt   07-20 0592</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuclear Plants, Bjt,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Energy Department May Face Possible Criminal Charges, Plant Shutdowns</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> faces more criminal probes of its nuclear weapons plants _ and mounting public pressure to close them _ unless it controls their environmental and safety problems, federal auditors say. In a report highly critical of department management, the auditors said urgent action is needed to ensure that environmental laws are obeyed and the public is reassured that the government can reliably and safely run the weapons plants. The report dated July 14 was made public Wednesday by a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel as a senior <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official disclosed that a special group of experts from outside the department had been dispatched to a weapons plant in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> Duffy </PERSON>, a special assistant to Energy Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, said in testimony prepared for a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee that the experts will attempt to verify the origin of a manmade radioactive element discovered at the Rocky Flats plant near <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. The plant processes plutonium for weapons manufacturing. Scientists of the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> have said it is possible the radioactive materials strontium and cesium were produced by an accidental nuclear reaction, even though <ORGANIZATION> Rocky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Flats </ORGANIZATION> operations do not include the splitting of atoms. <PERSON> Duffy </PERSON> said that while earlier <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> reviews of the radioactive material gave no evidence that a chain reaction had occurred, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> wants an independent study to `` help alleviate public concern regarding safety at this facility.'' <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Keif </PERSON>, a department spokesman, said the experts arrived at the site last week and are expected to report their findings by mid-September. He said he had no other details. <PERSON> Duffy </PERSON> also disclosed that the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> have launched an investigation of alleged criminal violations of environmental laws at the Feed Materials Production Center, an <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> weapons plant at <LOCATION> Fernald </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Duffy </PERSON>'s statement provided no details, and the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said they could not comment. <PERSON> Duffy </PERSON> did not present his remarks in person because the subcommittee hearing was interrupted before his turn to speak, and it was not resumed. The auditor's report, from the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s office of inspector general, said the department is unable to ensure that its nuclear facilities _ including 17 major weapons plants in 12 states _ are meeting state or federal environmental standards. `` Thus it faces the possibility of facility shutdowns, criminal prosecutions of employees and increased congressional constraints over internal operations,'' the report said. Rep. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Luken </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, chairman of the subcommittee, said he was shocked to learn that the department had no way of determining its own compliance with environmental laws. He harshly criticized <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Layton </PERSON>, the inspector general, for not finding this flaw earlier. `` You're not a watchdog, you're a lap dog,'' <PERSON> Luken </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Layton </PERSON> disputed the charge, but later acknowledged that `` in hindsight it may have taken too long'' for his office to take a broad look at the environmental problems. <PERSON> Layton </PERSON> told <PERSON> Luken </PERSON> he decided to take the unusual step of making public a `` flash'' preliminary version of the audit `` because of the urgency'' of the problems it identifies. Among the key findings is that the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is unable to solve environmental problems at its weapons plants because managers and other employees are not properly trained and are not fully knowledgeable about environmental law. The report also said the department had failed to adequately oversee the work of the private companies that operate the weapons plants under federal contracts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0312EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NegativeCampaignAds     07-20 0546</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Negative Campaign Ads,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Legislation Seeks to Put Attackers on the Defensive</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAY ARNOLD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Negative political ads from `` independent'' advocacy groups are leaving voters with a bad taste in their mouths, says Sen. <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON>. `` The election campaign of last fall hit a new low,'' the <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrat </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday in pushing for a new law to combat the effects of `` attack'' ads. `` It left an odious trail with hit and run attacks, misleading claims, hidden players and a lack of discussion of the major issues,'' he told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> subcommittee </ORGANIZATION>. He noted voter turnout in the 1988 election was the lowest since 1924, at just more than 50 percent, saying the public has been turned off by virulent television spots that slash candidates without discussing substantive issues. `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> knew more about <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Horton </PERSON> than it did about either presidential candidate,'' <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON> said. He was referring to ads attacking Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> furlough program that freed a convict who later raped a woman. Political analyst <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON> <PERSON> Gans </PERSON> illustrated the level of political rhetoric by showing ads ranging from <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s famous 1964 anti-Barry <PERSON> Goldwater </PERSON> message counting down to a nuclear explosion, to one against Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>, D-Tenn., in which a <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> lookalike lit a cigar with roll of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> foreign aid dollars <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON> has introduced a bill along with Sens. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON>, R-Mo., to require broadcasters to provide free air time to anyone targeted by a negative ad from political action committees not connected with a candidate or political party The bill also would require candidates to personally appear in any ad that mentions his or her opponent. The subcommittee is considering another bill by <PERSON> Sens </PERSON>. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON>, D-Nev., and <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., that would require political ad sponsors to be clearly identified on the Both bills are aimed mainly at PACs, which under federal law may make direct campaign contributions of $ 5,000 in a primary and $ 5,000 in the general election. But special interests may spend unlimited amounts on campaigns as long it is done without the knowledge or cooperation of the campaigns and candidates that benefit from independent spending. <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON> said his bill would help make `` the playing field more level'' by giving those attacked the means to respond. `` It in no way says to these independent parties that they can not advertise,'' he said. He said the massive expenditures by the PACs _ $ 10 million on broadcast ads in 1986 _ have driven up the costs of campaigns as candidates take out their own ads to shoot back. Except at one point when <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON> attacked Sen. <PERSON> Mitch </PERSON> <PERSON> McConnell </PERSON>, R-Ky., for ads depicting `` bloodhounds'' searching for an absentee opponent, the senators Wednesday generally steered clear of the touchy subject of negative ads carried out by their colleagues Several witnesses expressed First Amendment concerns about the <LOCATION> Hollings-Danforth </LOCATION> bill. Former Republican Sen. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> McC </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mathias </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> counsel <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> said the bill would involve the government in content regulation of political ads. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, R-Ariz., said since challengers naturally must attack the records of incumbents, the <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON> bill would `` dramatically restrict'' the challenger's ability to wage a campaign
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0319EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HydraulicFailure     07-20 0570</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hydraulic Failure,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pilot's Report of Hydraulic Failure Signals Loss of Control</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-DC-10 Crash Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> WASHINGTON </LOCATION> _ The pilot's report of `` complete hydraulic failure'' just before a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> DC-10 cartwheeled into the ground at <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, signaled he was losing control of the airliner, officials say. Authorities said the hydraulic failure in the spectacular crash Wednesday may have been triggered by an uncontained engine failure, which would mean that engine parts shot out, possibly into the fuselage. Officials in <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> initially estimated that 185 to 195 of the 293 people aboard Flight 232 were killed, but officials later said they did not have a reliable estimate. `` The pilot reported the loss of all of his hydraulic system, which made it very, very difficult to control that aircraft,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Leyden </PERSON>. `` We know he had a real problem bringing the aircraft down and lining it up with the runway.'' <PERSON> Leyden </PERSON> said the plane's wheels were down but little else is known about the amount of control the pilot had in the final minutes after he warned passengers to prepare for a crash landing. `` We ca n't speculate on exactly how much control he had or what happened up there. All we know is he had a very, very difficult time controlling the aircraft,'' said <PERSON> Leyden </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Airline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> and manufacturer <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> were all sending teams to assist in the crash investigation led by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Leyden </PERSON> said hydraulic failure would mean a loss of primary control over nearly every control surface on the wide-bodied, three-engine airliner. A plane's hydraulic system helps push its wheels down, opens and extends flaps to increase the lift of the wings. It also governs other control surfaces of the airplane on the wings and tail, and controls the brakes once the plane is on the ground. Failure of the system does not necessarily mean the pilot has no control, but it could make it more difficult to stabilize the aircraft, particularly in landing. Even with a hydraulic failure, backup mechanical systems could have allowed some control over wheels, flaps and other surfaces that control flight and landing, <PERSON> Leyden </PERSON> said. But he and other aviation experts said manual control can be difficult. Some aviation experts said they doubted the complete system could have gone out. `` I think we can say that we have a flight control problem, but we did not have an airplane that was totally out of hydraulics, or he would n't have been flying at all,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Nance </PERSON>, a pilot and aviation writer, in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolk </PERSON>, an aviation attorney and licensed transport jet pilot in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, said complete hydraulic failure on a DC-10 should be impossible because of required backup systems. Investigators cited partial hydraulic failure as contributing to a May 1979 crash of a DC-10 that killed 273 people seconds after takeoff from <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> O'Hare </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. The engine on that plane tore off and somersaulted over the wing, doing extensive damage to hydraulic fluid lines and electrical cables. Loss of hydraulics also was a factor in a 1974 crash of a Turkish DC-10 in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> that killed 346 people. A buckling of the floor caused by decompression when a cargo door blew off severed hydraulic lines. After that, the control lines in DC-10s were rerouted along the ceiling.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Panama-OAS 3rdLd-Writethru   07-20 0836</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-OAS, 3rd Ld-Writethru,a0833,860</SECOND>
<HEAD>OAS Set To Extend Effort Aimed at Transfer of Power</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDs: Leads with meeting recessing without a decision, grafs 1-7,
other editing changes, picks up 3rd graf pvs, ``It is time</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Organization of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> foreign ministers tentatively agreed to grant <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> mediators an additional month to help promote a solution to the political crisis in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> but deferred until Thursday a decision on other key aspects of a formal declaration. The deliberations adjourned at 1:02 a.m. EDT Thursday after negotiations that began Wednesday morning at the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. A draft proposal calls for a transfer of power in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> on Sept. 1, 1989, and the holding of free elections in the briefest period possible. These steps are to be carried out through `` democratic means and in conformity with existing internal Panamanian procedures.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Panamanian opposition representatives attending the meeting expressed disappointment with the proposal, contending that it could be interpreted by <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to his advantage. Their comments indicated that efforts to toughen the language would be made at the Thursday session to bring additional pressure to bear on <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. Addressing the meeting at <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in early evening, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Deputy Secretary of State <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> issued a forceful appeal for decisive <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> action to ensure the restoration of democratic rule in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. `` It is time to end the crisis in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and the suffering of the Panamanian people,'' <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> inaction would invite military leaders elsewhere in the hemisphere to oust elected governments, he added. He said that drug traffickers also would be encouraged if the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> refuses to meet the challenge in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. Ecuadoran Foreign Minister <PERSON> Diego </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON>, a member of the mediating team, said he believes two months of efforts by him and his colleagues have raised the possibility of a `` national accord'' leading to a restoration of democratic rule in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. He said the basis for his hope was the contacts in recent days between government and opposition leaders in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> aimed at reaching a solution. <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON> was cautiously optimistic about the prospects for a democratic outcome by Sept. 1. According to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s constitution, a new president must be sworn in by that date. The possibility of a national accord was alluded to in a report the mediators submitted to the meeting Wednesday, the deadline for the mediation team. Some delegates felt that the discussions in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> could lead to a government of national reconciliation and most foreign ministers felt there was no alterative but to extend the deadline. Delegates were expected to extend the mandate of the mediating team until late August but there was disagreement over the precise date and other aspects of the final declaration. Opposition leaders in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> said Wednesday they would not agree to any such proposal for a government of national reconciliation. `` We are not going to betray the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> people. We are not going to accept that junta even if they give it the name of National Reconstruction,'' said <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Endara </PERSON>, the opposition presidential candidate in May 7 elections. Intense give-and-take behind closed doors delayed the official opening of Wednesday's meeting by about four hours. After a public session lasting less than an hour, the meeting was recessed as delegates continued behind-the-scenes efforts to reach a compromise on the wording of an official declaration. The crisis was precipitated by the decision of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s electoral authorities to annul the outcome of presidential elections May 7. Independent observers said the candidate opposed to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, the head of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>, had won a landslide victory. The <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> on May 17 appointed its mediating team to promote a democratic `` transfer of power'' in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. It also blamed <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> for the `` grave events'' that occurred in connection with the elections _ a reference to bloody attacks on opposition candidates by government security forces. There was strong sentiment in the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION>, particularly among some <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> governments, not to bring too much pressure to bear on <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> charter forbids interference in the internal affairs of member countries. But the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, which has been a strong advocate of using maximum pressure to force <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> out, has been saying the charter also lists democracy as the system of government that all member states should adhere to. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> opposition to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> also was based on drug smuggling indictments handed down last year against him by two <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> grand juries. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials also argued that OAS credibility in the hemisphere could be preserved only by a strong stand against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. Opposition to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> led the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to state Wednesday, in a provision added to a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> bill, that it would not accept any nominee for administrator of the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> selected by him. The treaty under which the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will turn over the canal to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> calls for a Panamanian administrator acceptable to the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to be appointed next year by <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and confirmed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0639EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Guatemala-Volcano     07-20 0172</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Guatemala-Volcano,0177</SECOND>
<HEAD>Santiaguito Volcano Erupts</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GUATEMALA CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Santiaguito volcano spewed red-hot lava and a 15,000-foot column of ash and steam, a seismology official said. A resident of the city of <LOCATION> Coatepeque </LOCATION>, 25 miles south of the volcano, said ash fell on the city when the volcano erupted Wednesday and lava could be seen glowing on the mountain after dark. <PERSON> Eddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON>, assistant director of the seismology station in <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, said <LOCATION> Santiaguito </LOCATION>, 140 miles west of the capital, is constantly active but Wednesday's eruption was unusual. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and authorities in <LOCATION> Coatepeque </LOCATION> said they were on alert. If the activity continues, coffee and other fields in the western provinces of <LOCATION> Quezaltenango </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Marcos </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Retalhuleu </PERSON> could be affected, emergency officials said. <PERSON> Santiaguito </PERSON> is considered a second crater of the adjacent 12,447-foot <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Maria </LOCATION> volcano. The town of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palmar </LOCATION> was moved from the slopes of the volcano in 1988 after lava flows formed dams above it. The dams broke, causing mudslides that nearly destroyed <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palmar </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0319EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HorseshoePitchers     07-20 0519</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Horseshoe Pitchers,0536</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ancient Art Of Horseshoe Pitching Attracts New Interest</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOE KAFKA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associateed Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SPEARFISH, S.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ringers are sounding everywhere in this picturesque northern <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> town where the 1989 World Horseshoe Tournament is being held. Iron clangs morning till evening as almost 1,500 people from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> compete in the pastime that's enjoying new popularity because President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> enjoys it and even plays at the White House. Horseshoe contestants sporting colorful, lettered shirts similar to those bowlers wear are everywhere in this town of about 5,000 people. Motels are full, and many players and their families are staying in cities as far as 40 miles away. The two-week tournament features $ 73,450 in prize money. `` It's an old-timers' sport that's having a new revival,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Champion </PERSON>, publicist for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Horseshoe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pitchers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. The 16,000-member group has grown considerably in the past few years, he said. `` There's a pitcher in every town someplace,'' Champion said. `` Anybody can get into it regardless of how old you are.'' Horseshoe pitching originated with soldiers in ancient <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> who used discarded horseshoes for sport, imitating discus throwing at the Olympian Games; more than 30 million people now pitch horseshoes in tournaments or in city parks and backyards, according to the organization. Although the average age of horseshoe pitchers is about 45, entrants in the tourney range from 7 to 88, said <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Ficek </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Spearfish </LOCATION> resident and horseshoe player who helped organize the event. The sport is relaxing and tosses together a good mix of camaraderie and competition, <PERSON> Ficek </PERSON> said. But he said horseshoe pitching at the tournament level can be physically grueling. `` In a tournament, you'll probably walk 2 -LCB- miles and throw a ton of iron,'' <PERSON> Ficek </PERSON> said. Horseshoes weigh either 2 pounds, 8 ounces or 2 pounds, 10 ounces, <PERSON> Ficek </PERSON> said. They are tossed 40 feet by men and 30 feet by women and those under 17. <PERSON> Ficek </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Yvonne </PERSON>, who also throws horseshoes, said the competition sometimes gets tense. `` Especially if you need that last ringer to win and they keep topping every horseshoe you put on the stake,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Ficek </PERSON> said. A ringer, when the points of a horseshoe encircle a steel stake in a clay or sand pit, counts as 3 points. One point is awarded when a horseshoe lands within 6 inches of the stake. Two people compete in a game by throwing two horseshoes each to the other end of the court. They then walk to the stake and tally points before repeating throws to the opposite pit. The first to get 40 points is the winner. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Traversie </PERSON>, 70, said he took up the sport 15 years ago when his doctor urged him to get some exercise. He said he practices three hours daily. `` You ca n't teach nobody how to throw a horseshoe,'' <PERSON> Traversie </PERSON> said. `` It has to feel natural to you. <PERSON> Traversie </PERSON> said he was disappointed that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who was invited to attend the championship event, could n't make it. `` He should have at least showed up and throwed a couple of shoes,'' <PERSON> Traversie </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0628EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DC-10Crash-SiouxCity     07-20 0243</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-DC-10 Crash-Sioux City,0248</SECOND>
<HEAD>City Known Mostly For Meatpacking, Advice Sisters</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-DC-10 Crash, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SIOUX CITY, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> is a sprawling commercial center with 82,000 residents and is best known for its meatpacking industry and two sisters who give advice to millions of newspaper readers. The city is in <LOCATION> northwest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> on the east bank of a giant bend in the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, at a spot where the <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> expedition stopped in 1804. <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gateway </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> is used by five commercial airlines, including <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>. It has about 22 arrivals a day, mostly 737s and 727s, but DC-10s have landed there. Two of the city's most famous natives are twins <PERSON> Esther </PERSON> <PERSON> Pauline </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pauline </PERSON> <PERSON> Esther </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON>, who grew up to write the <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Landers </PERSON> and Dear Abby columns. Meatpacking giant <ORGANIZATION> IBP </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrell </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> each operate large meatpacking operations in the city, as do 10 smaller packing operations. The city is part of <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>'s 6th congressional district, represented by <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Grandy </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> native who starred as Gopher in `` The Love Boat'' television series. The only fatality of <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>'s expedition to scout the <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Purchase </LOCATION> occurred while it was camped on the river _ just across from what is now <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>. Sergeant <PERSON> Floyd </PERSON>'s grave is marked by a monument overlooking the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>. The last fatal plane crash at <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> occurred in May 1987, when three people died in a light plane.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0316EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Lucas Bjt   07-20 0688</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lucas, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lucas Could Face More Questions on Civil Rights Nomination</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Should stand</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> could face more grilling on his nomination to be the nation's civil rights chief as the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> seeks to resolve questions about his fitness for the job. `` There are a lot of charges against him. We need to get to the bottom of them,'' Sen. <PERSON> Howell </PERSON> <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON>, D-Ala., said Wednesday after <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> was questioned for more than three hours about his views, his qualifications and his character <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> defended both his commitment to the drive against discrimination and his actions when customs inspectors found $ 8,800 worth of undeclared goods in his luggage. Afterward, Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, D-Ill., who chaired the proceeding, said members reserved the right to recall him for more questioning <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON> told reporters <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> should be questioned again about a number of issues, including the fact that the black Republican from <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> made misstatements on a sworn application to be admitted to the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> bar in 1981. <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> did not disclose on the form that he had once failed the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> bar examination when asked if he had taken the test in other states. <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> testified that when he filled out the 1981 form he interpreted the question to pertain only to any previous applications to the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> bar. `` There was no intent to mislead,'' he said. Several Democrats on the panel questioned whether <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>, a lifelong Democrat who became a Republican in 1985, had the legal credentials and commitment to assistant attorney general for civil rights. `` It remains to be seen whether Mr. <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> is the right man for this important job,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass. `` If a case is brought to me involving a cross burning on the lawn of a citizen, believe me, this is not just cold facts to me,'' said <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>, 61, who was sheriff and later chief executive of <LOCATION> Wayne </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, which includes <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>. `` I have been there. I have smelled the smoke,'' <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> defended a series of recent <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decisions that civil rights lawyers say will make it harder to win discrimination cases in federal courts. <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>, echoing a pledge by Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>, said he would monitor the impact of those decisions on discrimination suits and push for legislation if the rulings thwart civil rights enforcement. But Sen. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, said he was troubled by <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>' defense of the recent high court rulings, adding, `` I've been around long enough to know time slips away.'' <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> also questioned <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> about why he was fined $ 594 by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in 1985 for failing to declare $ 8,884 worth of merchandise the <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> family brought back from a trip to the <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. `` How do you explain concealing receipts and merchandise from the customs inspectors?'' <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> said, reading from an April 24, 1985, report of the incident at the <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> airport. The report said `` there was a deliberate effort by all -LRB- family -RRB- members to conceal goods and receipts.'' <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> explained that customs agents found several pieces of undeclared jewelry in a cosmetics case carried by one of his daughters who accompanied him on the business trip to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> said he reported $ 4,800 worth of merchandise, relying on what his wife and two daughters told him they had bought. `` I reported exactly what I was advised of. I did not personally examine any of these things,'' <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> said he discussed the incident with <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents who investigated his background before his nomination by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as well as with committee staff members. <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> called the customs violation `` pretty minor-league stuff.'' `` Our feeling is that he had a very strong appearance today, answered any and all questions put before him by the committee,'' <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> said. `` We are ever more confident that he'll be confirmed.'' Sen. <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, calling <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> `` a take-charge guy who gets things done, who does what's right,'' vowed to fight hard for his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890720-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-20-89 0318EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PlasticFoam Bjt   07-20 0771</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Plastic Foam, Bjt,0791</SECOND>
<HEAD>Plastic Foam Bans: Is Government Missing the Point?</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MITCHELL LANDSBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
