<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0000EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LogExports     11-20 0987</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Log Exports,1012</SECOND>
<HEAD>Illegal Log Exports _ `Gold Bullion' Sitting on Docks</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RICHARDS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HELENA, Mont. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Japanese lumber mills are paying three or four times <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> prices, and trees worth millions of dollars cut from national forests may be exported illegally each year at a cost of American jobs. Northwest timber exports in 1988 were at least 4.3 billion board-feet, up 20 percent from 1987. Most of that was legal _ cut from private and state lands or, under limited authorization, from national forests. But federal law requires that national forest timber be milled in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` Since it's illegal, nobody really knows how much is going off the docks. As a wild estimate, I would imagine that maybe 5 percent might be federal logs. You're talking about $ 115 million to $ 120 million in lost revenue,'' said <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Sisco </PERSON>, a forester for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> LaDoux </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, disputes that estimate. `` There are people that have made claims that some are being exported,'' he said. `` Our opinion is that, if it is occurring, it is a real small percentage. We do n't think it's a major problem.'' But three men are awaiting trial in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> on charges of diverting more than 500,000 board-feet of national forest timber for illegal export. And the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> says it does n't know for sure how big the problem is; there are no full-time law enforcement agents assigned to illegal export `` We still do n't have the blessing of the powers-that-be to go ahead with it to any great extent,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON>, an investigator at the agency's office in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, adding that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> generally sets the priorities. `` They control the purse strings,'' <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON> said. `` During the summer months, drugs are our priority. Practically everyone is working on drugs, primarily marijuana growing.'' <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> uncertainty over exports comes amid timber shortages blamed for layoffs, sawmill closures and increased industry-conservationist rancor. `` People could get killed out there'' if more trees are n't made available, said a speaker at the annual meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> Montana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. The region may suffer shortages at sawmills, but not at the docks. Exports of raw logs from the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rim </LOCATION> countries jumped from 3.7 billion board-feet in 1987 to 4.3 billion board-feet in 1988, said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> DeFazio </PERSON>, D-Ore. A fourth of all trees cut in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> were exported in 1988, at a cost of up to 30,530 mill jobs, he said Roughly a fifth of the timber from the 12 Western states is exported, the <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> says. The <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Sisco </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> figures used by the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> frequently under-report log exports, and he put the total at 5 billion board-feet. In <LOCATION> Olympia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, for example, <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> researchers found exports of 230 million board-feet two years ago, while the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported around 26 million board-feet, he said. Logs from federal lands are illegally included in the exports since they add up to `` a lot of money very quickly,'' said <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Marke </PERSON> with the logs sitting there, people do n't look. `` You're talking about a serious amount of money being lost, either to the government or money being drained from the timber industry,'' <PERSON> Marker </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Sisco </PERSON> said: `` It's such big money, that is why the big companies have essentially closed their mills and they're into log exports now _ the log exports bring so much more money than the lumber would bring.'' He said that the Japanese pay `` at least three and four times'' the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> market price and that political pressure has blocked enforcement of the export ban on federal timber. Congressional pressure to enforce the ban `` is mounting,'' said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, D-Mont., who wants the annually renewed ban made permanent `` The most important reason why <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has not pressed on this is because, frankly, timber companies do not make one peep in support of proper enforcement of the export ban law. `` The same timber company that will argue about job losses because of environmental standards creates many, many times that job loss due to their exporting logs, which also happens to be a very profitable operation.'' A <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> report on job loss and law enforcement related to federal timber exports is due this month, and a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Banking subcommittee held hearings Nov. 7 on proposals by Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON>, R-Ore., to let states prohibit export of state-owned logs and to make the federal ban permanent `` Public lands should contribute to addressing public needs,'' <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldschmidt </PERSON> testified, adding there is a `` real timber supply need in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> right now.'' `` Timber that is harvested from our federal and state lands can make an important contribution to meeting this need,'' he said. `` Limiting exports is one positive way to do this while protecting other non-timber resources and saving American jobs.'' <PERSON> DeFazio </PERSON> and <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> have introduced companion measures in the House. The state-timber bill would legitimize <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> laws requiring in-state processing of logs, said a Packwood aide, <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON>. Meanwhile, in what prosecutors believe is the first trial of its kind, three <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> men are to go on trial Nov. 20 in <LOCATION> Helena </LOCATION> on charges of conspiring to export unprocessed federal logs to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tortorelli </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Bellevue </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Britz </PERSON> of Orting were indicted on charges in the shipment of 558,515 board-feet of timber from national forest in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>. `` There are only so many logs for our mills,'' said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunbar </PERSON>. `` If they are exporting logs illegally does n't that take away from the capability of <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> mills?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0001EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SouthAfrica-DeathRow     11-21 0754</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-South Africa-Death Row,0775</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mother of 10 Waits Alone on Death Row in South Africa</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SAHM VENTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAPE TOWN, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Were it not for one violent day in 1985, <PERSON> Evelina </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruin </PERSON> would be like countless other black South African women: an illiterate maid in her 50s, raised in a isolated farming district, mother of 10. Today, she is the only woman on Death Row _ alone, confused and ill. Her prison cell in <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION> is the farthest she's ever been from home. `` She can not eat, she ca n't sleep,'' said her lawyer, <PERSON> Andrea </PERSON> <PERSON> Durbach </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION>. `` It's a very dramatic thing to say, but I used to think to myself that she's just going to die of a broken heart.'' Mrs. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruin </PERSON> and 13 men were sentenced to death in May for the mob killing in November 1985 of a black policeman, <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> <PERSON> Sethwala </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Paballelo </LOCATION>, the black section of the remote northwestern town of <LOCATION> Upington </LOCATION>. Twenty-six people were tried for the killing, and four men were found to have physically contributed to the death of <PERSON> Sethwala </PERSON>, who was chased from his home, stoned, beaten and set afire. In addition to those four, Mrs. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruin </PERSON> and nine others were convicted of murder under the doctrine of `` common purpose,'' which holds them responsible because they were part of the crowd that sought to kill <PERSON> Sethwala </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sethwala </PERSON>'s death occurred at a time of nationwide black unrest. Hours before he was slain several thousand blacks gathered at a soccer field in <LOCATION> Paballelo </LOCATION> to protest rent increases and other grievances. After police dispersed the crowd with tear gas, about 300 people re-grouped around <LOCATION> Sethwala </LOCATION>'s home and threw stones to force him outside. Militant blacks have frequently attacked black policemen, accusing them of collaborating with the government and its apartheid policies. Mrs. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruin </PERSON> and her common-law husband, who also has been sentenced to death, were identified as having thrown stones at <PERSON> Sethwala </PERSON>'s house. According to the state's evidence, she allegedly yelled: `` The dog is in the house. Bring him out and burn him alive.'' Mrs. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruin </PERSON> testified during the trial that she and her husband went back to their own house after the protest meeting was broken up and were not present at <LOCATION> Sethwala </LOCATION>'s home. Mrs. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruin </PERSON>, who had no previous criminal record and worked for the same white family for 30 years, has little understanding of what is happening to her, Ms. <PERSON> Durbach </PERSON> said. Mrs. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruin </PERSON> suffers from arthritis, heart disease and has high blood pressure, the lawyer said. She does not know in what city her prison is and thinks she's been imprisoned for at least a year, when in fact it has been six months. She sees her husband for 30 minutes, once a month. They are separated by a window and communicate through microphones. Only three of her 10 children have been able to visit her, Ms. <PERSON> Durbach </PERSON> said. Because she can not read and is too ill to exercise, Mrs. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruin </PERSON> does little but listen to government-run radio that is piped into her cell, said Ms. <PERSON> Durbach </PERSON>, who visits her every three weeks. She has been treated well by the prison staff and has developed a good relationship with one of the guards, Ms. <PERSON> Durbach </PERSON> added. A judge ruled in September that the 14 people sentenced to death could appeal their sentences, but a bail request for Mrs. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruin </PERSON> was turned down. Two psychologists testified at her bail application that she had suffered mental and physical deterioration, including memory loss, since her imprisonment. Ms. <PERSON> Durbach </PERSON> said no date has been set for the appeal, but she hopes it could be early next year. In a similar mob killing, the Appeal Court, the country's highest court, last year upheld under the `` common purpose'' doctrine the death sentence of six blacks known as the `` Sharpeville Six. However, after a storm of domestic and international protest, then-President P.W. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> commuted their death sentences to lengthy prison terms. The last woman to be executed in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> was <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 25, who was of mixed race. She was hanged in June after being convicted of joining her boyfriend in the brutal knife murder of a teen-ager. More than 50 people, mostly black, have been executed so far this year, and more than 100 were hanged in each of the previous three years. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> and his successor, F.W. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>, have commuted 54 death sentences this year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0003EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador-Analysis     11-21 0974</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador-Analysis,1004</SECOND>
<HEAD>Guerrilla Offensive Achieves Several Objectives, but at High Cost</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A massive offensive left no doubt about the Salvadoran guerrillas' military capacity and drove home their point that serious negotiations and government concessions are necessary to end the 10-year-old civil war. And the killings of six Jesuit priests during the offensive galvanized opposition in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to continued aid for the rightist Salvadoran administration, which must be considered plus for the leftist rebels. But the <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> paid a high price for its achievements. They turned densely populated urban districts into battlefields, and the lives of tens of thousands of workers became a weeklong nightmare of death and destruction. Residents of <LOCATION> Soyapango </LOCATION>, Zacamil, <PERSON> Mejicanos </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ciudad </PERSON> <PERSON> Delgado </PERSON>, the humble neighborhoods devastated by the fighting that began Nov. 11, were angry at a government that sent warplanes to strafe and bomb guerrilla positions amid their homes. But those same residents seem to have saved most of their resentment for the rebels. `` We just want ` the boys' to leave, so we can go back to work and finish raising our children,'' said <PERSON> Porfirio </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> as he fled with his wife and two daughters from <PERSON> Zacamil </PERSON>. The guerrillas maintained fortified positions in and around a complex of low-income apartment blocks there for four days. Virtually the entire non-combatant population evacuated under fire. When it appeared most of the civilians had left, government forces subjected <PERSON> Zacamil </PERSON> to a six-hour barrage of bazookas, rockets and cannon fire that left the complex smoldering and practically ruined. `` I know women whose sons are with the guerrillas, and I see how they worry about their children and suffer when they are killed. They're human too. But because of them, we almost get killed. If they would not have come, this would not have happened,'' said <PERSON> Marta </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, sweeping her arm across her humble cinderblock <LOCATION> Soyapango </LOCATION> home hit by bullets and shrapnel. It is difficult to imagine that the rebels made many converts in neighborhoods where the fighting was heaviest, but guerrilla chief <PERSON> Facundo </PERSON> <PERSON> Guardado </PERSON>, interviewed at his command post near Mejicanos, said the display of strength, organization and morale was motivating adolescent men and women to `` incorporate themselves'' into the struggle. `` I hold the <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION> in high regard professionally,'' retired <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> Gen. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> last week. The war `` can not be resolved militarily,'' said <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON>, who drew up a strategic plan for the war in 1981 and was head of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> until the end of September. <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON> said the guerrillas can not be overcome until the roots of war _ unfair distribution of wealth and pervasive social injustice _ are addressed. In what appears to have been a response to the insurgent push, a squad of assassins murdered and mutilated six Jesuit priests and educators considered leftist ideologues by the country's rabid right. Two witnesses, who for the moment remain in hiding, reportedly saw men in army uniform commit the massacre. `` The time has arrived for President -LRB- <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> to make good on his promise to control those officials in his government and in his party who in a good measure are responsible for the civil war,'' Sen. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., said after the slayings `` In a time of reduced foreign aid, we must ask ourselves what it is we are achieving with the dollars we send,'' said Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>, D-Mass. But President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should not `` undermine a fragile democracy'' by withdrawing aid, and on Monday the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted narrowly against restricting military aid. But the debate was bitter and at times personal, and the issue had clearly become controversial again. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has provided more than $ 3.5 billion in economic and military aid to a succession of Salvadoran governments this decade. It is generally conceded, even by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, that the rebels would have won the war by 1985 had it not been for massive <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assistance. The guerrillas said this year they are willing to abandon armed struggle and convert the <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION> into a political party in exchange for sweeping political, economic and social reform. Rebel and government representatives sat down together in September and October to try to find a way toward peace. The government rejected the possibility of fundamental overhaul of the reigning system and limited its negotiating position to a demand that that the rebels lay down their arms and join `` the democratic process.'' When a bomb killed 10 unionists at a leftist labor federation, the rebels broke off talks. Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> late last week issued a call for truce and an exhortation to both sides to resume peace talks. <PERSON> Gregorio </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON>, auxiliary bishop of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, said both sides have agreed in principle to heed the Pope's call and to accept the church as mediator. `` But the means of working this out are complicated and causing us a lot of work,'' <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> said Sunday. The rebel offensive against the capital appeared all but over by early this week. It did not bring down the <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> government, but left it shaken. With the capital and several provincial cites besieged and paralyzed and a protracted standoff apparently the best the armed forces could manage, leaders of the country's business and industrial sectors reportedly talked with military and political elements about replacing the government with a provisional regime. Diplomats said discussion of such a change, whether peacefully or by a coup, was preliminary, a kind of worst-case contingency. But that it was talked about at all is another indication the guerrillas delivered a telling blow.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> <PERSON> Mine </PERSON> has covered the civil war in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> for two years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0013EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SitkaLighthouse     11-21 0707</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sitka Lighthouse,0731</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rockwell Lighthouse: Romantic Getaway on Southeast Alaska Coast</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRIAN S. AKRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SITKA, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A night's stay costs $ 160 if you use the hot tub, and summer reservations must be made months in advance, but once you're at <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lighthouse </ORGANIZATION>, the price and the wait seem a bargain. The privacy of the island lighthouse, its 360-degree view of <LOCATION> Sitka </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sound </LOCATION> and the peaceful symphony of waves and sea birds are enough to warm even the coldest of hearts. Since it was completed in 1985, <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lighthouse </ORGANIZATION> _ really a house although it does have a navigation light for sailors _ has been the site of 14 weddings, dozens of honeymoons and `` bunches of affairs,'' says owner <PERSON> Burgess </PERSON> <PERSON> Bauder </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bauder </PERSON> built it because he loves lighthouses and could n't figure what else to do with <LOCATION> Rockwell </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, a three-quarter-acre clump of rock, spruce and driftwood less than a mile from <LOCATION> Sitka </LOCATION>'s waterfront. He bought the island on speculation in 1973 for $ 3,000, then a decade later was unable to sell it at a profit. `` Thank God we did n't, because this has turned out better than any business venture,'' he said. <PERSON> Bauder </PERSON>, the town veterinarian and an occasional carpenter, began building the four-story, wood-frame structure in 1983. An architect provided a scale drawing in exchange for <PERSON> Bauder </PERSON> spaying his dog. Except for some help with the framing, <PERSON> Bauder </PERSON> did all the construction himself. The project raised some eyebrows in this scenic <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> fishing port and mill town about 90 miles south of <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION>. `` There were three people who through the grapevine told me that it was a potential eyesore because it was visible from all over town,'' <PERSON> Bauder </PERSON> recalled. `` And now it's the most photographed home in <LOCATION> Sitka </LOCATION>.'' In spite of virtually no advertising, <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lighthouse </ORGANIZATION> also has become the most hard-to-get overnight lodging in the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Panhandle </LOCATION>. It's open year-round, but summer reservations are recommended four to five months in advance. Most of next August already is booked. Although the lighthouse was built primarily as a romantic getaway, its little red beacon does aid mariners entering the island-studded sound. The Coast Guard even commissioned the building in July 1985, making it sort of an honorary lighthouse. The white-and-red lighthouse is a cozy escape from <LOCATION> Sitka </LOCATION>'s weather, which usually is wet and cool even in summer The interior walls are covered with cedar, black walnut, hemlock, fir. The spiral lattice staircase is handmade of Philippine mahogany. `` It's a cut above rustic,'' <PERSON> Bauder </PERSON> said modestly. There are all the amenities of home except a television. Do n't even think of asking <PERSON> Bauder </PERSON> if you can bring one `` I say if you want to watch television, why even go out there? The background music with the stereo system is an imperative to me, but the visual? You're inundated with the visual everywhere you look,'' <PERSON> Bauder </PERSON> said. The entire lighthouse rents for $ 125 per night for up to five people. The hot tub is an extra $ 35. Above the round living room is the tower with three small bedrooms, including an intimate cupola room with 10 picture windows affording the 360-degree view. The lighthouse boosted <PERSON> Bauder </PERSON>'s reputation for being somewhat eccentric, a description he savors. `` For sure,'' he said. `` Eccentric _ away from the center. But that's not by design. That's just who I am.'' The success of his island retreat has exceeded even <PERSON> Bauder </PERSON>'s expectations `` It is a romantic place,'' he said. `` It is private, it is beautiful. At the risk of paraphrasing <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Denver </PERSON>, it fills up your senses.'' In the living room is a collection of guest books, filled with the remembrances of hundreds of visitors. They tell of sunny views of volcanic <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Edgecumbe </LOCATION>, of nights spent weathering violent winter storms. Gushing newlyweds declare their love with words and little hearts. Would-be poets try their hand at verse. `` We can not tell you how much we enjoyed our stay _ the fog, the beautiful views, the eagle-watching,'' a <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> couple wrote. `` When we're back home in the terrible heat, we'll think of July in <LOCATION> Sitka </LOCATION> with the fireplace roaring.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Editor's Note: For reservation information, write to <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lighthouse </ORGANIZATION>, P.O. Box 277-A, <LOCATION> Sitka </LOCATION>, AK 99835.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0014EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Patrol     11-21 0853</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Patrol,0881</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israeli Soldiers Feel Mounting Frustration</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP Extra</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>^By NICOLAS B. TATRO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEACH CAMP, Occupied Gaza Strip (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Palestinian youths, unseen behind a row of tin-roofed shanties, showered a squad of <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers with stones and taunted them with curses. The Israelis, encumbered with automatic rifles, riot helmets and tear gas canisters, lumbered around a corner in pursuit, but the teen-agers had vanished. Musing about the elusiveness of the Palestinians, Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Ehud </PERSON> <PERSON> Gross </PERSON> chose a quotation from <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>'s `` Macbeth'': `` The earth has bubbles ... whither are they vanished?'' The soldiers' frustration at such encounters became quickly apparent as Gross, the army's chief education officer, gathered a dozen troops under a tree to talk about army orders limiting the use of force in battling the Palestinian uprising. `` I think our hands are tied. You can not do anything. You do n't fire because you're not allowed to,'' said Pvt <PERSON> Eitan </PERSON>, 21, cradling his riot helmet as he leaned on his Galil rifle. Defending the orders not to fire on stone throwers unless their lives were in danger, Gross asked, `` So, what's wrong with that?'' `` You do n't capture anyone. All day long you go around and around and you do n't catch anyone,'' said <PERSON> Eitan </PERSON>, whose full name could not be used in keeping with army regulations. As he spoke, stones smacked into the dirt near the gathering, first singly, then in flurries. Two soldiers stepped out of the semicircle and gave chase. They returned empty-handed. All the while there was whistling, which is used by Palestinian lookouts to signal that soldiers were in the camp. Gross asked if the soldiers believed they should be given more freedom to respond and what the consequences might be? A soldier wearing sunglasses argued that troublemakers _ `` those who deserve it'' _ should be punished, even beaten. `` I'm not saying shoot to kill but make it seriously painful for them and not give them two slaps on the face,'' he said. The army recently allowed soldiers to open fire with live ammunition against masked <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> activists who refused orders to halt. But most stone-throwers do n't wear masks. Other soldiers protested that tougher action would only increase the hostility of the population, escalate violence and undermine the morality of the army. `` They are limitations -LRB- on the use of force -RRB- because that's how we were educated. We were not educated to kill, especially women and children,'' said one soldier. `` We are a moral army.'' In the course of the two-year uprising, 615 Palestinians have been killed in encounters with Israelis, and 42 Israelis have been slain by Palestinians. Thousands on both sides have been wounded. Gross said pent-up desires for revenge were natural. `` It's not a shame to be angry and feel a tremendous urge to beat someone. But it's important to control yourself,'' he said. No matter what political solution emerged, <PERSON> Gross </PERSON> said, Israelis and Palestinians would have to live together. `` We have to try to avoid the expansion of circles of hate,'' he said. During the uprising, 530 officers and soldiers out of nearly 100,000 who have served in the occupied lands have been disciplined for overstepping the often-ambiguous limits on the use of force, army officials say. Punishment, criticized by liberals for being inadequate, has ranged from loss of pay, vacation or rank to a maximum jail term of two years. A captain, speaking at a <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> military base, unbuttoned his shirt pocket to reveal a wad of written orders. One booklet stresses soldiers have `` no right to use force in order to punish'' and that army units should not humiliate the Arab population or damage property. The captain, also named <PERSON> Eitan </PERSON>, conceded some violations go unreported because officers are reluctant to undermine morale by reporting the misdeeds of their soldiers. `` Basically, we rely on the humanity of the soldiers and the commanders,'' he said. During the three-hour patrol in the Beach Camp, where 41,000 Palestinian refugees live along the sandy <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> shoreline, soldiers walked dirt streets alongside open sewers and squeezed down passageways so narrow they could n't carry their rifles sideways. The patrol first encountered hostile looks, then stones and curses. The soldiers aimed their rifles threateningly but did not fire. Before the patrol began, there were no signs of unrest and the open-air market was jammed with shoppers. `` The calm appears real, but in fact -LRB- the <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> -RRB- had created a private army inside, with masked people walking around in the daylight. They started to run the daily life and soon they would have appeared with weapons,'' said Lt. Col. <PERSON> Bouzi </PERSON>, a unit commander interviewed in a tent encampment nearby. He said his soldiers had wounded 30 Palestinians with plastic bullets in efforts to establish order during the unit's first week in Beach Camp. He also criticized a previous unit that refrained from entering the camp because of the outward calm. `` With all due respect to the quiet, if you do n't get in once or twice a day and show them that we can go there whenever we want, they will take the initiative.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0445EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--MethadoneDeath     11-21 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Methadone Death,0187</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Orders Mental Exam For Mother Who Gave Daughter Methadone</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PROVIDENCE, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman charged with killing her 5-year-old daughter by giving her a heroin substitute to stop persistent coughing was ordered to undergo evaluation at the state <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION>. Chief Judge <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> DeRobbio </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Monday also set Nov. 27 as a bail hearing for <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, 41, of <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION>. Police said <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> gave methadone to her daughter, <PERSON> Shanna </PERSON>, because she was irritated with the child's cough. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> told police she gave <PERSON> Shanna </PERSON> 10 milligrams of the drug Friday because a friend told her it would help the girl's cold. <PERSON> Shanna </PERSON> died later in the day. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> was undergoing counseling at a treatment center for drug addicts, according to court papers. She received the methadone from the center as a `` weekend dose,'' she told police. Like heroin, methadone is a depressant narcotic that slows the heart and respiratory system. <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwab </PERSON>, a spokesman at the <ORGANIZATION> Rhode </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Poison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> said a normal adult dose is from 2 -LCB- to 10 milligrams.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0031EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-PressForPoles     11-21 0177</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Press For Poles,0179</SECOND>
<HEAD>French Daily Offers Polish Paper Old Printing Press</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The respected <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> daily <ORGANIZATION> Le </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monde </ORGANIZATION> has agreed to loan an old rotary printing press to the independent Polish daily <ORGANIZATION> Gazeta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wyborcza </ORGANIZATION> free of charge for a decade. <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Michnik </PERSON>, editor of the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> paper that began publishing in May and now has a circulation of 500,000, signed the contract Monday with <PERSON> Andre </PERSON> <PERSON> Fontaine </PERSON>, editor of <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Monde </PERSON>. The French paper revised its format last September and began printing at an ultra-modern facility in a <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> suburb. Under the agreement, <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Monde </PERSON> also will loan <ORGANIZATION> Gazeta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wyborcza </ORGANIZATION> some modern photogravure equipment. The old press, capable of printing up to 55,000 copies an hour, served <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Monde </PERSON> for more than 25 years. The $ 300,000 cost of dismantling and moving the machine to <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> will be paid for through a special subscription drive. Before signing the contract, <PERSON> Michnik </PERSON> pinned a Solidarity pin on <PERSON> Fontaine </PERSON>'s lapel and the French editor recalled an article <PERSON> Michnik </PERSON> had written for the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> daily when Solidarity was outlawed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0012EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Bush-Broncos 1stLd-Writethru   11-21 0197</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Broncos, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0695,150</SECOND>
<HEAD>Neat-o! Bush Poses For Photo With Denver Football Players</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS last graf with score, 14-10 Denver</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told a elementary school class Monday that some of the `` fun stuff'' he gets to do for being leader of the free world includes getting his picture snapped with famous football players. On this occasion, the location was <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The team was <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. The famous player was <ORGANIZATION> Broncos </ORGANIZATION> quarterback <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Elway </PERSON>. Later, in a meeting with fifth graders at <ORGANIZATION> Pickard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was asked how he liked being president. `` You know what I got to do? Some of the boys are going to be interested. Just before I came here, I got to meet the quarterback for the <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broncos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Football </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Team </ORGANIZATION> and I know <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Ditka </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Bears coach -RRB- ... so I get some fun stuff to do in sports.'' Also attending the picture-taking session were <ORGANIZATION> Bronocs </ORGANIZATION> owner <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowlen </PERSON>, general manager <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Beake </PERSON>, coach <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Reeves </PERSON> and defensive safety <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. With <PERSON> Elway </PERSON> sitting out the game because of an attack of stomach flu, the <ORGANIZATION> Broncos </ORGANIZATION> defeated the <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Redskins </ORGANIZATION> 14-10 Monday night in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0040EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-FrenchChefs     11-21 0620</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-French Chefs,0635</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bocuse, Robuchon and Girardet Named ``Chefs of Century.''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUZY PATTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Superstar French chefs <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Bocuse </PERSON> and <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Robuchon </PERSON>, and the Swiss <PERSON> Fredy </PERSON> <PERSON> Girardet </PERSON> have been named `` chefs of the century'' by the Gault-Millau guidebook. The honor also was a return to grace for <PERSON> Bocuse </PERSON> because the quide gave him back his fourth toque or chef's hat. The toque is <PERSON> Gault-Millau </PERSON>'s symbol for excellence and <PERSON> Bocuse </PERSON> was demoted to three toques by last year's guide. According to the guidebook's president and editor, <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> Millau </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bocuse </PERSON>'s problem last year was turning out the same basic menu for years, while other chefs were getting ahead with new ideas. Known as the `` emperor of cuisine,'' <PERSON> Bocuse </PERSON> also was criticized for traveling around the world rather than tending to his stock pots at his restaurant near <LOCATION> Lyon </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bocuse </PERSON> accused <PERSON> Millau </PERSON> of always bringing his dog to the restaurant and not asking for the bill. But the spat simmered down as <LOCATION> Millau </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Bocuse </PERSON> kissed and made up. `` I was very happy to be named a chef of the century, and we've settled our differences,'' said <PERSON> Bocuse </PERSON> `` But the century is n't over yet,'' he added `` I think there's room for more of us up there.'' He said he was flattered to be in the company of two legendary chefs who were posthumously named `` chefs of the century:'' <PERSON> Auguste </PERSON> <PERSON> Escoffier </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fernand </PERSON> <PERSON> Point </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Escoffier </PERSON> was the master of us all,'' said <PERSON> Bocuse </PERSON>. `` And Point was the first chef-owner, who ran his own show. Before that chefs were hidden away, as restaurants were owned by maitre d's or entrepreneurs.'' `` <PERSON> Bocuse </PERSON> deserves his place at the top,'' said <PERSON> Millau </PERSON>, who said his guidebook was celebrating its 20th anniversary. `` He is an exceptional personality who has done more than anybody else to promote French cuisine abroad.'' `` But I consider <PERSON> Robochon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Girardet </PERSON> more creative and visionary chefs,'' added <LOCATION> Millau </LOCATION>. `` Especially <PERSON> Robuchon </PERSON>, who has known how to marry traditional cuisine with new tastes.'' <PERSON> Robuchon </PERSON> made quite a name for himself by bringing back the mashed potato as a gourmet favorite _ on menus with other specialties like sweet-sour `` migononettes'' of venison and hot foie gras with cream of lentils. All three `` chefs of the century'' are regularly awarded the top three stars in the <ORGANIZATION> Michelin </ORGANIZATION>, considered the bible of guidebooks. <PERSON> Gault-Millau </PERSON>, nearly as well-known in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> as the <ORGANIZATION> Michelin </ORGANIZATION>, has a circulation of about 200,000 versus 720,000 for the <ORGANIZATION> Michelin </ORGANIZATION>, the venerable guidebook that was first published in 1900. <PERSON> Gault-Millau </PERSON> is avidly read for its picturesque and peppery commentaries, a different style from the <ORGANIZATION> Michelin </ORGANIZATION>, whose terse listing is a very serious reference for gastronomes in a country that takes its gastronomy seriously. At least 1,200 French chefs and 15,000 guests packed an exhibition hall last week at the futuristic <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Defense </LOCATION> area west of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> for the Gault-Millau awards followed by a tasting of regional food and wines. `` I have special prizes for our top chefs,'' announced <LOCATION> Millau </LOCATION>, `` provided they promise not to eat them.'' He presented each with a live Bresse rooster, a symbol of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> raised in the region known for producing its most succulent poultry. <PERSON> Bocuse </PERSON> looked his fowl right in the eye, claiming to hypnotize it. In the highest category of four toques and a grade of 19.5 out of 20 <ORGANIZATION> Gault-Millau </ORGANIZATION> listed 13 restaurants for 1990, adding three new establishments: the Auberge de l'Eridon at <LOCATION> Annecy </LOCATION>, the Auberge de l'Ill, at <LOCATION> Illhaeusern </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Alsace </LOCATION> and the Cote d'Or at <LOCATION> Saulieu </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Burgundy </LOCATION> country. No restaurants fell from the four-toque category this year, but three famous gourmet meccas were demoted from three toques to two: Le Grand Vefour, <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON> and <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Maree </PERSON>, all in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0020EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w BC-SenateSalvadorRollCall     11-21 0369</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Senate Salvador Roll Call,300</SECOND>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the 58-39 roll call by which the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Monday killed an amendment to place restrictions on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. On this vote, a yes vote was a vote to table, or kill, the restrictions. Voting yes were 18 Democrats and 40 Republicans. Voting no were 35 Democrats and 4 Republicans. xxx denotes senators not voting. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, D-Wash., no; <ORGANIZATION> Armstrong </ORGANIZATION>, R-Colo., yes; <PERSON> Baucus </PERSON>, D-Mont., no; <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, D-Del., no; <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.M. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Mo </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., xxx; <PERSON> Boschwitz </PERSON>, R-Minn., yes; <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Breaux </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON>, D-Nev., xxx; <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Burdick </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.D. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>, R-Mont., yes; <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-R.I. </LOCATION>, yes; Coats, R-Ind., yes; <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON>, R-Miss., yes; <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Maine </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.D. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Mo </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Daschle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.D. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ariz </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Ill., yes; Dodd, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan., yes; <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.M. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>, R-Minn., yes; <PERSON> Exon </PERSON>, D-Neb., yes; <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, D-Ky., no; <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON>, D-Ga., yes; <PERSON> Garn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, xxx; <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, D-Tenn., no; <PERSON> Gorton </PERSON>, R-Wash., yes; <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Grassley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Iowa </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, R-Ore., no; <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON>, D-Ala., yes; <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON>, R-Pa., yes; <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.C. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON>, R-Vt., no; <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Kassebaum </PERSON>, R-Kan., yes; <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON>, R-Wis., yes; <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., no; <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON>, D-Neb., no; <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>, D-Mass., no; <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Wis </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt., no; <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Mich </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Lieberman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Lott </PERSON>, R-Miss., yes; <PERSON> Lugar </PERSON>, R-Ind., yes; <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Fla </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Matsunaga </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> McClure </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Idaho </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> McConnell </PERSON>, R-Ky., yes; <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Mikulski </PERSON>, D-Md., no; <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Moynihan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Murkowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Nickles </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Okla </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., yes; <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON>, R-Ore., yes; <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Pressler </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-S.D. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Reid </PERSON>, D-Nev., yes; <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>, D-Mich., no; <PERSON> Robb </PERSON>, D-Va., yes; <ORGANIZATION> Rockefeller </ORGANIZATION>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Del </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Sanford </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.C. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Sarbanes </PERSON>, D-Md., no; <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Tenn </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Shelby </PERSON>, D-Ala., yes;
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TurkeyFarm     11-21 0389</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Turkey Farm,0402</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farmer Turns to Turkeys for Added Profits</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT LEE ZIMMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WELDON, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Turkeys are topical right now, but farmers say <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s growing preoccupation with health has turned the birds into a year-round money-maker. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Twist </PERSON>, who has 8,000 Toms fattening up for market, says he's learned turkeys are quite a bit smarter than most people think. `` They're very sociable ... docile and interested when people come in here,'' said Twist. `` The old wives' tales we heard were n't true _ they're intelligent and we enjoy them. So do consumers. Per capita consumption of turkeys has risen from 8.5 pounds in 1975 to 17 pounds a year in 1989. `` People are seeing turkey as a healthy, economical alternative to red meat,'' said <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Turkey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION>. `` There also are a lot more products available, and that's what people want _ variety and convenience.'' Whole turkeys still are popular for holidays like Thanksgiving and Christmas, but the real growth in the <LOCATION> turkey </LOCATION> industry has been with products like <LOCATION> turkey </LOCATION> ham, hot dogs, sausage, bacon and fresh breast cutlets. Farmers raised 164 million turkeys in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1982, and the flock increased to 255 million birds this year. Twist, whose turkeys end up in hospital meals and fast-food turkey sandwiches, expects to raise about 80,000 of the birds this year. The Twist family has been farming in <LOCATION> DeWitt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> since 1852. Chickens were added to the grain farm in 1969 and commercial egg production began in 1973. Twist said turkeys seemed a perfect way to balance the fluctuations in egg and grain markets. `` It's one area of our business where we do n't have to listen to the noon news to see if we're profitable,'' said Twist, who raises the turkeys for <ORGANIZATION> Trevcam </ORGANIZATION>, a company based in <LOCATION> Forrest </LOCATION>. Young turkeys hatched by the company are shipped to Twist's starter building, where they are fed and kept warm for eight weeks They then move to the two 50 - by 480-foot finishing buildings, where they eat a corn-soybean mixture, reaching market weight of about 27 pounds in a total of 18 weeks They are slaughtered and processed in <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>. Twist said he is paid 9 cents a pound for the finished birds, and it costs about 3 cents to raise them.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0445EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Plane-Winds     11-21 0109</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Plane-Winds,0111</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jetliner Lifted by High Winds</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEWARK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gusts up to 64 mph lifted a parked <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jetliner and dropped it on a baggage cart and fuel truck, authorities said. One minor injury was reported. The <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727's nose landed on the baggage cart at <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> on Monday night and the right wing came down on a fuel truck, said Police Officer <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Gato </PERSON>. There were no passengers on the plane but a worker inside the craft's baggage area was injured, said Gato. The man was taken to <ORGANIZATION> Elizabeth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, where emergency room officials said he was in good condition.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     11-21 0598</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0620</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Little Mermaid' Wins `Animation Showdown'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HORN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Disney's `` The Little Mermaid'' slithered by <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>'s `` All Dogs Go to Heaven'' at the box office last weekend in the animation showdown of the year. The weekend's top film, though, was <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s self-congratulatory `` <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> Nights,'' according to figures released Monday `` The Little Mermaid,'' which some critics have labeled an instant classic, finished in third place in its premiere weekend, setting a record for an animated film with a per-screen average of $ 6,068 a theater, <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> said. Its opening weekend of $ 6.1 million was 50 percent better than last year's `` Oliver and <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>,'' which became the all-time top-grossing animated film with a domestic gate of $ 53.3 million. <PERSON> Disney </PERSON> said half of `` Mermaid's'' viewers were adults and teen-agers unaccompanied by children. `` Harlem Nights,'' which bears the distinction of mentioning its star's name five times in the opening credits, was the third-biggest Thanksgiving-Christmas release ever, taking in $ 16.1 million last weekend. The biggest fall films are `` Rocky IV,'' which debuted with $ 20 million in 1985 and `` Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home,'' which collected $ 16.9 million in 1986. Overall business for last weekend's top 10 films was $ 52 million, up 47 percent from a year ago, <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> said. `` Look Who's Talking,'' the love-over-diapers comedy featuring <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Travolta </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Kirstie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alley </LOCATION> and the voice of <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON>, landed in second last weekend with $ 8.5 million. Down 25 percent from the previous week, `` Look Who's Talking'' nonetheless passed $ 85 million. The ensemble drama `` Steel Magnolias'' finished in fourth with $ 5.4 million and a strong per-screen average of $ 11,303 in a somewhat limited release. The film stars <PERSON> Dolly </PERSON> <PERSON> Parton </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> <PERSON> Field </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> MacLaine </PERSON>, among others. In fifth was `` All Dogs Go to Heaven,'' the new animated film from <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Bluth </PERSON>. Featuring the voice of <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>, `` All Dogs'' opened to $ 4.7 million. Its per-screen average was $ 2,988. `` Dad,'' the drama starring <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Lemmon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Danson </PERSON>, fell 30 percent to sixth place on receipts of $ 3.1 million. In seventh was `` Prancer,'' the story of a wounded reindeer who may _ or may not _ be traveling with a big guy in a red suit. `` Prancer'' grossed $ 2.9 million. `` The Bear'' was eighth with $ 2.8 million; `` Crimes and Misdemeanors'' finished ninth with $ 1.5 million; and `` Staying Together'' plummeted to 10th with $ 939,208, down 54 percent from last week. Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> and Exhibitor Relations Co. Figures are based on a combination of actual box-office receipts and studio projections where actual figures are not immediately available. 1. `` Harlem Nights,'' Paramount, $ 16.1 million weekend gross, 2,180 screens, $ 7,384 per screen, $ 16.1 million total gross, one week in release. 2. `` Look Who's Talking,'' Tri-Star, $ 8.5 million, 1,651 screens, $ 5,171 per screen, $ 85.1 million, six weeks. 3. `` The Little Mermaid,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 6.1 million, 994 screens, $ 6,068 per screen, $ 6.1 million, one week. 4. `` Steel Magnolias,'' Tri-Star, $ 5.4 million, 480 screens, $ 11,303 per screen, $ 5.4 million, one week. 5. `` All Dogs Go to Heaven,'' <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 4.7 million, 1,577 screens, $ 2,988 per screen, $ 4.7 million, one week. 6. `` Dad,'' Universal, $ 3.1 million, 1,123 screens, $ 2,800 per screen, $ 10.8 million, four weeks. 7. `` Prancer,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.9 million, 1,713 screens, $ 1,701 per screen, $ 2.9 million, one week. 8. `` The Bear,'' Tri-Star, $ 2.8 million, 1,054 screens, $ 2,648 per screen, $ 20.1 million, four weeks. 9. `` Crimes and Misdemeanors,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.5 million, 503 screens, $ 2,884 per screen, $ 11.1 million, six weeks. 10. `` Staying Together,'' <ORGANIZATION> Hemdale </ORGANIZATION>, $ 939,208, 1,004 screens, $ 935 per screen, $ 3.4 million, two weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     11-21 0333</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0348</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHETOPA, Kan. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Willard </PERSON> <PERSON> Warwick </PERSON> does n't need a calendar to know when report cards are out at <ORGANIZATION> Chetopa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. Within hours, pupils are lined up at his store. For the past 28 years, he has handed out bags of apples at his grocery store in this southeast <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> town of 1,700 people for pupils from kindergarten to eighth grade who receive an `` A'' in math. `` It's appreciation for the kids who have worked hard in math,'' he said. `` A lot of kids have worked pretty hard to get a bag of those apples.'' <PERSON> Warwick </PERSON> estimates he gives away 120 pounds of apples each quarter _ 480 pounds a year. By Christmas, <ORGANIZATION> Warwick </ORGANIZATION> will have given away more than 6.5 tons of apples to students over the years. The first year he gave away the apples, <ORGANIZATION> Warwick </ORGANIZATION>'s daughter was in the first grade. Now <PERSON> Cynda </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarrett </PERSON> is the mother of two apple-winning children and the school's second-grade teacher. Her son, <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>, a kindergartner, was one of the newest apple winners. He was nonchalant about his A when his mother asked him how he earned the high mark. `` Do n't ask me. I do n't know. Ask my brain,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>, it pays to sort your newspapers, cans and bottles correctly. <PERSON> Bernice </PERSON> <PERSON> Harbin </PERSON> did, and became the first $ 100 winner in the city's recycling trash lottery. To boost interest and increase participation in the voluntary recycling program, the city is giving away $ 100 a day for 20 days. Winners are picked at random from a list of the 100,000 residences that received green recycling bins. Ms. <PERSON> Harbin </PERSON> was in front of her home Monday when a city worker pulled up and checked her recycling bins. `` He said, ` Hey, I think you're a winner,''' Ms. <PERSON> Harbin </PERSON> said. The 20 winners will be eligible for a Dec. 16 grand prize drawing. The prize will create more items to recycle: a $ 1,000 grocery store certificate.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-StelloNomination     11-21 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stello Nomination,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Set Back in Battle for Nuclear Weapons Nominee</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Stello </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> will get another chance in January to plead his case to head the government's nuclear weapons production program, following the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's failure to win quick <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> announced Monday it would not act on the nomination before the holiday recess, which is expected to start before Thanksgiving. Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., the committee chairman, said more time was needed to analyze newly received documentation on Stello, who appeared before the panel last Wednesday <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> said further hearings on Stello would be held after <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> returns Jan. 22. `` We have an incomplete record now,'' <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Stello </PERSON> did not return a reporter's telephone call Monday after <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>'s announcement. Energy Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, in an unusual personal appeal to the committee at Stello's confirmation hearing last week, said he urgently needed a confirmed chief of nuclear weapons production to carry out needed reforms. In a statement issued on Monday, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said <PERSON> Stello </PERSON>'s nomination was `` one of my top priorities'' and said he expected him to be confirmed when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> reconvenes `` I am certain that additional hearings will prove that the accusations raised in the waning hours of this session are those same accusations investigated years ago and resolved,'' <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said. There was no indication Monday whether the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> would install Stello in the job temporarily for one year by making an appointment while <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is in recess. <PERSON> Stello </PERSON> said last week he told <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> he would prefer not to accept a temporary appointment. Stello's opponents, led by <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sens </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, believe <PERSON> Stello </PERSON> is not sufficiently committed to nuclear safety. Stello strongly denied this and vowed to carry out <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>' orders to improve management of the nuclear weapons complex. Some committee Republicans, including Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCain </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, have accused Democrats of politically motivated delay tactics in order to kill the nomination. But Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, ranking Republican on the panel, said Monday the decision to hold further hearings was a `` fallback procedure.'' This should not be interpreted `` as a weakness in support ... in this nominee's chances of winning confirmation,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> said, adding he did not expect the January hearings to `` produce anything new that we have n't heard'' about Stello. <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> U.S.A. </ORGANIZATION>, an environmental group that has spearheaded a campaign to defeat the nomination, praised the committee's decision to postpone a vote. `` We managed to beat back enormous White House pressure'' to quickly confirm Stello, said <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwartz </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> legislative coordinator. `` It's the right move by the committee.'' Stello technically is still employed by the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, where he holds the title of executive director of operations. But he has been working full-time for <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> since July as an adviser on preparations for the restart of the department's idled <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> nuclear reactors.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r e BC-Opera     11-21 0485</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Opera,0508</SECOND>
<HEAD>Met Opera Presents `Hoffmann'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Stands for PMs.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soprano <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Welting </PERSON>, not heard at the Metropolitan Opera since its 1981 -'82 season, returned to sing a part she sang that season, <PERSON> Olympia </PERSON>, the mechanical doll in Offenbach's `` The Tales of <PERSON> Hoffmann </PERSON> She was a delight, singing the coloratura lightly, beautifully and acting amusingly, charmingly. Miss Welting's doll does n't stay in the same mood throughout Act 1. She gets increasingly aggressive, flailing her arms at people, swinging <PERSON> Hoffmann </PERSON> too fast in the dance, then clasping her hands around his neck to swing him, in a veritable stranglehold. Sometimes, the Met casts the same soprano in all of <PERSON> Hoffmann </PERSON>'s tales The most recent was Dame <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutherland </PERSON>. On Monday night, in the opera's first presentation this season, three women sang the parts. <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Lima </PERSON> was singing <PERSON> Hoffmann </PERSON> for the first time at the Met. <PERSON> Hoffmann </PERSON>'s voice should be produced fully, with strong tone and resonance. <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> did that, but in Act 1 he sometimes seemed to be trying to make up for difficult high notes by increasing volume. In Act 2, he sounded vocally strained and tired, but he did n't sound tired anymore in Act 3. Altogether, it was a good job. <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Montague </PERSON>, from <LOCATION> Winchester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION>, who made her Met debut in 1987, was splendid as <PERSON> Hoffmann </PERSON>'s friend Nicklausse. In men's clothes, she still looked feminine, but that did n't matter. Her singing was clear, flexible and appealing. <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dam </PERSON> sang all four villains. He sang well but chose a path of subtlety which meant the audience missed the malevolence which makes the opera chilling. This especially was evident in his aria in <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION>, presented by the Met _ but not everywhere _ as Act 2. <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Forst </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Westminster </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, sang <PERSON> Giulietta </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION> courtesan. She sang well but did n't sound seductive. The third act's <PERSON> Antonia </PERSON>, originally announced to be <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Blegen </PERSON>, was sung by <PERSON> Myra </PERSON> <PERSON> Merritt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> D.C </ORGANIZATION>. Her voice is lovely, but she did n't build the drama of this most dramatic of the tales. Both Miss <PERSON> Forst </PERSON> and Miss <PERSON> Merritt </PERSON> sounded more like singers being serious than like the characters they portrayed. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaasch </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, made his Met debut as the physicist in Act 1. He sounds like a tenor of much promise and, despite his white <PERSON> Einstein </PERSON> wig, capered with unusually youthful agility, adding to the act's merriment. <PERSON> Sylvain </PERSON> <PERSON> Cambreling </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Amiens </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, conducted, and the orchestra sounded marvelous. This production was new in 1982. Act 1 is in a big room with a magical back wall of perpetual motion machines, but Acts 2 and 3 are gloomy. Act 3 is even darker than at first. No longer can the picture of <PERSON> Antonia </PERSON>'s mother be seen to become a real person who sings. Now it becomes darker and singing comes from that direction.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     11-21 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0025</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Up In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 36,059.87, up 166.29 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     11-21 0947</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,920</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chemical Industry Group Says Fungicides Help Keep Prices Down</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A ban on the use of crop fungicides would cause consumer food prices to rise by 13 percent and the supply of fruits, vegetables and peanuts to decline by 24 percent, a farm chemical trade association says. No total ban on fungicides has been proposed, and the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said none is in the works. But <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Vroom </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemicals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said he wanted to call attention to the `` enormous benefit and the very small risk'' that result from the use of fungicides and other high-tech farming methods on food supplies. `` In my view, the debate regarding the safety of our food is almost totally risk-dominated,'' <PERSON> Vroom </PERSON> said. `` There is precious little mentioned about the benefit side of the equation.'' An economic study showing the effects of a ban on fungicides _ chemicals applied to crops, particularly fruit and vegetable, to prevent plant diseases _ was released by the association at a news conference Monday. The study, paid for by the association, was done by <ORGANIZATION> GRC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economics </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, consulting subsidiary of <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Knowlton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>'s spokesman on pesticides, <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Heier </PERSON>, commented, `` We have always been concerned about fungicides, but we're not going to cancel all of them.'' He noted federal law requires the agency to balance benefits against risks when judging any pesticides and said the agency adheres to that mandate. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Urbanchuk </PERSON>, senior vice president and director of economics for the consulting firm, said, `` If fungicides were eliminated, you the consumer would pay more for lower-quality produce. You would find that many fruits and vegetables no longer look or taste the same as before, and they would cost much more.'' For example, he said, crops hit hardest with price increases would include popular salad bar items such as carrots, which would rise 80 percent; lettuce, 40 percent; tomatoes, 40 percent; and onions, 34 percent. Prices of other major crops also would go up sharply, he said. Peanuts and peanut butter would rise 68 percent; peaches, 37 percent; and potatoes, 37 percent. `` Some foods may not be available at all,'' <PERSON> Urbanchuk </PERSON> said. `` If fungicides were no longer used by American farmers, consumers would not have bananas to slice on their morning meal, and children may not have peanut butter for their lunch sandwiches.'' Production of fruits would decline by 32 percent, vegetables by 21 percent, peanuts by 68 percent, and the major grains such as corn and wheat by 6 percent, he said. <PERSON> Urbanchuk </PERSON> said in his statement that poorer families would suffer the most by not being able to afford higher prices for fruits and vegetables. <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Lefferts </PERSON> of the Center for Science in the Public Interest said she had not studied the chemical industry's report and had no comment on the study's specific figures. But, she said, the current way of growing food with large amounts of fungicides and other chemicals `` is n't the only way to do it.'' In fact, she added, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> recently reported on alternate ways of farming to reduce the contamination of soil, water and air by cutting back on chemicals. `` We're confident, and so is the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>, that we can produce foods profitably and competitively using far fewer fungicides and other pesticides,'' <PERSON> Lefferts </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. `` The most telling statistic would be not how much reduced fungicide use would cost consumers, but how much it would cost the chemical industry,'' she said. Fungicides represent about $ 370 million or 7.4 percent of the $ 5 billion-a-year farm chemicals industry, association officials said. An advisory board for the study included representatives of the association, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wheat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Growers </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Processors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Fertilizer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, Resources for the Future and the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Cason </PERSON>, turned away by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> for a top environmental job in the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, has asked the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to withdraw his nomination. The action effectively ends an eight-month battle between President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and environmentalists over the controversial nominee for assistant secretary of agriculture for natural resources and the environment. `` Withdrawal of this nomination is a great disappointment,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>, who announced <PERSON> Cason </PERSON>'s request on Monday `` The lobbying effort against him was both misguided and unfair.'' There was no immediate responses from the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, which never wavered in its support of <LOCATION> Cason </LOCATION> despite repeated requests from individual senators to withdraw the nomination. <PERSON> Cason </PERSON> was opposed by the <ORGANIZATION> Sierra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Wilderness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Voters </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. The groups alleged that <PERSON> Cason </PERSON>'s record in several top <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> positions during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration showed favoritism toward private development of public lands, despite environmental concerns. Sen. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, worked to defeat <PERSON> Cason </PERSON> after his committee sent the nomination to the floor on a 12-7 vote The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> sent the nomination back to the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Friday and asked that it not be resubmitted. It was the first rejection of a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> nominee by the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> since <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> was voted down as defense secretary in March.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Catfish farmers have boosted production sharply from a year ago, and their prices have dropped almost as much. Production in October was estimated at 31.7 million pounds, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Monday. That was up 21 percent from 26.2 million pounds a year earlier. Prices received by growers averaged 64 cents per pound. That was down 19 percent from 79 cents in October 1988.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0214EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Regan'sTurn     11-21 0531</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Regan's Turn,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Renewing an Argument With the Boss' Wife</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> is getting the last word _ or at least the latest _ in his little tiff with <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> over which one of them did more damage to <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s presidency. In a review of Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s book, `` My Turn,'' the former White House chief of staff says his former boss' wife `` seems incapable of understanding how her words and deeds might seem selfish, hypocritical and, indeed, even frightening to those on the outside.'' `` Very sadly ... this book gives aid and comfort to those who still believe that <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> never should have been elected president in the first place,'' <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> said. His review, in the December issue of Washingtonian magazine, also replied to Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s criticism of his disclosure in his memoirs that she had come to rely on the advice of an astrologer for scheduling <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s activities. Wrote she: `` It never, ever, occurred to me that <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> would do what he did _ that he would take this information about my interest in astrology and twist it to seek his revenge on <PERSON> Ronnie </PERSON> on me.'' Wrote he, in his review: `` Frankly, I hesitated before putting this astounding fact into the historical record. I certainly did not ` take this information ... and twist it to seek ... revenge.' `` The fact is, I wrote about astrology because it was an essential truth about the way the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> operated. My description of White House life in my period as chief of staff would have made little sense if I had omitted it.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> minimized her dependence on astrology _ saying she called the astrologer only once or twice a month _ but <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> said astrology played a significant role in shaping the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> presidency. `` It was a daily, sometimes hourly, factor in every decision affecting the president's schedule,'' he wrote. `` He _ or in this case she _ who controls the president's schedule controls the workings of the presidency.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> wrote that she urged her husband to fire <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> after `` a stream of high government officials and congressional leaders'' came to her with the same message: <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> had poor relations with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the press, was restricting access to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, was intimidating subordinates. Anyway, she said, <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> deserved to be fired because the Iran-Contra affair occurred `` on his watch.'' <PERSON> Regan </PERSON>, for his part, said, `` It apparently never registers with the former first lady that ... she damages her husband and his presidency'' in the way her book acidly criticizes many of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s closest advisers, including <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Stockman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>. `` After all,'' he wrote, `` these were <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s choices, made after close consultation with his financial and political supporters and friends in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>; he must have thought that they met his own standards.'' His conclusion: `` <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> both have written for the historical record. Others will no doubt do the same; and to that end, history, that greatest of all polygraphs, will makes its judgment. I am comfortable with that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-CongressRdp 6thLd-Writethru a0417 11-21 1060</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Congress Rdp, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0417,890</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Congressional Leaders Reach Deal on Deficit-Cutting Bill</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Tops with 7 grafs, agreement reached on deficit reduction bill;
picks up 3rd graf pvs, House and; This should stand for AMs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Congressional negotiators reached agreement on a $ 14.8 billion deficit-reduction package for this year early Tuesday and leaders of both parties predicted the measure would be quickly approved by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and signed by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The deal would bring to a close a partisan budget standoff that has lasted most of the year. `` It will pass overwhelmingly, I think, in both bodies, because it's a pretty good'' package, said Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Frenzel </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Minn </LOCATION>., ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> `` It is a very strong, effective deficit reduction package,'' <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, told his colleagues. Leaders scheduled votes on the agreement in both chambers on Tuesday. Senate Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> said he had been told by <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> and budget director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> `` the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> will support this package.'' The package includes about $ 5.7 billion in new tax revenues, as well as a collection of spending reductions and accounting changes that result in lowered spending this year. It also claims $ 4.6 billion in savings by leaving cuts in federal programs imposed by the Gramm-Rudman deficit-reduction law in effect through the first week of February. Those cuts were triggered on Oct. 1 when <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and lawmakers failed to reach a budget-cutting deal. <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders from both parties held meeting after meeting through the day on the two biggest unfinished pieces of the puzzle _ deficit reduction bill and a repeal or scale-back of Medicare catastrophic health insurance. The health plan, designed to prevent retirees from being financially ruined by major illness, was passed last year with strong bipartisan support and was considered one of the last major achievements of <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s presidency. But <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> was forced to rethink the legislation this year because of a storm of protest from the wealthy elderly, who would be taxed up to $ 800 a year to cover their new benefits. The House on Sunday, on a 349-57 vote, reaffirmed its position that the entire law should be scrapped, surtax and benefits together. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, however, favors a plan to scale back the benefits enough to drop the surtax in exchange for a small annual premium. The two chambers resumed negotiations Monday in hopes of a compromise. Another `` must-pass'' piece of legislation was a collection of about $ 5.3 billion in new taxes, a bunch of accounting changes, and some across-the-board spending cuts to reduce the budget deficit. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has said he wants at least $ 14 billion in deficit reduction for the current fiscal year. Three-way talks involving the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> were negotiating that deal, which covers a broad range of issues including a new system for paying doctors for services to <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> patients. In the long run, said Sens. <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Rockefeller </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Minn </LOCATION>., two of the sponsors, the change will hold down medical costs and help assure that high-qualify medical services are available to rural areas and The plan establishes a national fee schedule based on costs of providing services. Physicians now are reimbursed on the basis of historical fees that often have little relationship to costs of providing care. The government's costs for physician fees have been increasing at about 15 percent per year, and in the last fiscal year totalled $ 24.5 billion. The new fees would be based on the skill, training and time required to perform the service. The fee structure would be aimed at bringing down high fees for certain services such as surgery relative to fees for treatment provided by family practitioners and internists, who may perform fewer `` procedures'' but whose treatment, even if only counseling, may require equally high skill and knowledge. Adding to the incentive for approving the deficit bill was, indirectly, the pay raise that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> decided last week to give itself. The pay raise package includes initial `` cost-of-living adjustments'' of 7.9 percent in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and nearly 10 percent for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. But those raises wo n't happen until the budget bill is enacted. Enactment would cancel spending cuts ordered Oct. 1 under the Gramm-Rudman law because <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the president failed to meet their deficit-reduction goals. On the spending front, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Monday vetoed his second appropriations bill in two days because he objected to abortion provisions. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Sunday vetoed a $ 14.6 billion foreign aid bill because it contained $ 15 million for a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> population control agency that operates worldwide, including <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has a one-child-per-family policy that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said results in coerced abortions, and he said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> agency would make the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> a party to that practice. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, which does not have a two-thirds majority to override <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on abortion questions, approved and sent to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Monday a bill without the money for the population control agency, and the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> followed suit later in the day. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Monday vetoed the annual District of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> appropriations bill. While <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> barred the city from using federal money for abortions, it had taken out out a similar restriction on the city's use of its own local tax dollars. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> immediately took up and passed by voice vote a new version designed to meet the president's objections, sending the bill to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, which also passed the clean version of the bill just before midnight. The House by voice vote on Monday sent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a third spending bill, vetoed earlier in an abortion dispute, in a form more to his liking. The $ 156.7 billion appropriation for the <ORGANIZATION> Departments </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, and other agencies, was vetoed earlier because <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> voted to allow federal money to pay for abortions for poor women who were victims of rape and incest. At <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s insistence, the new bill would cover abortions cases only when the life of the mother was in danger Although its adjournment target dates are typically in early October, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> typically works until nearly Christmas in non-election years. The last time it adjourned before December in an odd-numbered year was in 1983, when lawmakers went home on Nov. 18.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0220EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-President-Lobbying     11-21 0529</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-President-Lobbying,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Presidential Lobbying Keeps President Out of Lobbying Bill</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Senators writing new lobbying restrictions for former government officials are taking President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s advice to exempt no one, except for one last-minute request from the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to leave out a single executive position _ the president. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> got his way last week, as <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> authors <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, D-Mich. and <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION> made last-minute changes to make sure the lobbying restrictions leave out presidents The restrictions, including the first application to former members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, were approved early Saturday as part of the legislation to raise pay of lawmakers, judges and top executive branch officials. A <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> source, speaking Monday on condition of anonymity, said, `` It's the White House that's been yelling ` parity, parity, parity''' to make sure that top officials in all three government branches were covered when they left government. `` That meant ` cover everybody else but me,''' the source said, referring to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. But White House spokesman <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> said the administration had good reason to seek the exclusion for presidents. The bill may have prevented `` a current president from consulting with a past president,'' he said. `` We felt the president should be removed because of his unique status,'' said <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>. `` The president would n't be able to talk to anybody in the government ... His work involves the entire government. It's in the national interest for a sitting president to be able to consult past presidents.'' <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> said there's never been an example of a president lobbying the government after leaving office, adding `` the notion that it would occur is somewhat demeaning to the presidency.'' He noted ex-vice presidents are covered by the restrictions, and should be because many have entered private business. Current anti-lobbying language is silent on presidential coverage, but presidents are considered excluded under a <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> ruling. `` In every version until the last one, the intention was to cover the president. We exempted the president at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s request,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevenson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON>'s spokesman Rep. <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, D-Mass., the prime author of lobbying restrictions in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, called the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's position `` inconsistent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, he said, `` lobbied so hard to make -LRB- the restrictions -RRB- tougher. The president wanted a provision that people could n't even lobby for free.'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said he reluctantly accepted the president's request when the pay and ethics package reached the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> because, `` We could n't negotiate everything. Provisions of the new legislation, some similar to current law and some going beyond it, would: _ Impose a lifetime ban on lobbying on matters where former officials were `` personally and substantially involved. _ Require a two-year ban on former officials lobbying on matters that were under their supervision, even if they had not directly participated _ Prohibit lobbying for a year by those personally and substantially involved in any trade or treaty negotiation _ Impose a one-year ban on top senior executives from lobbying their former agency on any matter in which the ex-officials would seek official action _ Bar any former top official, for one year, from representing, aiding or advising a foreign government or foreign political party in a matter before any department or agency
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891121-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-89 0221EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-Lincoln-Chronology     11-21 1075</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Lincoln-Chronology,1000</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Lincoln S&amp;L, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
