<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 2328EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TankerFire 1stLd-Writethru a0765 05-14 0236</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tanker Fire, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0765,0235</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Erupts on Tanker Carrying 450,000 Barrels of Crude</HEAD>
<UNK>Eds: LEADS with 5 grafs to UPDATE with fire put out; picks up 6th
graf, `The cause...'</UNK>
<DATELINE>PORT ARTHUR, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fire erupted Sunday aboard a Liberian tanker carrying 450,000 barrels of crude oil, but <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> officials said the cargo was not threatened and the blaze was extinguished nine hours later. `` The fire is safely out, there was no pollution and no problems,'' said Lt. j.g <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dubois </PERSON> with the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arthur </LOCATION>. Two crew members aboard the 810-foot Jalinga were taken to <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Place </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arthur </LOCATION> for treatment of smoke inhalation after the fire erupted in the vessel's engine room about 9:30 a.m. Sunday, said another <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, Lt. j.g. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Garrott </PERSON>. The two unidentified men were being held overnight for observation, <PERSON> Garrott </PERSON> said. No other injuries were reported. Two tugs were holding the Jalinga in place Sunday afternoon while firefighters battled the fire, which was contained in the engine room, <PERSON> Garrott </PERSON> said. It was extinguished about 6:15 p.m., <PERSON> Dubois </PERSON> said. The cause of the fire has not been determined, but <PERSON> Garrott </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> has begun an investigation. <PERSON> Garrott </PERSON> said the <PERSON> Jalinga </PERSON> originated in <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION> and was bound for the <ORGANIZATION> Fina </ORGANIZATION> docks in <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arthur </LOCATION>. The ship is owned by <ORGANIZATION> Jalinga </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navigation </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Monrovia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION>, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 2332EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SoapSemiautomatic     05-14 0264</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soap Semiautomatic,0270</SECOND>
<HEAD>Inmate Captured After Escaping Jail With Semiautomatic Carved From
Soap</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PERRY, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A jail inmate who made his second escape in two months by pulling a gun carved from soap was captured Sunday in a pecan grove. <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanford </PERSON>, 23, was caught while walking in the grove south of <PERSON> Perry </PERSON>, said <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Cullen </PERSON> <PERSON> Talton </PERSON>. He escaped Saturday after he pulled what looked like a semiautomatic weapon on three guards and ordered another inmate to open a cellblock door. The gun had been carved from two bars of soap and painted black, <PERSON> Talton </PERSON> said. `` At first glance, it looked like the real thing,'' <PERSON> Talton </PERSON> said. `` Of course, when you looked close you could tell it was n't. He even used an eye from a shoe, like you run shoelaces through, to make the barrel look real.'' <PERSON> Sanford </PERSON>, serving time for armed robbery and kidnapping, was one of seven inmates who escaped from the county jail two months ago. He was making a phone call Saturday when he asked jailer <PERSON> Clarence </PERSON> <PERSON> Cash </PERSON> if he could get a drink of water from a cooler outside the security door, <PERSON> Talton </PERSON> said. Cash let <PERSON> Sanford </PERSON> through, <PERSON> Talton </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Sanford </PERSON> went to the water cooler, then pulled what appeared to be a gun, forced jailers to lie on the floor and made his escape, <PERSON> Talton </PERSON> said. `` It's a situation that never should have happened,'' <PERSON> Talton </PERSON> said Sunday. `` It's a case of jailers being negligent and not following the rules of the jail.'' <PERSON> Talton </PERSON> said authorities would consider disciplinary action against Cash Monday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 2344EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Scott     05-14 0195</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Scott,0201</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gay Activist Peter Scott Dead at 50</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gay activist <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, who canceled a run for the state <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> after learning he had AIDS, has died of complications from the disease. He was 50. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, the former chairman of AIDS Project-Los Angeles, died Saturday at his home, friends said. A former lawyer who gave up his practice to champion gay rights, <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> worked to defeat measures to fire homosexual teachers and a state initiative requiring that people with AIDS be registered with the state. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> founded the <ORGANIZATION> Municipal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION>, the city's most powerful gay rights political group. He was active in fund-raising until his illness worsened last month. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> led the fight in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> to hasten testing of experimental AIDS drugs, resulting in a drug-testing bill passed into law in 1987. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> was diagnosed with AIDS in 1986, just as he was planning to challenge Assembly Majority Leader <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Roos </PERSON> for his 46th District seat. Instead, he worked to raise money to find a cure for AIDS. He is survived by his longtime companion, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Quarles </PERSON>; his mother, <PERSON> Camille </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>; and sister, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Jamison </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 2347EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-OnionPungency     05-14 0533</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Onion Pungency,0547</SECOND>
<HEAD>Even Sweet Vidalias Can Drive Researchers To Tears</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELLIOTT MINOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TIFTON, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Janie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON> wears a mask and goggles at work. Otherwise, her job would drive her to tears. The lab technician at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION>'s Coastal Plain Experiment Station peels and grinds samples of Vidalia onions and then conducts chemical tests that may someday enable consumers to identify the strength of an onion. The gourmet onions have a reputation of being the sweetest, mildest in the world, but when there are 50 to 60 Vidalias to slice in a day, her lab fills with eye-burning fumes and a pungent odor. `` I have to wear a mask and goggles,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON> said. `` Otherwise, my eyes burn and my sinuses throb.'' She and horticulturist <PERSON> Doyle </PERSON> <PERSON> Smittle </PERSON> are collecting information on sugar and pungency levels in Vidalias. `` We're trying to develop a rapid, objective method of measuring quality in onions,'' said <PERSON> Smittle </PERSON>. `` We'd like to have a technique ... simple enough that a grower or group of growers could measure the quality in at least every field of onions they have.'' This summer, food scientist <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Shewfelt </PERSON> will convene a taste panel at the Experiment Station in <LOCATION> Griffin </LOCATION> to sample some of the same onions that have been tested. <PERSON> Smittle </PERSON>, who has been studying the compounds in onions since the mid-1970s, hopes to establish a relationship between the chemical composition of Vidalias and the onions preferred by the taste panel. Onions have virtually no odor until their tissue is damaged by slicing. At that point, an enzyme triggers a chemical reaction that produces ammonia and other substances that cause tears. Chemical tests give a good indication of an onion's pungency, but they're too complicated and costly for routine use by growers, said <PERSON> Smittle </PERSON>. Taste buds are n't as reliable as laboratory tests because humans tend to forget how bad or good a sample was, he said. Members of the taste panel will sample six onions a day, then they'll come back a week or two later and evaluate the same onions. The horticulturist foresees use of an infrared device that would scan onions in the packing sheds and determine their mildness. Since sugars absorb infrared light, there may be a correlation between taste and the amount of light that passes through onions, he said. <PERSON> Smittle </PERSON> believes growers eventually will be able to place stickers on each onion, with a picture of a thermometer showing the degree of mildness. His tests have shown that onion mildness varies from field to field and season to season. With a pungency rating, consumers could use the hotter onions in dishes that require more flavor. The rating also would help consumers adjust the thickness of slices to specific needs. <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>'s 260 registered growers and packers have turned the Vidalia onion into a $ 30-million-a-year crop. Protected by state law, onions bearing the Vidalia label have to be a yellow Granex hybrid. The growing region encompasses 13 counties in southeastern <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and parts of six other. Growers claim Vidalias are sweetest because of the variety and the low-sulfur soil around Vidalia, a town of 10,000 residents about 80 miles west of <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 2350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BlackInventors Bjt   05-14 0715</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Black Inventors, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>From Trouser Stretchers to Traffic Signals, Black Inventors Get Their
Due</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Norbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Rillieux </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Matzeliger </PERSON> helped revolutionize American history with their inventions, but the two men scarcely rate a footnote in the annals of Yankee ingenuity simply because they were black. Historian <PERSON> Portia </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> is setting matters straight with an ambitious new <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION> exhibition that celebrates the genius of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s unsung black inventors. The show, which opens Sunday, pays belated tribute to 40 inventors whose creations include a trouser-stretching device for eliminating wrinkles, a machine for producing paper bags, a press for baling cotton and a mechanical traffic signal patented in 1923. `` The exhibition says a lot about their urge to create, and how important it was for blacks to feel they were part of the growth of American technology,'' said Ms. <PERSON> James </PERSON>, the show's curator. `` It was their assertion of black participation in the Yankee innovative spirit.'' The exhibition at the <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Anacostia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Afro-American </ORGANIZATION> history and culture is titled `` The Real McCoy: African American Invention and Innovation, 1619-1930.'' The show's name is taken from an invention by mechanical engineer <PERSON> Elijah </PERSON> <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON> _ a grease cup designed for lubricating rail locomotives while they sped down the tracks. Admiring train engineers nicknamed it `` the real McCoy.'' On display are the two devices created by black inventors which probably have had the greatest lasting impact on <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> society, said Ms. <PERSON> James </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> who is the <LOCATION> Anacostia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Museum </LOCATION>'s resident historian One of them, developed by the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> inventor <PERSON> Rillieux </PERSON> in 1830, is a vacuum evaporation machine that made refined sugar widely affordable. It later was used to produce such foods as evaporated milk and cocoa powder. The other is <PERSON> Matzeliger </PERSON>'s shoe-lasting machine, patented in 1883 by the inventor from <LOCATION> Dutch </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Surinam </LOCATION>. The machine radically changed the American shoe industry by eliminating the need for costly hand-stitching of soles to the soft leather uppers of shoes. The museum duly recognizes one of the few prominent black inventors, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON> <PERSON> Carver </PERSON>, with a sampling of the products he derived from peanuts, soybeans and sweet potatoes in his laboratory at <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Tuskegee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. But it also highlights such unknowns as <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> Latimer </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, the only black associate on <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Edison </PERSON>'s laboratory team, who patented a carbon light bulb filament. Another is <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, who invented both the stop-go traffic signal and an industrial `` safety hood'' or gas mask which he used to rescue workers trapped by a tunnel explosion under <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> James </PERSON> notes that African slaves introduced the banjo to American music, and that <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> clergyman <PERSON> Cotton </PERSON> <PERSON> Mather </PERSON> learned of inoculation against smallpox from his North African slave Onesimus. The exhibition honors <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> tailor <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON>, the first black believed to have received a patent, for his dry cleaning process in 1821. On display are three wood planes designed in the 1770s by <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> <PERSON> Chelor </PERSON>, a freed slave from <LOCATION> Wrentham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, who is believed to be the earliest black toolmaker in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> James </PERSON> said her research for the exhibition took three years because of the scarcity of historical records. Material came from old newspapers and magazines published for the black community and from an exhaustive record of pre-1900 patents awarded to black inventors that was compiled by <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, an early black <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> patent examiner, she said. Ms. <PERSON> James </PERSON>' research yielded the tale of Oscar J.E. <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> planter who tried to obtain a patent in 1857 for a labor-saving `` double cotton scraper'' invented by his slave, <PERSON> Ned </PERSON>. <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> argued that `` the master is the owner of the fruits of the labor of the slave both intellectual and manual,'' but the federal government granted neither man a patent. Undaunted, <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> began manufacturing <PERSON> Ned </PERSON>'s creation and issued advertising circulars containing this testimonial from a fellow plantation owner: `` I am glad to know that your implement is the invention of a <ORGANIZATION> Negro </ORGANIZATION> slave _ thus giving the lie to the Abolition cry that slavery dwarfs the mind of the Negro. When did a free Negro ever invent anything?'' As for the ingenious slave, Ms. <PERSON> James </PERSON> says, `` <PERSON> Ned </PERSON> disappeared from history, and nothing is known of what became of him.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 2350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Coelho-Ethics Bjt   05-14 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Coelho-Ethics, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Coelho Defends Legality of Junk Bond Loan, but Says he Regrets it</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A top House Democrat says an arrangement that earned him $ 6,882 in four months through buying junk bonds with other people's money `` was n't worth the trouble'' in light of the current focus on ethics. `` With the benefit of hindsight, I now regret having made this transaction,'' Rep. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, D-Calif., said Sunday as he released his lawyer's report on the bond purchase As <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> majority whip, <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> is the third-ranking Democrat and chief vote-counter for <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, who has been charged by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee with violating rules in his personal financial dealings. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, who could move up in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leadership if <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> falls, said Sunday he would be amending his 1986 financial disclosure to include a previously unreported $ 50,000 loan that financed half of a $ 100,000 investment in junk bonds in 1986. His lawyer's report said the chief executive of the savings and loan that provided that financing had suggested the junk bond investment to <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> and then purchased the bonds on <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>'s behalf when the congressman needed more time to raise the money Junk bonds are high-risk, high-yield bonds often used to finance corporate takeovers. According to his lawyer's report, <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> first considered investing his 1986 campaign funds in the 12 1 @ 2 percent bonds, based on a suggestion by <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON>, chief executive officer of the <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. After <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> decided against that investment for his campaign treasury, <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON> suggested that <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> himself could make an investment in the bonds, which were being issued for a takeover of Beatrice foods arranged by <PERSON> Drexel </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnham </PERSON> <PERSON> Lambert </PERSON> When <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> could not come up with the $ 100,000 by the required purchase date of May 5, <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON> bought the bonds himself and held them for a month while <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> completed his financing. Half the money came from <LOCATION> Spiegel </LOCATION>'s thrift institution and the rest from two other banks. At that point, <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> bought the bonds from <LOCATION> Spiegel </LOCATION> and paid him interest equivalent to what the bonds made during the period of the loan. When the congressman sold the bonds in October 1986, he was able to repay the loans and realize a $ 6,882 profit. In his report, attorney <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bauer </PERSON> concluded that <PERSON> Coehlo </PERSON> did not violate <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> rules in his arrangement with <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON>, because the congressman paid interest and thus accepted no `` gift'' which might have been improper. The fact that the investment was issued at first to <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>'s campaign committee, instead of the congressman, was a clerical error, <PERSON> Bauer </PERSON> said Errors in the reported dates of the transactions might require <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> to amend his 1986 tax returns, he said. `` We believe that the appearances presented by the transaction can be properly addressed by a full disclosure of all surrounding circumstances,'' he said. There is no indication whether the ethics committee is considering or plans to review the bond purchase. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> insists <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON> has asked for no legislative favors and none were granted. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> said in his statement he was `` accepting without reservations the conclusion of my legal counsel that the purchase of the bonds was totally above board.'' But, he said, `` public officials are today, however, living in a period of intense questioning. `` With the benefit of hindsight, I now regret having made this transaction,'' he said. `` I do n't like it when my public decisions or private actions raise questions, as this investment did, and the $ 6,882 profit was n't worth the trouble.'' <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> last year put all of his holdings into a blind trust. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> did not disclose the bond transaction with <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON> or the loan from <ORGANIZATION> Spiegel </ORGANIZATION>'s financial institution when <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> last month first reported on his junk bond investment. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Dreyer </PERSON>, <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>'s press secretary, said the congressman's staff had taken a month `` to understand fully and reconstruct this transaction. He said that effort did not include checking whether <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON> had any interest in legislation, since that indicates a violation of House rules only if <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON> had conferred a gift.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 2353EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress'SidePay Bjt   05-14 0736</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress' Side Pay, Bjt,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Speeches for a Fee: Congress Now Must Tell How Much it Gets</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Members of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> must soon disclose how much outside income they earned from speeches and other activities that have fueled debate over a congressional pay raise and created a preoccupation with ethics. On Friday senators and on May 22 members of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION> will make public their financial disclosure forms, which all high-level people in the government must file. Although the forms reveal such matters as what stocks the members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> bought, sold and own and how much they got in reimbursements when they went on the road to make a speech, attention this year, as never before, is apt to focus on the fees paid members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for giving speeches. Common Cause, the public interest membership group which has campaigned for tougher ethical standards, says it has counted 245 newspaper editorials demanding an end to these honoraria _ calling the fees `` legalized bribery,'' `` legislative prostitution'' and `` lobbyists' payola.'' Under <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' own rules, members are permitted to take $ 2,000 for giving speeches, writing articles or sometimes merely putting in an appearance. The fees are often paid by groups or companies with a vital interest in legislation before the speakers' committees Last May, members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> reported getting $ 9.8 million in honoraria fees in 1987, a 30 percent increase over 1986. Because House rules restrict outside earned income to 30 percent of salary and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rules restrict senators from taking honoraria fees worth more than 40 percent of salary, many members get more than they can keep and give the overflow to charity. Last year, members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> kept $ 7.5 million and gave away $ 2.3 million. The average senator kept $ 23,200 and the average House member kept $ 12,200. The defense industry alone paid more than $ 500,000 in speaking fees to members of congressional committees that deal with defense issues. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, in endorsing a 51 percent pay boost in January that had been recommended by a commission appointed by former President <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, also endorsed a simultaneous ban on honoraria. When a public outcry caused <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to vote down the pay raise, it also rejected the honoraria ban, but the issue did n't go away. A commission appointed by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to recommend tighter ethics rules for government proposed a ban on all honoraria and more stringent limits on how much outside income can be earned by someone in government. More recently, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> was charged with ethics violations, stemming in part from his earnings on a book. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee charged he used bulk sales of the book, `` Reflections of a Public Man,'' to circumvent restrictions on outside income. Former Attorney General <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>, a member of the commission, said honoraria fees present the appearance of a conflict of interest. `` People wonder who's paying all these honoraria,'' he said. `` It undermines confidence in government.'' The financial disclosure requirement grew out of the Watergate-spawned demand for higher ethical standards in government. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> adopted an ethics code in 1977 and put it into law in 1978. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> adopted most but not all of his commission's recommendations He called for banning honoraria for judges but not for members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. He said he would deal with an honoraria ban when he again approaches the delicate issue of proposing a pay raise for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Rep. <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, D-Mass., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> subcommittee </ORGANIZATION> that will consider <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s ethics recommendations, said he favors a ban on congressional honoraria fees, although he would allow members to continue earning some outside income for such activities as teaching a course in law school <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> refuses honoraria, as do a number of freshman congressmen. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is also required to disclose reimbursement for the `` actual and necessary travel expenses incurred'' when engaged in speechmaking. But Common Cause says many in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> `` have used creative interpretations of these rules.'' The organization cited a report by Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Exon </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Neb </LOCATION>., that he and his wife accepted round trip airfare to <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> and eight nights food and lodging paid for by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Executives </ORGANIZATION> as necessary travel expenses or the report by Rep. <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Callahan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ala </LOCATION>., that he got $ 3,948 in travel and lodging reimbursement for three days at <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, paid by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Moving </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Storage </ORGANIZATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 2354EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Sino-Soviet Bjt   05-14 0701</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Sino-Soviet, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Needn't Fear Shift in Sino-Soviet Relations</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration ca n't afford to be complacent about warming relations between the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, but neither must it fear the shift is taking place at <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s expense, say analysts of Sino-Soviet ties. Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s four-day pilgrimage to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, which begins today, is unlikely to result in a renewal of the 1950s military alliance of communist giants, says <PERSON> Seweryn </PERSON> <PERSON> Bialer </PERSON>, a Soviet specialist and professor of international relations at <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` I do n't think it's a -LRB- military -RRB- alliance. ... but it is a summit of major significance, because both countries need each other again,'' <PERSON> Bialer </PERSON> said at a recent luncheon hosted in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> by the East-West Forum. <PERSON> Bialer </PERSON> predicted that economic cooperation between <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> will grow extensively now that the 30-year rift between <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> has been healed. `` Economic cooperation is in the interest of both countries,'' he said. And, he noted, Chinese officials have taken pains to let the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> know that renewed Sino-Soviet links will not come at the expense of the expanding U.S.-China relationship. An invitation to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships to visit <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>, delayed until a day after <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> tours the port city, is designed as `` reassurance for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, because the Chinese are very worried that this -LRB- summit -RRB- would be received very badly in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' the professor said. <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Brick </PERSON>, an analyst at the conservative <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, argues that a military pact does n't appear to be in the offing because neither <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiao-ping </PERSON> wants `` to risk access to vital Western financial and technological assistance.'' He points out that Americans can hardly criticize the Chinese for following the pattern of warming U.S.-Soviet relations. Also, he argues, the summit comes at a time when <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Chinese ties `` have deepened on so many fronts _ industrial, trade, military cooperation, shared technology and vast cultural and educational exchanges _ there is almost no possibility that a rapprochement with the Soviets would come at the price of cooler relations with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>'' But the administration must be wary of any renewed military cooperation and let both nations know that such a development could cause the president to reassess his support for the normalization of relations, <PERSON> Brick </PERSON> said. If the Soviets and Chinese iron out their so-called `` three obstacles'' to improved ties _ tensions along their 4,670-mile border as well as Soviet involvement in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> _ a more stable <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> could result, <PERSON> Brick </PERSON> said, a development that would benefit the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> RAND </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> analyst <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollack </PERSON>, in an essay on the summit written for the <ORGANIZATION> Asia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, points out that the summit occurs `` at a time when the Sino-American relationship is on a vastly more diversified footing than when Soviet initiatives toward <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> first began.'' <PERSON> Pollack </PERSON> points to the growth in U.S.-China trade, which in 1988 surpassed $ 13 billion, or more than four times the level of Sino-Soviet trade; <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> investment in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has topped $ 3 billion, more than any other single country; and more than 30,000 Chinese students are in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as technological and military exchanges are growing. `` American interests would not be well served by an attempt to curry favor with either state in the aftermath of the summit; the basis for good relations with both <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> can and does exist independent of their relations with each other,'' says the think tank's specialist on Chinese-Soviet ties. Most analysts agree the summit may mark the symbolic end of the strategic triangular relationship that gave birth to the notion of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> playing the so-called `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> card,'' or the idea that the antagonistic relationship between <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> offered the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> leverage in dealing with either nation. `` There is no more triangle _ it is a quadrangle,'' said <PERSON> Bialer </PERSON>, who points to the entrance of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> as the major economic power in <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. The shift does present a new and more complex challenge, <PERSON> Pollack </PERSON> says, `` especially since there no longer seem any illusions about the ability of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to manipulate Sino-Soviet differences to the advantage of American interests.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 2355EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     05-14 0830</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,840</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Grain Sales Keep the Trains Rolling</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One million metric tons of wheat would fill 11,100 covered hopper cars used by railroads to move grain. If towed by a single locomotive, the train would be about 116 miles long, according to figures supplied by the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railroads </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has already bought enough wheat and corn this fiscal year to fill about 20 of the million-ton trains. If those were lined up one behind the other, they would stretch 2,320 miles _ roughly the distance from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> to Twin Falls, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. Specifically, <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> has bought a record 19.3 million tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat and corn for delivery through Sept. 30, and has been cleared to purchase a maximum of 24 million tons by then. And the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is only part of the huge annual export flow of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm commodities that move by railroad, truck and river barge to seaports and then to overseas points. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is the biggest single foreign customer of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> farmers, and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> _ this year, at least _ is the largest buyer of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat. But <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s grain needs, coupled with historic secrecy in the early dealings with Soviet buyers, are paramount in the way <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> and farmers look at the export situation. Crop failure in the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION>, or even the hint of significant losses, can send tremors through the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and world commodity markets. It's something that's watched closely by farmers, private traders and <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> analysts. By law, private exporters must report all big sales _ 100,000 tons or more _ to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> within 24 hours. All sales, regardless of size, are reported weekly. <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Nollmeyer </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> has updated her records showing the high marks for one-day grain sales. No specific country's are listed, however. The public announcements of large grain sales go back to early 1977, although weekly disclosures go back several more years. When very large grain sales are announced, there are sometimes inquiries about their relative size and whether a record has been reached. Nollmeyer's list helps answer those questions. The biggest day's activity on <PERSON> Nollmeyer </PERSON>'s list was on July 6, 1979, when exporters reported sales totaling nearly 2.48 million tons of grain, including 1.86 million tons of corn and 616,200 tons of wheat. But, because of a provision in the law, the exporters reported the grain's foreign destination as `` unknown.'' Often, however, the grain in the initial `` unknown'' category is changed in later reports to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> or some other buyer. Unofficially, since <PERSON> Nollmeyer </PERSON>'s one-day records go back only to April 14, 1977, there were a few sales larger than the one she cites. This requires a bit of history. The export reporting system was ordered by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in the early 1970s following huge secret dealings between <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and private grain companies. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in 1972, for example, secretly bought about a fourth of that year's <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat crop, plus corn, barley and soybeans. In all, more than 16 million tons of those commodities were contracted in a few weeks of dealing in the summer of 1972. About three-fourths of the grain was wheat. `` The huge, anticipated Soviet purchases of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat and corn that year produced a sizable runup in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> food prices and depleted <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> reserve stocks,'' the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> says in a background report. And there were charges that some <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> insiders had played along with the Soviets, that fat export subsidies were involved and that there was even a commodity spy at work. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> stepped into the fray in 1973, ordering an export sales reporting system to help bring order and accountability to the business. But there was still turmoil, and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, periodically faced with huge food deficits, continued to be an erratic customer of the American farmer. In 1975, after another round of large sales, further shipments were embargoed by President <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> in July and finally lifted the following October after a long-term agreement was worked out with the Soviets to buy annual amounts of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat and corn. The pact took effect on Oct. 1, 1976, and has been renewed or extended since then. Even so, sales to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> sometimes were huge. On April 28, 1976, for example, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> announced sales of corn totaling 1.4 million tons. Later the same day, officials announced a further sale of 1.7 million tons of corn plus 300,000 tons of wheat. In all, the one-day flurry involved the sale of 3.4 million tons of grain to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Nowadays, with exporters and the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> accustomed to the long-term agreement's terms and the reporting requirements, a sale of a million tons or so in one day is considered unusual. In fact, according to <PERSON> Nollmeyer </PERSON>'s list, one-day total grain sales to all foreign buyers, including the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, have exceeded 2 million tons only three times since 1977.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 2359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Economy     05-14 0619</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Economy,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Corporate America Upbeat in Face of Slowdown</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NANCY BENAC</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOT SPRINGS, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Leaders of corporate <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> say business is surprisingly good and they're prepared to weather the sharp downturn that looms ahead. Members of the Business Council, made up of chief executives from 65 major corporations, gathered at the posh Homestead resort this past weekend for their semiannual country retreat. The Business Council's economists are projecting that economic growth, as measured by the gross national product, will fall from last year's strong 3.9 percent pace to 1.4 percent by the end of the year and rebound late in 1990. But many executives were generally more bullish than their own analysts. `` We really see that as good news, not bad news,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kearns </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Xerox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> `` When you get a slowing of growth, it should keep inflation down.'' Signs of an economic slowdown have proliferated in recent months, in weak retail sales, flat industrial production, plunging home sales and construction and slower overall spending by consumers. Still, even among leaders of industries most affected by the slowdown, there were few furrowed brows over the weekend or admissions that trouble lies ahead. <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawley </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Carter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hawley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stores </ORGANIZATION>, said general merchandisers are seeing `` somewhat better sales than anticipated.'' <PERSON> Hawley </PERSON> did acknowledge the onset of a slowdown in spending on big-ticket `` durable goods'' such as major appliances, but he said companies are doing a good job of keeping their inventories under control. A similarly bright outlook for the auto industry, which has experienced sluggish sales so far this year, came from <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and of the Business Council. `` Any time that our industry is looking at car and truck sales up in the 15 million area, why it's got to be a good year for us,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. He conceded that sales are being propped up by big rebates and cut-rate financing, but said surveys showing that consumer confidence remains high bode well for future sales. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, said business leaders are making few plans to retrench because the slowing economy still offers the prospect of reasonable growth. `` We do n't see, at least in front of us today, any precipitous drop,'' <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> said. `` Capital spending will remain about where it is and productivity will continue to improve.'' Said <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, `` My view is that there's a little stronger undercurrent to the economy than this forecast, and I think there will be higher inflationary pressures.'' <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON> said he believes gains in American productivity have been underestimated and favorable exchange rates are making <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> products more competitive overseas. S.D. <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION>, chairman of the giant engineering and construction company that bears his name, had a similarly positive outlook for the economy overall, although he said the construction business remains weak. `` We've been down for several years and the economy got its strength without us,'' he said. Several chief executives said a possible jinx to the bright outlook lies in the risk of interest rates rising further. `` That changes currency rates and starts a whole set of things going that are difficult to plan for,'' <PERSON> Kearns </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> for a year has been pushing up interest rates in an effort to rein in inflation by restraining economic growth. A growing number of analysts are expressing concern that the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> could push interest rates so high and slow growth so much that it unintentionally pushes the country into a recession. `` The biggest thing that we would fear would be ... hype on the economy that would lead to <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> quick-trigger action,'' <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 2356EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Spain-Anti-US     05-14 0211</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spain-Anti-US,0218</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thousands March Against U.S. Bases, NATO</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CADIZ, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Protesters demanding the dismantling of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> garrisons in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> tried to go over a wall and into a U.S.-Spanish naval base but were turned back by police using clubs, rubber bullets and tear gas, police said. No arrests or injuries were reported in Sunday's confrontation. The roughly 400 protesters, many with their faces covered, were among about 5,000 people who had marched on the joint-use base, police said. March organizers estimated the crowd at 15,000. The marchers, who also shouted anti-NATO slogans, walked nearly 10 miles to the base from the town of <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Maria </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> base is about 50 miles north of the Strait of <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION>. The march was organized by regional pacifist groups. <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> signed a new eight-year pact on Dec. 1 that mandates removal of 72 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> F-16 fighter bombers from Spanish soil by 1992. But it permits continued <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> use of three military bases, including <LOCATION> Rota </LOCATION>. The new agreement reduces the maximum number of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops allowed to be stationed in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> by 36 percent, from 12,545 to 8,078. Though a member of the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> remains outside the alliance's military command structure.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 0056EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ClimbingDeath 1stLd-Writethru a0580 05-14 0285</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Climbing Death, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0580,0289</SECOND>
<HEAD>Missing Climber Found Dead On Mount Rainier</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf `Hentges said...' with 1 graf to show weather
prevented retrieval of body; edits 8th graf, `Mooney's body...' to conform</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ASHFORD, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An Army Chinook helicopter Saturday found the body of a climber on <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rainier </LOCATION> after a two-day search that began with the discovery of his climbing partner's frozen corpse. The helicopter's crew spotted the body of 26-year-old <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Derdowski </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Stateline </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, around noon at the 9,400-foot mark of <ORGANIZATION> Carbon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Glacier </ORGANIZATION>, on the mountain's north side, said <PERSON> Cy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hentges </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Mount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rainier </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. A crew of six to eight climbers were prevented from getting the body because thunderstorms made it unsafe for a helicopter to fly into the area, a Mt. Rainier dispatcher said. Rescue crews will try again Sunday, he said. `` He apparently slipped off <PERSON> Liberty </PERSON> <PERSON> Ridge </PERSON> as he tried to come back down,'' <PERSON> Hentges </PERSON> said. `` He apparently died of the fall.'' <PERSON> Derkdowski </PERSON>'s climbing partner, 33-year-old <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Mooney </PERSON> of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tahoe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, was found dead below Liberty Cap on the 14,410-foot mountain Thursday by two others in the climbing party. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Duin </PERSON>, 26, and <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Newell </PERSON>, 27, both of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tahoe </LOCATION>, came upon <PERSON> Mooney </PERSON>'s body Thursday at the 13,700-foot level and descended to alert authorities, who dispatched 30 searchers and three helicopters to look for <PERSON> Derdowski </PERSON>. <PERSON> Derdowski </PERSON> apparently had left <PERSON> Mooney </PERSON> to find the two other climbers, <PERSON> Hentges </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Mooney </PERSON>'s body was taken to the county medical examiner. <PERSON> Derdowski </PERSON> is survived by a wife and a 9-month old son. <PERSON> Mooney </PERSON> was single. The deaths brought to 11 the number of men killed while climbing <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rainier </LOCATION> since 1979.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Japan-Soviet     05-14 0098</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Soviet,0102</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japanese Trawler Seized by Soviets</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has seized a Japanese fishing boat in Soviet waters, an official from the <ORGANIZATION> Maritime </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday. Agency spokesman <PERSON> Mitsuru </PERSON> <PERSON> Akiyama </PERSON> said the No. 103 Koryo Maru, a 125-ton trawler with 16 crewmembers aboard, was seized southeast of <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nossapu </LOCATION>, 680 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, at around 2:45 a.m. Saturday -LRB- 1:45 p.m. EDT Friday -RRB-. He said the fishing boat was within territory claimed by the Soviets. The <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> has asked the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> for an explanation of the seizure, <PERSON> Akiyama </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China 3rdLd-Writethru a0648 05-14 0848</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0648,0870</SECOND>
<HEAD>Students on Hunger Strike for Democracy; Square To Be Cleared Monday</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: ADDS 2 grafs with China delaying U.S. warships' arrival in Shanghai
until day after Gorbachev visit.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto BEJ1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN BIERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of students huddled in wind-swept Tiananmen Square on Sunday after the first night of a hunger strike for democracy, ignoring government appeals they end their protest. <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziyang </PERSON> on Saturday urged the students not to disrupt the visit of Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, who arrives Monday for the first Sino-Soviet summit in 30 years. The official <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Daily announced the central square will be cleared of all pedestrians and traffic on Monday. <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> also told a workers' group Saturday in the Great Hall of the People, adjoining the square, that the government is seriously considering ways to promote democracy and end official corruption. Both are student demands. About 3,500 students from more than a dozen universities, all wearing white headbands to signify participation in the fast, converged on the square Saturday afternoon and evening. However, by Sunday morning there were only about 1,800 who appeared to be participating. They were encircled by about 1,000 other non-fasting students. Police made no attempt to interfere with the protest. But the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Daily said the square will be closed to pedestrians from 8:30 a.m. to 8:30 p.m. Monday -LRB- 7:30 p.m. EDT Sunday to 7:30 a.m. EDT Monday -RRB- and on Tuesday from 8 a.m. to noon. <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> told the workers Saturday that democratic changes and corruption will be discussed next month when the Standing Committee of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s legislature meets. `` Every patriotic Chinese citizen should safeguard the dignity of the motherland and its international image,'' the official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> paraphrased <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> as saying. `` Nobody should do anything to impede or jeopardize the summit.'' <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>'s remarks followed a meeting of the ruling Politburo last week that endorsed his moderate line toward student demands, according to Sunday editions of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. The newspaper, quoting three unidentified Chinese familiar with the proceedings, said the result of the meeting held Wednesday and Thursday was to bolster <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>'s faction and its calls for economic and political reform. Leading activist <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> said fasting students may still be in the square when the Soviet leader arrives Monday for the first Chinese-Soviet summit in 30 years. `` As for whether we will disrupt Mr. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s visit to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, that depends on the government,'' he said. `` We will persist to the end,'' said fasting graduate students from <ORGANIZATION> Qinghua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` This is a last resort.'' Early Sunday, hundreds of students and workers began flocking to the square with banners and posters to express support for the fast. <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> <PERSON> Xitong </PERSON> arrived at the square shortly before 3 a.m. Sunday but was shouted down when he tried to address the crowd. <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> was accompanied by <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Minister <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Tieying </PERSON> and they left 15 minutes later. About 30 students met earlier with <PERSON> Yan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mingfu </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Work </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. He was the highest-ranking party official to confer with the demonstrators. Two student leaders reported that he told them that some party members want to use the turmoil as a reason to stop reforms. The hunger strikers, wearing white headbands and sashes, sat inside a protective cordon of several thousand non-fasting students in the vast square that is the symbolic center of power in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. As temperatures dropped after sunset Saturday to below 50 degrees, many pulled on jackets or covered themselves with blankets, while others wrapped themselves in their red and white banners. Shortly before midnight, four trucks and two buses of police pulled up to the square and security forces stood watching. They did not intervene. The fast began Saturday evening after the students marched several hours from their campuses to the square. It is the latest in a month-old student campaign for a free press, human rights, an end to official corruption and other reforms. After repeated student marches, sit-ins and a class boycott, the government made a major concession Friday by offering to meet Monday with an independent student group. However, students said they were still discussing with officials the terms of a possible dialogue. They were dissatisfied with government conditions that include a limit on the number of student delegates and insistence that students from state-sponsored organizations also attend. Students also said they wanted the talks to be broadcast live. If talks are held, the students want the government to guarantee not to punish students who have protested; to observe constitutional guarantees of free speech; and to reinstate a liberal newspaper editor fired for resisting censorship. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> announced a one-day delay in the arrival of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships in <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> so the event does not coincide with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s planned visit to the port city. The <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said Saturday the ships will make the port call May 19, the day after <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s visit The announcement appeared to defuse a major source of diplomatic friction between the Soviets and the Chinese.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 0227EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TrainDerail 2ndLd-Writethru a0607 05-14 0693</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Train Derail, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0607,0708</SECOND>
<HEAD>Workers Remove Wreckage of Derailed Train, Four Dead</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: Leads with 7 grafs to UPDATE with investigators saying part
of braking system on two locomotives failed to work, more families returning
to their homes. Adds byline. Picks up 7th graf pvs: `The 69-car ...' ^By
LAUREN BLAU</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> SAN </LOCATION> <LOCATION> BERNDARDINO </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> CALIF </LOCATION> _ The braking systems were faulty on two locomotives of a freight train that thundered down the steep <LOCATION> Cajon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pass </LOCATION>, smashed into 11 homes and killed four people, investigators said Saturday. <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> acting Chairman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Kolstad </PERSON> told reporters Saturday night that the so-called dynamic brakes failed to work. But it was too early to tell if that caused the wreck, he said. Locomotives have air brakes which apply pressure to the wheels; dynamic brakes reverse the direction of the wheels, he explained. `` It appears a great majority of the cars were braking at the time of the accident,'' he said. The search of the wreckage ended Saturday afternoon, and heavy equipment began removing the twisted train cars that flew off curved tracks into the homes Friday. The body of a crewman was found at 2:30 a.m., hours after a man was pulled alive from his crumbled home. No one else was reported missing. Twenty-nine families were evacuated from their homes because the wrecked cars lay over an underground gas line. By Saturday night, 19 families still had to remain out of their houses, including those houses hit in the derailment, said <PERSON> Theresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON> of the local <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>. The 69-car <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> freight hauling a sandy mineral raced down 4,109-foot Cajon Pass between the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gabriel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>, derailed on a curve and hit 11 homes about 7:40 a.m. Friday. The crew radioed to a dispatcher that it was out of control at 90 mph. `` The train was all over the place,'' said a witness, <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorame </PERSON>. `` It looked like a toy in a sandbox. ... Some of the people thought it was an earthquake.'' The dead were identified as stepbrothers <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, 9, and <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, 7; conductor <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Crown </PERSON>, 36, a 17-year <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> employee; and brakeman <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reiss </PERSON>, 44, an 18-year employee, whose body was not found until Saturday morning. Three trainmen and six other people were injured. One of the injured, <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>, 24, survived for hours under the wreckage. He was found Friday evening later in a pocket of air under rail cars and the sandy cargo that crushed his home. He had surgery to have a pin put in a broken leg and was in serious condition at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said nursing supervisor <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>. Officials of the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railroad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Brotherhood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Locomotive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> met to coordinate the investigation, said <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopatkiewicz </PERSON>. Plans included on-site investigations and study of three event recorders that monitored train functions. `` They will certainly tell the speed of the train and might tell about brake application,'' <PERSON> Lopatkiewicz </PERSON> said. Investigators will also examine the train crew's history of work performance and whether there was evidence of alcohol or drug use, he said. Surviving crewmen will be interviewed, but probably not Saturday, he said. <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> was half-asleep when his home was flattened. He lay there all day and into the night before he was found, still conscious beneath the rubble. Rescuers extended an oxygen tube and encouraged him during the 1 -LCB- hours it took to free him. Debris had apparently formed a cave with enough oxygen to sustain him, said <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, a rescue supervisor. <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>'s mother, <PERSON> Maryann </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>, watched nervously during the rescue. `` I was so confused,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> said. `` I told him that his mama was outside and I was out here for him.'' The train was going from <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> in the high desert to <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> with a load of sodium carbonate and sodium bicarbonate, components of potash, a mineral used to make fertilizer and soap, railroad spokesmen said. The tracks were expected to remain closed at least a day, forcing the detour of 15 freights and two passenger trains.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 0229EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Pacific-Earthquake     05-14 0156</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Pacific-Earthquake,0162</SECOND>
<HEAD>Strong Quake Hits South Pacific Islands</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WELLINGTON, New Zealand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A strong earthquake in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> early Sunday shook the tiny <LOCATION> Kermadec </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, 760 miles north of here, the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scientific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industrial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> said. Initial reports said the quake measured 6.6 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, said a spokesman for the department's <ORGANIZATION> Seismological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observatory </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Wellington </LOCATION>, the capital. No information was immediately available on injuries or damage on the remote islands, which measure only about 13 square miles and belong to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>. The Richter scale is a gauge of the energy released by an earthquake, as measured by the ground motion recorded on a seismograph. Every increase of one number means that the ground motion is 10 times greater. A quake of magnitude 6 can cause severe damage in populated areas, while one measuring 7 is considered a major earthquake, capable of widespread, heavy damage in populated areas.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 0307EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Australia-BombScare     05-14 0118</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Australia-Bomb Scare,0123</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thousands Evacuated In Bomb Scare</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MELBOURNE, Australia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An estimated 20,000 people were evacuated from their homes in a suburb on Sunday after a package with wires attached was found atop a liquid petroleum gas tank at a service station, police said. The southern suburb of <LOCATION> Moorabin </LOCATION> was sealed off for more than three hours before residents were allowed to return to their homes. Locals were told to congregate at nearby schools and sports fields while police and army bomb disposal experts checked the package. A police spokesman, who declined to identify himself, said the suspected bomb was apparently the work of a hoaxer. Police were investigating the incident, the spokesman said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 0702EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-SouthKorea     05-14 0292</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-South Korea,0303</SECOND>
<HEAD>Riot Police Break Up Protest Over Student's Death</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY RENFREW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KWANGJU, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Charging riot police lashing out with truncheons and shields Sunday dispersed thousands of protesters who marched for a second day to protest the death of a radical student. About 5,000 riot police tore into a crowd of about the same number in front of the provincial government headquarters. Screaming protesters were trampled underfoot as troopers broke up the crowd after some people tried to force their way past police. Radical students pelted police with rocks and bricks as fighting surged up and down <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION>'s main street. Some police and protesters were hurt in the fighting. Police officials said they had no figures on injuries. Protesters were marching to denounce authorities over the death of radical student <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Chol-kyu </PERSON>. Dissidents claim police tortured and killed him. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s body was found Wednesday in a reservoir near <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION>, a provincial capital 170 miles south of <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>. Police, who were hunting <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> for anti-government acitivies, have denied any involvement in the death. In <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, officials said pathology tests were conducted Sunday to determine if <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s body contained plankton, which they said would suggest that he died by drowning. Initial results would be released Monday, they said. Radical student leaders told a news conference Sunday they would appeal to <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> to conduct an independent investigation of the death if an official Korean probe concludes police were not responsible. Dissident leaders called during the protest Sunday for the overthrow of President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-woo </PERSON>'s government and demanded the expulsion of the 43,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops based in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. The dissidents claim <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are trying to impose authoritarian rule on the country.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 0938EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Israel     05-14 0414</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Israel,0426</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cabinet Approves Shamir Plan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALLYN FISHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s Cabinet on Sunday approved Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s long-awaited plan for elections in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. The vote was 20-6. The four-page, 20-point <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> plan passed easily, largely because it sidestepped controversial points such as foreign supervision of elections, participation of 140,000 Arabs in east <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> and a timetable for the balloting. Industry Minister <PERSON> Ariel </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> led right-wing opposition to the proposal. He was joined in voting against the plan by two other ministers from the <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bloc </ORGANIZATION> members, two from the center-left <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> and one from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Religious </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> was quoted by an aide as telling the Cabinet it was `` a sure recipe for more violence and terror'' and one that could raise `` a danger of war.'' He was quoted by an aide as proposing his own seven-point plan, which calls for extending Israeli law to Jewish settlements in the occupied lands, an act equivalent to annexation. <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON>, a member of <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bloc </ORGANIZATION>, accused the Cabinet of rushing into a decision because of the presence of a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> delegation led by <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON>, chief of policy planning. <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> met with four moderate Palestinians but 11 others boycotted the meeting in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>. The key topic was the elections proposal, which Palestinians made clear would have to be endorsed by the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. Five Palestinians who did not attend sent a letter to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials criticizing the <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> plan as `` grossly deficient.'' The daily <ORGANIZATION> Yediot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ahronot </ORGANIZATION> said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials pushed for a timetable on elections. It said <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> believed elections could be held within one year while Defense Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> estimated six months were needed. In addition to the timetable, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> urged <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to allow 140,000 east <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabs </LOCATION> to vote and to permit international supervision of balloting. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s plan does not refer to either issue. It reportedly calls for electing 10 Palestinians from the occupied territories to negotiate with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> on an interim period of autonomy, with talks to begin after three years on the final status of the territories. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> hopes the plan will help end the 17-month Palestinian uprising in the occupied territories, in which at least 472 Arabs and 21 Israelis have been killed. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> captured the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> east </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> in the 1967 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> later annexed east <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 0957EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-CarrierFire 1stLd-Writethru a0658 05-14 0187</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Carrier Fire, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0658,170</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Killed In Explosion And Fire On USS America</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDs: SUBS 4th graf bgng ``The victims ... '' to CORRECT name of town
to Ham Lake, sted Hamlake.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two crew members were killed in an explosion and fire Saturday night aboard the aircraft carrier USS America while the ship was operating in the western <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> announced Sunday. A statement issued by the <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fleet </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, where the <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is based, said the incident occurred about 7 p.m. EDT Saturday in carrier's No. 2 fuel pump room. `` Shipboard firefighters successfully extinguised the fire with no additional casualties,'' the statement said. The victims were identified as Petty Officer 3rd Class <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Childress </PERSON>, 22, of <LOCATION> Ham </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, and Airman Recruit <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brunson </PERSON>, 19, of <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. `` An investigation into the cause of the explosion is now under way,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> statement said. It said the <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is continuing on her assigned mission, a previously scheduled deployment to the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>. The ship left <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION> on Thursday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 1023EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Gorbachev 1stLd-Writethru a0656 05-14 0262</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Gorbachev, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0656,0266</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gorbachev Arrives in Irkutsk on Way to China</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with three grafs with Gorbachev arriving in Siberian city.
Pickup 4th graf, ``Tass said ...''</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> left Sunday for <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and the first Soviet-Chinese summit meeting in 30 years. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s morning departure, reported by the <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency, came a day early. He arrived in the Siberian city of <LOCATION> Irkutsk </LOCATION>, where Soviet <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesmen in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> said he would rest before continuing to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> on Monday. The spokesman spoke on condition of anonymity. <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> called the visit to <LOCATION> Irkutsk </LOCATION> a `` working stop-over,'' and said he had a `` warm talk with working people'' at the airport. <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was accompanied by Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>, who just returned from a visit to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, and Politburo member <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yakovlev </PERSON>, alternate Politburo member <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Maslyukov </PERSON> and Health Minister <PERSON> Yevgeny </PERSON> <PERSON> Chazov </PERSON>. The last Soviet-Chinese summit was in 1959 when <PERSON> Nikita </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON> met <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse-tung </PERSON>. Relations soured then as <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> challenged the Soviet claim to leadership of the world communist movement. Both sides expect <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s meetings with <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> will normalize their governmental and party relations, and help ease the remaining tensions along their 4,300-mile border. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> announced last week that it will begin withdrawing soldiers from its Mongolian ally on Monday, the day <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s visit to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is to begin. Soviet soldiers were stationed in <LOCATION> Mongolia </LOCATION>, sandwiched between the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, because of border disputes that flared briefly into fighting in the late 1960s.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 1107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Lebanon-Missing 1stLd-Writethru   05-14 0349</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Lebanon-Missing, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0661,0360</SECOND>
<HEAD>PRECEDE Beirut</HEAD>
<HEAD>German Returns To Office in Lebanon, 10 Days After His Reported Kidnapping</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with Berri, Quint comments. ADDS byline.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By AHMED MANTASH</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ZAHRANI, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A West German relief worker who disappeared 10 days ago returned on Sunday to his organization's headquarters <PERSON> Markus </PERSON> <PERSON> Quint </PERSON> arrived at the ASME-Humanitas base in this southern town of <LOCATION> Zahrani </LOCATION> accompanied by <PERSON> Nabih </PERSON> <PERSON> Berri </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amal </ORGANIZATION> militia. <PERSON> Berri </PERSON>, also the justice minister in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s Moslem cabinet, said his militia obtained <PERSON> Quint </PERSON>'s release from kidnappers, but he refused to identify the kidnappers. `` I do n't want to say anything that will hurt <PERSON> Quint </PERSON> and his colleagues,'' <PERSON> Berri </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Quint </PERSON>, wearing a brown track suit and smoking a cigarette, turned to the pro-Syrian militia chief and thanked him for his help in his return. <PERSON> Quint </PERSON> disappeared on May 4. There had been no claim of responsibility. Palestinian guerrilla leaders had said unidentified kidnappers were holding <PERSON> Quint </PERSON> in connection with the case of <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> hijacker <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamadi </PERSON>. On Saturday, the West German newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Bild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> am </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sonntag </ORGANIZATION> reported <PERSON> Quint </PERSON> had signed a letter saying he was abducted in connection with <PERSON> Hamadi </PERSON> case. `` The kidnappers are demanding a mild sentence for <PERSON> Hamadi </PERSON>,'' it said. West German officials did not comment on the report. <PERSON> Hamadi </PERSON>, a Lebanese Shiite Moslem, faces life in prison if convicted of murder and air piracy in the June 1985 hijacking of a <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> jetliner and the slaying of an <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> diver on board. He confessed to the hijacking but denies taking part in the murder. He is on trial in <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. A verdict that is expected Wednesday. There are 15 foreigners held hostage in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, including nine Americans. The hostage held longest is <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. He was seized March 16, 1985. In addition, <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>, an elderly Briton, disappeared Friday, and his wife said she believes he has been kidnapped. ASME-Humanitas is a private organization that provides medical aid, mainly to Palestinian refugees in the camps of <PERSON> Ein </PERSON> el-Hilweh and <PERSON> Mieh </PERSON> <PERSON> Mieh </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 1134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Britain-Israel     05-14 0303</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Britain-Israel,0311</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Israel and South Africa Involved in Technology Plot</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A newspaper said Sunday that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Mossad </LOCATION> secret service was involved in South African efforts to obtain British missile technology. The Sunday Telegraph, a conservative weekly, attributed its report to unidentified `` security sources in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>.'' It said the sources claimed Mossad and the South African arms manufacturer <ORGANIZATION> Armscor </ORGANIZATION> were linked to an operation that led to the arrests of five men in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> last month in an arms deal. The report said, `` The ultimate goal of the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> operation is thought to have been for <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to undertake joint development of a series of high-speed missiles for use by both ground and air forces.'' It claimed three of the men arested in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> were <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> Protestants who allegedly were negotiating with a South African diplomat and a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms dealer to exchange British missile parts made in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> for South African arms. According to the newspaper, the plan involved smuggling parts of the shoulder-launched Blowpipe missile to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> to enable <ORGANIZATION> Armscor </ORGANIZATION> to develop its own missiles. It said <ORGANIZATION> Mossad </ORGANIZATION> wanted to acquire the technology for <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s Starstreak missile. Both the Blowpipe and Starstreak missiles are made at the <ORGANIZATION> Short </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> factory in <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. The Sunday Telegraph said <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s MI6 intelligence service was trying to determine how <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> activists in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> received arms believed to have been purchased with South African money and shipped through militia groups in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. `` It is here that sources believe <PERSON> Mossad </PERSON> actively assisted with the South African operation,'' the newspaper said. Protestant and Roman Catholic militants have been battling in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> for nearly 20 years. The Catholics want to unite the <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> province, where Protestants outnumber Caholics 3-2, with the predominantly <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 1134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Lebanon     05-14 0423</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Lebanon,0435</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fighting in Hills, Coastal Shelling Persists</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RIMA SALAMEH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Syrian and allied Druse gunners showered the besieged Christian heartland with sporadic artillery fire on Sunday, and gun battles broke out in the hills above <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. Police said Gen. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s Christian troops were locked in sniper fire and rocket-propelled grenade duels with Syrian and Druse forces at the mountaintop town of Souk el-Gharb southeast of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. The strategic town sits atop a road network leading from the Druse territory in the <LOCATION> Chouf </LOCATION> mountains to the Christian enclave north and northeast of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. No casualties were reported at the Souk el-Gharb front. Police said at least 40 shells were fired from Syrian-controlled west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> onto a coastal stretch running trough the port of <LOCATION> Byblos </LOCATION>, 19 miles north of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. No casualties were reported in the barrage, apparently aimed at preventing ships from entering the harbor. At least 359 people have been killed and 1,393 wounded since the current round of fighting in the 14-year-old war broke out March 8. The confrontation began when <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s gunboats and helicopter gunships blockaded illegal ports run by Moslem militias south of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. Druse warlord <PERSON> Walid </PERSON> <PERSON> Jumblatt </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Progressive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> retaliated by shelling the Christian enclave. The Syrians later joined the bombardment and sealed off the enclave's land and sea outlets. The fighting Sunday came despite a truce called by the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, the fourth cease-fire called by the group in two months. Arab League mediators proclaimed the latest cease-fire Thursday, calling it an `` inland truce'' to halt the shelling duels that wreaked havoc on <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s Moslem and <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> sectors and many summer resort towns in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s central mountains. <PERSON> Lakhdar </PERSON> <PERSON> Ibrahimi </PERSON>, a secretary-general of the 22-member <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, said he would begin new negotiations with the warring factions this week. Ibrahimi was in <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION> on Sunday where he met with Syrian Foreign Minister <PERSON> Farouk </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharaa </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s allies said they would keep shelling the Christian coast, despite the truce, to prevent arms supplies to <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s 20,000 troops. They contend that at least three ships carrying arms from <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> were waiting in international waters off <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> to cruise in and resupply the Christian forces. <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s spokesmen have denied the claim. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> is <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s main Arab foe. The Syrians maintain 40,000 troops stationed in 70 percent of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> under a 1976 peacekeeping mandate from the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> has charged the Syrians have become an occupation force because they sided with the Moslems. He has vowed to drive them out of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 1134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Sakharov     05-14 0215</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sakharov,0221</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sakharov Calls for Democracy, Criticizes Gorbachev</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MILAN, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Human rights activist <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> said Sunday that the reforms of Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> have not gone far enough to cure an ailing economy or bring democracy. The 1975 Nobel Peace Prize winner flew to <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> on Saturday with his wife, <PERSON> Yelena </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonner </PERSON>, to speak at an Italian <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> congress in the northern city of <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>, who was recently elected to the new Soviet parliament, said that while <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms were `` moving in the right direction'' in foreign affairs, `` there are many aspects that are causing profound distress.'' `` Economic reforms go ever more slowly and the people are losing interest in their work because they ca n't buy anything,'' he said. He said the stagnation was occurring because the government dismantled old bureaucratic structures but has not created new ones. The 67-year-old physicist criticized <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> for emergency measures he had taken to limit demonstrations in the wake of nationalist uprisings. `` We are in a blind alley, and there have been various political decisions taken lately which I will not hesitate to define as anti-democratic,'' he said. <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> was detained for nearly seven years in the northern city of <LOCATION> Gorky </LOCATION> after he criticized the Soviets' 1979 military intervention in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 1135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-NorthKorea-Iran     05-14 0247</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-North Korea-Iran,0255</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iranian President Arrives in North Korea</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 100,000 <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Koreans </LOCATION> greeted Iranian President <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Khamenei </PERSON> on Sunday as he arrived in their capital to drum up aid for rebuilding his country, devastated by the eight-year war with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. Crowds lined the streets of <LOCATION> Pyongyang </LOCATION> shouting `` Friendship and unity!'' according to the <ORGANIZATION> Korean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, monitored in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Khamenei </PERSON> arrived after a six-day visit to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and was received by North Korean President <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> <PERSON> Sung </PERSON> at the presidential palace, the agency said. <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> radio, monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, quoted <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> as saying he looked forward to an expansion of ties between <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. The radio said <PERSON> Khamenei </PERSON> told his host: `` Fortunately our countries enjoy friendly ties at the best possible level.'' Neither the North Korean agency nor <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> radio said how long <PERSON> Khamenei </PERSON> would stay in <LOCATION> Pyongyang </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> has been strengthening relations with non-Western industrialized nations that could help its postwar construction. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> were the main suppliers of arms to the <LOCATION> Islamic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> throughout the Iran-Iraq war, when a Western arms embargo virtually isolated <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. A cease-fire took effect Aug. 20. Both <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> hope to pick up lucrative reconstruction projects in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. The North Korean daily <PERSON> Rodong </PERSON> <PERSON> Shinmun </PERSON> said: `` The <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> people will steadily develop friendly and cooperative relations with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'' in their common struggle against `` imperialism in ideas of independence, peace and friendship,'' according to the North Korean agency.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 1135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SouthKorea     05-14 0451</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-South Korea,0464</SECOND>
<HEAD>Violence Grows in Kwangju as Grim Anniversary Nears</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By M.H. AHN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KWANGJU, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Riot troops Sunday broke up a march by thousands of people protesting the death of a radical student they claim was tortured and killed by police. Police used clubs and shields on the crowd of about 5,000 who gathered outside the provincial government headquarters in <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION>, 170 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>. Some protesters were trampled as people tried to force their way past police. Injuries were seen during the violent confrontation but police said they had no figures. Radical students pelted police with rocks and bricks as fighting surged up and down <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION>'s main street. Hundreds of onlookers jeered and yelled insults as police tried to clear the street by marching in lines with interlocked shields. `` Down with the military dictatorship!'' protesters chanted. `` Drive out the <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>!'' A larger but less-violent protest was held Saturday, and a march by about 1,000 people earlier on Sunday was peaceful. The marches were called by radical students to protest the death of <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Chul-kyu </PERSON>, whose body was found Wednesday in a reservoir near <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION>. Authorities fear <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s death will keep heightening tensions in <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION>, which marks the anniversary this week of the May 18, 1980, uprising in which at least 192 people were killed. Many students blame President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-woo </PERSON>, a former military general, for the bloody suppression of the uprising. All police in <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION> and nearby areas were put on special alert. Dissidents claim <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, who was being sought by police for anti-government activities, was tortured to death by authorities. Police said an autopsy last week showed no signs of torture and that pathology tests Sunday confirmed the existence of plankton in his body, indicating death by drowning. To ensure the credibility of the tests, authorities allowed two independent medical experts and opposition lawmakers to take part in or witness the process. Radical student leaders told reporters they would appeal to <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, the London-based human rights group, to conduct an independent investigation if the official Korean probe concluded police were blameless. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hyung-jang </PERSON>, one of the student leaders, claimed government pathologists were helping cover up police involvement. `` We can not trust them,'' he told the news conference. During the march, dissidents called for the overthrow of <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> and demanded the expulsion of the 43,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops based in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. The dissidents claim <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are trying to impose authoritarian rule on the country. Radical students and dissidents, estimated by government officials at 10,000, are a well-organized minority in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s 42 million population But they lack public support because of their violent tactics and extreme views.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890514-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-89 1135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Britain-Fire     05-14 0185</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Britain-Fire,0190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scottish Extremists Claim Fire Was Anti-Nuclear Protest</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
