<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 2354EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HardwoodProtest     11-10 0259</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hardwood Protest,0266</SECOND>
<HEAD>Protestors Say New Courthouse Will Decimate Rain Forests</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY LOPEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hardwood paneling may lend a stately air to a courtroom, but environmental activists are angry that a new state courthouse will be decorated with 47,000 square feet of mahogany from shrinking rain forests. `` Our halls of justice should not be decorated through the death of tropical rain forests,'' <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> said as he and other menbers of the <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rainforest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> picketed the site Friday. The building on the Capitol mall will house the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> as well as most of the <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> and other court-related agencies. The blueprints call for use of 32,880 square feet of -RCB- - inch plywood and 14,520 square feet of \ - inch mahogany plywood, according to Most mahogany comes from rain forests in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>, and there are estimates that about five acres of rain forest disappear every minute to meet <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> demand for tropical timber. Environmentalists say destruction of the rain forests threatens the natural balance and is detroying the lives of many indigenous tribes. Chief Justice <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> was n't available Friday, a state holiday, to comment on the issue, and the vice chief justice, <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON>, did n't return calls to his <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> homes. The demonstrators said the government should send a signal by using maple, ash, or other hardwoods cut in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. But <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> added, `` I frankly do n't think using any kind of hardwood is going to make a better justice system.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 2355EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     11-10 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0026</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 02; 03; 18; 32; 39; 41.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 2355EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     11-10 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0090</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 02; 03; 18; 32; 39; 41.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 1-6-5-6.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 04; 07; 22; 25; 27; 36.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 04; 15; 24; 30; 39; 46. Bonus: 04887.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday 54 Lotto Game: 03; 09; 32; 36; 38; 42. Supplementary 11.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 4-6-7-2.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 1-2-9; 1-0-7-5; 8-7-7-2-0; 7-5-2-6-3-6.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 2357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MissingCouple 3rdLd-Writethru a0402 11-10 0330</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Missing Couple, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0402,0335</SECOND>
<HEAD>GM Exec, Wife, Found Shot to Death in Park</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs last 2 grafs to change to past tense.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GRETEL WIKLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROCHESTER HILLS, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> executive and his wife were found shot to death, their bodies dumped in a park, after their home was ransacked and robbed Friday, police and <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents said. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Wanda </PERSON> <PERSON> Tarr </PERSON>'s neighbors reported a possible break-in about 5:30 a.m. Friday. The couple was not there, and police said it appeared they had had been abducted. Their bodies were discovered by a woman walking her dog in a park in nearby <LOCATION> Pontiac </LOCATION> later Friday. Each had been shot several times. `` We do not believe they were shot at the home,'' said <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Helterhoff </PERSON>, who heads <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> operations in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. `` They were shot somewhere between the house and the park.'' Investigators believe Mrs. <PERSON> Tarr </PERSON> may have abducted during an outing Thursday evening, forced to withdraw cash from the couple's bank account at a 24-hour teller machine and then taken to her home by her assailants, Helterhoff said After the house was ransacked, the Tarrs were abducted, he said. There was no forced entry at the house, he added. Deputies found no signs of violence or a struggle, police Sgt. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Quisenberry </PERSON> said. The couple's two cars, a 1989 Geo Prizm and a 1988 Chevrolet Cavalier, were missing. Guns, liquor, jewelry and part of a coin collection were believed taken from the home, Helterhoff added. Helterhoff said the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> was questioning neighbors and relatives and had talked with two of the couple's children, college students who were n't at the home Friday. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Tarr </PERSON> was assistant manager of marketing information and research for <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION>'s Chevrolet Division headquarters in <LOCATION> Warren </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Crellin </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON>, director of public relations for <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION>'s Chevrolet Division, said <PERSON> Tarr </PERSON> supervised the collection and analysis of sales data from across the country for Chevrolet.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APAppointment     11-10 0196</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Appointment,0202</SECOND>
<HEAD>AP Appoints New Director of Graphics</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Monahan </PERSON> has been named assistant managing editor for graphics of The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The announcement was made Thursday by <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boccardi </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> president and general manager. <PERSON> Monahan </PERSON>, 34, had been director of <ORGANIZATION> Gannett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>'s graphics network, which he helped develop in 1987 The next year he was named coordinator of <ORGANIZATION> Gannett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Graphics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>, and he was named director this year. <PERSON> Monahan </PERSON> will oversee the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s graphics department, which produces a daily graphics report for hundreds of newspapers in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and around the world. While at <ORGANIZATION> Gannett </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Monahan </PERSON> was instrumental in setting up the <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> Today @ <ORGANIZATION> Apple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>. He is the creator and editor of the <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Design </ORGANIZATION>'s monthly newsletter, `` Deadline Mac.'' He also helped develop MacTrac, a series of week-long training seminars held at <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Poynter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Petersburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, for newspaper Macintosh artists. He has taught workshops and classes in computer graphics at <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> School of Design. A graduate of <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION>, he also worked as a graphic artist for The Patriot Ledger in <LOCATION> Quincy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-GrayRefusal     11-10 0765</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Gray Refusal,0787</SECOND>
<HEAD>Some Israelis Dodge Military Duty in Occupied Lands</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ARIEH O'SULLIVAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More and more Israeli army reservists are coming up with a wide variety of excuses to avoid duty in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> to put down the Palestinian uprising known as the intefadah. One reservist, identifying himself as <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON>, a 25-year-old architecture student, said he invented `` psychological problems'' to get out of serving. `` There is a limit to what I will do,'' he said. `` If I killed a Palestinian kid, I do n't think I could live with it.'' Others called up arrive at induction centers on crutches or with letters from employers saying they are too essential to the business to be let go. Some claim illness. It is what Israelis call a `` gray refusal'' _ getting out of duty without directly refusing to serve, which would challenge the pride that Israelis hold for their army. Some have legitimate excuses. Others feel their previous combat training is wasted on what they view as essentially police work. Still others believe the uprising is not a real military threat to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Most reservists interviewed said they would not hesitate to serve if <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> faced a war or some other serious threat. `` But nobody feels threatened by the intefadeh,'' said <PERSON> Andre </PERSON> <PERSON> Dreszin </PERSON>, a spokesman for the conscientious objectors' group Yesh Gvul. `` It's not like the Egyptian and Syrian tanks in 1973 where if we did n't stop them they would have made it to <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION>.'' Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Ehud </PERSON> <PERSON> Gross </PERSON>, the army's chief education officer, said 61 soldiers had been tried for refusing to serve in the occupied territories and he called it `` an ignorable number.'' `` I do believe that today there is no problem with the mission,'' he added. `` There are some refuseniks, who decline to serve in the territories. Those are the minority. The vast consensus is against them.'' The newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Yediot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ahronot </ORGANIZATION> recently quoted senior army officers as estimating the number who avoid service in the territories has grown into the `` thousands.'' `` What is significant about this new phenomena is that it includes those who do n't usually try to evade service, like senior officers and guys from elite units,'' said <PERSON> Ariela </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>, a reporter on military affairs for the newspaper. Virtually all Israeli men and women serve two to three years of mandatory service starting at age 18. Men continue in the reserve until age 56, and it is estimated the army can triple its size by calling up 370,000 reservists within a few days. Since the uprising began in December 1987, seven <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers have been killed, including a 28-year-old reservist whose skull was crushed by a stone dropped from a roof by a Palestinian. At least 600 Arabs have been killed by soldiers or <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> civilians, and 33 Israeli civilians also have been slain. <PERSON> Dreszin </PERSON>, the conscientious objector who has not been called up during the uprising but served 63 days in jail for refusing service in the <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> war, said some reservists avoid service by using minor illnesses that they would disregard if called up for a real war. `` They exploit their illness,'' he said. `` They say to themselves, ` Why should I ignore my medical problems if they help me stay out of the territories?''' Reservists usually receive their call-up notices in the mail weeks in advance, so they have plenty of time to work out excuses. Letters from professors telling of upcoming exams are plentiful on call-up day, as well as those from employers and doctors. `` If you cry enough in the army they will say, ` Go home,' just to get rid of you; you are demoralizing,'' said a 32-year-old lawyer and father of three identifying himself only as <PERSON> Motti </PERSON>. There are other ways to get out of duty in the territories. One officer was indicted for accepting bribes from reservists to assign them to an `` easy posting.'' <ORGANIZATION> Yediot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ahronot </ORGANIZATION> also reported that one man called to duty fired a few rounds into the air and shouted, `` We're going to kill Arabs!'' His intent was to have officers declare him too unstable. Among soldiers who do serve in the territories, despite misgivings, some have found their own ways to protect their ideals. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, 29, a soft-spoken immigrant from <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, recently served 16 days in <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>'s largest city, but said he ignored orders to fire at stone throwers. `` Some of the guys were shooting at the kids as they got off the truck,'' he said. `` I shot at a garbage can.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     11-10 0411</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0429</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FLORENCE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Environmentalists will honor a farmer who won a battle of wits with bugs. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Szynal </PERSON>, a farmer in the western <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION> and chief mechanic at <ORGANIZATION> Woods </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION>, will be presented on Saturday with an award from the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> for a homemade device that vacuums bugs off potato plants. He developed the `` Beetle Eater'' two years ago at the request of another farmer, who did n't want to use pesticides. It can suck potato beetles off four rows of plants at one time as it is towed through a field. The machine can clean 50 to 70 acres of potatoes in a day and removes 75 to 95 percent of the beetles, according to <PERSON> Szynal </PERSON>. `` This farmer walked into my garage ... and said, ` You've got to invent something to take the bugs off the plant. The spray's killing me,''' <PERSON> Szynal </PERSON> said Thursday `` Ten days later I had a machine rolling.'' The key to the machine is a blower that dislodges the beetles; a vacuum hose then scoops them up. `` The <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> potato beetle likes to play dead as soon as it senses any noise or movement, that's why we had to add the blower to shake them up,'' <PERSON> Szynal </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Szynal </PERSON> has other inventions for the farm. There's a vacuum device that debugs strawberry plants, a plastic cutter that makes round holes in plastic ground covers for corn plants, and an automatic pickle picker. `` It used to be I'd put my whole week's pay into my inventions and be broke by Wednesday,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>EVANSVILLE, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two men who reeled in a cat from an old water well say their feat is no fish story. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolfinger </PERSON> and <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, reserve officers for the <ORGANIZATION> Vanderburgh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, said workers at a truck stop heard a cat's meows from a well. The attached a towel to a hook and dropped fishing line 45 feet down an 8-inch water pipe. The cat clawed on to the towel, and the men pulled it to safety. `` I thought that by instinct they like to claw things and I thought that if I could get a piece of cloth down to it, it would grab on,'' <PERSON> Wolfinger </PERSON> said. He said someone apparently had dropped the cat in the well because a heavy hinged lid over the opening had been closed. A worker took the cat home.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NBCTour     11-10 0238</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-NBC Tour,0244</SECOND>
<HEAD>NBC Opens Revamped Studio Tour</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s studio tour, begun at Rockefeller Center shortly after the network moved there at the dawn of radio's golden age in 1933, has a new look focusing on modern TV technology like satellites and robotic cameras. The revamped tour was formally opened Thursday by <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, who said the aim of the updated backstage tour is to `` make it as contemporary as possible.'' The tours, which were discontinued in 1977, then resumed six years later, draw nearly 200,000 people annually. The one-hour trip costs $ 7. A similar tour is available at <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> studios in <LOCATION> Burbank </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. Looks at the studios where `` Today'' and `` Saturday Night Live'' originate still are included in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> tour Each trip ends in a small studio where the customers can appear in a mock version of the `` Tonight'' show and see themselves on TV monitors. The tours are conducted by a staff of pages whose precedecessors include `` Nightline'' anchorman <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Koppel </PERSON>, actress <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and former <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Chairman Grant Tinker. Although the tours begin in what <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> calls the `` radio orientation theater'' and include videotaped looks at <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s radio days, no tours of radio broadcast operations are given, for such operations no longer exist at <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, owner of <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, sold the company's radio networks in 1987 to <ORGANIZATION> Westwood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> One </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LostCat     11-10 0210</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lost Cat,0216</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Calls in Detective, Lawyer in Her Search for Lost Cat</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GRAND RAPIDS, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some people have trouble finding homes for unwanted cats. One cat, though, is wanted by two families, and a detective and lawyer have been called in. In June, <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Bouman </PERSON>'s parents gave her 2-year-old cat, <PERSON> Dee </PERSON> <PERSON> Dee </PERSON>, to the the local <ORGANIZATION> Humane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> while she was in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> studying French. The cat had begun urinating in the house and bringing home dead mice. <PERSON> Bouman </PERSON> reacted in horror to the news and called the society from <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. She pleaded with them not to put <PERSON> Dee </PERSON> <PERSON> Dee </PERSON> to sleep. `` I told them I'd fly home immediately to claim the cat,'' said <PERSON> Bouman </PERSON>, now a student at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION>. Too late: Another family had adopted <PERSON> Dee </PERSON> <PERSON> Dee </PERSON>. Humane Society Director <PERSON> Betsy </PERSON> <PERSON> Pullen </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dee </PERSON> <PERSON> Dee </PERSON>'s new family wo n't give her up, and she wo n't make them. `` The cat is very content,'' <PERSON> Pullen </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bouman </PERSON> hired a private detective for $ 200 to track down the new owners. When that did n't work, she hired a lawyer. Some of <PERSON> Bouman </PERSON>'s friends think she's gone overboard, but she does n't care. `` Pets can be best friends, and that's what <PERSON> Dee </PERSON> <PERSON> Dee </PERSON> was to me,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Cannibalism     11-10 0128</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Cannibalism,0131</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three To Be Tried for Cannibalism</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LIBREVILLE, Gabon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two men and a woman alleged to have eaten human flesh during a ritual initiation ceremony will be tried on charges of murder and cannibalism, the national news agency said. The <ORGANIZATION> Gabonese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday that Mba Ntem, <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Mve </PERSON> <PERSON> Owono </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sabine </PERSON> <PERSON> Benga </PERSON> are charged with clubbing and stabbing to death <PERSON> Andre </PERSON> <PERSON> Ondo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ndong </PERSON> in the suburban community of <LOCATION> Owendo </LOCATION>. The trio then allegedly ate <PERSON> Ndong </PERSON>'s stomach, liver, heart, lungs, tongue and genitals in a ritual ceremony led by <PERSON> Ntem </PERSON>. The news agency did not give further details about the type of ceremony. Murder and cannibalism are both punishable by death in this West African country. The three will be tried Nov. 23.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0043EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BerlinWall     11-10 0674</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Berlin Wall,0693</SECOND>
<HEAD>Berlin Wall, Symbol of Communist East Germany</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-East Germany, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The jagged, gray concrete wall that divides <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> is a Cold War symbol of freedom denied. It was built under the direction of <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> to stop the hemorrhage of East Germans fleeing to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> _ about 2.5 million escaped to freedom from 1949 until Aug. 13, 1961. Now, in one of history's ironies, the flight to freedom of hundreds of thousands of East Germans around the wall and through neighboring countries has forced the Communist government to back down and declare free travel will be allowed. And 77-year-old <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> has been swept out as <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader by the exodus and by protests by East Germans demanding democratic reforms. The 15-foot-high structure cut through the city, dividing families, friend from friend, <PERSON> Berliner </PERSON> from <LOCATION> Berliner </LOCATION> and communism from capitalism. It drew American presidents like <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> who declared: `` Ich bin <PERSON> ein </PERSON> <PERSON> Berliner </PERSON>.'' It drew tourists like onlookers viewing the scene of a grim accident. Hundreds of brave East Germans tried to scale the wall or tunnel under it or crash through a checkpoint. Many died in the attempt. The 28-mile-long wall is only a part of elaborate fortifications that stretch all along the 860-mile border between <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. A barrier of barbed wire, armed guards, death strips and eerie lights that played over the border at night. But it was the cold concrete wall in <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, which is surrounded by East German territory, that became the symbol. `` We kept telling ourselves, ` You can not put a wall right through a major city,'' said <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Haar </PERSON> on the wall's 25th anniversary. `` Now we're used to it.'' Visiting presidents and prime ministers climbed a special stand to peer over the wall into <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Many called for the wall to be dismantled. But <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> insisted they dared not open the wall. <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> said time and again: `` The wall will remain as long as the conditions that led to is construction endure.'' With the political change sweeping in from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and striking reforms taking place in nearby <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, the discredited and hard-line East German was finally overwhelmed by a popular revolt. From barbed wire and simple barricades started in 1961, the wall has grown in some areas to a pair of parallel concrete barriers with a `` death strip'' in between. Many escape attempts have ended with freedom-seekers lying dead in the shadows of the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall or somewhere along the frontier between the two countries. Running, driving and even swimming, thousands of people have been caught trying to flee from <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> over the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall or across fortifications along the border with <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Mention of the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall conjures up memories not only of desperate escape attempts, but also of major spy swaps between East and West. For years, border guards watching out for escapes had shoot-to-kill orders, but earlier this year the East Germans announced the orders had been lifted. According to West German statistics, up until recently as many as 4,000 people were held in East German jails and prisons in connection with failed escape attempts. The East German government has since pardoned them and they are to be released by the end of the month. The Aug. 13 <ORGANIZATION> Working </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> organization that tracks human rights abuses in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, estimates a total of 191 people were killed trying to flee <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> between 1961 and 1988. In the first few months after the wall was erected, 14 trucks rammed holes in the barrier. In September 1962, 147 people dug under the wall in the largest of several successful tunnel escapes. In 1983, two young men used an archery bow to fire a cable over the wall from an attic to an accomplice on a rooftop in the West. They attached pulleys to the cable and rode in the dark over the heads of guards to the West.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0009EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MilitaryJetCrash 8thLd-Writethru a0873 11-10 1091</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Military Jet Crash, 8th Ld-Writethru, a0873,1120</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 5 grafs to UPDATE with two buildings destroyed, two
heavily damaged. Picks up 5th graf pvs, `Capt. George...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos AX7, AX8, AX9, NY65</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SONYA ROSS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SMYRNA, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> fighter jet exploded and crashed into an apartment complex while attempting to land near this <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> suburb Thursday evening, engulfing several buildings in a fireball that left five people missing. <LOCATION> Smyrna </LOCATION> police Lt. J.L. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said officers believed at least one man was trapped and killed in the fire that destroyed two apartment buildings and heavily damaged two others. Officials gave conflicting estimates of the number of injured ranging from four to 12 people. `` My first officer on the scene said he heard screams, but the building was engulfed in flames and he could n't get in,'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said. By late Thursday night, however, authorities had accounted for everyone in the two buildings that were destroyed and found no bodies in nine of 12 apartment units whose occupants had not been located, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Cobb </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> emergency management director. Five people were unaccounted for in the remaining three apartments, which were to be searched later in the night. Capt. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Brogdon </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Smyrna </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said several injuries were serious. Among the injured was the pilot, who was in critical condition with burns and internal injuries after ejecting from the plane. Authorities said the A-7E Corsair II attack jet crashed shortly after 6 p.m. into the Pine Village Apartments off <LOCATION> Windy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION>, a heavily traveled thoroughfare lined with scores of apartment complexes and businesses. Witnesses said the plane landed in a parking lot, setting several cars on fire and spewing burning fuel over the buildings. The fire was under control about two hours after the crash. Several witnesses said the jet exploded in the air. `` I saw it out my kitchen window. It was stable, then it just exploded in the air and went straight down,'' said <PERSON> Tawanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>, who lives in an adjacent apartment complex. `` When I went outside, I saw a ball of fire heading toward the ground,'' said eyewitness <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>. `` After the second or third explosion, the pilot ejected himself from the seat.'' <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> said he saw the pilot's parachute deploy when he was just about 100 feet above the ground. `` When I got to the pilot to give him CPR, he had multiple contusions and was bleeding profusely from the nose and mouth. I gave him CPR and got him as comfortable as possible.'' <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Honore </PERSON> said the pilot, a Naval reservist, was attempting to land at <ORGANIZATION> Dobbins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, about 15 miles north of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, but crashed 2.5 miles short of the runway. The jet is based at the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Station </ORGANIZATION>, which is located at <LOCATION> Dobbins </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Honore </PERSON>, who said the plane carried no ammunition, could not confirm that the jet exploded in the air. He said authorities did not know what caused the crash. A <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, Cmdr. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, said he presumed the plane was on a routine training mission. <PERSON> Joy </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmiedt </PERSON>, who lives two miles from the complex, said she heard two explosions and her TV blinked off. `` I went to door and saw flames in the air. -LRB- I -RRB- went over there and -LRB- the place -RRB- was just totally engulfed in flames,'' she said. Ms. <PERSON> Schmiedt </PERSON>, a nurse, ran to the scene and offered help. `` It was a horrible sight. I'm convinced there are people still in their apartments they have n't found.'' A resident of the apartment complex, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Finch </PERSON>, said he escaped from the building along with his wife. He said he saw a woman and a girl run out from another unit engulfed in flames. `` I do n't think the husband made it out,'' <PERSON> Finch </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON>, 21, said he had been away from his apartment visiting friends. `` I got back in time just to see my apartment on fire,'' he said. `` It's gone. There's nothing left.'' He said he was searching for a friend who he thinks was at home. `` I do n't know if he's dead or alive,'' <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Smyrna </LOCATION> Fire Chief <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> originally said 12 people, including the pilot, were injured. But <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> later said he was lowering the count to four. A check at area hospitals also indicated four people were injured. <PERSON> Brogdon </PERSON>, however, said police were standing by their earlier count of seven injured. He said some of the injured might not have been admitted to hospitals. Most of the injured were taken to <ORGANIZATION> Kennestone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospitals </ORGANIZATION>, two sister medical centers in <LOCATION> Marietta </LOCATION>, as a huge traffic jam of emergency vehicles, rush-hour commuters and curiosity seekers quickly developed. The pilot, a reservist who was not identified, was in critical condition after undergoing surgery late Thursday night, said <PERSON> Kennestone </PERSON> official <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Ballew </PERSON>. A 28-year-old woman and her 5-year-old daughter were in critical condition with burns at <LOCATION> Grady </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Grady </PERSON> spokeswoman <PERSON> Beverly </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>. The mother was identified as 28-year-old <PERSON> Margie </PERSON> <PERSON> Padovani </PERSON> by <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Padgett </PERSON>, a spokeswoman at <LOCATION> Kennestone </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, where the two were taken initally. <PERSON> Ballew </PERSON> said another woman was being treated for minor injuries at <ORGANIZATION> Kennestone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Windy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, a sister hospital of <LOCATION> Kennestone </LOCATION>. Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION>, a friend of the pilot, said he flew the same plane earlier Thursday on a separate training mission. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> said it was in `` beautiful'' shape at the time. He said he does n't have any idea what might have causd the crash. He said he and the pilot, who still had not been unidentified, both work at <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> and had put in time with the reserves. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> said he has known the pilot for about three years and described him as a `` capable, excellent'' pilot. Asked whether the pilots worry when they fly over heavily populated areas during training missions, <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> said, `` It's a concern. You have a tremendous concern for the people around here.'' The A-7E, which entered service as the A-7 in the 1965, is a single-seat attack aircraft used for a variety of bombing missions on land and at sea. The current version has undergone a number of modifications. The A-7E has a 20mm gun and can carry payloads of up to 15,000 pounds of bombs and missiles. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> records indicate that A-7E Corsair IIs were part of the two-carrier battle group that conducted a joint strike on selected Libyan terrorist-related targets in 1986. Together with carrier-based F-A-18s, A-7s used anti-radar missiles to neutralize air defenses.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0014EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ShakespeareSold     11-10 0353</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Shakespeare Sold,0363</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shakespeare's Four Folios Fetch $2 Million</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A set of the first four successive editions of <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>'s collected plays was sold Thursday for $ 2 million, a record for what are known as the `` Four Folios,'' Sotheby's said. Apart from an unfinished attempt in 1619 to publish a collected issue of <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>'s plays, the Folios were the only collected editions printed in the 17th Century, according to the auction catalog. `` I never paid $ 2 million for anything before,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Cummins </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> dealer who bought the Folios for a customer he would identify only as a private American collector. `` I'm a little nervous but excited.'' <PERSON> Cummins </PERSON> said he and his customer had been looking for at least the first Folio for about five years. `` The first Folio is the first collected works of <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>,'' he explained. `` The four together are exceedingly desirable, but the first Folio is the one that you're really paying a premium to get because it's almost impossible to find a fine copy and this is a very, very nice copy indeed.'' A first edition of the two volumes of `` El ingenioso hidalgo <PERSON> don </PERSON> <PERSON> Quixote </PERSON> de la Mancha,'' by <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cervantes </PERSON> <PERSON> Saavedra </PERSON>, sold for $ 1.65 million to a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> dealer, said a <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s spokesman, <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Weigman </PERSON>. A first edition of <PERSON> Nicolaus </PERSON> <PERSON> Copernicus </PERSON>' `` De revolutionibus orbium coelestium,'' dated 1543, in which he first put forth the theory that the sun is at the center of the planets, sold for $ 473,000 to an Italian dealer. The same dealer paid the same price for what <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s said is the only copy in private hands of the first edition of the first printed announcement of <PERSON> Copernicus </PERSON>'s heliocentric theory. `` De libris revolutionum ... <PERSON> Nicolai </PERSON> <PERSON> Copernici </PERSON> ... narratio prima,'' was written by <PERSON> Georg </PERSON> <PERSON> Joachim </PERSON> <PERSON> Rheticus </PERSON> in 1540. The works in Thursday's sale, which drew $ 10.4 million, came from <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Garden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION> collection of books and manuscripts relating to the history of ideas. It was amassed by <PERSON> Haven </PERSON> <PERSON> O'More </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> over more than 25 years as part of a publishing venture, <PERSON> Weigman </PERSON> said. The sale continues Friday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0029EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-King-Abernathy     11-10 0433</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-King-Abernathy,0448</SECOND>
<HEAD>King Tells Abernathy Book Was Unfair To His Father</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Rev. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>'s eldest son told the Rev. <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> that the former King aide's book about his father was unfair, a newspaper said In an interview Thursday to be published in Friday's editions of The Tennessean, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> said he had spoken with <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> following the dedication of the Civil Rights Memorial in <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION> `` I told him I have always been taught to love people and I still love you,'' <PERSON> King </PERSON> said. `` I said, ` I think your treatment of my father was unfair.' But I told him I loved him and I always will.'' It was believed to be the first time a member of the King family had talked to <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> since the publication of his autobiography, `` And The Walls Came Tumbling Down.'' <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON>, 63, was president of the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> from 1968 to 1977 and was King's closest aide during the civil rights movement. He wrote that King spent the night with two women and fought with a third in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> the night before he was assassinated by <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>. <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON>'s account has been condemned and disputed by other associates of King. After the memorial on the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Poverty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> grounds was dedicated Sunday, <PERSON> King </PERSON> said he took <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON>'s hand and called him `` Uncle <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON>.'' `` What I was doing in speaking to him was in no way to express any malicious sentiment. It was a concerned sentiment. It was just human nature to speak to him,'' said King. He said he spoke for himself and not other members of his family. Because of the negative reaction to his book, <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> was excluded from the speaker's platform during the ceremonies honoring King and 39 others slain in the struggle for civil rights. After the speeches, <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> rushed up the stairs and began shaking hands with people on the platform. He and King spoke briefly. <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> told The Tennessean on Thursday that King called him `` Uncle <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON>,'' and said <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> had embarrassed his family and him. <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> said he loves <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, and said he will be writing him and talking to him in the future. `` I will tell him that his father was my dearest friend,'' <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> said. `` I am a part of him. A part of me went on the trip with him. He was my best buddy.'' `` He was a human being,'' <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON> said. `` He was frail, just as all of us are. I want to tell his children that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Walesa     11-10 0899</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Walesa,0923</SECOND>
<HEAD>Walesa Says He's `Trembling' Before First Trip to U.S.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DANISZEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GDANSK, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> is about to make his first trip to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, and he says the prospect leaves him `` trembling.'' Simultaneously nervous about leaving <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> for too long and fearful of disappointing his <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hosts with a visit that's too short, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that he sees <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s future hinging at least in part on how he does during seven busy days in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. The journey, which begins in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and winds up in <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>, is highlighted by two meetings with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and a speech to a joint session of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Nov. 15, where <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> will appeal for economic aid and investment in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. When asked what his message was for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> replied: `` We need Columbuses from the States to come and discover <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, to clear the trail. First clear the trail, clear it like <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>. ... Then there will an influx of millionaires. Because there is business to be done here.'' The former shipyard electrician who won the Nobel Peace Prize in 1983 and engineered the formation of the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc's first non-communist government will be among the few people who were not heads of a government or state to address <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Other private people so honored included Revolutionary War hero <PERSON> Marquis </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> LaFayette </PERSON> and <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON>, after he left office. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, a guest of <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> and the union federation, arrives in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Monday and leaves for <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> Nov. 19. `` Any trip to the States shorter than one month is no good,'' a harried but bantering <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said in the interview in his <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> office before his departure. With the limited time at his disposal, `` I will disappoint many, and that it why it is not a good trip and a trip which is dangerous for me. I can not satisfy Americans in such a short time. I can not thank Americans enough. It is physically impossible,'' he said. In addition, he said he is burdened by the prospect of something going wrong in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> while he is away. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, whose mother and stepfather lived in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, canceled a trip in 1981 because the political situation was too unstable. Martial law was imposed a few months later. He seems to have similar fears about being away too long now, even with his friend <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> sitting comfortably at the helm of government and scores of his union colleages filling the benches of parliament. `` Whatever bad happens _ knock wood, it could _ will be all blamed on me,'' <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said. `` That I did it deliberately, that I did not anticipate it. ... That is why I am trembling. In these conditions I can not make a good visit.'' At a time when <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> would seem able to savor the fruits of his victories in 1989 _ Solidarity regained legal status, swept all the parliament races it entered and took over the government in a once-unimaginable defeat for the Communists _ he claims to be more burdened than ever. By comparison, his lonely work as an organizer of free trade unions in the late 1970s and his years of internment and surveillance after Gen. <PERSON> Wojciech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON>'s martial-law crackdown were `` easy, like playing in the boy scouts,'' he said. `` I think that the difficult things are only coming now. Let's not forget that we are building something now, we are building an <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> But can we anticipate everything? ... This will be the danger.'' He also sees a personal danger for himself _ the swift passage of time and the unlikelihood that he can lay his burdens down soon. `` I do n't like what I am doing,'' he said. `` I was born a free man, and now what's offered me is slavery. ... I felt better when I was a prisoner than I do now that I am free. Then I could lay down and rest. And now it is like being under arrest even at home. I can not even walk outside. Somebody is immediately on me. `` And so time is running out. I want to live a little, and I do n't know if it is possible anymore.'' He also worries a bit that his political wits may be getting dull. `` So far it is not too bad. But I do n't know. I am getting older, but I am trying to save myself. I am doing calisthenics now because I am starting to feel exhausted. Maybe I weigh too much. Just to stretch it out, I have started wearing jeans, pretending to be 18 years old. I do sports to extend my life. I do n't know if it is going to work.'' <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said he thought communism was finished `` a long time ago.'' `` But it all depends on what we understand by ` communism' If you understand the monopoly of one party, a monopoly over everything, then that has been over for a long time. It can not be maintained.'' But if communism was to find a way to stop limiting freedom and pluralism and correct `` a few other minor things,'' then `` it might not be entirely a stupid ideology someday, when people forget about all its sins.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-FirstCrossings     11-10 0451</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-First Crossings,0467</SECOND>
<HEAD>East Berliners Stroll To The Other Side For First Time</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-East Germany, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TONY CZUCZKA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Torsten </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryl </PERSON> had been a Berliner all 24 years of his life. But until early today, he had never seen the other half of the divided city. Suddenly, all it took was a flash of his identity card. `` At the stroke of midnight, they told us, ` The procedure has been shortened, and all you need is a stamp,''' said <PERSON> Ryl </PERSON>, a waiter, still awestruck at his sudden crossing into the West through Checkpoint <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON>. `` It's not my intention to stay here, but we have to have the possibility to come over here and go back again,'' <PERSON> Ryl </PERSON> said. `` I have my apartment and my car over there.'' A middle-aged West German reached over, gave him 20 marks -LRB- $ 11 -RRB- and said with a grin: `` Why do n't you go get yourself a beer first?'' In what seemed like a fantasy, thousands of Berliners today strolled through the other half of the city where <LOCATION> Communist </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> had denied them free passage for 28 years. <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> and <PERSON> Katarina </PERSON> <PERSON> Erdmann </PERSON> said they briefly left their three sleeping children at home in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. `` We just wanted to go for a stroll,'' <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Erdmann </PERSON> said. `` It's crazy.'' West Berliners also crossed eastward. Germans from both sides held impromptu dances atop the wall, hoisting people up from both sides to join them. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Moll </PERSON> said he was allowed to cross into <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> in less than five minutes. `` I just ca n't believe it,'' he said. `` A lot of people thought it was just another trick.'' <PERSON> Moll </PERSON>, 21, said he also intended to return home after having a look around <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. He reluctantly gave his name to reporters. `` You're not from <LOCATION> Stasi </LOCATION>, are you?'' he asked, referring to the East German state security service. It seemed as if each <PERSON> East </PERSON> <PERSON> Berliner </PERSON> who crossed the demarcation line was greeted with cheers _ many by hugs and kisses _ by the crowd at Checkpoint Charlie. Traffic jams built up on the western side of the checkpoint, and people with sparklers and champagne bottles streamed out of the Kochstrasse subway stop on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> side to join the party. Thousands celebrated on the Kurfuerstendamm, a boulevard in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s upscale shopping district. East German Trabant cars were welcomed by cheers and honking horns as they slowly wended their way down the boulevard, which for one night was the scene of the wildest celebrations since the Berlin Wall was born in the Cold War. `` This is a historic day!'' one man yelled. `` We're going to be able to tell our children about this!''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RapeIndictment     11-10 0255</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rape Indictment,0262</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Acquitted in Florida Rape Case to Face Georgia Charges</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAWRENCEVILLE, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man whose rape acquittal in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> gained national attention when jurors criticized the woman's clothing is now facing attempted rape charges in his home state of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamar </PERSON> <PERSON> Lord </PERSON>, 26, was indicted Wednesday on one count each of false imprisonment, aggravated assault with intent to commit rape, criminal attempt to commit rape and robbery in an attack on a <LOCATION> Gwinnett </LOCATION> woman Sept. 21, 1988. The 24-year-old woman says she was raped a knifepoint. Lord was first indicted in the case in January, but Assistant District Attorney <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Smeal </PERSON> said a new indictment was issued to change the language of the aggravated assault charge. A six-member jury in <LOCATION> Broward </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, found Lord innocent of charges last month that he raped a 22-year-old woman at knife point after abducting her from a <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> restaurant parking lot in November 1988. Several jurors said the woman enticed Lord with skimpy clothing, including a lace miniskirt with no underwear. `` She was obviously dressed for a good time, but we felt she may have bit off more than she could chew,'' juror <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradshaw </PERSON> said following the verdict, which unleashed outrage around the nation from sexual assualt counselors and women's groups. The woman, wearing various disguises, has appeared on several national talks shows to discuss the case. During the trial, Lord's attorney told jurors that the woman agreed to have sex with Lord in exchange for $ 100 and cocaine.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Wall-Chronology     11-10 0345</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wall-Chronology,0354</SECOND>
<HEAD>Events In History of Berlin Wall</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A chronology of the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall, erected 28 years ago at the height of Cold War tensions: Aug. 13, 1961 _ East German troops move to seal all access to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> after a mass exodus of hundreds of thousands of East Germans threatens to ruin the economy. In the following days, barbed wire is replaced by concrete barriers. Houses along the border are sealed. Border guards are issued shoot-to-kill orders for all those trying to flee. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> is encircled and isolated from the West. June 26, 1963 _ President <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> visits <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. In a show of solidarity with the divided city, he declares to a cheering crowd of 400,000 at the wall: `` I am a Berliner.'' June 12, 1987 _ President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> visits <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> and calls on Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to tear the wall down. March 8, 1989 _ The last fatality related to an escape attempt over the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall is recorded. An <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> man falls to his death after his homemade hot-air balloon deflates prematurely. A total of 80 East Germans have been reported killed trying to flee over the wall since 1961. Oct. 18, 1989 _ Hard-line leader <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>, who supervised the building of the Wall, is replaced after an unprecendented wave of unrest and the exodus of thousands of citizens. Nov. 3, 1989 _ In the first direct challenge to the wall's purpose, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> announces that East Germans who want to flee West can do so over the Czechoslovak border Tens of thousands do so. Nov. 9, 1989 _ The <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> leadership declares that citizens can travel directly to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> through East German checkpoints with proper documentation. Thousands of East Berliners make their way to the Berlin Wall. Officials waive the requirement for visas and thousands stream over to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> for a night of celebration. An East German border trooper jokes that the Wall will soon be broken up into pieces and sold as souvenirs for convertible currency.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     11-10 0613</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0634</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SOUTHFIELD, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Talk-show host <PERSON> Oprah </PERSON> <PERSON> Winfrey </PERSON> will launch the <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Youth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>' fall campaign to recruit foster and adoptive parents for black children. <PERSON> Winfrey </PERSON> will appear in the 30-second public service announcements that will air next month, urging black families to adopt or become foster parents of abandoned or orphaned youngsters, the office announced Thursday. One Church One Child of <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which focuses on the need for more adoptive and foster parents for black children, also is sponsoring the ads. They will air statewide.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SALT LAKE CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Redford </PERSON> owns a ski resort in the mountains east of <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, but he's opposed to widening the road that leads to it, and has mixed feelings about bringing the Winter Olympics to <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> voters on Tuesday approved a referendum calling for spending $ 56 million to build ski jumps, a speed skating oval and bobsled-luge runs required by the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Olympics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which will pick a 1998 site in June 1991. <PERSON> Redford </PERSON> said he personally was not opposed to the Games _ none of which would be held at his Sundance resort _ but felt the state should make sure the Olympics did not lead to further damage of the <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> environment. `` What is <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> going to do to protect its future rather than squander it for a 16-day event?'' he said. <PERSON> Redford </PERSON> criticized proposals to expand to four lanes the two-lane <ORGANIZATION> Provo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canyon </ORGANIZATION> highway, which leads to his resort. `` Are we going to cut the canyon to suit the road or cut the road to suit the canyon? Personally, I prefer the latter,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>VENICE, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 80 women on a tiny island in the Venetian lagoon are busy stitching lace for a shawl to be given to Soviet first lady <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. Italian Premier <PERSON> Giulio </PERSON> <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON> personally selected the model and decorative pattern for the shawl by the <LOCATION> Burano </LOCATION> lace makers that he will present during Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s Nov. 29 visit to <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. It has not yet been disclosed whether Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will accompany her husband. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will meet with <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> and meet Dec. 1 with <PERSON> Pope </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, the first meeting between the leaders of the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>. The fishing village of <LOCATION> Burano </LOCATION> is the center of traditional Venetian lace making, an art that has suffered from industrial competition. It takes three days for a pocket handkerchief to be braided in ` <LOCATION> Burano </LOCATION>' stitch. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> is among the former customers of the island's artisans. She ordered a set of sheets and tablecloths during the 1960s.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Another version on sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cowboys </ORGANIZATION> coach <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Landry </PERSON> will head a group of sports and business leaders working to attract sporting events to the <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> area, city officials said. The <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sports </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>'s first objective is to secure the 1994 World Cup Soccer Competition, said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Initiative </ORGANIZATION>. The panel's board of directors includes former <ORGANIZATION> Cowboys </ORGANIZATION> quarterback <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Staubach </PERSON>, golf legend <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mavericks </ORGANIZATION> general manager <PERSON> Norm </PERSON> <PERSON> Sonju </PERSON>. At a city hall news conference Thursday, Mayor <PERSON> Annette </PERSON> <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> said, `` Mr. <PERSON> Landry </PERSON>'s commitment to the commission means that <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> will quickly become a major player on the field of amateur and professional sporting events.'' <PERSON> Landry </PERSON> said the appointment `` presents a tremendous opportunity to give back to <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> some of what the city has given to me.'' <PERSON> Landry </PERSON> coached the <ORGANIZATION> Cowboys </ORGANIZATION> for 29 years, leading the team to five Super Bowls and two championships. He was fired last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Gasoline-Cancer Bjt   11-10 0581</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gasoline-Cancer, Bjt,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gasoline Vapors Unhealthy, Consumer Group Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A consumer group is calling for tighter controls on toxic gasoline vapors, saying that motorists who pump their own gas are being exposed to unhealthy levels of cancer-causing benzene and other pollutants. Citizen Action, a Washington-based organization that focuses on consumer and environmental issues, accused the oil companies Thursday of ignoring health concerns by increasing levels of benzene and other aromatic hydrocarbons in unleaded gasoline to boost its octane rating. The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> issued a statement that disputed the claims and accused Citizen Action of raising `` unwarranted fears about motorists' exposure to gasoline.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> acknowledged that toxic vapors from gasoline at the pump are a health concern, but an agency spokesman suggested the claims raised by Citizen Action on health impact may be exaggerated. Nevertheless, said <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration proposal for tightening federal air quality laws calls for better vapor-capturing devices such as sleeves or hoods on gasoline pumps. It also would require oil companies to produce gasoline that releases less vapor pollutants. Several localities already require vapor-control hoods on gasoline pumps, but the devices have been controversial because they have been found to be cumbersome and unpopular in many cases. Benzene, which has been shown to cause leukemia, appears in petroleum products such as gasoline and its vapors. It also is generated during combustion and releases through motor vehicle tailpipes. The report by Citizen Action claimed that motorists are exposed to benzene levels of more than 1 part per million when refueling their cars _ a level expected to result, according to several studies, in at least two additional cancer cases over a lifetime per 1 million people exposed. It said a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> study suggested even higher exposures. `` Despite the scientific evidence demonstrating that human exposure to benzene increases the risk of contracting cancer, oil companies have neither adequately warned consumers, nor acted to responsibly reduce benzene levels,'' said the citizen group. <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothschild </PERSON>, energy and environmental policy director for Citizen Action, said the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> `` has sat on its hands for the last 13 years and has done nothing to regulate mobile sources of benzene,'' although it recently announced regulations to curb benzene releases from industrial facilities and storage tanks. The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, the oil industry's trade group, denounced the <ORGANIZATION> Citizen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> claims, calling the allegations `` a disservice to the consumers it purports to represents.'' <PERSON> Gus </PERSON> <PERSON> Ensz </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, said consumers' exposure to benzene at service stations is for `` only a few minutes a week -LRB- and -RRB- typically to low levels.'' The trade group accused Citizen Action of trying `` to raise unwarranted fears'' among motorists. The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> recently announced tighter controls on benzene emissions from a variety of sources from industrial plants to storage facilities because chronic exposure is believed to cause leukemia. But the new regulations do not cover emissions from motor vehicles, which the agency says accounts for about 80 percent of the benzene releases. Most of the releases from gasoline occur through vehicle tailpipes during fuel combustion, but a substantial amount also is released through gasoline vapors with exposure being greatest at service stations when motorists are refueling, environmental studies have said. Citizen Action is a Washington-based federation of citizen groups that claims more than 2 million members in 25 states. It focuses on a variety of consumer, environmental and health issues.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SmokingBan Bjt   11-10 0389</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Smoking Ban, Bjt,390</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Adopts Airline Smoking Ban</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Opponents of smoking aboard airliners are on the verge of winning their fight to forbid passengers from lighting up on practically all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> flights. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> by voice vote Thursday passed a prohibition against cigarette smoking on all but a handful of domestic flights. Tobacco-state lawmakers, long convinced they were badly outnumbered, made no comments on the prohibition. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved the ban, included in a $ 12 billion transportation bill for the new fiscal year, on Oct. 31. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will continue debate on the spending measure Tuesday and will send it to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for his signature if no changes in the legislation are made. `` Approval of this law is a milestone in the efforts to protect those who do n't want to put themselves at risk by inhaling other people's smoke,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, the measure's sponsor The new restrictions permanently forbid smoking on all routes within the continental <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, and on all flights to and from <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> scheduled for six hours or less. The current ban _ which expires next April _ applies only to routes lasting two hours or less, covering 80 percent of all flights. Smoking would remain legal on only about 28 of the 17,500 daily scheduled <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> flights, according to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> sponsor of the measure, Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Durbin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ill </LOCATION>. Uncovered would be 24 flights each day to <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> and four to Guam. <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON> and his allies, citing studies by the surgeon general's office and other sources, have argued that it is unhealthy to breathe cigarette fumes from smokers. Tobacco industry supporters insist cigarette smoke is only one chemical in airline cabin air, which is recirculated. They have argued <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> should not act until the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> completes a study next year on the components of cabin air. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has essentially acted in an informational vacuum,'' said spokesman <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> <PERSON> Merryman </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Tobacco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, the cigarette industry's trade group. <PERSON> Cigar </PERSON> and pipe smoking aboard airliners has been illegal since 1983. The bill also provides $ 3.2 billion for anti-drug programs; $ 40 million to begin building a new airport in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, the nation's first new airport in 15 years; and $ 14 million to develop new bomb-detection machines
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0152EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-Pay Bjt   11-10 0777</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Pay, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>It's an Ethics Package, Not a Pay Raise</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ask House Speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> about plans for a 33 percent congressional pay hike and his response reflects the barrage of semantics that is a key part of many lawmakers' strategy `` Are you talking about the ethics package?'' he says. And the initial 7.7 percent raise members would receive on Jan. 1 is a `` cost-of-living adjustment, not a pay raise,'' he says. `` If you are talking about a pay adjustment, no one is proposing to do that in this Congress.'' Ten months after public uproar drove lawmakers to kill a proposed 51 percent salary increase for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the judiciary and top executive branch jobs, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leaders are charging ahead with a new mix of semantics and timing, public policy and financial self-interest. House members would within 14 months see their salaries rise from $ 89,500 to more than $ 120,000. The initial pay boost is billed as a cost-of-living adjustment to make up for two years of inflation without an increase. The bulk of the raise, a 25 percent boost, would be delayed until Jan. 1, 1991, after the next <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is elected. At that time, lawmakers would be banned from keeping money from speeches before interest groups. It was <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Madison </PERSON> who suggested that the Constitution bar lawmakers from approving pay increases to take effect in the same <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` This is not the same old saw,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Vic </PERSON> <PERSON> Fazio </PERSON>, D-Calif., who along with Rep. <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, R-Ill., led a bipartisan panel that fashioned the Other ethics reforms would include requiring members to disclose more about their personal finances and new restrictions on the gifts they could receive. Final details of the package were being negotiated this week between Republicans and Democrats in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, and with the White House. The new proposal also would be handled in a more straightforward way than earlier this year, when former <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> tried to force the 51 percent pay hike into effect without a vote. On this one, members will be forced to record their views. `` Clearly the package that's before us now is substantially better,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, a leader of the effort to defeat the earlier proposal. <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON> said he would not actively oppose the new plan, but he would n't vote for it. Among his reasons is the inclusion of the pay increase starting in January. `` It is very difficult, I think, to explain to people back home that a cost of living adjustment is not a pay raise,'' said <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON>, who is running for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON> and others said it was bad timing for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to consider a pay raise before it has taken steps to correct massive budgetary problems. The failure to enact a deficit-reduction bill this year has required the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, under the Gramm-Rudman law, to order across-the-board spending cuts. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said this week it could be forced to reduce <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troop strength by tens of thousands. <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> on Thursday said he was willing to put forward the pay-and-ethics plan before a fiscal settlement, but others said that would be a mistake. `` There is no question in my mind -LRB- that -RRB- if we can not eliminate the across-the-board cuts, there is no chance members are going to vote for a pay raise,'' said <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, D-Calif., who is working to complete the deficit bill Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, said many members, including himself, would be very cautious about voting for a pay raise. `` I do n't think there's anything about this thing that's popular,'' he said President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has indicated a willingness to accept a raise, since he badly wants to increase salaries for federal judges and his top political appointees in the administration. Senators, however, have little desire to risk anything for a pay boost. They generally have more personal wealth than their <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> colleagues and their rules let them keep honoraria equal to 40 percent of their salaries, compared to 30 percent in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> _ and senators have a much easier time lining up speeches. `` There's not a lot of support in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> for a pay raise,'' Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, said Thursday. House and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders have discussed the possibility that the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> might accept the initial 7.7 percent raise but, for its own members, eschew the later installment. On board or not, members are getting the message. `` It's an ethics package. It's not a pay raise,'' quipped Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Buechner </PERSON>, R-Mo., when he was asked for a stance `` If you ca n't get the jargon down ...''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0159EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ChildCare Bjt   11-10 0645</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Child Care, Bjt,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Child Care Confrontation Looms</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democrats, with the help of a maverick Republican senator, are setting the stage for a new showdown with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> over child care subsidies. Negotiators from the two congressional bodies reached agreement Thursday night on legislation that would increase direct federal child care subsidies to low - and moderate-income families by $ 1.2 billion in 1990 and by up to $ 8.5 billion over the next five years The accord was struck after Sen. <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, dropped his demand that states be allowed to issue vouchers for a new $ 300 million program to pay for keeping schools open longer hours to provide day care and establish a new education-driven program for pre-school tots. `` At least we have a running shot now with a bill that the president might not veto,'' said <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, who angered the administration, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and conservative groups by joining with liberal Democrats last spring in putting together the basic package. In exchange, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democrats agreed to allow more of the money to go to rural areas at governors' discretion and let states issue vouchers that parents could use to pay for day care services provided by churches. A separate group of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiators still must reach accord on another provision included in the child care package that would increase tax credits for poor families with children by $ 500 to $ 750 a year. But <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democratic leaders instructed the chairmen of their tax-writing committees Thursday to try to settle differences over that portion by Monday night in a drive to get a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote by the end of next week. `` We're going to move on the child care bill as a separate item ... and we hope to see an early enactment of it,'' said <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, D-Wash. His counterpart in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, said the same effort will be made there, but acknowledged it will be more difficult to accomplish before adjourning for Thanksgiving, under <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rules `` Our problem is there's Republican opposition,'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said. `` They're opposed to passing it any time, this year or next.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved its version of the bill by a 63-37 margin in June over fierce opposition from the administration and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> GOP Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. A companion measure was approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> last month as part of a bill aimed a bringing down the federal deficit in fiscal 1990, which began Oct. 1. With public opinion polls indicating a large majority of Americans favor federal aid for child care, Democrats and <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON> hope that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would not veto the bill. But if he does, said Rep. <PERSON> Gus </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, D-Calif., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will pass the same measure again early next year at the opening of the 1990 election cycle `` It's going to be pretty damned hard to get anybody in 1990 to vote against child care,'' said <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>. No one knows exactly how much of the federal block grants to states are now spent on child care subsidies, but estimates range from $ 400 million to $ 1 billion a year. Under the compromise reached Thursday, those block grants would be augmented with a new $ 750 million program of child care subsidies with a mandate that states regulate care providers. Another $ 150 million would be added to the Head Start pre-school program that now reaches about half a million 3 - and 4-year-olds each year with the aim of turning those facilities into all-day, year-round child care centers <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has adamantly opposed making states regulate day care centers and has insisted that any new aid be limited to tax credits for poor families with children under age 4 and a slight expansion of Head Start funding.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0215EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Alzheimer'sDisease Bjt   11-10 0643</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Alzheimer's Disease, Bjt,0660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Alzheimer's Disease More Widespread Than Previously Believed, Study
Finds</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRENDA C. COLEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four million Americans may have Alzheimer's disease _ 1.5 million more than had been thought _ according to findings that suggest the disease and its treatment will `` weigh heavily on our future. A study of 3,623 elderly people in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> indicates one in 10 of them probably had Alzheimer's disease, which robs people of their memories and their ability to function, researchers said. The rates of Alzheimer's grew rapidly higher with advancing age, as nearly half of those older than 85 suffer from it, said the researchers, led by Dr. <PERSON> Denis </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. Based on the study's results, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> on Aging revised its estimate of how many people in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> suffer from Alzheimer's from 2.5 million to 4 million. The institute issued a statement saying the study is unique because it involved large numbers of people, including those living in their own homes or with their families, and it included people with few or no memory problems. `` As a result, these estimates might lay the groundwork for developing the most accurate picture of Alzheimer's disease in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> population to date,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Zaven </PERSON> <PERSON> Khachaturian </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NIA </ORGANIZATION> associate director for neuroscience and neuropsychology of aging. Results of the study, partly financed by <ORGANIZATION> NIA </ORGANIZATION>, were published in today's Journal of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` People that I see do not realize that this is an extremely prevalent condition, that it is an epidemic that is going to weigh heavily on our future,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Naughton </PERSON>, geriatrics chief at <ORGANIZATION> Northwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> has estimated that from 1980 to the year 2000, the number of people 90 years old and up will increase 236 percent, to 1.9 million, <PERSON> Naughton </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> study consisted of giving brief memory tests to 81 percent of the 65-and-older population of east <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> beginning in 1982, and conducting more extensive psychiatric and laboratory testing on 467 of the individuals. Of people 65 to 74 years old, 3 percent had `` probable'' Alzheimer's disease, compared with 18.7 percent of those 75 to 84 years old and 47.2 percent of those over 85, said the study. `` Everyone in our study, whether they had Alzheimer's disease or not, was living in the community, not in institutions,'' <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> noted in a telephone interview. `` They may have had impaired function, far from perfect function, but they were able to live in the community.'' Victims of Alzheimer's disease often end up in nursing homes, but <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> called for finding ways to allow Alzheimer's sufferers to stay in the community with their families. Alzheimer's disease is a degenerative illness of the brain and nervous system with no known cause, no cure and no effective treatment, save medication to treat the depression that sometimes accompanies it. The disease usually is fatal within 5 to 10 years, according to <PERSON> Naughton </PERSON>, who said its first symptom is typically memory loss, followed by speech difficulties and a tendency to lose one's way even in familiar surroundings. Alzheimer's later robs people of their ability to cook and care for themselves, as well as exaggerating their personality traits _ such as hot-temperedness or passivity. The illness eventually confines victims to bed and renders them unable to respond to their environment, <PERSON> Naughton </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> study `` points out the need for further research, because the problem is greater than formerly recognized,'' said <PERSON> Creighton </PERSON> <PERSON> Phelps </PERSON>, vice president of medical and scientific affairs for the Chicago-based <ORGANIZATION> Alzheimer </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, a research and family-support group. <PERSON> Naughton </PERSON> said <PERSON> Alzheimer </PERSON>'s research is relatively well funded compared with financial support for training physicians to care for Alzheimer's victims. `` We're very poorly prepared in the medical profession to deal with chronic care,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0217EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     11-10 0951</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,900</SECOND>
<HEAD>US and Soviet Grain Harvests Larger Than Predicted</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American and Soviet farmers are both producing more grain this year than experts figured a month ago. This year's <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> corn crop, for example, is estimated by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> at a three-year high of 7.59 billion bushels, up 54 percent from last year's drought-reduced crop and up 2 percent from the forecast in October. Based on recent information out of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, the department on Thursday also boosted its estimate of 1990 total grain production by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to 208 million metric tons, up three million from October indications. On a metric basis, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> corn harvest is estimated at 192.8 million tons. And total <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> grain output this year _ not counting 52.7 million tons of soybeans _ is about 284 million tons. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 39.4 bushels of corn, or 36.7 bushels of wheat or soybeans. In October, the department estimated this year's production at 7.45 billion bushels, a 51 percent increase from last year's drought-reduced 4.92 billion bushels Based on Nov. 1 surveys, the 7.59 billion bushels now forecast would be the largest since 8.25 billion bushels in 1986. The record was the 1985 crop of nearly 8.9 billion bushels. `` Harvest progressed rapidly in the 17 major producing states during October and was 88 percent complete by Nov. 5, compared with 91 percent last year and the average of 78 percent,'' the department's <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported. Corn yields were estimated at 116.6 bushels per acre harvested, up from 114.4 forecast in October and 84.6 bushels in 1988 but still below the record of 119.4 bushels per acre in 1987. As livestock feed, corn is the largest and most important <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm crop. It is essential for the production of meat, poultry and dairy products. Consumer food prices, which rose an average of 4.1 percent in 1988, are expected to go up about 6 percent this year, according to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> economists. The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> has not issued its 1990 forecast, but some analysts tentatively believe food prices wo n't match this year's rise, the steepest since a 7.8 percent jump in 1981. Soybean production, a source of high-protein meal and vegetable oil, was estimated at 1.94 billion bushels, up 25 percent from last year's harvest of 1.54 billion bushels and 1 percent above the October estimate of 1.93 billion bushels. The record soybean output was 2.26 billion bushels in 1979. Yields were estimated at an average of 32.8 bushels per acre this year, compared with 26.9 bushels in 1988, the October forecast of 32.6 bushels and a record 34.1 bushels per acre in 1985. The department's all-crops production index was reported at 104 percent of its 1977 average used for comparison. Last year, reflecting the severe drought, the index plummeted to 89 percent. The record reading was 117 percent set in 1981, 1982 and 1985. Cotton production was indicated at 12.1 million bales, down 21 percent from last year's output and 2 percent below the September estimate of 12.3 million bales. The new estimate was up about 1 percent from October. The cotton record was 18.9 million bales in 1937. No new estimates of 1989 production of wheat and other crops harvested earlier were included in the report. In a related report on supply and demand for major commodities, analysts said total corn use in the 1989-90 marketing year that began on Sept. 1 is expected to be about 7.625 billion bushels, including domestic and export requirements, an increase from 7.5 billion forecast in October. With demand exceeding 1989 corn production, that will mean a further drawdown of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> stockpiles to about 1.9 billion bushels left over by next Sept. 1, down from inventories estimated at 1.93 billion bushels at the beginning of the marketing year. Still, that represents only a slight dip in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> corn stockpile, compared to last season's decline, when it plummeted from 4.26 billion bushels on Sept. 1, 1988, to the 1.93 billion bushels on hand this Sept. 1. Analysts said total corn use in the coming year will be boosted by larger exports than had been anticipated, about 2.15 billion bushels instead of the 2 billion that was forecast last month. Larger imports by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> are expected to account for much of the increase. According to the new estimate, <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> will import about 37 million tons of grain from all sources in 1989-90, up three million tons from the October forecast but still short of last year's 39 million tons. The report said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> corn prices may average in the range of $ 2 to $ 2.40 per bushel in the 1989-90 marketing year, down from $ 2.54 last season. The October forecast was $ 1.85 to $ 2.25 per bushel. Other 1989 crop estimates based on Oct. 1 indications, compared with 1988 output, included: _ Sorghum, 628.9 million bushels and an average yield of 59.8 bushels per acre, compared with 577.6 million and 63.8 in 1988 _ Rice, 156.4 million hundredweight and a yield of 5,697 pounds per acre, compared with 159.5 million and 5,511 _ Peanuts, 4.13 billion pounds and a yield of 2,523 pounds per acre, compared with 3.98 billion and 2,445 _ Potatoes, total, 367.3 million hundredweight and a yield of 292 hundredweight per acre, compared with 356.4 million and 283 _ Tobacco, 1.47 billion pounds and a yield of 2,105 pounds per acre, compared with 1.37 billion and 2,160 _ Sugarbeets, 26 million tons and a yield of 19.6 tons per acre, compared with 24.8 million and 19.1 _ Sugar cane, 30.4 million tons and a yield of 35.2 tons per acre, compared with 29.9 million and 35.4
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0220EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CapitalGains     11-10 0501</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Capital Gains,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Debate Set For Bush's Capital Gains Tax Cut</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Opponents of a capital gains tax reduction say new debate set in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is merely the `` death throes'' for the year for President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s tax cut proposal. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> took the first step in the new round of debate Thursday, repassing without debate or dissent the same capital gains cut it had approved in September as part of a deficit-reduction bill. But <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders say the new debate will only put the issue to rest for the year. `` This is just part of the death throes of capital gains,'' said Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Tenn </LOCATION>., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Only Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ill </LOCATION>., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, spoke on the bill Thursday `` It removes this issue as an impediment to moving forward on budget reconciliation -LRB- deficit reduction -RRB- and other important matters,'' he said. Republicans will offer their own version of a capital gains cut in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and the issue will be debated for a day or two. There likely will be two efforts to shut off debate on the bill. Although Republicans say most senators favor a cut, it is generally agreed backers will be unable to muster the 60 votes required to force a final vote. If, as expected, the second vote to limit debate fails, capital gains will be dead for the year. Senate Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> told reporters he would not attempt to attach the amendment to any other bill this year. Republicans agreed last week to stop trying to attach the reduction to debt-ceiling and deficit-reduction legislation. But they want to have next week's debate to keep the issue in the public eye in hopes of building support. Asked what chance the bill has of becoming law this year, <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON> told reporters, `` None.'' Republicans say a cut in the tax on capital gains, which are profits from the sale of investments, would spur investment and create jobs. Democrats call it a tax cut for the wealthy and cite estimates that 80 percent of the benefit from a reduction would go to those with incomes more than $ 200,000 a year. The cut approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday would exclude from taxation 30 percent of the gains on assets sold before Dec. 31, 1991. After that, only gains resulting solely from inflation would be excluded. Present law fully taxes capital gains at the same rates applied to wages and other income. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> plan would allow an exclusion based on how long an asset was held. If property was owned for more than a year, 5 percent of the profit would be excluded from tax. The excluded portion would increase by 5 percentage points each year, up to a maximum of seven years. Thus, 35 percent of the profit from the sale of an asset owned more than seven years would escape taxation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891110-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-89 0229EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Alzheimer's-Symptoms     11-10 0211</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Alzheimer's-Symptoms,0216</SECOND>
<HEAD>Symptoms of Alzheimer's Disease</HEAD>
