<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 2330EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CopterCrash 4thLd-Writethru a0742 10-10 0472</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Copter Crash, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0742,0482</SECOND>
<HEAD>Helicopter Crashes On Parkway, Three Trump Execs Among Five Dead</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS lead and SUBS 9th graf, `Tim Rose ..., to UPDATE with IDs
of pilot, co-pilot.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto ACB2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB McMAHON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LACEY TOWNSHIP, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A helicopter crashed Tuesday on the median of an expressway, killing the pilot, co-pilot and three <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> casino hotel executives of the Trump Organization, officials said. The helicopter was returning to <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> when it crashed at 1:50 p.m. on the Garden State Parkway, police said. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>, said he was camping nearby when he saw the helicopter as its `` rotor stopped spinning and became disconnected from the helicopter and tumbled.'' He said, `` It seemed like an eternity watching it'' plummet to the ground. State police Sgt. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Aceto </PERSON> said the main rotor was found about a quarter-mile north of the crash site. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Ghiorsi </PERSON>, regional director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, said a search was under way for the tail rotor. Investigators said the loss of one rotor could have caused the other to fall off. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Klores </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Trump </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> was not aboard the copter, but the presidents of his Trump Plaza and <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>'s Castle casino hotels died in the crash. <PERSON> Klores </PERSON> identified the <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> executives as <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON>, 43, chief executive officer of <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> casino operations; <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Etess </PERSON>, 38, president of the Taj Mahal casino project; and, <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Benanav </PERSON>, 33, senior vice president of Trump Plaza casino hotel. `` They were three fabulous young men in the prime of their lives,'' said <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> in a statement issued through his <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> office. `` No better human beings ever existed. We're deeply saddened by this devastating tragedy. Our hearts go out to their families.'' State police spokesman Capt. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallagher </PERSON> identified the other victims as pilot <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ronkonkoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, and co-pilot <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Diener </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Westbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Spitaliere </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, said the helicopter was an <ORGANIZATION> Agusta </ORGANIZATION> 109A, which seats eight people. The Trump executives had been in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> for a news conference promoting the Feb. 3 World Boxing Organization bout between junior welterweights <PERSON> Hector </PERSON> <PERSON> Camacho </PERSON> and <PERSON> Vinny </PERSON> <PERSON> Pazienza </PERSON> at <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>'s Plaza. Ocean County Sheriff <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Polhemus </PERSON> said his office has confirmed five people died in the crash. `` There was a lot of debris smack in the center of the Garden State -LRB- Parkway -RRB-,'' said <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Spitaliere </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Klores </PERSON> said the helicopter was leased by the Trump Organization from <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, and had taken off from a heliport in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> for the one-hour flight to <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Officials at <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> said they could not answer questions about the crash.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 2334EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--MarcosTomb     10-10 0199</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Marcos Tomb,0205</SECOND>
<HEAD>Marcos Family Cited In Tomb Construction</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The family of <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> was cited for failing to obtain a building permit before starting construction of a temporary tomb for the former <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> president, city officials said Tuesday. <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Muraoka </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Building </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, said the citation was sent out Tuesday, the day after building inspectors visited the site at Valley of the Temples Memorial Park in <LOCATION> Windward </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oahu </LOCATION>. The <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> family has 30 days to respond to the citation before the case is referred to the city prosecutor's office, <PERSON> Muraoka </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> supporter <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Lazo </PERSON> said the mausoleum was being built by volunteers with donated materials. The stucture is considered to be temporary because the <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> family hopes eventually to have <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> buried in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. The wood and corrugated metal structure was expected to be completed on Wednesday, and the casket containing <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' body is scheduled to be placed in the tomb on Sunday. The body remains on view at the family's estate until Friday, when a funeral Mass is scheduled at the Co-Cathedral of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Theresa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> died Sept. 28 of cardiac arrest following a long illness. He was 72.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 2334EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-UN-Bhutto 1stLd-Writethru a0769 10-10 0509</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-UN-Bhutto, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0769,0522</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mme. Bhutto Still Thinks of Prime Minister as Her `Baby'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS one graf for 11th pvs `Six years ...' to CORRECT year of
Shah Nawaz Bhutto's death. Picks up graf 12 pvs, `Zia himself ...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VICTORIA GRAHAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The matriarch of one of the world's most sorely tried political families said Tuesday she still sometimes thinks of her daughter, Prime Minister <PERSON> Benazir </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, as `` my baby.'' Madame <PERSON> Nusrat </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>, widow of executed Prime Minister <PERSON> Zulfikar </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>, herself is senior minister _ the equivalent of deputy prime minister _ and she conducts Cabinet meetings in her daughter's absence. `` As the wife of a prime minister,'' she said in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday, `` there was not much I could do, but as a mother, sometimes I feel she is still my baby and needs me and I am ready to help as much as I can.'' <PERSON> Madame </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> is standing in for her daughter, delivering <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s speech to the present General Assembly. Diplomats said her daughter's 10-month-old government is embattled and the prime minister dared not leave at this time. The mother denied a report that her daughter is in political trouble to the extent that she telephoned President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for help in fighting her enemies. `` No, the report is stupid, it is lies, none of it is true,'' <PERSON> Madame </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Zulfikar </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> was hanged for conspiracy to commit murder by his rival, Gen. <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> <PERSON> ul-Haq </PERSON>, in April 1979. Madame <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> was imprisoned in solitary confinement for three years, but formed the <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Restoration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION> in 1981. She reportedly suffered from cancer and went abroad for treatment for years, returning in 1988. Her two sons, Mir <PERSON> Murtaza </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>, and the younger <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> <PERSON> Nawaz </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> formed an anti-Zia organization based in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> called Al-Zulfikar, after their father. It was branded a terrorist organization, outlawed in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and the sons were exiled. Both married Afghan women. The organization claimed responsibility for the killing of the official who signed <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>'s execution order in 1979. Four years ago, <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> <PERSON> Nawaz </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> died in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> under mysterious circumstances. His mother says he was poisoned by Gen. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>'s supporters. Reports said he carried a vial of poison in case he was apprehended by enemies. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> himself died in a plane crash in August 1988. The surviving <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> son now is living in <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> at an undisclosed location, with a second wife whom he married last March, his mother said. Observers said he waits to return home to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and that his sister, the prime minister, is considering how to deal with his situation. Another child, the prime minister's younger sister <LOCATION> Sanam </LOCATION>, is a housewife living with her British husband in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. `` We always taught our children the difference between right and wrong,'' <PERSON> Madame </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> said. The daughters especially loved their father, the boys learned to be tough, she said. `` We said the only thing they leave behind is their good name.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 2346EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0760 10-10 0255</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0760,0258</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: ADDS Picker; No separates moved for the AMs cycle.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Richard Lindsley</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OGDEN, Utah (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lindsley </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Ogden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standard-Examiner </ORGANIZATION> managing editor who thrived on news, skiing and travel, died Monday of a blood infection stemming from an infected heart valve. He was 68. <PERSON> Lindsley </PERSON> was national advertising manager for the Times-Herald and <LOCATION> News-Chronicle </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Vallejo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and a teacher in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> before being hired by the Standard-Examiner. He joined the <PERSON> Standard-Examiner </PERSON>'s news staff as a reporter in 1955, became city editor in 1959 and assistant managing editor in 1964. <PERSON> Lindsley </PERSON> served as managing editor for five months before retiring in 1980. He had been a salesman in the classified advertising department and national advertising manager before joining the editorial department. <PERSON> Lindsley </PERSON> is survived by his wife, <PERSON> Carolynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Glasmann </PERSON> <PERSON> Lindsley </PERSON>, daughters <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> and <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Lindsley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and son <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON> <PERSON> Lindsley </PERSON> of <PERSON> Ketchum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Arnold Picker</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Picker </PERSON>, a former executive of the international branch of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Artists </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> who sought to preserve film's distinction as an art, died Sunday of pneumonia at age 76. <PERSON> Picker </PERSON> was former executive vice president and international head at <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Artists </ORGANIZATION>. He retired from the motion picture industry in 1967. Among his various achievements in the industry in a career that spanned more than 30 years, <PERSON> Picker </PERSON> was a protagonist in the forming of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. The institute is currently headed by <PERSON> Picker </PERSON>'s niece, <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Picker </PERSON> <PERSON> Firstenberg </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WhitherStarWars Bjt   10-10 0734</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Whither Star Wars, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Star Wars Backers Seek Stronger Administration Support of Defense
System</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> must `` put a line in the sand'' to head off further funding cuts for <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wars </ORGANIZATION>, say the missile defense system's hard-core backers who seek a sharper administration view of the program's purpose. These Republican lawmakers _ who bristle at use of the term Star Wars rather than the formal <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Initiative </ORGANIZATION> _ say <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> must act now as <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiators thrash out the defense budget for fiscal 1990. `` We need them to weigh in on this conference,'' Sen. <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallop </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wyo </LOCATION>., a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said in an interview last week `` The administration has to put a line in the sand on what is not acceptable to them,'' said Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasich </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ohio </LOCATION>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` Unless the administration is willing to come out and do something, it's going to continue to go downhill.'' Star Wars, introduced six years ago by then-President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as a nuclear-age antidote to a strike against the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, has suffered a series of blows in recent months. In early August, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> slashed $ 1.8 billion from President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s request of $ 4.9 billion for the program in fiscal 1990. The vote was 248-175, reflecting waning support for the program. Last month Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's SDI `` astrodome'' approach to protect the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was `` political jargon.'' Star Wars opponents cited these comments as an indication the administration does not have its heart in the program; proponents say the vice president's remarks were taken out of context. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> recently has moved to emphasize his support for the program. In a <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> System </ORGANIZATION> interview last weekend, the vice president urged <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> not to cut Star Wars funding. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has said little about Star Wars, but <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> insisted the president `` is a strong supporter of the Strategic Defense Initiative.'' Last week the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> slashed $ 900 million from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposal, but later reversed field and restored $ 600 million. That move was viewed not as an increase in support for Star Wars but rather the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s attempt to strengthen its bargaining position with the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. During negotiations, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> conferees have pushed for a Star Wars budget around $ 3.5 billion, far below the $ 4.1 billion spent on the program in fiscal 1989. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has favored a total closer to the $ 4.3 billion approved last week. In the wake of these events, the Republican disenchantment shows up in various forms. Wallop criticized the contact between the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, saying `` their congressional liaison is less than competent. They -LRB- the administration -RRB- are being told things that basically guided them elsewhere.'' `` The general tenor of their legislative liaison is to be a supporter once the crisis has arisen. Those of us trying to help have been frustrated by that,'' the <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> Republican said. Pressed for specific names, <PERSON> Wallop </PERSON> declined to identify them. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dewey </PERSON>, who handles legislative issues for the SDI organization at the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, said his office has been `` very supportive, right along. We have n't given up _ by no means. Nobody in our organization gives that impression.'' Another Pentagon official, who spoke on condition he not be identified, said he was `` a little taken aback'' by the senator's comments, and emphasized that `` we've worked the heck out of it and will continue to. Wallop said this week would be an ideal time for the administration to indicate the total fiscal 1990 budget it will accept for Star Wars, and he expressed his confidence that a former <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> lawmaker, <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>, will make that point clear. `` It's hard to fight for people who do n't have a target over which to fight,'' the senator said. Another SDI supporter, Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ill </LOCATION>., said he was looking to <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> to keep the program highly visible When asked if the administration has done enough to promote the program, <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON>, after a long pause, responded, `` probably not.'' `` Without administration support, the program will languish,'' said <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON>, who fears a substantial budget cut would `` emasculate'' the program. Rep. <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Kyl </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>., a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said he was not disappointed by the administration's efforts on behalf of <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wars </ORGANIZATION>, but said `` now is the time to weigh in
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GenericPrices Bjt   10-10 0664</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Generic Prices, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cheating Scandal May Lead to Costlier Generics</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Consumers may soon be paying higher prices for prescription drugs as more generic products are pulled from the market and cost-conscious buyers are left with fewer low-priced options, some industry observers say. Dozens of drugs have been recalled in the wake of allegations and admissions of cheating on safety tests required for <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> approval. The scandal is likely to produce a shakeout in the industry and result in more rigorous safety testing required for approval. Some generic drug makers and industry observers say this will force prices up, but others say the industry will remain competitive enough to withstand the financial pressures without price increases. A more immediate concern for consumers, however, is the possible effect of the recalls. `` The costs to pharmacists are going up for selected products, but not overall,'' said <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Grote </PERSON>, vice president of purchasing for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retired </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Persons </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pharmacy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The biggest impact of generic drug recalls may be seen by patients taking the high blood pressure drug Dyazide or its generic version. One of the drug's two clones was removed from the market earlier this year when its maker, <ORGANIZATION> Vitarine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pharmaceutical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, admitted cheating on safety tests to win <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> approval. Now the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> is trying to remove the other generic version from the market, saying its maker, <ORGANIZATION> Bolar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pharmaceutical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, misrepresented test data to the agency <ORGANIZATION> Bolar </ORGANIZATION>'s product is about half the price of Dyazide, and its removal from the market would mean higher prices for some consumers, at least until another generic version can win <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> approval. <ORGANIZATION> Bolar </ORGANIZATION> agreed to recall another drug, an antibiotic used to treat urinary tract infections, after the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> said the company cheated on product safety tests. The drug is nitrofurantoin, sold under the brand name Macrodantin by <ORGANIZATION> Norwich-Eaton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pharmaceuticals </ORGANIZATION>. Generic drugs, which account for about one-third of all prescriptions nationwide, now offer consumers savings averaging 50 percent to 70 percent over their brand-name counterparts. But some in the industry say the gap will narrow as the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> toughens regulations and as the industry itself consolidates. `` The prices for generics will show a gradual increase ... but still will be substantially below brand-name drugs,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Zenith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratories </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Northvale </LOCATION>, <PERSON> N.J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>, who with an investor group took the company out of bankruptcy last year and anticipates generic drug sales of $ 36 million to $ 40 million this year, also predicts an end to cutthroat pricing in the generic industry as companies realize that setting prices below costs to gain market share is unprofitable. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> has no formal proposal for tougher regulations, but agency officials have been discussing the need for more staff, the possibility of imposing user fees on the generic industry for new drug application filings and more rigorous safety testing. `` All of those things will affect the cost of the generic drug,'' said <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blissenbach </PERSON>, director of pharmacy programs for <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> HealthCare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a Minneapolis-based manager of health maintenance organizations. But an official at <ORGANIZATION> Rugby </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratories </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Rockville </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Center </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, disagrees. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeiger </PERSON>, executive vice president and general counsel of Rugby, a privately held generic drug maker said to be the largest in the country with about $ 500 million in annual sales, said the additional costs would not be enough to raise prices. `` It's a very competitive industry,'' he said. `` We do n't see the prices increasing at all.'' Analysts anticipate some generic manufacturers will not make it through the scandal. <PERSON> Hemant </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON>, a pharmaceutical analyst at <ORGANIZATION> HKS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, says more than half of the top 20 generic drug makers _ who account for 90 percent of the generic business _ will disappear within five years. `` But still the prices of generics probably are not going to rise because six or 10 companies are still enough for some form of pricing pressure,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0103EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lebanon-Life Bjt   10-10 0956</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon-Life, Bjt,0988</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lebanese Cautiously Pick Up The Pieces, Distrust Truce</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA ABU-NASR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This war-battered city is cautiously coming to life again after six months of fierce artillery battles. Beirutis are picking up the pieces of their lives under a cease-fire that took hold Sept. 22. But for many, the memories of the nightmare that killed 900 people will not go away. Schoolteacher <PERSON> Mona </PERSON> <PERSON> Khoury </PERSON> ate so much to calm her nerves during the fighting between <LOCATION> Syrian </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> forces that she ca n't get into her dresses now. Housewife <PERSON> Samia </PERSON> <PERSON> Iskandarani </PERSON> ca n't listen to the radio any more because it reminds her of fear-filled nights tuned to news flashes in her bunker. Another woman got hooked on sleeping pills during the shelling. While some people are having problems adjusting to a life without the fear of pulverizing bombardments, many are having fun while they can. The beaches that once were the playground of the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> are crowded again. Restaurants and bars are so full that customers have to make reservations. In Moslem west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> two weeks ago, when the city was largely deserted before the cease-fire, there was only one bar open. Movie theaters are open, screening action movies to people who by any stretch of the imagination should have had their fill of the real thing. Few people believe that the cease-fire will last or that Lebanese legislators meeting in <LOCATION> Taif </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>, to seek a settlement to the 14-year-old civil war will succeed. The Lebanese are grateful for the cease-fire. But after seeing hundreds of cease-fires collapse many consider this one nothing more than a respite in a conflict that has defied the peacemakers. They are returning to a normal life slowly and cautiously, if living amid the ruins with tightly rationed electricity and water can be called normal. `` I can only sleep if I take sleeping pills,'' said young Sunni Moslem woman who identified herself only as <PERSON> Ghada </PERSON>. `` It's the only way I can overcome my fear of being surprised by a shell during my sleep. It's a carry-over from the fighting. Ms. <PERSON> Iskandarani </PERSON>, a Moslem, said she has an aversion to radios these days: `` They're a reminder of the horrible days and nights we spent in the shelter waiting for news flashes to tell us where the shells were falling.'' Schools, offices and banks have reopened. Traffic around <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> is so heavy during the day that one driver, stuck in a traffic jam, joked with the driver of the car next to her: `` I wish the war was still on. It kept the streets clear and I'd be home by now.'' The moneychangers are back on <LOCATION> Hamra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>, the badly damaged center of the old commercial district in west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. Mostly they gather around a pile of stones outside a fast-food store, prompting local wags to dub the busy thoroughfare `` Wall Street.'' <PERSON> Samer </PERSON> <PERSON> Osseiran </PERSON>, proprietor of the Uncle <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> pub across from the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION>, said he wo n't remove the sandbags piled high outside his bar until a peace settlement is signed, sealed and delivered. `` Business is booming, but I do n't trust this truce,'' he said, echoing the feelings of most Beirutis. `` If there's no settlement I'll add more sandbags.'' Newspapers which a few weeks ago carried ads for 24-hour delivery of sandbags and cement blocks `` to protect your homes, shops and offices,'' now advertise repair services. People are making only essential repairs to their damaged houses, enough to make them habitable. Many are replacing broken windows with transparent plastic sheets. `` Why should I waste money fixing the whole place up?'' said <PERSON> Jihad </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON>, whose house in the seaside <LOCATION> Ein </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mreisseh </LOCATION> neighborhood of west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> took a direct hit from Christian artillery. `` I do n't believe in this cease-fire. Those deputies in <LOCATION> Taif </LOCATION> should be slaughtered for all the good they've done in the last 14 years,'' he said as he bought a lottery ticket. First prize is 15 million Lebanese pounds -LRB- $ 30,000 -RRB-, `` enough money to get out of this damned country.'' Most of the 1.3 million Beirutis _ 90 percent of the city's population _ who fled the fighting are settling back in their homes and students are returning to school The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> reopened on Monday. Many of those who stuck it out have found they're suffering from an unexpected problem _ weight gained down in the bunkers. `` I've just woken up to the fact that I put on 10 kilgrams -LRB- 22 pounds -RRB-,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Khoury </PERSON>. `` During the fighting I ate like a glutton. I found comfort in eating.'' She said she did n't realize how much weight she had gained because she was always dressed in `` shelter clothes,'' long, loose flowing dresses. `` But I learned the awful truth when I tried out a dress to go to back to school. I could n't do up the zipper.'' Colorful billboards advertising cosmetics and perfume have gone up again along the battered boulevards. The joggers are back, weaving through <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s shell-cratered gardens overlooking the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION>. The shell craters and bullet-pocked walls along west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s seaside boulevard are being patched up and many of the coffee vendors are back in business with their colorful umbrellas, small tables and rickety chairs Strollers gather for coffee during the day. At night, rats still dart out of huge piles of rotting garbage across the street. Uprooted palm trees and gutted vehicles still litter the corniche that runs around the rocky <PERSON> Ras </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Beirut </PERSON> peninsula jutting into the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION>. They are a reminder of the ferocious Christian barrages that sought to silence Syrian artillery, which took their toll on ships carrying fuel and weapons to the Christians in their beleaguered enclave across the bay.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-NursingHomeFire     10-10 0297</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nursing Home Fire,0302</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two More Patients Die From Nursing Home Fire</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NORFOLK, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The death toll from last week's nursing home fire rose to 11 on Monday with the deaths of two more elderly residents who had suffered smoke inhalation. Meanwhile, investigators said the four-story building's automatic alarm system malfunctioned when the fire broke out Thursday at the <ORGANIZATION> Hillhaven </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rehabilitation </ORGANIZATION> and Convalescent Center Nine residents were killed and 98 of the 161 residents were injured. The residents who died Monday were <PERSON> Ettie </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cunningham </PERSON>, 88, and <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hansthorn </PERSON>, 97, hospital spokeswomen said. Authorities said the fire was started when an elderly man who was smoking in violation of regulations accidentally tossed a match onto a mattress. The nursing home, built in 1969, did not have a sprinkler system. <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION> Fire Marshal <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> said investigators determined Monday that the building's automatic alarm system did n't work properly. The system should have automatically sent an alarm to the Fire Department through <ORGANIZATION> MGI </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> `` The alarm never left the building,'' <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> said after investigators checked the security company's records. `` We're still trying to determine what the problem was.'' Had the system worked properly, <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> said, firefighters would have been able to respond quicker. The fire was reported by four calls to the 911 emergency number. <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> said the response time was four minutes. <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> McKain </PERSON>, a vice president for the <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION>, Wash.-based <ORGANIZATION> Hillhaven </ORGANIZATION> chain, said <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> Secretary of Health and Human Resources <PERSON> Eva </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Teig </PERSON> and several other state and local officials toured the building Monday. <ORGANIZATION> Hillhaven </ORGANIZATION> officials had hoped to reopen Monday, but <PERSON> McKain </PERSON> said it appeared the nursing home would not reopen until Wednesday at the earliest because officials want written reports from the fire marshal and the building inspector.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CongressRdp     10-10 0558</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress Rdp,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrats Fear Child Care Could be Victim of Capital Gains Fight</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democrats fear that billions of dollars in proposed child care tax subsidies for low-income families could be lost in the fight over a proposed capital gains tax cut for the wealthy. The proposed child care tax writeoffs for families earning less than $ 25,000 are part of a broad deficit reduction bill that, in its House version, includes a cut in the capital gains tax rate for the rich. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> version also includes the new child care benefits. But Senate Democrats and Republicans are haggling over how to also provide a similar break for better-off taxpayers. The chamber's leaders from both parties planned to resume talks today on resolving the stalemate after making weak stabs at it through the weekend. Republicans and a handful of <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democrats want to fulfill President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign promise last year to cut the tax on capital gains _ profits made from selling stock, real estate and other property. Democrats are countering with a proposal to encourage savings by middle-and upper-income families by providing a tax break of up to $ 330 if they save $ 2,000 a year in Individual Retirement Accounts. Looming over the negotiations is an Oct. 16 deadline. Unless <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> completes work on a deficit-reduction plan by then, automatic across-the-board reductions will be triggered in most federal spending programs. `` We do n't have an agreement yet but everybody in there today thought we should get one,'' <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> told reporters on Sunday. `` Child care legislation is of the highest priority in this <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> _ a far higher priority than a capital gains tax cut,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>. `` We do n't want that to fall between the cracks. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders are searching for a way to strip away from the big deficit-reduction bill numerous provisions that are popular with lawmakers but do nothing to reduce the deficit. Democrats are trying to cut the capital gains tax cut from the deficit-reduction bill. But the child care provisions then could come under the same knife. Both the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> have approved slightly different child care measures that would rely on $ 11 billion to $ 13.5 billion in Earned Income Tax Credits for low-income families over the next five years to provide more than two-thirds of the new benefits. Republicans generally favor the tax-credit approach. But the plans approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> also include, at Democrats' insistence, $ 1.75 billion in new direct subsidies for child care plus a doubling of the current Head Start program for pre-school children Even if <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders are successful in stripping away the extraneous provisions and wrapping them together in a new bill, they still must seek agreement on the measure with their House counterparts. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> already has passed its own deficit-reduction bill. In addition to a capital gains cut, it includes repeal of catastrophic health coverage for retirees, restoration of the Fairness Doctrine that requires broadcasters to air all sides of an issue and extension of several expiring tax breaks for a variety of interests. Unless the House-passed deficit plan also is pared back, senators could be at a heavy disadvantage when they negotiate with <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members on final details of the bill.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Panama 2ndLd-Writethru a0681 10-10 0828</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0681,0850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Coup Leader Buried; Endara Ends Hunger Strike</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: To UPDATE with report of Giroldi's wife and children, others,
flown to Miami, INSERT two grafs after 21st, `Giroldki's widow ...' Picks
up 22nd pvs, `Defense Forces ...' ^By ELOY O. AGUILAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The army major who led the unsuccessful coup against Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was buried Monday and opposition leader <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> ended a 19-day hunger strike. Several reports have said an enraged <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> personally shot Maj. <PERSON> Moises </PERSON> <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON>, 38, to death minutes after the coup attempt against the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> leader ended a week ago. Relatives of <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON> said he was shot once in the neck and twice in the chest. His mother, <PERSON> Eloisa </PERSON>, cried `` They murdered him!'' and flung herself on the coffin. The major led an uprising Oct. 3 and captured <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who commands the Panamanian military and controls the government, but gave up when loyalists counterattacked while <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops looked on from a few hundred yards away. Officials of the <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> said eight officers and two sergeants were killed. They have not explained the circumstances or responded to reports that some were slain after surrendering. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> spokesman Maj. <PERSON> Edgardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Grimaldo </PERSON> on Monday said <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> met with his general staff to begin reshuffling military units that hesitated during the uprising or openly opposed him. The spokesman also said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> helicopters tried to intercept forces loyal to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> flying into <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hato </LOCATION>, but wavered, apparently because they had not been given specific orders. `` They tried to dissuade the <ORGANIZATION> Machos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monte </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- the company that now guards <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> headquarters -RRB- but there was no decision to say ` you can not pass,''' he said. <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Grimaldo </PERSON> did not describe what action the helicopters In another development, the civilian Cabinet met with President <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> to approve emergency laws first proposed by <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> last week and aimed at stifling military and political dissent. They include a military code, reforms to the penal code, labor laws to make it easier to fire disloyal public employees and economic laws to encourage investment. <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> meanwhile ended his fast and entered a clinic to `` normalize my body's system.'' A medical bulletin said his `` conscious process was excellent and his conversationcoherent,'' but he was suffering `` from progressive debilitation.'' The opposition leader has urged Panamanians to delay paying taxes and utility bills, and to shun the government lottery and casinos, on which the government has depended for much of its revenue the past 18 months. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has applied economic sanctions against <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> since federal grand juries in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> indicted <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> in February 1988 on charges of drug trafficking and money laundering. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> claims all efforts to oust him are part of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> plot to retain control of the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> after 1999, when it is to be turned over under treaties signed in 1977. At a news conference, <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> said he felt his hunger strike was a success. He said the opposition did not approve of the coup because it represented `` Noriegaism without <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>,'' not a movement toward democracy. Capt. <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Tejada </PERSON>, another rebel, was buried at the same small red stone church over the weekend. `` He had one bullet wound in the right temple,'' said <PERSON> Tejada </PERSON>'s mother, <PERSON> Esther </PERSON>, who was at the church again for <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON>'s burial. About 100 people attended the funeral Mass for <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON>. `` They were good friends,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Tejada </PERSON> said. `` My son had just come back from -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> duty in -RRB- <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> last Saturday. On Tuesday he told his wife he had to go to headquarters and would return later to go see his baby girl. `` We did not hear anything until Wednesday when they said on television that he was dead. We picked up the body.'' <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON>'s widow and three children did not attend. They have been under <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> protection at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clayton </LOCATION> since the coup. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported Tuesday that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has flown about 40 <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> coup participants, family members or <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> opponents to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, including Mrs. <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON>, her two sons, her father and other family members. The group included 14 military personnel, according to the paper, which quoted unidentified <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration sources. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> officials say the rebels surrendered after nearly five hours of negotiations with <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who was their hostage at Defense Forces headquarters. Sen. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>, and several <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> newspapers have said <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> personally shot <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON> in the final moments of the doomed uprising. <PERSON> Endara </PERSON>, the opposition's presidential candidate in May, took refuge in the <ORGANIZATION> Vatican </ORGANIZATION>'s embassy after soldiers beat him and threw him out of his office Thursday. Shortly before the assault, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> claimed he had evidence the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> planned to install <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> as president. Foreign observers said <PERSON> Endara </PERSON>'s ticket won the May 7 election by a 3-1 margin, but <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> had the results annulled May 10. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have said they consider <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> the legitimate president of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0114EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     10-10 0627</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Roach Revisionism Not Taking Hold at Agriculture Department</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Agriculture Department scientists are still out to bash cockroaches when they can, regardless of some who say live and let live. The department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> says there's a school of thought that suggests scientists `` ought to let up on the repulsive insects'' and concentrate on other pests. Defenders of cockroaches contend that unlike blood-feeding arthropods such as mosquitoes, ticks and fleas, the cockroaches `` are only incidental disease transmitters,'' says <PERSON> Regina </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiggen </PERSON>, associate editor of the agency's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> magazine. `` Thus, the roach revisionists argue, the risks that attend cockroach control may outweigh the benefits to be gained by maintaining a roach-free home,'' she said. But scientists at the department's Imported Fire Ant and <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insects </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, remain skeptical _ and they've been studying roaches since the 1940s. <PERSON> Wiggen </PERSON>, writing in the current issue of the magazine, admitted cockroaches `` have never been irrefutably incriminated in the natural transmission'' of disease organisms to humans. `` But there's plenty of circumstantial evidence to tie the roach to cases of typhoid fever and other diseases caused by Salmonella bacteria,'' <PERSON> Wiggen </PERSON> said. `` They've also been implicated as carriers of Clostridium perfringens, Staphylococcus aureus, and polio.'' <PERSON> Wiggen </PERSON> added: `` Roaches are notorious scavengers. They eat contaminated food and waste, then carry microorganisms in their digestive tracts, releasing them on the surfaces they contact. Release occurs through vomiting, excreting wastes and laying eggs on human food.'' A female cockroach can produce tens of thousands of offspring a year. In one study by the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> agency, scientists checking low-income housing in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> turned up 20,000 cockroaches in each apartment. There is also an esthetic dimension to the matter of food cleanliness, <PERSON> Wiggen </PERSON> said, quoting <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Currie </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> who described `` roaches crawling out of the drain, across the counter and onto the cream pie.'' Entomologist <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brenner </PERSON> of the agency's <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION> research center said in a related article that some 4,000 species of cockroaches are known to scientists. Only about 50 species are considered pests, but those are enough to prompt Americans to spend an estimated $ 1.5 billion annually on pesticides to control cockroaches. A goal of the <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION> research is to find long-term solutions, so <PERSON> Brenner </PERSON> is using electronic sensor and computers to help study cockroach behavior. Cockroaches thrive in areas of stagnant air and high humidity. Anything else `` tends to dry them out,'' he said. Also, a cockroach behaves differently in a group than it does when alone. Some cockroaches prefer attics, while others, such as the German cockroach, primarily inhabit walls. Once scientists determine the conditions cockroaches need to thrive, <PERSON> Brenner </PERSON> said it may be possible to manipulate the environment around the home to repel them. `` The bottom line is safer, more effective means of controlling cockroaches and ultimately preventing infestations,'' he said. Meanwhile, cardboard `` hotels,'' liquid doses of chemicals, spray and other weapons continue to be used by homeowners. A new slow-acting insecticide, sulfuramid, was developed by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> scientists to use against fire ants and was also found to be 90 percent effective against household ants and roaches. Sulfuramid was used as a wetting agent to coat baits with a potential insecticide for fire ants, says retired entomologist <PERSON> Clifford </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lofgren </PERSON>. `` When the ants were killed not only by the test bait but also by an non-toxic control bait coated only with the wetting agent, we realized we had stumbled onto a new class of compounds for controlling them,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> recently approved sulfuramid _ which is sold by <ORGANIZATION> Griffin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Valdosta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, under an exclusive license from the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> _ for use against household ants and roaches.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PlutoniumCharge     10-10 0601</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Plutonium Charge,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Employee Says Rockwell Ignored Warning on Plutonium Danger</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former engineer at the Rocky Flats nuclear weapons factory contends the plant operator knew for several years of possible accumulations of radioactive plutonium in the ventilation system but failed to investigate. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON>, a utility design engineer at the site near <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> from 1980 to 1986, said in a telephone interview Monday that the operator, <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, ignored the repeated warnings he voiced as early as 1984. `` They just said, forget it, we're not going to do it,'' <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said. Stone had no firm evidence of plutonium accumulations in air ducts, but his suspicions were proven correct by a team of independent investigators who last Friday told the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> they found 11 pounds of plutonium in air ducts linked to `` gloveboxes,'' or work chambers, in which plutonium is manually processed. The presence of plutonium in the ducts is considered a hazard because, under certain circumstances, it could lead to an uncontrolled nuclear reaction. Such a reaction could, in extreme cases, release lethal amounts of radioactivity. The investigators said the plutonium they found did not present an immediate health danger because it was not being released to the environment. But they criticized <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> for not having investigated earlier on the basis of <ORGANIZATION> Stone </ORGANIZATION>'s reports. Rocky Flats is owned by the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and makes plutonium triggers for nuclear warheads. <PERSON> Rockwell </PERSON> had contended prior to the investigation by experts from <ORGANIZATION> Scientech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, an engineering and management company based in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, that there were no accumulations of plutonium in any ductwork at Rocky Flats. <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Heintz </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said Monday he could not comment on Stone's allegations because they might be linked to an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> investigation of possible violations of environmental laws at Rocky Flats. He said the company was not prepared to comment on the Scientech findings because it had not studied the final report, which is highly critical of <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION>'s safety procedures. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> began investigating Rocky Flats last June but no indictments have been handed down so far. The independent investigators were sent to the weapons plant in July by Energy Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, who is attempting to resolve uncertainties about operational safety and waste management at Rocky Flats and other weapons plants. <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said he realized the probability of plutonium deposits in the ventilation system in 1984 while he was helping plan a renovation of Building 881, a former site of uranium and plutonium processing that now is used as a laboratory and computer center. <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said <PERSON> Rockwell </PERSON> did not act on his advice that the hundreds of feet of stainless steel ducts be sandblasted or cleaned in some other way to remove any plutonium buildup. `` It was n't part of the original scope of their work so they were n't going to do it,'' he said. <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Mattson </PERSON>, a vice president of Scientech and leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Rocky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Flats </ORGANIZATION> investigation, said in a telephone interview that <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> shut down several of the gloveboxes after the discovery in August and began taking steps to correct the problem. <PERSON> Mattson </PERSON> said `` it's still an open question'' as to whether plutonium deposits have accumulated in the ductwork at Building 881, where Stone had been working. Stone contended in an August 1986 lawsuit against <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> that he had been fired five months earlier in retaliation for having raised numerous health and safety issues, including the risk posed by the plutonium deposits. Stone's lawyer, <PERSON> Hartley </PERSON> <PERSON> Alley </PERSON>, said the suit is scheduled to go to trial later this month.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HUD-SpendingSpree     10-10 0589</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-HUD-Spending Spree,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>HUD Audit Details $35 Million Spending Spree in One Day</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal housing officials say they're honoring most loan commitments they made in a $ 35 million spending spree in a multi-family loan program on the last day of fiscal 1988. More than 100 loans from the Section 312 loan program were approved that day _ Sept. 30, 1988 _ in an apparent rush to spend the money before it was transferred to another program at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, according to agency records and auditors. <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> auditors determined most of the loans were approved despite incomplete applications and processing, but were told by the department's attorneys the government must keep its funding promises in all but a few cases. `` Where commitments were made they were honored, but -LRB- HUD -RRB- will not be making conditional commitments in the future,'' department spokesman <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON> said. The Section 312 program has not received new funding for several years but continues to make loans using payments on outstanding loans. Roughly $ 200 million was available for the program in fiscal 1988. In the final month of the budget year, Section 312 loans totaling more than $ 40 million were approved, including 107 totaling $ 35.3 million on Sept. 30, according to <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> records. Seven of the loans later were canceled, including the largest, a $ 6.1 million loan to convert a closed hotel in <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, to apartments. There is nothing in the documents to suggest political favoritism was involved in the year-end loan approvals, but the auditors and other <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> officials said intense competition within <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> for the shrinking federal housing allowance likely was a factor in the hasty approvals. The auditors also raised questions about program management, saying regulations requiring proper documentation and other checks before making loan commitments were ignored. Those criticisms mirror others levied at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> by auditors and congressional investigators who blame lax agency management for many of the problems being exposed in congressional hearings and internal reviews. <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s inspector general reviewed 19 of the biggest loans made in the final month of the 1988 fiscal year _ those for more than $ 500,000 _ and found 11 were approved on the final day. In all 19 cases, the obligations, totaling $ 29 million, were improper because the necessary approval requirements had not been met, the auditors concluded last month. The auditors attributed the rush to spend the money to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' decision that any Section 312 money not spent at the end of the fiscal year was to be transferred to the Community Development Block Grant Program That program falls under a different <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> department and provides loans and grants to projects designed to benefit low - and moderate-income citizens `` We believe that most of the obligations were recorded because the ... staff wanted to obligate the available Section 312 funds before they were reallocated to the Community Development Block Grant Program,'' the auditors concluded in a report late last month. Several <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> officials interviewed in recent weeks said conditional approvals for Section 312 loans had been a common practice for years, with officials committing money to the projects before developers completed their applications. But such approvals will no longer be given because of the concerns raised by the inspector general and <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s legal counsel, <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON> said. The <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION> loan was canceled because a regional <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> official who granted the project waivers did n't have the authority to do so, according to <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> records. The six other canceled loans totaled $ 5.1 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0104EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-USSForrestal-Fire 2ndLd-Writethru a0441 10-10 0320</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-USS Forrestal-Fire, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0441,0321</SECOND>
<HEAD>Electrical Fire on USS Forrestal</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with five grafs to UPDATE with fire confined to machinery
room and DELETES extraneous material at end.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MAYPORT NAVAL STATION, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An electrical fire broke out in an elevator shaft on the aircraft carrier <ORGANIZATION> USS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forrestal </ORGANIZATION> on Monday night, and four sailors suffered minor injuries putting it out, a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said. `` At this moment we believe the fire to be out,'' <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Byers </PERSON> said at 12:15 a.m. Tuesday. `` I believe it took place in one of the forward elevators, just forward of the ship's superstructure. Two people suffered cuts and bruises and two suffered smoke inhalation. All four were treated at the naval station's dispensary, <PERSON> Byers </PERSON> said The fire erupted just after after 8:30 p.m. aboard the ship docked at <LOCATION> Mayport </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Naval </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>. The fire was primarily confined to a machinery room inside the shaft of an elevator that raises aircraft to deck level, said Cmdr. <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>. There was `` quite a bit of smoke,'' he said. He could n't say where or when the ship was to be deployed next. At full capacity, the ship carries 148 officers and 2,810 enlisted men, plus 2,480 officers and men in the air wing, for a total of 5,438. The air wing was not on board Monday, leaving a crew of about 2,500 to 3,000 sailors on the ship, a spokesman said. The 1,086 foot-long <PERSON> Forrestal </PERSON>, which is based at <LOCATION> Mayport </LOCATION>, was the first <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aircraft carrier launched after World War II and the first designed to operate jet aircraft. Now the third oldest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> carrier on active service, the <PERSON> Forrestal </PERSON> has been modernized several times since it was launched on Dec. 11, 1954. It underwent a major refit from January 1983 to May 1985 at the <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yard </ORGANIZATION> that was designed to extend its life another 15 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     10-10 0390</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0409</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CASHMERE, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Neither bees nor rocks nor fast-drying cement could stop county officials from placing a marker at the state's geographic center. About 40 people attended a ceremony Saturday to install a brass <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Geological Survey marker at a spot four miles up the <LOCATION> Devil </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulch </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Trail </LOCATION> south of Cashmere But the siting was no simple matter. On the day before, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Warby </PERSON>, Cashmere centennial chairman, and <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> pushed a wheelbarrow carrying a portable generator toward the site. The generator was to power a drill, which would make a hole for the anchor spike. But a sharp rock flattened one of the wheelbarrow tires, and as the two stashed the generator in the brush they set it down on a nest of bees. They left hurriedly. On Saturday, they retrieved the generator after spraying the bees with insecticide. Their hard luck persisted, though, at the site. Someone mixed up fast-acting cement for anchoring the plaque sooner than expected and officials had to work fast to get the marker in place. There was no time for speeches. `` We just said, ` This is the center of the state as near as anybody can tell,''' <PERSON> Warby </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PROVIDENCE, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The price of a ticket to Trinity Repertory Theater's production of `` Summerfolk'' tonight should spark precurtain murmurs. That's because theatergoers are paying what they want. `` The objective is to give everyone an opportunity to come to the theater,'' said <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Langan </PERSON>, managing director of the theater company that has won many national honors. The normal ticket price is $ 24. Based on similar experiments by others in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Langan </PERSON> said he expected people tonight to pay $ 3 or $ 4. `` But that's OK,'' he said. `` The whole purpose of this is for someone to be comfortable in coming to the theater.'' Patrons can offer a price as low as they want; the only rule is they must pay something, he said. <PERSON> Langan </PERSON> wo n't turn down offers of more than $ 24. `` I'd love to see that,'' he said. `` There is a great pressure to produce quality shows, and then the discussion gets into money and then there's pressure on ticket prices.'' Trinity has set aside $ 5,000 from a sponsorship grant from <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Trust </LOCATION> bank to cover projected losses.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NobelPrize Bjt   10-10 0706</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nobel Prize, Bjt,0727</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pair of U.S. Microbiology Researchers Win Nobel Prize in Medicine</HEAD>
<HEAD>With LaserPhoto</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHLEEN MACLAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> was unsure about becoming a doctor, and <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Varmus </PERSON> wrote his thesis on <PERSON> Dickens </PERSON>, not DNA. But today the pair share the Nobel Prize in medicine. The two microbiology researchers at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> celebrated their award on Monday, by toasting each other with French champagne at a news conference at the university. Then they headed to Candlestick Park to watch the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION> win the National League playoff series against the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cubs </ORGANIZATION>. The 50-member Nobel Assembly of the <ORGANIZATION> Karolinska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s largest and oldest medical university, cited <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> and <PERSON> Varmus </PERSON> for their discovery of a collection of normal genes that can cause cancer when they go awry. In 1976, their research showed that normal genes that apparently control cell growth can undergo alterations that lead to the uncontrolled growth that is cancer. Their work has led to the discovery of more than 40 different genes that can cause cancer, and is leading to better ways to diagnose cancer and predict who is at risk. As knowledge of the genes increases, researchers hope to find ways to block them if they become deranged, stopping the growth of the cancerous cells. The research helped scientists understand how cancer begins, and it `` widened our insight into the complicated signal systems which govern the normal growth of cells,'' the assembly said. <PERSON> Varmus </PERSON> called the research by him and <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> a `` cornerstone in understanding the genetic mosaic of cancer.'' <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> and <PERSON> Varmus </PERSON> were optimistic about the practical applications of their work. But they were cautious about forecasting a cancer cure. `` This is just another step in what's a long journey,'' <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> said. `` It's very difficult to predict when a full view of the cancer cell will be at hand.'' <PERSON> Varmus </PERSON> saluted other researchers in the field, saying, `` We all stand on the shoulders of those who came before us.'' But Dr. <PERSON> Dominique </PERSON> <PERSON> Stehelin </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> researcher who carried out experiments overseen by <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> and <PERSON> Varmus </PERSON> in the 1970s, said bitterly Monday that he was disappointed about not being included in the Nobel Prize. `` This work belongs to me,'' he said, `` and I do n't know why the scientific community refuses to attribute the discovery to me.'' <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> and <PERSON> Varmus </PERSON> called <PERSON> Stehelin </PERSON>'s work `` crucial'' to their research, but referred questions about the prize to the Nobel committee. `` We did n't nominate each other,'' <PERSON> Varmus </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Varmus </PERSON> said he abandoned plans to become an English professor, and his studies of 17th century literature, to attend medical school after learning that writer <PERSON> Gertrude </PERSON> <PERSON> Stein </PERSON> enrolled at <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hopkins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> after being told that `` medicine opens all doors.'' Gradually he found that he enjoyed being in the laboratory more than the clinic, and his research career began. `` My mother died of breast cancer, but I do n't know if that in itself caused me to study the cause of cancer ... there's hardly anybody in this room who is not touched by cancer somehow,'' <PERSON> Varmus </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> said he was interested in science in high school, and decided to become a doctor. But he said that `` by the time I finished college, I was n't so sure I wanted to be a doctor.'' It was a rural <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> doctor, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kough </PERSON>, who became his mentor and convinced him that his calling was in medical research. <PERSON> Kough </PERSON>, director emeritus of hemotology at <ORGANIZATION> Geisinger </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Danville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON>'s `` spark was recognized not only by me, but by his professors ... by everybody who came into contact with him.'' <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, holds degrees from <ORGANIZATION> Gettysburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Varmus </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Oceanside </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, has degrees from <ORGANIZATION> Amherst </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. Both said they do n't expect their lives to be dramatically altered because of winning the Nobel Prize. `` It's the only job I've ever had since putting on roofs in high school, <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> quipped. `` I like my life the way it is, and I hope it stays that way,'' <PERSON> Varmus </PERSON> said. `` The danger is you're supposed to be smarter today than you were yesterday, and I'm not.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0143EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtoninBrief     10-10 0326</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington in Brief,330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Government Switching Phone Systems</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The federal government says its switchover to a new long-distance telephone network will save millions of dollars and provide 1.3 million federal workers with state-of-the-art voice, data and video communications. The changeover began during the long Columbus Day weekend at 31 government buildings nationwide. Ultimately, more than 1,300 locations in 90 federal agencies will be tied to the network when it is fully installed in mid-1990. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> is overseeing the mammoth switchover with the two prime contractors that won a fierce bidding war for the project, <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sprint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> estimates FTS2000 will save taxpayers between $ 15 million and $ 20 million a month for regular telephone service _ or as much as half of the government's $ 400 million annual phone bill
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Battle Brewing Over Animal-Protection Bills</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A mounting number of animal-rights related bills face <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and both sides are preparing for the battle. On one side is Rep. <PERSON> Vin </PERSON> <PERSON> Weber </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Minn </LOCATION>., who says <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> needs a `` common-sense voice'' to combat the efforts of animal-rights activists He's recruiting colleagues for a group he tentatively calls the <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welfare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caucus </ORGANIZATION>. On the other side is <PERSON> Annette </PERSON> <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, wife of Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, D-Calif. She is helping him and Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, organize the Congressional Friends of Animals The caucuses plan to serve as forums for debate and clearinghouses of information on bills such as ones to make it illegal to break into laboratories and destroy documents; prohibit certain lethal testing of laboratory animals; and require special labels on cans of tuna that were caught in nets that endanger dolphins. <PERSON> Weber </PERSON> says consumers and many members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> do n't realize the impact the animal-rights movement could have on farming and medical research, but animal-rights activists say the increasing number of bills on the issue reflects a rising public concern about it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-EGermany-Media     10-10 0540</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-EGermany-Media,0559</SECOND>
<HEAD>Aging Communists Find New Scapegoat in Western News Media</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-East Germany, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN COSTELLOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FRANKFURT, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> leaders have found a new scapegoat to explain away mounting protests for reform and the refugee exodus. The culprit is Western news media. Worldwide television broadcasts of police beating people protesting for democratic reform in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION> and elsewhere have pushed the Communist government to bitter denunciations. One party newspaper condemned the `` gang of Western reporters,'' while <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s official news agency accused Western journalists of working in cooperation with the demonstrators. During protests, police roughed up journalists, smashed cameras, confiscated film and ordered some photographers and television crews to leave the East German capital immediately. They also detained at least two journalists before letting them go several hours later. Until recently, large street protests were a rarity in a country whose government traditionally blamed its woes on Western agents and an allegedly unfriendly government in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>. Television footage of unrest was scarce. But over the last month, that has changed. An exodus of at least 50,000 East Germans to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> since Sept. 11 emboldened those left behind to speak out and protest during a weekend visit by Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> on <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s 40th anniversary. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> attracted dozens of Western correspondents and television crews anxious to know what he told <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s hard-line leader, <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>, who has rejected the reforms embraced by some East bloc allies Consequently, the many foreign journalists accredited to cover <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s visit were on hand to hear the thousands of East Germans who want reform. In <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> and five provincial cities, police over the weekend beat and arrested hundreds and perhaps thousands of protesters. <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s leaders were angered. The first broadside came on Sunday, after thousands of protesters filled <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s main square. `` In the evening hours of Oct. 7, troublemakers tried to disturb the people's celebrations for the 40th anniverary of the GDR -LRB- <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> -RRB-,'' the state news agency, <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION>, said. `` In cooperation with Western news media, they banded together in the <ORGANIZATION> Alexanderplatz </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s main square -RRB- and nearby areas and called out slogans against the Republic.'' Among the slogans the protesters chanted was, `` <LOCATION> Gorby </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Gorby </LOCATION>, help us!'' The East German government tried to clamp down on reporting Sunday, declaring whole areas of the capital off-limits to photographers. That included a Lutheran church that has become the focal point for <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s growing opposition movement. `` Wherever the gang of Western reporters went, especially the television crews, certain types showed up seconds later and started trouble,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> youth newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Junge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welt </ORGANIZATION> charged. But, as if to balance hostility to the Western news media, the newspaper also said that its own photographer's camera had been smashed in the weekend clashes. The nation's official newspapers printed Sunday's <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> dispatch calling the pro-democracy demonstrators `` troublemakers.'' <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> lodged an official protest against the East German interference with the Western journalists, but the East German government's diplomatic mission in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> rejected the allegations. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> ARD </ORGANIZATION> television network also lodged a protest, saying the East Germans' interference with its reporters' work violated `` international rules and regulations,'' including the <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> accords.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Liberia     10-10 0219</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Liberia,0225</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Suspends Diplomatic Relations With Liberia</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> suspended diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION> today, a week after the African state normalized ties with the Nationalist government on <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>. The official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION>'s ambassador to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Ricks </PERSON>, was summoned to the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> this morning to be told of the Chinese decision. <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION> is the second nation this year, following the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Indies </LOCATION> island state of <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION>, to normalize ties with <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, a step which always leads to a severing of ties with the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> government. <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, which regards <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> as a renegade province, refuses to accept dual recognition of the governments in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>. A Foreign Ministry official told <PERSON> Ricks </PERSON> that <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION>'s decision ran counter to principles set forth when the two countries established relations in 1977, when <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION> recognized the People's Republic as the sole legal government representing <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> `` Under such circumstances, the Chinese government can not but suspend its diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION> as of today,'' <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> quoted the ministry official as saying. <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s Foreign Minister <PERSON> Lien </PERSON> <PERSON> Chan </PERSON>, in announcing the establishment of relations with <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION>, said the diplomatic victory was achieved because `` we are making more progress politically, economically and socially'' than Communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> now has relations with 137 countries, compared to 25 for <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0204EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hugo-Aftermath     10-10 0742</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hugo-Aftermath,0765</SECOND>
<HEAD>Long, Painful Recovery Seen for U.S. Island Territory</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT GLASS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHRISTIANSTED, U.S. Virgin Islands (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For many residents of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Croix </LOCATION>, the resort island raked by Hurricane Hugo and then plundered by looters, life is still chaotic. Three weeks after one of the century's most destructive storms struck the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> on its way to <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Carolinas </LOCATION>, most of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Croix </ORGANIZATION>'s 56,000 inhabitants still have no electricity or telephone service. Running water is just beginning to be restored. Thousands of houses, schools and churches are destroyed, and some beaches are fouled by sewage and fuel oil. Health officials have raised concerns about the possibility of epidemics caused by contaminated water, a lack of refrigeration, poor sanitation and millions of mosquitoes breeding in stagnant water. A tent hospital in <LOCATION> Christiansted </LOCATION> is the only one on the island admitting patients. The looting has long since stopped, but 1,000 military police deployed by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to help restore order still patrol the streets with pistols and M-16 rifles. A curfew remains in effect. Scores of supermarkets and hardware, appliance and clothing stores stand in ruins, their shelves emptied by looters. `` We do n't have anything to eat. We do n't have any stores to go to,'' said <PERSON> Lillian </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON>, a mother of seven children ranging in age from 10 months to 20 years, as she stood in a <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> food line in the eastern port town of <LOCATION> Frederiksted </LOCATION>. `` We need rice. We need corn flour,'' she said. `` I try not to get depressed. I just have to think things are going to get better.'' <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Croix </LOCATION>, about 70 miles east of <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, was by far the hardest hit of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, although St. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> and <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> also suffered substantial damage when Hurricane Hugo hit on Sept. 17. Three people were killed on <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Croix </LOCATION>, where winds of up to 216 mph stripped the once lush landscape of its foliage. From the air, towns on the 84-square-mile island look as if they were bombed. Dr. <PERSON> Carlton </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodgson </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Frederiksted </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said he and 13 other doctors have treated nearly 5,000 patients for storm-related injuries such as nail punctures, broken bones and burns. <PERSON> Hodgson </PERSON> said he was beginning to see patients with psychological problems caused by <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON>'s devastation. A typical case, he said, was a man depressed over the loss of rare vases collected over a lifetime. `` The thought of having something to leave as a legacy is not there anymore,'' <PERSON> Hodgson </PERSON> said. The territorial government has estimated damage to the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> at $ 500 million, but Lt. Gov. <PERSON> Derek </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodge </PERSON> said he expected the figure to rise to $ 4 billion. Damage to the giant <ORGANIZATION> Hess </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> refinery in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Croix </LOCATION> alone was $ 100 million, he said. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration has alloted $ 1.1 billion for hurricane relief in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hodge </PERSON> said he believed it would take up to two years for <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Croix </LOCATION> to recover fully from the hurricane. `` This is going to be a long one,'' said <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON>, who is directing the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>'s relief operation in the territory. `` I think we'll be in the full-steam-ahead recovery program for six months. We may still be building some houses after that.'' Federal officials say 6,300 houses in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Croix </LOCATION>, about one-third of all homes, were heavily damaged or destroyed. <PERSON> Hodge </PERSON> said most of the homeless were staying with relatives but that 500 remained in shelters. Tap water started flowing to <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Croix </LOCATION> homes on Thursday, but was being rationed while repairs continued. Officials said it would take at least six months to fully restore electricity and telephones. There is extensive damage to hotels, guesthouses, restaurants and marinas, and the outlook for tourism is bleak. However, nine of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Croix </ORGANIZATION>'s 13 hotels say they hope to reopen by the start of the winter tourist season in December. Meantime, hundreds of workers have been laid off and there is concern some businesses might never reopen. Some businesses said they were ruined by looters, who went on a four-day spree and stole everything from food and building supplies to lawn mowers and TVs. <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents are searching homes for stolen goods, and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney's office is investigating allegations that members of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> and the local police force were involved.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0230EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CountryAwards     10-10 0658</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Country Awards,0679</SECOND>
<HEAD>George Strait _ a White House Favorite _ Voted Top Entertainer</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos NS1,NS2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOE EDWARDS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Strait </PERSON>, a former ranch trail boss whose songs are White House favorites, was voted entertainer of the year by the <ORGANIZATION> Country </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Music </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Strait, 37, won country music's top honor Monday night during the association's nationally televised 23rd annual awards show. <PERSON> Ricky </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Mattea </PERSON> won top vocalist honors, and perennial honoree <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> received two awards. The accolade for <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION> came a month after President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, a country music fan, told the singer how much he enjoyed his songs. The president made the comments during a Rose Garden ceremony honoring <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION> and 11 others for promoting vocational-technical education. Monday night at the Grand Ole Opry House, <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION>'s peers gave him a standing ovation as he accepted a bullet-shaped trophy for entertainer of the year. `` I'm so excited. I've wanted this for so long,'' said Strait of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Marcos </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. He thanked his Ace in the Hole Band, adding: `` I truly believe audiences go away entertained.'' Strait's July hit single, `` What's Going On in Your World,'' was his 19th No. 1 song in eight years of recording. His album `` Beyond the Blue Neon'' has been a top seller this year. Besides his crisp tenor, he is known for his spiffy cowboy hats, neatly pressed jeans and starched shirts that accent his lean, athletic frame. `` This is incredible,'' he said backstage after the awards program. `` I'm my own worst critic. I know I'm not a great singer.'' A fourth-generation cattle rancher who was a trail boss in the 1970s, <ORGANIZATION> Strait </ORGANIZATION> has a degree in agriculture from <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. Top male vocalist honors went to <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON>, an ex-pipefitter in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, for his recent hit singles `` From a Jack to a King'' and `` Hole in My Pocket.'' `` I thank God he gave me a voice instead of big feet,'' <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON> quipped as he accepted the award. Top female vocalist <PERSON> Mattea </PERSON>, a former tour guide at the Country Music Hall of Fame, had a No. 1 single in `` Come From the Heart.'' `` I've always liked to do this -LRB- sing -RRB-, because I liked the doing of it,'' she said, her voice choked with emotion. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, the association's entertainer of the year in 1987 and 1988, was the night's only double winner. Both awards were for his music video, `` There's a Tear in My Beer'' _ on which old footage and sound recordings are used to make it appear that <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> is singing with his late father, the famed country artist. The vocal event of the year award goes to two performers who do n't normally sing together. The late <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON>, 33, who died of an accidental alcohol overdose in May, won single of the year for his hit `` I'm No Stranger to the Rain.'' The award was accepted by his widow, singer <PERSON> Lorrie </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, who said as her voice cracked, `` Five months ago on this date, I lost the world's greatest husband, and country music, in my eyes, lost the world's greatest singer.'' The mother-daughter team the <ORGANIZATION> Judds </ORGANIZATION> won duo of the year, making it the fifth consecutive year they won either duo of the year or group of the year. `` I think as time goes by, we appreciate it -LRB- winning -RRB- more every day,'' daughter <PERSON> Wynonna </PERSON> <PERSON> Judd </PERSON> said. `` Music is n't just a living, it's our life.'' Singer <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> and music publishers <PERSON> Cliffie </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> and the late <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Stapp </PERSON> were chosen for the Country Music Hall of Fame. Other winners included: `` Will the Circle Be Unbroken Vol. II'' by the Nitty Gritty Dirt Band, top album; Highway 101, group of the year for the second straight year; fiddler <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Gimble </PERSON>, musician of the year; `` Chiseled in Stone'' by <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> and <PERSON> Vern </PERSON> <PERSON> Gosdin </PERSON>, song of the year, a songwriters' award; and <PERSON> Clint </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, Horizon Award for a rising star.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891010-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-10-89 0231EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CountryAwards-List     10-10 0185</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Country Awards-List,0212</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Country Awards</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winners in the 23rd annual Country Music Awards show Monday night:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>ENTERTAINER OF THE YEAR:</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Strait </PERSON>
</TEXT>
<HEAD>FEMALE VOCALIST OF THE YEAR:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Mattea </PERSON>
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MALE VOCALIST OF THE YEAR:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ricky </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON>
</TEXT>
<HEAD>SINGLE OF THE YEAR:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` I'm No Stranger to the Rain'' _ <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON> _ RCA
</TEXT>
<HEAD>ALBUM OF THE YEAR:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` Will the Circle Be Unbroken Vol. II'' _ Nitty Gritty Dirt Band, Universal
</TEXT>
<HEAD>SONG OF THE YEAR (A</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` Chiseled in Stone'' _ <ORGANIZATION> Max </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> D. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Barnes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Vern </PERSON> <PERSON> Gosdin </PERSON>
</TEXT>
<HEAD>VOCAL GROUP OF THE YEAR:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Highway 101
</TEXT>
<HEAD>VOCAL DUO OF THE YEAR:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The Judds
</TEXT>
<HEAD>VOCAL EVENT OF THE YEAR:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> & amp; <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> Sr.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MUSICIAN OF THE YEAR:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Gimble </PERSON> _ fiddler
</TEXT>
<HEAD>HORIZON AWARD:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Clint </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON>
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MUSIC VIDEO OF THE YEAR (ATARDED TO PERFORMER AND DIRECTOR)</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` There's a Tear in My Beer'' _ <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ethan </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>
</TEXT>
<HEAD>HALL OF FAME:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
