<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 2326EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-CostaRica-American     02-06 0348</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Costa Rica-American,0359</SECOND>
<HEAD>Costa Rican Court Denies Bond For American Arrested On Drug Charges</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARLOS SANDI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN JOSE, Costa Rica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hull </PERSON>, a well-known supporter of Nicaraguan rebels, remained in custody for drug and weapons charges Monday after a court denied his request for release on bond. The <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Penal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Alajuela </LOCATION> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Monday that it rejected <PERSON> Hull </PERSON>'s request to be released on $ 12,500 bond. Judge <PERSON> Maximo </PERSON> <PERSON> Esquivel </PERSON>, head of the court issuing the ruling, refused to comment on the decision. <PERSON> Hull </PERSON>, 69, has been held since he was arrested Jan. 13. Officials also said he was being investigated on charges of spying for the U.S.-backed rebels, known as the Contras. <PERSON> Hull </PERSON> remained in custody a Costa Rican hospital where he was taken Jan. 24 after suffering a heart attack in his jail cell. <PERSON> Matias </PERSON> <PERSON> Quesada </PERSON>, director of <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, said Monday that <PERSON> Hull </PERSON> was recuperating and in stable condition. <PERSON> Elda </PERSON> <PERSON> Zuniga </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hull </PERSON>'s attorney, claims her client is the victim of political persecution and that his arrest was unconstitutional. <PERSON> Hull </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> resident, has lived in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> for 20 years. He has denied any drug trafficking connections. He said in 1986 that authorities twice raided his home in unsuccessful attempts to find evidence of gun-running and drug smuggling. <PERSON> Hull </PERSON> has acknowledged permitting the Contras to use his ranch property for their activities before the Iran-Contra case broke in 1986. In the case, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration officials sent arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> for money to be sent to the Contras. Witnesses testifying before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on illegal arms shipments to the Contras have said <PERSON> Hull </PERSON>'s ranch was a way station for gun smugglers and cocaine traffickers. <PERSON> Hull </PERSON> was not among 13 men indicted in Spetember in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> on charges of running an illegal arms network for the Contras. Reports said <PERSON> Hull </PERSON> was granted immunity by the special prosecutor in the case. Convicted cocaine pilot <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Betzner </PERSON> has testified that <PERSON> Hull </PERSON> once met his plane when it landed on the ranch to exchange Contra arms for Colombian cocaine.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 2343EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-People SUB a0588 02-06 0388</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People, SUB, a0588,0398</SECOND>
<HEAD>Givens' Lawyer: Divorce Agreement Signed</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS New York-dated final item in AM-People to UPDATE with Givens
signing divorce agreement and comments from attorney. No pickup.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY44</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Givens </PERSON> has signed a divorce agreement that will end her stormy marriage to heavyweight boxing champion <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON>, her attorney said Monday. They plan to file for divorse in the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> and the divorce should be final within 45 days, said lawyer <PERSON> Raoul </PERSON> <PERSON> Felder </PERSON>. A no-fault divorce _ in which both parties agree that they should be divorced _ can be obtained in the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> by either husband or wife following an overnight stay in the country, said <PERSON> Felder </PERSON>. Residency requirements are more stringent in other places, he said. `` Theoretically, either one of them could go there tomorrow and get it,'' he said. However, he said, because both of them have prior commitments, the Dominican divorce will not be sought until at least 30 days from now. <PERSON> Felder </PERSON> described the agreement, which <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> signed last week and Ms. <PERSON> Givens </PERSON> signed Sunday night, this way: `` Basically, she will keep what was hers, including all of her jewelry, and he will keep what is his.'' <PERSON> Felder </PERSON> declined to discuss the settlement in detail. Asked who would get the couple's <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> mansion, he said, `` She never wanted it.'' In a statement Ms. <PERSON> Givens </PERSON> released through her publicist <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON>, she said she and her family would be rooting for <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> when he fights British boxer <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON> on Feb. 25. She also said: `` In view of the fact that <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> has honored our personal agreement not to further publicly discuss our matter, nor the terms of the agreement, I will do no less. This is the last statement I will have on our personal lives.'' Earlier Monday, <PERSON> Felder </PERSON> said he would know by the end of the week whether Ms. <PERSON> Givens </PERSON> had signed the agreement, but later in the day he acknowledged that she had signed it Sunday evening. He said he originally did n't want to confirm the agreement had been signed because of a technical glitch in the paperwork, but he later decided to confirm that Ms. <PERSON> Givens </PERSON> had signed the agreement to clear up conflicting reports. Ms. <PERSON> Givens </PERSON> appears in the TV series, `` Head of the Class.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 2347EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SowetoSchool     02-06 0690</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soweto School,0709</SECOND>
<HEAD>US-Financed School in Soweto Reopens after Unrest</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANDREW TORCHIA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SOWETO, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of new pupils have entered the battered classrooms of <ORGANIZATION> Pace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, signaling the rebirth of a private high school that was once a showpiece of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> investment in black education. When Pace opened in 1982, the $ 6-million, tan brick building gleamed like a well-endowed institution in a wealthy <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> suburb. Despite the grassy, 22-acre campus separating it from <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION>'s dirt streets and shabby bungalows, the school now seems to belong to an inner-city slum. Offering commercial studies as an alternative to <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION>'s rundown state schools, Pace suffered during the 1984-87 period of nationwide black unrest and school boycotts against apartheid. Militants advocating `` people's education'' tagged Pace as elitist. Politics and violence distracted the students and few passed their exams. The school closed for several months. Principals came and went, vandals invaded the building, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> companies that had built the school withdrew their support, the staff served without pay, and enrollment shrank. As the new term began Jan. 25, the roof leaked and the telephone did n't work. Toilets and lockers were broken. Books, chairs and teachers were scarce. Two derelict cars stood in the driveway. Weeds had grown waist-high in the tennis courts. A handwritten note taped on a classoom door recalled an extracurricular struggle: `` Do n't push us, turkeys, ` cause you'll never get away with it.'' But Pace has human assets: <PERSON> Wilkinson </PERSON> <PERSON> Kambule </PERSON>, 68, the new principal, and <PERSON> Lekgau </PERSON> <PERSON> Mathabathe </PERSON>, 63, chairman of a new school board composed entirely of <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION> residents. Both were school principals in <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION> in 1976, and from their schools came leaders of student riots against Afrikaans-language instruction imposed by the white-minority government. Both resigned to support the student protest, <PERSON> Kambule </PERSON> becoming a university mathematics teacher, <PERSON> Mathabathe </PERSON> joining a food-processing company. <PERSON> Kambule </PERSON> retains a reputation as an insirational teacher who gets results, and his arrival at Pace in mid-1988 was particularly welcomed by Sowetans. `` Parents have confidence. Children started coming back from private schools in <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Kambule </PERSON> said in an interview. `` I'm budgeting for the full number of 600 students and I've had to send hundreds away.'' Some of Pace's <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> corporate backers have divested and left <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, but those that remain are showing renewed interest. `` We no longer have any say in running the school but we have recommended to our members that they become involved financially again,'' said <PERSON> Adrian </PERSON> <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. `` One company has already appointed a fund raiser for Pace.'' Students are required to pay only half their annual fees of 3,000 rand -LRB- $ 1,250 -RRB- and company donations are expected to make up the balance. <PERSON> Mathabathe </PERSON> said Pace needs 60,000 rands -LRB- $ 25,000 -RRB- a month to stay open, and much more to renovate the building and increase salaries. The school increasingly has encouraged community involvement. Civic groups use the gymnasium, and the auditorium is rented out for church services, wedding receptions and taxi drivers' meetings. But <PERSON> Kambule </PERSON> emphasized that Pace's goal remains the same: to provide a superior education to blacks seeking middle-management business jobs. The first Pace students to take final high school exams under <PERSON> Kambule </PERSON>'s direction numbered only 55 but 31 passed, by far the best percentage of any <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION> school last year. `` I'm interested in children setting out on their own for the future, through education,'' <PERSON> Kambule </PERSON> said. `` I tell them, ` Do n't call me principal, I'm your employee, I'm in your service. But there's lots of discipline.'' He appears to have ended Pace's political isolation from <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION>'s young militants `` People have been asking for alternative education. I explain that this is an alternative school,'' <PERSON> Kambule </PERSON> said. `` Politics in the school are n't over. The revolution is still on. But they should n't treat us like they treat a government school.'' <PERSON> Kambule </PERSON> said he allowed a youth group to use the auditorium last year to celebrate the birthday of the imprisoned black leader <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>. `` They came to me afterward and said, ` We did n't think you'd let us.' I replied, ` Why not? It's your school.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 2348EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-APArts:MexicanCartoonists     02-06 0895</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Mexican Cartoonists,0919</SECOND>
<HEAD>For Mexico's Cartoonists, the President Is Mickey Mouse</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report. ^By CANDICE HUGHES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The president, the military and the Virgin of <LOCATION> Guadalupe </LOCATION> used to be off-limits for Mexican political cartoonists. Now only the generals and the Virgin are taboo. The best of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s cartoonists say what others ca n't _ or wo n't. Their razor-sharp commentaries sparkle on gray pages awash in windy pro-government prose. `` They are in the vanguard of free expression in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Monsivais </PERSON>, one of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s most outspoken, acerbic social analysts. `` They get away with things I never could.'' The political ferment of 1988, a year of unprecedented losses at the polls for the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Institutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, sparked a wave of graphic daring. More than one artist has depicted <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s diminutive, jug-eared, balding new chief executive, <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON>, as a Disneyesque rodent named <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON>. `` They are tough, very tough,'' <PERSON> Monsivais </PERSON> said approvingly, although President <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> seems to be getting a bit more cartoon respect than he did as candidate and president-elect. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, head of the New York-based Cartoonists and <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Syndicate </ORGANIZATION>, agrees that something special is afoot. `` <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> has a fantastically high number of exceptional cartoonists,'' said <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, who syndicates many of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s best. `` They are high-caliber graphic artists. It makes their work very, very effective.'' <PERSON> Rogelio </PERSON> <PERSON> Naranjo </PERSON>'s razor-sharp pen has been on the cutting edge for years. Day by day, stroke by ironic stroke, <PERSON> Naranjo </PERSON> has chiseled away at the pretensions, foibles, hypocrisies and taboos that have buttressed a one-party government for 60 years. He's honed a sixth sense for what he can get away with in his 22 years of political cartooning. `` It's like a mystical thing in my work. I navigate the line that divides what is possible and what is n't,'' he said. When it comes to government policy, now `` there are very few limits.'' Government austerity programs and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s crippling foreign debt provoke some of the bitterest commentary. <PERSON> Naranjo </PERSON> resorted, literally, to gallows humor, depicting a plump man representing the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> picking the pocket of a starved, barefoot and hanged worker. <PERSON> Bulmaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Castellanos </PERSON>, who draws under the monicker Magu, showed <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>, architect of an austerity pact that controlled wages and prices, as a crazed workman armed with a chainsaw standing over a bloody body skewered by the pact. The generals are another story. Both official censorship and self-censorship have a long history in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, where few care to rouse the military and endanger decades of civilian rule. `` The army is the most taboo thing,'' <PERSON> Naranjo </PERSON> said. `` Everyone assumes the army is a great power in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> that can influence the government in a radical and substantial manner.'' As for the Virgin of <LOCATION> Guadalupe </LOCATION>, even <PERSON> Naranjo </PERSON>, who has lampooned the pope, says such a revered symbol can not be used to make a point. A museum exhibit that included irreverent paintings of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s patron saint was shuttered after a public outcry Although most of their satire is directed at the ruling establishment, the cartoonists do take occasional pokes at the opposition. <PERSON> Efren </PERSON> <PERSON> Maldonado </PERSON> showed opposition leader <PERSON> Cuauhtemoc </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> as a giant head supported by a magic carpet in the image of former President <PERSON> Lazaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cuauhtemoc </PERSON>'s father and a national hero. Cartoonists such as <PERSON> Naranjo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Helio </PERSON> <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> began stretching the limits of the possible as founders of the cheeky humor magazine <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Garrapata </ORGANIZATION> in 1968, a year of political upheaval in much of the world, including <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. `` The notion of reverence disappeared,'' <PERSON> Monsivais </PERSON> said. In a show of impatience with the one-party status quo, thousands took to the streets. The unrest lasted only a few months, until the army opened fire on a demonstration in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, killing scores. Not long after the massacre, <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Garrapata </PERSON> co-founder <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> del </PERSON> <PERSON> Rio </PERSON>, who signs himself <PERSON> Rius </PERSON>, was kidnapped by uniformed men and forced to stand next to an empty grave in front of what turned out to be a mock firing squad. Subsequent administrations began slowly opening a safety valve that included tolerance for press freedom. The Mexican chief executive was traditionally above reproach, no matter how unpopular. Even now <PERSON> Maldonado </PERSON>, the first cartoonist to put Dumbo ears on <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>, insists he intends no disrepect. <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> remembers a cartoon of President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Portillo </PERSON>, who left office to almost universal relief in 1982. `` He was drawn as <PERSON> Hamlet </PERSON> _ but very, very handsome, very athletic,'' <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> said. With <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>, cartoonists have gone far beyond making fun of his ears and his austere economics, attacking the very legitimacy of his presidency. His election was marred by accusations of fraud and <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> still claims that he won. The most audacious cartoons appear in El Universal, a mainline newspaper that gave significant space to the opposition in 1988, and in two publications born after 1968: <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jornada </ORGANIZATION>, a liberal daily, and the feisty weekly Proceso. But both <PERSON> Naranjo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Flores </PERSON>, who just won his second Gran Prix from the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Salon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cartoon </ORGANIZATION>, say even El Universal sometimes refuses a cartoon it considers too daring. After the July 6 presidential election, which many say the ruling party rigged, <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> did a sketch portraying <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> as Dr. <PERSON> Caligari </PERSON>, the eerie protagonist of a classic silent horror film. El Universal rejected it without explanation, he said. The cartoon later ran in an opposition paper.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Romania-Mayor     02-06 0168</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Romania-Mayor,0172</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mayor Abruptly Replaced In Troubled Capital</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The mayor of <LOCATION> Bucharest </LOCATION> has been replaced after less than a year in office, the Romanian state news agency said in a terse report that gave no reason for the personnel change. <PERSON> Constantin </PERSON> <PERSON> Radu </PERSON>, who had also headed the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in the capital, `` was given other tasks,'' Agerpres reported Monday without details. <PERSON> Barbu </PERSON> <PERSON> Petrescu </PERSON>, 63, a former deputy premier, was named to replace him in both posts, the news agency said. <PERSON> Radu </PERSON>'s ouster comes at a time of widespread food and energy shortages in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s capital. But the announcement came as a surprise, Western diplomats in <LOCATION> Bucharest </LOCATION> said, since <PERSON> Radu </PERSON> was named mayor in May. <PERSON> Radu </PERSON>, previously deputy premier for construction and investment, apparently oversaw construction in <LOCATION> Bucharest </LOCATION> of a giant party headquarters and apartments for the party elite. About 30 churches or synagogues were destroyed or moved to make way for the project. Hundreds of old private homes were also pulled down.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--France-Drugs     02-06 0148</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--France-Drugs,0150</SECOND>
<HEAD>Record Cocaine Haul Seized On Yacht</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police tipped off by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Italian investigators found 1,038 pounds of cocaine, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s largest seizure of the drug, in a yacht being towed across the country, the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said. Three men were arrested Monday during the search of the 40-foot yacht at <LOCATION> Nevers </LOCATION>, 150 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, and police in <LOCATION> Marseille </LOCATION> arrested four other men, the ministry said. Those arrested were not immediately charged and they were not identified. The yacht arrived in the northwestern port city of <LOCATION> Le </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Havre </LOCATION> last month needing repairs after an <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> crossing, the ministry said in a statement. It was loaded on a trailer to be towed to <LOCATION> Cannes </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION>. The previous record cocaine seizure in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> was 880 pounds in December 1987 on a plane on the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> island of <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Galante </PERSON> near <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 2352EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BushText 8Takes   02-06 0516</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush Text, 8 Takes,0541</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Bush-S&amp;Ls</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a transcript of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s news conference Monday. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: Well, for more than half a century the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> has operated a deposit insurance program that provides direct government protection to the savings of our citizens. This program has enabled tens of millions of Americans to save with confidence. In all the time since creation of the deposit insurance, savers have not lost one dollar of insured deposits, and I am determined that they never will. Deposit insurance has always been intended to be self-funded. And this means that the banks, the savings and loans, and credit unions that are insured pay a small amount of their assets each year into a fund that's used to protect depositors. In every case these funds are spent to protect the depositors, not the institutions that fail. For the last 20 years, conditions in our financial markets have grown steadily more complex, and a portion of the savings and loan industry has encountered steadily growing problems. These financial difficulties have led to a continuous erosion of the strength of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corporation </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> FSLIC </ORGANIZATION>. Economic conditions have played a major role in this situation. However, unconscionable risk-taking, fraud, and outright criminality have also been factors. Because of the accumulation of loses at hundreds of these thrift institutions, additional resources must be devoted to cleaning up this problem. We intend to restore our entire deposit insurance system to complete health. While the issues are complex and the difficulties manifold, we will make the hard choices, not run from them. We will see that the guarantee to depositors is forever honored, and we will see to it that the system is reformed comprehensively so that the situation is not repeated again. To do this, I am today announcing a comprehensive and wide-ranging set of proposals. The secretary of the treasury, <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, will describe these proposals to you in detail in a few minutes. However, I think it's important to summarize some of the major points. The proposals include four major elements. First, currently insolvent savings institutions will be placed under the joint management of the <ORGANIZATION> FDIC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> FSLIC </ORGANIZATION>, pursuant to existing law. This will enable us to control future risk-taking and to begin reducing ongoing losses. Second, the regulatory mechanism will be substantially overhauled to enable it to more effectively limit risk-taking. The <ORGANIZATION> FDIC </ORGANIZATION> would become the insurance agency for both banks and thrifts under this system, although there's no comingling of funds. The insurer will have the authority to set minimum standards for capital and accounting. Uniform disclosure standards will also be implemented. The chartering agency for thrifts would come under the general oversight of the secretary of the treasury. Third, we will create a financing corporation to issue $ 50 billion in bonds to finance the cost of resolving failed institutions which will supplement approximately $ 40 billion that has already been spent. All of the principal of these bonds and a portion of the interest on them will be paid from industry sources.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 2353EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BushText-1stadd     02-06 0626</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush Text - 1st add,0651</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: industry sources.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 However, the balance would be paid from on-budget outlays of general revenues. Hopefully, some of these revenues will be recovered in the future through sale of assets and recovery of funds from the wrongdoers. Fourth, we plan to increase the budget of the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> by approximately $ 50 million to enable it to create a nationwide program to seek out and punish those that have committed wrongdoing in the management of these failed institutions. These funds will result in almost doubling the personnel devoted to the apprehension and prosecution of individuals committing fraud in our financial markets. As you can see, these proposals are based upon several overriding principles. First, I will not support any new fee on depositors. Second, we should preserve the overall federal budget structure and not allow the misdeeds and the wrongdoings of savings and loan executives and the inadequacy of their regulation to significantly alter our overall budget priorities. And third, I have concluded that this proposal, if promptly enacted, will enable our system to prevent any repetition of this situation. And fourth, I've decided to attack this problem head-on, with every available resource of our government, because it is a national problem. I've directed that the combined resources of our federal agencies be brought together in a team effort to resolve the problem. And fifth, I believe that banks and thrifts should pay the real cost of providing the deposit insurance protection. The price the <ORGANIZATION> FDIC </ORGANIZATION> charges banks for their insurance has not been increased since 1935. We propose to increase the bank insurance premium by less than 7 cents per $ 100 of insurance protection that they receive. Every penny collected would be used to strengthen the <ORGANIZATION> FDIC </ORGANIZATION> so that the taxpayers will not be called on to rescue it a few years from now. And I make you a solemn pledge that we will make every effort to recover assets diverted from these institutions and to place behind bars those who have caused losses through criminal behavior. Let those who would take advantage of the public trust and put at risk the savings of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> families anticipate that we will seek them out, pursue them, and demand the most severe penalty. In closing, I want to just say a word to the small savers of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. Across this great land, families and individuals work and save, and we hope to encourage even greater rates of savings to promote a brighter future for our children. Your government has stood behind the safety of insured deposits before. It does today, and it will do so at all times in the future. Every insured deposit will be backed by the full faith and credit of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, which means it will be _ that it will be absolutely protected. For the future, we will seek to achieve a safe, sound and profitable banking system. However, integrity and prudence must share an equal position with competition in our financial markets. Clean markets are an absolute prerequisite to a free economy and to the public confidence that is its most important ingredient. I've determined to face this problem squarely and to ask for your support in putting it behind us. I have ordered that the resources of the executive branch be brought to bear on cleaning up this problem. I have personally met with the leadership of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on this issue. My administration will work cooperatively with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> as the legislation that we will submit in a few days' time is considered. I call on the Congress to join me in a determined effort to resolve this threat to the American financial system permanently, and to do so without delay.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 2354EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BushText-2ndadd     02-06 0571</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush Text - 2nd add,0593</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: without delay.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 I welcome the leaders that are with me here on this platform. I think their support says a lot about the efficacy of our proposal. And now I propose to take just a few questions. On the technical aspects, I will defer to these people and then I'll be glad to turn this over to Secretary <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>. I believe we start with <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> and then <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> and then get going. Q. Mr. <PERSON> Pesident </PERSON>, are you guaranteeing that the extra costs, premium increases and so forth, will not be passed on to the depositors, taxpayers? And also, what is your responsibility in this debacle? I mean the Reagan-Bush deal for deregulation of business and banking? A. On the first place, we're not guaranteeing that. I would hope that would n't happen, but there's no guarantee what the institutions will do. Secondly, there's enough to be said for everybody in this together trying to solve this problem. So I ca n't equate any personal _ I'm not inclined to go into any personal blame, simply to say that we've got to solve this problem and we're on the path to doing that. Yeah, <PERSON> Terry </PERSON>. Q. Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> votes tomorrow on that controversial pay raise plan. And the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has already voted against it. Would you sign a bill that vetoes the pay raise, not only for the members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, but also for federal judges and other high officials in the government? A. I said I support it. Yes? Q. Mr. President, there is a feeling that part of this problem is attributable to deregulation of the financial industry. In retrospect, do you think that deregulation might have gone too far in the last 10 years or so? And, in the future, is your marching order to your administration to be a little more careful in regulating this particular industry? <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON>, I do n't know the answer. I'd be most interested to know what our experts here feel about whether _ how much of the problem could be attributed to deregulation. I just do n't know the answer to your question. So, I ca n't reply. Yes? Q. Mr. President, you have placed considerable stress in these early days of your presidency on ethics and propriety, yet in recent days there's this controversy on Capitol Hill concerning the propriety of Senator Tower's alleged behavior, and questions raised over the weekend about the financial arrangements on the private funds of the man in charge of ethis, your counsel <PERSON> Boyden </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, and other questions involving members of the administration, or members-to-be of the administration. And I wonder sir, what's happened here Is it too harsh behavior on our part, too lax behavior on your part? What? A. I do n't think anything has happened. I learned long ago in public life not to make judgments based on allegations. But having said that, I want to have my administration aspire to the highest possible ethical standards. And we have appointed a commission to go out there now and try to detail what these standards should be. And we are in a new era on these matters; matters that might have been approved and looked at one way may have a different perception today. And, so, what I want to do is finalize our standards and then urge everybody in all branches of government to aspire to those standards.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 2357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BushText-3rdadd     02-06 0699</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush Text - 3rd add,0730</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: those standards.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 But I do think, <PERSON> Rick </PERSON>, that it's fair that we not reach judgment on <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> hearings before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> hearings are concluded, because it's very hard to filter out fact from fiction, spurious allegation from fact. And I am not about to make a judgment based on a sensationalized newspaper story. I'm simply not going to do that. That would n't be fair, and I'm not sure how ethical it would be. So let's wait and see. This _ you're referring to the Tower matter up there. That matter has been looked at by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>. The committee now has that. They have the responsibility to make determination. And I'll be very interested to see what they say. But I am not going to make conclusions _ jump to conclusions based on stories that may or may not have any validity at all. Yes? Q. Mr. President, even if, as your spokesman says you do, you continue to back Senator Tower for the position, there are those, you've heard, who say that the best thing he could do for you is to step aside, because even if confirmed, he then would become `` damaged goods,'' weaker in administering, a very, very tough job on your behalf. How do you respond to that suggestion? A. Well, I think people would not want a person to step aside, given rumor, particularly if the rumor is baseless. And the process _ what _ the problem is the process is taking a little longer than I would like, and yet, I think the Senate has got to do what they're doing _ looking at these allegations very carefully. But, you know, as I said here at this same podium a while back, the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people are basically fair. And, if these allegations prove to be allegations without fact behind them, I think the people are going to say, `` Wait a minute. What went on here? How come it was all this _ we'd read this one day, and then kind of a puff of smoke the next?'' And, so, I do n't think, in your substantive question though, that if it proves _ if the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committee gives its endorsement to the senator, particularly after all of these allegations, that there is any danger at all of damage to his credibility or his ability to do the job. Yes? Q. Mr. President, there are new and substantive allegations that Senator Tower lost control over the highly classified security documents and computer disks that were used in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> under his watch. If those allegations prove to be founded, would you then withdraw his nomination? A. I would not answer hypothetical questions of that nature. You're telling me something that I have n't heard before. And, we did have access to <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> reports. So, if this matter is now before the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, let them investigate it. But, I ca n't go into a hypothesis. All I would be doing would be adding to, I think, speculation that is not helpful at this juncture. Q. But, sir, will you pursue these allegations in the executive branch? Are you going to track what the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> is looking into? Are you going to personally surveil these kinds of allegations yourself? A. Every rumor and every innuendo? No. But, if you make _ if there's some substantive allegation of this nature, of course it would concern me. Yes? Q. Mr. President, back to S & amp; Ls, if we might. Millions _ -LRB- laughter -RRB- _ millions of Americans save alternatively. That is, they put their funds in mutual funds, stocks, and that kind of thing. As I read it, you've now outlined a plan that places a lot of the S & amp; L bailout on the backs of the general treasury. How fair is that? A. We've got a major problem and something has to be done. And this is the fairest system that the best minds in this administration can come up with. And, so, I'd _ I, again, would ask you to ask the specifics of the treasury burden to the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> or the secretary of the treasury. Ask how they see that.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 2358EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BushText-4thadd     02-06 0563</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush Text - 4th add,0582</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: see that.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 But, look, as I've said, there is no easy answer to this. All I want to do is make a sound proposal, work to put it into effect, and have that proposal such that the country wo n't have to face this problem again. Yes, <PERSON> Dave </PERSON>? Q. Mr. President, you said you dropped the deposit fee idea. But this plan you've given us has an increase in premimums that may be paid by consumers as well as a large amount of taxpayer's money. Is n't that the same thing _ consumers and taxpayers are still going to have to pay the price for this? A. Well, as I indicated earlier on, there is no guarantee of passing this on to the consumer, nor is there a guarantee it wo n't be passed on But this arrangement has been there since _ for 50 years. And you might argue whether it's been passed on or not, I just do n't know; I have n't seen the flow-through in the industry. But nothing is without pain when you come to solve a problem of this magnitude. Yes? Q. Mr. President, you've talked to several members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in various receptions and dinners and personal conversations over the past couple of weeks, in many of them you discussed your plan for this problem. What is your feeling for the reception that it's going to get on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> and of the selling job that it will make you have to get it passed? A. We may have a big selling job. But I've been encouraged so far with the spirit epitomized by the members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, particularly at the joint leadership meeting the other day. We did n't go into every detail of this; these plans were still being formulated and I wanted to get their views. I was encouraged by what <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Seidman </PERSON> told me earlier on about how he _ what he felt the receptivity of the plan will be. But I do n't think it's fair to the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to say that they have signaled to me that they are going to be enthusiastic on this plan, although I hope they are. Yes? Q. Mr. President _ A. I'm going to take about three more, and then turn this over to these gentlemen here who are prepared to go into as much detail as you want. Yes? Q. Mr. President, on these allegations that surround Tower now, at least variations on the theme surfaced early in the transition _ allegations of womanizing and taking money from defense contractors, that sort of thing. Have you satisfied yourself that he is still the nominee you want? And can you give us, at this time, a wholehearted endorsement of Tower? A. Yes, I can, and I will right now, because some of the very same allegations that were floated that long ago apparently have been looked at and examined by the best possible examiners _ I'm talking about the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> _ and found to be groundless So, therefore, I'm not about to change my view. Now if somebody comes up with facts, I hope I'm not narrow-minded enough that I would n't take a look, but I am not going to deal in the kinds of rumors that I've seen reported and then knocked down, and then reported and then knocked down. Yes?
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BarbaraBush Bjt   02-06 0780</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Barbara Bush, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Barbara Bush's View of the White House</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two weeks after moving into the most prestigious home in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> can not conceal her excitement. For starters, there's the collection of presidential china: `` <PERSON> Grover </PERSON> <PERSON> Cleveland </PERSON> at lunch today ... <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> yesterday. Can you believe that?'' There's more. `` The views are pretty spectacular,'' she says, noting she can gaze directly at the Oval Office from her second-floor office in the White House. `` See, I can see him right there,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says, pointing across the Rose Garden to the office occupied by her husband, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. In the <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> <PERSON> Bedroom </PERSON>, Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> shows off a felt-covered frame that contains one of only five copies of the <LOCATION> Gettysburg </LOCATION> Address. `` This is the only one signed and dated. You can read that. ... Is n't that amazing? `` The Library of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> man who was up here one day _ I showed it to him and he looked absolutely green.'' A canopy bed on the second-floor `` was where the four presidents before <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> slept,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says as she leads a visitor on a tour of the presidential residence. `` Pretty grand, huh?'' In an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said she `` felt right at home from the very first moment.'' Her husband, she said, is `` exactly the same'' and has not changed since moving up from vice president under <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. However, she said everyone else has changed and `` everybody treats you differently when you're president.'' `` When you're vice president and certainly vice president's wife, you get away with many more things than you do when you're president,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said `` Everything you say becomes major and it is major. He is the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' She said her husband has an `` enormous job. ... Has he philosophized about it? No. But he's absolutely determined to do the best he can. `` I see my job as trying to take some of that pressure off him,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` I see that as my job ... to try to not talk about those problems and also _ do not talk when he's working. I mean, I think that's a big part of it,'' she said. `` Because he knows with me, I hope, that he can curl up with his problems and study them and he's not going to have me badgering him about something else. `` I really do not lobby <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>,'' his wife said. `` I do n't lobby anyone. A lot of people try to skirt regular channels and send letters intended for the president to Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in hopes she'll pass it on. `` I just do n't give them to him,'' she said. Despite the intense demands of his office, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> does not seem weighed down by the job, his wife said. `` I should tell you ` yes' but no _ he sleeps like a baby,'' she said. `` Because he knows he's human. I mean, he's been around the presidency so long that I think he really feels he can do the best job that can be done.'' She said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> awakens every morning about 6 a.m. and has coffee and juice in bed while reading morning newspapers _ about five in all _ and scanning the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> news summary. He also watches morning television shows before leaving for the Oval Office about 7 a.m. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the president returns to the residence between 6 p.m. and 6:30 p.m. `` It's so much earlier -LRB- than when he was vice president -RRB- because he does n't have that drive home. I mean, it's wonderful,'' the first lady said Describing a typical evening at home, she said, `` We'd sit in our little room, private room, watch the television, have dinner. Then he'd go to his office and I'd go to mine, probably.'' Most nights, she said, they use the <LOCATION> china </LOCATION> service from <PERSON> Woodrow </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>'s presidency but `` we can do anything we want. Is n't that fun?'' She said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as president is working `` exactly the same'' routine he followed as vice president. `` I mean, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was born, I think, on this schedule.'' Does he bring work home? `` Yes, he always has,'' his wife said. `` He does a lot of reading. And he does an awful lot of personal writing. He brings home mail, works on it. He gets his little briefcase sent up ahead, full of work.'' Typically, they go to bed between 10 p.m. and 11 p.m., Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. She said she walked their dog, <PERSON> Millie </PERSON>, at 10 p.m. on a recent night. The president, suffering from what Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said was the flu, `` was asleep at that moment.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CivilRights     02-06 0779</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Civil Rights,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Broader Civil Rights Agenda with Reagan Gone</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Affordable housing, the minimum wage and other issues not tied directly to fighting racial bias are moving onto the shopping list of civil rights forces as they gear up for the post-Reagan era on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. `` The traditional notion of what a civil rights bill is is sort of going through a change,'' says <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Grady </PERSON>, a labor official and legislative chairwoman of the <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION>. Issues that civil rights advocates group under the heading of economic justice, often dealing with labor and welfare, are prominent on the list. Civil rights for the disabled, legal services for the poor and mandatory leave from work for parents of newborns and sick children are all priorities for the <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>, an umbrella group that takes in virtually the entire civil rights community. The new emphasis represents not so much a change in direction as a return to issues that were largely ignored while civil rights forces skirmished with the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration throughout much of the 1980s. Not all of the new priorities are economic. For example, civil rights advocates continue to press for easier voter registration and they are preparing to fight English-only legislation that would bar bilingual education programs for Hispanics. `` It is an aggressive and ambitious agenda,'' says <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Neas </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>. `` But we are confident that the 101st <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will pass it. We hope that the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration will play a constructive role.'' As usual, civil rights advocates are watching carefully to see if President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will name federal judges inclined toward moderate positions or hard-line conservatives who might challenge the legal changes of the past three decades. Judicial nominations are always a chief concern of civil rights groups. They count the defeat of outspoken conservative <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> for the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> as one of their most important victories of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> era. But the showdown over <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> represented only one in a series of Capitol Hill victories for civil rights forces over the last eight years. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> prevented the right wing from passing any major items on its legislative agenda and, furthermore, the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> years passed many important civil rights initiatives,'' says <PERSON> Neas </PERSON>. The conference points with pride to the success of last year's bill to toughen fair housing enforcement, recent victories on <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> sanctions legislation and the <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> holiday, plus the congressional override of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s veto of the Civil Rights Restoration Act That legislation came in response to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Grove </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> decision, in which the justices held that the government could not deny federal aid to one program merely because of discrimination in an unrelated program operated by the same institution. In fact, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has passed so many measures urged by civil rights advocates that they now say some of the most pressing needs lie outside the legislative arena. That is especially so with the departure of <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> as attorney general and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>, the longtime head of the civil rights division in the <ORGANIZATION> Reagan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. A recent report from the <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION>, a 17-member panel of former federal officials, was sharply critical of the department's enforcement record in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> era. It said, for example, that the <ORGANIZATION> Reagan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> filed about 10 housing bias cases annually, half the number under the <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> administrations. `` I think the question of enforcement of civil rights laws will be stronger, because I think that with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> gone, there will be no great voice of weakening,'' says <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hooks </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Colored People and chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>. There may be some reluctance to move forward with civil rights legislation until President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> indicates what he might accept. `` I think that's just a sensible thing to do,'' says Rep. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, D-Calif., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s civil rights and civil liberties subcommittee Meanwhile, he envisions hearings in the year ahead to determine just how well the existing civil rights laws are being enforced. Additional sessions of his panel will take up the long-festering question of whether college entrance examinations are skewed toward whites and thus place minority students at an unfair disadvantage. The Equal Rights Amendment to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Constitution, which would ban discrimination on the basis of gender, remains a cause dear to women's groups and many civil rights advocates. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> says, however, that the measure will not be brought to the floor unless there is enough support to pass it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 2359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Gray-Ethics 2ndLd-Writethru a0696 02-06 0984</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gray-Ethics, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0696,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: To update with Times report, Adds 3 new grafs after 13th graf
previous, ``Spurred by''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> defended the ethical conduct of high-ranking officials in his administration Monday but said he might have to tighten standards and make `` our people bend over backwards'' so they avoid even the appearance of conflict of interest. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s statement came as <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyden </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, his longtime counsel and chief ethics adviser, reversed an earlier decision and resigned as chairman of a multimillion-dollar communications company. Last week, Dr. <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, the president's nominee as secretary of health and human services, asked if he could take a paid sabbatical leave from the <ORGANIZATION> Morehouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> while serving in the Cabinet. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said later he would forfeit his accumulated sabbatical pay, estimated at $ 300,000. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said both officials had acted properly and gone beyond what was actually required. The president also defended former Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, his nominee to be secretary of defense, against new allegations of womanizing and drinking, as well as other matters. Asked if would still endorse Tower, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` Yes, I can and I will right now.'' He said some of the allegations about Tower have been examined by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and found to be groundless. However, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` If somebody comes up with facts, I hope I'm not narrow-minded enough that I would n't take another look.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said all of <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>'s actions had been reviewed and approved by the Office of Government Ethics as he served for eight years as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s counsel during his vice presidency. However, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` We are in a new era on these matters. Matters that might have been approved and looked at one way, may have a different perception today. ... So, I think it might be different now. I have to approach it differently as president.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said that when it comes to the appearance of conflict of interest, `` I'd like our people to bend over backwards ... as far as we possibly can.'' On the other hand, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he did n't want to go overboard. `` I do n't want to have the standards set in such an irresponsible way that good people just throw up their hands and say, ` Look, who needs that kind f grief, who needs it, why should I have to give up all my whatever it is _ a health plan from <ORGANIZATION> XYZ </ORGANIZATION> company?' `` And yet,'' he added, `` we're in a different time now. We're in a time when we've got to set these standards as high as possible.'' Spurred by publicity about his finances, <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> announced he was stepping down as chairman of the family-owned <ORGANIZATION> Summit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, and putting his personal assets _ estimated at $ 10 million _ into a blind trust. The Office of Government Ethics is investigating whether <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> should have reported $ 89,000 in income from the company in 1985 and 1986, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported in Tuesday's editions. A reporter for the newspaper had raised the issue Monday, and the office said later in the day that it was investigating, the Times said. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> did not return a telephone call from the reporter seeking comment on why the money was not reported, the Times said. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> deferred receiving the income, his financial adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheets </PERSON> told the Times. But deferred income had to be reported in the year it is earned, said <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, deputy director of the ethics office, according to the newspaper. Earlier, <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> had said he would remain as head of the firm but would refuse a salary, complying with rules announced by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> last July during the presidential campaign. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> changed his mind and decided to resign after consulting with the leaders of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s new ethics commission and seeing his financial background become front-page news. `` He has done nothing wrong,'' said White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. `` There's been no conflict of interest. He has not profited or benefited in any way from his government service but the issue has been raised now in the press and so he simply wanted to take care of it.'' <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> is the latest <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> appointee to find himself in the spotlight after questions about his ethical or personal conduct. Allegations about drinking and womanizing by Tower resulted in a delay on a confirmation vote by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> sought a ruling on whether he could accept $ 300,000 in sabbatical pay earned as head of the <ORGANIZATION> Morehouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> while taking a leave to serve in the Cabinet. Saying he wanted to avoid even the appearance of any conflict of interest, <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said he would forfeit the sabbatical pay. Rejecting the notion the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration was having problems with ethics, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, `` It's the president's spotlight of focus on this matter that's caused everyone to be so ultrasensitive about every little thing. And so be it.'' Talking about <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, `` There was no real problem in either case but to avoid the appearance of conflict and to get on with the business, they said, ` Fine, do it.''' He said <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>'s decision was prompted in part by stories in <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> which noted that the <ORGANIZATION> Reagan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> had a policy banning employees from serving in board chairmanships and from earning outside income. `` Rather than try to let that fester, you simply deal with it and go on,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. Although <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> worked in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, he was not bound by those rules because he was employed by then-Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, whose policy was more lenient. Over the past eight years, <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> was paid hundreds of thousands of dollars for serving as chairman of the company that owns more at least a dozen radio stations and has about 130,000 cable television subscribers in the South.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Cambodia-MIAs     02-06 0708</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cambodia-MIAs,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Diplomatic Stalemate Dims Hopes For Getting MIA Remains From Cambodia</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A year ago, the hopes of families of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> servicemen shot down over <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> during the Vietnam War were buoyed by <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION>'s declaration that it was prepared to hand over the remains of 83 airmen to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> officials. But a diplomatic stalemate, which some congressmen blame largely on <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> inaction, has prevented the return of the bodies and dimmed hopes for a return any time soon. `` They've made these gestures in the last year to turn remains over and so far the good faith has n't been followed up on,'' said Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Conn </LOCATION>. `` There's -LRB- the remains of -RRB- 80 American soldiers over there ... and we're tripping over bureaucracy. During a January 1988 trip to <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, Reps. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> McCloskey </PERSON>, D-Ind., and <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON> were told by <PERSON> Tep </PERSON> <PERSON> Henn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>'s ambassador to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, that the Cambodian government had the bodies of the American servicemen and would return them to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials The condition: the administration would have to make the request directly. The lawmakers lobbied the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and enlisted the help of senior legislators, including the late Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>, D-Ala., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> investigations subcommittee But the administration agreed only to send a message through a third party, the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> does not recognize the Cambodian regime of Premier <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON>, installed by <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> after <PERSON> Pol </PERSON> <PERSON> Pot </PERSON> and his brutal <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> regime were driven from power by Vietnamese forces in late 1978. `` We do not have diplomatic relations -LRB- with <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> -RRB- and we do n't recognize it, so any diplomatic approach would be inappropriate,'' said <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Almasov </PERSON>, an east Asian specialist at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The congressional critics point to diplomatic contact with <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> over soldiers missing-in-action there. `` We do n't recognize <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> but we're constantly interacting with them,'' <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON> said. `` Half the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has been over there'' as well as special <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> emissaries. `` We've picked up remains from <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> and they're not exactly our friends either,'' he said. `` We allowed them to get some political mileage.'' While <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> is essentially a satellite of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, diplomatic contact with <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> is a more delicate matter than dealing with <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION>, which is largely accepted despite the lack of diplomatic ties. In <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, three rebel groups including the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> headed by <PERSON> Pol </PERSON> <PERSON> Pot </PERSON> and two others supported by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid have been fighting to overthrow the Vietnam-installed government. With <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s pledge to withdraw its troops from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON> is desperately seeking legitimacy for his government. Earlier this year he visited <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> for the first time for negotiations with Thai leaders to seek a resolution to the 10-year conflict. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials fear that the <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> government would simply use <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> contact over the MIA issue as a political tool. `` Obviously what the <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> regime wants from us is some sort of diplomatic approach that would confer some sort of legitimacy on them,'' <PERSON> Almasov </PERSON> said. `` Since we feel the MIA issue is a humanitarian one and since we have made it clear that we are prepared at any time to receive the remains they say they have, we feel they should respond positively.'' The <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> congressmen say they are well aware of <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON>'s political motivations, but they believe that direct contact over the remains alone would not seriously affect American foreign policy in <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> `` I have no desire to build him up and give him credibility ... but my God, we have to be willing to at least talk to the people,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. He added that <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials `` think it will shake our credibility in the region and insult <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>. I do n't.'' The congressmen believe <PERSON> Phnom </PERSON> <PERSON> Penh </PERSON> is genuinely willing to turn over the remains. `` They have clearly seen the positive exposure <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> has gotten by turning remains over. I think they would like to duplicate that,'' <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON> recently reiterated his willingness to discuss the MIA issue with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials. But <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON> predicted that <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> leaders would hold out for direct <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> contact so they can `` get more bang for their effort.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 0137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Mideast     02-06 0511</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Mideast,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mideast Leaders Want to Meet with Bush</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will meet in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> later this month with King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Egyptian </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>, and then at the White House in the spring with them and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, according to <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials. The <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> talks will be held when <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the two Arab leaders attend the funeral of Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. Details of the separate visits to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> by <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> will be worked out over the next few weeks, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials speaking on condition of anonymity said Sunday. The main topics are the future of restive Palestinians on the Israeli-held <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>, and the role the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will try to play in settling the 40-year-old <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> conflict. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s funeral, which will draw scores of world leaders to <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, is accelerating <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s introduction to murky <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> diplomacy. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy is now under review by the new administration, but Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> said at his confirmation hearing last month that he is opposed to the establishment of an independent Palestinian state. <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> all notified the new administration separately that they would like to visit <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in the spring, which could drive <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to an early decision on how to approach the Palestinian problem and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s troubles with its Arab neighbors. After a slow start, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration tried to steer <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> toward a peace settlement, but that was undercut by <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>. The administration then tried to set up <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> negotiations, but despite four trips to the region by former Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, the effort failed. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> both rejected <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> proposals for peace talks while <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, kept Palestinians from meeting with <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>. In one of its final acts, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration broke a 13-year freeze and opened talks with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, but there are no indications this has improved prospects for a settlement or an easing of violence in the Israeli-held territories. <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> would make separate visits to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials said they all asked to be received in the spring and timetables were being worked out. Administration officials on Jan. 28 opened informal talks with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on possible arms sales to <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. There were no items on the list for <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, which <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> since 1985 has excluded until the kingdom shows willingness to negotiate with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, to whom it lost the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> in the 1967 <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> war. Jordanian Prime Minister <PERSON> Zaid </PERSON> <PERSON> Rifai </PERSON> was asked in an interview published Sunday in the Kuwaiti newspaper Al-Watan whether he thought the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would offer a new <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace initiative. `` We're fed up with initiatives,'' <PERSON> Rifai </PERSON> said. `` The basis for a settlement and the solutions are there, and agreed upon internationally, with the exception of the Israeli stance. And regrettably they -LRB- <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> -RRB- are supported by the American stance.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 0149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-BrownProfile     02-06 1086</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Brown Profile,1080</SECOND>
<HEAD>Incoming Democratic Chairman Once Lobbied to Oust Predecessor</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Note language in 4th graf</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> was chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> when he first got to know <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON>. `` They were around the office all the time, mostly with a press release demanding my resignation.'' White, a sandy-haired Texan, was <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s handpicked choice to head the party. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> were aides to Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> who was opposing the incumbent president's bid for renomination. This was down and dirty, no-holds-barred politics. `` I'll whip his ass,'' the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had said of the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> senator who bore one of the most famous names in American politics. But White was an old pro and <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> were budding young pros. `` Hell, they were so nice about it, I just got so I would invite them in for a cup of coffee,'' recalled White. `` We just got to where we liked each other. I knew what they were doing and they knew what I was doing.'' Six years later, <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> became <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chairman and on Friday the 47-year-old <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> will succeed him in that post. That transition will take place when the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> meets at a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> hotel a few miles from the <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> House </LOCATION>, a building where only one Democrat has resided during the past 20 years. When <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> began his quest for the chairmanship his opponents portrayed him as `` <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON>'s man,'' a reference to his role in <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s presidential campaign. And if not <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON>'s man, then `` Teddy's man,'' a reference to his earlier involvement with <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. `` Ultra liberal,'' was the assessment of the <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> party chairman. The wrong symbol, said many party officials, at a time when the electorate seemed more comfortable with conservative views. Yet, none of that criticism stuck and one by one <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s four opponents in the chairmanship race dropped out and endorsed him. In part, he succeeded because the only label that has stuck firmly on <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> is `` <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> insider.'' `` He's nobody's man but his own,'' said <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> could say no to me or to <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> or to anyone else if he believed that whatever was requested was n't in the interests of the party.'' From his childhood, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> has bridged two very different worlds. He grew up in <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION>, but his parents sent him to predominantly white private schools on the Upper East Side of <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>. He attended <ORGANIZATION> Middlebury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> where he was one of only a handful of black students. When he joined <ORGANIZATION> Sigma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Phi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Epsilon </ORGANIZATION> fraternity, the house was stripped of its national membership for violating the whites-only charter. At <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, one of his professors was <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> ran the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> office of the <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> before joining <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s staff and becoming a senior aide on his presidential campaign. Later, he became general counsel of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> which <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> chaired. Big-time, big-money law beckoned and <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> now is a partner in one of the capital's biggest, most politically active firms. That was the period he also became deputy chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. Once again, he was seen as `` Teddy's man'' at the <ORGANIZATION> DNC </ORGANIZATION>, the party official who would look after the senator's interests in advance of the 1984 presidential campaign <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Campion </PERSON> was at the <ORGANIZATION> DNC </ORGANIZATION> as <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>'s man. <PERSON> Campion </PERSON> recalled that instead of becoming rivals they became friends _ an outcome typical of <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s career. His law practice prospered with clients that included the Japanese electronics industry and the government of <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>. So did his establishment credentials. He is a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Middlebury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trustees </ORGANIZATION> and chairman of the advisory committee for the <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>. During a visit to <ORGANIZATION> Middlebury </ORGANIZATION> last fall, a student asked <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> for advice on pursuing a political career. His response offered an insight to his careful operating style: `` Keep a diary. Write down the names of people you meet and then keep track of them. Remember them when you meet them again. Connections are important.'' A little ironic coming from a man whose connections were used against him in his most prominent effort to strike out on his own in politics. When <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> did n't run in 1984, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> stayed on the sidelines. That was the campaign in which <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> emerged as a force in <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> politics. Four years later, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was rebuffed when he tried to get <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> to head his 1988 presidential campaign. As the campaign approached the end of the primary season, the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> forces began looking ahead to the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> that would take place in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> in July. It was clear that <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> would be the presidential nominee, but <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and his followers had a full agenda. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hightower </PERSON>, the populist agriculture commissioner from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, was the choice of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> aides to head their convention operation. But then <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, a top adviser to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, suggested <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> knew the players and knew the territory; <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> did n't,'' said <PERSON> White </PERSON>, who also was advising <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. To the relief of most Democrats, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> agreed to take on the job. `` There was a rather tense atmosphere going into the convention,'' recalled <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON>, chairman of the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign. `` The Reverend <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> had started a bus caravan in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> which picked up speed and people on the way to the convention _ this was after several weeks where Reverend <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was hitting <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> pretty hard, building an expectation that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> deserved more than he had received. `` None of that created an environment which assured any kind of unity,'' <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> and <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> met privately on the Saturday before the convention and the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> aide showed up with a list of his concerns. By the time their meeting ended, <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> said, `` I understood where he was coming from and I was able to respond to most of them and give an indication where I was coming from.'' There would be more meetings including one that included <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. The result was a convention that ended on a note of harmony. During his visit to <LOCATION> Middlebury </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> candidacy showed that `` the issue of race has become less of a factor in American politics.'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s accession to the chairmanship of his party may confirm that assessment _ or may offer new evidence of how strong a factor race continues to be.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 0156EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bennett     02-06 0481</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bennett,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drug Czar Assesses the Problem in Detroit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Drug czar-designate <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> took a close look at `` the heart of the problem'' with a two-hour tour of <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, a visit that `` underlined the urgency of working fast to make things better.'' `` We have a deadly serious issue on our hands,'' he said Sunday in a telephone interview from the Detroit airport. `` It's compelling This was fact-finding for me, very preliminary, to find out what people on the ground are facing. `` They emphasized what I was looking at was the heart of the problem,'' he said. `` Downtown <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> is as bad as it gets anywhere.'' Last year, <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> recorded 629 homicides, an 8.3 percent drop from the 686 homicides in 1987, according to city police statistics. The city figures did not indicate how many of them were drug-related. An analysis of <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> crime statistics by the <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> showed <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> was the only city last year with a higher ratio of murders per 100,000 people. The visit did n't result in any specific plans for how the war against drugs should be waged or how he should handle his new job, said <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, who has been nominated by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to become director of national drug control policy. `` I've got to work all parts of it,'' he said. `` What I saw today only underlined the urgency of working fast to make things better. It must get better.'' <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> Police Cmdr. <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilliam </PERSON> told him, `` One index showing we are winning the battle will be when the price goes up and purity goes down, but prices are down and purity is up,'' <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> recalled. Whether drug trafficking was going on during the tour was a matter of opinion. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said he did n't see any. But the officers accompanying him _ <PERSON> Gilliam </PERSON>, who is chief of staff to <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, and Sgt. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> _ said they did. `` My eyes are n't sufficiently expert, discerning yet'' to spot the drug deals, he said. `` It was also Sunday afternoon, not Saturday night.'' <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> deferred questions on what the drug budget should be, saying that six months after he is confirmed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> _ hearings begin March 1 _ he will have completed a national drug strategy and `` that will have budget implications.'' He said he plans additional fact-finding tours, but he refused to disclose which cities he might visit. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> went to <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> because of a speaking engagement at <ORGANIZATION> Cranbrook </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, a private school in the wealthy suburb of <LOCATION> Bloomfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich </LOCATION>. The talk had been scheduled before <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> nominated him to the drug czar post. `` I told them when I got to the podium that I've just been in downtown <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> and now I'm in one of the loveliest places in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. I feel like I'm getting the bends.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 0203EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Korea-PettyOffenses     02-06 0194</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Korea-Petty Offenses,0198</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cutting, Shoving in Bus Lines Added to Petty Offenses List</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cutting into line at a bus stop or into a ticket line at a subway or train station is now punishable by fine in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. So is displaying `` visibly unpleasant living things'' such as snakes or worms for sale on the street. The formerly simply discourteous, or distasteful, practices are on a new list of petty offenses _ with transgressors subject to an official warning and a $ 5.75 fine. The new list was released last weekend by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> and its additions are expected to become law. Other new offenses include luring customers to buy `` supernatural potions'' by claiming they can cure and prevent illness. Also new to the list of 21 petty offenses is disobeying officials in times of emergency, such as a snowstorm, fire or traffic accident, and neglecting one's duty for public safety, such as making sure street lamps are turned on. Turning off lights at public gatherings and failing to repair a house that is dangerous to passersby, or a structure that may fall over, will draw also fines.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     02-06 0486</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0503</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MEDINA, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's a mail carrier's nightmare, a magazine lover's delight. Someone is ordering magazine subscriptions by the dozens for five city officials in this increasingly literate northern <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> town. `` It's pretty entertaining,'' said city Service Director <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramer </PERSON>, who has received 70 subscriptions from the anonymous donor. `` There is always something to read. ... There are a lot of magazines that I never knew existed.'' Although some of the magazines have been obscure, most are fairly well-known. They include Time, Popular Photography, Working Woman, People, Sassy, Men's Health, Life, Consumer Reports, and Ladies' Home Journal `` If the magazines had been weird magazines, I would have been more concerned, but they were n't,'' said Mayor <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamb </PERSON>, who's received about a dozen subscriptions The officials have asked the magazines' publishers to cancel the subscriptions, and in most cases the companies have complied. Some magazines have arrived with cards telling the new and surprised reader that the subscription is a gift. For example, <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Wilda </PERSON> <PERSON> Bell </PERSON> got a card saying Lamb had given her a subscription. `` It's a nuisance,'' said <PERSON> Lamb </PERSON>, who later was billed for the subscription. `` People keep coming up to me and thanking me for sending them a magazine, and I have to tell them that I did n't send it. ... I like <PERSON> Wilda </PERSON>, but not $ 109 worth.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ALLENTOWN, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As gingerbread men go, the one at <PERSON> Kinsley </PERSON>'s Market in nearby <LOCATION> Brodheadsville </LOCATION> is very big But at 12 feet tall, it's not big enough for the <ORGANIZATION> Guinness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Book </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION>. And if it were big enough, it still would n't make the book because <ORGANIZATION> Guinness </ORGANIZATION> does n't have a category for gingerbread men. `` It's disappointing to us,'' said <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lockwitch </PERSON>, assistant manager at <PERSON> Kinsley </PERSON>'s bakery. `` If we would have known, we would have attempted something else or we would n't have bothered.'' <PERSON> Lockwitch </PERSON> said bakery manager <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Laiso </PERSON> called Guinness before he and <PERSON> Lockwitch </PERSON> made the giant cookie. She says he was told that <ORGANIZATION> Guinness </ORGANIZATION> would consider their claim after they had made their gingerbread man. But <PERSON> Cyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, assistant editor at <ORGANIZATION> Guinness </ORGANIZATION>, said she told a <PERSON> Kinsley </PERSON> employee that there was no category for a gingerbread man and little chance that <ORGANIZATION> Guinness </ORGANIZATION> would add the category. `` People sometimes do n't want to hear what you're saying,'' she said. `` They do n't want to hear, ` No,' because they're determined to do their thing.'' It took 300 pounds of gingerbread mix, 280 pounds of icing, 600 egg whites and nearly 100 hours to create the giant cookie. `` With all the attention and publicity we got, we thought we were in,'' <PERSON> Lockwitch </PERSON> said. But late last month, <PERSON> Kinsley </PERSON>'s received a letter from Guiness explaining the book's position. Adding insult to injury, the letter added that <PERSON> Kinsley </PERSON>'s had no claim on the world record anyway because a chef in <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, created a 24-foot gingerbread man in 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     02-06 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0025</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Up In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 31,828.75, up 142.97 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Monday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890206-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-06-89 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AmishRobberies Bjt   02-06 0696</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Amish Robberies, Bjt,0717</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arrests In Amish Robberies In Tennessee Soothe Outraged Residents</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN GEORGE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAWRENCEBURG, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
