<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0004EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Britain-Libel Bjt   08-18 0715</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Libel, Bjt,0735</SECOND>
<HEAD>Magazine Relies on Reader Loyalty to Pay Libel Bill</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JESSICA BALDWIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of Britons, for whom life without Private Eye is unthinkable, are digging into their pockets to rescue the magazine from being bankrupted by a massive libel bill. The response to the $ 1 million award against Private Eye has triggered an extraordinary display of reader loyalty. Contributions totaled $ 80,000 by early August, according to editor <PERSON> Ian </PERSON> <PERSON> Hislop </PERSON>. On May 24 a jury ordered Private Eye to pay the record sum to <PERSON> Sonia </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutcliffe </PERSON>, the estranged wife of mass murderer <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutcliffe </PERSON>, the so-called `` <LOCATION> Yorkshire </LOCATION> Ripper,'' for two articles alleging that she tried to sell her story to newspapers. The magazine also was ordered to pay court costs of $ 160,000. The award caused outcry, partly because it far outweighed the damages paid by the state to families of <PERSON> Sutcliffe </PERSON>'s 13 victims. Editor <PERSON> Hislop </PERSON>, 29, said: `` If this is justice then I'm a banana. ... I think this is very nearly the end of Private Eye. We can not possibly pay that amount of damages.'' He then launched an appeal, hoping to get $ 5 from each of the magazine's 210,000 readers. Private Eye's reader loyalty may seem unusual. But then, so is Private Eye. Its semimonthly serving of news, gossip, opinion and satire has kept it afloat with barely a change of format since its birth in 1961, at the dawn of Swinging Sixties <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. With its carefully cultivated air of shabbiness, it still looks like something pasted together in a college basement _ which keeps the street price low at 95 cents a copy. Its 32 pages carry little advertising and it shows no political bias, savaging hypocrisy, pomposity and wrongdoing wherever they appear. `` While other magazines poke fun at contemporary mores, Private Eye pokes fun at real people,'' said <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Loynes </PERSON>, publisher and editor of the industry magazine <ORGANIZATION> U.K. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION>. `` Their satire bites at the rich, the famous, the makers and the shakers. It's wickedly satirical, even dangerously satirical.'' Some Private Eye euphemisms, designed to avoid libel problems, have entered the language, such as `` tired and emotional'' for drunk. Lately it has been prominent in investigating the controversial shooting deaths of three Irish terrorism suspects in <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION> last year, and the procedures that caused a British ferry to capsize off <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION> in 1987, with 193 lives lost. `` Street of Shame'' reports dark secrets from <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s newsrooms. `` Heir of Sorrows'' chronicles Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>' marriage as a tawdry romantic serial. Book reviews invariably debunk the literary darling of the day. <PERSON> Graydon </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, editor of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s Spy magazine, says his publication owes its existence to Private Eye and its founding editor, 51-year-old <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Ingrams </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Ingrams </PERSON> was a guiding spirit and we've always appreciated the sauciness and the great investigations,'' <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. Since the libel blow, each issue includes a page listing several hundred donors, and the quirkier letters of support are printed. `` As a basic old-age pensioner hardly able to afford a new tire for my 1939 pushbike, I have decided to drink water instead of beer for the rest of July,'' wrote H.J. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, who sent $ 8. An appeal of the libel verdict will be heard on Oct. 3. If the award is reduced, <PERSON> Hislop </PERSON> says the donations will go to families of <PERSON> Sutcliffe </PERSON>'s victims. According to <PERSON> Loynes </PERSON>, readers who went through the British private school network provide the magazine with high-ranking contacts in business, politics and the bureaucracy. Journalists of the establishment media also use Private Eye to publish stories their own papers wo n't touch, he said in an interview, because `` Private Eye is prepared to take the risk to be irresponsible.'' Managing director <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Cash </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Financial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> in May that the magazine's profits were just $ 4,800 last year after making provisions for libel damages and costs of about $ 800,000. Seventy percent of Private Eye shares are owned by comedian <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>, with smaller stakes owned by Cash and founder <PERSON> Ingrams </PERSON>, who used to list his recreation in `` Who's Who'' as `` litigation.'' <PERSON> Hislop </PERSON> succeeded <PERSON> Ingrams </PERSON> in 1986, long after the <PERSON> Sutcliffe </PERSON> item appeared. Ironically, when <PERSON> Hislop </PERSON> took over one of his promises was to reduce the number of libel suits draining Private Eye's coffers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0601EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--MistakenForDead     08-18 0138</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Mistaken For Dead,0138</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boarding Home Operator Charged</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SPRINGFIELD, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The operator of a boarding home where an 87-year-old resident was mistaken for dead and nearly embalmed has been charged with three counts of operating an unlicensed nursing home. The charges filed against <PERSON> Robbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Caldwell </PERSON> are minor misdemeanors and carry a maximum fine of $ 100, City Prosecutor <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> said Thursday. A resident of the boarding home, <PERSON> Carrie </PERSON> <PERSON> Stringfellow </PERSON>, apparently lost consciousness Aug. 5 and was mistaken for dead. She was transported to a funeral home, where her murmurings startled a mortician who was preparing to embalm her. Ms. <PERSON> Stringfellow </PERSON>, who is blind, was taken to Mercy Medical Center. She was released from the hospital Wednesday and transferred to a nursing home. Doctors said she apparently remembers nothing of the events at the funeral home.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0602EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--ChineseStudent     08-18 0131</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Chinese Student,0133</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Student Leader to be Visiting Student at Harvard</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One of the leaders of the student pro-democracy movement in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> will be a visiting undergraduate student at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> during the 1989-90 school year, <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> officials said. Wu'er <PERSON> Kaixi </PERSON> was chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Universities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Students </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Autonomous </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the unofficial union that coordinated the majority of student demonstrations in <LOCATION> Tianenmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>. The visiting undergraduate program is aimed at students who want to spend one semester or one academic year studying at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>. About 35 students are enrolled each term in the program. Wu'er is expected to take two classes in the first term and three classes in the second term, including courses in English, math, social science and Chinese, officials said Thursday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0132EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-APArts:Flight007     08-18 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Flight 007,0657</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Korean Airliner Disaster, Anglo-American Style</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT WOLF</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 1983 <ORGANIZATION> Korean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> disaster is returning to television in an Anglo-American docudrama focusing on behind-the-scenes political intrigue. `` Tailspin: Behind the Korean Airliner Tragedy'' recreates the American political response to the Soviet downing on Aug. 31, 1983 of <ORGANIZATION> KAL </ORGANIZATION> Flight 007 in which 269 people were killed. The 90-minute film stars <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarandon </PERSON> as <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lenczowski </PERSON>, then <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> affairs director for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> as <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Burt </PERSON>, then the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s assistant secretary for <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> affairs `` Tailspin'' will be aired Aug. 20 on cable TV's Home Box Office as the first in a three-project partnership between <ORGANIZATION> HBO </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Granada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. The trans-Atlantic line-up includes producer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Smithson </PERSON> and director <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Darlow </PERSON>, who are British, and writer <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>, an Irishman. Besides <PERSON> Sarandon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, the American cast includes <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> <PERSON> Yulin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Moriarty </PERSON>. In an on-set interview last December in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, producer <PERSON> Smithson </PERSON> called the project `` a serious and intellectual work of the type you do n't often see on American TV.'' In more than 150 hours of interviews with up to 60 people, some claimed the downing was a deliberate, cold-blooded Soviet attack; some that the airliner was on an espionage mission, and some that it was all a tragic blunder. Missing American records fueled allegations of a cover-up. `` Tailspin'' does n't take sides. <PERSON> Smithson </PERSON> said it is interested not in fixing blame but in examining the middle-level, decision-making process in American government. In one scene, <PERSON> Sarandon </PERSON>, as <PERSON> Lenczowski </PERSON>, argues in a White House boardroom about the wording of a speech President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> would later deliver. `` We're interested in the political battle in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> at the time between the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION>, the center and the right,'' said <PERSON> Smithson </PERSON>. He said the emergence of a Soviet policy of glasnost, or openness, made `` Tailspin'' a period piece with perceptions of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> as `` the evil empire'' soon to be outmoded. `` This is a curious piece of modern history, an entirely pre-glasnost piece,'' said <PERSON> Smithson </PERSON>. `` It marks a turning-point where we're beginning to see the softening of <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>.'' Director <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Darlow </PERSON> said he intended the film to be `` an international political thriller.'' `` If we've succeeded, it will have a sort of ` All the President's Men' feel about it,'' said the director, referring to <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Pakula </PERSON>'s acclaimed 1976 film about the Watergate In telling its story from the inside, <PERSON> Darlow </PERSON> distinguished his film from `` Shootdown,'' the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> TV-movie with <PERSON> Angela </PERSON> <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON> that aired last Nov. 28. That version examined the crises of the outsiders _ families of the victims and others. `` Tailspin'' focuses, he said, on three groups: the hard-line anti-Soviets, represented by <PERSON> Lenczowski </PERSON>; the middle ground, represented by the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>; and <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials who, <PERSON> Darlow </PERSON> said, saw the incident as `` a gigantic screw-up by the Soviets.'' <PERSON> Sarandon </PERSON>, a 1975 Academy Award nominee for `` Dog Day Afternoon,'' came to the project directly from filming in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. He had no time to meet the real <PERSON> Lenczowski </PERSON>, now a strategic studies consultant at the Council for Inter-American Security in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. But he thinks attitudes to the KAL tragedy have changed following the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> downing of a civilian Iranian airliner in July, 1988. `` Since that was, as our government says, accidental, I think Americans will be more open-minded over the shooting down of the Korean airliner,'' <PERSON> Sarandon </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bridget </PERSON> <PERSON> Potter </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> HBO </ORGANIZATION>'s Senior Vice-President for Original Programming, agreed, saying the later incident means the earlier one `` can not be seen in isolation.'' `` It can happen again,'' she said. `` Mistakes are going to be made.'' <PERSON> Potter </PERSON> said the HBO-Granada partnership had resulted in a truly international style of TV that works for both British and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> audiences.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NoPledging     08-18 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-No Pledging,0633</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fraternity Eliminates Pledge Period, Spending on Alcohol</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Animal House'' is out and temperance in at <LOCATION> Zeta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tau </LOCATION>. The national fraternity next month becomes the first to eliminate the traditional pledge period, that rugged rite of passage when hazing can break both spirits and bones. ZBT, like others, also is cutting off fraternity spending on alcohol. `` It's not easy to implement, it may be painful, but nevertheless it's an idea which we felt should be followed through,'' said <ORGANIZATION> ZBT </ORGANIZATION> executive director <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Greer </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, one of the movers behind the decision. The rules are aimed at breaking the image of the stereotypical fraternity house _ <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Belushi-like </PERSON> lunacy, heavy drinking, random abuse of pledges _ while keeping positive aspects such as bonding and community service, <PERSON> Greer </PERSON> said Thursday. <ORGANIZATION> Zeta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tau </ORGANIZATION>, which has 5,000 active members at more than 100 chapters in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, is the first national fraternity to put an end to pledging. A dozen other national fraternities are considering similar plans, said <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Brant </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interfraternity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's critical to eliminate hazing, and this is a viable option,'' said <PERSON> Brant </PERSON>, whose group includes 59 national fraternities. `` We are supporting them, and hope through their success others will learn the right lessons.'' Potential ZBT members will be initiated as brothers within 72 hours of receiving their invitation to join, said <PERSON> Greer </PERSON>. Once in, there will be a combination of orientation and education for the new members rather than a torturous pledge period capped by `` Hell Night.'' `` We've had, as have other organizations, a continuation of hazing incidents _ none life-threatening or severe, but we worry about it,'' said <PERSON> Greer </PERSON>. `` We wanted to take the bull by the horns.'' <PERSON> Greer </PERSON> said no single incident prompted the decision, but several highly publicized incidents involving other fraternities have focused attention on the organizations and hazing in the past two years: _ A <ORGANIZATION> Rutgers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> pledge died of alcohol poisoning after a fraternity house party last year. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Callahan </PERSON>, 18, had a blood alcohol level of 0.43 _ more than four times the legal limit. _ A pledge at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lowell </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> was stuffed in a sleeping bag while fraternity members turned on heaters nearby. The pledge survived, but arrived at the hospital with a body temperature of 109 degrees. _ A <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delaware </ORGANIZATION> pledge charged in a lawsuit that a corrosive oven cleaner was dumped on his head during `` Hell Night'' activities. `` The national fraternities do n't like being identified as the root cause of problems,'' said <PERSON> Greer </PERSON>. `` We have to find some answers and remain on the cutting edge of solving problems.'' While ZBT's Supreme Council unanimously approved the new policy, <PERSON> Greer </PERSON> acknowledges response from its members _ both active and alumni _ has not been uniformly positive. `` In the beginning, there was a lot of shock and denial and anger that the national fraternity would do this,'' said <PERSON> Greer </PERSON>, a Class of'64 ZBT at <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> at Long Branch. `` We've had letters and phone calls from alumni, calling this a break with tradition, saying they do n't understand what we're doing. But overall, it's been far more positive than negative.'' <PERSON> Greer </PERSON> said his organization knew it was risking a possible fall-off in membership and dues this year, but was confident its decision would quickly turn into a recruiting advantage for ZBT. `` We're dealing with a smarter, more savvy freshman. His parents read the papers, they know what's going on with fraternities,'' said <PERSON> Greer </PERSON>. `` Once we get past the initial anxiety, it'll be to our advantage.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0602EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--CerealRecall     08-18 0164</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Cereal Recall,0167</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gerber Withdraws Cereal, Cites Swallowing Problems</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FREMONT, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Gerber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> is recalling some shipments of <ORGANIZATION> Toasted </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rings </ORGANIZATION> because a new manufacturing process made the cereal too hard for some children to swallow. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> has been notified ... and removal of the product from retail store and wholesale grocer warehouses is under way,'' said <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Lovasz </PERSON>, vice president of quality control for Gerber. Some parents reported their children had trouble swallowing the rings, so the company voluntarily recalled 7-ounce packages of the cereal with `` Better If Used By'' codes of 30MAY90 thorugh 15AUG90, <PERSON> Gerber </PERSON> said Thursday. `` While the product's ` donut' design provides an airway and no injuries have been reported, our examination of more than 100 product samples indicate the reports may be related to a recent change in the manufacturing process that rendered the product crispier,'' <PERSON> Lovasz </PERSON> said. Consumers can return boxes of the cereal to stores for a refund, <PERSON> Gerber </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Poland-Powers     08-18 0339</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Powers,0357</SECOND>
<HEAD>Powers of the Polish President and Prime Minister</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Poland, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are brief descriptions of the powers and duties of the president and prime minister in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PRESIDENT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 The president is the head of state and commander-in-chief of the armed forces. Chosen by a joint vote of the <ORGANIZATION> Sejm </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, a president may declare a state of war or a state of emergency when he judges that a security threat exists, and rule for up to three months without the consent of the <ORGANIZATION> Sejm </ORGANIZATION>, the lower house of parliament. He must ratify or consent to abrogate international agreements. He also appoints and recalls ambassadors. He may veto legislation passed by the <ORGANIZATION> Sejm </ORGANIZATION>, subject to a two-thirds majority override. He may dissolve parliament and call new elections in strictly limited circumstances, for instance if parliament fails to choose a government or pass a budget within three months of being seated, or if parliament passes laws curtailing the president's powers. The presidency was restored this year after a 37-year absence. Former <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Wojciech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> now holds the office. The president serves a six-year term and may run once for re-election.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The prime minister is the head of government. Nominated by the president and elected by a simple majority of the <ORGANIZATION> Sejm </ORGANIZATION>, the prime minister assembles a Cabinet to direct the activities of the government and runs the ministries that control <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s state-sector-dominated economy. The Cabinet must also be approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Sejm </ORGANIZATION>. The prime minister is responsible for the day-to-day actions of government and also drafts and proposes laws to the parliament. Other duties include drafting annual budgets and national plans for the economy. The prime minister leads the weekly meetings of the <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION>, known as the <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministers </ORGANIZATION>, and controls all important government personnel decisions. The prime minister serves for the four-year term of the <ORGANIZATION> Sejm </ORGANIZATION>, unless he is recalled by the president and voted out of office by a majority of the <ORGANIZATION> Sejm </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HostageStandoff 2ndLd-Writethru a0401 08-18 0338</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hostage Standoff, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0401,0344</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Man Reported Holding Eight Children and Wife</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: New throughout with standoff ending in death of wife, self-wounding
of gunman; quotes from police; no pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STOCKTON, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man who held his wife and eight children at gunpoint shot her to death and critically wounded himself Thursday after a 6 -LCB- - hour standoff in which he played Russian roulette with the hostages, police said <PERSON> Dang </PERSON> <PERSON> Cha </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiong </PERSON>, 35, identified as a refugee from <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION>, was in critical condition at a city hospital, authorities said. `` Apparently none of the children were injured,'' said police Lt. <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. He said <PERSON> Dang </PERSON> was under court order to stay away from his family. Deputy police chief <PERSON> Lucien </PERSON> <PERSON> Neely </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dang </PERSON> told police he would surrender, but police then heard shots inside the apartment. Officers rushed the dwelling, finding the children unharmed in a front room and the two wounded parents in a rear bedroom. The wife was pronounced dead at <LOCATION> Dameron </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Neely </PERSON> said the gunman apparently had played Russian roulette with the hostages during the standoff. The identity of the woman was not immediately avaailable, police said. A tenth hostage, a 12-year-old boy, escaped and reported the incident to police about 2 p.m., <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. A special weapons and tactics team went to the apartment and attempted negotiations, but the gunman did not released the hostages, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said the man was armed, but did not specify the weapon. He had threatened the children, but there was no indication anyone had been harmed, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. The boy told police that <PERSON> Dang </PERSON> had played Russian roulette with the hostages, apparently sticking a bullet in the cylinder of a pistol and pulling the trigger. Seven of the eight children, between one and 13 years of age, were <PERSON> Dang </PERSON>'s, police said. A man with an assault rifle on Jan. 17 killed five children and wounded 30 other people before killing himself in a schoolyard in this city 75 miles east of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Poland-Ministries     08-18 0096</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Poland-Ministries,0114</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Ministries in Poland</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Poland, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 List of ministries in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>: Ministry of Finance. Ministry of Labor. Ministry of Internal Affairs. Ministry of Defense. Ministry of Foreign Affairs. <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welfare </ORGANIZATION>. Ministry of Justice. Ministry of Industry. Ministry of Environment. Ministry of Internal Trade. <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION>, Shipping and Communications. <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>. Ministry of Construction and Local Planning. Ministry of Foreign Trade. Ministry of Agriculture and Forestry. Ministry of Culture and Fine Arts. Office of Religious Affairs. Council of Sports and Tourism.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0219EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FirelineCooks     08-18 0389</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fireline Cooks,0398</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Kitchen Cooks Savor Their Work</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SALMON, Idaho (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 They do n't see the firefighters they cook for, but the women of the <ORGANIZATION> Salmon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> fire kitchen fuss over every meal as if their favorite children were coming to dinner. During fire season, two crews of local women work round the clock. Housed in the basement of the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management-Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> warehouse, the 20-by-30-foot kitchen can prepare meals for 700, and the cooks have pushed the limit to more than 1,000 when firefighters on lines in other parts of the state are still waiting for their caterers to arrive. They cook in five - and ten-gallon pots and stir their concoctions with ax handles The meals are airlifted to the fire camps. Retired cook <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Yakovac </PERSON> was on hand when the fire kitchen opened more than 40 years ago. It was before the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> used helicopters, so meals were packed in five-gallon tins and parachuted into the camps. Mrs. <PERSON> Yakovac </PERSON> recalls one fire in which the T-bone steaks they sent got hung up in a tree and spoiled before the crews could get them down. The advent of helicopters and pickups helped improve things, she said. It even meant they could send pies to the crews. After the Corn Creek fire in 1961, Mrs. <PERSON> Yakovac </PERSON> went home and built enough pie boxes to feed 180 people. They've been sending out pies ever since. <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> regulations now require a caterer for a fire camp of more than 250, but the fire kitchen still finds itself busy, serving smaller camps and picking up the caterers' slack. `` We do everything homemade here, everything from scratch,'' said <PERSON> Virginia </PERSON> <PERSON> Perry </PERSON>, Mrs. <PERSON> Yakovac </PERSON>'s daughter and a 34-year veteran who serves as head cook for the five-person daytime crew. Their menus include such entrees as steak, chops, chicken, and casseroles, plus a variety of salads and baked goods. A meal of stew and fruit salad for 700 requires 100 gallons of stew, 50 gallons of fruit salad, 90 gallons of coffee, 70 gallons of punch, and 18 gallons of milk. The women turn out meals for less than $ 10 a day for each firefighter, <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Eileen </PERSON> <PERSON> Havens </PERSON> said. In contrast, the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> this year paid caterers more than $ 28 a day for each firefighter's meals.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0219EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--SpaceJournalist     08-18 0152</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Space Journalist,0156</SECOND>
<HEAD>Candidates Selected for First Journalist In Space</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Japanese television station selected seven employees as candidates to accompany a Soviet space mission and become the first journalist in space, the network said. The <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> System </ORGANIZATION> staffers will travel to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> for tests later this year, the company said Thursday. Two finalists will undergo 18 months training at <ORGANIZATION> Glavkosmos </ORGANIZATION>, the Soviet space agency. The seven include two 23-year-old assistant directors, the network's 42-year-old <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> bureau chief and its 47-year-old deputy foreign editor. Two of the candidates are women. The successful candidate will join a Soviet mission to the space station Mir in late 1991 and will put together daily television and radio broadcasts during the six-day trip. Three Japanese astronauts, including one woman, are currently being trained by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> for a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> space mission scheduled for mid-1991.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0102EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-18 0933</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0970</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> will team up for the first time in their combined 179 years for a Madison Square Garden performance this fall. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>, 93, and <PERSON> Hope </PERSON>, 86, have crossed paths for decades but never performed together. On Oct. 1, the two <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> legends whose talent has brought smiles to millions will take the same stage. `` It did n't take so long _ we met last week,'' said <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>, trademark cigar in his fingers during Thursday's news conference. The Madison Square Garden appearance will be performance in-the-round with a full orchestra and will include singer <PERSON> Dionne </PERSON> <PERSON> Warwick </PERSON>. `` We did n't have anything to do; somebody started mentioning money,'' <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> said when asked why they were going on the road.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONG BEACH, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian-actor <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> will be the first recipient of an honorary doctoral degree given by <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, the school announced. The star of the movies `` Parenthood,'' `` All of Me'' and `` <PERSON> Roxanne </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> will collect his degree Aug. 25 when the school celebrates its 40th anniversary, the university said Thursday. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, a former philosophy student at the school, was singled out for `` his sincere and profound interest in and contributions to the university, the world of entertainment and the expansion and elevation of the human spirit.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Leno </PERSON> is n't behind the `` Tonight Show'' desk, chances are he's in an airport, airliner or hotel. <PERSON> Leno </PERSON> substitutes for <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> 77 times a year on the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> talk show and does about 250 one-night shows a year around the country. `` To go somewhere and stand onstage for an hour and talk is not hard work,'' <PERSON> Leno </PERSON> said in the September issue of Cosmopolitan. `` Plus, your stand-up does begin to atrophy if you do n't do it a lot. If you start playing only in selected places, pretty soon you lose touch. `` I've seen a few comedians who were funny fifteen years ago and are still doing <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> impressions and jokes about the women's liberation movement. Traveling, he says, is `` no big deal. I arrive in town in the afternoon. The show is at 8 p.m., and I really do n't have to be there until 10 minutes before. There're only two questions: Where do I stand? Is the microphone OK? No trucks jammed with equipment, no female groupies. It's pretty basic.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SANTA ANA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Tilly </PERSON>, the fast-talking ditzy gambler's girlfriend in the movie `` Let It Ride,'' says she likes being one of <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>'s busiest actresses, but would prefer some meatier roles. Miss <PERSON> Tilly </PERSON>, sister of actress <PERSON> Meg </PERSON> <PERSON> Tilly </PERSON>, said she was on location for the movie when the trade paper <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Variety </ORGANIZATION> named her Hollywood's busiest actress, with 11 films to her credit in the last three years. `` I knew I worked a lot, but I was really surprised I was the busiest,'' she said in a recent interview. `` Of course that kind of statistic is pretty misleading. I do a lot of small character parts while some other actresses with bigger roles work on them a year or more. `` I do n't think Meryl Streep called to complain that she was n't on the list. It's the bigger roles that <PERSON> Tilly </PERSON> wants, away from the typecast she believes she fell into when she was cast in several television shows, including a six-show stint as a gangster's moll on `` Hill Street Blues.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge has denied a request to lower bail for one of three men from the entourage of rap musician LL Cool J accused of raping a 15-year-old girl. Bodyguard <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Elias </PERSON> <PERSON> Tsipouras </PERSON>, 26, of <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, sought on Thursday to have the bail lowered from $ 100,000 to $ 20,000. Assistant County Attorney <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> argued that <PERSON> Tsipouras </PERSON> represents a danger to the community and would be unlikely to return to the state for prosecution if he were set free on bail. Two other men accused in the rape, band technician <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Saunders </PERSON>, 22, and singer <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, 26, have not yet had bail hearings. The alleged victim and a 16-year-old friend had received backstage passes to the group's concert Aug. 9 in <LOCATION> Bloomington </LOCATION> and later accompanied the group to a party. Sexual advances were made to the girls, and the 16-year-old left the party, but the younger girl could not escape and eventually was sexually assaulted by three men, police said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Baseball, of course, is an American as Mom and apple pie. But salami? A delicatessen owner is offering a free, 1-pound kosher salami worth $ 7 to anyone who can produce a ticket stub from a <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> game won by pitcher <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Viola </PERSON>. Average attendance at a <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> game is 37,300. `` If 40,000 people come to the deli, I do n't have that many salamis, but I am printing up rain checks,'' said <PERSON> Abe </PERSON> <PERSON> Lebewohl </PERSON>, owner of the Second Avenue Deli. `` I was warned, ` Abe, you're going way over your head.' `` But look, these are challenges which make life interesting and we'll see what we can do. Worse comes to worse, we'll give rain checks.'' <PERSON> Viola </PERSON>'s parents, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sr. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Helen </PERSON>, were regular customers years ago when the elder <PERSON> Viola </PERSON> worked in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>. They've since retired to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, but <PERSON> Lebewohl </PERSON>, who opened the delicatessen 35 years ago, came up with the salami idea two weeks ago when the couple stopped in to eat and wound up having their picture taken by a <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> photographer. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Viola </PERSON> joined the <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> recently from the <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Twins </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DC-10Engines Bjt   08-18 0523</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-DC-10 Engines, Bjt,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>NTSB Looking Into Possibility That Cracks Triggered Engine Breakup</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The investigation of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> DC-10 crash in <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, is looking into whether the engine breakup may have been triggered by cracks in its fan assembly, officials say. However, no direct evidence of cracking has been found, officials said Thursday. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> disclosed that a routine inspection of a <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> CF6-6 engine on another <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> DC-10 at <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>'s maintenance facility in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> recently uncovered a number of small cracks on a flange component of the fan assembly. The safety board cited the discovery in a letter to the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> in which it urged the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> to begin a special investigation to determine how much stress the GE engine can withstand before such components show signs of a problem, including cracking. The board, however, made no recommendations that would immediately affect the operation of any of the DC-10s being flown with the CF6-6 engines. There are 124 DC-10s with that engine being flown by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airlines, most belonging to <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> said. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> Flight 232 crashed July 19 as it tried to make an emergency landing at the <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, airport, killing 111 of the 296 people on board. The plane's No. 2 engine, located at the center tail section, broke apart during flight. The breakup, in which much of the fan rotor assembly separated, destroyed the jetliner's hydraulic control system. The safety board emphasized that critical parts of the engine, including front portions of the fan assembly where the cracking was found in the engine in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, have not been found and are presumed scattered across the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> countryside. Nevertheless, the board said it was concerned that cracks similar to those found in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> may have developed in other CF6-6 engines. If such cracks were allowed to progress to the point that the fan flange were to fail, the agency said it could `` cause catastrophic release of the -LRB- engine -RRB- fan section'' such as apparently occurred aboard Flight 232. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Broderick </PERSON>, acting <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> executive director, said in a telephone interview that the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> is aware of the cracks found in the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> engine in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. However, he disputed the theory that the cracks might be related to the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> crash. `` They were not cracks related to stress ... or strain on parts. ... They are completely unrelated to the events in <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>,'' he said, adding that the cracks appeared to have been caused by `` a chemical corrosion process'' rather than metal fatigue. But <PERSON> Broderick </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> agreed with the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> recommendations and that a review of CF6-6 engine performance was under way. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> said the investigation of the CF6-6 engine should include `` close scrutiny of the design, certification, manufacture, inspection and maintenance of the fan section of the engine.'' It also should include various tests to determine the `` life limits'' of engine fan components so that inspection frequencies can be established for those engine parts, the agency said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0107EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     08-18 0334</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0345</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OCEAN CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the winner circles, these victors were a shade above the others. The `` Miscellaneous Sun Tanning Tournament,'' held in this seaside vacation resort Thursday, attracted competitors in categories such as best tanned underarms, best left arm tan _ `` for folks who drive a lot'' _ and the Count Dracula division, for those who avoid the sun, said city publicist <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Soifer </PERSON>. `` We had a very pale young man win that award,'' <PERSON> Soifer </PERSON> said of 13-year-old <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Cheltenham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> `` He uses a lot of sunscreen.'' The best overall tan went to a repeat winner: <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> `` Mr. White Feet'' Savino of Ocean View. <PERSON> Savino </PERSON>, an avid gardener, wears work shoes every day. Bare-headed competition for the Golden Dome Award was tight, said <PERSON> Soifer </PERSON>, who dreamed up the categories. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Scavillo </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Williamstown </LOCATION> took `` top'' honors for the second year in a row, but an honorable mention went to 8-month-old <PERSON> Mathew </PERSON> <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Danbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION> `` He had the cutest little bald head,'' <PERSON> Soifer </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>EMMAUS, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Men are more likely than women to think about sex while bicycling, and women are more likely than men to think about cycling during sex, according to cyclists who told a magazine the sport generally improves their sex lives. Sixty-six percent of the 1,675 respondents to a mail-in survey by Bicycling magazine said they believed cycling has made them better lovers, and 44 percent said it increased their sex drive, while 11 percent said it decreased. `` All this time you were logging your miles, this little sport was becoming the hottest thing since naked volleyball,'' the magazine said in its September issue, due on newsstands next week. Asked whether they thought about sex while cycling, 1,146 men, or 85 percent, said they did, while 234 women, or 77 percent, acknowledged such thoughts. Asked whether they thought about cycling during sex, 19 percent of the men and 23 percent of the women said they did.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0106EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DeathofTuxes Bjt   08-18 0600</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Death of Tuxes, Bjt,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Death and Taxes _ Or is it Death of Tuxes?</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> said nothing is certain but death and taxes. To the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> nothing is as certain either as the death of tuxes. The Department's Depreciation Analysis Division has issued what is probably the first federal tuxedo study. It is contained in 54 pages, complete with tables, three appendices, graphs and a bibliography. `` There are two major types of tuxedos: basic black tuxedos and fashion tuxedos,'' the analysts inform us. `` Basic black tuxedos generally do not change in style, while fashion tuxedos generally change in style from year to year,'' says the Depreciation Analysis Division, a newcomer on the governmental scene. `` The basic black tuxedo ceases to rent either because it is worn out as a result of the multiple process of wearing and cleaning. ... Fashion tuxedos are also susceptible to sudden unrepairable damage, but usually go out of style or become obsolete before they physically wear out.'' The study was done to help determine the rate at which rental establishments should depreciate their tuxedos for tax purposes. To the tax man, depreciation is the process in which the owner of property is allowed to deduct the yearly decrease in the value of that property. According to the report, no matter how long a tuxedo may hang on a rack in the back room, its economic life is only as long as customers want to rent it. `` The principal findings of this study are that the equivalent economic life of tuxedos held for rental is 1.9 years, while their useful life, which measures the period of which they provide service, is 3.7 years,'' the report says. `` If <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> were to establish a separate asset class for tuxedos, <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> would suggest that a 2.0 year life be assigned to such class.'' The department chose August for its report, perhaps to prove that some government is around _ what with the president in <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> scattered to the four winds and bureaucrats at the beach. `` The basic unit of input is the tuxedo jacket,'' says the section on characteristics of the formal wear industry. `` The average rental includes the jacket, pants, cummerbund, shirt, tie, and studs. ... Since pants usually wear out faster than jackets, approximately one and a third pairs of pants are purchased for each jacket.'' The study notes that a set of tuxedos in a single style `` typically contains tuxedos in a wide range of sizes, some of which may rent very frequently and others of which may rent hardly at all.'' `` The latter are nevertheless needed, because rentals are often made to entire wedding parties and it is necessary to fit the entire party in order to rent even a single tuxedo.'' Under the heading `` useful life of tuxedos,'' the report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> spells out the rental patterns reported for 199 styles of tuxes. `` Most styles, 182 out of 199, had a useful life of approximately three to five years,'' said the statisticians. They found that formal wear rental companies infrequently sell used tuxedos. `` Industry representatives noted that before used tuxedos are discarded, they may be spray painted, shredded, or their sleeves may be cut off to prevent the tuxedos from being worn when their appearance would no longer suggest elegance,'' the report says. `` There is thus little or no salvage value for retired tuxedos.'' The tuxedo report is the first depreciation report issued by the Depreciation Analysis Division. There is no mention of what the second study might be.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0211EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     08-18 0879</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Outlook Good for Poultry, Livestock Production</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Most livestock and poultry producers appear to have outdistanced the impact of last year's drought and rising feed costs, according to <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> economists. `` Prospects remain positive for continued expansion of red meat and poultry production as more favorable weather ... caused crop and forage conditions to improve in most areas,'' the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday Looking ahead, the report said that total output of red meat and poultry in 1990 is expected to increase 2 percent to 3 percent from this year's record level, continuing the pace that began in 1982. `` Sharpest year-to-year increase will occur in the broiler and <LOCATION> turkey </LOCATION> sectors, but fed beef production -LRB- from feedlots -RRB- also may rise. Non-fed beef output probably will decline as herd expansion accelerates, and pork production may slip about 1 percent after increasing since 1986.'' A rebound in crop production from last year's drought-shriveled output `` is expected to result in lower feed costs'' as corn and soybean prices drop below the levels of a year ago. `` Continued expansion in meat exports will soften price impacts of record production,'' the report said. `` However, rising per capita meat consumption in 1990, together with a slowing economy and a lower rate of increase in consumer real incomes, should result in only modest increase in red meat prices and declining poultry prices.'' Analysts said consumer prices of beef and pork may increase 1 percent to 3 percent next year. But because of sharp production increases, retail prices of broilers may drop 8 percent to 20 percent, and turkey prices may decline 3 percent to 5 percent from 1989 averages. Improved returns for egg producers and prospects for lower feed costs are expected to boost 1990 egg output 1 percent to 2 percent, the report said. As a result, retail egg prices may decline 10 percent to 15 percent. Per capita egg consumption could rise for the first time since 1979. Cattle producers indicated July 1 that herd expansion is continuing, although slowed by drought in some areas. Beef cow inventories were up marginally for the second consecutive year, and producers were holding 4 percent more beef replacement heifers for possible expansion in 1990, according to the July 1 figures. `` Current inventory estimates indicate that as feed prices decline, feeder cattle supplies will be adequate to allow an accelerated pace of herd expansion and increased fed cattle marketings in 1990,'' the report said. In a related report Thursday, the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> said the number of cattle being fed for the slaughter market as of Aug. 1 in the seven major beef states totaled 6.57 million head, down 4 percent from a year ago and 2 percent below the level of two years ago. Marketings of fed cattle in July totaled 1.69 million head, down 4 percent from a year ago and 1 percent below two years ago. But the placement of new cattle and calves in fattening pens last month was reported at 1.31 million head, up 5 percent from a year ago and 3 percent more than two years ago. As of Aug. 1, feedlot inventories were smaller than a year earlier in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Only <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> feedlots showed increases, while those in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> were reported unchanged. State feedlot cattle inventories are listed here for the seven states, which account for about three-fourths of the nation's beef. The first number is the number of cattle, in thousands, as of Aug. 1, and the second number is the percentage of a year earlier.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> 153 77 <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> 460 102 <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> 730 104 <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> 495 100 <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> 1,400 96 <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> 1,580 99 <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> 1,750 90
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has bought <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> corn for the first time in almost two years, along with more wheat for delivery in the marketing year that began June 1. The sales, disclosed Thursday by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, included 150,000 metric tons of corn and 100,000 tons of wheat. No further details were announced. Although <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has been buying <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat periodically, it was the first purchase of corn since December 1987, officials said. In that year, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> bought 278,500 tons of corn. The latest wheat sales boosted to more than 3.48 million tons the amount of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has purchased for the 1989-90 season, officials said. Last year's sales totaled 8.3 million tons, making <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> the leading foreign market for American wheat farmers. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 36.7 bushels of wheat or 39.4 bushels of corn. The 100,000 tons of wheat would be about 3.67 million bushels, and the 150,000 tons of corn would be about 5.91 million bushels. Wheat prices at the farm have averaged around $ 3.73 per bushel nationally, according to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> recent five-day market estimates. That would make the sale worth about $ 14 million. Corn prices at about $ 2.26 per bushel would make the corn sale worth about $ 13.4 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0105EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DoctorCheckup Bjt   08-18 0564</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Doctor Checkup, Bjt,0581</SECOND>
<HEAD>Checking Up on Doctors: Consumers Find Credentials Hard to Verify</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LESLIE DREYFOUS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Consumers looking for a reputable physician often turn to the Yellow Pages, but researchers say verifying the credentials advertised can be all but impossible. Confirming a doctor's education, specialty training, certification and other background is frequently beyond the average citizen's grasp, according to an article published Thursday in The New England Journal of Medicine. `` It's very difficult in most communities in this country for patients to get important facts about physicians they'd like to consult,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Relman </PERSON>, the journal's editor in chief. The problem is that no straightforward directory is available to the public and those who consult professional listings often find them indecipherable. `` While trying to ascertain how physicians' credentials corresponded to those they listed ... we encountered a veritable obstacle course of inconsistent and illogical policies that effectively deny information to the consumer,'' wrote Drs. <PERSON> Julia </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reade </PERSON> and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ratzan </PERSON>, who conducted the informal survey. `` In conclusion, obtaining access to complete, up-to-date, and verified information about physicians is all but impossible.'' Like many consumers, <PERSON> Reade </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ratzan </PERSON> started their research by thumbing through the Yellow Pages. They found <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'s listings were not routinely corroborated and included a warning suggesting additional consultation with a local medical association. The <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which receives about 20,000 similar inquiries annually, answered many of the researchers' questions. But the process is rarely that simple, they reported. `` Many medical associations are too small, or are unwilling, to commit the time and manpower needed to provide rigorous verification, and they accept at face value whatever information the physician supplies,'' according to the researchers. <PERSON> Reade </PERSON> is a psychiatrist at <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Ratzan </PERSON> an associate professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Connecticut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>. Because physicians supply much of their own background information, <PERSON> Relman </PERSON> said, patients may face medical fraud. Doctors who need periodic re-certification in their specialities may skip the exams or, if they fail to pass, not report the results, he said. To protect consumers `` organized medicine must ... take the initiative and see that standardized directories about physicians be provided and readily accessible to the public,'' said <PERSON> Relman </PERSON>, who for more than a decade has pushed for an accessible consumer directory. `` If I were sick and needed an operation I would want to know a lot about the surgeon who was going to operate on me,'' <PERSON> Relman </PERSON> said. `` But if you're a lay person and do n't have access to professional sources of information it's rather difficult.'' Tenacious consumers can track down the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>'s directory, but the guide uses complicated numerical and letter codes in verifying information about a physician's year and state of licensure, medical school and specialty-board certification. Beyond that, no information is provided on advanced training. `` Thus, there is no way to distinguish between the self-styled cardiologist with board certification in internal medicine alone and the cardiologist who has board certification in that sub-specialty,'' the doctors said. The researchers studied several other compendiums, including how-to manuals spawned in the 1970s by the consumer movement, but found similar gaps and obstacles in each case. State licensing boards agreed that the best way to remedy patients' confusion would be to establish a carefully verified directory, <PERSON> Reade </PERSON> and <PERSON> Razan </PERSON> reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0225EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DefenseSecrets     08-18 0563</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Secrets,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon Looks Into Leaks of Spending Plans</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal investigators are trying to determine how defense contractors supposedly obtained secret budget documents containing details on the military's spending plans for weapons. Although the inquiry has centered so far on the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a major defense contractor, it is expected to extend to other defense contractors, government officials familiar with the case said Thursday. The investigation is being run by the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> inspector general's office and is separate from the 3-year-old `` Ill Wind'' investigation of bribery and influence-peddling in the awarding of <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> contracts. The `` Ill Wind'' investigation conducted by the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> focused on the role of private consultants in obtaining inside information about <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> contracts. The separate <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> case became public Tuesday when <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> official, was indicted by a federal grand jury in suburban <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, on 39 counts of theft, conspiracy and fraud. The charges stem from his alleged trafficking in classified documents, according to the indictment. `` It's part of a continuing investigation by the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> inspector general's office into how certain contractors and their employees have illegally trafficked in classified documents,'' said one <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> official, speaking on condition of anonymity. `` How <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON> obtained these documents is the subject of further investigation.'' According to the 68-page indictment, <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON>, while he worked for <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> as a senior marketing analyst from 1978 to 1986, obtained hundreds of the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s most sensitive documents. Among those papers were <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> directives on budget proposals, along with the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s five-year plan, according to the indictment. The five-year plan is closely held within the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> because it is the chief defense spending blueprint used by the secretary of <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION> and civilian service leaders in making major budget decisions about weapons. In addition, <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON> received three <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> decision directives signed by former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, the indictment charged. Distribution of those documents is extremely limited. The three documents dealt with the Strategic Defense Initiative, a proposed shield against nuclear attack, the indictment said, but it did not give more details. Although <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON> had a high-level security clearance, he did n't have authorized access to those papers, the indictment said <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON> refused to discuss the case. Contacted by telephone at his suburban <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> home, he said only, `` I do not wish to comment whatsoever on any of this.'' <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON> was fired by <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> in September 1986, said <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Carr </PERSON>, a spokesman for the company in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. The Wall Street Journal said the firing was because investigators were looking at <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON>'s activities <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> is cooperating with the investigators. `` There has been a considerable number of requests for documents, papers, records and so on,'' he said. `` We have provided those and will continue to answer requests for them.'' After obtaining the papers, <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON> passed them along to <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> officials and other, unnamed contractors, the indictment said. He also allegedly obtained some documents that had been specifically requested by <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> officials. None of the other people under investigation are identified, although the indictment said some of other alleged conspirators created separate log books to keep <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials from knowing that <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> had the unauthorized classified documents. <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> has authority to handle certain classified documents because it is a major defense contractor.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0227EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Navy-Trident     08-18 0520</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Navy-Trident,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Navy Evaluating Latest Trident 2 Test Failure</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The latest test failure of the Trident 2 missile is n't expected to affect plans to put the submarine-launched weapon to sea next year, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> says. However, the admiral in charge of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s newest and reportedly most deadly weapon says he'll delay deployment if he has to. A Trident 2 missile exploded Tuesday, seconds after being launched from the nuclear submarine <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> about 200 miles off the coast of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. It was the second such failure in three undersea test firings. The three-stage Trident 2 is a more lethal version of the Trident 1, the heart of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s nuclear deterrent. The new version, built by the <ORGANIZATION> Lockheed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Missiles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, is almost twice as heavy as its predecessor. The Trident 2, each of which costs $ 26.5 million, is to be deployed in the 1990s aboard a new generation of submarines, providing the sea-based leg of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s land, sea and air nuclear forces. Until the test failures, the missile had been one of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s nuclear modernization programs to be mostly problem-free, with 16 of 19 successful land launchings. In a statement released Thursday at the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said that despite the latest test failure `` no impact is presently foreseen on the planned deployment of the USS Tennessee in early 1990.'' The <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> is to be the first of nine submarines equipped to carry 24 of the missiles. The statement said that problems with water pressures on the missile appear to have caused electrical cables in the first-stage motor to sever, triggering the missile's self-destruct order. Rear Adm. <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Malley </PERSON> said in an interview published Thursday in the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> that he's confident problems with the missile will be resolved by the March 31 target date for deployment. `` If I have to slip the date again, I'll slip it again,'' said <PERSON> Malley </PERSON>, who earlier delayed the target date by three months. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday that <PERSON> Malley </PERSON> was not available for an interview, but it did confirm that his statements to the Times were accurate. <PERSON> Malley </PERSON> told the newspaper that initial reports from Tuesday's failed test indicated that engineers, despite computer simulations, seriously underestimated the amount of pressure on the Trident The missile, he said, `` is much larger than anything we've fired before. ... We expected some extra pressure on the rear end of the missile and its rocket nozzles, but not as much as we're seeing. It turns out that the pressure and the aft load are much more severe than was anticipated.'' Asked if the failures were a result of a design error or a flaw in the manufacturing, <PERSON> Malley </PERSON> said: `` The device was built to specification. There is no question that it was designed the way it was intended to be designed.'' In a statement, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said the submarine will undergo a two-month `` shakedown'' at the Electric Boat docks in <LOCATION> Groton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>. During that time, `` evaluation and correction action for the test failure will be conducted.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0239EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Depression-Disability     08-18 0560</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Depression-Disability,0577</SECOND>
<HEAD>Depression More Disabling Than Many Chronic Diseases, Researchers
Find</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Doctor Checkup, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRENDA C. COLEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Depression robs people of the ability to function more often than arthritis, ulcers, diabetes or high blood pressure, according to researchers who say depression is taken much too lightly. `` We've greatly underestimated up until now how disabling depression is related to other chronic medical conditions,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ware </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, principal investigator in a study that questioned 11,242 outpatients in three cities. Depression proved at least as bad as emphysema or back problems at limiting people in their physical functioning or causing them to stay in bed, said the study, published in today's Journal of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. The only two worse chronic conditions were heart pain and advanced coronary artery disease, in terms of limiting activities such as walking, dressing, bathing, climbing stairs or participating in sports, the study found. `` The findings are very important,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keller </PERSON>, a depression researcher and director of psychiatric research at <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. Four percent of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> population, or 9.9 million people, suffer from major depression at some point in any given year, he said. Millions more may have some depressive symptoms and may be `` highly treatable'' with anti-depressant medications, said Dr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Zajecka </PERSON>, clinical director of psychiatric treatment research at Rush-Presbyterian-St. <PERSON> Luke </PERSON>'s Medical Center in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Depressed people sometimes give up jobs and lose spouses while bouncing from doctor to doctor for years before being correctly diagnosed and effectively treated, he said. Dr. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerman </PERSON>, a depression researcher and psychiatry professor at <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, estimated that only about 20 percent of depressives are getting treated. `` The majority suffer in silence or are misdiagnosed _ as having tension, anxiety, personality disorder or weak character,'' he said. The study, coordinated by the <ORGANIZATION> RAND </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, looked at adult patients in a variety of settings _ health maintenance organizations, group medical practices and solo practices _ in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. About half of the subjects studied suffered from either depressive symptoms or one of eight chronic medical conditions _ high blood pressure, diabetes, advanced coronary heart disease, heart pain, arthritis, back problems, lung problems or digestive problems. More than one-fifth of the subjects _ a total of 2,467 people _ reported depressive symptoms, which they typically explained to their doctors as feeling `` down in the dumps'' or chronically tired, <PERSON> Ware </PERSON> said. Such patients experienced as much or more bodily pain and stayed in bed as many or more days as patients with back, lung or digestive problems, heart pain, high blood pressure or diabetes, the researchers found. Only arthritis proved more painful and only advanced heart disease caused more bed days, they said. In addition, patients with depressive symptoms reported significantly less ability to function socially than those with any of the chronic medical conditions, the researchers said. `` If the doctor ... is unable to come up with a certified psychiatric diagosis, that does n't mean the person can be ignored,'' said <PERSON> Ware </PERSON>, a research psychologist and senior scientist at <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospitals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. Such patients `` have a tremendous unmet need and burden that costs a lot from society's point of view, because they're not able to function,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0239EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;Ls     08-18 0205</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;Ls,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>RTC Takes Over Six More S&amp;Ls</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The new agency created by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to resolve the savings and loan crisis is taking control of another six thrifts, bringing the total under government control to 268 in 33 states. The <ORGANIZATION> Resolution </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> announced action Thursday against four institutions in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and two in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. The S & amp; Ls will remain open during normal business hours and all deposits are protected up to the government insurance limit of $ 100,000. The agency will look for buyers to take over the <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls, or determine whether depositors should be paid off and the institutions closed. The six, and their assets at the end of March, are: _ <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, $ 356 million _ Black <ORGANIZATION> Hawk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, $ 74 million _ <ORGANIZATION> Southside </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, $ 48 million _ <ORGANIZATION> Hearne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Building </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Hearne </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, $ 28 million _ <ORGANIZATION> Guadalupe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Kerrville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, $ 28 million _ <ORGANIZATION> Taylorbanc </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, $ 127 million The <ORGANIZATION> RTC </ORGANIZATION>, created by <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L legislation signed by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Aug. 9, last week sold the deposits of three small institutions to healthy institutions and is preparing to resolve the cases of additional thrifts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0239EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nation'sIcebox     08-18 0304</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nation's Icebox,0312</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Nation's Icebox' Title Surrendered To International Falls</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FRASER, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a warm ending to a cold war, <PERSON> Fraser </PERSON> surrendered the title `` Icebox of the Nation'' to International Falls, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Fraser </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Town </ORGANIZATION> Manager <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said Thursday the town trustees voted 5-2 on Wednesday night to accept a $ 2,000 out-of-court settlement offered by International Falls for sole use of the chilly title Both cities have spent thousands of dollars in litigation over the title in the last two years, he said, adding that <PERSON> Fraser </PERSON> still will be allowed to use it in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>. `` We do n't have the dollars to continue the legal battle,'' said Mayor C.B. <PERSON> Jensen </PERSON>. `` But in our hearts we still believe we are the icebox of the nation.'' International Falls uses the nickname to attract corporations to its cold-weather testing grounds. <PERSON> Fraser </PERSON>'s frigid reputation also has attracted companies _ Zerex antifreeze and <ORGANIZATION> Malt-O-Meal </ORGANIZATION> cereal. <PERSON> Fraser </PERSON> also is `` The Town Goodyear Put on Spikes.'' `` The thing started out as a friendly wager and has gotten way out of hand,'' said <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>. `` The board did this in part for the people of <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>.'' Part of the settlement calls for <PERSON> Fraser </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Falls </ORGANIZATION> to become sister cities. `` We want to get on with this and promote our state,'' International Falls Mayor <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> said Thursday. `` This will help the economy of the small communities in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. Everything has worked out for the best.'' <PERSON> Fraser </PERSON>, a town of 470 about 60 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, said it can document use of the phrase back to 1958, when tax dollars were used to buy a sign for the town. International Falls, a city of 5,000 on the Canadian border, claimed it had the term printed on hockey jerseys in 1955. Newspaper stories referred to <PERSON> Fraser </PERSON> by that nickname in 1945.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0241EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ExxonSuit     08-18 0346</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Exxon Suit,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Environmental Groups Sue Exxon, Seek Court-Supervised Fund</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> is being sued by two environmental groups that say the company should pay the full cost of repairing environmental damage caused by the <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION> oil spill in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> The suit, filed Thursday in state <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION>, charges that <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> was negligent in failing to prevent the March 24 spill. It also contends that <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> and its six partners in the <ORGANIZATION> Alyeska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pipeline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which runs the trans-Alaska oil pipeline, fraudulently misrepresented their ability to prevent or control a major spill. `` This lawsuit simply seeks to force those who caused the unprecedented assault on the environment to pay to restore one of the world's last reservoirs of natural beauty to its original, unspoiled state,'' said the complaint by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Newsome </PERSON>, the wildlife federation's vice president for resources conservation, told a news conference the suit `` complements and reinforces'' one filed Tuesday by <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> seeking to recover unspecified damages for losses from the spill. The suit by the environmental groups says <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> should be forced to finance a court-controlled fund to cover the cost of assessing and repairing environmental damage in areas affected by the spill. The money, which Ms. <PERSON> Newsome </PERSON> said would amount to `` billions,'' also would be used to buy natural resources such as fish and wildlife to compensate for ecological damage that can not be repaired. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said the company would not comment on the suit until it had seen it. The suit says <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> should pay for the establishment of an independent group of scientists appointed by the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> court to control and monitor the environmental restoration effort. The suit names each member of the <ORGANIZATION> Alyeska </ORGANIZATION> pipeline consortium: <ORGANIZATION> Amerada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hess </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pipeline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Arco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pipe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> BP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pipelines </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> -RRB- </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pipeline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Mobil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pipeline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Phillips </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pipeline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pipeline </ORGANIZATION> The consortium was responsible for the initial response to the spill.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>b a AM-RichardsonExecution 4thLd-Writethru a076dgarHolmescalledthecasino'saction_quote_``insensitive
08-18 0444</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Richardson Execution, 4th Ld - Writethru, a0761,0453</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Pipe-Bomb Killer Executed</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 2 grafs to UPDATE with execution; picks up 3rd graf:
`The U.S. ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN THOMPSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATMORE, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> was executed in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>'s electric chair early Friday for the 1977 pipe-bomb killing of an 11-year-old girl. <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> was pronounced dead at 12:14 a.m. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> refused Thursday to intervene in the case after the 11th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> upheld a lower court's decision to reject a stay of execution. Gov. <PERSON> Guy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON> earlier refused to grant clemency for <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, who was married last week in a prison ceremony. <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, 43, was condemned to die in the electric chair at Holman Prison for the murder of <PERSON> Rena </PERSON> <PERSON> Mae </PERSON> <PERSON> Callins </PERSON>, whose body was blown apart on the porch of her home when she picked up a pipe-bomb and it detonated. <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> contended the device was not meant to explode, only to scare the girl's family. The girl's aunt had broken off a relationship with him shortly before the pipe-bomb was planted. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Varner </PERSON> of <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON>, who rejected <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>'s motion for a stay, said it is `` beyond the bounds of reason ... to believe that a device which maimed and killed an 11-year-old child by exploding in her hands could be thought of ... as not presenting a serious risk of harm.'' `` I ca n't rest until he gets the chair,'' said <PERSON> Margie </PERSON> <PERSON> Callins </PERSON>, the girl's mother. In <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Lucia </PERSON> <PERSON> Penland </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> Prison Project said <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> `` was what most of us would call an all-around American boy with a bright future before he went to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>.'' She also said, `` The terrible tragedy of Mrs. <PERSON> Callins </PERSON> and her family can not be understated.'' Courts in recent weeks have rejected defense claims that <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> wrongly was denied a state-funded psychologist to show that he possibly was suffering post-traumatic stress disorder stemming from his Vietnam War experiences. <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> was married Aug. 9 at <LOCATION> Holman </LOCATION>, prison system spokeswoman <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> said. `` They let him out of the cell to go into the visiting room and she -LRB- the bride -RRB- was there along with some other guests and after the prison chaplain married them, they had some cake and then he returned to his cell,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> said. The governor's press secretary, <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Abbott </PERSON>, said that according to the clemency plea, <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Katie </PERSON>, met 3 -LCB- years ago. `` He wrote a letter to her church, saying he listened to their broadcast and she started visiting,'' <PERSON> Abbott </PERSON> said. The church was identified as <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bethel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Primitive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in Mobile.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0602EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--CouponBonanza     08-18 0173</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Coupon Bonanza,0176</SECOND>
<HEAD>Couple Finds 254 Coupons in One Can of Coffee</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SULPHUR, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A couple is going to have to drink a lot of java between now and 1991 to redeem all the coupons they found in a single can of coffee. <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Spates </PERSON> recently found 254 discount coupons totalling $ 101.60 in a 1-pound can of Sanka brand coffee. `` <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> was making coffee for friends, and there was a coupon in the first scoop out of a newly opened can, then another in the next scoop until she had pulled out three or four coupons,'' <PERSON> Spates </PERSON> said Thursday. They emptied the coffee into a bowl and ended up with half a can of coffee and half a can of 40-cent coupons. <PERSON> Spates </PERSON> said he called the maker of <LOCATION> Sanka </LOCATION> to report the coupon bonanza. `` I told the man who answered the phone at General Foods that we do n't usually drink <LOCATION> Sanka </LOCATION> coffee and asked him if all the cans have this many coupons in them,'' <PERSON> Spates </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0245EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LonetreeBook     08-18 0258</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lonetree Book,250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court-Martialed Marine Fights Book on Embassy Case</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALEXANDRIA, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Marine Sgt. <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Lonetree </PERSON>, who was court-martialed in the sex-for-secrets scandal at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, wants a federal court to pull copies of a book about his case from stores and halt further publication. The former embassy guard said in a complaint filed Thursday in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> that the book, `` The Court-Martial of <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Lonetree </PERSON>,'' is based on confidential information obtained by his defense team and jeopardizes his appeal. The book was written by <PERSON> Lake </PERSON> <PERSON> Headley </PERSON>, a private investigator who worked for <PERSON> Lonetree </PERSON>'s defense at his 1987 court-martial. The book is already available in some bookstores. The complaint also names publisher <ORGANIZATION> Henry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Holt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, and asks $ 100,000 in punitive damages. <PERSON> Murial </PERSON> <PERSON> Caplan </PERSON>, counsel for the publisher, said she could n't comment because she had not seen a copy of the complaint <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, one of <PERSON> Lonetree </PERSON>'s lawyers, said publishing company officials told defense lawyers Wednesday that it would not voluntarily withdraw copies of the book. <PERSON> Lonetree </PERSON>, stationed in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in 1985 and 1986, was identified in news accounts as having had an affair with a Soviet woman who allegedly introduced him to a spy. That spy allegedly used his relationship with <PERSON> Lonetree </PERSON> to obtain documents describing the layout of the embassy. <PERSON> Lonetree </PERSON>, who says his defense team did n't fully inform him of plea-bargain offers, is appealing the case to the <ORGANIZATION> Navy-Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION>. He was convicted of espionage in August 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890818-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-18-89 0244EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AsteroidEncounter Bjt   08-18 0635</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Asteroid Encounter, Bjt,0647</SECOND>
<HEAD>Earth Safe From Collision With Asteroid _ At Least For Now</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE SIEGEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
