<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 2346EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Soviets-Threat     05-24 0221</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviets-Threat,210</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Soviets Pulling Back From Threat to Stop Destroying SS-23</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Soviets have pulled back from a recent threat to stop destroying a missile covered by last year's treaty covering medium-range nuclear missiles, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Thursday editions. The missile is the SS-23, one of the weapons that will be taken apart under the Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces pact that went into effect last year. Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> had told journalists in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> recently that Soviet destruction of the SS-23s might be halted if <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> deployed a similar type of missile. The SS-23 has a range of slightly more than 300 miles, the minimum distance set by the INF treaty. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and its western allies are considering deployment of a new Lance missile with a range just under the limit set by the treaty. The Soviets have gone ahead and moved almost two dozen SS-23s from a storage site to an elimination site, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported, quoting unnamed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet sources. All the SS-23s must be destroyed by Dec. 31, but ample time remains to meet the deadline, the officials said. While the Soviets have n't yet destroyed any of the 239 SS-23s deployed before the pact took effect, they have destroyed training missiles and launchers, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 2358EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-IowaExplosion 4thLd-Writethru a0823 05-24 0858</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iowa Explosion, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0823,0881</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Evidence Leads Navy to Suspect Iowa Blast Was Deliberate</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 7-9, `Hartwig's family ...,' with 9 grafs to UPDATE
with comments by Hartwig's sister; picks up 10th graf, `A Naval ...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> investigators have found evidence to support the possibility that murder or suicide was involved in the explosion that killed 47 sailors aboard the battleship USS Iowa, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> reported Wednesday. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> quoted unidentified <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> sources as disclosing `` some disturbing facts'' about a surviving sailor who stands to collect $ 100,000 from the insurance policy of a gunner's mate killed in the explosion April 19. Investigators found gunpower and blasting caps in a search of the belongings of Gunner's Mate 3rd Class <PERSON> Kendall </PERSON> <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON>, 21, two years ago after he was arrested for stealing a car, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said. In a search of his home after the explosion, investigators found one of the burlap patches that gunners insert between bags of powder to clean the barrels of the battleship's huge guns during firing, the network said. <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> was quoted in published reports last week as saying the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> created homicide or suicide scenarios involving him and <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>, 25, to make them scapegoats for an explosion investigators can not otherwise explain. <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> has denied any blame for the explosion, and has said that in response to investigators' questions, he denied a homosexual relationship with <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said that because the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has failed to find an accidental cause for the explosion, it believes it may have been caused deliberately through placement of a detonating device in one of the burlap patches, which normally would have been handled by <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>. However, his sister, <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Kubicina </PERSON>, said Wednesday night that reports that <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> helped load the fatal shell were inaccurate. `` My brother was n't on the duty roster that day,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Kubicina </PERSON> said in a telephone interview with The Associated Press in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>. `` He was in the turret but he was not on duty that day.'' She said she has talked to a <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investigative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> investigator looking into the accident. <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>'s family told <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> that he was depressed when his friendship with <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> broke down last year. The family also said that at age 17, <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> threatened suicide when another relationship ended, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said other sources, which it did not identify, have learned that before the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> went on maneuvers off <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> wrote several letters that could be construed as farewell messages. Mrs. <PERSON> Kubicina </PERSON> said her brother was not a homosexual. `` He was a loner,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Kubicina </PERSON> said in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. `` He did a lot of reading. `` He wanted to be in the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>,'' she said. `` My dad was a gunner's mate on destroyer in World War II.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Kubicina </PERSON> said earlier Wednesday that she is contesting the fairness of <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> collecting $ 100,000 from her brother's insurance policy. A <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investigative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> agent told Mrs. <PERSON> Kubicina </PERSON> that <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>'s insurance policy, which listed <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> as its beneficiary, would not be paid until the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> completes its investigation of the explosion. She said NIS agents have visited her and her family four times since the explosion to question them about <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> and his relationship with <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON>. <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> said his son and <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> took out $ 50,000 policies from the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> credit union just before their battleship left <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION> for the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> in 1987. The policies carried double indemnities for accidental death, making <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON>'s payout $ 100,000. <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> had dropped <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>, however, as the beneficiary on his policy, said <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Kubicina </PERSON> said a close friendship between the two men waned because <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> was married last year and his wife did not care for <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>. She said <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> intended to change his beneficiary, too. `` I'm sure he had all intentions of changing it. I'm sure of it,'' she said. `` He had made comments to myself and my parents.'' The Hartwigs will receive a $ 50,000 payout on a separate government life insurance policy. <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fleet </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, referred questions about the case to the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Lt. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> of the information office said the investigation of the blast was continuing and `` nothing is categorically rejected.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fleet </ORGANIZATION> would not provide information on how to contact <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON>, who has denied any wrongdoing in connection with the explosion. `` In my opinion, they have no idea what's going on, what caused it,'' <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Newport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Times-Herald </ORGANIZATION> in a story published Sunday. `` I think they're trying to find an easy way out.'' <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> said he is used to being a scapegoat and that he and <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> often had been harrassed by fellow sailors `` because neither one of us drinks. ... They razz you if you're not out there with them getting trashed.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Kubicina </PERSON> said she did not intend to raise the possibility that the explosion was caused deliberately. `` I do n't wany anyone to think, including <PERSON> Ken </PERSON>, that I think he was a murderer,'' she said by phone from her home. `` I do n't think so. Truthfully, honestly, I do n't know the man.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0015EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-APArts:HirohitoFilm     05-24 0770</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Hirohito Film,0790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sensitivities Over Hirohito Complicate Making of Epic Film</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELAINE KURTENBACH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kazuo </PERSON> <PERSON> Okuyama </PERSON> began his career with typical Japanese movie fare: gangster and cute animal movies. Now the ambitious young producer hopes to inspire jaded Japanese with the tragedy of an idealistic rebellion in 1936 which tried to install a military government under the late Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Okayama </LOCATION>'s problem in making the film, due for release June 17, has been that the attempted coup by 22 fervent young right-wing military officers was quashed under orders of <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> himself, who was then revered as a living god. The emperor is n't portrayed in the film, but his order against the young rebels, whom <PERSON> Okuyama </PERSON> describes as martyrs, is depicted as a misjudgment that ultimately led <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> into World War II, the producer said. Reflections on the emperor's judgment and the question of his responsibility for the war are acutely sensitive here, although discussion of <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s historical role has become freer since his death Jan. 7 at age 87. Historians generally agree <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> was a figurehead, wielding little real power. His most famous decision was <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s World War II surrender in 1945, when the government was deadlocked over the issue. But <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> also ordered the 1936 leaders of the coup back to their barracks after two days of assassinations and political turmoil in the `` 2-26 Incident,'' so called because it was launched on Feb. 26. Several coup leaders committed suicide, and others were imprisoned. On July 12, 1936, two civilians and 13 of the rebel officers were executed by firing squad. <PERSON> Okuyama </PERSON>'s movie, `` 2-26'' tells the story of the young officers who led about 1,500 soldiers and nine civilians in a bloody attempt to overthrow the government and install a military regime under <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>. The rebels claimed they sought to restore integrity to a nation they believed was corrupted by a political elite living in luxury while millions suffered Depression-era deprivation. Many of the rebels, historians say, were sons of poor farm families who had suffered hunger and seen their sisters sold into prostitution. But in the repressive atmosphere after the failed coup, an opposing faction in the military used the incident to build its own power, eventually establishing a militaristic regime that led <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> into World War II. `` There was an energy and an intensity alive then that has been forgotten in today's <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>,'' the 35-year-old producer said. `` One main reason I wanted to produce this film is because we live in a similar era, when young women prostitute themselves and revelations of political corruption surface every day,'' said <PERSON> Okuyama </PERSON>. `` The only difference is that then we were poor and now we're rich.'' The film is coming out amid outrage over a scandal in which 14 prominent bureaucrats and businessmen have been arrested on suspicion of bribery and other illegalities, and more than 150 people embarrassed by disclosures that they accepted unlisted shares at discount prices from an employment information firm. `` I wanted to sound an alarm, to use the tragedy and drama of the 2-26 incident to tell people what they do n't want to hear about political corruption and decay,'' <PERSON> Okuyama </PERSON> said. `` Influential people are gathering dirty money. Like the martyrs of 2-26, people should care.'' The film depicts the deaths of the coup leaders as a tragic loss of courageous young men who died still true to their ideals. `` Even though the emperor does n't understand that we were right, history will answer for us,'' says one coup leader before putting a bullet in his head. <PERSON> Okuyama </PERSON> said in an interview that he knew a decade ago that there was material to make a good movie, but it just was n't possible because of a lack of funds, and sensitivities about the emperor The screenwriter did n't want to get involved, he said, but `` finally agreed on the condition we play down politics and aim the movie more toward young people.'' Corporate backers also feared a backlash from right-wing groups that vociferously protest anything they interpret as disrespectful toward the imperial family. `` When we get to the last print, just before distribution, we plan to show the film to some of the major right-wing groups to try to gain their understanding,'' <PERSON> Okuyama </PERSON> said. But he still expects some trouble. `` Actually, I'm very worried just now, very afraid. But even if there's controversy, I think I can explain what we're trying to do.'' The film ends on a note the rightists should appreciate: a clash of gongs and `` Tenno <PERSON> Heika </PERSON> <PERSON> Banzai </PERSON>,'' or `` Long Live the Emperor.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Byways-EgyptianOasis     05-24 0883</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Byways-Egyptian Oasis,0916</SECOND>
<HEAD>WORLD BYWAYS: Egypt's Siwa Oasis _ A Glimpse at the 13th Century</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 This is one of a series of periodic dispatches by <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> correspondents on life and customs in the byways of the world.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>By MIMI MANN</NOTE>
<NOTE>Associated Press Writer</NOTE>
<DATELINE>SIWA OASIS, Egypt (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The temple of the Siwan Oracle, where the superstitious young conqueror <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> the </PERSON> <PERSON> Great </PERSON> was told he was a god, sits in ruin on its hillside perch. <LOCATION> Shali </LOCATION>, a majestic 13th-century fortress that protected Siwans from medieval Bedouin marauders, is a sandcastle of rubble, stripped of its glory by neglect and the oasis' infrequent but devastating desert rains. The village silversmith is gone, along with most of the elaborate jewelry he crafted _ gigantic bangles that jingled from the oasis' richly costumed women. Berber and Sudanese heritage have blended into Siwan life, along with other tongues and cultures carried over Saharan sands to form its roots and distinct language. So much made <LOCATION> Siwa </LOCATION>, only 85 miles from <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, unique in <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, and much of that is gone. But much is left. As it has for a thousand years, life in <LOCATION> Siwa </LOCATION> begins before dawn with the muezzim calling Moslems to prayer from minarets of mosques scattered through the oasis' date palms and olive groves. Then a donkey serenade begins. Hundreds bray, echoing through the palms, followed by a chorus of roosters. Early-morning markets open to the cloppety-clop of donkeys pulling kerussahs, family carts driven by caftan-wearing men or boys. Wives and mothers covered head-to-toe in flowing blue embroidered shawls called milayah sit behind with smaller children. Covered kerussahs provide the local taxi service, sharing bumpy roadways with military trucks and, with increasing frequency, tourist buses from <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION>. Camels never made it big in <LOCATION> Siwa </LOCATION>. Donkeys are cheaper. Until the early 1980s, virtually all sounds and sights in <LOCATION> Siwa </LOCATION> would have been familiar to Siwans centuries earlier. But four years ago a highway became the oasis' umbilical cord to <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and the Arabic language. The three-hour, 190-mile drive from <ORGANIZATION> Mersa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Matrouh </ORGANIZATION> on the western Egyptian coast covers generally the same desert route over which, 2,000 years ago, people from around the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> among them _ trekked for more than a week seeking the wisdom of the famed desert oracle. More recently, buyers for chic boutiques in <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> have traveled it, taking with them the best jewelry and handicrafts. Siwans have been put on parade for an ever-growing number of often scantily dressed visitors. Television invaded <LOCATION> Siwa </LOCATION> in 1986, and more than 1,000 sets were sold the first week. Like their fellow Egyptians, <PERSON> Siwans </PERSON> go to bed chatting about the latest plot twists of <LOCATION> Falcon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION> or Knots Landing. Young Siwans, now heading in increasing numbers for higher education in <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, have far fewer traditions to remember but many more influences to contemplate. But for <LOCATION> Siwa </LOCATION>'s 10,000 inhabitants, the infusion and confusion has n't been all bad. A year-old <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid project gives them clean water for the first time. Extracted from salty subterranean pools, the desalinated water costs 5 piasters -LRB- just over 2 cents -RRB- a jerrycan, which even the poor can afford, instead of 75 piasters -LRB- 30 cents -RRB- when water was trucked from outside. Electricity supplies remain uncertain and sporadic, but Czechoslavakian generators are being installed that promise a constant power supply. One aid project is working to save <LOCATION> Siwa </LOCATION>'s soul. More than a year ago, <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Perron </PERSON>, then <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s ambassador to <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, asked Siwan officials what his country could do for their changing oasis. Help us save our heritage, they said. `` Everybody talked for years about how to save <LOCATION> Siwa </LOCATION>, that its cultural heritage must be saved, but nobody did anything about it,'' said <PERSON> Heba </PERSON> el-Kholy, fund coordinator at the <ORGANIZATION> Canadian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION>. The Canadian project aimed to build a traditional Siwan house in the old way, using mudbrick and palm trunks and to teach young women old skills. Now nearing completion, the two-story house going up in the village garden will become a museum dedicated to Siwan culture and a reservoir for handicrafts. Six miles away, in a poor desert village, <PERSON> Khadiga </PERSON> <PERSON> Ismail </PERSON> <PERSON> Sami </PERSON> has spent the last year teaching five cheerful girls, aged 11 to 15, to embroider bridal scarves in the Siwan way. Siwan girls, who marry about age 14, must have an extensive bridal trousseau, including seven elaborate wedding dresses. Mrs. <PERSON> Sami </PERSON> is among nine women team leaders, each passing along her sewing or basket-making artistry to five girls. The Canadian project has supplied each of Mrs. <PERSON> Sami </PERSON>'s apprentices material for bridal scarves, which can take several months to complete Once finished, she has the option of keeping them or selling them back to the project for 5 Egyptian pounds -LRB- about $ 2 -RRB- each. `` A bride has to have these scarves for her wedding,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Sami </PERSON> said. `` If she has to buy them ready-made, she will have to pay 75 pounds -LRB- $ 30 -RRB- for one scarf.'' Miss el-Kholy, the Canadian co-ordinator, said she considers both efforts a first step in saving <LOCATION> Siwa </LOCATION>'s unique traditions. `` Young girls today prefer watching television to making handicrafts,'' she said. `` But once we begin selling the products, and the women can see the results, I believe the traditions wo n't die.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SocialSecurityMixup     05-24 0501</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Social Security Mixup,0517</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quirks of Fate</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOUISVILLE, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The odds of two unrelated women sharing the same birthdate and similar names are high enough. But they are partners to another quirk: they share Social Security numbers. <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> and <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> learned three weeks ago that the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> made a freakish mistake years ago and assigned them the same number. Ms. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>, whose maiden name was <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, was the first to learn about the mixup. When she was considering buying a house, a mortgage company's printout of her credit history also contained Ms. <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>'s, who was born <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> took the question to the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, which told her it stemmed from a clerical error in the early 1970s. Ms. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> called Ms. <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> to explain. `` I was dumbfounded,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>. `` I could n't understand how two people could have the same Social Security number. I've had this one since it was issued to me when I was a little girl.'' Social Security officials declined to discuss the specifics of this case, but did say such mistakes are rare. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Battistelli </PERSON>, a spokesman at the agency's <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> headquarters, said he had heard of only one similar case. `` The other instance involved twins. By no stretch of the imagination is this a commonplace occurrence,'' he said. <PERSON> Darryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Mull </PERSON> of the Social Security office in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> said the chances of two people receiving the same number are `` infinitesimal, but it does happen some times.'' But that's of no comfort to the Ms. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>. `` The thing that aggravates me is that I have to take time out of my work schedule to solve their problem, their error,'' Ms. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> said. `` I do n't think that's fair. It's an error that should never have occurred.'' What happened is still unclear and the stories the women tell differ with each other and the account provided by the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. What is clear is that both women were born with similar names and two years apart _ Ms. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> on Dec. 12, 1937, in <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION> and Ms. <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> on Dec. 12, 1939, in rural <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>, who moved to <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> at age 15, said she applied for a number while seeking a job as a waitress at a Greyhound bus station in <LOCATION> Elizabethtown </LOCATION> in 1954 or 1955. Ms. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> said she applied for a number about the same time in <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>. The only time Ms. <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> said she applied for a new card was when she got married in 1957. She says she never applied for another new card in the early 1970s when Social Security officials claim the error occurred. Ms. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> said she applied for a new card each time she got married in 1962 and 1984. Ms. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> said Social Security officials told her that because she had the number first she could keep her number and that Ms. <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> would have to apply for a new one.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Sunshine Bjt   05-24 0550</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Sunshine, Bjt,0567</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sunbathing Britons Bask in a Balmy May</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By AUDREY C. WOODS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The sun, so elusive in a British spring, has been positively beaming down on the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> area for so many rainless days that people are in danger of forgetting where they put their umbrellas. Much of the country is sharing the sunshine bonanza. So far, it is the warmest May since 1964. <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> was the country's sweltriest spot Tuesday. The 84-degree high made it the capital's hottest day in May since official record-taking began in 1948. Temperatures of 82 degrees made the south coast towns of <LOCATION> Bournemouth </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Southampton </LOCATION> hotter at the weekend than <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Tangier </LOCATION>. It has n't rained in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> since a light shower fell May 13, and the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> Weather Center records .032 inches of rain so far _ against an average May rainfall of 2.02 inches. Raincoats hang at the back of the closet, <LOCATION> Wellington </LOCATION> boots are buried by accumulating debris in the car trunk and eager barbecuers have bought out the lawn furniture stocks in some stores and garden centers. Opportunities like this do not arise very often for a nation of picnickers. A good drenching is part of everybody's outdoor dining experience, and the ability to hold on to your plate, your glass and your humor while sprinting for shelter is a basic of British sang-froid. Bookmaker <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> says it faces a $ 170,000 payout if temperatures exceed the 96.6-degree mark reached in 1976, and has shortened its odds from 33-to-1 to 16-to-1. It would lose an additional $ 85,000 if the century's record high of 98 degrees, set in 1911, is exceeded and has dropped odds against this happening to 50-1, a spokesman said. Of course there is still a week left for a deluge, but nothing can take away the 224 hours of sunshine so far. Average May sunshine is 198 hours for the entire month, the weather center said. Londoners are taking all this in their stride. What is left of British reserve seems to have been shelved for the time being as people of all ages walk around the capital with large portions of their anatomy exposed to the sun. Barefoot, barelegged and occasionally bare-chested, they go to the parks and the zoo, eating ice creams and pushing toddlers in strollers. The people of the northern <LOCATION> Calder </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yorkshire </LOCATION> have not had the same good fortune. On Friday, a two-hour rainstorm caused flash floods and two towns had to be evacuated. A bolt of lightning struck 26-year-old <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Blake </PERSON> as he walked over a hill in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION> on Tuesday, but his life apparently was saved by a crucifix he wore around his neck. He suffered damaged ear drums and burns. `` The burning cross has left a perfect mark at the top of his chest,'' said a spokeswoman for <LOCATION> Gwynedd </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Bangor </LOCATION>, speaking anonymously. The <ORGANIZATION> Automobile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said `` near monsoon'' rainstorms Tuesday made driving treacherous and caused dozens of road accidents across <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Midlands </LOCATION>. But for most of the nation, television weather forecasters are running out of novel ways to express the good news and some have begun to point out that a cold front edging south from <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> might get to northern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> by Friday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0056EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Daley     05-24 0601</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Daley,0619</SECOND>
<HEAD>Daley at One Month: Off to Good Start, Critics Say, but Wait and
See</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SHERI PRASSO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Critics called him a pharoah and said he would resurrect the machine politics of his late father, but one month after his inauguration, even some detractors praise Mayor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> for his political shrewdness. Since taking the oath of office on his 47th birthday April 24, <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> has ordered a television-worthy cleanup of City Hall, which he likened to a `` pig pen,'' and called for appointment of an ethics watchdog with subpoena power to root out corruption among all city employees _ even aldermen. He also cut more than $ 40 million from planned city spending, and broke with tradition by ordering parked cars, some driven by city honchos, towed from illegal spaces surrounding City Hall. Even his press secretary found her car missing. And saying he did n't want to be the only survivor of a nuclear attack, he pledged to sell a new, $ 50,000 bullet-proof mayoral limousine ordered before he took office. Visible reforms make good ink, said <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, a political activist and long-time <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> critic who worked for <PERSON> Alderman </PERSON> <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>'s independent challenger in the April 4 election. `` Those are public relations, nice attention-getting moves,'' <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> said, calling some of the actions self-serving. `` I think I have to say whatever the motives, he's gotten off on the right foot.'' But, <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> added, `` We have n't seen any of the real actions of government yet, and I'm still very, very wary of what his policies ... are going to be.'' <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> faces re-election in the spring of 1991, leading some detractors to call the mayor's actions mere campaign tactics. But <PERSON> Marj </PERSON> <PERSON> Halperin </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the mayor, defends his moves. `` I keep wondering when people will finally understand that this is real,'' she said Tuesday. `` These are n't things you do just for show. These are things you do to manage the city responsibly and effectively.'' <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>, son of the late boss of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>, defeated <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, who is black, and Democrat-turned-Republican <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Vrdolyak </PERSON> April 4 for the right to finish out the last two years of the second term of the late Mayor <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>, who died in office in 1987. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> was the city's first black mayor, and the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> elected <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>, a black South Side alderman, to be interim mayor following <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s death. <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> defeated <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> in the Democratic primary in February. <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, who called <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> a pharoah at the beginning of the campaign, has criticized the mayor's performance as lackluster. `` <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> made a campaign promise that he would always look to collecting revenue already owed to the city before he would raise taxes,'' <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> said. `` Yet ... the first thing he did was to raise water and sewer taxes.'' The increase was drafted under <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>, but passed under <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>. `` We did reduce it from the previous administration,'' <PERSON> Halperin </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Roesser </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and a political analyst close to the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> is doing what most politicians do while facing the next election. `` I see nothing nefarious or hollow or not serious at all,'' he said. `` I'm amazed, frankly, at how much reform he has brought.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON>, a white alderman who supported <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, said he has been pleased with <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>'s reforms and a push for city efficiency. `` There's still a part of me that's surprised at his political astuteness in the last few weeks,'' <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> said. `` I think it sets a critical tone.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MalibuTurmoil     05-24 0712</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Malibu Turmoil,0730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Celebrity Colony Rankled by `Mayor' Martin Sheen's Invitation to
Homeless</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MALIBU, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The possibility of a wave of homeless headed for its celebrity-soaked shores has <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION> in a dither over the notion honorary Mayor <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> may have invited a tent city encampment. <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> declared the beach town where <PERSON> Sylvester </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> and Barbra Streisand live a nuclear-free homeless sanctuary. A nationally syndicated radio talk show host responded by calling for a `` March on <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION>'' on Saturday, for which he says he has 15 buses available as far away as <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. By Tuesday, at least one bus load of homeless people was organized, in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION>, and that was enough to have the beach community fretting. `` If God had intended them to live in <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION>, he'd have made them television producers,'' mused <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> columnist <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>. The declaration sparking the turmoil read: `` I hereby declare <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION> a nuclear free zone, a sanctuary for aliens and the homeless and a protected environment for all life, wild and tame.'' The attention <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> has attracted to the beach town of 19,000 has put pressure on the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, which appointed him honorary mayor earlier this month to promote a `` Shop Malibu'' campaign. `` The community is pretty upset,'' said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackwood </PERSON>, the chamber's executive vice president, who says she has handled hundreds of telephone calls. <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION> is a town with no coin laundry, no car wash, no mortuary and no car lot. It has trendy restaurants and three supermarkets, where it's not unusual to see <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Elliot </PERSON>, <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Irving </PERSON>, <PERSON> Whoopi </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> or <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyke </PERSON>. Few heads turn when <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> roars by on his motorcycle. <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION> is a place where <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Halen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hagar </PERSON> can jam at the <LOCATION> Trancas </LOCATION> nightclub without screaming throngs. Homes start at $ 500,000 and go up to $ 20 million, which is the price tag on Miss Streisand's compound. Despite its celebrity-enclave stereotype, most residents are working stiffs with an average annual income of $ 60,000. Sheen neighbor <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> joked on the `` Tonight Show'' that residents were offering to pay for valet parking for the homeless and provide free sunblock. The honorary mayor responded to criticism by declaring <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION> a free-speech zone. <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> said the following night: `` Mayor <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> just declared <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Landon </PERSON>'s hair a national forest.'' But many local Malibuites are n't amused. The Malibu Inn and Restaurant's `` Dump <ORGANIZATION> Martin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheen </ORGANIZATION>'' marquee _ changed Tuesday to `` Johnny For Mayor'' _ seemed to express prevailing opinion. `` We should disassociate ourselves with him. There is no community that welcomes the homeless,'' said manager <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Casson </PERSON>. Friends of <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON>, who has been heavily involved in anti-nuclear weapons protests and the farm workers' grape boycott, pledged to provide food and clothing if homeless people show up. `` We're not going to ask them to leave. We feel those people have suffered enough and they are being used,'' said neighbor <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Olk </PERSON>. Supporter <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Israel </PERSON> said: `` Homeless people are n't meat.'' New York-based conservative radio talk show host <PERSON> Rush </PERSON> <PERSON> Limbaugh </PERSON>, who has been needling <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> and the <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> `` left coast'' for years, said his offer of one-way bus tickets to <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION> was a fair comment on <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON>'s declaration. `` I like to illustrate absurdity with the absurd,'' <PERSON> Limbaugh </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` It is my intention to discredit <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON>. The march is purely to embarrass <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> and not <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Limbaugh </PERSON>, who embraces programs making the homeless self-reliant rather than giving them handouts, said he telephoned the chamber to ask where to take his homeless bus and a spokeswoman said, `` There's no place for them here,'' then hung up. `` See! There's no sanctuary. We are going to show them they do n't want you,'' said <PERSON> Limbaugh </PERSON>, conceding his reservations about bringing homeless to <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION>. `` I do n't want to be thought of as a cheap theatrical stunt guy.'' <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON>, who has been in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> directing <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Busey </PERSON> and son <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> in the movie `` Count a Lonely Cadence,'' said in his latest missive from <LOCATION> Vancouver </LOCATION>: `` I regret that my concern for the poor and the environment was so dishonestly misinterpreted and misused to perpetrate a cruel hoax on 4 million Americans who are already broken beyond any measure of understanding.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0058EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Argentina 2ndLd-Writethru   05-24 0602</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Argentina, 2nd Ld-Writethru,a0755,0617</SECOND>
<HEAD>Alfonsin to Stay Til Dec. 10; Economic Plan by Sunday</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: LEADS with 9 grafs to UPDATE with protest at congress, Menem
comments. Pickup 7th pvs, `The mood...' DELETES 13th pvs, `Menem said...'
which moved up.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED McCULLOUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> said Tuesday he wo n't leave office early because President-elect <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> will not agree on policies to stabilize the economy during a transfer of power. `` We will get to the 10th of December with the extraordinary effort of the Argentine people,'' <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> said in a 14-minute speech broadcast nationwide. His six-year term expires Dec. 10. <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Radical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Menem </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Peronist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> had been holding talks on the possibility of an early transition because of the economic crisis. After <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON>'s speech his Cabinet members submitted their resignations. Press secretary <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Ignacio </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> said <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> will decide Wednesday whether to accept them. <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> told the independent news agency <ORGANIZATION> Diarios </ORGANIZATION> y Noticias Tuesday night that his party did not break off the transition negotiations that were initiated by <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> last weekend. `` We simply were not in agreement with the -LRB- economic -RRB- proposals of the ruling party,'' he said. `` As I said before, I want the president to depart with every honor, without resigning, as befits a man who has struggled for democracy.'' About 3,000 people gathered outside <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> Tuesday night for what they called a `` hunger march.'' The demonstration was organized by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Left </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> alliance </ORGANIZATION> to protest inflation and increased utility rates approved last week by the government. `` There will be no pact or social peace arranged from above, because now begins the struggle and mobilization of those from below,'' <PERSON> Patricio </PERSON> <PERSON> Echegaray </PERSON>, secretary-general of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, told the crowd. <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> said his <ORGANIZATION> Radical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> will unveil its own economic program by Sunday. `` It will be as hard as you can imagine,'' he said, and suitable for `` an economy of war ... a government in crisis.'' The mood in <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION> was somber as teachers and other public employees planned strikes for higher wages, stores in the capital marked up prices and some supermarkets rationed purchases. <PERSON> Menem </PERSON>, 58, defeated presidential nominee <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Angeloz </PERSON> of the Radical Civic Union in national elections on May 14. The Peronists won virtual control of both houses of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Instead of giving the economy a boost of confidence, the election was followed by a plunge in value of the austral against the dollar. Interest rates soared to record highs and other key economic indicators grew worse. Inflation is projected at 50 percent this month. Wages are shrinking, unemployment and public anger are rising, the national budget is in deficit, reserves in the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> are low and no payments are being made on the foreign debt. Banks and foreign exchange houses were closed Monday and Tuesday as the government increased public utility rates and raised taxes to help balance the budget. Banks will resume restricted operations Wednesday, but exchange houses will remain closed until Monday. Peronists rejected the tariff increases and insisted that the national minimum wage be raised substantially and the federal government bail out provinces _ almost all Peronist-governed _ that could not meet their payrolls. <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> earlier indicated he might be willing to take office early. Analysts said he backed out because he counted on the seven-month transition to prepare his own economic program. `` He does n't want to take over in the middle of a crisis he did n't cause,'' said <PERSON> Angel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pena </PERSON>, chief economist at the <ORGANIZATION> Mediterranean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> think tank. `` It could be worse in December, but not necessarily.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0610EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Students-Terrorism     05-24 0113</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Students-Terrorism,0116</SECOND>
<HEAD>School Officials Worry About Foreign Trips</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GREENSBURG, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 School board members have decided not to sponsor any more foreign-exchange programs because of fears of terrorism. The decision was made because rioting and looting in the streets of <LOCATION> Caracas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>, coincided with a trip by <ORGANIZATION> Hempfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> students to a neighboring town this spring. `` We tried calling the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, but it's impossible to make a determination -LRB- about instability -RRB-. <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> has been stable for so many years. It's so unpredictable,'' Superintendent <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. Students in the <ORGANIZATION> Hempfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> who want to travel abroad still can do so by making their own arrangements, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0610EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--EmergencyLanding     05-24 0101</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Emergency Landing,0104</SECOND>
<HEAD>Oil Pressure Drop Forces Jetliner to Make Emergency Landing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jetliner carrying 103 people made an emergency landing after an oil pressure problem forced the pilot to shut down one of its two engines, officials said. Flight 1209 was en route from <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> on Tuesday when it developed the problem, said <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Messing </PERSON>, a spokesman at <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. The pilot decided to land the McDonnell-Douglas MD-80 at <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hopkins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airport </ORGANIZATION> as a precaution, <PERSON> Courtney </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Courtney </PERSON> said passengers were directed to other Denver-bound flights by late afternoon.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Americans'Health Bjt   05-24 0613</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Americans' Health, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Most Americans Are Too Fat, Study Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nearly two-thirds of Americans are too fat, and more than a third are at least 10 percent over the recommended weights for their height, body build and sex, a nationwide health survey shows. The study, done for <ORGANIZATION> Prevention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magazine </ORGANIZATION>, determined that 64 percent of adults age 25 and over could stand to lose at least a few pounds. But fewer than half of those people were trying to shed the extra pounds when polled in November, the study by <ORGANIZATION> Louis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Harris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> says. The percentage of overweight Americans is the highest since the magazine began keeping track in 1983, and is up from 59 percent in 1987 and 1986, 62 percent in 1985, 56 percent in 1984 and 58 percent in the first year of the survey. More than a third of Americans are at least 10 percent over the weight recommended for their height, body build and sex by the <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> tables used by many doctors, the survey found. Only about one-fifth weigh about what they should, and they are more likely to be `` people in the East and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>, suburban residents, people in their 30's and 40's, college graduates,'' the magazine said. Slightly more women than men are the proper weight _ 22 percent compared with 20 percent _ and gender aside, only 29 percent of people making more than $ 50,000 a year are appropriately trim, the survey said. `` Weight control becomes more problematic when those who are overweight do not feel overweight,'' the magazine said. One in five surveyed fell into that category, and only 48 percent of those who needed to shed pounds were actively fighting the battle of the bulge, according to the survey. Despite the weight problem, the survey found some good news about Americans' health, including more people who quit smoking and cut down on high-cholesterol foods and more women who examined their breasts monthly for signs of cancer. Overall, it found that people 65 and older are more likely to take preventive health measures than those under 35. Among the findings: _ 48 percent said they try to avoid high-cholesterol foods, up 6 percentage points from 1987 However, fewer people are trying to get enough vitamins and minerals, to avoid eating too much salt and sugar and to eat fish twice a week, the survey said. _ 36 percent said they exercise strenuously, sustaining an accelerated heart and pulse rate for at least 20 minutes, at least three days a week That proportion has remained stable over the past five years. _ 63 percent reported that they feel under great stress at least once a week, up from 55 percent in 1983 Stress is reported more frequently by those in the lowest and highest income brackets, the survey found. _ Americans are continuing to kick the cigarette habit, with the percentage of smokers declining to 26 percent, down from 30 percent in 1983 _ The rate of heavy drinkers _ 11 percent _ has changed little since 1983, but the proportion of adults who say they never consume alcohol rose 5 points over the period to 39 percent _ One out of 10 people under age 30 said they used drugs in 1988, compared with two out of 10 in 1984 _ The proportion of women who said they examine their breasts at least once a month for signs of cancer rose to 51 percent, up from 37 percent five years earlier The telephone survey of 1,250 randomly selected adults was conducted last Nov. 9-23. Results had a margin of error of plus or minus 3 percentage points.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0012EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CompanyTrial     05-24 0378</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Company Trial,0388</SECOND>
<HEAD>65 Guilty Verdicts at End of Nevada's Longest Trial</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM GARDNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RENO, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal jury convicted 12 people Tuesday on charges they operated an interstate drug ring that called itself `` The Company.'' The trial lasted 16 months. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> jury found all the defendants in the case guilty of 65 of the 71 counts against them. Members of the ring were accused of making and selling methamphetamines and operating a marijuana plantation and other drug operations in northern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. They allegedly distributed the drugs from northern Califorian through western <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> and south to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Rupley </PERSON> <PERSON> Sr. </PERSON>, the ringleader of the cartel based in nearby <PERSON> Sparks </PERSON>, was convicted on all 15 counts. <PERSON> Rupley </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonnenfant </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dwain </PERSON> and <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> were found guilty of conducting a continuing criminal enterprise, which carries a maximum penalty of life imprisonment. The jury acquitted the defendants on three counts, and said they could not agree on a verdict on three other charges after 10 days of deliberations. The defendants appeared undaunted by the trial's outcome, chatting with each other as the verdicts were read and chuckling as Judge <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> mispronounced one defendant's name. <PERSON> Bonnenfant </PERSON> and another defendant winked and waved at girlfriends in the audience. <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> ordered the jurors, who first entered the courtroom on Jan. 19, 1988, to return Wednesday afternoon for the trial's final phase. They will determine whether the defendants should forfeit about $ 2 million to $ 3 million worth of possessions seized during their arrests. Prosecutors hope to get the cars, weapons and other items to help defray the huge cost of trying the case, estimated at $ 8 million to $ 10 million. Twenty-four people originally were indicted in the case, but half were removed before it went to trial after pleading guilty to reduced charges in exchange for cooperating with the government. The charges against the defendants convicted Tuesday included manufacture, possession and possesion for sale of methamphetamines and marijuana; interstate transportation in aid of racketeering; wiretapping, and unlawful use of a firearm. Except for the continuing criminal enterprise charge, most of the counts carry a maximum sentence of 5 years in prison and some permit a maximum sentence of 20 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Superconductor-Consortium     05-24 0453</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Superconductor-Consortium,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Group Formed to Find Commercial Uses for Superconductors</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A university and two giant companies that are leaders in technology research have joined forces to try to beat <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> in development of commercial uses for superconductors. The announcement by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Machines </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday said the consortium's goal is develop applications for the new technology. Superconductors are ceramic materials cooled to beyond minus 200 degrees Fahrenheit, at which point they can let electricity pass through them without resistance. In theory, superconductors could let energy be stored and sent without any loss of strength and more cheaply than is now possible. Potential uses include faster computers and more powerful batteries and motors. Both the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> are researching superconductors, but the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> has the edge. The goal of the consortium is to make sure American firms, rather than those from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, have the advantage in commercial application of the research. `` This will be a consortium of open communication among the researchers involved,'' the three organizations said in a joint statement. `` The combining of their scientific knowledge and their knowledge of applications will benefit the nation.'' The new organization will be called the Consortium for Superconducting Electronics. Researchers will remain at their present locations but will share information. In January, the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> said such an organization was needed if the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> wanted to avoid what occurred in laser and videotape technology. Both were created in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> but were commercially exploited by <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. The consortium announced that research efforts will be concentrated in four areas, including signal distribution, high-temperature materials and technology, advanced devices and integrated circuits, and junctions. The consortium will focus on applying superconductor technology to high-speed microelectronic devices for use in computers, telecommunications and military systems, the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported today. `` It is a model of how universities, government labs and industry have to cooperate in the future to address a number of issues,'' <ORGANIZATION> MIT </ORGANIZATION> Provost <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Deutch </PERSON> told the Times. <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gomory </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> senior vice president for science and technology, told the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> that the consortium would seek $ 4 million to $ 6 million in financing from a <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> research agency, most of which would go to MIT. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dynes </PERSON>, director of chemical physics research at <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratories </ORGANIZATION>, told the Times that consortium organizers thought having big organizations involved would give the group weight to attract other members. `` I do n't regard this as the big guys banding together and wiping out the little guys as much as giving the little guys an ability to get in the same building as us,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Abuse-Release     05-24 0244</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Abuse-Release,0251</SECOND>
<HEAD>Confessed Child Abuser Released From Prison, Deported</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A babysitter who pleaded guilty in 1985 in one of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s most notorious child abuse cases has been released from prison and deported to her native <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, immigration officials said Tuesday. <PERSON> Ileana </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuster </PERSON> was convicted along with her husband, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, in 1985 on numerous charges of child abuse at the Country Walk day care center in southwest <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Fuster </PERSON>, who had served only about four years of her 10-year sentence, was released from the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Lowell </LOCATION> May 16, said <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivkind </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> district director of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. She was placed in the custody of immigration officials and two days later put on a plane to <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Rivkind </PERSON>, adding that the release was not announced at the time for Mrs. <PERSON> Fuster </PERSON>'s own security. Mrs. <PERSON> Fuster </PERSON>, 22, had written the INS from prison before her release, asking to be permitted to remain in the country, <PERSON> Rivkind </PERSON> said. But the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> director said she was illegally in the country and a convicted felon. `` She'll never be able to return to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' he said. Mrs. <PERSON> Fuster </PERSON> pleaded guilty to 12 counts of sexual battery and lewd assault charges, while her husband, who has never admitted guilt, was convicted on 14 counts of sexual battery, lewd assault, and aggravated assault. He is currently serving six consecutive life sentences, plus 110 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Fire-Crafts     05-24 0274</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fire-Crafts,0281</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Destroys Princeton Home With Collection Of Crafts</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PRINCETON, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fire started accidentally by a plumber Tuesday destroyed a <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> home housing a large collection of works by famed furniture maker and craftsman <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakashima </PERSON>, officials said. More than 100 pieces of woodwork and furniture by <PERSON> Nakashima </PERSON> were destroyed, the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported Wednesday. <PERSON> Nakashima </PERSON>, 83, is considered by many to be the elder statesman of American crafts. Only two pieces of the collection, owned by Dr. <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> and <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Krosnick </PERSON>, survived. A picture frame and a boardroom table were on loan for an exhibit of <PERSON> Nakashima </PERSON>'s work at the American Craft Museum in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. `` It is a great loss _ for them and for us,'' <PERSON> Nakashima </PERSON> told the Times in an interview from his studio in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hope </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> `` Some of the pieces can be replaced, but many can not. They are precise pieces _ one of a kind, many of them.'' The blaze began about 11:20 a.m. when an acetylene torch being used by the plumber caught fire, said <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Township </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Lt. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Musso </PERSON>. The plumber set the torch on the floor while he looked for something to extinguish the flames, and while he was gone the fire engulfed the basement and spread to the rest of the house, <PERSON> Musso </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> Fire Chief <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Freda </PERSON> estimated damages to the home and its contents at about $ 1 million. The house was in a secluded, wooded area. Mrs. <PERSON> Krosnick </PERSON> and her housekeeper escaped without injury, officials said. The plumber was treated for minor burns to his hands and hair at a hospital and released.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-CannesFestival     05-24 0472</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cannes Festival,0487</SECOND>
<HEAD>26-Year-Old American Director Takes Top Award At Cannes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CANNES, France (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first film by 26-year-old American director <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Soderbergh </PERSON>, `` sex, lies and videotape,'' won the Golden Palm award at the 42nd <LOCATION> Cannes </LOCATION> film festival, and Americans took several other top awards. One of the low-budget movie's four stars, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Spader </PERSON>, won best actor during Tuesday night's ceremonies and <PERSON> Meryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Streep </PERSON> was chosen best actress for her performance in `` A Cry in the Dark,'' directed by <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Schepisi </PERSON>. American <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarmusch </PERSON>'s `` Mystery Train,'' the tale of three characters connected by a ride on the same train, took the prize for best artistic contribution. <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Peck </PERSON>, whose latest film `` Old Gringo'' officially closed the 13-day festival, also won a special prize for lifetime contribution to cinema. `` Well, I guess it's all downhill from here,'' said <PERSON> Soderburgh </PERSON> as he accepted the festival's top prize. `` I do n't know what to say.'' West German director <PERSON> Wim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wenders </PERSON>, president of the jury, presented the award to <PERSON> Soderbergh </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Wenders </PERSON> said the movie, a surprise choice among the 22 entries, brought the jury `` an enormous joy and a great confidence in the future of cinema.'' The Jury's Special Prize went to two films: French director <PERSON> Bertrand </PERSON> <PERSON> Blier </PERSON>'s `` Trop Belle Pour Toi'' -LRB- Too Beautiful for You -RRB- and Italian director <PERSON> Giuseppe </PERSON> <PERSON> Tornatore </PERSON>'s `` Nuovo Cinema Paradiso'' -LRB- New Paradise Cinema -RRB-. Emir <PERSON> Kusturica </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> received the best director award for his movie `` Dom Za Vesanje'' -LRB- Time of the Gypsies -RRB-. The Jury Prize went to `` Jesus de Montreal'' by Canadian director <PERSON> Denys </PERSON> <PERSON> Arcand </PERSON>. The film had been among those rumored for the <LOCATION> Golden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION>. Shot on a $ 1.2 million budget, `` sex, lies and videotape'' tells the story of a seemingly happily married, prosperous couple, whose lives are disrupted when a troubled friend returns to town, upsetting a carefully constructed system of lies and sexual betrayal. <PERSON> Spader </PERSON> portrayed the returning friend. Impotent, he videotapes interviews with women about their sex lies as a substitute for real intimacy. The movie, through well received, had not figured in rumors for the <LOCATION> Golden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Blier </PERSON>'s `` Trop Belle Pour Toi,'' starring <PERSON> Gerard </PERSON> <PERSON> Depardieu </PERSON>, tells the story of a garage owner who betrays his beautiful wife following a sudden, unexplained attraction for his less attractive temporary secretary. `` Nuovo Cinema Paradiso'' a French-Italian entry, focuses on the cinema and its demise. `` Old Gringo,'' directed by Argentine <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Puenzo </PERSON> and also starring <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON>, officially closed the 13-day festival. Both <PERSON> Peck </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> received standing ovations from the audience at the Palais des Festivals. <PERSON> Booes </PERSON> could be heard from the audience when no one came forward to collect the best actress prize for <PERSON> Streep </PERSON>, who was in town only for the showing of her film on May 13. American actor <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Palance </PERSON>, on stage to help present the award, accepted Streep's prize.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AIDSProtection     05-24 0687</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS Protection,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Regulations Designed to Curb Worker Exposure to AIDS, Hepatitis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government says 5.3 million workers would be better protected from exposure to AIDS, hepatitis and other viruses under new regulations requiring all blood and bodily fluids to be handled as if they were known to be infected. The regulations, proposed Tuesday by the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, were applauded by two unions that represent health-care employees and other workers who would be affected, although one of the unions suggested some minor changes. `` We sincerely hope that the department lives up to its commitment to finalize the standard at the very latest by the end of the year,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employees </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>. In addition to 4.7 million health-care workers, the government said the regulations would protect 600,000 people working in law enforcement, fire and rescue squads, corrections facilities, research laboratories, blood banks and the funeral industry. The regulations would require employers to study any procedures which could expose workers to blood or other potentially infectious materials, identify workers who perform such tasks, and take appropriate steps to reduce the risk of exposure, including a written infection control plan and use of protective clothing. The department's <ORGANIZATION> Occupational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> estimated that the regulations would prevent about 10,000 infections and 200 deaths a year among health-care workers. They would replace general <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> safety requirements for handling and disposal of potentially contaminated items with measures designed to deal specifically with AIDS, hepatitis and other diseases carried by blood and bodily fluids. Preliminary <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> estimates put the average annual cost of complying with the regulations at $ 1,373 apiece for the approximately 600,000 workplaces affected, ranging from $ 32,875 for a hospital to $ 141 for funeral service establishments. A hospital industry group, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said its staff was reviewing the proposal and had no immediate comment. If unchanged after a period of public comment, the regulations would require: _ That all blood and certain bodily fluids be handled as if they were infected with the AIDS-producing human immunodeficiency virus, or HIV, the hepatitis B virus and other blood-borne viruses _ A number of controls for disposal of potentially infectious materials, including leak-proof, puncture-resistant and clearly labeled containers for the disposal of needles and other potentially infectious materials _ Clear labeling and signs in areas where potentially infectious materials are handled or stored _ Employers to offer free hepatitis B vaccines to workers who on average are exposed to potentially infectious fluids once or more a month That represents a shift from the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, which during early consideration of the regulations opposed forcing employers to pay for the costly vaccine. _ Employers to provide, and employees subjected to possible exposure to infectious materials to wear, protective clothing One of labor's complaints was language allowing that provision to be ignored if donning protective clothing `` would interfere with the proper delivery of health care of public safety situations.'' <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> <PERSON> Barab </PERSON>, occupational safety and health director for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> and Municipal Employees, said labor supported allowing workers to decide to proceed without protective clothing in life-threatening situations. But <PERSON> Barab </PERSON> said the language in the proposed regulations was too vague and did not specify whether such a decision should rest with an employee or employer. Labor's second concern was that the regulations did not contain language, often found in new <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> regulations, requiring employers to make engineering improvements to reduce potential hazards. Such improvements, which often include development of new machines and techniques of handling potentially hazardous marterials, are considered more foolproof than requiring protective clothing. A draft of the regulations released in January required improved engineering controls where possible. `` The proposal has been seriously weakened,'' said <ORGANIZATION> AFSCME </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> McEntee </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> estimated workplace exposure results in 6,000 to 7,400 hepatitis B infections each year in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, causing up to 400 hospitalizations and between 130 and 165 deaths. The agency said it did not have such estimates for HIV exposure, but said fewer workers were exposed to the AIDS-producing virus than were exposed to hepatitis.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0030EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Noriega-Mentors     05-24 0173</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Noriega-Mentors,160</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING to correct cycle designator</HEAD>
<HEAD>Manuel's Manual Praises Genghis Khan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Mongolian marauder <PERSON> Genghis </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON> should be praised as the father of psychological warfare, <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> wrote in a 1975 primer on techniques of manipulating the masses. `` He, better than anyone, employed the technique of the rumor ... and with it assured the conquest of half the world with only a handful of men,'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> wrote about the 12th century warrior in an 80-page treatise called `` Psychological Operations.'' The manual, obtained by the <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, was the subject of a story in the newspaper's Wednesday editions. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s de facto ruler wrote the book while he was a lieutenant colonel in charge of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s military intelligence service. The book quotes such diverse thinkers as <PERSON> Aristotle </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sigmund </PERSON> <PERSON> Freud </PERSON>, and expresses admiration for such figures as <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Zedong </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ho </PERSON> <PERSON> Chi </PERSON> <PERSON> Minh </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>. The manual, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, develops <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s theory of a malleable and easily exploited `` mass man.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SirhanParole 4thLd-Writethru a0779 05-24 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sirhan Parole, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0779,0701</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Sirhan Sirhan Denied Parole in Kennedy Slaying</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDs: UPDATES throughout with quotes, details on hearing, Sirhan eligible
for another hearing in one year; no pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVE WILSTEIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SOLEDAD, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON>, serving life in prison for assassinating Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, was denied parole for the 10th time Tuesday despite saying he felt `` very remorseful'' about the slaying. The state <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Terms </ORGANIZATION> made its decision after deliberating for nearly an hour, saying <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON> was unsuitable for parole and calling <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s 1968 murder one of the most shocking crimes in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history. `` You still constitute a danger to society,'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, chairman of the three-member panel, told <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON>, who will be eligible for parole again in a year. In denying <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON>'s release, the board cited his unstable social history and `` selective memory'' of the June 5, 1968 slaying and events leading to it. The board also told <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON> they wanted him to complete a more extensive psychiatric evaluation. <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON>, 45, showed no visible reaction to the decision, but expressed his frustration at a news conference after the hearing. `` Oftentimes I feel like a dog at the dog races. When the race is on, he's always chasing the rabbit ... whatever I do is not enough,'' said <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON>, who called the panel's reasons for denying parole `` specious at best.'' During the four-hour hearing at the State Correctional Training Facility in this small community about 180 miles south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON> told the prison board he was sorry for <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s death The senator from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> was shot with a .22 - caliber pistol as he walked through the kitchen of the Ambassador Hotel in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> shortly after winning the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Democratic presidential `` I feel very sad, very sorry, very remorseful ... that a human life was taken,'' <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON>, dressed in prison-issue blue denim shirt and jeans, told the board. `` After 21 years ... I have become quite convinced that my act was very wrong, morally and humanly, toward <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, and especially toward his family and his loved ones and his suporters. `` I realize the mistake of it and I wish from the bottom of my heart ... that this crime, this horrible event, never occurred. `` I feel 21 years of this type of prison has been plenty of punishment,'' he said. `` I wish I could reverse it and undo it but I ca n't.'' <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON>, a Jerusalem-born <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> Arab </PERSON>, was sentenced to death for <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s murder but was spared the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Quentin </LOCATION> gas chamber after <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s death penalty law was overturned in 1972 by the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. His sentence was changed to life in prison with possibility of parole, and <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON> faced his first parole hearing in 1975. He is imprisoned at the State Correctional Training Facility. <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON> last came before the board two years ago. At the time, the panel recommended he undergo extensive psychiatric evaluation, pursue vocational training, attend Alcoholics Anonymous sessions, remain free of disciplinary problems, earn an associate's degree and provide documentation of job offers. `` The American system of justice is going to let me go home in a coffin,'' an angry <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON> said then. On Tuesday, <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON> and his attorney, <PERSON> Luke </PERSON> <PERSON> McKissack </PERSON>, asked that the hearing be postponed so <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON> could complete the psychiatric evaluation, which began in March. <PERSON> McKissack </PERSON>, who engaged in frequent shouting matches with board members, argued they should disqualify themselves as prejudiced against <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON> because they had taken part in a previous hearing. The board, however, denied his requests to postpone the hearing and disqualify themselves. <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON>, who cried out, `` I did it for my country'' seconds after the shooting, told television interviewer <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Frost </PERSON> in February that he acted not `` out of personal malice towards the man but out of concern for other people.'' He compared his act to a Jew killing <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON> apparently was angered after <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, a staunch supporter of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, repeated his proposal that 50 Phantom jets be shipped to the Jewish state. During the interview, <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON> repeatedly apologized for the killing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0208EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CathedralStones     05-24 0538</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cathedral Stones,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Great Gothic Church Finally Nearing Completion</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Cathedral, the `` great church for national purposes'' that <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> L'Enfant </PERSON> dreamed of as part of his plan for the nation's capital, is at last nearing completion. Signaling the beginning of the final phase of construction, a flatbed truck pulled up in front of the 14th century Gothic-style structure Tuesday with one last load of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> limestone. The first load was delivered in 1910. The ceremonial placing of the final stone is scheduled for Sept. 29, 1990 - 83 years to the day from the laying of the cornerstone in 1907. But most of the heavy work will have been completed by this fall, said <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Feller </PERSON>, canon clerk of the works, or head of construction for the cathedral. `` This is a great day,'' said the Rt. Rev. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, <PERSON> Episcopal </PERSON> bishop of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` It's been a labor of love,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cleland </PERSON>, master mason, who has worked on the project since 1953. L'Enfant, the man commissioned by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON> to lay out the capital on the <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION>, included the church in his plans, but no steps were taken to build it until a group of citizens took up the project in the 1890s. Work has continued with few interruptions since 1907. Construction was halted during World War I and World War II and because of a shortage of funds in the 1970s. But 83 years is by no means a long time for building such an edifice, said the Rev. <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON>, communications director at the cathedral. `` This is about middle range for building a cathedral,'' <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> said. `` A shorty might take 50 or 60 years. Some of them go 150 years or more without having been finished.'' `` A modern building, you put up a steel frame and put things around it, but that's not the way this was built,'' he said. `` This was built physically in the same manner that they were built in the Middle Ages.'' That is, he said, `` stone on stone.'' <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Segreti </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Segreti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tepper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Architects </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> firm overseeing the job, said, `` There's quite a difference working on this project and on a specification office building downtown. This type of construction you do n't see in this day and age.'' The first section, <LOCATION> Bethlehem </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chapel </LOCATION>, was completed in 1912; the central tower was finished in 1964, and the nave was ready for the nation's bicentennial in 1976. The cathedral was the setting for the funeral of President <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> in 1969 and a national memorial service for President <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> in 1972. It is the final resting place of <PERSON> Woodrow </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> preached his last Sunday sermon there, three days before he was murdered. Each year, about 350,000 people visit the unfinished house of worship, the sixth largest cathedral in the world. It is a tenth of a mile long and 289 feet wide at its widest point. The stones from <ORGANIZATION> Bybee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Bloomington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, which has supplied the cathedral for about 10 years, weigh from 150 to 450 pounds. There were other suppliers before <PERSON> Bybee </PERSON>, but all the limestone has come from <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0205EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     05-24 0357</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0371</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>POCATELLO, Idaho (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Governors get all kinds of mail, but the postcard from a climbers' base camp on <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Everest </LOCATION> was a new twist for Gov. <PERSON> Cecil </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrus </PERSON>. Climber <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Whittaker </PERSON>, one of three <LOCATION> Pocatello </LOCATION> residents in a party trying to scale the world's highest peak, advised the governor the trek is going well `` despite high winds.'' `` I'm having a blast,'' <PERSON> Whittaker </PERSON> said in the missive from the 23,500-foot base camp in <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION>. `` It's still a long way to the top, but there are no complaints.'' Before <PERSON> Whittaker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kellie </PERSON> <PERSON> Rhoads </PERSON>, all graduates of <ORGANIZATION> Idaho </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, left for the climb, <PERSON> Andrus </PERSON> gave them an <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> state flag to plant at the summit. <PERSON> Whittaker </PERSON> said two members of the party had already recovered from flu.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Most U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> customers realize it's going to take a few days for their mail to reach its destination, but some <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> residents believe 23 days between pickups is a bit much Mortgage payments, parking ticket fines and `` a whole stack of Mother's Day cards'' on Tuesday came tumbling from an overstuffed mailbox that apparently had n't been emptied for more than three weeks, said Rep. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N </LOCATION>. The congressman's staff looked into the problem after constituents complained they were receiving past due notices for things they knew they had paid. <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON> said all but one of the post cards his staff members mailed from mailboxes in the <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION> neighborhood to his <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> office arrived, enabling them to pinpoint the forgotten mailbox. Four hundred pieces of mail were retrieved from the box, including some stamped with the date by a postage meter. `` There was a whole stack of Mothers' Day cards,'' he said. `` I guess some mothers are wondering why they were forgotten.'' The congressman said he asked the local postmaster to write a letter that people who might have incurred late payment penalties could send to their creditors. They were also considering marking the mail as delayed, although, <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON> said, `` They do n't have a stamp that says, ` Oops, We forgot your mailbox existed.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TankerSpill-Bell 1stLd-Writethru a0769 05-24 0407</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tanker Spill-Bell, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0769,0417</SECOND>
<HEAD>Exxon Names Griffin Bell To Investigate Spill</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES throughout with more Bell comment, other details, Alaska
hiring law school professor. A version also moved on the financial wire
as AM-Exxon-Bell.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney General <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> B. Bell has been named by a special <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> legal committee to head an investigation into the Alaskan oil spill, according to published reports. <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>'s task will be to try to determine responsibility for the nation's worst oil spill and recommend to <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s board whether lawsuits should be filed against former or current <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> officials, the Wall Street Journal reported Tuesday. `` I'm going to interview everyone who knows anything about the spill,'' the Journal quoted <PERSON> Bell </PERSON> as saying. `` It will be very exciting and very challenging,'' he said in an interview published Wednesday in the <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> Journal-Constitution. `` We're going to get to the bottom of everything ... to make an investigation of everything and -LRB- make a recommendation -RRB- as to what ought to be done for the best interest of the shareholders.'' <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>'s investigation is expected to begin in about three weeks and include questioning of <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rawl </PERSON>, who said he would cooperate. <PERSON> Bell </PERSON> said up to eight lawyers could eventually be involved in the probe. The tanker Exxon Valdez ran aground on March 24 and spilled 10.9 million gallons of oil into <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> says it has spent nearly $ 100 million trying to clean up the oil that has stained hundreds of miles of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s southern coastline and killed thousands of animals. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s board set up the three-member committee of outside directors after receiving letters from shareholders' attorneys calling for such a probe. <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>, who was attorney general in President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s admininstration, in 1985 conducted a similar inquiry into a check-kiting scandal at <ORGANIZATION> E.F. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hutton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Co.. <PERSON> Bell </PERSON> found that senior managers were n't <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON> eventually pleaded guilty to 2,000 counts of check-kiting and agreed to pay $ 2.75 million in fines and legal fees. In other legal preparations, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> has hired a prominent <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> law professor to help represent the state in its expected lawsuit against <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schoenbaum </PERSON>, director of the university's <ORGANIZATION> Dean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rusk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION>, joins the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> attorney general's office and a an Alaskan law firm <PERSON> Schoenbaum </PERSON> said he was hired about 10 days ago and will travel to <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> in about two weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890524-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-24-89 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Khomeini-Successor Bjt   05-24 0765</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Khomeini-Successor, Bjt,0791</SECOND>
<HEAD>Khomeini's Illness Underlines Iran's Leadership Problem</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED BLANCHE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
