<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 2323EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Bush-DrugPenalties 4thLd-Writethru a0709 08-30 0992</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Drug Penalties, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0709,940</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quarter-Million Aid Program Eyed for Andean Drug Strategy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>EDS: INSERTS two grafs after 16th pvs, In addition ..., to give
published report that strategy will focus resources on middle-level traffickers;
EDITS to tighten. ^By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The drug control strategy President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will present next week will call for $ 250 million to $ 260 million in economic and military aid for the three principal cocaine producing countries _ <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION> _ an administration source said Wednesday. Earlier, sources had said that aid figure could hit $ 300 million, and national security adviser <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON> indicated Tuesday that the figure would be even higher than that. When asked about the reported $ 300 million figure for the Andean countries, <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON> said, `` That figure, I think you can assume, has already been increased by the fact that we have given <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> $ 65 million'' to help it fight the `` total war'' declared by the drug traffickers there. However, the $ 65 million is coming out of a discretionary fund available for fiscal 1989, which ends Sept. 30. The strategy covers fiscal 1990. Scowcroft had not intended to add the $ 65 million onto next year's budget, said the source, who spoke on condition of anonymity. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> met with his top lieutenants in the drug war Tuesday at his vacation home in <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, to discuss the strategy, but sources said Wednesday that the focus of the meeting was <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, not the strategy, and that no specific decisions were made on changing plans for future aid to that country. `` The fundamental issues of the strategy, <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION> did not change,'' one of the sources said, noting that the final strategy had gone to the printer before the meeting took place. The source declined to be named publicly. <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> has suffered numerous bombings by drug traffickers since Colombian President <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> imposed emergency regulations 1 -LCB- weeks ago that allow for the immediate resumption of extraditions of alleged drug traffickers to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for trial. Last Friday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> announced the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would give <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> $ 65 million in military equipment such as helicopters, in addition to some $ 2.5 million for protection for the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> judiciary that had been promised previously. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last year set aside $ 5 million for such protection. Colombian Justice Minister <PERSON> Monica </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Greiff </PERSON> asked Tuesday for $ 19 million in aid for judicial protection. Mrs. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Greiff </PERSON> met for about 40 minutes Wednesday with <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> who developed the draft strategy, said <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>. `` She expressed appreciation for what the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was doing and they agreed this was not a problem that was going to be solved quickly,'' <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> said. `` She said that the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> government was in it for the long haul and that she certainly hoped the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would continue its support.'' <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> would not comment on the report that the strategy called for a total of some $ 250 million to $ 260 million for <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION>. Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, on Wednesday proposed a plan to create `` debt-for-drugs'' swaps to help reduce coca cultivation. The plan calls for trading debt relief to governments in coca-producing nations in exchange for their commitments to fund specific crop substitution and coca eradication programs. <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION> are the chief coca-growing countries, while <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> is the main cocaine trafficking country, exporting about 80 percent of the world's cocaine. The drug strategy, meanwhile, will urge states to impose tough laws against drug users, but wo n't threaten to withhold highway funds from those states that fail to do so, as the draft strategy had proposed, an administration source said Wednesday. In addition, a proposed $ 25 million <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, to be run jointly by the <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, was eliminated from the strategy due to a last-minute bid by the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to develop a money-laundering intelligence center and combine all the elements, the source said. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> objected to the sudden change of plans. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, quoting <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> sources in its Thursday editions, reported that the plan will focus on arresting middle-level figures like pilots, couriers and money handlers. Although the government has been trying for years to identify and arrest middle-level workers, it has not concentrated resources in this area, the Times said. The officials said the effort would be a major change from the current emphasis on going after the leaders of international drug organizations, by trying to seize drugs at the border and by eradicating coca leaf cultivation. However, most of the elements included in the draft strategy _ the emphasis on targeting drug abusers who fuel the drug traffic, the hiking of funds for drug treatment by 49 percent and the need for massively increased aid to the Andean countries _ remain the same as proposed originally by <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, the source said. In <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION> on Wednesday, the vacation White House press office announced that a new program allowing judges to strip student loans and other federal benefits from drug offenders starts Friday. The vacationing President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sent <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> a report on Wednesday spelling out how the penalties will work in both state and federal courts. Those convicted of drug trafficking or possession can be denied federal grants, student loans, contracts, and professional and commercial licenses, but not welfare, disability or Social Security benefits. The decision to deny any or all of an individual's benefits rests solely with the sentencing judge, except for those convicted of a third drug trafficking offense. For them, permanent denial of the benefits is mandatory. The penalties can be applied to convictions occurring after Friday for offenses occurring on or after Nov. 18, 1988. Next Tuesday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will go on radio and television to describe his new national drug strategy that is expected to stiffen penalties for individual users.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 2324EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China-Economy     08-30 0426</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Economy,0436</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Acts To Reassert Controls Over Economy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM ABRAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The official press reported Thursday that the government is taking new steps to re-establish order in an economy reeling from speculation and profiteering in scarce materials and widespread tax evasion. The steps include measures to reassert controls over the distribution and pricing of raw materials such as coal and steel, the reports said. The state will also begin a campaign against what it says is rampant tax evasion among <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s 14.5 million privately owned enterprises, the <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> reported. <PERSON> Xie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mingan </PERSON>, an official of the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Materials </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Equipment </ORGANIZATION>, said the state will tighten controls on prices of some raw materials such as coal, rolled steel and non-ferrous metals. He said redundant middlemen will be eliminated, illegal dealers and officials trading power for money will be disciplined and state supplies of materials to production enterprises will be maintained. One aspect of the economic reforms _ decentralization of controls over raw materials _ has led to hoarding, speculation and price-gouging. Middlemen, often with links to influential party and government officials, buy up scarce materials at low government-set prices and sell them for huge profits on free markets. <PERSON> Jin </PERSON> <PERSON> Xin </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tax </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, told a conference Wednesday that if the problem of tax evasion among private businessmen goes unsolved, `` it will certainly sap the morale of the dominant working classes and bring adverse effects on the enthusiasm of intellectuals.'' <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s conservative leadership has singled out private entrepreneurs as an example of unhealthy disparities in income levels. Many private businessmen, some operating from simple street stalls, earn more in a day than a worker or teacher makes in a month. A young worker earns about $ 27 a month. <PERSON> Jin </PERSON> said the state was not trying to add to the financial burdens of private businessmen, who have been a stimulus in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s economic growth over the past decade. He also promised no change in the preferential terms on taxation for foreign investors in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s parliament, was also told Wednesday that more than 2,800 companies lost their business licenses and nearly 800 party and government officials were punished after the government began a drive against shady business practices in October The moves come against the backdrop of a return to Marxist orthodoxy in the political sphere following the military crackdown on the pro-democracy movement in June and a general reassessment of the pace of the nation's market-oriented economic reforms.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 2333EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-WayeExecution 3rdLd-Writethru a0766 08-30 0682</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Waye Execution, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0766,0697</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Inmate Put to Death in Virginia's Electric Chair</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 3 grafs to UPDATE with Waye's final statement; picks
up 3rd graf: `Waye went ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BILL BASKERVILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RICHMOND, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man convicted of the 1977 rape and murder of a 61-year-old woman was executed Wednesday night in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s electric chair <PERSON> Alton </PERSON> <PERSON> Waye </PERSON>, 34, was pronounced dead at 11:05 p.m. after receiving two 55-second jolts of nearly 2,500 volts of electricity, said <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrar </PERSON>. `` I would express that what is about to take place is a murder,'' <PERSON> Waye </PERSON> said in a final statement. `` I do n't hate anyone. I forgive everyone involved.'' <PERSON> Waye </PERSON> went to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> earlier Wednesday seeking a stay of execution, but the high court refused by a 7-2 vote to postpone the execution and to consider his case on appeal. <PERSON> Waye </PERSON>, a former textile worker, also was denied clemency earlier Wednesday by Gov. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baliles </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> has said <PERSON> Waye </PERSON> should not be executed because he is borderline mentally retarded. <PERSON> Baliles </PERSON> has received 638 letters opposing the execution, largely due to a letter campaign urged by the human rights group. <PERSON> Baliles </PERSON>, in letters Wednesday to <PERSON> Waye </PERSON>'s attorneys, said he had reviewed <PERSON> Waye </PERSON>'s case and `` I am not persuaded that the governor's power of executive clemency should be exercised in this matter. <PERSON> Waye </PERSON> received communion of bread and juice Wednesday night from a boyhood schoolmate, the Rev. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>, and the Revs. <PERSON> Russ </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> and <PERSON> A.C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Epps </PERSON>. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Coble </PERSON>, operations officer at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Penitentiary </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Waye </PERSON> was baptized Tuesday night. `` He said to tell the people, ` I am blessed,''' <PERSON> Coble </PERSON> said. `` He's relying on his religious faith at this time,'' <PERSON> Coble </PERSON> said. `` He's savoring the time he has with his family.'' <PERSON> Waye </PERSON>'s mother, brother, two sisters and other relatives visited him Wednesday. <PERSON> Waye </PERSON> was the eighth person to die in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s electric chair since the state reinstituted the death penalty in 1977, and the 117th executed in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> since the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s 1976 allowing reinstatement of capital punishment. Earlier Wednesday, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Merhige </PERSON> denied a stay of execution based on claims of <PERSON> Waye </PERSON>'s diminished mental capacity. Monday he denied a stay on claims that the trial jury was given faulty instructions. <PERSON> Merhige </PERSON>'s rulings were upheld Wednesday afternoon by a three-judge panel of the 4th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>, which heard arguments via conference call, said <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Rohrer </PERSON>, a spokesman for Attorney General <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Terry </PERSON>. <PERSON> Waye </PERSON>'s attorneys contended the condemned man should be spared the death penalty because of new evidence showing he has `` a very seriously damaged brain.'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Burr </PERSON>, a lawyer from the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> Legal and Educational Defense Fund in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, told the appeals panel <PERSON> Waye </PERSON> was deprived of an adequate psyciatric evaluation when he was tried in 1978. He also said <PERSON> Waye </PERSON>'s previous attorneys failed to adequately investigate <PERSON> Waye </PERSON>'s psychiatric condition. Deputy Attorney General <PERSON> Linwood </PERSON> <PERSON> Wells </PERSON> argued that the defense was legally barred from raising such objections, which should have been raised at trial or in earlier appeals. <PERSON> Waye </PERSON> was convicted of the Oct. 14, 1977, rape and murder of <PERSON> Lavergne </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>, whose nude body was found in a bathtub. Her face was beaten beyond recognition, and she had been stabbed 42 times with a butcher knife. The killer had poured laundry bleach on the body. Shortly after the killing, a man who identified himself as <PERSON> Waye </PERSON> called police to tell them he had killed a woman, according to trial testimony. Police picked up <PERSON> Waye </PERSON> at his home and said he led them to the farm house where Mrs. <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> lived alone. <PERSON> Waye </PERSON>'s court-appointed attorney, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wellons </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Victoria </LOCATION>, did not dispute that <PERSON> Waye </PERSON> committed the crime. However, he pleaded for a verdict on a lesser charge than capital murder. <PERSON> Waye </PERSON> could be the last person executed in <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>. The State Penitentiary is scheduled to close by June 30, 1990, and the electric chair will be moved to a new prison in <LOCATION> Greensville </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 2349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TropicalWeather     08-30 0177</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tropical Weather,0180</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tropical Storm Gabrielle Forms Off Cape Verde</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tropical Storm <PERSON> Gabrielle </PERSON> formed late Wednesday off the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> African </LOCATION> coast with top winds of 40 mph, becoming the seventh named storm of the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> hurricane season, forecasters said. At 10:30 p.m. EDT, the center of <PERSON> Gabrielle </PERSON> was near latitude 11.0 north and longitude 25.8 west, or about 435 miles southwest of the <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Verde </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>. The storm, heading west at 20 mph, was expected to strengthen over the next day, according to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in suburban <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION>. The storm formed less than a day after its predecessor, <PERSON> Felix </PERSON>, dwindled to a tropical depression. It carried winds of 30 mph Wednesday night and was centered about 920 miles south of the westernmost <LOCATION> Azores </LOCATION> in the north <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>. A depression becomes a tropical storm when its winds reach 39 mph. A tropical storm becomes a hurricane once its winds hit 74 mph. There have been three hurricanes so far during the hurricane season, which runs from June 1 to Nov. 30.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-NJDisturbance     08-30 0622</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-NJ Disturbance,0640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Funeral Service For Slain Man, TV Crew Attacked In Aftermath of Rioting</HEAD>
<HEAD>Laserphoto PX5</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MELANIE BURNEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEWFIELD, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Funeral services were held Wednesday for a black man whose shooting death by police sparked two days of rioting and looting in <LOCATION> Vineland </LOCATION> while a special panel convened on how to calm racial tensions. Community leaders had hoped the unrest following the Sunday night shooting had subsided, but four people were arrested Wednesday, including a man who scuffled with a television news crew, said <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Tofanelli </PERSON>, a city spokesman. The WPVI-TV news crew from <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> was attacked by a group of youths as they interviewed people in downtown <LOCATION> Vineland </LOCATION>, where rioting and looting broke out Monday night, <PERSON> Tofanelli </PERSON> said. News reporter <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> was listed in stable condition at <ORGANIZATION> Newcomb </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Vineland </LOCATION> with a broken nose and facial injuries, hospital officials said. A cameraman and sound technician were treated for minor injuries and discharged. `` I feel no animosity toward those youngsters out there,'' <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> said in a telehone interview. `` There is a lot of frustration ... a lot of anger here.'' <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON>'s wallet and some television equipment were stolen. The equipment was returned later, <PERSON> Tofanelli </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON>, 23, was arrested on assault and robbery charges, <PERSON> Tofanelli </PERSON> said, and three other people were arrested in a separate incident when they disobeyed police orders to leave the area. The charges were not available. About 200 people packed into <ORGANIZATION> Truth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Newfield </LOCATION> for a two-hour ceremony in remembrance of 26-year-old <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, who was shot and killed by <LOCATION> Vineland </LOCATION> police on Sunday. Mayor <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Curley </PERSON> met with community leaders and announced the formation of an eight-member special task force to find ways of restoring calm to the city. `` We're hoping this will be the first step,'' <PERSON> Curley </PERSON> said at an informal press conference at his City Hall office. `` We're hoping that we can be assured there wo n't be any more outbreaks.'' <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, president of the local chapter of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Colored People, thought the unrest would end with the memorial service. `` They're grieving, but I do n't think it's going to be a destructive type of thing,'' <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said. Mourners gathered outside the small white church in <LOCATION> Newfield </LOCATION>, about several miles north of <LOCATION> Vineland </LOCATION>, as the coffee-colored casket containing <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' body was led to a black hearse. They raised clenched fists in a symbol of black power as a choir sang `` Oh How I Love Jesus.'' <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' body was taken to a funeral home and then to the state medical examiner's office in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION> for a second autopsy. An initial autopsy was performed Monday by the county coroner. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, a father of two children, was shot after he allegedly threatened officer <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Letizia </PERSON> with a steel rod, said police Chief <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Cassisi </PERSON>. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, who was wanted on drug and weapons charges, was spotted by officers after police received an anonymous telephone call about a man on a bicycle carrying drugs, <PERSON> Cassisi </PERSON> said. After being told he was under arrest, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> picked up the rod and approached <PERSON> Letizia </PERSON>, swinging, <PERSON> Cassisi </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Letizia </PERSON>, who is white, fired two shots at <ORGANIZATION> Williams </ORGANIZATION>, hitting him both times, the police chief said. <PERSON> Curley </PERSON> said <PERSON> Letizia </PERSON> has been taken off street duty and put on special assignment. The mayor said he did not plan to follow the demands of some blacks who want <PERSON> Letizia </PERSON> suspended without pay pending the outcome of an investigation by the state Attorney General's office. <PERSON> Curley </PERSON> said the task force would review the police department's relationship with the mostly minority community as well as the handling of citizen complaints He said a report was expected in about 30 days.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 0000EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-HomicideRate 1stLd-Writethru a0405 08-30 0239</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Homicide Rate, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0405,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>EDS: Subs grafs 2 and 3 to CORRECT time element from Monday to Tuesday</HEAD>
<HEAD>Record Killing Pace Surpasses 300 in Nation's Capital</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Killings in the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, continuing at a record pace that police say is largely driven by a burgeoning drug trade, has passed the 300 mark for the year. The city's 300th homicide victim, recorded early Tuesday, was a suburban <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> man gunned down in a northwest <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> drug market, police said. At least 10 people were shot or stabbed in the city Tuesday, police said, and three died. One woman was seriously injured by a stray bullet as she stood outside her northest <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> home. The deaths bring the district's 1989 homicide count to 301, compared to 216 at this time last year. The city's homicide record of 372 was set last year. Police say about 60 percent of the city's killings are related to drugs. Drug-related violence has also hiked the murder rate in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s suburbs, according to police. Twelve people have been killed so far this year in <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, compared to nine at this time last year. In Prince <PERSON> George </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, 77 people have been killed this year, compared to 53 at this time in 1988. <LOCATION> Fairfax </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, has had 19 killings this year, compared to 12 last year, and <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, has eight compared to three last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 0001EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     08-30 0554</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0576</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> officials are hoping to boost tourism by telling <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Belt </LOCATION> residents that summers are better in the Sweat Belt. The <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Travel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> plans to spend $ 250,000 on advertising in cities along <LOCATION> Interstate </LOCATION> <LOCATION> 75 </LOCATION>, which ends in southern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, spokeswoman <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON> said. The ads will target <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, she said. `` We know there are a lot of Floridians who went to school in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, worked in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, have family in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. They're our main target,'' bureau director <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Savich </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` If we can get the average Floridian who by July has had months of hot, muggy weather, we'll be happy to get them, too,'' he said. Tourism is <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>'s second-largest industry following manufacturing, worth $ 16 billion a year. Most tourists come from the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> region, though. <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> wants to become a national tourism draw. The ads will use themes like, `` Come up to the cool <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> summers,'' <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON> said. The campaign also will stress festivals, golfing and other outdoor activities, she said. `` We referred to it as the Sweat Belt'' in brain-storming sessions, <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Raphael </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcucci </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> said he was n't worried about the competition. `` A beach on a <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>'' is n't the same as one on the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> or the Gulf of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, he said in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ROCK FALLS, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Call it the `` wheel of misfortune.'' That's what a woman feels about the popular television game show after receiving prizes she says were used, filthy and damaged. `` I just wanted to go on ` Wheel of Fortune' and have a good time,'' said <PERSON> Debra </PERSON> <PERSON> Stuker </PERSON>, 30, who appeared on the show 15 months ago. `` And I did have a good time _ it was a lot of fun. `` Now, all the problems have kind of ruined it.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Stuker </PERSON> said her winnings included a $ 4,200 jukebox that arrived at her northern <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> home used, dirty and with parts missing. She also said the sparkling $ 10,000 blue canopied dinghy she picked out turned up with a broken windshield, cracks in the fiberglass, splotches of tar on the hull and dirty, torn upholstery. A representative of the <PERSON> Merv </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> Enterprises show said officials are working on the complaints. The representative declined to give her name. Mrs. <PERSON> Stuker </PERSON> was the show's big winner for two days, garnering $ 36,829 worth of prizes including a Jeep, a sailboat, a small motorboat, artwork, sportswear and sporting equipment. She and her husband, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>, forfeited some items they did n't want, but still got hit for $ 1,300 in federal and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> state taxes on the prizes `` We got the Jeep, and it was nice _ we traded it in for a van,'' <PERSON> Stuker </PERSON> said. `` We got the TV and the VCR and some other nice things.'' But then the jukebox and the boat arrived. The couple's lawyer, <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, has a file of letters indicating the Stukers' repeated attempts to have the problem corrected. The Stukers refused the game show's offer of $ 2,500 in cash in lieu of the $ 4,200 jukebox. The show took back the boat but has n't offered a replacement `` We do n't want to be greedy but anybody in their right mind would want this stuff if they had it coming to them,'' <PERSON> Stuker </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 0534EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--OilSpill     08-30 0166</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Oil Spill,0168</SECOND>
<HEAD>Last Rhode Island Beach Closed by June Oil Spill Reopening</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PROVIDENCE, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The last <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> beach closed by an oil spill in June was prepared for reopening today as state crews plowed oil-soaked sand. Mackerel Cove in <LOCATION> Jamestown </LOCATION> had been closed since the June 23 accident involving the Greek tanker World Prodigy. The tanker spilled about 300,000 gallons of home heating oil into <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sound </LOCATION> when it ran aground at <LOCATION> Brenton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reef </LOCATION>, about a mile south of <LOCATION> Newport </LOCATION> and five miles from Mackerel Cove. The spill caused most <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> beaches to be closed about a week, but Mackerel Cove, the hardest-hit of the beaches, remained closed because oil had soaked into the sand. State environmental workers have been harrowing the sand to expose the oil to air so it can evaporate. The department decided to bulldoze the rest of the contaminated sand instead of turning it because it is now a manageable amount, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Fran </PERSON> <PERSON> Segerson </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FishermanBush     08-30 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fisherman Bush,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Fish 14, President Bush 0</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KENNEBUNKPORT, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The vacation was 14 days old and the standings were: Fish-14, President Bush-0. The presidential patience appeared to be wearing thin. Sure he was worried about the drug lords in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> and the civil war in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. But the other thing bugging <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as he relaxed on the coast of <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> was why the heck could n't he catch a fish. Despite daily excursions in his speedboat <ORGANIZATION> Fidelity </ORGANIZATION> _ sometimes twice daily _ to ply the ocean off his seaside home, the president failed to reel one in. He tried all kinds of lures and a variety of fishing partners _ from grandchildren to visiting dignitaries _ but still came up with an empty line. He canceled an afternoon of golf Sunday in favor of a fishing jaunt, and on Monday morning decided to forgo his 6:30 a.m. jog to try again. On the advice of longtime fishing buddy <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Boilard </PERSON> the president even ordered the <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> to keep extraneous boats, including the small flotilla of press chase boats, 500 feet away on the theory that the vessels might be scaring off the fish. Still no luck. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> tried not to show dismay, and <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> claimed the president was n't bothered a bit. But there were signs it was getting to be something of a sore subject. `` The fishing's been lousy,'' he confided to reporters at the end of the first fishless week. `` I fish every single day and have n't got one. Eventually there were inklings of a Hemingwayesque obsession, as he talked of having a `` rendezvous with bluefish.'' He laid down a decree: `` I guarantee there will be fish caught.'' When he learned that an 18-pounder was caught off one of the TV crew boats tailing <ORGANIZATION> Fidelity </ORGANIZATION>, he could barely contain his envy. `` Eighteen pound bluefish?'' he repeated several times. `` Out there with us? There's no justice here. That's just not fair.'' Meanwhile, word was spreading fast about the fishless vacation. The <ORGANIZATION> Portland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> came out with a front page graphic called Fish Watch, featuring a picture of a circled fish with a line drawn across it and the statistics on how many days <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has fished without a catch. When <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> piloted his boat into town one day, a local fisherman gave him a large fish, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> grudgingly agreed with the press corps that this seemed the only way he could hook one. Evangelist <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s weekend house guest, told a local church congregation the president took him along on a fishing trip as a <PERSON> Jonah </PERSON>, a reference to the biblical figure who was swallowed by a whale. The president laughed and nodded when a reporter asked if he would have <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> bless his fishing rods. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has previously espoused a philosophical viewpoint on fish-free vacations, saying the fun was more in the fishing than the catching. But this trip, the situation seemed a bit much to take. By Monday both the president and his staff were trying to put the best face on his bad luck streak. That morning presidential photographer <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> caught six fish on the president's boat and <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> Adviser <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON> caught one that he described by extending his hands about two feet. White House spokesman <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Zanca </PERSON> later said diplomatically, `` Under the president's careful tutelage, the fishing trip was successful ... The fish were caught under his strong leadership.'' When reporters came upon him later at the golf course, the president also took the cheery tack. `` We did it today,'' he said. But when asked if `` we'' meant he too had caught a fish, he quipped, `` I was so busy trying to make General Scowcroft feel at home there ... we did well today.'' By the time Scowcroft finished beating his boss at golf, a game <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has vowed to improve on this vacation, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was directing all questions about golf and fishing to him. `` Brent, they want to talk to you about this. I'm too grumpy,'' he said before darting off in his golf cart.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Shoppers'Advocate Bjt   08-30 0654</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shoppers' Advocate, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Low-Fat, Low-Salt, Low-Cholesterol Pain in the Neck</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LANDOVER, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Shoppers at the biggest supermarket chain in the <LOCATION> Baltimore-Washington </LOCATION> area are accustomed to getting advice from <PERSON> Odonna </PERSON> <PERSON> Mathews </PERSON>, whether they want it or not. She is the consumers' ombudsman, advocate and confidante at <ORGANIZATION> Giant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foods </ORGANIZATION>, and what's good for customers turns out to be good, too, for the prospering chain, the country's 12th largest supermarket company. Twenty thousand times a year, customers write or call Mrs. <PERSON> Mathews </PERSON> to ask for a recipe, to request that stores stock an old familiar brand or to complain about the checkout clerk who put the eggs at the bottom of the bag. When Giant started selling live lobsters, two customers asked for a merciful way to cook the crustaceans. Mrs. <PERSON> Mathews </PERSON> consulted animal rights people, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aquarium </ORGANIZATION> and the fish industry and wrote into a guidebook two alternative methods _ severing the spinal cord or starting out with cool water. The experts said lobsters feel less pain than when they are plunged into boiling water. On Giant's commercials, Mrs. <PERSON> Mathews </PERSON> brims with advice. She tells how to combat cholesterol, compare costs of different brands or opt for healthful snacks -LRB- `` choose pretzels, plain or fruit-filled shredded wheat or matzo.'' -RRB- `` Lower The Fat,'' urges a sign over the stores' meat counters. `` Choose chicken. Remove the skin. Eat more white meat than dark.'' On the shelves, green arrows point out foods that are high in fiber or low in fat and cholesterol. Three ounces of meat in a serving is really enough, Mrs. <PERSON> Mathews </PERSON> advises budget-minded shoppers. `` Slice the meat thinly and fan it out on the plate.'' `` Everyone in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> area can tell you who <PERSON> Odonna </PERSON> is,'' says <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Professionals </ORGANIZATION>, which represents 1,000 firms that employ consumer advisers. `` Not many of them have her kind of recognition.'' The only woman among 22 Giant vice presidents, Mrs. <PERSON> Mathews </PERSON> says she is free `` to openly disagree with company policies when they are not in the consumers' best interest.'' She pestered Giant's bakers until they finally agreed to forswear highly saturated palm and coconut oils in baked goods, except for in whipped toppings _ and she's working on those. `` Some people think I'm a pain in the neck,'' she says. `` If I am, I'm doing my job.'' Another idea came from <ORGANIZATION> Giant </ORGANIZATION>'s consumer board, on which customers volunteer to serve. At their urging, she pressed Giant to create one checkout lane in each store with no candy to tempt kiddies. The chocolate industry protested in vain, she says. In an interview in Giant's nothing-fancy corporate headquarters in a warehouse neighborhood outside <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Mathews </PERSON> spells out her philosophy: `` People are going to eat their hot dogs and their chocolate chips. But choices should be there. Consumers have the right to choose, and they have the right to be informed.'' A native of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, she started as an intern to the company's first consumer adviser, <PERSON> Esther </PERSON> <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON>, who also served as consumer adviser to Presidents <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> `` Giant was ahead of the curve,'' says <PERSON> Guy </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, who analyzes supermarket stocks for <ORGANIZATION> Investment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> `` The industry is just coming around to what <ORGANIZATION> Giant </ORGANIZATION>'s been doing for years.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marketing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> says a third of 164 retailers who took part in a 1987 survey have consumer affairs departments. Forty percent of the consumer advisers report to top management. Analyst <PERSON> Kimberly </PERSON> <PERSON> Walin </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Prudential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bache </ORGANIZATION> notes that what Mrs. <PERSON> Mathews </PERSON> does is also good business. `` The costs are not that high and the goodwill between Giant and the community is great,'' she says. With 147 stores, <ORGANIZATION> Giant </ORGANIZATION> enjoys net profit margins of over 3 percent of sales _ well above the industry average of 0.71 percent. Giant's sales, near $ 3 billion a year, have doubled in eight years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 0122EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CanyonPollution Bjt   08-30 0664</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Canyon Pollution, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Grand Canyon Pollution Pits Federal Agency Against Federal Agency</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two federal agencies contend that a large <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> power plant, partly owned by another government agency, is polluting the skies over the Grand Canyon. But the operator of the plant, one of the nation's largest coal-burning electric facilities, criticizes the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> study. `` We designed and built the Navajo Generating Station to meet all air-quality standards,'' said A.J. `` Jack'' <PERSON> Pfister </PERSON>, general manager of the Salt River Project, which operates the plant near Page, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> `` The plant was located to assure that emissions would blow away from the Grand Canyon,'' he said Tuesday. The controversy pits the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> against the federal <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reclamation </ORGANIZATION>, which owns 24.3 percent of the plant and would be responsible for much of the cost of expensive pollution controls. Costs estimates to control the pollution range from $ 300 million to $ 1 billion. The government has tried for years to determine to what extent the plant, 80 miles from the center of the Grand Canyon, is responsible for the layers of haze and pollution that cloud the skies during certain times of the year. The <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> defends its $ 2 million study tracking the plant's pollution and favors strong curbs. But the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reclamation </ORGANIZATION> sides with plant operators who argue the plant should n't be singled out for expensive pollution controls Both agencies are part of the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Interior Secretary <PERSON> Manual </PERSON> <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON> said Tuesday he was n't prepared to accept the <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> conclusions, suggesting the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> conduct a review. That suggestion was widely seen as giving the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reclamation </ORGANIZATION> the upper hand. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said Tuesday that pollution from the 2,250-megawatt plant `` is a significant contributor to visibility impairment'' at the canyon. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> relied heavily on last year's six-week <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> study, in which plant pollutants were traced using a specially colored chemical. The <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said that during the study, an average 40 percent of the pollution could be traced to the plant, and that the figure reached 70 percent on some days. `` We have substantial evidence that the Navajo Generating Station is a significant contributor to the visibility problem,'' said <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Habicht </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> deputy administrator. `` Action must be taken now to protect the Grand Canyon.'' The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said it would determine by February how sharp a reduction in sulfur dioxide emissions will be required. Curbs could force the plant to install expensive `` scrubbers'' or other technology. <PERSON> Pfister </PERSON> said he would go to court to stop any attempt to require installation of expensive pollution controls. The Salt River Project has put the possible cost as high as $ 1 billion, although other estimates are in the $ 300 million to $ 400 million range. About one-fourth of the bill could be sent to the government because of the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reclamation </ORGANIZATION>'s partial ownership. The agency uses its electricity to pump water from the <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> to an irrigation project in central <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>. The plant burns 24,000 tons of coal a day and releases an estimated 12 tons to 13 tons of sulfur dioxide from its 750-foot smokestacks hourly. Plant operators contend much of the pollution comes from other sources, including the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> freeways, and that a number of studies have shown that the plant is n't responsible for the canyon's visibility problems <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Yuhnke </PERSON>, a lawyer for the Environmental Defense Fund, and other environmentalists say they fear <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> will try to pressure <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON> into seeking only modest emission curbs because of the potential cost to the federal government. In addition to the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, other owners of the plant are the Salt River Project, 22 percent; <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, 14 percent; the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION>, 21 percent; the <ORGANIZATION> Nevada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, 11 percent; and <ORGANIZATION> Tucson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, 8 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HUD-Pierce     08-30 0436</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-HUD-Pierce,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>HUD Kills Project OK'd By Pierce in Final Days</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal housing officials are refusing to fund a project approved over agency officials' objections by former Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> in his final days on the job, a source says. The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> told <ORGANIZATION> One </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> early this month it will not honor <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s decision to fund a project to develop a computerized listing of black entrepreneurs, said a <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> source who spoke Tuesday on the condition of anonymity. One <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, a Maryland-based company owned by a prominent black Republican couple, had requested $ 421,000 for the project. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> approved half of that Jan. 17, three days before he left <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> after heading the agency for eight years. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s approval came despite a 6-1 vote against the proposal by a <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> review committee, which questioned the need for the listing. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> approved the funding through a technical assistance program over which he had authority, including the right to overrule objections from others in the agency. But his action appears at odds with sworn congressional testimony that he took no direct role in funding decisions. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> is scheduled to be the first witness when congressional hearings into influence-peddling, mismanagement and possible fraud at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration resume Sept. 15. <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> can halt the project despite <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s approval because the department never entered into a contract with One <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. `` Since there's no contract, we do n't need a reason to kill it,'' said the source. The One America project had been put on hold by new <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>. Attempts to reach One <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> officials late Tuesday were unsuccessful. The telephone at the company was not answered. The company is owned by <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> and <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>. During the early 1980s, Mrs. <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON> headed a group of black Republicans known as the Council of 100 and also served on a White House commission on small business. <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON> is a former <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official and was the first black to serve on the National Labor Relations Board. Mrs. <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>, in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in July, said she had not received any special treatment from the agency. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> has not returned calls seeking comment. In a recent interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said that getting more blacks involved in <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> programs was one of his greatest achievements at the agency but said politics played no part in his decisions. `` A lot of blacks got business and we certainly did n't ask them were they Republicans, Democrat, liberal or what,'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 0157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugPrices     08-30 0569</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Prices,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prescription Costs Vary</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NANCY BENAC</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A prescription that costs $ 28 in one community could sell for $ 2 in another, according to a private survey of drug prices that found wide variations nationally and even within communities. The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retired </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Persons </ORGANIZATION> said Tuesday that its survey found that prices differed by factors of up to 14-to-1 nationally and that costs typically vary by more than 25 percent from one pharmacy to another in the same town. Even bigger price differences were found between some brand-name medications and their generic substitutes, which on average cost half as much, the <ORGANIZATION> AARP </ORGANIZATION> said. One pharmacy had the city's highest cost, $ 36, for a brand name and the lowest, $ 9.75, for the generic. The findings confirm the wisdom of shopping around, and are especially important for older Americans, who account for 12 percent of the population but use 32 percent of all prescription drugs, <ORGANIZATION> AARP </ORGANIZATION> said. `` It was possible that an older consumer could save more than $ 30 on a single prescription,'' the report said. `` For example, in one community a prescription for Procardia -LRB- heart medication -RRB- sold for $ 26.99 at one pharmacy and for $ 58.60 at another pharmacy in the area.'' The findings also have important implications for government and private health insurance programs, which could hold down spiraling costs by making sure beneficiaries get the lowest-priced medications, <ORGANIZATION> AARP </ORGANIZATION> said. The 42-state survey also looked at services offered by pharmacies and found somewhat higher drug costs at outlets that have special programs such as 24-hour operations, after-hour emergency service, free delivery, patient drug profiles and discounts. `` Since for many older consumers, these services can be as important as cost savings, and since many offered them ` at no additional cost,' consumers should ask about the services and any associated costs,'' the <ORGANIZATION> AARP </ORGANIZATION> said. The group used older volunteers to survey prices at 1,050 pharmacies between September 1987 and September 1988. The resulting study, which did n't identify specific towns or pharmacies, examined price differences among 165 communities on 15 drugs often prescribed to older Americans. While the pharmacies surveyed were not scientifically selected, the true range of prices can not be less than those found in the study, <ORGANIZATION> AARP </ORGANIZATION> said. The report said there were large state-to-state differences in drug costs, with <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> having the highest overall average prices and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> the lowest, but <ORGANIZATION> AARP </ORGANIZATION> could not immediately provide actual figures for the states. There were big differences within states as well. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, for example, the price for Dyazide, a medication for high blood pressure and extra fluid in the body, varied from $ 20 to $ 45 in six communities. In <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, one pharmacy had an average price of $ 15.88 for certain drugs surveyed while another had an average of $ 31.36. Drugs included in the survey were: Dyazide; <LOCATION> Procardia </LOCATION>; Slow-K and its generic, potassium chloride TR, used to treat the need for more potassium; Hydrodiuril and its generic, hydrochlorothiazide, for high blood pressure and extra fluid in the body; Isordil and its generic, isosorbide, for chest pain; Cardizem, chest pain; Lasix, and its generic, furosemide, for high blood pressure and extra fluid; Tenormin, high blood pressure; Inderal and its generic, propranolol, for high blood pressure and chest pain; and Tagamet, ulcers. The survey did not include <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> or the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 0159EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Colombia     08-30 0693</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Colombia,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush's Anti-Drug Strategy Focusing More on South America</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6 ( X6C)</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s new drug strategy is being adjusted to focus more <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid on <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> and two other <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> nations that are fighting cocaine cartels in the region. The crisis in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, with seven bombings Tuesday in the city of <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, was high on the agenda when the president met with top <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> officials at his <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> seaside retreat to complete the new anti-drug strategy to be unveiled next week. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> promised `` to cooperate to the best of our ability'' with <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s latest request for $ 19 million to protect judges from drug cartel death squads. He did not comment specifically on the request but said details were being worked out in discussions in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> with a delegation of <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> officials headed by Justice Minister <PERSON> Monica </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Greiff </PERSON>. Because of the crisis there, `` <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> is a new ingredient in the overall drug strategy,'' national security adviser <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON> told reporters in <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Greiff </PERSON> told reporters `` the law is under siege in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> and we must protect it every way we can.'' `` We must uphold the rule of law, and regrettably at this moment that requires intensive physical protection of our judges,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Greiff </PERSON>, her country's eighth justice minister in three years. The 32-year-old lawyer denied reports she had considered resigning in the face of death threats against her family, saying: `` The threats are out there, but I am satisfied with my protection right now. I am determined that the integrity of our justice system survives this crisis and I hope to play my full part in assuring this.'' Meanwhile, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> recommended Tuesday that Americans postpone non-essential travel to <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> indefinitely and suggested that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens living there consider leaving. `` Although Americans have not yet been the target of any violence, visitors and Americans resident in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> should carefully re-evaluate whether it is essential that they travel to or remain in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> at this time,'' said the statement. `` The department believes it would be prudent for those who deem their presence non-essential to seriously consider leaving.'' Asked about reports that the anti-drug proposal will include $ 300 million for <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, Scowcroft indicated it will contain an `` Andean strategy'' to help these countries improve drug interdiction. He said the aid package was adjusted upward to include the $ 65 million that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> announced last week for the Colombian armed forces. Mrs. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Greiff </PERSON> said the additional $ 19 million she sought would be used to buy armored cars, metal detectors and other security equipment to protect judges. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration has already promised $ 5 million over two years to train Colombian security guards to protect the judges. `` While training and other such programs are useful, we also need to channel resources into such items as bulletproof cars -LRB- and -RRB- metal detectors,'' she said. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said it is ready to airlift military equipment to <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> under the $ 65 million aid package as soon as it receives a list of materiel requested by <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>. The crisis prompted cancellation of today's <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> hearing on <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, D-Del., scratched the hearing after the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> expressed fear that publicity would further jeopardize the lives of Colombian authorities <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> said the panel was told that `` because of the sensitive nature of the situation in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> at this time that it would not be appropriate to have an open hearing.'' <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> indicated that a review of emergency extradition decrees by the <ORGANIZATION> Colombian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> could delay <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> efforts to get custody of <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>, who is wanted on money-laundering charges. But he said `` we have every hope and expectation of getting custody of Mr. <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is seeking to extradite <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> under emergency extradition decrees promulgated this month. Extradition papers are being prepared for 12 other Colombians under federal indictment, <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> said, `` so that when someone is captured we would be in a position to have everything signed, sealed and delivered to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 0147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     08-30 0426</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0442</SECOND>
<HEAD>ABC's `Roseanne' Eases NBC's `Cheers' Out of First Place</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY BUCK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne'' took first place last week in the Nielsen ratings, switching places with <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Cheers'' in their summer seesaw rivalry as sitcoms dominated prime-time viewing. Eighteen of the 20 highest rated shows were comedies. The only non-comedies were the movie pilot for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Baywatch,'' tied for seventh, and the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> movie `` Tricks of the Trade,'' in 12th place. <PERSON> Roseanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Barr </PERSON>'s sitcom in which she and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON> play a working class couple was the success story of this past season. Another working class couple, <PERSON> Al </PERSON> and <PERSON> Peg </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Married ... With Children,'' also have done well this summer That show, which stars <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON> and <PERSON> Katey </PERSON> <PERSON> Sagal </PERSON>, finished ahead of all network competition this past Sunday, and tied for 17th place with <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Empty Nest.'' Its 13.4 rating is the highest ever for a Fox show. The Fox show and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` 20-20'' were the only original productions in the top 30 for last week. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> was first in the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> survey for the 62nd consecutive week with an average rating of 11.4. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> had 9.7 and CBS 9.6. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> was first for the season to date from Sept. 19, with 14.5, to <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s 11.7 and CBS' 11.6. Each rating point is the percentage of the estimated 90.4 million homes with televisions in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. This summer, <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> made its first ratings breakthrough after a long period at the bottom of the ratings. Shows such as `` Married ... With Children,'' `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted'' and `` Totally Hidden Video'' have all climbed out of the cellar. <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>'s `` Open House,'' a new version of `` Duet,'' made its debut last week in 47th place, ahead of the second part of the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday movie, `` The Gladiator.'' Here are last week's top 10: <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Cosby Show'' and `` Dear John'' tied, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Wonder Years,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Baywatch: Panic at <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION>'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Who's the Boss tied, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Night Court.'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> had only three shows in the first 20: `` Tricks of the Trade,'' `` Designing Women'' 13th and `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'' 14th. The <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> summer comedy `` FM'' dropped from its fifth place premiere to 37th for a tie with <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s occasional magazine show, `` Yesterday, Today, Tomorrow,'' was 32nd. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s weekly `` PrimeTime Live'' was 46th. `` The CBS Evening News'' was first among the evening news shows with a rating of 9.7. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> had an 8.5 and NBC 8.0.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 0205EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     08-30 0690</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0772</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time TV ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of August 21-27. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.5, 17.6 million homes. 2. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.0, 17.2 million homes. 3. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.5, 15.8 million homes. 4. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.4, 14.8 million homes. 4. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.4, 14.8 million homes. 6. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.0, 14.5 million homes. 7. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.7, 13.3 million homes. 7. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` Baywatch: Panic at <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION>,'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 14.7, 13.3 million homes. 9. -LRB- 41 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.5, 13.1 million homes. 10. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.2, 12.8 million homes. 11. -LRB- 39 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.1, 12.7 million homes. 12. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` Tricks of the Trade,'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 14.0, 12.7 million homes. 13. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 13.9, 12.6 million homes. 14. -LRB- 32 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 13.7, 12.4 million homes. 15. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Anything But Love,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.6, 12.3 million homes. 15. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.6, 12.3 million homes. 17. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4, 12.1 million homes. 17. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4, 12.1 million homes. 19. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.3, 12.0 million homes. 19. -LRB- 47 -RRB- `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.3, 12.0 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' CBS, 13.0. 21. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' CBS, 13.0. 23. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7. 24. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5. 24. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5. 24. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> Special,'' CBS, 12.5. 27. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.4. 27. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.4. 29. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.1. 29. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 12.1. 31. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0. 32. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` Midnight Caller,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.6. 32. -LRB- 56 -RRB- `` Yesterday, Today & amp; Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.6. 34. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Newhart Special,'' CBS, 11.3. 35. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Alf </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.2. 35. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` In the Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.2. 37. -LRB- 39 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 11.0. 37. -LRB- 60 -RRB- `` FM,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.0. 39. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> Pre-season Football,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.9. 39. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' CBS, 10.9. 41. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Totally Hidden Video,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 10.6. 42. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Takedown </LOCATION>,'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 10.4. 43. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.1. 44. -LRB- 92 -RRB- `` Alone in the <LOCATION> Neon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jungle </LOCATION>,'' _ `` CBS Friday Movie,'' 9.9. 45. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 46. -LRB- 75 -RRB- `` Primetime Live,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.5. 47. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Open House,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 9.3. 48. -LRB- 77 -RRB- `` 13 East,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.1. 48. -LRB- 75 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: Crack Capital,'' CBS, 9.1. 48. -LRB- 61 -RRB- `` Nightmare at <LOCATION> Bitter </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION>,'' _ `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' 9.1. 51. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` The Gladiator,'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 8.8. 52. -LRB- 63 -RRB- `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 8.7. 53. -LRB- 48 -RRB- `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.6. 54. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.2. 54. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` The Equalizer,'' CBS, 8.2. 56. -LRB- 59 -RRB- `` Coach,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.1. 57. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.9. 57. -LRB- 44 -RRB- `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.9. 59. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> Pre-season Football,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.8. 59. -LRB- 48 -RRB- `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.8. 61. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` Hooperman,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.7. 61. -LRB- 100 -RRB- `` Best of Knots Landing,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 7.7. 63. -LRB- 89 -RRB- `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.6. 64. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` B.L. <PERSON> Stryker </PERSON>,'' _ `` ABC Mystery Movie,'' 7.0. 65. -LRB- 102 -RRB- `` West 57th,'' CBS, 6.9. 65. -LRB- 95 -RRB- `` Smothers Bros. Comedy Hour,'' CBS, 6.9. 67. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.4. 68. -LRB- 84 -RRB- `` Paradise,'' CBS, 6.2. 68. -LRB- 97 -RRB- `` A Man Called Hawk,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.2. 70. -LRB- 82 -RRB- `` The Barefoot Executive,'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> Magical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.1. 71. -LRB- 80 -RRB- `` Beauty and the <LOCATION> Beast </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 6.0. 72. -LRB- 121 -RRB- `` CBS Summer Playhouse: Outpost,'' 5.9. 73. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.8. 74. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.5. 75. -LRB- 102 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 5.4. 76. -LRB- 108 -RRB- `` ABC Family Classics Special: Student Exchange,'' Part 2, 5.3. 77. -LRB- 106 -RRB- `` Incredible Sunday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.2. 78. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.9. 79. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` The Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.5. 80. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.7. 81. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.9.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 0131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TamponLabeling     08-30 0288</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tampon Labeling,280</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Requires Labeling Rules by Oct. 30</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> has until Oct. 30 to issue rules on tampon labeling aimed at preventing toxic shock syndrome, a federal judge says. `` This delay in issuing a tampon absorbency regulation is wholly unreasonable and unacceptable,'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Barrington </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> said Tuesday in issuing the deadline. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION>, he said, `` has been lethargic in responding'' to its legal obligation, especially since the government has known about the danger for more than seven years. <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> McLearn </PERSON> declined to comment on the ruling. A revised <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> proposal issued in June would require tampon makers to prominently display one of six new standardized terms for absorbency ranging from low to highest. Under the proposal, tampon boxes would have to carry labels advising women to select the lowest absorbency needed to minimize risk of toxic shock syndrome. Toxic shock syndrome, or <ORGANIZATION> TSS </ORGANIZATION>, is a rare but sometimes fatal condition associated with tampon use. `` Women are unknowingly subjecting themselves to toxic shock syndrome simply because -LRB- government officials -RRB- drag their feet in ... standardizing tampon absorbency labels,'' <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>'s opinion said. The opinion came in a lawsuit filed a year ago by <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citizen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, a non-profit organization, to force the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> to issue tampon-labeling regulations. Regulations have required a warning about <ORGANIZATION> TSS </ORGANIZATION> since 1982 but allow it to appear on a package insert. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> has tried since 1981 to have manufacturers label tampons with a standardized absorbency rating. The agency tried unsuccessfully to get tampon makers to voluntarily standardize labeling, but began regulatory efforts in 1984. <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION>'s reasons for delay are `` lame at best and wholly irresponsible at worst.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 0143EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Israel     08-30 0254</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Israel,250</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Condemns Israeli Deportations</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is urging <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> authorities to complete an investigation into the death of an Arab-American teen-ager and the disappearance of two other Americans. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> said Tuesday the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> wants <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to determine who killed a 14-year-old American-born youth in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> earlier this month. A report by a Scottish pathologist retained by the family of <PERSON> Amjad </PERSON> <PERSON> Jibril </PERSON> <PERSON> Tawil </PERSON> said the youth was killed by a single gunshot wound. <PERSON> Amjad </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, but lived in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> for the last four years. <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> had been in close touch with the youth's family, as well as with relatives of two other Americans of Palestinian origin who have been reported missing for more than 10 days in Israeli-held territory. `` We certainly understand the tragedy of the situation and their agony,'' <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> said. `` We've been talking to their families. We've been following up with the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> authorities We urge the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> authorities to conduct a full investigation.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> also condemned <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s expulsion of five Palestinians on Sunday. The expulsions brought to 60 the number of Arabs deported for their alleged role in organizing the 20-month uprising against Israeli rule in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. `` We deplore these latest deportations,'' <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> said. `` These measures corrode the atmosphere within which the peace process must be moved forward and make it more difficult for Israelis and Palestinians to engage in constructive dialogue.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 0217EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Tourism-PLO     08-30 0255</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tourism-PLO,0263</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tourist Group Votes to Put Off Admitting Palestine as Member</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY DUNPHY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The World Tourism Organization voted to put off consideration of a membership application by the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s self-declared state of <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION> until the organization meets again in 1991. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, supported by <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, forced the vote Tuesday to delay the membership consideration afer daylong discussions. The vote was by secret ballot. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> effort was led by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolton </PERSON>, assistant secretary of state for international organizations, who said he was `` very gratified'' by the outcome. The vote was 40-34 to postpone the issue, with six absentees, six abstentions and five blank votes. One diplomat, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said it was the first time he could recall a Soviet bloc country supporting a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> resolution at an international meeting. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> maintains that bids by the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> to join international bodies threatens <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace efforts. <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Massalha </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s observer mission to the Paris-based <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION>, Scientific and Cultural Organization, called the vote `` a bad decision.'' <PERSON> Massalha </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> would continue its efforts to join international organizations. The <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, a sort of parliament-in-exile, proclaimed the state of <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION> last November. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, backed by most Western allies, says it does not fulfill international criteria because it has no defined territory. The <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tourism </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, with headquarters in <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>, is an intergovernmental group set up in 1975 to promote and develop tourism.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 0103EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Pepper'sSeat 9thLd-Writethru a0433 08-30 0973</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pepper's Seat, 9th Ld-Writethru, a0433,1002</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Ros-Lehtinen First Cuban-American Elected To Congress</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 26 grafs to UPDATE with quotes from winner, loser,
Republican and Democratic chairmans, editing to conform; picks up 20th
graf, `Ms. Ros-Lehtinen, a ...' Should stand for AMs. Ileana Ros-Lehtinen
pronounced ill-ee-AHN-ah ross-LAYT-ih-nen.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto MH3</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN SEWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Havana-born Republican state senator rode heavy support from <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>'s Hispanic community Tuesday to become the first Cuban-American elected to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, winning the seat held by the late <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON> for nearly three decades. With all precincts reporting in the ethnically divisive race, state Sen. <PERSON> Ileana </PERSON> <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON>, 37, received 49,638 votes, or 53 percent, to 43,759, or 47 percent, for Brooklyn-born attorney <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Richman </PERSON>. The 48-year-old Democrat, who is Jewish, had been making his first run for elective office. The race was made necessary by Pepper's death May 30 at 88. Pepper, a Democrat, had held the seat since its inception 27 years ago The 93,000-plus turnout was nearly 51 percent, far higher than normal for a special election and higher than election officials' 43 percent projection. The outcome was delayed more than an hour late Tuesday by a <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> elections computer problem that temporarily halted vote-counting. Higher final counts for both candidates were revised early Wednesday because of the counting problems. The unofficial returns indicated that predominantly Hispanic precincts, with turnouts of more than 60 percent, boosted Ms. <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON> with 80 to 90 percent margins, while <PERSON> Richman </PERSON> was favored by margins of 80 to 90 percent in predominantly black or non-Latin white precincts. In her victory speech, Ms. <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON> said she wanted to unify and heal the community and `` provide leadership ... which is based on acaring conscience and conservative convictions. `` We do not have the luxury to waste time on divisive politics,'' she told cheering supporters at the Airport Hilton Hotel. `` We must focus on what we have in common and not ponder on the negative.'' <PERSON> Richman </PERSON>, addressing disappointed supporters at the Clarion Castle Hotel in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, said, `` We have done incredibly well and we did it on a positive theme.'' He said Ms. <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON> outspent him and had campaign help from President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> and Sen. <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Fla </LOCATION>. The Democrat, noting that more Hispanics turned out than blacks or non-Hispanic whites, said, `` We've got to get everyone in this community to get out and exercise their right to vote. If that had happened, we would have won tonight.'' The Democrats, mindful that August is vacation month for many <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> residents, had tried to build an absentee-vote margin for <PERSON> Richman </PERSON>. But election officials said <PERSON> Richman </PERSON> had only 3,933 absentee votes to 3,599 for Ms. <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON>. The victory gave the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> an 11-8 majority in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s congressional delegation, and <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> called it a Republican milestone in the South `` That seat has been a Democratic seat since it was created,'' he said in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` For us to win it is a major victory.'' Democratic Chairman <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, who campaigned for <PERSON> Richman </PERSON>, expressed disappointment in a statement issued by his <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> office, but said, `` The Democrats ran a surprisingly competitive race after an admittedly divisive primary.'' Ethnic-bloc campaigning dominated the short, tense race between Ms. <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Richman </PERSON> for the remaining 14 months of Pepper's term <PERSON> Richman </PERSON> had come under fire for declaring, `` This is an American seat.'' <PERSON> Richman </PERSON> had hoped to capitalize on the 30,000-plus edge that Democrats, mostly blacks, Jews and retirees, hold in registration. Ms. <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON> looked to the Hispanic community, which makes up 40 percent-plus of the vote. Polls in the final week of the race had indicated it was too close to call. ` It's been a very controversial election,'' said <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Elections Supervisor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>. `` There has been a tremendous amount of media exposure, and we think both camps are getting a lot more people out to vote.'' Pepper's seat was one of five openings in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> House. The others were caused by the resignations of <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, D-Calif., and <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, and the deaths of <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Larkin </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, R-Miss., in plane Ms. <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON> had refused to appear with <PERSON> Richman </PERSON> during the campaign, charging his `` American seat'' message was bigoted. However, the same charges were made against her campaign over a Spanish-language mailing that urged Hispanics to show how American they were even though they were n't born in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> and did n't speak English like <PERSON> Richman </PERSON>. <PERSON> Richman </PERSON>'s said his `` American seat'' remark was an appeal to voters to decide on qualifications, not birthplace. He also said it was a response to <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>'s statement that the party wanted to elect a Cuban-American. But many saw <PERSON> Richman </PERSON>'s theme as anti-Hispanic code. Ms. <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON>, a legislator for seven years, emphasized experience and populist appeal in her campaign. Her campaign chairman was the president's son <PERSON> Jeb </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON>, whose husband, <PERSON> Dexter </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehtinen </PERSON>, is <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, portrayed herself as tough on crime and drugs. But <PERSON> Richman </PERSON> argued that her legislative record against gun control showed softness on crime, because it allowed criminals easy access to guns. <PERSON> Richman </PERSON> also tried to make abortion an issue; he's pro-choice, Ms. <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON> is for further restrictions on abortion. With polls indicating most voters were pro-choice, Ms. <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON> claimed it was n't an issue. <PERSON> Richman </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> president, stunned the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> establishment by breaking out of a seven-candidate pack to win narrowly the party's Aug. 1 primary, then trouncing erstwhile front-runner <PERSON> Rosario </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> in an Aug. 15 runoff. Ms. <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON> won the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> nomination in the Aug. 1 primary. The district covers black neighborhoods such as <LOCATION> Liberty </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, most of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> and sections of blue-collar <PERSON> Hispanic </PERSON> <PERSON> Hialeah </PERSON> and upscale Coral Gables and Key Biscayne.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890830-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-89 0222EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtonInBrief     08-30 0672</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington In Brief,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Environmentalists Say Banned Pesticides Enter U.S. in Imports</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An environmental group says new laws are needed to prevent chemical companies from manufacturing highly toxic pesticides banned in this country and sending them abroad. The practice `` has created a circle of poison'' where some food tainted by the toxic chemicals is imported into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Marquardt </PERSON>, who has followed the issue for the environmental group <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> cited the practices of the <ORGANIZATION> Velsicol </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which from its plant in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, is the world's only producer of the pesticides chlordane and heptachlor. Both pesticides are banned for agricultural use in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and for virtually all other uses because they were found to cause cancer. They are also banned or severely restricted in 48 countries. Nevertheless, Ms. <PERSON> Marquardt </PERSON> said Tuesday, <PERSON> Velsicol </PERSON> exported nearly 5 million pounds of the pesticides to 25 countries between 1987 and the middle of this year. More than 330,000 pounds went to <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> and another 510,000 pounds to <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, countries that import meat and other products into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. In a statement from company headquarters in <LOCATION> Rosemont </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Velsicol </PERSON> called the <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> report `` grossly inaccurate.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Appeals Court OKs Random Drug Tests for Some Army Civilians</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal appeals court says the Army may subject more than 6,500 civilian workers, including law enforcement and aviation personnel, to random drug tests. The <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> in 1986 implemented drug testing for more than 9,000 of its 450,000 civilian employees. In a 3-0 decision Tuesday, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> said 3,700 civilian police and guards should face mandatory drug tests because of the threat to public safety posed by `` drug-impaired, gun-toting civilian officers.'' The 2,800 civilians who fly and service the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s airplanes and helicopters also should undergo random drug testing due to the possibly `` calamitous consequences'' of a single drug-related lapse, the appeals court said. A small group of civilian lab workers do n't have to undergo mandatory, random testing, said <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Sentelle </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Banking Chairman Will Reopen Probe of Lincoln S&amp;L</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
