<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 2343EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Panama-Resistance     12-20 0723</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Panama-Resistance,0746</SECOND>
<HEAD>Defense Forces, Noriega Resist; Loyalty Remains Strong Enough</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELOY O. AGUILAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Instead of collapsing when the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> threw its military might against Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, his Defense Forces stubbornly resisted. The elusive general the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration had hoped to put before a federal judge in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> on drug charges remains at large and in hiding despite an attack Wednesday by thousands of American troops. Many in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> had thought the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> would simply `` throw down their guns as soon as an American helicopter appeared over the barracks,'' as a <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> opponent once put it. In interviews prior to the attack, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military leaders had claimed <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> troops would refuse to shed their blood for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. Part of their evidence stemmed from the fact that disloyal officers mounted two coups against him. But the general, who sometimes seemed to escape by magic, apparently retained enough loyalty for his men to put up a fight when the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> stroke came. From Defense Forces posts all over <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> came reports of stubborn fighting that lasted for hours. With their garrisons destroyed or under siege, many Panamanian officers left and joined small paramilitary groups in urban guerrilla warfare. While <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces had heavy artillery and air power to use against installations and sent their armored personnel carriers rolling over fences and cars, Panamanian armed groups fought a delaying action. `` We are acting as urban guerrillas, although we have lost some positions, some garrisons,'' said <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, the second in command in the paramilitary groups, known as Dignity Battalions. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> spoke with an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reporter as the five men with him took up positions in the bushes with Soviet-made AK-47 rifles near the Tinajitas garrison, taken over Wednesday morning by the Americans. `` The people are joining the struggle for national sovereignty,'' he said. The Noriega forces marshalled resistance with appeals over the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION>, broadcasting in a national network. Announcers called on Panamanians to organize neighborhood armed resistance and guerrilla war. The station played Panamanian patriotic songs that taunt Americans. Officers even used it to broadcast instructions to troops and messages to each other, often in code. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces finally did slowly close down the radio stations that made up the chain, but it was a slow process. `` Incredible,'' said a sweaty <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> sergeant as he listened to the exhortations. `` That was the first thing we should have silenced.'' Unlike the armed forces in other parts of <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> officer corps is made up largely of men from poor backgrounds and became the vehicle dictator <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON> used in the late 1960s to topple the ruling oligarchy. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, a Torrijos disciple, once observed that the upper-class had only itself to blame when they complained about the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>' dominance, because they preferred to make money. He openly mocked the upper-class and his supporters frequently refer to the opposition election victory on May 7 as an effort by the oligarchy to return to power. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> promoted officers with poor backgrounds, often from discriminated-against black and Chinese minorities, and worked hard to retain their loyalty with lucrative slices of the corruption pie in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. But when that loyalty slipped, it did in coup attempts in 1988 and 1989, he reacted brutally, and reports that he personally beat or shot coup instigators circulated. Accused of domestic repression by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government, he whipped up nationalistic feelings showing himself as a Panamanian wrongly accused by the large country that wanted to renege on the the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> treaties. The invasion was a slap in the face to Panamanians who have considered themselves friends and allies of the Americans since the two countries joined hands in the construction of the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> at the beginning of the century. As the armored personnel carriers rolled out of <PERSON> Fort </PERSON> <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> after midnight Wednesday past the Panamanian town of <LOCATION> Diablo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION>, some men and women watching them cursed them or cried. `` Whey are they doing this?'' a housewife asked a reporter. `` Are they going to kill our people just for one man?'' `` The Americans have no control of the situation,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Leonardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Santo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tomas </LOCATION> hospital. `` Their strength is in their personnel carriers and their Cobras -LRB- helicopters -RRB-, but the people are angry.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0031EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RollingStones     12-20 0372</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rolling Stones,0385</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stones Pay Per View Concert Tops North American Tour</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HENRY STERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Rolling Stones capped the next-to-last show of their 32-city North American tour with a guest appearance by British blues guitarist <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Clapton </PERSON> for the band's pay-per-view concert Tuesday night The capacity crowd of 16,000 at Convention Hall roared when the bearded <PERSON> Clapton </PERSON> stepped to center stage for two bluesy solos during `` Little Red Rooster.'' The Stones' lead singer, <PERSON> Mick </PERSON> <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON>, in turquoise shirt, black jeans and silver-studded belt, then joined the <PERSON> Clapton </PERSON> on harmonica. <PERSON> Clapton </PERSON>, wearing a black leather jacket and white T-shirt, was making his first appearance with the Stones on the current tour. The pay-per-view concert Tuesday night was to be seen in 13.5 million homes and heard on about 150 radio stations, promoters said. The concert, the second of three scheduled at 16,000-seat Convention Hall, also featured appearances by vocalist <PERSON> Axl </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> and guitarist <PERSON> Izzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Stradlin </PERSON> of Guns' n' Roses and by 71-year-old Southern blues guitar legend <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Hooker </PERSON>. Rose and <PERSON> Stradlin </PERSON>, introduced by <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> as having come `` all the way East to get their tattooes touched up,'' sang, `` Salt of the Earth'' with the original bad boys of rock' n' roll. <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> seemed more animated Tuesday night, playing up to the television cameras, leading middle-aged fans through the new lyrics of `` Terrifying'' and swaying to `` Ruby Tuesday'' with fans born after it was first recorded in 1967. Tickets for each of the Stones' concerts Sunday, Tuesday and Wednesday in <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> cost $ 38.50, $ 150 and $ 250. The Stones, who have been performing since 1962, opened the tour Aug. 31 at Veterans Stadium in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. The group took off Monday to celebrate guitarist <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON>' 46th birthday <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Kurnit </PERSON>, the president of Set Pay Per View, the show's distributor to cable companies, said the suggested retail price for the concert was $ 24.95, but added that some cable companies were charging $ 19.95 <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> said the live televised performance would inject just the boost needed for the Stones at the end of their first tour since 1981. `` You get wound up for live TV ... especially at the end of a tour,'' said <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON>, 46.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Christmas-Jesus'KinI     12-20 1240</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Christmas-Jesus' Kin I,1277</SECOND>
<HEAD>Part I: Jesus Descended From Checkered Ancestry</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 This first installment of a three-part Christmas series about the relatives of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> deals with his ancestral roots.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE W. CORNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Religion Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Everyone is a special sum of ancestry _ to enhance or diminish through a lifetime. That was so for the child of Christmas, the product of a heritage. Some biblical passages cloak his origins in utter mystery, before time itself. But others accord him a thoroughly natural family tree. `` He was in the beginning with God,'' says one account, a `` Word'' or `` Logos,'' a vitalizing wisdom inherent in the Creator before the world began. Yet other passages say he was `` made like his brethren in every respect.'' `` Son of man,'' he usually called himself, but also `` Son of God.'' He combined `` universality with particularity,'' the `` divine and human model,'' writes church historian <PERSON> Jaroslav </PERSON> <PERSON> Pelican </PERSON> in his book `` Jesus Through the Centuries.'' It says a key question put to him was, `` Where do you come from?'' Although seldom noted, he had a long string of forebears as well as contemporary relatives who gave him both problems and help. His lineage ran deep into Jewish history. As with most people if their descent is traced back far enough, he had a checkered ancestry, good and bad, the lowly and great, kings, betrayers, heroes, adulterers, warriors and prostitutes. It was an odd assortment, like humanity itself, alien Gentiles and fellow Jews, the weak and strong, upright and corrupt. The fact that he shared these common roots is considered theologically basic to his purpose: becoming identified with all humankind. They `` were all members of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>' family, his great-great-great grandaddies and grandmamas in the faith,'' wrote church scholar <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Willimon </PERSON>. `` For all their weaknesses and shortcomings, this motley but richly human crew were indeed his people.'' Two genealogies of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> are recorded, one in the first chapter of the Book of <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON>, the other in the third chapter of the Book of <PERSON> Luke </PERSON>. They vary in some detail and some interpreters debatably assume <PERSON> Luke </PERSON> gives the line of his mother, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>, and that <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> gives that of <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON>, legally the father. `` It is possible that the original genealogy did interpret <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> as the father of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>, that is, that it had been formulated before the understanding of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> as the divinely generated son of God,'' writes New Testament scholar <PERSON> Henrikus </PERSON> <PERSON> Boers </PERSON> in his book `` Who Was <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>?'' Some progenitors are on both lists, including olden patriarchs of Judaism and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s great King <PERSON> David </PERSON>, along with other lesser figures of sundry character. <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> lists 41 ancestors, starting back at the time of <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON>, ancient father of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, and other early patriarchs, <PERSON> Isaac </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON>. <PERSON> Luke </PERSON> lists 77 progenitors in reverse order, starting with <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> and enumerating others going back to the first man, <PERSON> Adam </PERSON>, and finally to his creator, God. Other figures out of dim antiquity also are included, such as <PERSON> Noah </PERSON>, and that legend of longevity, <PERSON> Methuselah </PERSON>, who lived 969 years, all designated ancestors of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>. In the mostly male lists, four women are named, and they're a mixed group _ a soldier's beautiful wife, <LOCATION> Bathsheba </LOCATION>, seduced by King <PERSON> David </PERSON>; the harlot of <LOCATION> Jericho </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Rahab </PERSON>; the sexually maneuvering Cananite, <PERSON> Tamar </PERSON>; and the loyal Mohabite, <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON>. <PERSON> Tamar </PERSON> was the daugher-in-law of <PERSON> Judah </PERSON>, son of the patriarch <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON>. Her husband died and after prolonged widowhood, she disguised herself as a prostitute and enticed her father-in-law to lie with her. She bore twins, one named <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>, also among <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>' forbears <PERSON> Rahab </PERSON> was a harlot who sheltered two scouts sent by the Israelite warrior-leader <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON> to spy out <LOCATION> Jericho </LOCATION> before taking it. She hid them from searchers in flax stalks on her rooftop. She later helped the pair escape, lowering them on a rope from a window in her house, which was built into the city wall. By agreement with the two, her clan was spared when <PERSON> Jericho </PERSON> was destroyed, her house marked by a scarlet cord hung from a window. The devoted woman of <LOCATION> Moab </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON>, widowed by her Hebrew husband, insisted on returning with her mother-in-law, <PERSON> Naomi </PERSON>, to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, with these memorable words: `` For where you go I will go ... your people will be my people, and your God my God.'' On <PERSON> Naomi </PERSON>'s advice, <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> worked in the harvest, sleeping at the feet of the owner, <PERSON> Boaz </PERSON>, thus winning him as her husband. They were parents of Obed, father of <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON>, who fathered King <PERSON> David </PERSON>. His philandering with <PERSON> Bathsheba </PERSON>, the gorgeous wife of an absent military officer, <PERSON> Uriah </PERSON>, produced sons <PERSON> Nathan </PERSON> and future King <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON>, alternatively listed in <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>' line of descent. Other men on the lists also displayed foibles, such as <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON>'s deceiving his father to gain an inheritance, and even <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> fearfully palming off his lovely wife, <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON>, as his `` sister'' to placate the ruling pharaoh while temporarily in <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> Nevertheless, those honored patriarchs also displayed courage, initiative and devotion in their covenant with God to lead a people that would be a promised `` light to the nations.'' The great Israelite military commander, <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON>, successor to <PERSON> Moses </PERSON>, also is listed, along with a long succession of kings, decent and debauched, in addition to charming, psalm-singing <PERSON> David </PERSON> and wise <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON>, credited with the Book of Proverbs and builder of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>'s first Temple. Other kings include <PERSON> Rehoboam </PERSON>, whose oppressions, idolatrous rites and immoralities stirred a revolt that divided the kingdom; <LOCATION> Uzziah </LOCATION>, stricken with leprosy in a prosperous reign, and <PERSON> Hezekiah </PERSON> who led reforms under guidance of the prophet <PERSON> Micah </PERSON>. Also listed is <LOCATION> Manasseh </LOCATION>, described as `` the most wicked king of <PERSON> Judah </PERSON>,'' whose religious deviations included Baalism, exaltation of the idol Astarte, wizardry and <PERSON> Molech </PERSON> worship that involved forcing children through fire. Tradition has it that <LOCATION> Manasseh </LOCATION> had the great prophet <PERSON> Isaiah </PERSON> sawed asunder. One king listed, <PERSON> Josiah </PERSON>, took the throne at age 8 when his father, <PERSON> Amon </PERSON>, was murdered. But <PERSON> Josiah </PERSON> had a long, just reign, ousting corrupt priests and recovering the lost `` Book of law'' in repairing the Temple. Of many others named, some are clouded, uncertain figures, while others are notable in Jewish annals, such as <PERSON> Judah </PERSON>, founder of a main Israelite tribe, and the prophet <PERSON> Nathan </PERSON> who rebuked <PERSON> David </PERSON> for his illicit affair. The mixed lot of people, with their sundry faults and strengths, were all `` part of the promise fulfilled'' by the Christ child, <PERSON> Willimon </PERSON> writes. They, `` for all their weaknesses, ... were instruments of the promise.'' On the other hand, <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>' descent also is traced directly to the Godhead, adding an unfathomable engima to his humanity. `` In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God,'' says the distinctively interpretative gospel of <PERSON> John </PERSON>. `` And the Word became flesh and dwelt among us, full of grace and truth.'' He is `` fully God and fully man,'' classic Christian doctrine says. His conception by the virgin <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> is ascribed by the gospels to divine intervention. <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> calls him the `` image of the invisible God.'' <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> himself, though he was generally elusive about it and though he identified closely with common folk, sometimes laid it out plainly, as related by <PERSON> John </PERSON>'s gospel: `` Truly, truly, I say to you, before <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> was, I am,'' he said. `` I and the Father are one ... the Father is in me and I am in the Father.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Tomorrow: John the Baptist, Cousinly Forerunner</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SAfrica-CoupTrial     12-20 0176</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SAfrica-Coup Trial,0178</SECOND>
<HEAD>Leader Of Failed Homeland Coup Gets 18-Year Prison Term</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A soldier who led a failed coup attempt in one of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s nominally independent black homelands has been sentenced to 18 years in prison for high treason. Warrant Officer <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Phiri </PERSON> was the last of 142 soldiers to be sentenced for their roles in a February 1988 coup attempt in <LOCATION> Bophuthatswana </LOCATION>, one of four tribal homelands designated independent by <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> but not recognized abroad. The other defendants, convicted last month of treason or terrorism, were sentenced Monday and Tuesday to prison terms ranging from 2 to 10 years. The coup was crushed by South African commandos, who freed homeland president <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> <PERSON> Mangope </PERSON> from captivity at a soccer stadium and arrested the rebels, all members of the homeland army. <ORGANIZATION> Bophuthatswana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> M.W. <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> said <PERSON> Phiri </PERSON> was `` a danger to society'' who had allowed <PERSON> Mangope </PERSON> to be ill-treated during the coup attempt and had ordered his rebels to fire on the homes of homeland Cabinet ministers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RobinsonProfile     12-20 0558</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Robinson Profile,0576</SECOND>
<HEAD>Savannah Leaders Praise Slain Alderman</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Mail Bombs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURAN NEERGAARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAVANNAH, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, the alderman and lawyer assassinated by a mail bomb, is being remembered as an easygoing, generous man whose community affairs work made people `` believe they can make a difference.'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, whom even new acquaintances called `` <PERSON> Robbie </PERSON>,'' died Monday when a package containing an explosive and nails blew up at his law office. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> and Mayor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Rousakis </PERSON> had planned to attend a meeting that evening at the lawyer's church to discuss how blacks could fight drugs in their neighborhoods. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> was black. The 42-year-old attorney was the second victim in a rash of mail bombs in the South. A package bomb killed 11th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vance </PERSON> on Saturday. A mail bomb found at the federal courthouse in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> was disarmed Monday. A parcel bomb mailed to the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, office was disarmed Tuesday. On Tuesday, <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION>'s legislative offices were closed in mourning. <PERSON> Rousakis </PERSON> said <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> `` was a warm, kind person, always with a smile on his face and a hand out to help.'' `` He meant the future to <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION>, he gave to the community in such a selfless way that he made people just believe they can make a difference,'' said <PERSON> Alderman </PERSON> <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>. At a news conference, city leaders said they believed <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>'s involvement with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advancement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colored </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION>, which he represented in a school desegregation case, was related to his death <PERSON> Rousakis </PERSON> said <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> was an active member of his church and was worked to help the homeless. Friends said <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>'s political activity was not the kind that would be expected to generate murderous enemies. `` I've known him a very long time, and he is not the kind of guy I would think would be a target of such an action,'' said Superior Court Judge <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadsden </PERSON>. `` He was easygoing and went about his business.'' Longtime friend <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivers </PERSON> said <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> took part in civil rights protests until he went off to college. `` Then he came back, got into politics and his time began to get tight.'' <PERSON> Rousakis </PERSON> said <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> had been a city councilman for eight years, but had served on other government and community boards his entire adult life. As city transit authority chairman 10 years ago, <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> led a move to provide transportation for the poor and the elderly. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, one of the first black students to attend <ORGANIZATION> Savannah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in the 1960s, represented the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> in the long-running <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> schools desegregation case. The 11th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> ruled in October that the city's magnet-school plan was appropriate for desegregation. Neither city nor school officials knew whether the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> was planning to appeal, and NACCP head <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> could not be reached for comment. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> is survived by his wife, <PERSON> Ann </PERSON>, and three daughters. <PERSON> Alderman </PERSON> <PERSON> Floyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> said city officials would start a fund for <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>'s family. <PERSON> Rousakis </PERSON> said a local business, All-American Builders, had already donated a $ 1,000 reward for information in the case. `` We are sure the <ORGANIZATION> Savannah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> will not quit until they come to some conclusion,'' <PERSON> Alderman </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said. `` Meanwhile, the fund gives people a way to prove their love for <PERSON> Robbie </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Romania-Force Bjt   12-20 0557</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Romania-Force, Bjt,0574</SECOND>
<HEAD>Only Violence Can Bring Down Ceausescu</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VIOREL URMA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In contrast to the largely peaceful changes in other Eastern European countries, President <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> appears determined to use force to defend his hard-line regime. <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>, 71, the most senior Soviet bloc leader after 24 years in power, has said reform-minded Communists elsewhere have betrayed their people by refusing to defend Marxist orthodoxy. <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>'s refusal to embrace change has isolated him from all his <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION> allies. Some analysts say he is seeking stronger ties with rigid Communist systems similarly opposed to political reform, particularly <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. His leadership is based on a family dynasty with some 40 relatives reportedly placed in key state and party jobs. His wife <PERSON> Elena </PERSON>, virtual second-in-command in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, is a Politburo member and first vice premier. One of <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>'s brothers, <PERSON> Ilie </PERSON>, is an army general and deputy defense minister. Another brother, <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Andruta </PERSON>, is a police general and deputy interior minister and another brother, <PERSON> Ion </PERSON>, is in charge of economic planning. His youngest son, <PERSON> Nicu </PERSON>, 39, is a Politburo candidate member and party chief of <LOCATION> Sibiu </LOCATION> region in southern <LOCATION> Transylvania </LOCATION>. `` <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> is a showcase for any repressive totalitarian state. The harsher the repression, the more violent the public upheaval it brings about and the greater the desire to take revenge on leaders,'' <PERSON> Ion </PERSON> <PERSON> Ratiu </PERSON>, chairman of the London-based <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> of Free Romanians, said Monday. Since he became party leader in 1965, <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> has exercised absolute power and carried out a foreign policy independent of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. While that maverick stance won him praise and credits from the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> kept Romanians under iron-fisted control. Now, with reform ascendent in the rest of the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact, the harsh Romanian stand draws condemnation from abroad. About 30,000 coal miners went on strike in the <LOCATION> Jiu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> in 1977 and 10,000 workers demonstrated in the city of <LOCATION> Brasov </LOCATION> in 1987 demanding freedom, better living conditions and <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>'s ouster. Police arrested hundreds of demonstrators and their leaders disappeared. An extensive secret police force keeps strict control on religious and political expression, and dissent is quickly crushed, making chances for peaceful change in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> seem remote. But poverty and despair engendered by economic problems and political repressions could cause people to risk direct confrontations with armed forces, as in <LOCATION> Timisoara </LOCATION> now. Unlike recent protests in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, witnessed and reported by the Western media, demonstrations in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> have taken place well outside the public eye. The Western reporters permitted into the country in recent years have been kept under close watch, and police have detained journalists and even diplomats attempting to visit the country's few dissidents <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> has closed its borders and barred most foreigners from entering the country in an apparent attempt to prevent the spread of news about the <LOCATION> Timisoara </LOCATION> protest, the largest demonstration against <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>'s policies since the <LOCATION> Brasov </LOCATION> riots. <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> has little tradition of democratic rule. After five centuries under the Ottoman Turks, <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> won independence in 1877, becoming first a monarchy, then, during the Second World War, an ally of the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION>. The last monarch, King <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>, was forced to abdicate in December 1947 under threat of civil war and pressure from the Kremlin and its Romanian Communist allies.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ArtAuctioneers     12-20 0228</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Art Auctioneers,0234</SECOND>
<HEAD>Art Auction Houses More Than Double Yearly Sales</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two leading art auctioneers are reporting more than doubled yearly sales with the market for impressionist, modern, and contemporary art racing to dizzying heights. <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s fine art auctioneers on Tuesday reported worldwide sales in 1989 of $ 2.9 billion, a 61 percent increase on 1988. And <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s reported worldwide sales in 1989 of $ 2.2 billion, a 69 percent increase. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ainslie </PERSON>, president and chief executive officer of <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Holdings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement: `` The opportunities for forming major collections have never been better as the flow of significant works onto the market is stronger than we have ever witnessed. `` More collectors are participating in our business, and balanced competition from <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has become a regular feature of the international art auction market.'' <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s said auctions of Impressionist, modern and contemporary art worldwide during its autumn sales season this year alone accounted for $ 797 million of overall sales. Lord <PERSON> Carrington </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Christie </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, said in a statement: `` The strength of the market has been underpinned by the growth in world wealth and the emergence of new buyers into the arena. This has caused a change in the emphasis of the market place, which has become more international.'' He said <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> has become the leading sales center.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0018EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Obit--Wedemeyer     12-20 0326</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit--Wedemeyer,310</SECOND>
<HEAD>World War II Planner Dead at 92</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT BELVOIR, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wedemeyer </PERSON>, who drafted the `` <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> first'' strategy under which the allied coalition led by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> won World War II, is dead. He was 92. <PERSON> Wedemeyer </PERSON>, who had Alzheimer's Disease, died Sunday at the <ORGANIZATION> Fairfax </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retirement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Belvoir </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Wedemeyer </PERSON> was a temporary lieutenant colonel when the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> entered the war in December 1941. His first major assignment came earlier that year when President <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> asked the then War Department for suggestions as to how to win the war that the nation was surely going to have to enter. Gen. <PERSON> Wedemeyer </PERSON>, at that time the only American officer to have graduated from the <ORGANIZATION> Germany </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> general staff college, drew up what became known as the `` Victory Program,'' advocating the defeat of German armies on the continent of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> by allied ground troops. After the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> entry into the war, a refined version of the plan was adopted by <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> and <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Winwston </PERSON> <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON>, and, despite a few detours, led to the invasion of <LOCATION> Normandy </LOCATION> in June 1944 and the defeat of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Wedemeyer </PERSON> stayed with the War Department until October 1943 when he was made deputy chief of staff to British Adm. Lord <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Montbatten </PERSON>, the commander-in-chief of the Southeast Asia Command. After returning to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1946, he took on a fact-finding mission in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, racked by civil war between Communist and <PERSON> Kuomintang </PERSON> forced, for President <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>, and held stateside posts until his retirement in 1954. His decorations included the Distinguished Service Medal with Oak Leaf Cluster and the Distinguished Flying Cross. In retirement, he served as director of several corporations, published his memoirs and settled on a farm in <LOCATION> Boyds </LOCATION>, Md. He moved into the <ORGANIZATION> Fairfax </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retirement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> earlier this year. Wedemyer is survived by his wife, <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON>; two sons, six grandchildren and nine great-grandchildren.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens-List     12-20 0707</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens-List,0796</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of Dec. 11-17. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 92.1 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.7, 21.8 million homes. 2. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.5, 20.7 million homes. 3. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.2, 20.4 million homes. 4. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.5, 18.9 million homes. 5. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.4, 18.8 million homes. 6. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.8, 18.2 million homes. 6. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 19.8, 18.2 million homes. 6. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.8, 18.2 million homes. 9. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.3, 17.8 million homes. 10. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.2, 17.7 million homes. 11. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 18.9, 17.4 million homes. 12. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` NFL Monday Night Football: 49ers vs Rams,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.8, 17.3 million homes. 13. -LRB- 48 -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 18.4, 16.9 million homes. 14. -LRB- 12 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.3, 16.8 million homes. 15. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Bob Hope Christmas,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.6, 16.2 million homes. 16. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` In the Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.5, 16.1 million homes. 16. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.5, 16.1 million homes. 18. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` Coach,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.1, 15.7 million homes. 19. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.9, 15.6 million homes. 19. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 16.9, 15.6 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Julie & amp; Carol: Together,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.1. 22. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Rudolph The Red Nose Reindeer,'' CBS, 15.5. 23. -LRB- 25 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Doogie </PERSON> <PERSON> Howser </PERSON>, M.D.,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.5. 24. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4. 25. -LRB- 20 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.2. 26. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.0. 27. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.8. 28. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS, 14.6. 28. -LRB- 44 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 14.6. 30. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Simpsons Christmas,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 14.5. 31. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.4. 32. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Christmas In <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.2. 33. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 14.0. 34. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 13.8. 35. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` Knots Landing,'' CBS, 13.7. 36. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4. 37. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` Lady In A Corner,'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 13.3. 37. -LRB- 61 -RRB- `` Beauty & amp; The Beast'' _ `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' 13.3. 37. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` Anything But Love,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.3. 37. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` 20 @ 20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.3. 41. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` Midnight Caller,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2. 42. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` Desperado: Badlands Justice,'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 13.1. 43. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5. 44. -LRB- 42 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5. 45. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` Magical World of Disney,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.4. 46. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` Rescue 911,'' CBS, 12.3. 47. -LRB- 42 -RRB- `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.2. 48. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` Major Dad,'' CBS, 12.1. 48. -LRB- 56 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: The Other <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 12.1. 48. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.1. 51. -LRB- 49 -RRB- `` Just The Ten Of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0. 52. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` Fear Stalk'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 11.7. 52. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 11.7. 54. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` Beauty & amp; The Beast,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 11.5. 55. -LRB- 61 -RRB- `` Doctor, Doctor,'' CBS, 11.3. 55. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` Family Matters,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 57. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` My Brother's Wife'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 11.2. 58. -LRB- 59 -RRB- `` True Blue,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.1. 59. -LRB- 58 -RRB- `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 11.0. 60. -LRB- 65 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Falcon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 10.2. 61. -LRB- 67 -RRB- `` Young Riders,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.1. 62. -LRB- 67 -RRB- `` Mancuso: <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.0. 63. -LRB- 63 -RRB- `` Baywatch,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.7. 63. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` Famous Teddy Z,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.7. 65. -LRB- 75 -RRB- `` Sister <PERSON> Kate </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.6. 66. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Jillian </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.4. 66. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Hallmark Hall of Fame: The Secret Garden,'' CBS, 9.4. 68. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` Quantum Leap,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.1. 68. -LRB- 65 -RRB- `` Island Son,'' CBS, 9.1. 70. -LRB- 78 -RRB- `` B.L. Stryker'' _ `` ABC Mystery Movie,'' 8.8. 71. -LRB- 97 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 8.5. 72. -LRB- 80 -RRB- `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.2. 73. -LRB- 79 -RRB- `` Primetime Live,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.5. 74. -LRB- 88 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.0. 75. -LRB- 94 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Booker </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.9. 76. -LRB- 90 -RRB- `` Living Dolls,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.8. 77. -LRB- 87 -RRB- `` Saturday Night With <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Chung </PERSON>,'' CBS, 6.7. 78. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Trans-Antarctica Expedition,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.5. 79. -LRB- 92 -RRB- `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.3. 80. -LRB- 88 -RRB- `` Open House,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.1. 81. -LRB- 80 -RRB- `` Free Spirit,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.8. 82. -LRB- 95 -RRB- `` Alien Nation,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.6. 83. -LRB- 93 -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.4. 84. -LRB- 86 -RRB- `` Homeroom,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.2. 85. -LRB- 96 -RRB- `` Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.9. 86. -LRB- 99 -RRB- `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.8.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-China Bjt   12-20 0826</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-China, Bjt,830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baker `Regrets' Misleading Statement</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> says he regrets possibly misleading the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> public about a secret trip to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> taken by two high-level <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration officials. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said through a spokeswoman Tuesday night `` he felt obligated to protect the secrecy of a mission the president wished to have classified.'' Speaking for <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, spokeswoman <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> added: `` He regrets that he may have misled some ...'' It was the first acknowledgement of error since the White House announced on Dec. 9 that national security adviser <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON> and Deputy Secretary of State <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> were visiting <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. Their trip was roundly condemned in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> as a friendly gesture to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and a cancellation of the ban President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> imposed on high-level exchanges after pro-democracy students were massacred in early June in Tiananmen Square. Another sanction crumbled Tuesday night when <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> moved to end a ban that prevented the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Export-Import bank from providing financial aid to companies doing business in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. Also, the White House announced that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had approved the export of three communications satellites expected to be launched by <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, saying the deal was in the `` national interest.'' Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, D-Tenn., called <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s approval of the satellite export licenses `` a true outrage'' and `` another effort to curry favor with the hardliners in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and an insult to the memory of those who died for democracy in Tiananmen Square. Criticism also mounted on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> against this month's visit by Scowcroft and <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, as well as an earlier one in July `` To have sent two of our highest level officials to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> only weeks after announcing a ban on such exchanges makes the president look like a wimp in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and a hypocrite in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Solarz </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, a leading congressional spokesman on <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> issues. In defense of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s actions, White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said: `` It is not misleading to not tell you about everything he's doing. The president's up there in the Oval Office doing things all day long that you do n't know and wo n't know about and that's not misleading.'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, appearing on <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> on Dec. 10, called the trip taken in early December to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> by <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON> and <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> `` the first time we've had high-level <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials go to the People's Republic of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. On Monday, however, the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> disclosed Scowcroft and <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> also had made a secret trip to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in July. Asked about the apparent discrepancy, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> said <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> had explicitly acknowledged the December trip by <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON> and <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> `` was not the first time we had high-level contacts'' with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> since the crackdown. She noted that <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> mentioned on <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> his own meeting in August with <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> Foreign Minister <PERSON> Qian </PERSON> <PERSON> Qichen </PERSON> at a conference on <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. `` He specifically referred to his own contacts,'' Ms. <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> said. `` But he felt obligated to protect the secrecy of a mission that the president wished to have classified. `` He regrets that he may have misled some, but he felt that by acknowledging his own direct involvement it was sufficient to make the point that this was not the first case of high-level contact.'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> sponsored the legislation that forbids the launch of U.S.-manufacturered satellites on Chinese rockets unless the president declares it to be in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> national interest, as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has done. The <ORGANIZATION> Hughes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> is selling the satellites to firms in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> for launching on a Chinese rocket. `` Approval of these licences is in keeping with the president's policy not to disrupt normal commercial relations with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>,'' a White House statement added `` These satellites are intended for civil use and represent significant investments for the firms, based in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>,'' the statement said. `` It is in the national interest of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to approve export licenses for the three satellites currently being prepared for launch in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>.'' The White House also cited `` national interest'' in waiving restrictions on the Export-Import bank's financing of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> business activities within <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The White House said the waiver `` preserves a level playing field for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> business. Additional business activity with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> will be considered on a case-by-case basis as part of a continuing review process.'' One of the few on Capitol Hill who has supported <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s overtures, Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, said sending Scowcroft and <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> to underscore human rights concerns `` was exactly in conformity with the congressional position, which reflected the views of the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people. But Rep. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, D-Ind., a senior member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said `` the administration did what it told us they were not doing. `` Surely the Chinese would see it that way. If we send the national security adviser to the president, there is no sanction from the standpoint of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. I do n't buy that distinction at all,'' <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0155EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-YuleBang Bjt   12-20 0558</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Yule Bang, Bjt,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chemist's Christmas Show Seeks to Lure Kids Into Science</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bassam </PERSON> <PERSON> Z. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shakhashiri </PERSON> is ushering in the Christmas season with a bang. Several hundred children squealed with delight Tuesday night when a loud boom and burst of flames from an exploding hydrogen balloon signaled the start of the Lebanese-born professor's 20th annual Christmas science show. It's called `` Once Upon a Christmas Cheery in the Lab of <PERSON> Shakhashiri </PERSON>,'' and he's taking his popular chemistry lecture this season to <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. Standing on the stage of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> auditorium, <PERSON> Shakhashiri </PERSON> doffed his tuxedo jacket, black bow tie and ruffled shirt and set to work wearing a `` Science is Fun'' T-shirt. For the next hour, he captivated his audience of more than 600 kids and their parents with a demonstration of `` the beauty, the magic and the adventure'' of science, often using ordinary household chemicals found in vinegar, laundry detergent and disposable diapers. As <PERSON> Shakhashiri </PERSON> performed his scientific sleight of hand, bottles popped their corks, a metal can collapsed, a phony dollar bill vanished in a puff, a dishpan overflowed with fog, clear liquids turned into Yuletide greens and reds or glowed in the dark, and a gooey yellow stuff kept oozing out of its glass jar like a yogurt machine gone haywire. While a visiting <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION> applauded from the front row, <PERSON> Shakhashiri </PERSON> delivered his show-stopping finale, shaking a flask containing silver nitrate, ammonia, sugar and other ingredients to produce a giant, shiny Christmas tree ornament. Then he made his pitch to the wide-eyed youngsters. Have fun and work hard in school, he said, and think about a career in science or mathematics `` because our country needs you.'' <PERSON> Shakhashiri </PERSON>, whose first name rhymes with `` Shazam'' and means `` Smiley'' in his native <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, emigrated to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> with his parents in 1957. He is a chemistry professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin </ORGANIZATION> at Madison on leave as assistant director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, an independent federal agency that awards grants to colleges and public schools for scientific education and research. It was at the <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> campus that <PERSON> Shakhashiri </PERSON> delivered his first Christmas lecture `` for kids of all ages'' in 1970. He borrowed the idea from <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Faraday </PERSON>, the great English chemist and physicist whose Christmas science lectures for children were popular in the 1840s. `` I'm trying to share the excitement and joy of doing hands-on science,'' <PERSON> Shakhashiri </PERSON> said in an interview. `` I do n't try to snow anybody with technical details. My idea is to capture their interest and not allow them to extinguish their flame of curiosity.'' <PERSON> Shakhashiri </PERSON> is disturbed by a foundation estimate that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> faces a cumulative shortfall of 450,000 native-born college graduates with bachelor's degrees in science, math and engineering by the year 2000, and a projected shortage of 8,000 scientists with doctorates by 2004. `` It's very, very alarming,'' he says. The nation desperately needs highly trained scientists to tackle such challenges as the superconducting super collider, space stations, human genetic mapping and the AIDS epidemic, he says. `` What's at stake is the pre-eminence of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in science and technology and the global economy, and the quality of life not only in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> but on earth,'' <PERSON> Shakhashiri </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0155EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     12-20 0373</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0388</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It was a big bull, but it did n't sit well outside the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION>. The 3-ton bronze bull sculpture, which turned up uninvited Friday outside the exchange, is being moved to a park in the Wall Street area, said city <ORGANIZATION> Parks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Skip </PERSON> <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON>. The city yanked the sculpture from its spot outside the market last week, but it has changed its mind. Parks Commissioner <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Stern </PERSON> was scheduled to dedicate it today. `` It's our custom to allow sculptors to display their works in city parks. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON>'s found the bull a temporary home,'' <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON> said Tuesday. The sculptor, <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> DiModica </PERSON>, was ecstatic about the city's reversal `` I feel fantastic,'' said <PERSON> DiModica </PERSON>, who spent two years and $ 300,000 on his work, `` The Charging Bull.'' <PERSON> DiModica </PERSON> brought the bull to the stock exchange under cover of darkness Thursday, but within 24 hours the unlicensed art work was hauled off. <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON> said the bull's home will not be permanent, although <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON> did n't have a time frame for its departure.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A private yacht navigator has won enough money to buy a yacht of his own after claiming a $ 13.6 million Lotto prize. <PERSON> Hagne </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> and his wife, <PERSON> Theresa </PERSON>, were celebrating their wedding anniversary Saturday night and did n't even look at their tickets until late Sunday after hearing the winning ticket had been sold in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> Mrs. <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>, 32, was already in bed when her husband told her about the winning tickets. `` I thought he was kidding,'' she said. <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>, 39, who bought 20 tickets for the drawing, had played the same numbers for weeks. On Dec. 10, he matched four numbers on one pick, winning $ 127. `` When I matched four numbers, I felt like the marlin was tugging a little bit on my line,'' <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` So I played those numbers again and landed the big one.'' By matching the winning numbers, 01-06-22-23-34-47, the <ORGANIZATION> Murrays </ORGANIZATION> will receive $ 684,000 before taxes annually for the next 20 years. The <ORGANIZATION> Murrays </ORGANIZATION> have four children, ages 12 to 19. They have no plans for the money yet, but will go ahead with a planned vacation this week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0603EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Blackbird     12-20 0156</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Blackbird,0160</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spy Plane's 25th Anniversary Being Marked in Flight</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PALMDALE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A spy plane that was one of the mainstays of Cold War intelligence-gathering today was marking its 25th anniversary with a flight over its maker's once-secret plants. The SR-71 Blackbird was to take off from <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plant </ORGANIZATION> 42 in <LOCATION> Palmdale </LOCATION> and fly over <ORGANIZATION> Lockheed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>'s plants in <LOCATION> Burbank </LOCATION> and Rye Canyon. An SR-71 first flew on Dec. 22, 1964. Since then, Blackbirds, which can fly at least three times the speed of sound and higher than 85,000 feet, have helped <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence keep watch on sensitive areas around the globe. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> last week signed a defense appropriation bill that did not include funding for the SR-71. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> and other top <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials had advocated dropping the program. The Blackbird _ angular, with short wings and enormous engines _ replaced the U-2, a high-flying but slow craft.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0215EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AFL-CIO-Soviets     12-20 0400</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AFL-CIO-Soviets,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Miners to Visit; Solidarity-like Support Promised</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> says it will host a nearly month-long visit to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> by 10 Soviet miners seeking to form independent unions and promises to support the miners even if it has to defy the Soviet government. <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON>, president of the 14.1 million-member labor federation, announced Tuesday that the delegation would arrive in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on Dec. 29 for a nearly month-long stay. The visit will begin in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and bring the miners to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Jan. 3. A more detailed itinerary was not available, but the delegation plans to visit some <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mines to study mining and safety practices, <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> said. The miners will be the guests of the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> but their trip is being paid for by through a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> exchange program. The <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> has repeatedly refused torecognize visits by members of government-sanctioned Soviet unions, arguing those are little more than puppet organizations. The miners requested the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>'s support last month and <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON>, likening their struggle to that of Solidarity organizers in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> in the early 1980s, promised American unions would deliver. `` If necessary,'' was <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON>'s response when asked if the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> would take the same steps it took to support Solidarity, which included the smuggling of printing and other communications equipment into <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> during the period in which Solidarity was outlawed. In all, the federation gave about $ 5 million worth of equipment and other assistance to Solidarity. Although it refused to allow the federation delegation into the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> noted that the Soviet government had allowed two trade union activists to attend the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>'s recent convention and had granted exit visas to the miners, all members of strike committees which have been at loggerheads with the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>. Because of those steps, <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> said it was clear `` there is a measure of glasnost'' in <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> policy toward independent union activity and said that made it unclear whether the Soviet government would move to block <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> support of the miners. `` I'm interested in testing its limits,'' <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> said of the Soviet government. The Soviet miners scheduled to visit were among the leaders of strikes by thousands of Soviet miners beginning last summer. Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was critical of the strikers, accusing them of undermining his efforts to revive the Soviet economy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0222EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HUDEthics     12-20 0506</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-HUD Ethics,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kemp Vows Swift Action to Improve Ethics Oversight</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Housing and Urban Development Secretary <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> says he is moving quickly to correct problems that caused a congressional study to say <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> has an `` extremely weak'' ethics review system. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s pledge came Tuesday following the release of a <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> study that said <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> was failing to make sure consultants filed financial disclosure forms and was not reviewing the ones filed by employees. `` We found that <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s system for obtaining and reviewing disclosure statements is extremely weak, for its own employees as well as for experts and consultants,'' <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said. `` The fact that the problems we are reporting have existed for so long demonstrates to us that the <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> secretary has not held the -LRB- ethics officials -RRB- sufficiently accountable for developing and administering an effective financial disclosure system.'' <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said there have been three <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> workers who have filled in as the agency's chief ethics officer since <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> took over early this year, and said there has not been a staff and resource commitment to policing for conflicts of interest. `` It appears that to a large extent it is business as usual at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>,'' said Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>., who requested and released the report `` I am faulting Secretary <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, through <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> General Counsel <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>, acknowledged the problems. <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> said <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> would hire a new chief ethics officer by year's end and would soon fully staff an expanded ethics department. A new ethics manual also will be published by the end of the year and all <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> employees are being required to attend ethics seminars, <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> said. `` There are still things that need to be done but they are being done,'' <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> said. `` No one is having to make a convert at this department on the subject of ethics.'' The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said it reviewed the files of 62 consultants hired by <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> from 1986 to 1989 and that 52 had not filed required financial disclosure forms. The agency, the investigative arm of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, also said that <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> received 62 disclosure reports from employees who are required to file them but that the agency had not reviewed any of them more than 100 days later. Ethics law requires that the reports, designed to uncover possible conflicts of interest, be reviewed within60 days. <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> said most have since been reviewed and the rest would be scrutinized by Jan. 15. <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said the problems date back at least seven years and persist despite <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s promises to rid the agency of mismanagement, political influence and other problems blamed for a number of agency scandals during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. It is the second time <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s administration has come under some criticism in a study of agency management. The department's inspector general issued an earlier report praising <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s plans to reform the oversight of agents <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> contracts to sell properties but said the department's regional offices were slow in implementing the changes
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-StockClosing     12-20 0023</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stock Closing,0021</SECOND>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 38,512.00, up 72.90 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Wednesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0604EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--TitanLaunch     12-20 0104</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Titan Launch,0106</SECOND>
<HEAD>Postponed for Fourth Time</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Marietta </PERSON> will try for the fifth time tonight to launch its first commercial Titan 3 rocket with British and Japanese communications satellites. Stiff high-altitude winds forced a delay Tuesday night, just as they had on Monday. Technical and weather problems caused two postponements earlier in December. `` The upper level winds are too strong for Titan this evening,'' launch commentator <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> said Tuesday. The announcement came after the countdown reached the five-minute mark and was being held there for a weather evaluation. The launch was rescheduled for 7:21 p.m. today.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0237EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Gramm'sCandidates     12-20 0566</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gramm's Candidates,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gramm's Involvement in Races Angering Democrats</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats are attacking Sen. <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON> for handpicking candidates to challenge <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>' Democratic congressmen next year, but they say the senator's record of choosing Republican losers gives them little to worry about. Calling those who complain `` wacko,'' <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON> says the Democrats are running scared because `` 1990 does n't look like a good year for them.'' <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>, a first-term Republican, is running for re-election next year and is not believed to be currently facing a serious challenge. His only announced opponent is Democratic state Sen. <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Parmer </PERSON>, a former mayor of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>. The filing deadline is Jan. 2. While <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>'s people say the senator is concentrating on his own race, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Schloss </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, claims <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON> has handpicked challengers to Reps. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON> of Sulphur Springs, <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Laughlin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarpalius </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Amarillo </LOCATION>. `` He's going into the district, handpicking the candidate, forcing him down the throat of the local <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, then the candidate loses and everybody has hard feelings,'' <PERSON> Schloss </PERSON> says. `` He's being a real Lone Ranger, causing problems in his own party.'' <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON> intervened this summer in a special election to fill the <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> seat vacated by former <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> when he released a name recognition poll conducted by Dr. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Lanier </PERSON>, signaling to local Republicans they should rally behind the physician. <PERSON> Lanier </PERSON> lost a close race to Democrat <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Geren </PERSON>. In 1985, <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON> helped create a congressional opening by recommending Democratic Rep. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> B </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> for a federal judgeship. <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON> backed <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> candidate <PERSON> Edd </PERSON> <PERSON> Hargett </PERSON>, who lost the election despite outspending <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON> 3-1. <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>, however, says he's not handpicking candidates, merely talking to people who are interested in running for office. State <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Meyer </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Koops </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, agree and say the senator is a tireless worker for the party. `` I've talked to 200 people about running for governor, lieutenant governor, attorney general, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, state representative, county commission, county sheriff. People who are interested in running for office talk to me,'' <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON> said. But several <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Democrats say <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>'s intervention damages the congressional delegation's bipartisan unity. `` It creates schisms and divisions that we do n't need, as well as bitterness _ there's no way better way to alienate a person than to go out and solicit someone to run against him. It's one of the most personally offensive things anybody could possible do,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> says. `` I wish he would reconsider and consider the effect on the delegation.'' Countered <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>: `` <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> was elected running against a long-time entrenched incumbent. Did that tear up the delegation? I think what's happening is that the Democrats are getting scared.'' With the delegation's clout at low ebb from <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s resignation and other setbacks, Democratic Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> says <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>'s interference is particularly unwelcome as Texans fight to preserve federal funding for several state projects `` It's very difficult to work with a guy who spends all of his time trying to create political problems for you,'' <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> says. `` He does it every two years _ the opponents he recruits always lose, but it creates an enormous amount of ill-will in the congressional delegation. He's hard to work with anyway, a shameless headline seeker, and this just makes it worse.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0237EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     12-20 0267</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0278</SECOND>
<HEAD>ABC's `Roseanne' Beats Out NBC's `Cosby' in Ratings Race</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY BUCK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne'' reclaimed the top spot in the <PERSON> Nielsen </PERSON> ratings and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Cosby Show'' fell to third place. `` Married ... With Children'' zoomed to 13th place. So far this season, `` Roseanne'' and `` Cosby'' each have won six times. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Cheers,'' which was second last week, has had one first-place finish. The brash <PERSON> Al </PERSON> and <PERSON> Peg </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> of `` Married ... With Children'' flirted with the top 10 with their Christmas special. Its rating of 18.4 was <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>'s best ever. Its 13th place finish was better than <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON>'s Christmas show on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Who's the Boss?'' and `` Coach,'' and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` In the Heat of the Night'' and `` Matlock.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won the week with an average rating of 14.7. CBS had 12.6 and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 12.3. A ratings point represents the percentage of the nation's 92.1 million television households tuned to a show. The second-place finish was CBS' best performance since the week that ended Oct. 22. For the season, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> leads with 14.9 to <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s 13.2 and CBS' 12.3. Here's the top 10: <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne''; <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Cheers,'' `` The Cosby Show,'' `` The Golden Girls,'' `` A Different World''; a three-way tie for sixth place between <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Empty Nest,'' CBS' `` 60 Minutes'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Wonder Years''; <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Dear John'' and `` <LOCATION> L.A </LOCATION> Law.'' The two-hour movie marking the return of CBS' `` Beauty and the Beast'' was 37th. The show's first regular episode was 54th. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> maintained first place among evening news shows. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> had a rating of 11.0 to <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' 10.4 and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s 10.2
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0240EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Vessel-CoastGuard     12-20 0521</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Vessel-Coast Guard,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>NTSB Blames Deaths on Lack of Coast Guard Rules</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal safety investigators are blaming the boat accident deaths of four people in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> last year on the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>'s failure to require lifeboats and a signal beacon on the vessel that carried them. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> has tried for years to get the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> to toughen requirements for an estimated 4,700 small commercial vessels that are equipped to carry 300,000 passengers. `` There has been a long, documented absence of regulatory action,'' said board member <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION>'s 3-0 decision Tuesday was the first time it has said the service's lack of regulations contributed to deaths in an ocean accident. The Sept. 15, 1988, incident off the coast of <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> involved the sinking of the Cougar, a 46-foot vessel used to carry passengers on a fishing trip. After the boat took on water and sank, passengers and crew were left in the cold <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>, clinging to float devices and debris, for 18 hours as searchers tried to locate them. The captain, a deckhand and two passengers died. A ship's mate and four other passengers survived. The last victim drowned 15 minutes before a helicopter rescued the others about 35 miles out into the ocean, west of <LOCATION> Depoe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, investigators said. The board also blamed the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> for failing during inspections to confirm the watertightness of hatchcovers on boat's deck Its report said the probable cause of the accident was the captain's failure to ensure that his hatchcovers were watertight, that the bilge pump was operating properly and that rubber flaps designed to let water flow off the deck were correctly installed. The captain was not identified in the report. The flaps were on the wrong side, preventing water from flowing off the deck, investigators said. The ship sank in moderately heavy seas while returning from a fishing trip, after its crew and passengers tried for 90 minutes to remove water with buckets. The board for years has recommended that the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> require all passenger boats to carry lifeboats that will keep all passengers and crew out of the water if the ship sinks and that emergency position indicating radio beacons, or EPRIBs, be carried on all vessels so they can be quickly located by searchers. In the last five years, the board has investigated five passenger vessel accidents, including two collisions, one fire, one capsizing and one grounding. In each case, <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> survival craft requirements were found inadequate, but there has been no change in the regulations. The board recommended that the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> require that within five years all flotation devices and buoyant apparatus be replaced by lifeboats, life rafts or inflatable devices that can keep people out of the water. Passengers using flotation devices remain in the water where they can suffer from a rapid loss of body heat, or hypothermia. The board also advised the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> to improve its testing rules and procedures and require all passenger vessel operators to file sailing plans before they set out.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>b i AM-Panama-Fighting 3rdLd-Writethru a0434 12-20 0427</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-Fighting, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0434,0436</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Fighting In Panama; U.S. Troops Move Toward Military Headquarters</HEAD>
<UNK>Eds: ADDS details on U.S. attempts to oust Noriega. U.S. troop strength
in the country. No pickup</UNK>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mortar, machine-gun and cannon fire was heard in the capital Tuesday night as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tanks and truckloads of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> troops headed toward <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s military headquarters. Planes and helicopters were flying over the city. The movement indicated <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces were attempting to force <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s military leader Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> out of power. <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> quoted Panamanian armed forces television as reporting that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military had been ordered into action against the Panamanian Defense Forces. It said gunfire and explosions were heard in the vicinity of <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> headquarters, where <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has offices. Gunfire was heard near the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> base <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clayton </LOCATION>, 6 miles north of the city. Three young Panamanian soldiers told an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reporter in the capital `` There is all kinds of hell loose out there.'' The reporter saw 24 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tanks and at least four trucks carrying <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> troops head in the direction of Panamanian Defense Forces headquarters. Troops in olive uniforms ran through the luxury <ORGANIZATION> Marriott </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotel </ORGANIZATION> and lights in the hotel went out. Channel 8, television station of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, issued an Echo level alert, its highest, and said movement by unauthorized <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> personnel was prohibited. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has tried to oust <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> with economic and political pressure since he was indicted on federal drug trafficking charges in February 1988. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sanctions have depressed the economy, but have not budged <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, and two coup attempts _ most recently in October _ failed to unseat him. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> had been on maximum alert and restricted to base since a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> lieutenant was killed by Panamanians on Saturday in what <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> officials called an unprovoked incident. There had been reports all day Tuesday of unusual <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troop and military plane movement in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> maintains 12,000 troops in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, at installations including <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clayton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Amador </LOCATION> _ a joint U.S.-Panamanian base across a causeway from the capital and <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> headquarters at <LOCATION> Quarry </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION>, bordering the capital to the west. The Panamanian <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> has 15,000 regular troops but <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has also armed citizen `` Dignity Battalians'' of his loyalists. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> accuses the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> of trying to oust him so it can renege on 1977 treaties under which <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> is to cede control of the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> by the end of the century.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>b i AM-Panama 5thLd-Writethru a0417 12-20 1029</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0417,1064</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Fighting In Panama Between U.S.-Panamanian Troops</HEAD>
<HEAD>LEADS with 15 grafs with details of fighting; Picks up 16th pvs,
`A U.S. ...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Machine-gun and cannon fire resounded through the capital Tuesday night as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tanks and truckloads of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> troops headed toward <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s military headquarters in an apparent bid to oust Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. The Panamanian leader had said Friday that <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> was in a `` state of war'' with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the following day a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> lieutenant was killed by Panamanians in what <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> officials called an unprovoked attack. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> have been on maximum alert since and on Monday a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military officer wounded a <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> police officer in what he said was self-defense. An <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reporter saw 24 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tanks and at least four trucks carrying <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> troops head in the direction of Panamanian Defense Forces headquarters on Tuesday night. Troops in olive uniforms ran through the luxury <ORGANIZATION> Marriott </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotel </ORGANIZATION> and lights in the hotel went out. Channel 8, television station of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, issued an Echo level alert, its highest, and said movement by unauthorized <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> personnel was prohibited. The roar of planes and helicopters were heard over the city. Earlier Tuesday, <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> accused the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces of violating its air space with `` observation planes and helicopters'' in preparation for military action. Frequent movements of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers and equipment have been seen within <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military installations the past three days, and appeared to escalate Tuesday at <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>. About 12,000 American soldiers are stationed along the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has tried to oust <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who controls the Panamanian military and the country, since he was indicted on federal drug trafficking charges in February 1988. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sanctions have depressed the economy, but have not budged <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, and two coup attempts _ most recently in October _ failed to unseat him. An NBC News broadcast Tuesday showed what it said were C-141 Starlifter transport planes landing in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in the afternoon. It said one plane was landing every 10 minutes and that security had been tightened around the air base. Later Tuesday, a <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reporter and a <ORGANIZATION> Reuters </ORGANIZATION> reporter were detained for about an hour by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military police when they tried to enter <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> air base to determine whether <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces were landing. The Times reporter's notebooks were confiscated by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, and the two reporters were released without incident. An AP reporter who drove through <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> air base Tuesday night saw at least 10 large transport planes, an unusually high number. There also were six to eight helicopters parked there, in contrast to the usual three or four. It was not clear what kind of planes they were or whether they transported troops or cargo. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said earlier Tuesday `` no unusual military activity'' was taking place. Later he said he knew nothing about the reported arrival of C-141 planes. At <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clayton </LOCATION>, headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION>, tanks were pulled into a circle in an open area and troops climbed on and off them in routine cleaning and exercises Tuesday afternoon. Trucks and armored personnel carriers also were moved into public view. Telephone lines to the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> offices at <LOCATION> Quarry </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION> and to officers' homes were busy late Tuesday. Access to Quarry Heights is limited, but a public road goes through <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>. Earlier Tuesday, C-141 planes were seen in the air around <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bragg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, home of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s 82nd Airborne division. It was not known if they were connected to any <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military activity in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bragg </LOCATION> spokesmen would say only that <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> units there were taking part in a routine `` emergency deployment readiness exercise.'' Sgt. <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Feibel </PERSON>, a spokesman for the division, said he had no information on reports that some of the division had left <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bragg </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, soldiers of the 7th Infantry Division -LRB- Light -RRB- were mobilized Monday at <ORGANIZATION> Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ord </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> base, also for a readiness exercise, said base public affairs officer <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>. `` As a matter of policy, we do not address destination, unit size, unit designation, or times of departure,'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> added. Lt. <PERSON> Pascual </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, director of civil aviation, said <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> has `` a critical situation'' with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` We think the level of aggression and intimidation will increase,'' he told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. `` There are helicopters flying during the night over our installations,'' he said. At the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, spokeswoman <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> said <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s declaration last week that a state of war existed with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, followed by `` indiscriminate and unprovoked violence against Americans, clearly increases tensions in <LOCATION> Panma </LOCATION>.'' Ms. <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> would not say what contingencies or options were under consideration. Panamanian officials say the American officer was killed when he and three others drove a car past checkpoints, then fired at <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s military headquarters building, wounding two civilians and a soldier. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> says the four were unarmed, in civilian clothes, when they got lost near the headquarters. Lt. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Paz </PERSON>, 25, who had been in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> since September, was killed when the group fled civilians and soldiers who tried to force them from their car at the checkpoint, <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> said. On Monday, a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> officer wounded a Panamanian police corporal because he thought the man was about to draw a weapon, according to Southern Command. Police Cpl. <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> <PERSON> Tejada </PERSON>, who was shot once in the left arm, told journalists permitted to interview him in a hospital Tuesday the American had initiated the incident. `` I was merely standing there, doing my job, when this car went by at high speed and the driver fired two shots at me,'' he said. `` I never gave him a reason for it.'' Journalists also were permitted to interview another patient, <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Correa </PERSON>, who said he belonged to the security detail at military headquarters. <PERSON> Correa </PERSON> said he was shot in the arm Saturday by the Americans. Southern Command officials have said repeatedly the only shooting was by Panamanian troops. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has denied the drug charges.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891220-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-89 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Markets     12-20 0305</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Markets,0315</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dollar, Nikkei Up</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The key index on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchage </ORGANIZATION> reversed its early downswing and edged up Wednesday, while the dollar firmed against the Japanese yen. The dollar closed at 144.23 yen, up 0.43 yen from Tuesday's close of 143.80 yen It started trading at 143.92 yen and ranged between 143.90 yen and 144.25 yen. The Nikkei Stock Average of 225 selected issues regained 72.90 points, or 0.19 percent, ending the day at 38,512.00. It lost 147.08 points Tuesday on rumors the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> might raise the nation's discount rate by the weekend. Market players, however, avoided making major moves amid uncertainties over the discount-rate increase, said <PERSON> Tomoyuki </PERSON> <PERSON> Morimoto </PERSON>, a dealer with <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> `` Many market players were reluctant to make major moves amid uncertainty over the discount rate hike,'' he said. `` Few people will be inclined to buy further until they find out what exactly will happen to the rate.'' Higher interest rates discourage stock investment. News reports speculated the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> might raise its key lending rate to commercial banks by 0.5 percentage point to 4.25 percent, but both the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> denied the hike would happen any time soon. <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported Wednesday the central bank will begin negotiations with the government in an attempt to raise the discount rate soon, citing sources from within the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION>. In currency dealings, trading was quiet in the absence of fresh market-affecting news ahead of the Christmas holiday, traders said. `` Although the market was hectic yesterday due to the rumor about the discount rate, it no longer has any impact here. The market already expects there will be a hike sometime early next year,'' said a trader with <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, speaking on condition of anonymity.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
