<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0000EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Panama-CoupWidow 1stLd-Writethru a0805 10-11 0684</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-Coup Widow, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0805,0705</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Widow of Panama Coup Leader Says He Was Betrayed</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 5 grafs after 5th, ``Everything was ..., to UPDATE with
telephone interview; picks up 6th graf: `Mrs. Giroldi ...</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The widow of the Panamanian major who led an unsuccessful coup against Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> says it failed because her husband was betrayed by another major who switched sides at the last minute, according to a published report. Countering what <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have been saying, <PERSON> Adela </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonilla </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON> is quoted by the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> in its Thursday editions as saying that the coup was `` very well organized and coldly calculated.'' She said her husband, Maj. <PERSON> Moises </PERSON> <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON> <PERSON> Vega </PERSON>, had worked with Maj. <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Olechea </PERSON>, commander of the elite Battalion 2000, in planning the coup. Instead of being used to oust <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, however, Battalion 2000 was airlifted 55 miles from the scene of the fighting and led <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s troops in crushing the coup. `` Everything was ready. But <PERSON> Olechea </PERSON> was playing a winner's game and he failed to come through because of his cowardice. He committed treason,'' she told the Times in an interview conducted in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. In a television interview with <ORGANIZATION> WTVJ </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, she said she warned her husband of the perils of the attempted coup. `` I told him ` Think of what you're doing.' I said, ` If you're going to do that, you're going to have to kill him. `` He said, ` I do n't think that will be necessary. If things get difficult, we'll give him over to the Americans. If not, we'll retire him under house arrest,''' she said She says her husband had wanted help from the Americans, but military bureaucracy may have prevented that help from arriving in time, she told the station. She said the battle with <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> will continue, and her husband's death could be a catalyst. `` Where -LRB- <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON> -RRB- is now, he is OK,'' she told <ORGANIZATION> WTVJ </ORGANIZATION>. `` He's with God. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, not even hell wants him. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> does n't want him. Hell does n't want him. So, where will he go?'' Mrs. <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON>, airlifted from <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, is staying with her children and invalid mother at a secret location in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. She was not at military headquarters during the coup attempt on Oct. 3 and her information came from officers who took part in the coup and fled to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the Times said. She said she believed the coup would have succeeded had it not been for <PERSON> Olechea </PERSON>, whose battalion would have provided the firepower to topple <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, she told the newspaper. <PERSON> Olechea </PERSON> `` turned sides at the last moment'' although <PERSON> Olechea </PERSON> and her husband `` were good friends and had talked several times about this coup'' she said. She also said that three captains who were supposed to persuade <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to surrender `` did n't do it because they were cowards.'' Her lends credence to reports that officers held <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> for up to five hours as they argued whether to turn him over to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials. While the captains argued, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> slipped into a separate room and telephoned for help and the coup was crushed. Mrs. <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON> said that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> `` himself assassinated my husband.'' `` My husband could have killed <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, but he would not do that. He thought the commander's fate should be decided by the people,'' not the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, she told the paper. Mrs. <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON> did not have firsthand evidence that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> killed her husband, the paper said. She confirmed that she had approached <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials and told them that a coup attempt was imminent and that the sealing of roads by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces would help her husband's attempt. She told the Times that the coup attempt was hatched by junior officers who were fed up with <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who she said `` always seemed drunk.'' `` My husband told me that most of the time <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was operative only an hour a day,'' she said, adding that it was widely believed that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> drank heavily and used amphetamines. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is very bright, she told the Times. `` The next time, he has to be the first to be killed,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0004EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ChicagoSchoolReform 2ndLd-Writethru a0415 10-12 0627</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Chicago School Reform, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0415,0637</SECOND>
<HEAD>Elections Wednesday and Thursday Will Put Reform in Action</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 4 grafs to UPDATE turnout figures; picks up 5th graf:
`Officials said ...</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto CX2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES WEBB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 150,000 Chicagoans voted to elect local school councils Wednesday as part of sweeping reforms that will give parents more control of an education system labeled the worst in the nation. At issue is the quality of learning in a system whose 410,000 students make it the nation's third largest, but whose low test scores and high dropout rates in 1987 caused then-Education Secretary <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> to brand it the nation's worst. The final tally is expected to show that more than 30 percent of the parents voted in the elections, school officials said. An early tally of votes cast showed that 150,401 people voted. Officials said that included 70,053 parents, 55,319 community residents and 25,029 ballots cast by <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> staff members. Officials said there were a number of reports of irregularities in the balloting, most caused by inexperienced election judges and ballots at some schools that had more than 20 candidates. `` I want to be part of the reform _ I think this is one way of having a solution to the problems in the schools of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. I feel it's a responsibility of the parents,'' said <PERSON> Nacer </PERSON> <PERSON> Boundaoui </PERSON>, who voted at <ORGANIZATION> Robert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Healey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, where his son attends first grade. <PERSON> Boundaoui </PERSON> led his 4-year-old daughter, <PERSON> Assia </PERSON>, into the school gymnasium and stood behind a wooden screen hiding a metal school desk, where he marked his vote on a paper ballot. The elections _ Wednesday at the city's 469 elementary schools and Thursday at 71 public high schools _ were part of a reform package passed last year by the <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. Reform also included cutting administrative jobs and shifting money in the $ 2.26-billion school budget to educating low-income students. Community activists spent weeks trying to mobilize residents to vote, but predicted a 50 percent turnout among parents with children in school. <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Saigh </PERSON> said that turnout was low by late afternoon, but was expected to improve by the time polls closed. The 17,256 candidates sought 5,400 unpaid positions on the 540 councils, each of which will include six parents, two teachers and two community residents without schoolchildren. School staffs will elect the teacher members. The 11th member of each council will be the principal of the school or schools the council oversees. The councils, scheduled to begin their monthly meetings within a week of the elections, will have authority to hire and fire principals, develop school-improvement plans and spend money. The councils would receive much of the authority previously vested in the school system's central bureaucracy, headed by a superintendent and the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>. The old board of mayoral appointees was scrapped under the plan and a seven-member interim board, also appointed by the mayor, is running the system. Ultimately, a 15-member permanent board will be named by the mayor, following screenings by citizens' panels. At <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> McClellan </PERSON> school, Mayor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> was one of about 60 people who had voted by 11 a.m. `` I'd like to have them coming in, but it's slow,'' said election judge <PERSON> Alfreda </PERSON> <PERSON> McLain </PERSON>, surveying the empty polling place at <PERSON> McClellan </PERSON>. `` Maybe they do n't understand that they should help the public schools.'' A survey by Designs for Change, an education research and advisory council that helped shape the reform package, found that nearly equal numbers of candidates came from low-income neighborhoods as middle-class sections of the city. Participation was as high at mostly black and Hispanic schools as at integrated schools, the survey found.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0035EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     10-12 0860</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0898</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Arsenio </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, star of his own late-night talk show, was disappointed when he was n't tapped to be the heir apparent to the king of the talk shows, <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>. In <ORGANIZATION> Rolling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stone </ORGANIZATION> magazine's November issue, <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> said that when <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Leno </PERSON> was selected as <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>'s substitute host, `` I thought it should have been me.'' Hall has long admired <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> and dreamed of being host of `` The Tonight Show.'' `` He was the guy,'' <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>. `` Even when he was n't funny, he looked good I had to cry to my mother for one pair of sneakers, but what I really wanted was a <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> suit.'' <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> praised <PERSON> Leno </PERSON>, saying: `` <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Leno </PERSON> is one of the last pure stand-ups left.'' But no praise is forthcoming for another late-night host, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Letterman </PERSON>. `` I think he hates my guts,'' <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> said. `` Sometimes you're just not someone's cup of tea.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> honored televangelist <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, awarding the preacher its highest humanitarian award. <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> was given the <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Booth </PERSON> Award on Wednesday in recognition of four decades of ministry and crusades, said Lt. Col. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Riley </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> division commander. `` People are finding today that materialism does n't satisfy,'' <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> said, describing the world's spiritual hunger. Today, <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> is to be feted at a fund-raising dinner for the homeless. <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>'s `` The Hour of Decision'' hit the airwaves in 1950 and is broadcast on 500 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> stations and several hundred overseas. On Sunday, <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> is scheduled to become the first clergyman to receive a star on the <ORGANIZATION> Hollywood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Walk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fame </ORGANIZATION>, said his spokesman <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s homecoming excited <ORGANIZATION> Gardner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> pupils, who watched as the pop music superstar helped dedicate a remodeled auditorium named in his honor. `` This is the happiest day of my life,'' said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, a sixth-grader at the Hollywood school during the 1969-70 school year. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, wearing a leather outfit covered in zippers, studs and buckles, arrived at the school Wednesday to students' squeals of `` <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>! <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>!'' and was guided into the building by police officers. After speeches by school officials, pupils and parents, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was presented a commemorative plaque by his former teacher <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerson </PERSON>. `` I am deeply touched and honored that the <ORGANIZATION> PTA </ORGANIZATION>, principal, faculty members and students have been so kind as to dedicate this auditorium, where I sat as a child, in my honor,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Janique </PERSON> <PERSON> Hennessee </PERSON>, 11, said she was so excited to see <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> that she started crying, but <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> came up to her and dried her tears.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 While the Rolling Stones were thrilling <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> rock fans, another longtime star, <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Horowitz </PERSON>, created a different kind of excitement for classical music devotees. As selections from his new recording, `` <PERSON> Horowitz </PERSON> at Home,'' played in a midtown record store Wednesday, the 85-year-old pianist autographed copies of it for his fans. Outside, more than 1,000 people patiently lined Sixth Avenue from 51st to 52nd streets, waiting for a chance to meet the virtuoso inside the store. It was a quiet crowd, not at all like the boisterous thousands who greeted the Rolling Stones performances at Shea Stadium on Tuesday and Wednesday. `` This is a very rare event. His last public signing was in October of 1986,'' said <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Heinlein </PERSON>, a spokesman for Deutsche Grammophone records. `` And this is a very good crowd.'' <PERSON> Horowitz </PERSON>'s latest album, recorded in the living room of his <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> home, features him playing <PERSON> Mozart </PERSON>, <PERSON> Schubert </PERSON> and <PERSON> Liszt </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>JENSEN BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former movie star-singer <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Langford </PERSON> has donated a $ 600,000 house on the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> to the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanographic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. The society is planning a $ 14 million <ORGANIZATION> Coastal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Langford </PERSON>'s gift will finance half of the center's first phase. `` The right people just happened to tell me about the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanographic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Langford </PERSON> told reporters Tuesday. `` Somehow, the activities of the society seem very exciting to me and so I was pleased to make the gift.'' The oceanfront residence on <LOCATION> Hutchinson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> will be sold and the proceeds will be placed in the building fund, said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Wacha </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, the society's president. <PERSON> Langford </PERSON>, probably best known for playing Blanche on the 1940s radio show `` The Bickersons'' with <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Ameche </PERSON>, has been named a founder of the new center and appointed to the society's board of directors.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lipton </PERSON>, a star of the old TV series `` The Mod Squad,'' has filed for divorce from music producer <PERSON> Quincy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>. Miss <PERSON> Lipton </PERSON> cited irreconcilable differences and is seeking unspecified spousal and child support, according to court papers filed Tuesday. The couple married Sept. 14, 1974. She also seeks joint custody of the couple's two daughters, <PERSON> Kidada </PERSON>, 15, and <PERSON> Rashida </PERSON>, 13, who have been living with their mother since their parents separated three years ago, the court papers say. Miss <PERSON> Lipton </PERSON> played <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> in `` The Mod Squad,'' a series about undercover, counterculture cops that was broadcast from 1968 to 1973. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> has produced numerous hit albums, including <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s `` Thriller.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0041EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AngolaWarden     10-12 0348</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Angola Warden,0359</SECOND>
<HEAD>Warden Fired for Running Cockfighting Game at Prison</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN SAYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BATON ROUGE, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The ex-warden of the <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penitentiary </LOCATION> was fired for lax security, not reporting escapes and operating a cockfighting business at the prison, the state's corrections chief said Wednesday <PERSON> Hilton </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON>, who has been on leave since in August, was fired Tuesday for eight violations of department policy that alleged administrative malfeasance, said <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON>, secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION>. `` I was going to give him the opportunity to retire. ... He chose not to retire,'' <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Butler </PERSON>, a career corrections employee, stepped aside as warden after a court-appointed investigator, former <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> warden <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> <PERSON> Maggio </PERSON>, issued a highly critical report on operations at the vast prison complex at <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> later asked the <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> to reinstate him, claiming that Gov. <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> coerced him into retiring. <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> has denied that <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> was coerced. <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> said he was not involved in the details, but added that <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> `` made the right decision'' to step aside. The governor said Wednesday that he backed <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON>'s decision to dismiss <PERSON> Butler </PERSON>. <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> can appeal his firing to an internal department panel and to the <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> refused comment and referred questions to his attorney, <PERSON> Floyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Falcon </PERSON>. <PERSON> Falcon </PERSON> said he had not received a copy of the charges and declined comment. According to the charges, <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> was raising fighting cocks for sale on prison grounds, using inmate labor and prison utilities. Several hundred fighting cocks he owned have been removed from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> grounds on <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON>'s orders. The charges said he also failed to maintain searches of employees and visitors to the prison, allowed inadequate and inoperable security equipment, ill-trained personnel, and failed to report at least seven escapes for prosecution, as required by agency policy. <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> said the charges were referred to the district attorney who handles <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and a copy would be sent to U.S. District Judge <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Polozola </PERSON>, who is overseeing a long-running federal suit involving the prison system.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Lyphomed-AIDS 1stLd-Writethru a0425 10-12 0336</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Lyphomed-AIDS, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0425,0342</SECOND>
<HEAD>Company Distributing AIDS-linked Pneumonia-Fighting Drug Free to
Poor</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: New throughout to UPDATE with cost of drug, quotes from officials;
a version moving on business wires; no pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Lyphomed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> has been distributing its drug pentamidine, used to combat AIDS-linked pneumonia, free to poor patients, the company said Wednesday. The company announced its plans to give away the drug in February, but the actual distribution was held up until after the drug won full government approval in June, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON> <PERSON> Marsden </PERSON>. Community health organizations have been notified of the availablity of pentamidine for the poor and for those who lacked insurance to cover its costs. Ms. <PERSON> Marsden </PERSON> said there have been no recent talks within the company about reducing the cost of the drug to the paying public. <ORGANIZATION> Lyphomed </ORGANIZATION>, based in suburban <LOCATION> Rosemont </LOCATION>, has been accused by AIDS activists and others of overcharging for the substance. <ORGANIZATION> Lyphomed </ORGANIZATION>'s action represents the first time a company has distributed an approved drug to poor patients free of charge, company officials and <ORGANIZATION> federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. Since 1984, <ORGANIZATION> Lyphomed </ORGANIZATION> has produced an injectable form of the drug for use in patients who already have contracted pneumocystis carinii pneumonia, a life-threatening form of pneumonia that is the leading cause of death among AIDS patients. In June, the company obtained approval for marketing an aerosol version to be taken once every four weeks as a preventive measure by people likely to contract that form of pneumonia. <ORGANIZATION> Lyphomed </ORGANIZATION> charges about $ 100 wholesale for a monthly dose. Patients pay up to $ 200 for the same dose through doctors and pharmacies. Last month, the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> With </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> AIDS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> said it would import the drug from <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, where is it cheaper, and sell it to AIDS patients in this country at a lower cost that the drug can be bought here. <ORGANIZATION> Lyphomed </ORGANIZATION> said its charge is appropriate, given the research money it spent developing the drug.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0101EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bishops-Mideast     10-12 0695</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bishops-Mideast,0718</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Bishops Attack Israeli Rights Abuses, Call for Palestinian Homeland</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRIGGS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Roman Catholic archbishops said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> should negotiate directly with Palestinians over `` territory and sovereignty,'' and criticized <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> for alleged human rights abuse. The joint statement by Archbishops <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahony </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Keeler </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> and Cardinal <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> also called on <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> to leave <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. Their statement, to be presented to the nation's 300 bishops, asked the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration to take more action in negotiating a peace in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> that meets the security needs of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and the `` long-denied rights'' of Palestinians. But it also called on Palestinians to pursue `` sovereign co-existence'' with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. `` The key to successful political dialogue will be Palestinians willing to discuss secure boundaries and stable political relations with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and Israelis willing to discuss territory and sovereignty with Palestinians,'' the statement said. `` We feel as Christian leaders in the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> community that we have a responsibility to ... pull factions that have been in conflict together, to be instruments of peace,'' said <PERSON> Mahony </PERSON>, chairman of the committee that drew up the statement. `` We see this as a moral challenge. There is a better way to live.'' The statement, `` Toward Peace in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>: Problems and Principles,'' will be presented to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bishops </ORGANIZATION>' fall meeting Nov. 6-9 in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>. Rabbi <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudin </PERSON>, national interreligious affairs director of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jewish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Banki </PERSON>, his associate, said they were troubled by the bishops' `` premature'' support for Palestinian sovereignty. They also said that in criticizing <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s handling of the Palestinian uprising, the prelates failed to give equal weight `` to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s very real problems and legitimate rights in maintaining order in the territories,'' and a 40-year history of terrorist attacks by Palestinians. An <LOCATION> Arab-American </LOCATION> leader praised the statement. `` The addition of such a respected moral voice on the side of Palestinian independence is an historic development at a critical juncture in the <LOCATION> Palestinian-Israeli </LOCATION> conflict,'' said <PERSON> Abdeen </PERSON> <PERSON> Jabara </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American-Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Anti-Discrimination </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` History will record that the moral authority of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> was indisputably on the side of peace in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>.'' The prelates cited Israeli responsibility in the beating deaths of Palestinians and people not involved in the uprising against <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s occupation of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, the demolition of homes and arrest and detention without trial. They said the statement was devised after consultations with the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>, religious leaders in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policymakers and major Jewish, <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> and Christian organizations. `` It is our conviction that a truly open moment for peace exists in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, and that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has an indispensable role to play in the peace process which has moved us to write this statement,'' said the committee. The nearly 2-year-old intefadeh, or <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> uprising, is a cry for justice and personal and political identity that demands `` on both moral and political grounds, a response by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> government,'' the prelates said. They stopped short of calling directly for the creation of a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state. But they said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> must go beyond the approach of the Camp David accords of the late 1970s, which gave Palestinians a secondary role in the peace process, and grant `` their right to participate as equals, through representatives selected by Palestinians, in all negotiations affecting their destiny.'' Having opened political discussions with the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> in December 1988, `` the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> now has the opportunity to use its influence and relationships to foster a more extensive dialogue among <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> and the <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> states,'' the prelates wrote. They also called for a `` clear, consistent'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy `` pressing Syrian withdrawal from <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>.'' They called on the Arab states and <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> to recognize <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s right to exist, and asked the Arab nations to establish full diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. `` Anything short of this leaves the ` legitimacy' of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> undefined in the policy of the Arab states, and reinforces <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s position that the only road to survival is one requiring superior military power.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0044EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Soviet-Unrest 1stLd-Writethru a0743 10-12 0728</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Unrest, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0743,0744</SECOND>
<HEAD>Armenians Call for Own Defense Units in Feud With Azerbaijan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: ADDS 6 grafs with newspaper report of Kremlin endorsing use
of force against April demonstration in Georgia. ^By CAREY GOLDBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tens of thousands of Armenians fed up with the ethnic conflict that has deprived them of food and fuel massed Wednesday and called for creating self-defense units, activists said. `` We consider it pointless to count on <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> any longer,'' said <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Shakhbazyan </PERSON>, an Armenian independence activist who described the rally by telephone from the <LOCATION> Caucasus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> republic </LOCATION>'s capital of <LOCATION> Yerevan </LOCATION>. `` People called for a free, independent <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> and there were appeals to the West and the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> for weapons support, because <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> is turning to open self-defense,'' Ms. <PERSON> Shakhbazyan </PERSON> said. The 19-month-old feud between Armenians and neighboring Azerbaijanis over control of the enclave of <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION> appeared to be only steps away from full-fledged civil war. <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION> has put a stranglehold on the Armenian economy the past two months by blocking much of the rail traffic intended for <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, including food, fuel and building supplies for repairing areas ravaged by the earthquake that killed 25,000 people in December. The Soviet legislature ordered the blockade lifted last week, but a top transport official said Wednesday trains still were having trouble getting through <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>. Railways Minister <PERSON> Nikolai </PERSON> <PERSON> Konarev </PERSON> said Azerbaijani nationalists were `` still taking measures to prevent trains that carry food and fuel from getting through. They sit down and lie down on the tracks,'' and have women and children do the same, he said on Soviet television. <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION> has a predominantly Christian Armenian population but was an enclave mostly of Moslem <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION> until February, when growing tensions prompted <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to impose direct rule. The move failed to ease tensions, however. <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION> is plagued with frequent armed clashes, widespread work stoppages, supply shortages and almost total blockage of its roads. Soviet troops have been stationed in <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION> to try to keep peace for the past year. Armenian speakers at Wednesday's rally said the troops ineffective and `` there was an appeal to creat self-defense units,'' said activist <PERSON> Mehat </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabrillian </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gabrillian </PERSON> said the meeting was called by 12 organizations that consider themselves a type of `` pre-parliament'' in preparation for <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>'s independence. In the lastest violence in <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION>, firefighters shot at a crowd of attackers Tuesday night and critically wounded at least eight people, officials said. <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Arshenevsky </PERSON> said the cadets were riding in 19 vehicles and crossing a bridge into <LOCATION> Stepanakert </LOCATION>, the enclave's capital, when a mob began throwing stones and firing on the passing column. He said the firefighters were forced to shoot in self-defense. However, representatives of the group that has led the campaign for the annexation of <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION> said the crowd was not violent. <PERSON> Ashot </PERSON> <PERSON> Manucharyan </PERSON>, an Armenian legislator from the region, said in a telephone interview from the headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> Karabakh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Yerevan </LOCATION> that the civilians were attracted to the bridge by warning shots fired into the air by the cadets. He said one civilian was killed. Meanwhile, a Soviet government commission investigating the use of military force to put down a peaceful nationalist demonstration in the nearby republic of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> in April said the decision to send in the troops was made in the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>, according to Thursday editions of The Washington Post. The <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> has said local authorities made the decision to use troops and denied involvement. But the commission, appointed by <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>'s legislature, disputed this, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. In the resulting clash in the Armenian capital of <LOCATION> Tbilisi </LOCATION>, 19 demonstrators were killed and hundreds injured by soldiers who dispersed them with sharpened shovels, clubs and poison gas. The commission said <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> was in constant communication with <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leaders in the area and was involved in an operation that was `` of a punishing nature, having the appearance of a deliberately planned slaughter of innocent people carried out with extraordinary cruelty.'' `` The principal blame is with the republic,'' the report said, `` but at the same time responsibility lies with officials of the central organs of power.'' The report said the final decision to allow the use of troops was made by <PERSON> Viktor </PERSON> <PERSON> Chebrikov </PERSON>, former head of the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Dimitri </PERSON> <PERSON> Yazov </PERSON>, the Soviet defense minister. It cast no direct blame on President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-UrbanETs     10-12 0604</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Urban ETs,0621</SECOND>
<HEAD>There's A Sign Post Up Ahead _ Queens?</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 That extraterrestrial story from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> may have been cleared up _ those 12-foot, tiny-headed guys who landed in the <LOCATION> U.S.S.R. </LOCATION> were just trying to get back to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. `` Anything's possible,'' says <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Knell </PERSON>, a local UFO researcher who firmly believes there was an alien presence in a park in the borough of <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION> seven months ago. `` Absolutely, there was some type of UFO in <LOCATION> Kissena </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Knell </PERSON>'s assertions _ he also said there may have been a return visit two weeks ago _ came two days after the Soviet news agency <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> reported the presence of ETs in the town of <LOCATION> Voronezh </LOCATION>. Since then, scientists have disparaged the report, attributing it to rising sensationalism in the Soviet press under `` glasnost,'' or greater openness. Neither story seemed to impress local residents, who were more concerned with <PERSON> Knell </PERSON>'s presence in the park than any report of visiting ETs. `` This is my haunt. I've been coming to this park for years, and there's nothing going on here,'' said <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, shaking her head and laughing. `` They say that tree there was burned by a UFO _ it was broken by kids swinging on the branches.'' Sure enough, <PERSON> Knell </PERSON> did offer the damaged willow as evidence that something had beamed down there. But he also offered a mineralogist's report that a burned oval on the ground contained particles of a type of feldspar quartz found on the island of <LOCATION> Aruba </LOCATION>, not in <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION>. `` We find this amazing,'' said <PERSON> Knell </PERSON>, who was joined by several other believers in UFOs. According to <PERSON> Knell </PERSON>, five people riding a bus on March 9 saw `` very bright lights'' hovering near a lake in the park. Since the park is located between <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> LaGuardia </LOCATION> airports, they initially thought it was a downed aircraft, said <PERSON> Knell </PERSON>. Based on their accounts and other evidence, <PERSON> Knell </PERSON> said, UFO investigators determined this was a legitimate sighting. <PERSON> Knell </PERSON> thinks he knows why the people who spotted something in <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION> never saw aliens or spoke with them. `` I believe they have their own agenda, and at this time it does n't include communication,'' said <PERSON> Knell </PERSON>, who on Wednesday addressed several skeptical reporters at the site where the UFO allegedly burned the ground. Unfortunately, that's also the site where the remnants of a downed tree were piled, killing off all the grass underneath, said park maintenance man <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Mackey </PERSON>, 60. `` If there was a spot around here burned out, I woulda known about it,'' said <PERSON> Mackey </PERSON>, who spends three days a week in the park. `` It's a figment of somebody's imagination.'' Perhaps, but <PERSON> Knell </PERSON>'s not alone. Some residents of <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> region say the Soviet description of a UFO is similar to a fast-moving metallic ball they spotted earlier this month <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Abide </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> said he first saw the object about three or four months ago. He saw it again early Wednesday while on his way to work at <ORGANIZATION> Abide </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aero </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Flying </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> about five miles south of <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION>. `` And it did n't come out of a bottle of vodka,'' he said, referring to some speculation about the Soviet witnesses. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Kimmel </PERSON>, a pilot, said he saw the object two days ago while flying to <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn </LOCATION>. He said it was round, metallic, kept changing colors and was moving 800 to 900 mph at 3,000 feet some distance off his left wingtip. `` There was no way it was a weather balloon because no balloon can travel that fast,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     10-12 0440</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0455</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Readers of the 1990 <ORGANIZATION> Guinness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Book </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION> will have plenty to cluck about besides the world's largest rooster. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Steele </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Banff </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, says his rooster named <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON> tipped the scales at a record 22 pounds, 1 ounce on July 4, 1989, but an 11-foot-high hairdo and a first-rate chin-balancing act are among the book's other tidbits. The book, which went on the market Wednesday, is `` exploding with the most astounding facts of nature, human endurance scientific achievement, entertainment, business and sports,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Sterling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement. Take that beehive hairdo, for instance. Team Hairfax of <LOCATION> Fairfax </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, built it onto a wig. <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> Villasenor </PERSON> walked around wearing it _ in public _ on July 29, 1989, `` without the wig tilting or falling,'' the book said. The chin-balancing record could escape even the greatest scholars. But Guinness readers will know that <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> balanced 24 milk crates, weighing 74 pounds, on his chin for 19 seconds at <LOCATION> Leyton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, on July 30, 1988. `` More amazing information is packed into this exciting volume than ever before, since more new records were set in the past year than in any since the book was first published,'' said the publisher. And if you ca n't cope with all that excitement, go to <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> _ the city most prolific in psychologists and psychiatrists, with `` one shrink per 328 heads.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PROVIDENCE, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Trinity Repertory Theater is counting its pennies, especially the ones that some patrons handed over for $ 24 tickets. But that's what theater officials expected when they told people to pay what they wanted. `` We got everything from a penny a ticket to $ 20 a ticket'' at Tuesday night's performance, spokeswoman <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Fortier </PERSON> said Wednesday. The only rule was that no one got in free. The audience of about 240 people for the performance of <PERSON> Maxim </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorky </PERSON>'s `` Summerfolk'' ranged `` from students to elderly from the apartment up the street,'' <PERSON> Fortier </PERSON> said. The crowd was larger than expected for a weekday night preview performance in the 550-seat theater, she said. Based on similar experiments in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Trinity </ORGANIZATION>'s managing director, <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Langan </PERSON>, said he expected people would be willing to pay between $ 3 and $ 4. <PERSON> Fortier </PERSON> said most people paid between $ 5 and $ 10. <PERSON> Langan </PERSON> said the theater had set aside $ 5,000 to cover the costs of the experiment. The average cost to produce a play is $ 30 a seat, he said. `` There are no guarantees, but we do intend to do it again'' depending on whether outside subsidies can be found, <PERSON> Fortier </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CleanAir Bjt   10-12 0664</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Clean Air, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Subcommittee Approves Bush Clean Air Plan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s clean air bill is advancing through a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> committee that once was a graveyard for air pollution legislation, but the measure is saddled with a conflict between top administration officials. Wednesday was a day of political triumph and confusion for the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> legislation, which was approved in modified form by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> environment subcommittee, 21-0. Except for an acid rain bill passed by the panel in 1986, the subcommittee has been deadlocked over clean air measures for a decade while its two most powerful members fought over automobile and utility emissions. This year, subcommittee Chairman <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, D-Calif., champion of strict controls on autos and industry, and Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Mich </LOCATION>., a friend of the auto industry, reached an historic agreement on auto emissions that ensured action on the The bill intended to clear the skies of urban smog, acid rain and toxic chemicals by the end of the century moves on to the full <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> _ possibly stopping first at another subcommittee for a debate on acid rain. But just before the subcommittee vote Wednesday, the panel was thrown into confusion by conflicting, nearly simultaneous statements from administration officials on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s plan for some cars to run on cleaner burning fuels than gasoline. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> clean fuels language was weakened by a 12-10 vote, with the bill's chief sponsors and most panel Republicans supporting the change backed by the oil and auto industries. Rep. <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Lent </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, said White House Chief of Staff <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> expressed the administration's neutrality on the clean fuels amendment, which eliminated <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s requirement that automakers build a million cars a year to run on alternative fuels. Lent and <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, the chief co-sponsors, backed the change which environmentalists said would weaken the legislation. But <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> said he, too, was called about the same time by <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON>. According to <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON> urged rejection of the amendment. `` I do n't know where the administration is and it may be all over the lot ... on both sides,'' <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> said. `` It tells a lot about how they're handling the bill.'' A White House spokesman, <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, said after the vote, `` We support the president's proposals on alternative fuels.'' He said <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> told Lent the administration wanted something close to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s language, and suggested changes in the amendment to that end. Lent never mentioned such changes during debate. The bill that passed the subcommittee considerably toughened <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s original auto emissions standards, thanks to the Oct. 3 <ORGANIZATION> Waxman-Dingell </ORGANIZATION> agreement to adopt nationwide <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s toughest-in-the-country auto tailpipe requirements But panel members all agreed that there will be more harsh words and vigorous debates as the bill advances through <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. There is disagreement over sharing the cost of acid rain reduction, a dispute over permitting expansion of coal burning utilities and argument over the severity of controls on chemical plants. Plus, the clean fuels issue is certain to surface again. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposal would have required auto companies to build 1 million clean-fuel cars a year from 1997 through 2004 in the nation's smoggiest cities. The new language, introduced by Reps. <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Fields </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>, would only require auto companies to certify they could build the cars, but the government would not order them built. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Sykes </PERSON>, a lobbyist for <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION>, said the carmakers did n't like <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s language because there was no guarantee consumers would buy the alternative-fuel vehicles. The amendment also would define clean fuels as anything that achieves the same pollution reductions as a mixture of 85 percent methanol and 15 percent gasoline. The oil industry contended the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plan would give the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> strong authority to choose a fuel and that the agency favored methanol. The oil industry argued that every clean-burning fuel should have an equal chance to power <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s future cars.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BabyDoctors Bjt   10-12 0747</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Baby Doctors, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poor Hurt Most as Fear of Lawsuits Drives Away Doctors, Study Finds</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fear of being sued is causing doctors to stop delivering babies, leaving impoverished women with poor obstetrical care and contributing to an increase in infant mortality, the Institute of Medicine says. `` Significant numbers'' of obstetricians, family physicians and nurse-midwives now are limiting their practices because of frequent malpractice lawsuits and sharply increasing insurance premiums, the institute study committee reported Wednesday. `` The fear of being sued has caused many doctors and midwives to limit care especially for women with high-risk pregnancies,'' said <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bulger </PERSON>, chairman of the committee and president of the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION>. `` In urban areas, this often means that low-income women have been hurt the most by the lack of providers,'' he said, but noted that there is a `` serious shortage of obstetrical care'' in both rural and inner areas. He said health providers tend to avoid patients with high-risk pregnancies. These most often are the impoverished because they generally are more likely to smoke and have poor diets, both of which increase the risks of having an imperfect child. One result, he said, is that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> ranks 19th in the world in infant mortality and, by some measures, the statistics f infant death are getting worse. `` In 1985, infant mortality for blacks and other non-whites actually increased for the first time in 20 years,'' said <PERSON> Bulger </PERSON>. `` While the causes for this increase are many, the inaccessibility of care for poor women, a situation clearly made worse by liability concerns, is an important factor.'' The committee, which includes doctors, lawyers and educators, suggested both short-term and long-term solutions. Immediate actions recommended were: _ State subsidies for medical liability premiums for obstetrical providers who treat women on Medicaid _ Reviving the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> This would provide more loans for medical students who then would be obligated to serve in areas where physicians are in short supply. For more permanent solutions, the committee recommended: _ State experiments with alternatives to the system of medical liability Possible models could include a no-fault compensation system for certain conditions, such as neurological impairment of a newborn. Also suggested were negotiated contracts between doctor and patient, and establishing in advance a system of binding arbitration to settle disputes. _ Consideration of a plan by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> that calls for an administrative processing of claims that would determine fault, fix awards and discipline offenders The committee found that legal claims against obstetricians run two to three times higher than for other medical specialties, and that juries are twice as likely to find for the plaintiff in cases where an obstetrician is the defendant. `` It is easy to understand this situation, since most cases involve brain-damaged infants whose parents generally are without the resources to provide for a lifetime of complex health care,'' <PERSON> Bulger </PERSON> said. Malpractice insurance premiums for obstetrics in some cities now exceed $ 100,000 a year _ and sometimes the pro-rated cost per delivery is higher than the Medicaid reimbursement for a normal delivery, the committee found. Members of the committee said they found a number of misperceptions on the part of both patients and baby doctors. Dr. <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Herbst </PERSON>, chairman of the department of obstetrics at the <ORGANIZATION> Pritzker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION>, said many doctors mistakenly believe poor families are more apt to sue if there is a poor result from childbirth. Another misperception, said Dr. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Medearis </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, professor of pediatrics at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, is that obstetricians are to blame for all of the mental retardation problems that occur in newborns. `` We do n't know what causes most mental retardation,'' he said. The committee said the number of obstetrical care providers in rural areas has fallen by 20 percent over the last five years. In some states, said <PERSON> Bulger </PERSON>, there are whole counties where there is no obstetrical care available. Doctors' fear of liability is also contributing to an increase in the number of babies delivered by cesarean section, <PERSON> Herbst </PERSON> said. The committee said that 20 years ago, only one in 20 babies was delivered by the surgical procedure, but the rate in some areas now is one in four babies. The Institute of Medicine is chartered by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>. It is a private organization that acts as an advisor to the federal government and initiates research of its own.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Italy Bjt   10-12 0608</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Italy, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Asks Italy to Investigate Alleged Computer Sale to Soviets</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is asking <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> to investigate allegations that an Italian company violated Western export control rules and sold the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> computer equipment used to manufacture a highly sophisticated jetfighter. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> case regarding the Italian <ORGANIZATION> Olivetti </ORGANIZATION> company, which officials say is based on intelligence information, was brought up Wednesday at a White House meeting between President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Italian President <PERSON> Francesco </PERSON> <PERSON> Cossiga </PERSON>. `` The President did mention the concern about the Olivetti case. And President <PERSON> Cossiga </PERSON> stressed that this was being pursued in ... a highly cooperative manner,'' said Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Seitz </PERSON>, briefing reporters about <PERSON> Cossiga </PERSON>'s talks with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> notified <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> earlier this month that <PERSON> Olivetti </PERSON>, one of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s largest computer companies, was suspected of violating rules set by the 17-nation <ORGANIZATION> Coordinating </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Multilateral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Export </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Controls </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> COCOM </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-, said <LOCATION> Italian </LOCATION> Foreign Minister <PERSON> Gianni </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Michelis </PERSON>. He said <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> was investigating the information and would inform the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> of the results at a meeting Oct. 22 in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> with <PERSON> Reginald </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartholomew </PERSON>, assistant secretary of state for science and technology. In <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, Premier <PERSON> Giulio </PERSON> <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON> met for about an hour Wednesday with <ORGANIZATION> Olivetti </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Carlo </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Benedetti </PERSON>. Neither made any statements at the end of the meeting, although <ORGANIZATION> Olivetti </ORGANIZATION> has issued a statement denying any violation of <ORGANIZATION> COCOM </ORGANIZATION> rules and contending the products in question were shipped to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> with <ORGANIZATION> COCOM </ORGANIZATION> authorization. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Italian officials have refused to publicly discuss details of the case, which involves one of the most powerful companies in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and sensitive intelligence information about Soviet weaponry. But an American official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said <PERSON> Olivetti </PERSON> was suspected of selling the Soviets machine tools and computer software which were used to manufacture components for the YAK-41 supersonic jetfighter. The highly sophisticated plane is capable of taking off vertically. Another official said the sales had been going on for several years, and involved `` less than $ 50 million.'' Members of <ORGANIZATION> COCOM </ORGANIZATION>, which regulates the sale of high-technology to communist countries, have differed in recent years regarding sales of so-called `` dual use'' technology, which can be converted to manufacture weapons. The most famous case of such a <ORGANIZATION> COCOM </ORGANIZATION> rule violation involved the sale of computerized milling equipment by the Japanese <ORGANIZATION> Toshiba </ORGANIZATION> electronics firm and the Norwegian state-owned <ORGANIZATION> Kongsberg </ORGANIZATION> conglomerate to the Soviets. The equipment was used by the Soviets to make silent propellers for submarines, making them harder for the West to detect. As a result, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> passed legislation last year empowering the administration to impose sanctions, including import bans, against companies found in violation of <ORGANIZATION> COCOM </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Michelis </PERSON> sought to play down the <ORGANIZATION> Olivetti </ORGANIZATION> case, saying he had only discussed the matter for `` 25 seconds'' with <PERSON> Bartholomew </PERSON> Wednesday. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Michelis </PERSON> stressed that the main thrust of the Cossiga talks with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was prospects for peace in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, the upcoming elections in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and, above all, the reforms in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Seitz </PERSON> told reporters <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cossiga </PERSON> `` waxed philosophical about East-West issues and the importance of defense throughout this period of change in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` stressed how in these times of transition and uncertainty and, in some instances, unrest, that the hope not precede the deed and that the importance of a strong defense, a continuing defense, a steady approach, a long-term approach can not be understated.'' Later at a state dinner <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> hosted in <PERSON> Cossiga </PERSON>'s honor at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the American president lauded the friendship between <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, saying the ties have `` never been stronger.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-OurLadyofExxon     10-12 0699</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Our Lady of Exxon,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arlington Temple: A Tiger for Your Tank, Salvation for Your Soul</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROSSLYN, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Looking for a different worship experience? Consider `` Our Lady of <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>,'' a local Methodist church where you can drive in for gasoline and a lube job, then walk upstairs for some fire and brimstone. And if you do n't think God is watching, be forewarned that <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> spooks might be peering down from their shuttered office windows next door. For 17 years, the white steeple of <ORGANIZATION> Arlington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> has towered over a busy intersection in the heart of this high-rise hotel and office building suburb just across the <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Thousands of neighboring office workers have given the Arlington Temple its irreverent nickname because of the red, white and blue <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> signs that beckon motorists to the gas pumps on the open-air ground floor beneath the church. As far as anyone knows, <ORGANIZATION> Arlington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> is the only combination church and filling station in the country, the result of a deal between a local businessman and a minister searching for a place to house his congregation. In the early 1960s, when developers began razing <LOCATION> Rosslyn </LOCATION>'s taverns, pawn shops and decaying homes, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ames </PERSON> decided to build a hotel on part of his lumber yard and donate another parcel for a church in his father's memory But first, <PERSON> Ames </PERSON> had to relocate a gas station sitting on a corner of his property. Along came the Rev. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, whose flock had been worshiping in hotels, a school and a carpenter's shop. The pastor wanted to build a `` church of the marketplace in the concrete jungle of <LOCATION> Rosslyn </LOCATION>,'' a place where `` bishop or bum, rich or pauper, influential or nameless'' could find a spiritual home. Under their deal, <PERSON> Ames </PERSON> donated the land for the new church, and <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> agreed to rent the ground floorto the gas station. Arlington Temple was completed in 1972 at a cost of $ 750,000. The mortgage was paid off last year, thanks partly to the $ 18,000 in annual rent from Exxon. Today, the Rev. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> and station operator <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamblett </PERSON> are close pals and partners of sorts, as <PERSON> Hamblett </PERSON> puts a tiger in his customers' tanks and <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> pumps his message of salvation for the soul. The <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> recruiting office in the 12-story building next door keeps its business to itself. During the gasoline crunch in the 1970s, <PERSON> Hamblett </PERSON> opened his station for an hour after Sunday services so elderly parishioners could fill up without waiting in long lines. <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> exchanged his black robes for a pair of overalls to help <PERSON> Hamblett </PERSON> pump gas. <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> says he can always borrow a few dollars from <PERSON> Hamblett </PERSON> to help a family in distress, and <PERSON> Hamblett </PERSON> volunteers as <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION> for church Christmas festivities. After years of standing at the church's rear door, observing Sunday services in grease-stained denims, <PERSON> Hamblett </PERSON> recently became a formal member of <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Temple </LOCATION> with his family. `` <PERSON> Jack </PERSON>'s a really great guy,'' <PERSON> Hamblett </PERSON> says. `` I would n't be in business without him.'' <PERSON> Hamblett </PERSON> explains that some of his customers have gotten nasty since the Exxon oil spill in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. They've spit in his face and threatened to pour motor oil in his fish tank. `` I can go upstairs and talk to <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> for five minutes and feel all is right with the world again,'' he said. <PERSON> Hamblett </PERSON> unwittingly provided the sound effects for a Saturday wedding ceremony that <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> conducted a few years ago. Just as <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> uttered the words, `` Let them speak now or forever hold their peace,'' <PERSON> Hamblett </PERSON> revved his drag racing car's 3,000-horsepower engine in the garage below A deafening roar filled the sanctuary, penetrating 18-inch walls and floors of reinforced steel and concrete that are designed to shut out noise. `` It actually vibrated the whole building,'' <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> recalled. `` The groom sort of went into mild shock. I sent a minister friend downstairs to tell <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> to turn it off, and told the congregation ` that was not an objection.''' <PERSON> Hamblett </PERSON> says he learned his lesson. `` If I hear organ music, I try to keep the noise down,'' he says.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HispanicPopulation     10-12 0378</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hispanic Population,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hispanic Population Tops 20 Million</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has more than 20 million Hispanic residents, the <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> reports, meaning only five other countries have larger Latin American populations. `` This is our first estimate of over 20 million,'' <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Del </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinal </PERSON>, chief of the Ethnic and Hispanic Statistics Branch at the bureau, said Wednesday. `` It's up from about 14.5 million in 1980.'' <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> has the largest Latin American population at more than 147 million people. The only other countries in this hemisphere with more Hispanics than the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are: <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> with 86.7 million; <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, 31.9 million; <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, 31.2 million and <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, 21.4 million. The new Census analysis showed that as of last March Hispanics constituted 8.2 percent of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> population and are the fastest growing large population group. The bureau said immigration accounted for about half the growth. About two-thirds of the Hispanics in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> live in just three states. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> leads with 34 percent, followed by <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> at 21 percent and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> with 10 percent. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> has 8 percent of the nation's Hispanics, and there are significant populations in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, the bureau reported. Estimates are not prepared for every state because `` Hispanics are not well spread out throughout the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> Del </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pinal </ORGANIZATION> said. The Census report estimated the total Hispanic population of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> at 20,076,000 as of March, up from 19,431,000 a year earlier. The largest segment is Mexicans at 12,567,000, followed by people of <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> origin, 2,545,000, Puerto Ricans, 2,328,000, and Cubans, 1,068,000. The balance were of Spanish or other Hispanic origin. Mexicans were mostly concentrated in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, the report said. Cubans are mostly in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, while Puerto Ricans tend to live in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, and Central and South Americans are largely in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. While Mexicans were the largest group they are not the fastest growing, the report said. Comparing the estimates for 1982 and 1989, the bureau said Central and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Americans </LOCATION> had increased by 67 percent. The `` other Hispanic'' category rose 31 percent, followed by Mexicans, up 30 percent, Puerto Ricans, 14 percent and Cubans, 12 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PuppyDelivery     10-12 0259</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Puppy Delivery,0269</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pizza Man Delivers Puppy After Car Runs Over Dog</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GRAND ISLAND, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three sisters got an unexpected delivery from the pizza man who had accidentally ran over the family dog: a fluffy, white puppy to help make up for the loss. `` I was in tears,'' said the girls' mother, <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mendyk </PERSON>. `` I could n't believe he did something like that. It restored my faith in young people.'' <PERSON> Brett </PERSON> <PERSON> Croner </PERSON>, 20, accidently killed the first dog during a Saturday night run for Pizza Hut. <PERSON> Croner </PERSON> said he knew how the girls felt because his own dog was killed by a car last spring. `` To lose one is to lose a part of yourself,'' he said. Mrs. <PERSON> Mendyk </PERSON> said her daughters, <PERSON> Rachel </PERSON>, 8, <PERSON> Sara </PERSON>, 9, and <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON>, 12, were all smiles when <PERSON> Croner </PERSON> brought the new dog Sunday afternoon. She said <PERSON> Croner </PERSON> had stopped and apologized to the family on the night of the accident, but she told him it was n't his fault because the 3-year-old dog, <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON>, was chasing a cat. `` I've had people get more upset about me dropping a pizza than me running over their dog,'' <PERSON> Croner </PERSON> said. Still, <PERSON> Croner </PERSON> said he was determined to help ease the girls' pain After looking at about eight or nine different pups, he found a mixed-breed, female dog that looked like <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON>. He left the puppy at the door of the Mendyks' house with a note that read, `` Please accept this puppy as my apology.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Mendyk </PERSON> said the girls have named the 6-week-old dog <PERSON> Brett </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0142EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SaudiTanks     10-12 0643</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Saudi Tanks,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arab Arms Deal Moves Ahead</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A $ 3 billion <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms purchase by <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> faces little apparent opposition from <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s supporters on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration on Wednesday informally notified <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> of the intended sale. That touched off a 50-day period in which <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> either kills the deal by majority votes in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> or lets it go through. The key items are 315 modern tanks, but two-thirds of the price tag _ which is equivalent to a year's <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> _ is the cost of equipment and ammunition, including huge trucks to transport any tanks that break down. Rep. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., said more than two dozen members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had written to Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> requesting `` additional consultation. But before notifying <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> of the plan, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> and other administration officials held several sessions designed to gauge congressional sentiment. `` We intend to have a full hearing,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. Yet, the congressman added in an interview: `` I do n't think anyone is inclined yet to file a resolution of disapproval. We want to be sure these tanks are not used by anyone else in the region.'' Political maneuvering in recent weeks managed to diffuse the concerns that customarily touch off strong opposition on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> deals with <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> countries technically at war with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. The Saudis would receive the M1A2 tanks beginning in the middle of the 1990s, at about the same time the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> would field them. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has a comparable tank, the Merkava. To smooth congressional approval, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration agreed not to equip the Saudi tanks with plates of uranium armor, a much denser metal than steel. It was not immediately clear where the tanks would be based. If some are deployed at the <ORGANIZATION> Tabuk </ORGANIZATION> military base the tanks would be only 120 miles from <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Others may be based near <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>, and still others at an armored training school near <LOCATION> Mecca </LOCATION>. In a separate deal, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> is to receive $ 100 million in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> payments for the pre-positioning of American military equipment. The arms presumably would be used in the event of a <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> war that threatened <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> security. Next year, <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> is expected to try to purchase American jet fighter planes. The purchase of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tanks to replace 15-year-old and largely inoperable French tanks is considered a warm-up test of congressional sentiment. Asked why <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s supporters had not launched a fight against the sale, a local military expert said the administration consulted in advance with members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and `` an effort is under way to avoid a confrontation.'' `` Besides, the tanks are a ground system, having a marginal effect on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s security,'' said the non-governmental expert, who spoke on condition of anonymity. Administration officials have stressed in recent weeks the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commitment to make sure <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> maintains a qualitative edge over Arab armed forces. The Saudi tanks will be equipped with special viewers for the commanders and with night-fighting capability. Also, they will have no electronics. `` It is the most advanced version of the tank that has been put out to date,'' the expert said. Last year, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration signed a deal with <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> for the manufacture of 555 tanks for the Egyptian army. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> declined to discuss the purchase except to say <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had been informally notified of the administration's intention. The purchase was designed initially as a goodwill gesture for a visit by King Fahd. But twice this summer the <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> monarch canceled trips to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> with the explanation his government was engaged in trying to arrange a cease-fire in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> between warring Christian and Moslem factions. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> over the years has turned back several <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms sales to <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> countries out of concern for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s security.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0143EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NewsSurvey     10-12 0625</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-News Survey,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Zsa Zsa Outdraws Pierce, Frank in Public Interest</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four out of five Americans know why <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON> has been in the news lately, but only about one in 10 can identify <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> or Barney Frank without help, according to a news industry survey. The survey, released Wednesday by the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mirror </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; the Press, showed that <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> news gets a low rating when people are asked what stories they are following very closely. Stories about <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> congressman from <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> who has admitted having sex with a male prostitute and then hiring him as a personal aide and driver, were followed by only 6 percent of those surveyed. This made the <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> affair one of the lowest-interest stories since the surveys began in 1986, equaled only by the influence-peddling scandal that drove former Japanese Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> from office in May. Only 12 percent of the 1,234 adults interviewed by telephone correctly identified <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>. Ten percent knew that <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> was the former housing secretary whose administration of rental subsidy programs for the poor is under investigation by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. But 80 percent knew that Ms. <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON> was tried in <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, on charges of slapping a policeman. The survey was conducted Oct. 5-8, a week after the actress was convicted. The most closely followed story in the survey was Hurricane Hugo, with 60 percent saying they kept up with developments closely. This made it the third-ranking story in public interest since the surveys began, exceeded only by the 1986 Challenger space craft explosion at 80 percent and the rescue of young <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> McClure </PERSON> from a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> well in 1987, which 69 percent said they kept up on. <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mirror </ORGANIZATION> said in a news release that the difference in public response to the <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> stories `` is in keeping with a pattern that has become clear from the monthly findings of the Times Mirror News Interest Index. Public attentiveness to coverage of news events is high, while public attentiveness to news about most personal scandals is usually low.'' Times Mirror also said its October findings `` dramatically reinforced'' previous indications that news from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, even when it has far-reaching consequences, often gets little attention. No major <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> story in the latest survey was followed closely by as many as 25 percent of Americans. The most closely followed <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> story in the history of the surveys was the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision in July upholding a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> law against burning the American flag. It was followed closely by 51 percent of those surveyed. Overseas stories often get a low rating also. The elevation of the once-outlawed <ORGANIZATION> Solidarity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> to a role in governing <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, for instance, was followed closely by only 12 percent of those surveyed in July. In the latest count even interest in overseas events, such as the flight of East German refugees to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> at 31 percent and the failed coup attempt in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> at 29 percent, outdrew <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> stories. Only 19 percent paid close attention to attempts in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to repeal the new catastrophic illness insurance plan. Among persons over age 50, this rose to 36. House approval of a cut in the capital gains tax drew close attention from 14 percent. Among people with family incomes of $ 50,000 or more, this increased to 26 percent. The study was conducted by the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mirror </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; the Press, a division of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mirror </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>, which publishes the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Times, <ORGANIZATION> Newsday </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sun </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> Courant and other newspapers and owns broadcast stations. The center said the study was subject to a 3 percent sampling error.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EcclesiaAnniversary     10-12 0648</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ecclesia Anniversary,0672</SECOND>
<HEAD>One Year After Girl's Death, 40 Children Still in Custody</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto PD1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB BAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WOODBURN, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A year ago Saturday, members of a religious group brought the body of an 8-year-old girl to a rural fire station. The death of <PERSON> Dayna </PERSON> <PERSON> Broussard </PERSON> set off a child abuse investigation that is far from over. The next night, 53 <ORGANIZATION> Ecclesia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> children were taken into state custody. Today, 40 remain in foster homes because their parents wo n't agree to conditions set by the state Children's Services Division `` I think this is the only time in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> that so many children have been taken into care on such a crisis basis under such horrible circumstances,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, the agency administrator. Parents of the children live at a farmhouse near <LOCATION> Sandy </LOCATION>, east of <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, where the youngsters were rounded up by state officials 12 months ago. State officials want the adults to admit their children were victims of abuse and to promise that they wo n't be abused again. `` We're still working with their parents,'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said. `` We would like very much to make the kind of commitment that we in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> need to hear so their children can be safe.'' One parent they have n't worked with is <PERSON> Dayna </PERSON>'s father, <PERSON> Eldridge </PERSON> <PERSON> Broussard </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, the founder of <LOCATION> Ecclesia </LOCATION>. State officials believe he is in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, but his whereabouts could not be determined this week. A telephone call to Ecclesia officials for comment was not returned. On Wednesday, the state officials held a news conference at the juvenile detention center where the children were taken on Oct. 14, 1988. `` Why we are here today is to remember <PERSON> Dayna </PERSON> <PERSON> Broussard </PERSON> and ... to remember that <PERSON> Dayna </PERSON> did not die accidentally. <PERSON> Dayna </PERSON> was brutally, ceaselessly, needlessly beaten to death,'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said. Four adult Ecclesia members were convicted of manslaughter. A fifth member was convicted of criminal mistreatment in connection with other beatings of children. Several children testified at the trial that they were systematically beaten as part of the group's tough discipline. They said that <PERSON> Dayna </PERSON> was beaten with an electrical cord, rubber hose, piece of plastic pipe and weightlifting belt as the other children were forced to watch and count the blows. <PERSON> Eldridge </PERSON> <PERSON> Broussard </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> appeared on the `` <PERSON> Oprah </PERSON> <PERSON> Winfrey </PERSON> Show'' after the arrests of Ecclesia members and blamed the media's negative publicity about the group for his daughter's death <PERSON> Broussard </PERSON>, a former college basketball player, founded <ORGANIZATION> Ecclesia </ORGANIZATION> in 1975 at the <ORGANIZATION> Watts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> to steer children away from drugs and crime. He motivated them through discipline and athletics, saying once he wanted to prepare them to compete in the Olympics. The group came to <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> in the summer of 1987 and announced plans to cultivate crops and train children for athletic competition. Since the manslaughter convictions of his associates, <PERSON> Broussard </PERSON>, who was not charged, has kept a low profile. `` He's not had any contact with the caseworker for his family. He has n't had any contact with me. He has n't appeared in court hearings. He has n't been involved in any of the meetings or contacts that we've had,'' said <PERSON> Bart </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Clackamas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> branch manager for the children's services agency. <PERSON> Broussard </PERSON>'s four surviving children are in state custody. He has n't seen them; his wife has, <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. The state has spent $ 545,000 on the case as of July, and continues to spend about $ 10,000 per month for foster care. Of the 53 children taken by the state, two were returned to the custody of their parents, while 11 others remain under state jurisdiction but live with relatives. The 40 in foster homes are impatient to reunite with their parents. `` A year to you and I is 10 years to a kid,'' said caseworker <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Huntley </PERSON>. `` No one can tell them what will happen tomorrow and that's really difficult for them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0142EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Panama-Noriega     10-12 0358</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-Noriega,0370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Noriega: U.S. Recruited, Paid Junior Officers to Launch Coup</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Panamanian officers who led last week's abortive coup were recruited and paid more than $ 1 million by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government, Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> charged in an interview The Panamanian leader also alleged that <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> businessmen and Nicaraguan Contras served as messengers for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, relaying messages between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the plotters, the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported in Thursday's editions. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was involved before, during and after the coup,'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said. `` They had to make the contacts, woo them, convince them. It's a lot of work before you've hooked the fish. But they were the hook and the useful fools were the fish.'' `` The Contras put them the coup plotters in contact with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said that an investigation following the uprising revealed the existence of a bank account in the name of Capt. <PERSON> Erick </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Murillo </PERSON>, one of the alleged coup leaders, containing more than $ 1 million. `` There was a lot of money there for a normal Panamanian. Six zeroes. It was a million-dollar account,'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said. He charged that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials gave <PERSON> Murillo </PERSON> the money for bribes, but would not identify the bank that held the account. <PERSON> Murillo </PERSON>, a member of the elite Battalion 2000, was one of 10 officers the Panamanian government said was killed during the coup attempt. While government reports have said 37 soldiers were detained following the attempt, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said 77 have been. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> also said that one of the detained rebels had $ 700,000 in cash that he had been using to bribe the troops. He refused to identify the soldier but said he is still in custody. The coup was masterminded by 17 members of the <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> also accused <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> member <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Briggs </PERSON> of involvement in the conspiracy, because <PERSON> Briggs </PERSON> visited the country shortly before the uprising. <PERSON> Briggs </PERSON> served as ambassador to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and then as ambassador to <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, where the Nicaraguan rebels were based. There was no immediate comment from <PERSON> Briggs </PERSON> or an <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in the newspaper's account.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891012-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-89 0147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Panama-Noriega     10-12 0768</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama-Noriega,0799</SECOND>
<HEAD>Noriega's New Rule: Kill or Be Killed</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto PAN1</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CANDICE HUGHES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
