<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 2345EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SuperCelebration 1stLd-Writethru a0791 01-22 0617</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Super Celebration, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0791,0630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Town Revels In 49er Super Bowl Victory</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS one graf after 1st graf to UPDATE with arrests, road
closings. Subs penultimate graf with two grafs to UPDATE with comment from
cable company affected by video pirates. A version moving on sports wires.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By THOMAS MURPHY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Horns blared, fireworks lighted the sky and strangers kissed in the streets Sunday night as fans celebrating the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> 49ers Super Bowl victory turned the town into an impromptu open-air party. Authorities closed several streets and Highway 480 near the Embarcadero because of crowds. Police reported numerous arrests, most for public drunkenness, but did not have exact figures. Roman candles rocketed aloft as fans in the largely Hispanic Mission District erupted into the streets to celebrate the 20-16 last-minute victory over the <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bengals </ORGANIZATION>. `` We stomped them like bugs in a barn,'' said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernhard </PERSON>, 21, from his post on a jammed street corner. `` For the last five minutes, it was like having an electric eel attached to your spine.'' `` I feel great,'' said <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Anaya </PERSON>, 20, of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> as he jumped up and down on a crowded sidewalk, waving a 6-foot-long 49ers banner. `` I knew it all the way. I never gave up, I never gave up.'' A man leaned from an apartment window overlooking Mission Street, and played a trombone. `` We expect the unusual right now,'' said Officer <PERSON> Stephanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Thorne </PERSON> at the Mission District police station. `` Cars driving by with their boom boxes, honking their horns. They're going pretty good out there.'' Additional officers were on duty for the evening, <PERSON> Thorne </PERSON> said, although she could n't say how many. At the jammed Mad Hatter sports bar, fans leaped into the air, roaring, slapping high fives and wagging fingers at the television screen. At <PERSON> Perry </PERSON>'s, a bar, host <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> said the atmosphere has been `` insane'' all day. `` They've been going crazy ...,'' <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> said. `` We knew we were going to win it.'' `` You ca n't walk on the street, you ca n't get in the door,'' he said. `` That's what's going on. We had fire trucks, horses and police blowing their sirens. It was great. Now they're blocking off the street.'' At a <LOCATION> Redwood </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> bar-restaurant called <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>'s, which is owned by former 49ers wide receiver <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, the crowd `` went crazy'' when 49er quarterback <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Montana </PERSON> was shown on the post-game show wearing a hat advertising the tavern, said hostess <PERSON> Pameaux </PERSON> <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON>. `` We had people on top of people and people on each other's laps, sitting, standing, leaning,'' she said. Elsewhere, the broadcast of the game was interrupted for fans in at least two parts of the country. In <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, the audio portion of a cable television broadcast was disrupted for a few seconds with music from `` The Jetsons'' cartoon and an anti-Semitic slur. `` First there was music from ` The Jetsons' cartoon show. Then someone said something about Century Cable and ` there's too many -LRB- expletive deleted -RRB- Jews in this industry,''' said <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Debber </PERSON>, a viewer in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monica </LOCATION>. The interruption occurred about 3:15 p.m. when an audio signal invaded Century's cable system, affecting viewers in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monica </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, a company official said. `` I'm baffled at how it was done and I'm shocked and outraged at the statements that were made,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosendahl </PERSON>, vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Century </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monica </LOCATION>. In eastern <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and the northern panhandle of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, viewers of <ORGANIZATION> WTOV </ORGANIZATION> television missed much of the second quarter. Technical problems put the station off the air for about 25 minutes, a station worker said. The station serves a market of 154,000 households.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 2359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Heartland-MotorCities 2Takes   01-22 1025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Heartland-Motor Cities, 2 Takes,1054</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Changing Heartland</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Part I: Cornfields and College Towns _ and Cars</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Profound changes are at work in the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>, sent reeling this decade with blows to its auto, steel and farming powerhouses. For autos, the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> was the place, <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> the hub. <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> also boasted auto plants. Now, Japanese automakers are setting up shop in rural, largely white communities and jobs are becoming increasingly scarce for big-city blacks. The first story in a four-part AP Extra series, `` The Changing Heartland,'' examines this trend.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>By SHARON COHEN</NOTE>
<NOTE>Associated Press Writer</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NORMAL, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With a college campus and fertile fields, this patch of <ORGANIZATION> mid-America </ORGANIZATION> is a place where students learn and farmers earn side by side. But corn country has a new face producing a new crop _ cars. Last fall, this tranquil town and its twin city, <LOCATION> Bloomington </LOCATION>, joined a growing number of smaller <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> locales with Japanese-associated plants that are shaking up the auto industry. The increasing Japanese presence in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s midsection _ plants in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, one planned for <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Chrysler-Mitsubishi </PERSON> here _ is creating work and growth in white rural areas while jobs and opportunity disappear in heavily minority big cities. `` Certainly, it's a restructuring of the auto industry,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> urban affairs and sociology professor. `` The reorganization ... is definitely detrimental to blacks.'' The trend has aroused concern in a business that's already lost thousands of blue-collar jobs, raised questions about potential bias, and worried blacks, who've long regarded the auto industry as a steppingstone to a better life. `` Auto shops were really the bridge that brought black people from the lower class to the middle class,'' said <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, former head of a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> local at a closed <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> plant. `` What are you going to do for the people left behind, locked up in the ghetto who have no place to go and no car to get out to rural areas?'' Japanese automakers, who've invested $ 5 billion in U.S.-based facilities in the last decade, point to their affirmative action programs and insist transportation, education and the work ethic _ not race _ determine location. But some academics also claim the Japanese generally avoid unionized areas and towns with large pools of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> autoworkers, preferring to train novices. Whatever the reason, communities such as Bloomington-Normal _ thriving, white-collar towns that are worlds apart from gasping-for-survival, blue-collar cities like <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> _ are becoming motor capitals. `` It's just a different culture,'' said <LOCATION> Bloomington </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Smart </PERSON>. `` This whole city is like a big neighborhood. -LRB- And -RRB- with modern auto plants being clean, it's not smokestack anymore; it's compatible with agriculture. In Bloomington-Normal, insurance, farming and academia are big. Urban blight, crime and unemployment are not. Bloomington-Normal, 4 percent minority, had a 4.1 percent unemployment rate in October. <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, 65 percent minority, had a 10.1 percent jobless level. Studies have shown black men have been devastated by industrial decline. In the <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> area, 52 percent of black men in heavy manufacturing production lost their jobs from 1979 to 1984, according to a study by <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> State's <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>. Nationwide, about 27 percent of blacks lost their heavy manufacturing jobs in the same period, said the study, based on <ORGANIZATION> Equal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opportunity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> reports. Future prospects are even bleaker. A 1988 study concluded Japanese `` behavior with regard to site location and hiring practices heightens rather than eases the dilemma of blacks who are being rapidly displaced from their traditional American employers.'' The study, by <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> professors <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> and <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Deskins </PERSON>, said although they had no concrete evidence, they believe `` avoidance of blacks is one factor'' for the Japanese in determining plant sites. `` I think it's a factor,'' <PERSON> Deskins </PERSON> said. `` I ca n't say this is their intent.'' The study found while blacks comprise 11 percent of the civilian labor force, they represent 17.2 percent of workers at the Big Three <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> automakers. In contrast, the study said, <ORGANIZATION> Mazda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturing </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>'s plant in <LOCATION> Flat </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, has a potential black labor pool of 29 percent and <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, in <LOCATION> Marysville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, has one of 10.5 percent. Company officials say their black workforce is 15.1 percent and 5.1 percent, respectively. <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Lambert </PERSON> disagreed with the calculations and also pointed out the company recruits at black colleges. <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION>, however, agreed last March to give $ 6 million to 377 blacks and women after an <ORGANIZATION> EEOC </ORGANIZATION> investigation concluded they should have been hired sooner. The <ORGANIZATION> EEOC </ORGANIZATION> claimed <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION> employed discriminatory practices with a 30-mile hiring radius that excluded <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, which has the area's largest minority population. <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION>, which expanded its hiring area before the settlement, admitted no wrongdoing. Many Japanese-associated auto plants are close to universities and near Interstate 75, dubbed Auto Alley, which stretches south from <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Toyota </ORGANIZATION> is in <LOCATION> Georgetown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, near the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kentucky </ORGANIZATION>; Chrysler-Mitsubishi is in Normal, home of <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, while <ORGANIZATION> Subaru-Isuzu </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Automotive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> is near <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, across the river from <LOCATION> Purdue </LOCATION>. These towns say automakers are attracted to cheaper land, lower taxes, open space and a well-educated work force. Bloomington-Normal, population 87,718, was appealing because of its good highway and rail systems, incentives, strong work ethic and schools, said <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON>, former chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Diamond-Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, the firm formed by <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION>. `` We needed people with very good communication skills _ verbal, written and reading,'' he said. `` Some of the major larger cities have a very difficult time graduating significant numbers of students.'' In <LOCATION> Tippecanoe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, surrounding <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION>, one in four people 25 years and older has four years of college, said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Greater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lafayette </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Progress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a non-profit development corporation. `` What kind of public education system does <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> have?'' he asked. `` What kind of technological capability in terms of college graduates does <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> have? `` There's no God-given right big cities should be viewed as the automotive centers,'' he said. `` We small towns, technologically sophisticated centers, think we can compete, too.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 2359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Heartland-MotorCities-1stAdd     01-22 0358</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Heartland-Motor Cities - 1st Add,0370</SECOND>
<HEAD>NORMAL: compete, too.''</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 They do, engaging in fierce bidding wars, offering free land and water, road and sewer improvements, employee training funds and tax abatements. Chrysler-Mitsubishi received $ 88.7 million in state incentives alone, including 630 acres of farm land. `` Nobody ever offered us a site in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> ... Detroit ... -LRB- or -RRB- <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> said. Experts also say Japanese automakers prefer areas where unions are n't strong. `` They're afraid wages will be high,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Japanese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` They're afraid unions will create demands that will make the company unproductive.'' <ORGANIZATION> Mazda </ORGANIZATION> is atypical _ it is 25 miles from <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> and, spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Gill </PERSON> said, the only wholly owned subsidiary of a Japanese automaker with <ORGANIZATION> UAW </ORGANIZATION> affiliation. `` If you're going to locate in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Gill </PERSON> said, `` you best be prepared to deal with the <ORGANIZATION> UAW </ORGANIZATION>.'' <ORGANIZATION> Mazda </ORGANIZATION>, because of its location, also has many former Big Three employees _ nearly a fourth of its workers. But <PERSON> Vladmir </PERSON> <PERSON> Pucik </PERSON>, international business professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION>, said the Japanese prefer `` a relatively inexperienced labor force so they can train them in the Japanese way of doing things. They want to go somewhere so nobody will say, ` At <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, we did it differently.'' <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> conceded Chrysler-Mitsubishi sought fresh faces. `` We did n't want to have another car plant that -LRB- would -RRB- have 20 years of experience transferred to our plant,'' he said. `` We wanted some green people when it comes to building cars.'' But he said any suggestion race was involved in site selection was `` utter nonsense'' and any charge `` we selected a town to stay away from a union ... is absolutely and unequivocally dead wrong.'' The plant was built with a 100 percent unionized labor force. <LOCATION> Bloomington </LOCATION> Mayor Smart says the Japanese will be happy they built here. `` When you get into any rural setting, people are not afraid to put in long hours,'' he said. `` Here there's a satisfaction in seeing the end result. You're just bred that way.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> is the AP <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> regional reporter, based in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-NoahRobinson     01-22 0539</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Noah Robinson,0556</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gang Member Says Robinson Ordered `Hit' On Barber</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GREENVILLE, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> street gang member testified Saturday that <PERSON> Noah </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> ordered a `` hit'' to kill a former employee, but the witness admitted he was promised money and leniency for cooperating with authorities. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> businessman and the half-brother of <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, is accused of hiring the <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rukn </LOCATION> gang to kill <PERSON> Leroy </PERSON> `` Hambone'' Barber in <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION> in January 1986. He pleaded innocent to the murder and conspiracy charges earlier this month. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, known as `` Toomba'' in the <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rukn </LOCATION> gang, also has been charged with murder in the 1986 slaying. <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> said he was the brother-in-law of <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Fort </PERSON>, the gang leader who is serving time in a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> prison on drug charges. Testimony has described the <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rukn </LOCATION> as a violent organization that makes millions of dollars from the sale of narcotics, murder-for-hire, extortion and racketeering. Another former gang member, <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, testified Friday that <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> was a close friend of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> and wielded some power in the organization. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barber </PERSON> were childhood friends in <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Barber </PERSON> once worked for <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. Circuit Judge <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> agreed last week to combine in the same trial the charges stemming from the Barber shooting and the charge that <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> conspired to kill <PERSON> Janice </PERSON> <PERSON> Denise </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosemond </PERSON>, a witness to the murder, who survived a stabbing attack. <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> said he met <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> in 1985, but said he did not recall the month. `` He -LRB- <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> -RRB- told us he needed hit duty.'' When Solicitor <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Watson </PERSON> asked if <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> offered to pay for the murder, <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> testified that <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> `` mentioned $ 10,000.'' <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> said that as a general in the <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rukn </LOCATION>, he relayed the information to <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION>, who told him and several other gang members to `` take care of it.'' <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> said that during another meeting at <PERSON> Roinson </PERSON>'s home, the defendant gave them $ 2,000 in expense money to travel to <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION>. He said a first attempt to kill <PERSON> Barber </PERSON> failed because several members of the gang got into an argument over how to execute the killing. The second trip to <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION> ended in the fatal shooting of Barber in front of a business owned by <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>. During cross examination from <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Simone </PERSON>, <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> admitted that he lived a `` double life'' and that he sometimes lied. <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> also said he was promised as much as $ 100,000 from federal authorities for information about <PERSON> Barber </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Simone </PERSON> described <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> as a `` liar who makes deals to save his own life.'' `` I'm telling the truth because I decided I was going to take control of my life,'' <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> maintained. `` Nobody _ not Mr. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> and not <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Fort </PERSON> _ tells me what to do.'' <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> also testified the prosecution said it would not seek the death penalty against him in return for his cooperation. `` Your real interest right here now is delivering up <PERSON> Noah </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> on a platter,'' <PERSON> Simone </PERSON> said. `` You know very well that federal authorities wanted to get <PERSON> Noah </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> has maintained that federal authorities wanted to frame him to discredit <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, while the former Democratic presidential hopeful said he had no recent contact with his half-brother.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-StaunchFan     01-22 0218</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Staunch Fan,0223</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dead 49ers Fan Going To Super Bowl In A Brass Urn</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Boatwright </PERSON>'s death wo n't keep him from going to the Super Bowl on Sunday. He'll be there in a small brass urn. <PERSON> Boatwright </PERSON>, 75, died of a heart attack Monday, clutching two Super Bowl tickets as he prepared to place a bet with his bookie, said <PERSON> Boatwright </PERSON>'s widow, <PERSON> Midge </PERSON>. His two sons will take the urn carrying the ashes of the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, resident to the Big Game between the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> 49ers and the <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bengals </ORGANIZATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Boatwright </PERSON> said. `` I told the boys, ` Do it for your daddy,''' she said. `` This is going to be so thrilling for <PERSON> Les </PERSON>, because I know he'll be there in spirit,'' she said `` It's a shame the Lord took him so soon. He could have at least waited until after the Super Bowl.'' National Football League officials will not object to the family's plans, said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Steeg </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> director of special events. <PERSON> Boatwright </PERSON>'s 33-year-old son, <PERSON> Todd </PERSON>, flew to south <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> with his father's ashes early Saturday. His brother <PERSON> Marc </PERSON>, 37, arrived earlier. After the two return to the <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area, they will organize a fishing party and scatter the staunch 49ers fan's ashes in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Boatwright </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-LibyanChemicals     01-22 0379</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Libyan Chemicals,0388</SECOND>
<HEAD>Newspaper: Deaths of Wild Dogs Was Clue To Suspected Libyan Chemical
Plant</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Bryen is cq in 8th graf</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' assertion that <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> was building a chemical weapons plant involved luck, old-fashioned spying, high-technology surveillance and meticulous analysis, a newspaper reported Sunday. But it was the deaths of wild dogs in the Libyan desert that provided the crucial clue that the plant was allegedly intended to produce chemical warfare weapons, The <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said. A toxic spill of chemical wastes at the site last August apparently killed the dogs, and panicked Libyans breached security by using international phone lines to call the German firm helping them build the plant. For the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence analysts accumulating bits of information about the plant, the excited telephone calls sealed the case they had been building. The phone conversation was picked up by sophisticated electronic intelligence equipment, reportedly revealing the nature of the plant and the involvement of West German firms. <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> has denied the charges, saying the plant will produce pharmaceuticals. Sources have confirmed British-U.S. cooperation in the detection, but have n't said whether <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> monitoring stations or well-placed British listening posts in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> picked up the Libyans' call. The discovery was the first time that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> monitoring has exposed construction of a chemical warfare facility, the newspaper said. But `` we've got a long way to go before any of us can take comfort,'' said <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryen </PERSON>, a recently retired deputy undersecretary for trade security policy at the Pentagon. `` The fact is that no government is very well-organized to deal with this problem.'' The compilation of data included satellite photos of a major construction project in the middle of nowhere, the curious involvement of an Arab businessman who used circuitous routes to ship equipment to <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, and pictures of an oversized ventilation system usually associated with micro-toxin production, the Times said. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kupperman </PERSON>, an expert on arms and terrorism at the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said biological weapons pose some of the most difficult detection problems because facilities can be smaller. For example, a batch of anthrax that could kill millions of people could be concocted in `` a room the size of a broom closet,'' <PERSON> Kupperman </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Bundy 5thLd-Writethru a0636 01-22 0922</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bundy, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0636,0944</SECOND>
<HEAD>Condemned Killer Confesses to Unsolved Murders, Officials Say</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: CORRECTS time element in lede to reflect that some confessions
made Friday. INSERTS two grafs after 17 graf, `In Washington...', to add
comment from victim's mother. Picks up 18th graf pvs, `Keppel said...'.
</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY27</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By IKE FLORES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ORLANDO, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Convicted murderer <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> confessed to at least nine killings while his lawyers maneuvered to block his execution scheduled for Tuesday, officials from two Western states said Saturday. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> confessed to killing at least eight young women in western <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state in 1974, investigator <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Keppel </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> attorney general's office said. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> also confessed to the 1975 slaying of a 26-year-old <LOCATION> Vail </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, ski shop employee whose body was never found, <LOCATION> Vail </LOCATION> Police Chief <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughey </PERSON> said. Bundy who grew up in <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, was scared, shaken and tearful as he responded to questions from investigators, <ORGANIZATION> Keppel </ORGANIZATION> told <ORGANIZATION> KIRO-TV </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seattle </ORGANIZATION> on Saturday night in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. `` The man is trying to save his life,'' <ORGANIZATION> Keppel </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>, scheduled to die in the electric chair for the kidnap-murder of 12-year-old <PERSON> Kimberly </PERSON> <PERSON> Leach </PERSON> in 1978, has been linked to as many as 36 killings and disappearances of young women in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and other Western states. The 42-year-old law school dropout was visited Saturday by officials from several Western states, and more interviews were scheduled for Sunday, said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Decker </PERSON>, assistant warden at <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> State Prison in <LOCATION> Starke </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s lawyers lost two more bids for a stay of execution Saturday. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kendall </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharp </PERSON>, who in 1987 called <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> `` a diabolical genius'' and `` probably the most competent serial killer in the country at this time,'' denied a request for a stay Saturday morning. A three-judge panel of the 11th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> denied <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s appeal in a telephone conference Saturday afternoon without addressing any of the legal issues, said court clerk <PERSON> Matt </PERSON> <PERSON> Davidson </PERSON>. As a last resort, attorneys can appeal to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, but the nation's high court already refused to hear a separate Bundy appeal Tuesday. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> last week had offered to trade information about other slayings for a delay in his execution, but Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, who signed <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s fourth death warrant Jan. 17, refused, saying he would not `` negotiate with a killer.'' <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> also has been sentenced to die for the murders of two <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> sorority sisters, but he had not previously admitted to any slayings. <PERSON> Hughey </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> acknowledged killing <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Cunningham </PERSON>, who disappeared in <LOCATION> Vail </LOCATION> March 15, 1975. `` Detectives believe the confession is indeed valid,'' he said, noting <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s details about the victim, her clothes and the <LOCATION> Vail </LOCATION> area have been persuasive. The police chief gave this recounting of what <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> said: He approached her on crutches asking for help, one of several ruses attributed to the suspected serial killer. She agreed to carry his ski boots to his car, where <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> knocked her unconscious with a metal bar. The woman regained consciousness after 20-30 miles west of <LOCATION> Glenwood </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, but he knocked her unconscious again, strangled her, left her body where she fell and drove to <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>. He returned four or five weeks later and buried her. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state, <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> confessed to the eight `` Ted'' murders, said <ORGANIZATION> Keppel </ORGANIZATION>, who had been a police detective working on those cases in the 1970s. Witnesses had reported seeing a charming young stranger who called himself `` Ted'' in the area where several victims disappeared. For the parents of one victim, <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> student <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rancourt </PERSON>, the confession helps write the final chapter to a tragedy. `` It's been an open wound for 15 years, and every time we think it's settling down, something happens,'' said <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Rancourt </PERSON>'s mother, <PERSON> Vivian </PERSON> <PERSON> Rancourt </PERSON>, of LaConner, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION> `` There will always be that loss that we can not replace, but at least we can put it all together. <ORGANIZATION> Keppel </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> admitted to three additional <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state killings, but he was `` at a loss'' to say whether <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> was telling the truth about those cases, or just trying to buy time. <ORGANIZATION> Keppel </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> provided no details of the three additional killings. <ORGANIZATION> Keppel </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> confirmed in addition to the deaths of the eight victims that some unidentified bones found near the east <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Issaquah </LOCATION>, where two victims were found, were those of <PERSON> Georgann </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> student who disappeared from an alley behind her sorority house on June 11, 1974. Her remains had never been found, although <LOCATION> King </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> police considered her a `` Ted'' victim. <ORGANIZATION> Keppel </ORGANIZATION> hopes to talk to Bundy again Sunday, he said. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON>, a defense attorney before being elected a prosecutor in the <LOCATION> Daytona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> area in November, told the <ORGANIZATION> Orlando </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sentinel </ORGANIZATION> late Friday that <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> called him last Tuesday and said: `` I want to tell it all, but it will take longer than six days.'' <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON>, who befriended <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> and has acted as a spiritual adviser for two years, told the Sentinel he believes it could take as long as several months for <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> to tell detectives everything they want to know, including where the remains of some victims are. `` Bundy had over 10 years to tell what he had to tell, and if he is now telling all, that's nice, I'm pleased, but his execution should n't be delayed any longer,'' said Attorney General <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Butterworth </PERSON>. <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON> on Saturday did not return telephone calls from The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AbortionViews     01-22 0264</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Abortion Views,0269</SECOND>
<HEAD>Abortion Support Still Splits Americans</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sixteen years after the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> legalized abortions, Americans' views remain sharply split on the issue, The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. Polls over the years have found a majority of Americans consistently support legalized abortion when the woman's health is endangered, when the pregnancy results from rape or incest, or if the baby might be born with a birth defect. But the support dips below 50 percent when the reason a woman wants an abortion is that she is unmarried, does not want the baby or is too poor. Although recent polls indicate that a majority of Americans do not want the landmark Jan. 22, 1973, <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision, <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON>, overturned, other polls indicate support for legalized abortions is dropping. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, director of general social surveys for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opinion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, said the differing results stem from how pollsters phrase questions. `` The reason you get different results is that there are 10 percent of the people who are absolutely against abortion, except maybe to save the mother's life, and 30 percent who are for abortion on demand, and that leaves 60 percent who swing back and forth conditionally, depending on what trimester -LRB- of pregnancy -RRB- and what circumstances you're talking about,'' he said. The Times said other polling experts agree that more people are more likely to say they favor abortion when the question is framed in terms of a `` woman's right to choose'' than when the question talks about `` protecting an unborn child.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 0121EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HomelessPoll     01-22 0257</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Homeless Poll,0262</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poll: A Lot Of Blame To Go Around For Homelessness</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More people today say they see homeless people in their communities than did three years ago and they blame everyone from the federal government to the homeless themselves, according to a poll published Sunday. Most of the 1,533 people interviewed by telephone for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times-CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> poll said they wanted the government to do more and half said they would pay higher taxes to get it done. Fifty-one percent of those participating in the nationwide poll answered yes when asked if they `` personally see homeless people around your community or on the way to work.'' Three years ago, 36 percent said yes to that question. `` A lot of the blame'' for the worsening should be put on the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, according to 24 percent of those surveyed. But they also assigned `` a lot'' of blame to alcohol and drug abuse by the homeless, 50 percent; to mental institutions for `` releasing patients who are n't ready to lead normal lives,'' 44 percent; the homeless themselves as being unwilling to work, 37 percent; and local governments for failing to take care of people in need, 30 percent. Sixty-five percent said they supported more federal spending on the homeless, and 49 percent of all those polled said they would pay $ 100 a year more in federal taxes toward that end. The interviews were conducted from Jan. 12 to 15. The poll's margin of error is plus or minus 3 percentage points
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ArsonFire 1stLd-Writethru a0651 01-22 0352</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Arson Fire, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0651,0357</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Held In Connection With Arson Fire</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 4 grafs to UPDATE with third arrest. Picks up 4th
graf pvs, `Survivors of...'.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KANSAS CITY, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Third people were arrested and a fourth person surrendered to police Saturday in connection with a predawn arson fire that killed six people from four generations of a family, police said. A 17-year-old boy and a 22-year-old man were arrested Saturday within a few blocks of the house that was heavily damaged by fire early Friday morning. Another 17-year-old boy surrendered to police Saturday evening, said police spokesman Sgt. <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Mills </PERSON>. A 32-year-old man was arrested late Saturday evening, police said. No charges were immediately filed against the four, who were held in the <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jail </LOCATION>, police said. Survivors of the fire said a feud with a man who allegedly ran a nearby drug house may have been the motive for the arson. The fire was discovered at 2:45 a.m. Friday by a man inside the house who went to investigate the sound of breaking glass in the first-floor living room, <PERSON> Mills </PERSON> said. The fire spread quickly up the stairs to the second floor, where all six victims were found in their bedrooms. Gasoline was used to start the blaze, <PERSON> Mills </PERSON> said. A nearly empty five-gallon gasoline can was found near the broken window. Preliminary reports said the six victims, who represented four generations of the family, died of smoke inhalation. The victims were identified as <PERSON> Trisha </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, 19; her baby, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 6 months; <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Addison </PERSON>, 2; <PERSON> Courtney </PERSON> <PERSON> Addison </PERSON>, 2; <PERSON> Velma </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, 76, and <PERSON> Nola </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, 59. Two other occupants of the 2 -LCB- - story frame house were hospitalized Four other people fled without serious injury. `` They lost their lives for nothing, over something that do n't really make no sense,'' said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON>, the father of the infant Police had staked out the neighborhood Thursday after getting `` numerous complaints about drug activity,'' said Capt. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>. Several people were arrested on outstanding warrants after they left a house in the block, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Pakistan-BusCrash     01-22 0098</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pakistan-Bus Crash,0100</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bus Plunges Into Canal, Kills 12</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bus ferrying a wedding party to an eastern <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> village plunged into a 10-foot canal, killing 12 and injuring another 15, the official news agency reported Sunday. The bus was en route Saturday to the small village near the eastern city of <LOCATION> Jhelum </LOCATION>, about 70 miles southeast of the <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> capital, when the driver lost control and plunged into a canal, the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> said. Hospital officials reported eight of the injured were in serious condition. Police were investigating the accident.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Alamodome 2ndLd-Writethru a0654 01-22 0405</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Alamodome, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0654,0413</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tax Hike Approved to Finance Alamodome</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 2 grafs to UPDATE with final tally. Inserts mayor's
comments in matter below dash.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID SEDENO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN ANTONIO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A proposal to increase the sales tax to finance a $ 174 million domed stadium won an easy victory in a referendum Saturday. The countywide vote for the dome was 93,091, or 53 percent, to 82,612, or 47 percent. The vote culminated an 18-month battle between city officials, businessmen and grass roots groups over the referendum, which proposed to raise the sales tax in <LOCATION> Bexar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> by a half-cent to a total 8 percent over the next five years to pay for construction of the 65,000-seat stadium. `` I think we were outspent and outadvertised. We were just outperformed,'' said a leading opponent of the project, C.A. <PERSON> Stubbs </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Homeowners </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taxpayers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` We're going to go from here, no cry-baby speeches,'' <PERSON> Stubbs </PERSON> said. `` We are disappointed, but we will fight another day.'' About 31 percent of the county's 566,000 registered voters turned out for the election amid clear skies and warm weather. There are 1.2 million people in the county, which includes <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Mayor <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Cisneros </PERSON>, who leaves office in May after eight years as mayor and six as a councilman, led the pro-dome factions that said the stadium would help the city increase its $ 1.5 billion tourism industry by luring bigger conventions and attracting new hotels. The possibility of using the stadium to attract a professional sport team was discussed, but that was overshadowed by talk of boosting convention and tourist business. `` Today is an affirmation by the people of <LOCATION> Bexar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> of the vision of the future that they want for this area and that is the real victory of what occurred today,'' <PERSON> Cisneros </PERSON> told about 500 supporters who had gathered at a hotel ballroom Saturday night. The Rev. <PERSON> Rosendo </PERSON> <PERSON> Urrabazo </PERSON>, a co-chairman of the grass roots organization <ORGANIZATION> Communities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organized </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, was among the leading opponents of the stadium's financing proposal. <PERSON> Cisneros </PERSON>, <PERSON> Urrabazo </PERSON> and others had debated the issue at town meetings and on television. Urrabazo and others said the private sector should take over financing of the proposal and said any tax increase should be used for educational programs and basic services. `` This stadium is not a vision for the future. It's a step backwards,'' <PERSON> Urrabazo </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 0943EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Poland 1stLd-Writethru a0665 01-22 0548</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Poland, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0665,0563</SECOND>
<HEAD>Solidarity And Government Will Talks About Legaizing Union</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: New thruout to UPDATE with Walesa quotes, Solidarity march.
No pickup. ^By JOHN DANISZEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GDANSK, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Solidarity on Sunday accepted a <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> offer to hold talks on legalizing the outlawed trade union movement and said the negotiations should begin `` as soon as possible.'' They would be the first formal talks between Solidarity and authorities since the union was crushed in a December 1981 crackdown. Solidarity, the first independent trade union in the Soviet bloc, was outlawed a year later. Asked if the agreement between the union and authorities represented a victory, Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said: `` I am a practical man and practice will show how far Poles can go in agreement.'' His comments came during an impromptu news conference that was held after Solidarity's leadership accepted the government offer and he took a few minutes to address 5,000 people who attended a Mass at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brygida </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> wore a Solidarity pin on his lapel and a tie clasp given to him by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> when the American visited <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> as vice president last year. The Solidarity leader, who appeared very happy, said the union could be ready within two months to hold its first nationwide congress since martial law was declared in December 1981. After the Mass, 1,000 people marched from the church chanting, `` Solidarity! Solidarity! Legalize Solidarity!'' Police blocked the procession after it had gone a few blocks and it disbanded peacefully. In a statement Sunday ending nearly two days of talks of the union's leadership, Solidarity said it is willing to respect the law and its original 1980 statute. It called on the government to respect the conventions of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> guaranteeing trade union freedoms. The decision to accept the offer for talks was adopted unanimously with one abstention of the union's <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Executive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, which is made up of about 20 regional leaders from across <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. On Thursday, the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Polish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> announced a new stance endorsing more than one trade union organization. The party offered to legalize Solidarity under terms to be negotiated if the union respects the law and agrees to help reform the economy. Solidarity said the government has met its conditions for beginning talks on legalizing it and on the social and economic problems facing <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. `` It is necessary to start negotiations as soon as possible. They should have a realistic and concrete character, and public opinion should be informed about it fully,'' the commission said. `` On our side we express the will to act according to the law and according to the statute of our union in the spirit of the superior interests of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>.'' Solidarity called for agreement on a reform program to confront <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s `` dramatic economic, ecological and material situation.'' The statement opens the way for formal talks to begin with authorities at a talks first proposed by the government during a wave of strikes in August. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> had demanded that the party make a political decision to legalize Solidarity before he would join the talks. Both sides have said they are ready to talk, and it appeared that negotiations could begin very quickly, perhaps within the next few weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 1134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a AM-BRF--CrashReport     01-22 0148</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Crash Report,0150</SECOND>
<HEAD>Helicopter Crash Report Blames Pilot Error</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The crash of a minesweeping helicopter off the Golden Gate that killed eight crewmen was the result of pilot error, according to a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> investigation. The investigation found that mechanical error was not a factor in the July 18 accident, despite earlier accidents involving models of the Sea Dragon MH-53E three-engine helicopter, the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chronicle </ORGANIZATION> reported Saturday. The models have been involved in five accidents that cost at least five lives. Three lawsuits stemming from these accidents have been filed in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> against the aircraft's manufacturer, <ORGANIZATION> Sikorsky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Division </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technologies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> investigation said salvage operators were able to recover 95 percent of the helicopter. However, only six of the eight crewmen were found. All eight died in the crash, which was eight miles west of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 1134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a AM-BRF--ArtificialReef     01-22 0161</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Artificial Reef,0164</SECOND>
<HEAD>Navy Cargo Ship Sunk For Reef</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT PIERCE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The USS Muliphen, a cargo ship with 44 years of naval history, was intentionally sunk in 175 feet of water to add to an artificial reef. Former sailors came for the sinking Saturday, but only a salvage and tug crew were present when the 468-foot ship was sent to the bottom about four hours earlier than planned because of bad weather. The salvage and tug crews were jostled by seven-foot seas and winds gusting to 25 knots just before the ship rolled slightly starboard and disppeared about 17 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pierce </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Inlet </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lucie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recreation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pierce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sportfishing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> and private donors raised $ 107,000 for salvaging and sinking. The Muliphen, commissioned in October 1944, joined two tugboats submerged earlier as part of the August <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Busch </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr </PERSON>. Artificial Reef, planned as a fish lure and a fishing spot.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 1143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-East-West Bjt   01-22 0808</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-East-West, Bjt,0835</SECOND>
<HEAD>Accord Fosters Disarmament Hopes, Stirs Unrest in Alliances</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROL J. WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The document on human rights and security 35 nations approved in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> this month has narrowed the gap between East and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> but widened some fissures in their alliances. Both superpowers praise the agreement, which promises broader individual freedoms and provides for new arms talks, as a herald of future disarmament successes. The ultimate success of the 27-month conference that produced the document, however, has stirred unrest within the blocs led by <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. European members of the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> show increasing resistance to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> views of how disarmament should proceed on their continent. <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact allies of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> demonstrate markedly different degrees of commitment to the human rights protections spelled out in the <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> accord. Whether the internal divisions will develop into disabling rifts will depend in large part on the superpower leaders. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is expected to continue <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration policies on disarmament, but mounting pressure from <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> could produce an approach more receptive to the Kremlin. President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reform program has met resistance at home and in some nations of the Soviet bloc. At the moment, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> desperately needs to cut arms spending as a way of stabilizing the economy and improving the living standard. Western allies are aware of the pressure he faces and of the serious consequences for arms control if <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s conservative opponents gain the upper hand. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomats concede the <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> conference succeeded primarily because of the Soviet reforms. Earlier this month, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said release of political prisoners, easing of emigration and more tolerant policies on free speech and religious practice changed the American position on the Soviet proposal for a 1991 human rights conference in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. Agreement on a final document in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> was delayed because Western nations objected to holding such a meeting in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. The conference was one of several since 1975, when the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and all European nations except <LOCATION> Albania </LOCATION> signed the <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> agreements on <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> security and cooperation. The <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> statement approved Jan. 15 proclaims the right of all citizens to assemble, speak their minds, travel, emigrate and monitor compliance of their governments. It sets ambitious goals for better trade relations and environmental protection and mandates new negotiations on reducing conventional military forces in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, to begin March 9 in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>. Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> for the closing session, described the agreement as the result of commitment and compromise. He said the Kremlin would disclose the numbers of its soldiers and armaments in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> before the new talks begin. Arguments and secrecy surrounding the relative strength of forces have hamstrung existing negotiations that began 15 years ago. Asked why he was so confident the new forum would avoid the pitfalls of the old, <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> said the alliances were under increasing pressure to improve the international climate. `` It's something our peoples want and their governments, if they are true governments, should express the will of the people,'' he told reporters. In his speech to the conference, <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> would remove some short-range nuclear weapons from <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and asked <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> to negotiate withdrawal of the remaining European-based missiles with ranges of 300 miles or less. All missiles of intermediate range are being withdrawn and dismantled under an accord signed in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in December 1987, and negotiators report good progress on a pact to cut stockpiles of long-range weapons. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> has said repeatedly it does not want to give up short-range nuclear arms until a Soviet advantage in conventional forces is reduced. `` There's not going to be anything left except the short-range,'' a senior <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomat said. `` If we want to keep the flexible response doctrine credible, I do n't see any way we can negotiate these in the foreseeable future.'' That <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> doctrine holds that the West must retain its nuclear option until the Soviet advantage in troops, tanks, artillery and other conventional weapons is reduced. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and other <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> members, however, have been chafing under that and other constraints on the pace of disarmament. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ledogar </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to the forthcoming talks, said <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> wants to see a Soviet reduction in conventional forces first, but added: `` I'm not trying to suggest there is no difference of opinion within the alliance.'' Within the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s planned pullouts are popular with the masses but worrisome for some leaderships. Even more divisive is the question of human rights and the varying degrees of willingness among the East-bloc allies to emulate the <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> policies of glasnost and perestroika.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> has reported from <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1984.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 1144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-MideastPeace Bjt   01-22 0705</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mideast Peace, Bjt,0730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Europeans Step Up Middle East Peace Role</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN RICE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AMMAN, Jordan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> looks to the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> in the first days of his presidency, he will find Soviet and European leaders jostling to share the stage in the peace process that once seemed an American monopoly. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> remains the region's most important outside power. But it no longer holds the solo role of matchmaker it played in the 1979 Egyptian-Israeli treaty. `` I believe that <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> is making, can make and will make a considerable contribution ... toward this <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace settlement,'' Lord Plumb, President of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, said in <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> this month. The Europeans have played a path-finding role that often has complimented American actions _ as well as channeling them. Their contacts with the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> helped both legitimize the organization and prod it toward more moderate positions that opened the way for a dialogue with <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. European calls for <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> compromise have underscored quieter <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pressure on the Jewish state. <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> was a crucial mediator late last year to draw the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> back into contact with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> after a 13-year <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> boycott. <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>'s embassy in <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION> hosted clandestine meetings to help pave the way for those talks. Its foreign minister, delegated by the 12-nation <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, visited <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> leaders this month and urged them to respond to <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> peace efforts. Soviet officials pressured their leftist allies in the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> to accept <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, renounce terrorism and endorse <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peace resolutions, setting the stage for the U.S.-PLO dialogue. Both the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> have improved relations with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, partly in expectation of a role in <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> peace talks. European parliamentarians and ministers have paraded through the Holy Land on political pilgrimages, lecturing irritated <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> leaders on the need to compromise. Italian, Spanish, Greek, British, Scandinavian and East European leaders have met <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> to encourage the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s shift from the gun to the conference table <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> upgraded the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> mission in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> to a `` general delegation'' _ a step short of diplomatic recognition. The barrage of activity led <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> to accuse the European Community on Jan. 13 of a `` love affair'' with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> He insisted the community `` can not bring us closer to the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. That depends only on us. They have no right to impose solutions or to apply economic pressure.'' <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s long boycott of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> eventually achieved a key aim. The organization last month embraced the moderate stands <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> had demanded to help sow the seeds of a possible peace settlement. But the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> isolation of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> worked both ways. Its repeated efforts to find an alternative to the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> were all but demolished by the 13-month-old Palestinian uprising, which evoked a storm of pro-PLO sentiment in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. The policy also caused popular hostility to American policy throughout the Arab world, whose governments unanimously insist the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> is central to any settlement. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> was unable to get <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> to agree on the U.S.-backed concept of trading occupied Arab land for peace _ the heart of all major <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace efforts over the past 20 years. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> largely stood by as Israeli troops invaded <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and bombed <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> in 1982, then reneged on a promise to protect Palestinian refugees after the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s withdrawal from <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> blocked a key arms deal for <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, considered the Arab key to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace plans, infuriating King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>. By 1984, <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had ruled itself out as a sole peace mediator. Together with <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>, he embraced a Soviet-inspired call for the five permanent members of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> to oversee Arab-Israeli peace talks. That plan eventually won broad European support as frustrated Arabs increasingly asked <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> to pressure the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to influence <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> responded, keeping an eye on its major economic interests in the region and mindful of the perils of war between increasingly well-armed rivals on its southern flank.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON>, The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> correspondent in <LOCATION> Amman </LOCATION>, has covered <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> affairs for five years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 1144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-WarsawPact-Glance     01-22 0464</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Warsaw Pact-Glance,0477</SECOND>
<HEAD>East Europe At-a-Glance</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-East-West, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a brief review of the political, social and economic policies of <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact countries:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> SOVIET </LOCATION> <LOCATION> UNION </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, who gained power in March 1985, has pursued policies that enlarged personal freedoms, promoted economic change, reduced involvement in such regional conflicts as <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and took major steps in arms control. His domestic reforms are endangered by conservatives in high places; ethnic strife between Armenians and Azerbaijanis; and nationalist movements in the Baltic states of <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Latvia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> also faces opposition because living conditions are slow to improve and conservatives see danger in disarmament.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> POLAND </LOCATION> _ Gen. <PERSON> Wojciech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON>'s government has agreed to give workers a greater voice in economic decisions by offering to legalize Solidarity with some conditions. The concession seems born of frustration over inability either to stop an economic slide or inspire Poles to accept price increases and other means of financing reform.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> HUNGARY </LOCATION> _ The <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact pioneer in economic and social change plans to open the first stock market in a communist country and has set the stage for a multiparty political system. It has been the most vocal of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s allies in pressing for international standards on human rights guarantees and has been tolerant of protest and unofficial groups.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EAST <LOCATION> GERMANY </LOCATION> _ The 16 million Germans ruled by <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> have one of the bloc's most industrially productive nations but have not won the greater freedom championed by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and instituted in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. Restrictions on emigration and travel have been eased somewhat, but the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall remains a symbol of repression and a point of contention between East and West.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> CZECHOSLOVAKIA </LOCATION> _ Although it has the highest living standard of the seven <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> nations </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> takes one of the hardest lines on dissent and has balked at many of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s political and economic reforms Police attacks on demonstrators in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> this month have emphasized the different attitudes among Soviet allies on free expression.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> BULGARIA </LOCATION> _ The nation <PERSON> Todor </PERSON> <PERSON> Zhivkov </PERSON> has led 34 years is known as one of the Kremlin's most loyal followers but has been slow to embrace change. Human rights abuses and police repression are reported with increasing frequency as those advocating reform challenge the leadership.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> ROMANIA </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> runs the most repressive nation in the Soviet bloc and his attempt to rid it of foreign debt also has left <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> financially strapped. Food and power shortages have further reduced a poor standard of living. Hesitant attempts at public disagreement with the `` The Chosen One,'' as <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> is called, have met harsh response. <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> said it would refuse to honor any provisions of the <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> document it considered intrusive.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 1145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SouthKorea     01-22 0532</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-South Korea,0549</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Battle Thousands Of Anti-U.S., Anti-Government Protesters</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY RENFREW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police hurling tear gas grenades battled thousands of protesters who tried to march through <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> on Sunday to demand the overthrow of President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> Tae-woo and the expulsion of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops. Dozens of the estimated 5,000 radicals were injured or detained when 6,000 riot troopers charged them, but police had no figures on injuries or arrests. The demonstrators chanting `` Yankee go home!'' and `` Down with <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> Tae-woo!'' were trying to reach the headquarters of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Troopers in green combat fatigues and black, visored helmets blocked the march and retaliated with tear gas when some protesters threw firebombs and rocks to try to force their way. The riot police charged the protesters, forcing many to flee downstairs into subway stations where some were trampled or hit by people leaping from above. Police beat and kicked groups of protesters who were surrounded by the charging security forces. Other protesters hurled scores of firebombs, and some police were beaten to the ground by radicals using clubs and fists. `` You are the enemies of our people!'' an enraged man yelled at police. Clashes continued for more than an hour along one of <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>'s main shopping avenues. Hundreds of terrified pedestrians ran to escape the fighting and clouds of tear gas. Demonstrators repeatedly called for removal of the 42,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops based in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> under a mutual defense treaty. An effigy representing <PERSON> Roh </PERSON>, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and top Korean industrialists was burned during the march. The rally before the march also demanded an end to controls on labor unions. The protest was the first action organized by a new dissident alliance, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> a </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, which was formed Saturday by about 20 dissident, labor and student groups. Coalition leaders said it was the largest dissident group ever formed in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and claimed a membership of 30,000 people. Coalition leaders pledged to seek the fall of the <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> government, charging it is a front for military rule. The coalition also called for an end to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s powerful industrial conglomerates and to all foreign influence. The coalition claims it will launch a movement of students, workers and farmers to remove <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> and create a `` society of equality'' for workers and the poor. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Bu-young </PERSON>, a leader of the new group, said, `` Since the organization is based on grass-roots groups, it will be able to resist any government oppression and struggle for national development.'' Formation of a similar dissident alliance in May 1987 was a key event in sparking major anti-government protests that forced the authoritarian government of President <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> <PERSON> Doo-hwan </PERSON> to agree to democratic presidential elections. <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> won the election, and his government has introduced broad democratic reforms. Radicals refuse to accept that there have been democratic reforms and claim the nation is still ruled by the military and powerful industrialists. The radicals appear to lack substantial public support, but their violent protests make them a powerful force in domestic politics. <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> warned last week that radicals were a threat to political stability and ordered a harsh crackdown.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 1145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Iran-Earthquake     01-22 0088</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Iran-Earthquake,0090</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yet Another Quake Shakes Iranian Town</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A small earthquake shook Garmsar early Sunday, one of more than 150 quakes to hit the northern Iranian town since August, the official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported. No casualties or other damage was reported in Sunday's temblor, which measured 3.5 on the Richter scale, said the agency, monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>. A quake of that size can cause slight damage. The epicenter was registered at <LOCATION> Garmsar </LOCATION>, 62 miles southeast of the capital, <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 1145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--FalsePoll     01-22 0155</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--False Poll,0159</SECOND>
<HEAD>Magazine Published False Results On Popularity Poll</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A magazine falsely reported results of a popularity poll to say that <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Karoly </PERSON> <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON> had the highest score, state radio said. The latest edition of the popular independent weekly Reform said <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON> topped the list of its `` The Year's Reform Man'' survey with 22.9 percent of nearly 5,000 votes received. Pal Emoed, a Reform editorial board member, told the radio late Saturday that `` not even'' 500 votes had arrived in the magazine office. He told the radio that of those votes, <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON> finished second to <PERSON> Imre </PERSON> <PERSON> Pozsgay </PERSON>, a minister of state and leading reformer. Emoed gave no figures and did not say who was responsible for publishing the allegedly false results. The public admission of error was extremely unusual in a Communist country, even in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, where the media have become increasingly open over the past year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 1146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Bhutto-China     01-22 0183</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bhutto-China,0190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bhutto Set to Visit China in February</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Benazir </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> will visit <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> on Feb. 11-14 on her first official trip abroad, the foreign ministry announced Sunday. Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> also may attend the funeral of Japanese Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> on Feb. 24, but her plans are not complete, said a ministry spokesman. The spokesman, who by custom is not identified by name, did not give an agenda for the <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> visit but said the prime minister would meet top leaders. Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> had indicated her first official trip would be to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> because of the traditionally warm relations the Asian nations share. Late President <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> <PERSON> ul-Haq </PERSON> had planned to visit <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> last May but canceled the trip after firing <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s government. He died in a plane crash three months later. Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>, 35, became the Moslem world's first female government leader Dec. 2. Earlier this month she went on a pilgrimage to the holy city of <LOCATION> Mecca </LOCATION>. Although it was described as a private trip, she held talks with King Fahd and other Saudi officials.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 1157EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Budget-Darman Bjt   01-22 0533</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Budget-Darman, Bjt,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Darman Offers Glimpse of Shape of Budget Future</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The budget director who will help write President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s fiscal 1990 spending plan gave a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committee an early peek at the basic framework last week, along with acknowledgment that it will not elicit unanimous applause from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` I would love it if we could do something you would n't criticize,'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> told members of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> at his confirmation hearing `` But I do n't think we'll be able to meet that test.'' <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>, whose nomination as director of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> could be approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> this week, spent most of his five hours before the committee on Thursday fencing with Democrats eager to find holes in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign pledge of no new taxes. But the 45-year-old former investment banker, deputy treasury secretary and <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide also gave some indications of what <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s revisions to the budget former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> presented on Jan. 9 will look like. And he gave hints as to how the new president will honor his campaign pledges to support education, research and other priorities, while grappling with the federal deficit. The administration says the imbalance would reach $ 127 billion this year without savings, well above the $ 100 billion cap set by the Gramm-Rudman deficit reduction law. Asked about education spending, <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> responded, `` You'll see a lot of emphasis on the role the federal government can play in providing leadership in regard to education.'' But in the next breath he said there would be only a `` modest increase'' in federal education spending. He suggested that, instead, the government could provoke improvements in education by other, unspecified means. He said the budget would provide tax breaks and other incentives to spur research and development. He said that in looking for savings, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would not reduce the giant Social Security program. But he said the growth of spending for <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION>, which provides medical services for the elderly and handicapped, would be reined in. He provided no figures. Defense, which accounts for more than one-quarter of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s $ 1.15 trillion budget, will not receive the boost of 2 percent growth, above inflation, that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> gave it, <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> said Again, he offered no specifics. He insisted that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s flexible freeze plan _ a brew of spending increases that rises no faster than inflation, along with no tax increases _ could reduce the deficit and eventually balance the budget. But he left the door open to retain the $ 13 billion in asset sales, user fee increases and other revenue raisers that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> inserted into his spending plan. <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> insisted that none of those items can be considered taxes, a viewpoint Democrats in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are already disputing. <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> said the blueprint would be longer than the 12-page document submitted by President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> when he succeeded <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> in 1969, but would not be as comprehensive as the six-volume budget <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> submitted earlier this month. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s document, <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> said, would specify `` what the particular programs are he wishes to emphasize.'' Those yet-to-come details are what <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the new administration will wrestle over for months to come.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 1200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-France-Cambodia     01-22 0258</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-France-Cambodia,0266</SECOND>
<HEAD>France Offers to Host Cambodia Peace Conference in Paris</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> has offered to organize a meeting of the warring Cambodian factions followed by an international peace conference, the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> announced. `` To this end, it has decided to intensify its diplomatic activity with each of the countries involved'' to encourage their participation, the ministry said in a statement late Saturday. <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> is `` at the disposal of the Cambodian parties to organize, in the form which appears appropriate to them, a meeting that might encourage a true national reconciliation and open the path toward the holding in 1989 of an international conference,'' it said. It said the issue was discussed at a meeting Friday between resistance leader Prince <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> and Foreign Minister <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> <PERSON> Dumas </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> has met three times in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> with <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON> and also met in November with <PERSON> Khieu </PERSON> <PERSON> Samphan </PERSON>, a leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>. Representatives of the four factions _ <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>'s army; the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>; a smaller anti-Communist group called the <ORGANIZATION> Kampuchean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>; and <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON>'s Vietnamese-backed government _ are scheduled to meet next month in <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>, as they did last July The three rebel groups are fighting the Communist government installed after the Vietnamese invasion of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> 10 years ago ended the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>'s reign of terror. <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>'s foreign minister, <PERSON> Siddhi </PERSON> <PERSON> Savetsila </PERSON>, said Sunday in <LOCATION> Brunei </LOCATION> that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> might be invited to join in Cambodian peace talks if their participation would be helpful.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 1211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Britain-Duchess Bjt   01-22 0626</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Britain-Duchess, Bjt,0645</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tabloids Turn On Duchess of York</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LESLIE SHEPHERD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> was lauded as a breath of fresh air in the stuffy world of royal protocol when she married <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> 2 -LCB- years ago, but today the Duchess of <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> is known in some quarters as `` Her Royal Idleness.'' <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s brassy tabloids also are calling her `` Duchess Dolittle'' for what they view as her love of holidays and jet-setting lifestyle. A recent scorecard listing the public engagements of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s royal family put <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> lieutenant, at the bottom with only 30 last year <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> was next with 55, less than half those performed by her husband's 88-year-old grandmother, Queen <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON>. Buckingham Palace noted that <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, as a naval officer, was not expected to have other commitments and that <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> gave birth to their first child in August. But a public opinion poll published Sunday in News of the World indicated 34 percent of Britons surveyed believe the 29-year-old duchess does not earn the $ 150,000 she and her husband receive yearly from the government for royal duties. `` Her Royal Idleness,'' the newspaper's headline blared. `` Freeloading <PERSON> Fergie </PERSON> is the most unpopular member of the royal family,'' its story said. The newspaper said Market and <ORGANIZATION> Opinion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION> polled 501 adults last week. No margin of error was given. News about <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> and her family sells newspapers in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, and the duchess has suffered her share of barbs since she first was linked to <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> more than three years ago. At first, the duchess was lauded for her breezy style and friendly, open manner. But she slowly became a target, mainly for her healthy appetite, sometimes plump figure and fashion gaffes. After an official visit to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> last March, even the serious newspapers said <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> and <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>'s behavior had been brash and vulgar, particularly her bold repartee with audiences. As the duchess gained weight last summer during the later months of her pregnancy, the tabloids delighted in publishing unflattering photographs of her. Criticism intensified last fall when she left her newborn baby, Princess <PERSON> Beatrice </PERSON>, at home with a nanny for six weeks while she went to <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> on official business and holidays. The attacks reached a crescendo last week when <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> and <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> went skiing at <LOCATION> Klosters </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>, where Maj. <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Lindsay </PERSON>, a close friend of the royal family, died last year in an avalanche that narrowly missed <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, heir to the throne. Critics considered the trip an excessive holiday and unseemly because it came only a year after the tragedy. The Daily Mirror, which branded <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> `` Duchess Dolittle,'' said she sobbed after daily briefings by aides on the tabloid attacks. The duchess flew to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> on Friday to attended a memorial service for the 34 people killed in a triple-train crash in south <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> in December. It was one of only six public engagements she has scheduled until March, according to <ORGANIZATION> Buckingham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palace </ORGANIZATION>'s official list. The Sunday Times of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, which usually does not focus on the private lives of the royal family, said the duchess was suffering from a general cooling in relations between the palace and the media. The chill is largely due to the royal family's failure to attend a memorial service in <LOCATION> Lockerbie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, for victims of the Dec. 21 crash of <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> Flight 103, and the decision to send <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> to the funeral of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>. Many British veterans still consider <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> a war criminal. `` Whether the activities of the duchess are an embarrassment and a disgrace or whether she is merely fulfilling a popular need for a bete noir in the nation's most popular soap opera is debatable,'' The Sunday Times said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890122-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-22-89 1232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-UnfinishedBusiness 1stLd-Writethru a0688 01-22 0830</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Unfinished Business, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0688,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>EDS: Subs lead to delete extraneous Reagan and 14th graf, ``Non-agreement
in xxx to fix grammer</HEAD>
<HEAD>The Problems President Bush Inherited</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
