<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 2347EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-HorribleHomeland     09-17 0740</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Horrible Homeland,0935</SECOND>
<HEAD>Why East Germans Want to Flee Their Country</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GIRARD C. STEICHEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LEIPZIG, East Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Outside of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, the country's showcase capital, East Germans live in dreary and decaying cities where nagging shortages and chronic pollution aggravate a rigidly regulated life. `` Everywhere you look outside the city centers, where most foreigners go, the country is disintegrating. It's crumbling before your eyes,'' said <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Lange </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION> student who recently joined an exodus to the West. Although East <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s standard of living is the envy of its Eastern European neighbors, thousands are embarrassing the Communist leadership by fleeing shortly before next month's 40th anniversary celebrations. Many of them come from the provincial cities where life is the toughest, and the harsh crackdown on diseen 100 years this month since a jury sentenced eight <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON> clan members to life in prison and ordered a ninth hanged for the slaying of five McCoys, ending the bloodshed in which 10 to 20 people died. But most participants died of old age. The Hatfields' patriarch, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> `` Devil Anse'' <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, got religion and gained community respect before he died in 1921 at the age of 83. His grave at <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> is marked by a towering Italian marble sculpture of him. The leader of the McCoys, <PERSON> Randolph </PERSON> `` Old Ran' l'' <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON>, embittered by the deaths of five of his 16 children, moved to town in <LOCATION> Pikeville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, dying in 1910 at age 85. Buried with them are the real reasons behind the feud in the heart of <LOCATION> Appalachia </LOCATION>. What is known is that the Hatfields, living mainly in what is now <LOCATION> Mingo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, and the McCoys, in <LOCATION> Pike </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, fought on and off for a dozen years in the region's wooded tangle of valleys and ridges Some say the feud started in 1878 over a pig that belonged to the McCoys and ended up in a Hatfield pen. Others say the dispute stemmed from the Civil War, in which, this version goes, the Hatfields fought for the Confederacy and the McCoys the Union. Others say both families fought for the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>. Romantics say the feud stemmed from an illicit affair between <PERSON> Johnse </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON> and <PERSON> Roseanna </PERSON> <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON>, and that she eventually bore him a child out of wedlock. In a 1988 book `` Feud: Hatfields, McCoys and <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Change </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Appalachia </LOCATION>, 1860-1900,'' author <PERSON> Altina </PERSON> <PERSON> Waller </PERSON> contends the feud was the result of a clash between the traditional culture based on subsistence farming, represented by the McCoys, and the emergence of capitalism fueled by coal mining, timber cutting and railroad interests in the Hatfields' region. Whatever the cause, open warfare between the families began in 1882 when <PERSON> Devil </PERSON> <PERSON> Anse </PERSON>'s brother, <PERSON> Ellison </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, was stabbed two dozen times and shot during an election day brawl in <LOCATION> Pike </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. The Hatfields seized the three McCoys responsible, and when <PERSON> Ellison </PERSON> died they were tied to paw paw trees and executed. The feud escalated until New Year's Day 1888, when the Hatfields attacked the <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON> home in <LOCATION> Pike </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, burning it to the ground and killing two of Old Ran' l's children. The governors of <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> became involved in a jurisdictional dispute over the fighting that wound up before the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. Now, <PERSON> McAllister </PERSON>'s organization is trying to find a way to commemorate the feud and the 1920 Matewan Massacre, a downtown gunbattle between <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> sympathizers and coal company guards in which at least nine people died. The incident was depicted in the 1987 movie `` Matewan.'' <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON>, a former Matewan mayor, is among those who had to grow up with the stigma attached to the feud, even though his branch of the family had economic ties to <PERSON> Devil </PERSON> <PERSON> Anse </PERSON> and never took part in the bloodshed. `` Not every McCoy or every <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON> participated in the shootouts,'' <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON> said. `` We're directly related to the so-called feudists, but we were n't participants in the violent part of it.'' But <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON> also is on the <ORGANIZATION> Matewan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>'s board of directors, whose plans call for historic restoration downtown. `` As a member of the family, I probably get a little tired of it. Through the years, ever since I was in high school, it has been brought to my attention,'' he said. `` But as a community, I think it's one of our great hopes for economic survival here.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 2349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Poland'sProspects     09-17 0922</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland's Prospects,0953</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mazowiecki's Economic Challenge Hard To Over Estimate</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DRUSILLA MENAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s historic transition to democracy is to survive, the new government must quickly solve some serious economic problems. Yet the dimensions and complexity of the crisis are so staggering that even Solidarity's <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON>, the first non-Communist prime minister in the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc, says `` Society has no concept how difficult it will be to reform this economy.'' How bad is it? Consider: The value of the zloty currency continues to plummet as inflation soars. At the end of June, 4,900 zloties bought a dollar. Last week, it took 10,000. That means a man who receives $ 20 a month from an aunt in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> gets more than a month's average wage, which was 122,000 zlotys in July, up from 55,000 in January. As a result, workers by the score have walked away from their state jobs, forcing shops to close, mail to go undelivered and assembly lines to stall. This year's state budget envisioned a deficit equivalent to $ 989 million at the official exchange rate, but the government raised it to $ 4.9 billion in just seven months, said economics Professor <PERSON> Jozef </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaleta </PERSON> in the Express Wieczorny newspaper. To span he gap, the government issues more money. Nearly 45 percent of the budget is being covered by the printing of banknotes, according to a <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> report. The list of basics available only with difficulty this week in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> includes flour, cheese, sugar, razor blades, matches, washing powder and sanitary napkins. The government survey of the `` mounting disequilibrium'' in the non-food market listed as `` particularly painful'' shortages of clothing, footwear, furniture, consumer electronics, appliances, refrigerators, kitchenware, radios, sewing machines, bicycles, cars, soap and shampoo. `` I have two children and I literally live in front of this store for three weeks because my refrigerator broke down,'' said a woman who, at 11:30 p.m., was in line outside a <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> shop where a shipment of new appliances was expected some day. She and other relatives took turns sleeping in a car. The hopelessly inadequate telephone system has less than 3 million telephones for 38 million people, no direct connections to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and a tendency to cut off whole districts where numbers start with a certain digit. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s $ 39 billion on foreign debt, $ 1,026 for every man, woman and child, is the fourth largest in the world after <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>. Thirty percent of the government budget subsidizes goods and services, according to a <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> report. The cost of producing beef and veal is 50 percent subsidized, according to the report. Such subsidies mean a farmer could find it cheaper to buy milk at a store than drink it from his own cows. With the average price for coal covering only 53 percent of production costs, supplies for the approaching winter are down dramatically for lack of government subsidies, the state news agency <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> warns. Other state industries ca n't pay for their coal. Outmoded, inefficient factories should be closed. But they employ huge work forces, making up much of Solidarity's membership, and the critical housing shortage makes it difficult for displaced workers to move to new jobs. The wait for a minuscule <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> apartment is a decade or more, but this year forecasters expect to complete 30,000 housing units less than planned nationwide. Typical is a 20-year-old high rise apartment house on <LOCATION> Dolna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> which has not had hot water for seven of the past 11 months due to shoddy construction and lack of spare parts. Five older neighboring buildings are not equipped for hot water at all. About 20 percent of university students emigrate, <ORGANIZATION> Gazeta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wyborcza </ORGANIZATION> says. Doctors frequently prescribe medicines not available at pharmacies, relying on patients to secure them in the West. Hospital stays require a supply of gifts to the staff to secure everything from clean sheets to anesthetics. Physicians and nurses are among the most underpaid of Poles, a remnant of the glorification of the laborer, and are allowed private patients only after hours at government clinics. A dual currency system has developed, with the dollar used for most meaningful transactions. Coffee, orange juice, Scotch, televisions and apartments generally are available only for dollars. Most economic indicators are down, according to the most recent government statistics: industrial sales by 5.9 percent, manufacturing sales by 6 percent, June livestock procurement 25 percent below June 1988. Harder to quantify, but widely felt, is a decline in the pride of craft as workers become demoralized. `` The present state of services, transportation, communications and health care ... makes daily life extremely difficult, forces people to break moral standards and accept humiliating treatment,'' wrote <PERSON> Stanislaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Chelstowski </PERSON> in Economic Life newspaper. The challenge is partly psychological, <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> says. `` The most difficult task is to make people feel that it can be better, although it can not be better immediately,'' he said. A 21-year-old teacher, learning of <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON>'s election, commented: `` We're so tired, it does n't really matter what happens.'' On Aug. 1, the outgoing government took the first radical step, lifting controls on almost all food prices. Although price increases of several hundred percent followed, economists hope supplies will improve. But a consensus is forming that even more painful and radical reforms are needed. `` The economy is on its knees. The pauperization of society advances almost from day to day so there is no time to look for some miraculous cures,'' said <PERSON> Kaleta </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Storm-Grapes     09-17 0356</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Storm-Grapes,0368</SECOND>
<HEAD>Storm Threatens California Grapes, Brings Rare Lightning</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A powerful storm pelted parts of northern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> on Saturday, causing power failures and a death by lightning and threatening the nation's most valuable white wine grape harvest. The storm knocked out electricity from <LOCATION> King </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, 100 miles south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>, to <LOCATION> Chico </LOCATION>, about 160 miles north of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Rutkowski </PERSON>. He said 200,000 residents lost power beginning at 5 a.m., mostly because of lightning strikes, which are unusual in this part of the West. Service was restored in most areas after a few hours, <PERSON> Rutkowski </PERSON> said. Lightning struck and killed a man during a softball game in <LOCATION> Cotati </LOCATION>, about 40 miles north of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, police said. A train that takes visitors on tours of the famed <LOCATION> Napa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> wine country made its inaugural ride, despite being struck by lightning and suffering a power failure before leaving the station. But growers in the area visited by the wine train said the rain threatened to cause rot or late maturity for pricey chardonnay and sauvignon blanc grapes that are nearly ready for harvest on 21,000 acres in <LOCATION> Napa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sonoma </LOCATION> counties. `` It all depends on what happens in the next three of four days,'' said grower <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Beckstoffer </PERSON>. `` We've got to get some wind and heat to dry things up. But if we get humidity ... these grapes will rot.'' He said as much as three-quarters of the most expensive white grapes in the country, worth $ 1,800 a ton or more, could be lost. The rains could allow ruinous mold to form on the grapes, or dilute the grape sugar, delaying the maturation process and thereby putting the grapes at greater risk of being reached by the rot, saidJerry <PERSON> Luper </PERSON>, winemaster at <LOCATION> Rutherford </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> winery. Enologists say the 1989 white grapes of <LOCATION> Napa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sonoma </LOCATION> counties have a potential to be a great vintage _ if the rain does n't get to them first. The red grapes, tougher and thicker-skinner than the whites, are still on the vines and wo n't be harvested for weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Emmy Advisory   09-17 0039</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Emmy, Advisory,0040</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 The list of the winners of the technical Emmy Awards was delivered to the The Associated Press later than expected. The story and the list of the winners should be moving shortly.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>The AP</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 0125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>b a AM-MissAmerica 4thLd-Writethru a0647 09-17 1248</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Miss America, 4th Ld - Writethru, a0647,1284</SECOND>
<HEAD>Miss Missouri Named 1990 Miss America</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 28 grafs to add reaction quotes from winner and friends
and additional background; Debbye is cq. Picks up 21st graf pvs, `Ten finalists
...'; Expected to stand for AMs. Below dash material stands.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos XACC2, XACC3, XACC4, LaserColor XACC5</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOYCE A. VENEZIA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Miss Missouri <PERSON> Debbye </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, a marimba-playing veterinary student, was crowned Miss America 1990 on Saturday night. Miss Turner grabbed and hugged first runner-up Miss <PERSON> Maryland </PERSON> <PERSON> Virginia </PERSON> <PERSON> Cha </PERSON>, 25, of <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON>, and gave a thumbs-up sign to the audience before tearfully walking the runway. The other contestants swarmed around her as she finished her walk. `` It's exhilarating. I can only compare it to being in the Olympics,'' said <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, 23, of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>. The second runner-up was Miss Colorado <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Riecks </PERSON>, 24, of <LOCATION> Aurora </LOCATION>; the third runner-up was Miss <PERSON> Illinois </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeri </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Zimmermann </PERSON>, 21, of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>; and the fourth runner-up was Miss <PERSON> Ohio </PERSON> <PERSON> Kristin </PERSON> <PERSON> Huffman </PERSON>, 24, of <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Winchester </LOCATION>. Miss Turner is the third black woman to become Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> in the pageant's 68-year history. She succeeds Miss America 1989 <PERSON> Gretchen </PERSON> <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON>, 23, of <LOCATION> Anoka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>. Miss <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> said she felt no added pressure being a black Miss America `` I'm <PERSON> Debbye </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>. I grew up in <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>. I attend school in <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>. I'm a born-again Christian,'' she said. `` That's who I am. Being black is not who I am.'' She said she could only attribute her victory to the `` grace of God,'' and now that she has won, her plans include eating pepperoni pizza and sleeping. Miss <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> placed the crown on Miss Turner's head before sending her walking down the runway in the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> Convention Center as host <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> sang the pageant standard, `` There She Is.'' This year's contest became a platform for social issues for the first time. Each finalist was asked a question about the issue of her choice. Miss Turner was asked how to best motivate <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s youth. `` You have to let them know they can do anything and then show them the way to do that,'' she said. The 5-foot-7 -LCB-, 118-pound contestant with dark brown hair and brown eyes won one of the three preliminary swimsuit competitions, in which she wore a canary yellow swimsuit. Miss <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> said her studies as a senior at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Missouri-Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterinary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shool </ORGANIZATION> have given her the opportunity to treat `` everything from a 4-day-old Vietnamese pot-bellied piglet to a 2,000-pound <ORGANIZATION> Hereford </ORGANIZATION> bull.'' She said she collects `` surgery souvenirs'' such as puppy fetuses. `` I just have a pure love for animals,'' said <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, who turns 24 on Tuesday. Miss Turner wowed the crowd by playing the rapid-fire `` Flight of the Bumblebee'' on the marimba. Wearing a two-piece red chiffon pants suit with silver beading and a peplum waistline, she used four mallets for part of the number before tossing two of them behind her in an intense performance. For the evening gown competition, she wore a white velvet beaded gown with a rhinestone bodice. The V-neck gown featured a keyhole back. Each contestant was asked to write an essay before the pageant to detail what she would like to advocate during her year as Miss America. Miss Turner, a poised, self-assured woman, has said she wants to use her reign to motivate young students to strive higher. `` I'm not naive,'' she said before the pageant. `` If I win Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, I'm not saying I'm going to change every youth. If I've inspired one person to be an astronaut, then I'd feel I made a difference. She deflects criticisms that the pageant offers a chance only to white women. `` The doors were n't closed to me,'' she said. `` It's open for any woman who is talented.'' There have been two black Miss Americas. Miss America 1984 <PERSON> Vanessa </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, however, was dethroned after a men's magazine published nude photos of her cavorting with another woman. The first runner-up that year, <PERSON> Suzette </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, was also black, and she completed Miss <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' reign. Black women were not allowed to enter the pageant for the first three decades of the contest. Blacks portrayed slaves in crowning ceremonies during the early years of the pageant. Miss Turner's father, <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON>, is a retired <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> career officer. Her mother, <PERSON> Gussie </PERSON>, is a counselor, a missionary and an evangelist. She has a 27-year-old sister, <PERSON> Suzette </PERSON>. About 15 friends from Miss Turner's veterinary class at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> attended a party to watch the contest. `` Debbye has the morals, she has the talent and she's a professional,'' said <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Patton </PERSON>, a third-year veterinary student. `` It was exciting. It was a thrill just knowing she was there.'' Ten finalists were announced early in the televised program. In addition to the runners-up, the finalists were Miss <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Frick </PERSON>, 23, of <LOCATION> Hialeah </LOCATION>; Miss <PERSON> Oklahoma </PERSON> <PERSON> Tamara </PERSON> <PERSON> Denise </PERSON> <PERSON> Toshiko </PERSON> <PERSON> Marler </PERSON>, 26, of <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION>; Miss <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Kline </PERSON>, 24, of <LOCATION> Easton </LOCATION>; Miss Texas <PERSON> Leah </PERSON> <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyle </PERSON>, 22, of <LOCATION> Plainview </LOCATION>; and <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Wall </PERSON>, 20, of <LOCATION> Issaquah </LOCATION>. The 10 finalists had the highest scores after three days of preliminary swimsuit, talent and evening gown competitions and interviews with judges. All of this year's contestants were asked by pageant officials to take a stand on the issue of their choice, and the winner will be urged to promote her platform during her reign. Pageant director <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Horn </PERSON> said the idea of giving <LOCATION> Miss </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> a voice is one that might bring her more national respect. He has stressed in the past several months that `` this is not just a beauty pageant.'' For the first time, the contestants this year had to submit an essay on the an issue they planned to promote during their year's reign Some of the issues chosen among the 10 finalists included human organ donation, volunteerism, better education for minority students, accessibility for the disabled and discrimination. The festivities were marred Friday night when <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Marler </PERSON> was struck in the head with a beer bottle during the Miss America Parade and suffered a concussion. She spent the night under observation at a city hospital and returned to rehearsal Saturday morning.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The 68-year-old Miss America Pageant awards more than $ 5 million in scholarships annually to more than 80,000 young women who compete on the national, state and local levels. The new Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> receives $ 42,500 in scholarships and the next three runners-up receive $ 20,000, $ 14,000 and $ 11,000, respectively. The remaining finalists each receive $ 6,000 to be used toward their educations, and every remaining contestant receives a $ 2,500 scholarship. <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> was joined by his co-host, <LOCATION> Miss </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> 1971 <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, for this year's show, an <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION> production with the theme `` A Moment in Time.'' The 51 contestants were interviewed and judged during the week by a preliminary panel of seven judges. On Saturday, a panel of seven celebrity judges started with a clean slate evaluating the 10 finalists. The scoring has been revised this year so that the interview with the preliminary judges is counted in the final point tally Saturday night. In the final scoring, talent counts for 40 percent, the interview for 30 percent, and the evening gown and swimsuit divisions each count for 15 percent. The celebrity judges were: developer <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>, entertainer and casino owner <PERSON> Merv </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, actresses <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Phylicia </PERSON> <PERSON> Rashad </PERSON>, former <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Phillies </ORGANIZATION> third baseman <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmidt </PERSON>, psychologist and columnist <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Brothers </PERSON>, and gossip columnist <PERSON> Claudia </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 0132EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TechnicalEmmys     09-17 0877</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Technical Emmys,0937</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Lonesome Dove' Dominates Technical Emmys</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PASADENA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The popular CBS miniseries `` Lonesome Dove'' stampeded over the competition Saturday night with six Emmy awards in the technical categories announced by the <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>. Thirteen other shows won two technical awards each, including the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> fantasy `` Beauty and the <LOCATION> Beast </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` thirtysomething'' and the <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show.'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, which has been a ratings loser, led the technical awards race with 21, followed by <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> with 13. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> System </ORGANIZATION> received seven program and individual awards each. The <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> and the syndicated show `` Star Trek: The Next Generation'' won two awards each. Home Box Office and the Turner Broadcasting System each won one award. Awards in the major Emmy categories will be presented Sunday night at the <ORGANIZATION> Pasadena </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auditorium </ORGANIZATION> in a three-hour-plus ceremony to be broadcast live by <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> at 8 p.m. EDT. Here is a complete list of winners in technical categories of the 41st annual Prime Time Emmy Awards, with multiple awards given in some categories: 1. ART DIRECTION, SERIES: `` Moonlighting: A Womb with a View,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. 2. ART DIRECTION, VARIETY OR MUSIC PROGRAM: `` The <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>. 3. ART DIRECTION, MINISERIES OR SPECIAL: `` I'll Be Home for Christmas,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. 4. CHOREOGRAPHY: `` Disney-MGM Studios Theme Park Grand Opening,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` The <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>. 5. CINEMATOGRAPHY, SERIES: `` Quantum Leap: Pilot,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. 6. CINEMATOGRAPHY, MINISERIES OR SPECIAL: `` Shooter,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. 7. COSTUMING, SERIES: `` thirtysomething: We'll Meet Again,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. 8. COSTUME DESIGN, SERIES: `` Beauty and the Beast: The Outsiders,'' CBS. 9. COSTUME DESIGN, MINISERIES OR SPECIAL: `` Lonesome Dove,'' Part Two, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>. 10. COSTUME DESIGN, VARIETY OR MUSIC PROGRAM: `` The Magic of <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Copperfield </PERSON> XI: The Explosive Encounter,'' CBS. 11. SINGLE CAMERA PRODUCTION EDITING, SERIES: `` thirtysomething: First Day, Last Day,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. 12. SINGLE CAMERA PRODUCTION EDITING, MINISERIES OR SPECIAL: `` War and Remembrance,'' Part 10, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. 13. MULTI-CAMERA PRODUCTION EDITING, SERIES: `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>: Respect,'' CBS. 14. MULTI-CAMERA PRODUCTION EDITING, MINISERIES OR SPECIAL: `` Great Performances: Dance in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>: <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Hines </PERSON> Tap Dance in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' PBS. 15. GRAPHIC DESIGN AND TITLE SEQUENCES: No award given. 16. HAIR STYLING FOR A SERIES: `` Quantum Leap: Double Identity,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. 17. HAIR STYLING FOR A MINISERIES OR SPECIAL: `` Jack the Ripper,'' Part One, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>. 18. LIGHTING DIRECTION FOR A COMEDY SERIES: `` Who's The Boss: A Spirited Christmas,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. 19. LIGHTING DIRECTION FOR A DRAMA SERIES, VARIETY SERIES, MINISERIES OR SPECIAL: `` The Magic of <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Copperfield </PERSON> XI: The Explosive Encounter,'' CBS. 20. MAKEUP FOR A MINISERIES OR SPECIAL: `` Lonesome Dove,'' Part Four, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>. 21. MUSIC COMPOSITION FOR A SERIES: `` Falcon Crest: Dust to Dust,'' CBS. 22. MUSIC COMPOSITION FOR A MINISERIES OR SPECIAL: `` Lonesome Dove,'' Part Four, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>. 23. MUSIC DIRECTION: `` Christmas in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. 24. MUSIC AND LYRICS: `` Beauty and the Beast: A Distant Shore,'' CBS. 25. MAIN TITLE THEME MUSIC: No award given. 26. GUEST ACTOR IN A COMEDY SERIES: <PERSON> Cleavon </PERSON> <PERSON> Little </PERSON>, `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. 27. GUEST ACTOR IN A DRAMA SERIES: <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Spano </PERSON>, `` Midnight Caller,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. 28. GUEST ACTRESS IN A COMEDY SERIES: <PERSON> Colleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Dewhurst </PERSON>, `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS. 29. GUEST ACTRESS IN A DRAMA SERIES: <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Lenz </PERSON>, `` Midnight Caller,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. 30. SPECIAL EVENTS: `` Cirque de Soleil,'' <ORGANIZATION> HBO </ORGANIZATION>; `` The 11th Annual Kennedy Center Honors: A Celebration of the Performing Arts,'' CBS; `` The 42nd Annual Tony Awards,'' CBS; `` The 17th Annual American Film Institute Life Achievement Award: A Salute to <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Peck </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. 31. CLASSICAL PROGRAM IN THE PERFORMING ARTS: `` Great Performances: <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> at 70!,'' PBS. 32. CHILDREN'S PROGRAM: `` Free to Be ... A Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. 33. INFORMATIONAL SPECIAL: `` American Masters: <PERSON> Lillian </PERSON> <PERSON> Gish </PERSON>: The Actor's Life for Me,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. 34. INFORMATIONAL SERIES: `` Nature,'' PBS. 35. ANIMATED PROGRAM -LRB- FOR PROGRAMMING ONE HOUR OR LESS -RRB-: `` Garfield: Babes and Bullets,'' CBS. 36. ANIMATED PROGRAM OF MORE THAN ONE HOUR: No award given. 37. SOUND EDITING, SERIES: `` Star Trek: The Next Generation: Q Who,'' syndicated. 38. SOUND EDITING, MINISERIES OR SPECIAL: `` Lonesome Dove,'' Part Three, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>. 39. SOUND MIXING, COMEDY, SERIES OR SPECIAL: `` Night Court: The Last Temptation of Mac,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. 40. SOUND MIXING, VARIETY OR MUSIC SERIES OR SPECIAL: `` <PERSON> Kenny </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dolly </PERSON> and Willie: Something Inside So Strong,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. 41. SOUND MIXING, DRAMA SERIES: `` Star Trek: The Next Generation: Q Who,'' syndicated. 42. SOUND MIXING, DRAMA MINISERIES OR SPECIAL: `` Lonesome Dove,'' Part Four, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>. 43. SPECIAL VISUAL EFFECTS: `` War and Remembrance,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. 44. CAMERA-VIDEO TECHNICAL DIRECTION, SERIES: `` Night Court: Yet Another Day in the Life,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. 45. CAMERA-VIDEO TECHNICAL DIRECTION, MINISERIES OR SPECIAL: `` American Playhouse: The Meeting,'' PBS. 46. CLASSICAL MUSIC-DANCE PROGRAMMING DIRECTING: No award given. 47. CLASSICAL MUSIC-DANCE PROGRAMMING PERFORMANCE: `` Great Performances: Dance in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>: <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON> <PERSON> Dances </PERSON> <PERSON> Balanchine </PERSON>,'' PBS. 48. INFORMATIONAL PROGRAMMING DIRECTING: No award given. 49. INFORMATIONAL PROGRAMMING PERFORMANCE: <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Holbrook </PERSON>, `` Portrait of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>: <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>,'' TBS. 50. INFORMATIONAL PROGRAMMING WRITING: <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Heminway </PERSON>, `` The Mind: Search for Mind,'' PBS. 51. SPECIAL EVENTS DIRECTING: <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Hemion </PERSON>, `` The 11th Annual Kennedy Center Honors: A Celebration of the Performing Arts,'' CBS. 52. SPECIAL EVENTS LIGHTING DIRECTION: No award given. 53. SPECIAL EVENTS MUSIC: No award given. 54. SPECIAL EVENTS PERFORMANCE: <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Crystal </PERSON>, `` The 31st Annual Grammy Awards,'' CBS. 55. SPECIAL EVENTS SOUND MIXING: `` The 31st Annual Grammy Awards,'' CBS. 56. SPECIAL EVENTS WRITING: <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Lane </PERSON>, `` The 42nd Annual Tony Awards,'' CBS. 57. CASTING, MINISERIES OR SPECIAL: `` Lonesome Dove,'' CBS.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-HurricaneHugo 8thLd-Writethru a0646 09-17 0934</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hurricane Hugo, 8th Ld-Writethru, a0646,0957</SECOND>
<HEAD>Storm Hits Guadeloupe, Other Eastern Caribbean Islands Brace for
Onslaught</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 9 grafs to UPDATE with eye of storm over Guadeloupe,
France prepares to send relief aid. Pickup 8th graf ``It's a very...''</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto MH3</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT GLASS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN JUAN, Puerto Rico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hurricane Hugo ripped away rooftops and uprooted trees in <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION> early Sunday and approached other popular resort islands of the eastern <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> with deadly winds of up to 140 mph. Forecasters described <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> as `` extremely dangerous'' and said it could be the most powerful hurricane to hit the region since Hurricane David in 1979. That storm killed an estimated 1,200 people in the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. `` The eye of the hurricane is directly above <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Israel </PERSON> <PERSON> Matos </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> bureau in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION>, said Sunday at 1:25 a.m. EDT. It was impossible to telephone to <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION> early Sunday morning as telephone circuits were either jammed or busy. At midnight EDT Saturday, <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON>'s center was near 16.3 north latitude and 61.1 <LOCATION> west </LOCATION> <LOCATION> longitude </LOCATION>, about 350 miles east-southeast of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION>. After hitting the French island it was expected to move north toward <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, said forecaster <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> at the National Hurricane Center near <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. The hurricane was moving west-northwest at 12 mph, sending showers and gusty winds to the eastern edge of the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> and threatening islands over a 600-mile arc stretching from <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lucia </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>. The storm's effects would start to be felt in the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> by Sunday morning, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION> said. By midnight there was a blackout in most of <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION> as authorities turned off electricity as a precautionary measure, government radio <ORGANIZATION> RFO </ORGANIZATION> said. The island experienced very strong winds, which blew the metal roofing off some homes on <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION>'s eastern side late Saturday night. In <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION> to the south there were power outages on the island's north side where strong winds uprooted trees, the radio said <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> France </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Internationale </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, monitored in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION> shortly before midnight Saturday, said <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> authorities were preparing to send emergency supplies and personnel to <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION>. `` It's a very dangerous storm, extremely dangerous in fact,'' <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said. Forecasters said if the storm remains on its northwesterly course it would pass over <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Croix </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> about 6 p.m. Sunday and continue on to the northeastern coast of <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> early Monday. <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rican </LOCATION> capital with a population of 1.1 million, is on the northeastern coast. Earlier, forecasters had said the hurricane was headed for <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>'s southern coast. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> issued hurricane warnings at 3 p.m. EDT for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> and for <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, which previously had been on a hurricane watch. The warnings were posted from <LOCATION> Martinique </LOCATION> northward and westward through <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, including the <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Martin </LOCATION> and surrounding islands. Tropical storm watches for the islands of <LOCATION> Barbados </LOCATION> and <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> were discontinued, and a warning for <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lucia </LOCATION> was changed to a tropical storm watch. Forecasters said waves 10 feet above normal could be expected near the eye of Hugo, and warned of heavy rain and flooding. In <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION>, the first two islands directly in <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON>'s path, civil defense officials prepared to evacuate people to rescue shelters. <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>, head of the Pan-Caribbean Disaster Preparedness and Prevention Project in <LOCATION> Antigua </LOCATION>, said several relief teams from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> already were headed to the region. State radio said a heavy downpour set off a landslide early Saturday on <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION>'s isolated southeast side, which faces the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>, partly blocking a road but causing no injuries. The Public Works Department deployed earth-moving equipment at strategic points across the island. Non-critically ill patients at Princess <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Hospital </PERSON> in the capital of <LOCATION> Roseau </LOCATION> were sent home late Friday and early Saturday to make room for possible hurricane victims. The government of <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION> urged its citizens via radio to take emergency precautions, and said police were put on alert `` to deal with any security problem which might arise.'' There was widespread looting after Hurricane <PERSON> David </PERSON> battered the tiny island of 81,000 people. In <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION>, which has a population of 340,000, heavy traffic built up in Pointe-a-Pitre, the biggest city, late Friday as people rushed supermarkets and hardware stores, stocking up on food, bottled water and supplies such as flashlights, batteries, timber, nails and tape. The government ordered all pedestrians and cars to be off the streets by 6 p.m. in what amounted to a curfew. The directions were broadcast on radio stations. Residents boarded up doors and windows of their homes and many on the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> side fled inland. At <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Meridien </PERSON>, a luxury, 271-room beachfront hotel in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francois </LOCATION>, a woman who answered the telephone said guests were being moved from ground-floor rooms and those facing the ocean. But she said none of the 100 guests had checked out. `` Many people are worried; nobody's hysterical,'' said the hotel employee, who asked not to be identified by name. In <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> France </ORGANIZATION> canceled all three of its flights scheduled Saturday to <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION>'s sister island, <LOCATION> Martinique </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> canceled its flight from <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Antigua </LOCATION>, where the airport was closed. Officials in <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> said up to 6,000 people might have to be evacuated from flood-prone areas if <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> passes near the densely populated island of 3.3 million. <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> is the eighth named storm of the current <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> hurricane season, which runs from June 1 to Nov. 30.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 0227EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-MarconiAwards     09-17 0204</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Marconi Awards,0220</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chicago's WLS Named Legendary Station</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s WLS-AM was named `` Legendary Station'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> news </ORGANIZATION> commentator <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> won the personality of the year award in the first Marconi Radio Awards. <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> was awarded in the network-syndication category of the awards announced at the annual National Association of Broadcasters convention. The other personality of the year winners, by markets, were: <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, KVIL-AM-FM, <LOCATION> Dallas-Forth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, major market; <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Steele </PERSON>, WTIC-AM, <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, large market; <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Summers </PERSON>, WBBQ-AM-FM, <LOCATION> Augusta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, medium market; <PERSON> Billie </PERSON> <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON>, KMA-AM, <LOCATION> Shenandoah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>; small market. The Stations of the year winners were: KNIX-AM-FM, <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>, major market; WIVK-AM-FM, <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, large market; WBBQ-AM-FM, <LOCATION> Augusta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, medium market; and <ORGANIZATION> KBOZ-FM </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bozeman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, small market. Winners of station of the year by format were: Country _ KNIX-AM-FM, <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>. Adult Contemporary-Soft Rock-Oldies _ KVIL-AM-FM, <LOCATION> Dallas-Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>. News-Talk _ KMOX-AM, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>. Contemporary Hit Radio-Top 40 _ KPWR-FM, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. Jazz-New Age _ KTWV-FM, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> _ WQBA-AM-FM, <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. Black-Urban _ WVAZ-FM, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. Classical _ WQXR-AM-FM, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Big Band-Nostalgia _ KMPC-AM, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. Religious-Gospel _ KLTY-FM, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>. Easy Listening-Beautiful Music _ KABL-AM-FM, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. Middle of the <LOCATION> Road-Variety </LOCATION> _ WGN-AM, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. Album Rock-Classic Rock _ WMMR-FM, <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 0350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-CaspianQuake     09-17 0281</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Caspian Quake,0294</SECOND>
<HEAD>Strong Quake Hits Caspian Sea Region</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A strong earthquake shook the <LOCATION> Caspian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> region of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> before dawn Sunday, the third relatively strong earthquake in the area since Tuesday, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported There was no word of casualties or damage from the quake centered in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION> 250 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>, measuring 5.6 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, said the agency monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>. An observatory in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> said the quake was centered in the <LOCATION> Caspian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> about 120 miles northeast of the Azerbaijani capital and port city of <LOCATION> Baku </LOCATION> and measured 6.5 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale. <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION>, monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, said <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> and other cities in northern <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> were jolted by the earthquake registered by the <ORGANIZATION> Tehran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Geophysics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> at 4:24 a.m. -LRB- 8:54 p.m. EDT Saturday -RRB-. <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION> reported Saturday that an earthquake registering 5.5 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale shook the region Saturday. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Geological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Survey </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> said that quake, also with an epicenter east of <LOCATION> Baku </LOCATION>, registered 6.6. Another tremor registering 5.2 shook the area around <LOCATION> Gorgan </LOCATION>, 185 miles east of <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> on Tuesday, <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION> said. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> is shaken by hundreds of earthquakes a year, ranging from 2.4 to 5.5 on the Richter Scale. The last major earthquake, registering 7.7, was in September 1978. It killed 25,000 people. The <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale is a measure of energy released by an earthquake as recorded on seismographs. Every increase of one whole number means a tenfold increase in magnitude. An earthquake of 5 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale can cause serious damage and one of 7 can cause widespread heavy damage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 0501EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-MotherTeresa     09-17 0269</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Mother Teresa,0278</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nobel Laureate Having Chest Pains Again</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FARID HOSSAIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CALCUTTA, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> developed chest pains again Sunday, but doctors treating the Nobel laureate said her overall condition was stable. A statement issued by <LOCATION> Woodlands </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nursing </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Home </LOCATION>, the hospital where she is recovering from a heart attack, said the 79-year-old Roman Catholic nun was `` resting comfortably.'' `` The mother is having some chest pains. But her temperature is showing signs of settling down and her overall condition is stable,'' the statement said. `` We have found one or two causes for the infection. We are hopeful that now she will improve faster,'' said Dr. A.K. <PERSON> Bardhan </PERSON>, refusing to elaborate. <PERSON> Bardhan </PERSON> said <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> was still using a temporary pacemaker that was attached after she suffered a heart attack Sept. 8. `` But her heart is still weak even though she is improving and responding to treatment,'' he said. <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> first developed chest pains and high fever Thursday just as doctors thought she was progressing well. The soft-spoken nun was admitted to the hospital Sept. 5 with an irregular heartbeat, a blocked artery and high fever. Born in <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> gave up a comfortable life as a convent teacher to live and work among the destitute and dying in this eastern Indian city's squalid slums. She was awarded the 1979 Nobel Peace Prize for her work. She founded the <ORGANIZATION> Missionaries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Charity </ORGANIZATION> in October 1950 in an abandoned rundown hostel donated by the city. The order, formally recognized by the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> in 1965, expanded and has 3,000 nuns working in 87 countries.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 0655EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Britain-Tankers 3rdLd-Writethru   09-17 0355</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Britain-Tankers, 3rd Ld-Writethru,a0657,0366</SECOND>
<HEAD>Oil Tankers Collide And Burn in North Sea, Causing 5-Mile Slick</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES to CORRECT that officials unsure how collision occurred,
UPDATES with gallons spilled. No pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HULL, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two oil tankers collided in the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> off eastern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> early Sunday, causing a fire aboard both vessels and an oil slick five miles long, the coast guard said. Seventeen of 26 crew members were evacuated from the Liberian-registered <LOCATION> Phillips </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> after it collided with the Maltese-registered <PERSON> Fiona </PERSON>, anchored near the mouth of the <LOCATION> Humber </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> about 150 miles north of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, said spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Clempson </PERSON>. The <PERSON> Fiona </PERSON>'s bosun jumped overboard and was treated for shock after he was rescued, but the rest of the ship's 30-member crew remained aboard, <PERSON> Clempson </PERSON> said. No other injuries were reported. The collision caused about 340,000 gallons of crude oil to escape from the <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, forming a slick about five miles long and a quarter-mile wide before the leak was contained, said <PERSON> Clempson </PERSON>. `` Most of that will have probably been burnt up in the fire,'' he said. `` The way it is heading it does n't appear to be coming ashore.'' <PERSON> Clempson </PERSON> said aircraft were dispatched to spray chemicals to disperse the oil. The fires were extinguished by mid-morning and both ships were anchored off Spurn Head in the mouth of the <LOCATION> Humber </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Clempson </PERSON> said. The <LOCATION> Phillips </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, laden with 56,000 tons of crude oil, and the <PERSON> Fiona </PERSON> carrying 46,500 tons of refined oil collided at about 5 a.m. -LRB- midnight EDT Saturday -RRB-, he said. `` I'm not going to be drawn on the question of who's responsibility it was,'' he said, adding that the investigation would be conducted by the Marine Accident Investigation branch of the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Clempson </PERSON> said it was not clear how the collision occurred, since the <LOCATION> Phillips </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, the moving ship, was damaged on the stern while the <PERSON> Fiona </PERSON> was damaged on the bow. Humberside police said the <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> was inward bound to discharge its cargo. Sea King helicopters, a Nimrod reconnaissance aircraft, a <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> minesweeper and firefighting tugs took part in the rescue, <PERSON> Clempson </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 0839EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-StaynerDeath     09-17 0393</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Stayner Death,0404</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kidnap Victim Steven Stayner Dead At 24</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MERCED, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Stayner </PERSON>, who as a child was kidnapped and held captive until he escaped seven years later, died in a motorcycle accident, a coroner's spokesman said. <PERSON> Stayner </PERSON>, 24, was pronounced dead at <ORGANIZATION> Merced </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> shortly after the 5:30 p.m. Saturday accident on <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> Fe Highway between <LOCATION> Merced </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, said a <LOCATION> Merced </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> coroner's spokesman, who declined to give his name The car that hit <PERSON> Stayner </PERSON>, who was riding a motorcycle without a helmet, took off after the accident, said state police officer <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Maxfield </PERSON>. It was found in <LOCATION> Merced </LOCATION> after the driver apparently switched to another car, <PERSON> Maxfield </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Stayner </PERSON>, the subject of an <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> miniseries in May, lived as the son of his abductor, <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Parnell </PERSON>, a convicted child molester. In 1972, at the age of 7, <PERSON> Stayner </PERSON> was kidnapped while walking home from school in <LOCATION> Merced </LOCATION>. When <PERSON> Stayner </PERSON> was 14, <PERSON> Parnell </PERSON> kidnapped another boy, 5-year-old <PERSON> Timmy </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>. A short time later, <PERSON> Stayner </PERSON> escaped, taking <PERSON> Timmy </PERSON> with him and going to a police station in <LOCATION> Ukiah </LOCATION>, about 150 miles north. <PERSON> Stayner </PERSON> recently talked candidly with reporters of his life with <PERSON> Parnell </PERSON>, who he said alternately molested him and passed him off as his son, calling him <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON>. The boy was led to believe his parents did n't want him any more. <PERSON> Parnell </PERSON> was convicted of two counts of kidnapping and was sentenced to eight years and eight months in prison in February 1982 after an 18-day trial in <LOCATION> Hayward </LOCATION>. He served five years at Soledad State Prison, then was on parole for another two years. While no sex charges were filed against <PERSON> Parnell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Stayner </PERSON> testified during trial that he had been sexually abused. In 1985, <PERSON> Stayner </PERSON> married <PERSON> Jody </PERSON> <PERSON> Edmondson </PERSON> in Atwater, where the two were living with their two small children at the time of his death. Earlier this year, <PERSON> Stayner </PERSON> had a walk-on part as a Merced police officer in the television series about his case, `` I Know My First Name is <PERSON> Steven </PERSON>,'' which was broadcast in May on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. In April, he told an interviewer, `` My hope with the movie is that some kid sees it and gets up the nerve to tell someone and try to come home.'' <PERSON> Parnell </PERSON>, 57, is believed to be living in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 0922EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Hugo 3rdLd-Writethru   09-17 0643</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Hugo, 3rd Ld-Writethru,a0661,0659</SECOND>
<HEAD>Storm Leaves Thousands Homeless in Guadeloupe, Heads to Puerto Rico</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 14 grafs to UPDATE with latest location of hurricane,
ADDS details from weather service bulletin. Clarifies that storm surges
up to eight feet above normal, sted up to eight feet, expected. Pickup
13th pvs, `In Dominica...</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN JUAN, Puerto Rico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hurricane Hugo ripped across resort islands of the eastern <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> on Sunday with winds up to 140 mph, ripping away rooftops, uprooting trees and leaving an estimated 3,000 people homeless on the island of <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION>. Forecasters described <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> as `` extremely dangerous'' as it churned toward <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> and said it could be the most powerful hurricane to hit the region since Hurricane David in 1979. That storm killed an estimated 1,200 people in the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. At 9 a.m. EDT, <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON>'s center was located near latitude 16.6 north and longitude 62.7 west, about 250 miles east-southeast of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION>, said the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> was moving west-northwest at 12 mph and was expected to hit the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> on Sunday night or early Monday, the weather service said. Hurricane warnings were in effect for islands throughout the region. `` All preparedness actions should be rushed to completion in the warned areas,'' the weather service said in its 9 a.m. weather bulletin. The storm slammed into the French island of <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION>, about 350 miles east-southeast of <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, just after midnight Sunday. Phone circuits to affected islands were either busy or jammed early Sunday and it could not be immediately determined if the storm caused any casualties on the island of 340,000 people. <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Roure </PERSON>, a government official on <LOCATION> Martinique </LOCATION>, told French radio there were no reports of deaths of serious injuries on <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION> but that it appeared about 3,000 people were left homeless. <LOCATION> Martinique </LOCATION> is about 100 miles south of <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Roure </PERSON> reported heavy damage to buildings and said the airport control tower in the city of Pointe-a-Pitre was `` partially destroyed.'' `` Since people ca n't move around and almost all communications are cut, it is possible there's more information that has not been passed along,'' he said. He said it appeared that <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Desirade </PERSON>, an island of about 1,600 people 22 miles east of <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION>, may have been the hardest hit so far but that all communications with it were cut. The director of civil security at the French <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hubert </PERSON> <PERSON> Fournier </PERSON>, said emergency supplies and personnel were being prepared to be sent to <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION> as soon as it was known what was needed. Rainfall of up to 10 inches was expected in the path of the hurricane, producing flash floods and possible mud slides in hilly regions, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. It warned residents in mountainous areas to move to safer locations. Storm surges up to eight feet above normal were expected in coastal areas, forecasters said. In <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION> to the south of <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION>, there were power outages on the island's north side where strong winds uprooted trees, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> RFO </ORGANIZATION> radio said. In <LOCATION> Antigua </LOCATION>, just north of <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION>, heavy rain and very strong winds also uprooting trees were reported. Authorities there turned off power to the entire island of 100,000 people as a precautionary measure shortly before midnight. The radio reported flooding in low-lying areas but provided no details. It said dozens of people were moved to shelters. At the plush <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> James </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> hotel, on the island's southeastern side, guests were evacuated. In the British dependency of <LOCATION> Montserrat </LOCATION>, northwest of <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION> and directly in <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON>'s path, <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Dominique </PERSON>, editor at <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Antilles </ORGANIZATION>, said the storm blew down trees and ripped away galvanized rooftops of several homes in the capital, <ORGANIZATION> Plymouth </ORGANIZATION>, early Sunday. <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> is the eighth named storm of the current <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> hurricane season, which runs from June 1 to Nov. 30.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 1123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--ParachuteDeath     09-17 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Parachute Death,0083</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sky Diver Falls to His Death</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MELBOURNE, Australia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An experienced sky diver plunged to his death Sunday after his parachute failed to open, police said. <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Scouller </PERSON>, 27, jumped from a twin-engine airplane at <LOCATION> Pakenham </LOCATION> outside <LOCATION> Melbourne </LOCATION>, a police spokesman said. His parachute did not open until moments before he hit the ground. <PERSON> Scouller </PERSON>, a veteran of more than 100 jumps, was one of 10 sky divers to jump from the aircraft. The nine others landed safely.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 1125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--ShootingSpree     09-17 0137</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Shooting Spree,0139</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gunmen Fire Into Shops</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HYDERABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Marauding gunmen fired indiscriminately into crowded shops Sunday, killing five people and wounding at least 12 before fleeing, police said. Ethnic strife appeared to be the cause of the shooting, which began on a college campus when a fight broke out between student nationalists seeking independence for the southern province of Sindh and those of immigrant parents from <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, police said. The gunmen later moved from the college campus to <LOCATION> Hyderabad </LOCATION>'s shopping district Police said both sides appeared to responsible for the shootings. Shopkeepers shuttered their businesses, and police and paramilitary forces began patrolling the streets. Hundreds of people have died and thousands have been injured in ethnic violence in <LOCATION> Hyderabad </LOCATION> and in the port city of <LOCATION> Karachi </LOCATION>, 66 miles south on the <LOCATION> Arabian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 1141EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--ChemicalLeak     09-17 0100</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Chemical Leak,0101</SECOND>
<HEAD>103 Hospitalized After Chemical Leak</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AMMAN, Jordan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 103 people were hospitalized and thousands were evacuated from their homes when poisonous chlorine gas leaked from a sulphur factory, the civil defense department said Sunday. Gen. <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON> <PERSON> Tarawneh </PERSON>, the civil defense director, said the leak Saturday night was caused by `` bad maintenance'' on three gas valves at the plant on the <LOCATION> Zarqa </LOCATION> Highway in northeastern <LOCATION> Amman </LOCATION>. He said the leak was an accident, and had been brought under control. Among those hospitalized were 28 civil defense personnel. The local police chief was also treated.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 1204EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PatrickKennedy     09-17 0698</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Patrick Kennedy,0718</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Political Education of a Young Kennedy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FLIPPEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PROVIDENCE, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Growing up in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s most famous political family did not prepare <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> for the ways of the <ORGANIZATION> Rhode </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. The political education of Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s younger son began last year, when he challenged a 10-year incumbent in the Democratic primary for a state <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> seat from northwest <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION>. It continued when he got to the Statehouse and learned what it really takes to pass a bill. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, 22, was no ordinary freshman. Then a junior and now a senior at <ORGANIZATION> Providence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, he spent $ 87,694, or $ 66 per vote _ a record for a state legislative race _ for a job that pays $ 300 a year. All but $ 5,904 of that was his own money. Then <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> hired a staff aide and opened an office in his district. His predecessor, like most <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> members, had operated alone, using space in his house and his funeral home. But despite his family's wealth and prominence, <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> soon found his bills treated the same as everyone else's in a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> where, observers like the group <ORGANIZATION> Common </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cause </ORGANIZATION> say, the speaker's word is law. Several of <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s major initiatives, including a bill to require <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> automobiles to adhere to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> emissions standards, never got out of the committee he sits on, Health, Education and Welfare. `` I talked to most of the members of the committee and it was clear to me that we had a majority to pass that,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said. `` I was told to go speak to the leadership, and I went to speak to -LRB- Majority Leader -RRB- <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamb </PERSON> and he said, ` Well, we have to look into this more,' and it was tabled. `` And I asked around, ` what did this mean?' and people said, ` Well, that's tantamount to letting a bill die quietly.''' The committee's chairman, Democrat <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fiorenzano </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s family background should have prepared him for his legislative losses. `` Maybe he's disappointed that things did n't move as fast as he wanted them to, but he should n't have been taken aback,'' <PERSON> Fiorenzano </PERSON> said. `` I've submitted some pieces of legislation every year since I've been elected and they still have n't been passed.'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said his father's life in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> was nothing like the routine of the <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Statehouse </LOCATION>. `` My father ... has had to come to compromise, he's had to work on things with other colleagues and he's had to agree and disagree,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said. `` That's the way the legislative process is supposed to work, and that can still work without it being -LRB- a system -RRB- where the shots are called without any compromise or agreement.'' The Rev. <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> West </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, director of the <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> chapter of Common Cause, a legislative watchdog group, agreed that power is highly centralized in the state house. `` So much seems to happen here by the decision from the speaker's office,'' he said. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said he plans to seek re-election despite his frustration with the system, and already is busy deflecting attacks from Republicans. The <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> did not run anyone against him last year but since then has criticized <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> repeatedly for raising thousands of dollars from out-of-state sources. ` Where I receive my contributions has no bearing whatsoever on my voting. I thought it was offensive that they implied that people in this neighborhood had their votes for sale,'' he said. `` After a certain point, the amount of money you spend in a local race is ineffective because people have to meet you.'' House leaders said <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> has been as effective as any freshman legislator and could have a bright future if he remains in the House. Speaker <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> DeAngelis </PERSON> said he never had asked for <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s vote on any particular bill, but, `` On those issues that were party issues, he has always been a Democrat. <PERSON> Fiorenzano </PERSON> praised <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s devotion to the job. `` Everyone, when you first get up there, thinks they're going to change the world,'' <PERSON> Fiorenzano </PERSON> said. `` Then you learn not everyone shares your view and you have to work with other people to reach compromises on your issues.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 1211EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Pentagon-Drugs Bjt   09-17 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pentagon-Drugs, Bjt,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reconstruction-era Law Defines Military Role In Drug Battle</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The idea of deploying <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s military forces on the nation's streets to battle the scourge of drugs may be fodder for headlines and congressional demands, but <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials point out there are strict legal limitations on such a thing. `` It just makes hair stand on end here,'' said one senior <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> official. `` Our primary mission is to prepare for any possible military threat _ not to be a national police force. ... There's been a lot of very loose talk about expanding our role.'' To counter assumptions that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops could be used to patrol the streets and nab drug dealers, <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials point to a little-known law that prevents active duty troops from acting as law enforcement officers within the nation's borders. It is known as the Posse Comitatus Act and was passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1878 as a post-Civil War reaction to the use of federal troops in enforcing the Reconstruction Acts. Because it deals with the enforcement of domestic law, the law does not affect <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces overseas. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Super </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said that while it may be enticing to think of the nation's military might as a machine to be turned against drug king pins, the ramifications have to be taken into account. `` It's really a rather profound idea when you think about it,'' he said. `` Posse Comitatus is a reflection on our free society. There are a lot of countries where the military is used to police the streets, but they are n't much fun to live in.'' According to a common legal definition, the term `` posse comitatus'' means the power of the county and refers to the authority of the sheriff to call to his aid the male population above the age of 15 to in capturing escaped felons and keeping the peace. In effect, the law is interpreted to mean that military forces _ the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION> and their respective reserves _ may be used in a support role for the battle against drugs, such as aiding in surveillance or interdiction efforts. But they are prevented from adopting the role of law enforcement officials, tasks assigned to the local police or other officials, such as from the Drug Enforcement Agency. For example, the military may provide boats to help interdict drug traffickers, or radar surveillance to spot a drug-transporting plane, but it is up to civilian law enforcement officials to seize evidence, make arrests, and testify in court. The law does not affect a state's <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> when units are under the control of its governor, but the laws in each state vary, said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunlap </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> is the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> agency that serves as a coordinating body for the Guard forces in the various states. It is <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> policy that its members `` not be tasked'' with enforcing civil law, officials point out. `` It's important, because we just do n't have the training _ we're not trained to do police work,'' <PERSON> Dunlap </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dunlap </PERSON> said Guard units have been involved in helping local officials support drug interdiction efforts since 1977, and since 1983 has been involved on the federal level. In fact, the role of the Guard has been expanded in 21 states to allow them to aid Customs officials in cargo inspections for illicit drugs, <PERSON> Super </PERSON> said. `` Guardsmen are happy to be involved. ... Guardsmen are all volunteers and part of the community they serve. But our proper role is in support of civilian law enforcement officials,'' <PERSON> Dunlap </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has been pressing the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> to become more active on the home front in the war against drugs, despite concerns among the military brass about draining resources from their traditional defense mission. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> is slated to outlined an expanded military role this week. The secretary's plan is not expected to call for an enforcement role for the military, but rather emphasize increased interdiction and radar surveillance methods, among other things.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 1217EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Iran-Iraq     09-17 0542</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iran-Iraq,0560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran Threatens Force if Iraq Does Not Give Up Land</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED BLANCHE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Iranian President <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> said Sunday that if <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> does not relinquish Iranian territory it seized in the last days of the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> war, his country `` will make it retreat by force.'' It was the toughest statement made by an <LOCATION> Iranian </LOCATION> leader since a cease-fire in the eight-year war took effect Aug. 20, 1988. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, quoted <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> as telling commanders of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s Revolutionary Guards: `` We have no territorial ambitions, but we will not cede one inch of our Islamic land. <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> did not give <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> a deadline but said, `` We will be patient as far as possible.'' His comments to commanders of the paramilitary Revolutionary Guards were carried by the official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> in a report monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>. `` It will be very easy for us to regain our land,'' said <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, who was elected July 28. He made clear <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> will not make any concessions to break a deadlock in peace talks that began more than a year ago. The Iranians insist there can be no advance in the talks until the Iraqis withdraw from Iranian soil. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> claims the Iraqis hold 1,028 square miles of Iranian border territory. <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> observers say the Iraqis hold 386 square miles. The land was captured in a series of Iraqi offensives shortly before the cease-fire took effect. Those military setbacks were a key factor in forcing <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> to accept the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> cease-fire resolution. `` <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> is not seeking any illogical concession from <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, just as it will not make any concessions to the enemy, even if the present situation lasts 10 years,'' <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> said at the Revolutionary Guards' commanders annual conference in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>. `` If one day we become certain that the enemy is not willing to return our land, we will make it retreat by force,'' he declared. <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has no desire to resume the war, which by Western military estimates killed more than 1 million people. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> was believed to have suffered losses three times as heavy as <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. In addition to the land issue, the peace talks are stalled over disagreements concerning the <LOCATION> Shatt-al-Arab </LOCATION> waterway, the southern boundary between the nations. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> is demanding that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> allow the waterway _ <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s main outlet to the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> _ to be dredged and reopened. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> refuses. In addition, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> does not recognize a 1975 treaty that drew the Iran-Iraq border down the center of the waterway. Before that treaty, the border ran down the Iranian bank of the Shatt-al-Arab. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> says the 1975 treaty is valid. <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> will not back down on the <PERSON> Shatt-al-Arab </PERSON>. `` We will repel the enemy to the borders defined in the 1975 accord,'' he said. Before <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> spoke, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s spiritual leader, <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Khamenei </PERSON>, told commanders their forces and the regular army must be in a state of constant combat readiness. But he noted: `` We are determined to achieve peace within the framework of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> resolution and we will never initiate a step to weaken it.'' The last session of peace talks was held in April under <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> auspices.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 1233EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--Solidarity-Citizenship     09-17 0170</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Solidarity-Citizenship,0174</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Solidarnosc' Logo Creator to Take U.S. Oath</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The creator of the `` Solidarnosc'' banner of the Polish trade union Solidarity is adopting another flag. <PERSON> Kazimierz </PERSON> <PERSON> Bascik </PERSON>, 47, is to take the oath of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizenship Tuesday in a ceremony at the Statehouse in <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bascik </PERSON> created the Solidarity logo _ the word `` <ORGANIZATION> Solidarnosc </ORGANIZATION>'' in red with the white-and-red Polish flag flying from it _ in 1980, when the organization became the first legalized trade union in the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc. The next year <PERSON> Bascik </PERSON> visited <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, but while he was on his way home, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s Communist government imposed martial law. <PERSON> Bascik </PERSON> moved to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, then returned to <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>. When his mother, <PERSON> Cecylia </PERSON> <PERSON> Bascik </PERSON>, was allowed to immigrate, they settled in <LOCATION> Clintonville </LOCATION>, a suburb north of the city. Though he loves his homeland, <PERSON> Bascik </PERSON> said he is thrilled to become a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen. The day he takes the oath, <PERSON> Bascik </PERSON> said, `` I'm going out to dinner and wave the American flag.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 1235EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-ChinaEconomy Bjt   09-17 0374</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China Economy, Bjt,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>World Bank Traces Economic Fallout from Political Troubles in China</HEAD>
<HEAD>For release at 6:30 p.m. EDT - time set by source</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GENE KRAMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s violent crackdown on demonstrators for democracy is sharply cutting tourism and private investment and contributing to troubles that will keep the Chinese from matching last year's 11.2 percent economic growth rate, <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> officials say. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, the world's most populous country, will `` need to deal with the economic consequences of political problems this -LRB- past -RRB- summer,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>'s vice president for <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Attila </PERSON> <PERSON> Karaosmanoglu </PERSON>. `` These problems include a sharp downturn in tourism and a significant reduction in private investment,'' he told reporters at a briefing on the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>'s annual report released Sunday. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is enjoying a strong year in agriculture, `` which will reduce the need for food imports,'' but the growth rate can be expected to decline as Chinese leaders pursue measures to cool the economy and reduce inflation, <PERSON> Karaosmanoglu </PERSON> said. He declined to guess how far it would drop under 11.2 percent. For <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, `` the most difficult part of the reform process lies ahead,'' said the annual report. `` The stunning economic results of promoting private enterprise in agriculture and decentralizing decision-making in urban enterprises have brought with them more fundamental problems. ... `` While the rising tempo of economic activity has raised the living standards of the broad mass of population and served to keep alive grassroots support for <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s reform program,'' it said, `` such high rates of growth have clearly pushed the economy to the limits of its productive capacity.'' The <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> reduced its anticipated fiscal 1989 lending to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> by $ 780 million, to $ 1.3 billion, <PERSON> Karaosmanoglu </PERSON> said, because action by its board on seven projects `` was postponed last June following the events in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>.'' Postponement was ordered in consultation with <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> authorities, he said, adding that `` we hope we can return to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in the near future. ... We fully intend to keep the door open.'' But he said there is no timetable for reviving the postponed projects. World Bank programs in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> include development efforts in remote, deprived areas where, the report noted, `` an estimated 70 million people live in conditions of absolute poverty.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 1254EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Babylon     09-17 0641</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Babylon,0659</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rebuilt Babylon to Harken Back to Fabled Past</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SALAH HASRAWI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BABYLON, Iraq (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Songs written 6,000 years ago and deciphered from stone tablets will waft through this fabled city on Friday as <PERSON> Babylon </PERSON> relives the ancient days when it was the center of civilization. Tens of thousands of people are expected at the huge cultural extravaganza planned in Babylon, which is about 55 miles south of <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION>. The city was rebuilt by President <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> at a cost of about $ 100 million in an ambitious program to revive the splendors of the past and to build a tourist industry folowing the eight-year <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> war. For two weeks, <PERSON> Babylon </PERSON>'s reconstructed palaces and temples will echo with music, opera, dance and drama performed by troupes from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and 35 other countries. The focuses of the festival will be the 2,500-seat Greek amphitheater, built in the 4th Century B.C. by <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> the </PERSON> <PERSON> Great </PERSON>, who died in <LOCATION> Babylon </LOCATION>; and the crown hall in the Palace of <LOCATION> Nebuchadnezzar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> II </LOCATION>, who ruled in the 6th century B.C. `` Babylon was the center of the world's civilization, arts and culture and it is right that it regain that fame again,'' said <PERSON> Munir </PERSON> <PERSON> Bashir </PERSON>, chief director of the festival. The first festival was held here in 1987, when <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> were at war. Last year's festival was held just a month after the hostilities ceased under a U.N.-brokered truce. An estimated 100,000 people flocked to <PERSON> Babylon </PERSON> for last year's festival, which featured artists from 24 countries, including Brazilian guitarist <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Liva </PERSON> <PERSON> Sao </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, the American <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> <PERSON> Jazz </PERSON> <PERSON> Quartet </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ballet </LOCATION> and the Glamos Folk Group from <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> Only a handful of Europeans and Americans attended. But the Iraqis expect more this year. `` Now that the war's over, we expect many more people,'' <PERSON> Bashir </PERSON> said. A highlight, he said, will be an Iraqi troupe's presentation of songs, dance and music based on ancient Babylonian music. The ancient music was played primarily on harps, some of which have been found in the ruins of the city on the banks of the <LOCATION> Euphrates </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bashir </PERSON> and other Iraqi researchers spent months unraveling the notations on stone tablets to reproduce the primitive tunes, which will be performed in public for the first time in millenia. <PERSON> Bashir </PERSON>, 59, is director of music at the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Culture </ORGANIZATION> and is the world's most renowned virtuoso of the oud, an Arabic stringed instrument that was the forebear of the lute. The Iraqis claim that the ancient land known as <LOCATION> Mesopotamia </LOCATION>, or `` land between the rivers'' _ the <LOCATION> Euphrates </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tigris </LOCATION> _ was the `` cradle of civilization.'' It is also the reputed site of the Garden of Eden. The Babylonians ruled an empire that flourished as a cultural, religious and commercial center for hundreds of years. The legal and social codes they developed were the first to provide for individual and family rights and have influenced modern legal systems. Thousands of <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION>, Sudanese and Egyptian laborers have toiled in the blistering heat for the last few years to rebuild the 54,000-square foot Palace of <LOCATION> Nebuchadnezzar </LOCATION>, the Temples of <LOCATION> Nabashkhari </LOCATION> and Ninmakh, the Processional Way, <PERSON> Babylon </PERSON>'s main thoroughfare, and the Ishtar Gate, named after the Babylonians' main goddess. Officials said an estimated 15 million bricks, baked as they were in ancient times, were used to restore the city's monuments based on archaeological evidence, cuneiform texts and the description of historians of the day. In other attractions at the festival, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> will send an Azerbaijani dance troupe, the <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Trisslet </PERSON> dance troupe is coming from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The amphitheater this year has been equipped with state-of-the-art technology, including three-dimensional projectors, to transform the performances at the ancient site into what one official called `` a journey through time.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890917-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-89 1311EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-RefugeeCrisis Bjt   09-17 0758</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Refugee Crisis, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Plans to Admit 50,000 Soviets, Mostly Jews</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
