<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0004EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hugo-NavyIsland     11-09 0712</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hugo-Navy Island,0733</SECOND>
<HEAD>Island, Used for Naval Practice, Left Scarred by Hugo</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANA HAYWARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ESPERANZA BEACH, Puerto Rico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 On the hurricane-battered island of <LOCATION> Vieques </LOCATION>, a practice site for <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> bombing off <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, residents link their destiny to a century-old tamarind tree on a barren hill. `` If the tree survives, so will <LOCATION> Vieques </LOCATION>,'' said engineer <PERSON> Sixto </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> after a ceremony to replant the tree, which was uprooted by Hurricane Hugo on Sept. 18. `` It has been silent witness to our history,'' <PERSON> Nana </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Castano </PERSON>, a retired teacher, told schoolchildren gathered around the tree. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has been part of <LOCATION> Vieques </LOCATION>' history since World War II. It owns two-thirds of the island and uses it for practice bombings and maneuvers. In the 1970s, <LOCATION> Vieques </LOCATION> was rocked by violent anti-Navy protests. Similar demonstrations in 1975 drove the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> off its sister island, <LOCATION> Culebra </LOCATION>. Although the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> says relations have improved in recent years, many Viequenses, as the 8,000 residents are called, say Hurricane Hugo has made matters worse. <LOCATION> Vieques </LOCATION> was one of the areas hardest hit by the storm. <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> pounded <LOCATION> Vieques </LOCATION> for 12 hours with winds clocked at 140 to 200 mph, demolishing or damaging virtually all its 3,000 homes. Trees were either knocked downed or defoliated, leaving the once-verdant, sun-splashed island with little shade. `` It will take 10 years to recover,'' said <PERSON> Luiz </PERSON> <PERSON> Davila </PERSON>, manager of a <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> plant that makes electric switches and is the island's largest employer, with 132 workers. `` Now we are seeing the devastation,'' <PERSON> Davila </PERSON> added. `` In six months, a year, we will see the lack of income people will have.'' With their homes and possessions gone and their future livelihood in doubt, some residents despair. Officials say two people hanged themselves and several others attempted suicide after the storm. No one in <LOCATION> Vieques </LOCATION> died in the hurricane itself. `` There is lot of depression, a lot of suicide attempts,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Eva </PERSON> <PERSON> Almodovar </PERSON>, who is in charge of the emergency room at the <LOCATION> Vieques </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>. `` It's people who have lost everything. ... They do n't see a way out.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> is helping rebuild roads and restore power and water. The day after the hurricane, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> put up a roadblock to prevent squatters from returning to a disputed area where they had set up shacks and burned two <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> vehicles in April. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Ravin </PERSON>, a high school history teacher, charged that the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> acted `` like thieves in the night,'' taking advantage of the hurricane crisis. But a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, Lt. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyle </PERSON>, said the roadblock was put up because the squatters were `` unauthorized people on <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> property. The shacks had been blown down and were completely demolished.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> bought <LOCATION> Vieques </LOCATION> land for training during World War II, resettling residents in the center of the island, which is 20 miles long and six miles across. Most of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> property is unused and hundreds of squatters have moved in over the past year. Rear Adm. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Moriarty </PERSON>, commander of <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> naval forces, said relations with <LOCATION> Vieques </LOCATION> residents have been `` very, very good.'' But squatter organizer <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Figueroa </PERSON>, a carpenter who says his movement is `` rescuing land,'' believes the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> `` has a master plan'' to stifle development to keep the island to itself. Many Viequenses complain that the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s presence has kept the island underdeveloped, underpopulated and poverty-stricken. <LOCATION> Vieques </LOCATION> has a severe housing shortage, an unemployment rate of 70 percent, and an annual per capita income of $ 5,281, as opposed to the <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> average of $ 8,721. The majority of the islanders are on welfare. Although its unspoiled beauty has made it the location for several movies, most recently `` Heartbreak Ridge,'' with <PERSON> Clint </PERSON> <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON> about the 1983 U.S.-led invasion of <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vieques </LOCATION> has seen little tourism. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> occupies two-thirds of the island and this prevents it from developing to its plenitude because they own the best beaches, the best land,'' said Mayor <PERSON> Manuela </PERSON> <PERSON> Santiago </PERSON> <PERSON> Collazo </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Vieques </LOCATION> has been losing population for years, and is expected to lose 2,000 of its 8,000 inhabitants by the year 2000. `` A young <PERSON> Viequense </PERSON> who becomes an engineer, a doctor or a lawyer ca n't come back because there is nothing to do here,'' said <PERSON> Figueroa </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0019EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Proposition103     11-09 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Proposition 103,0710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Year Later Insurance Rates Still Not Slashed</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN ANTCZAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first anniversary of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> voters' approval of Proposition 103 passed with citizens still waiting for insurance rates to be slashed Its author claims that while victory has been delayed, it has not been denied. `` What's at stake here is democracy and who's in charge,'' the initiative's author, <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenfield </PERSON>, told a press conference Wednesday at the headquarters of the Voter Revolt organization. The proposition, which has the force of law, called for 20 percent rollbacks from 1987 auto insurance rates. It also said that geography should be less important to setting rates than drivers' records and experience and made the office of insurance commissioner an elected position The major insurance companies, however, have not rolled back their rates in the wake of a court battle over the referendum. An estimated 700 companies were affected. They also have not begun judging rates according to driving records. The insurance commissioner, at least, becomes an elected position in the November 1990 election. On the anniversary day, <PERSON> Rosenfield </PERSON> and <PERSON> Conway </PERSON> <PERSON> Collis </PERSON>, an elected state tax official who also is a candidate for the 1990 race for insurance commissioner, stood behind boxes marked `` $ 1,000 s'' symbolizing the 20 percent rollbacks still in insurers' coffers They said Prop. 103's promises would soon be realized if supporters keep faith. `` It's fair to say that for the first time we can see light at the end of the tunnel,'' <PERSON> Rosenfield </PERSON> said. But they acknowledged frustration, and <PERSON> Rosenfield </PERSON> fired salvos at state Insurance Commissioner <PERSON> Roxani </PERSON> <PERSON> Gillespie </PERSON>. `` We are as frustrated as anybody else is,'' <PERSON> Rosenfield </PERSON> said. `` It is an absolute outrage that we are basically 11 months behind schedule in the provisions of 103 that were supposed to go into effect on election day.'' Voters approved Prop. 103 on Nov. 8, 1988, on a vote of 4.8 million to 4.6 million. The next day insurers filed numerous lawsuits against it and a day later the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> suspended implementation for a review. By December, the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> had lifted the stay on implementing most of the measure except for the 20-percent rollbacks. To add insult to injury, the largest seller of auto insurance in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION>, announced in January that it was raising rates an average of 9.6 percent. Prop. 103 was upheld by the high court in May, but the court said the commissioner should exempt a company from rollbacks if it would not receive what the court called a fair and reasonable rate of return. In early August the commissioner set the fair rate of return at 11.2 percent annually. By the end of August that figure had been characterized as tentative and could be revised upward. In the meantime, more than 400 insurance companies had filed for exemption from rollbacks and the commissioner said three of the state's largest insurance sellers were among hundreds likely to win exemptions. During summer hearings, insurance companies also told <PERSON> Gillespie </PERSON> she should continue to allow territorial rating systems in which prices are set according to neighborhood. As more rate hikes were announced and confusion over the status of Prop. 103 mounted, <PERSON> Gillespie </PERSON> on Oct. 2 ordered rate increases frozen for six months and said all issues would be taken up at hearings. <PERSON> Collis </PERSON> sought to put the best face on the developments. `` It's really important for people to realize on this anniversary of 103 that rollbacks have been delayed, the move away from territorial rating system has been delayed but it's now in the process and if we hang together awhile longer it's now going to happen,'' <PERSON> Collis </PERSON> said. The insurance companies want people to become apathetic about Prop. 103, <PERSON> Rosenfield </PERSON> claimed. `` If you talk to the insurance companies they gloat about the fact that 71 percent of the people have said they do n't ever think that they ever have forced the insurance companies to give us those rollbacks,'' he said. Asked if he would have done anything differently, <PERSON> Rosenfield </PERSON> said he should have incorporated criminal penalties into the law.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0023EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Hepburn's80th     11-09 0731</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hepburn's 80th,0750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eight Decades for Kate the Great</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOLORES BARCLAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Arts Editors</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Life is a thief,'' <PERSON> Katharine </PERSON> <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> tells <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> <PERSON> Clift </PERSON> in `` Suddenly, Last Summer.'' But life knew better than to steal from <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> the Great. The voice <PERSON> Tallulah </PERSON> <PERSON> Bankhead </PERSON> once likened to `` nickels dropping in a slot machine'' has grown tremulous with age. But nothing can daunt that special <ORGANIZATION> Yankee </ORGANIZATION> strength that has seen 80 autumns. <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> remains arrogant, bossy and tenacious, principled, passionate and clever. Her viperish wit slices and dices. No, do n't mess with <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> `` I think I'm very irritating to some people,'' she once said. `` It fascinates me, though, because I'm so sweet really.'' <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> celebrated her 80th birthday Wednesday not quietly at home as some her age would have it, but dashing about <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, visiting ill friends. `` She's being a good Samaritan,'' her secretary, <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Powers </PERSON>, said. `` Who cares about my birthday?'' the actress said recently. `` I do n't, as long as I can get around and think straight.'' And she does think, about many things. She frets about the backyard garden of her <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> brownstone, rails at youthful sex, supports abortion and champions euthanasia for the elderly. If it exists, <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> has something to say about it. `` I think there's sort of a terrible fear of death in this country, and I just do n't think you should fear something that is absolutely inevitable,'' she said in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. `` I've been extremely lucky. I've got money and I can decide to work or not work. I've been terribly lucky all my life.'' <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> had a scare when a growth was discovered last year on her vocal cords. A biopsy showed it was not cancerous, and she recovered nicely from surgery. From the day RKO studio bosses first spotted her on the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> stage in an abbreviated tunic playing an <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> queen in `` The Warrior's Husband,'' <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> has enchanted and seduced a moviegoing public. Her first movie, `` A Bill of Divorcement,'' with <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrymore </PERSON>, was a success. Her next was a dud. The third, the stagey 1933 production `` Morning Glory,'' won her first Academy Award; three others came in 1967, 1968 and 1981 for `` Guess Who's Coming to Dinner,'' `` The Lion in Winter'' and `` On Golden Pond.'' But after `` Morning Glory,'' <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> made several flops that turned her into box-office poison. `` The <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> Story'' in 1940 marked her resurrection from <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>'s graveyard with her champagney portrayal of a spoiled rich girl who marries and remarries the man she loves. Playwright <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> wrote it for her and the play was a smash on <LOCATION> Broadway </LOCATION>. `` I bought the movie rights. They wanted to buy it for all my rivals, but I already owned it. Very clever,'' she said. `` Then I stayed at <ORGANIZATION> Metro </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- MGM -RRB- and did all those pictures with <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON>. I've done things for the honest reason that I like them. You ca n't do things just to be successful. You have to do things that affect you.'' <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> was <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON>'s closest friend for 27 years. She was linked romantically with billionaire industrialist <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> and producer <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayward </PERSON>, and was married once _ in 1928 to <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> socialite <PERSON> Ludlow </PERSON> <PERSON> Ogden </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. They divorced in 1934. <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> inherited her Yankee tenacity from her parents. Her father, Dr. <PERSON> Norval </PERSON> <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON>, was a urologist who campaigned for public awareness about venereal disease. Her mother, <PERSON> Katharine </PERSON> <PERSON> Houghton </PERSON>, was a suffragist and a crusader in the birth control movement. Their tenacity, she said, freed her from fear. `` I was n't afraid to pay the price of saying what I thought. I was n't cautious.'' At <ORGANIZATION> Bryn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mawr </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> with its high academic standards and mannered students, she survived on her wits. She almost flunked out but buckled down to work so she could act in school plays. After graduating, she plunged into stock and finally landed a bit role in a Broadway flop. Lately, she's done some television work, including last year's `` <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Lansing </PERSON> Slept Here. But mostly, she putters about in her garden, visits friends, spends time in her home on the <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> shore and looks for the right movie projects. `` It's terribly difficult to find interesting roles,'' she once said. `` And a poor old thing dying in a rest home is not a terribly interesting picture. I think it's just depressing.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0007EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SouthernStorms 1stLd-Writethru a0875 11-09 0706</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Southern Storms, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0875,0725</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tornadoes Hit Georgia, Alabama; Louisiana Recovers From Flooding</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 4 grafs to UPDATE with tornado hitting Georgia, child
killed. Picks up 2nd graf pvs, `In Louisiana...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NU1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Tornadoes and torrential rains hit <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> on Wednesday, killing a 3-year-old boy, damaging dozens of buildings and tossing a mobile home with a woman inside into a fish pond. She suffered slight injuries. In <LOCATION> Pineview </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, three houses and at least two mobile homes were damaged when the tornado hit about 5:45 p.m., <PERSON> Wilcox </PERSON> Deputy Sheriff <PERSON> Stacy </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. One of the mobile homes, the home of the 3-year-old, was demolished, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. Five other people were injured, including the child's father, <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> West </PERSON>. West suffered an apparent broken neck and was undergoing tests at the <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Macon </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> did not know the child's name. In <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans-area </LOCATION> residents cleaned up flooded homes as rain kept falling in the southeastern part of the state. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said the latest storm was not expected to cause floods like Tuesday's, when hundreds of homes were swamped and a 2-year-old boy drowned after being swept into a drainage canal in <LOCATION> Jefferson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Parish </LOCATION>. Wednesday's rain knocked out power to about 600 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> homes and businesses, far fewer than the 11,000 affected the previous day, said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Tregre </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Entergy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. In <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, the morning twisters caused damage only in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> and a mile-long stretch <LOCATION> Dothan </LOCATION> in the state's southeast corner, but streets were flooded from Mobile in the west and much of southern <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, officials said. No other injuries were reported. Two or three tornadoes destroyed three homes and a restaurant, damaged six businesses and did minor damage to about 40 homes in the <LOCATION> Dothan </LOCATION> area, <ORGANIZATION> Dothan-Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> officials said. The restaurant's roof and walls blew across the street into a tire store's parking lot, damaging dozens of cars. `` We've found some roofs that were taken seven blocks away and dropped,'' said emergency agency Assistant Director <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>. At <ORGANIZATION> Wallace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Dothan </LOCATION>, about 2,000 panicky students were ordered to remain inside a building for more than an hour as flood waters inundated the campus because tornado warnings were in effect, said school spokeswoman <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Alford </PERSON>. `` We had some cars floating in the parking lot,'' said <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, secretary to the president at the school. Classes were called off for the day. <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> public schools were also closed. In <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> about 40 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Dothan </LOCATION>, a tornado tossed Mrs. E.C. <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON>' mobile home into a pond with her inside, said a <LOCATION> Samson </LOCATION> police dispatcher who refused to give his name. `` They had to go out in a boat to get her,'' the dispatcher said. Mrs. <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON>, 54, suffered cuts and was hospitalized for observation, he said. In <LOCATION> Malvern </LOCATION> about 10 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Dothan </LOCATION>, thunderstorm winds damaged a house trailer and peanut wagons. Nearly 10 inches of rain fell in <LOCATION> Florala </LOCATION>, 7 inches in <LOCATION> Dothan </LOCATION> and 5.6 inches in Mobile by mid-afternoon, the weather service said. The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> area received up to 1.75 inches of rain by noon, far less than Tuesday. Between 6 p.m. Monday and 3 p.m. Tuesday, a deluge of 12.5 inches fell at <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airport </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Kenner </LOCATION>, the weather service said. By Wednesday, flood waters had receded nearly everywhere, except for a 1,000-house subdivision in <LOCATION> Destrehan </LOCATION> nearly 15 miles west of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. Officials did not know how many buildings in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> and the surrounding <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Charles </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON>, and St. <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> parishes were flooded or how much damage was done. `` It happened so quick and it caught everybody off-guard. We have n't calculated any hard figures,'' said Capt. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Zinna </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Charles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>. Public and <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> schools were closed Wednesday in <LOCATION> Jefferson </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Charles </LOCATION> parishes. Public schools were open in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernard </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Parish </LOCATION>, but Catholic schools were closed. Some residents were able to get back to their homes and start cleaning up. `` I'm still here mopping up water,'' said <PERSON> Alberta </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> of </PERSON> <PERSON> Kenner </PERSON>, who said she had about 2 feet of water in the house Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0026EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-FrenchWine     11-09 0675</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-French Wine,0696</SECOND>
<HEAD>Early Signs Suggest 1989 Was a Very Good Year</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUZY PATTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An exceptional harvest in vineyards across <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> has wine growers and wine lovers happily anticipating their first tastings of this year's vintage. There's even talk, perhaps overexcited, that 1989 could produce some of the best wines of the century. The enthusiasm stems from near-perfect growing conditions: a hot, dry summer that meant drought for other farmers, followed by an early harvest free from rain. `` We've got sun in the vats,'' said <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Vigier </PERSON>, a producer of Chateau Reve d'Or, a <LOCATION> Bordeaux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pomerol </LOCATION>, and winner of the Concours Agricole wine competition. `` The quality is very high.'' Hopes are high from <LOCATION> Alsace </LOCATION> in the northeast to <LOCATION> Bordeaux </LOCATION> in the southwest, and in all the winegrowing regions in between. `` It's a good year all over <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> Amare </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Maison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> la </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vigne </ORGANIZATION> et du Vin. Besides the high quality, production is up in quantity by 5 percent over last year, he said. <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON> <PERSON> le </PERSON> <PERSON> Flaive </PERSON>, a grower of Puligny-Montrachet and a wine dealer for the Cote d'Or, said the 1989 Burgundy whites will be the best in a decade. `` They are of very, very good quality, at least equal to the good wines of 1978, the acidity is minimal but acceptable. I'd grade the whites 19 out of a perfect 20,'' he said, adding that the region also will have some exceptional red wines But there are reservations as well among wine experts and producers, many of whom are withholding praise until the first corks are popped. `` It may be the year of the decade, because growers and the media want it to be,'' said <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spurrier </PERSON>, the founder of l'Academie du <PERSON> Vin </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and one of the best-known wine connoisseurs in the city. <PERSON> Spurrier </PERSON> said he would wait to see if overripe grapes produce `` a flabby, over-rich product.'' <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, co-owner of <PERSON> Willi </PERSON>'s Wine Bar and Juveniles in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, said: `` It was a great year, but people who are hyping the harvest have n't understood the problems of drought. Some of the whites, for example, are lacking freshness and acidity.'' <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Hone </PERSON> of <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Serbet </PERSON>, a wine brokerage firm in <LOCATION> Burgundy </LOCATION>, said the white wines from his region have finesse `` with good intensity of taste.'' `` But these wines may not be as rich and lush as 1986, nor as alcoholic as 1985. For now, the white Burgundies still have a milky quality like grapefruit juice,'' Hone said. `` It's a good year, but too early to say if it's great.'' Hone said <PERSON> Burgundy </PERSON> suffered hailstorms and frost in June and that `` quality varied according to vineyards up and down the Cote d'Or.'' There will be plenty of vintage Champagne as producers there bubble with enthusiasm for a crop that produced 10 percent more wine than usual. `` We've had an exceptional year,'' said <PERSON> Philippe </PERSON> <PERSON> Coulon </PERSON>, director of oenology at <ORGANIZATION> Moet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> et </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chandon </ORGANIZATION>. `` The condition of the grapes was perfect; they reached the ideal maturity, were perfectly healthy, giving a balanced product. `` For the final verdict, we have to await February and March, but we're predicting a ` millesime' or vintage year,'' <PERSON> Coulon </PERSON> said. The year's wines may be memorable for their abundance and flavor, but they also will be remembered for being more expensive than ever before. Champaign prices are fixed at 13 percent higher than last year. Some blame rising labor costs or the expense of improved vinification. Often it simply is a question of supply not meeting demand. And sometimes public relations campaigns have as much influence as producers in how a wine is priced. Wines from regions that are `` hyped'' bring as much as the market will bear. `` A lot of speculators in <LOCATION> Bordeaux </LOCATION> buy it up even before the secondary fermentation is finished,'' said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON> of <PERSON> Willi </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Wine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION>, adding that it is too early to judge the 1989 <LOCATION> Bordeaux </LOCATION>. Nevertheless, he said, `` Thanks to this year's hype, the price will probably rise.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0029EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Secord-Chronology     11-09 0306</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Secord-Chronology,0315</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Secord Plea</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a chronology of retired <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>'s involvement in the Iran-Contra affair: 1983: <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> leaves the government under a cloud concerning his ties to <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> agent convicted in 1983 of illegally shipping munitions to <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> and plotting to kill an opponent of <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON>. 1984: <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>, an expert in handling covert operations, begins selling arms to the Contras at the request of White House aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>. North says he got <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>'s name from <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> about the time <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to the Contras was running out and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> was barring the intelligence agency from supplying the rebels with military aid. Late 1985: North brings <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> into the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's secret arms initiative with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> October-November 1986: One of the North network's planes is shot down over <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and the administration's arms sales to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> are exposed. Also uncovered is the diversion of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> arms sale money to the Contras through the complex of secret accounts operated by <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> and his business partner <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON>. May 1987: <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> is the first witness in the congressional Iran-Contra hearings. In four days of testimony, he says that: _ He assumed President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> knew of his activities _ He forswore profits in the Iran-Contra operation, never getting any money besides his $ 6,000-a-month salary March 16, 1988: <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>, <PERSON> North </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> and former National Security Adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> are indicted following a criminal investigation by independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>. A federal judge ultimately decides the defendants must be tried separately, and <PERSON> North </PERSON> later is convicted on three counts. Nov. 8, 1989: <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> pleads guilty to a single felony, concerning lying to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> about financial help he gave <PERSON> North </PERSON>, five days before his trial is to begin on 12 criminal charges.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0259EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Pepper'sGlasses     11-09 0128</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Pepper's Glasses,0131</SECOND>
<HEAD>Glasses Stolen From Statue of Late Congressman</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Someone stole the five-pound bronze wire-framed glasses from a statue of the late Rep. <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON>. The frames were soldered to the 9-foot statue's nose and ears. Sculptor <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> said he has a way to foil any similar thefts on his likeness of the venerable <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Democrat, who died in May. `` I'm going to make him contact lenses.'' Kidding aside, <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> said he plans to attach the next pair of glasses _ at a cost of $ 100 to $ 300 _ with screws imbedded in the figure. The theft from the statue in <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Marti </PERSON> <PERSON> Park </PERSON> was discovered Monday by <PERSON> Lazaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Albo </PERSON>, who headed the drive that raised $ 60,000 to pay for the monument.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-TerrorizedElections 1stLd-Writethru b0295 11-09 0772</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Terrorized Elections, 1st Ld - Writethru, b0295,0790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Peru's Shining Path Guerrillas Disrupting Local Elections</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: CORRECTS typo in lead of b0295 sent Nov. 2 for use today. Sunday
in first graf is Nov. 12.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto LIM1 sent Nov 2.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MONTE HAYES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANDAJES, Peru (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Although high in the Andes and far from anything else, this village of communal farmers has not escaped a Maoist guerrillas' terror campaign to disrupt nationwide municipal elections Sunday _ and in the long run the presidential election next year. A column of 30 guerrillas of the Sendero Luminoso -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Shining </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Path </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- movement entered Andajes one stormy night and seized Mayor <PERSON> Heraclio </PERSON> <PERSON> Segundo </PERSON>, four other local officials and a sixth man they accused of cattle rustling. They then dragged them into the village plaza, where they killed them with single gunshots to the back of the neck. As a result, no candidates are running for office Sunday in <LOCATION> Andajes </LOCATION>. `` All that people think about is that they will come back, that there will be more killings,'' said <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Zuniga </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernabe </PERSON>, a young farmer. The wave of assassinations of mayors and other local officials in <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> has reached levels unprecedented in the Shining Path's 9-year-old insurgency Latest available figures show that 263 mayors' posts around <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> are unfilled, nearly all of them in small towns and villages with little or no police protection. In <LOCATION> Junin </LOCATION> department, in the country's mining and farming heartland 150 miles east of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>, only 61 of 122 municipalities have mayors. Some 4,500 candidates registered to run in the nation's nearly 2,000 mayoralty races, but an estimated 400 have resigned in fear, and government officials expect many more to withdraw before election day. So far this year the rebels have slain 45 mayors. They also have killed 73 local judges, clerks, councilmen and municipal candidates. In October, 22 local authorities were slain. A total of 330 people died in armed clashes and political violence, one of the highest monthly tolls since the <ORGANIZATION> Shining </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Path </ORGANIZATION> launched its insurgency to topple <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>'s elected government. Shining Path seeks to install a workers' and peasants' state patterned on the ideas of the late Chairman <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse-tung </PERSON> of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. Political analysts and counterinsurgency experts agree that the rebels' campaign to disrupt the municipal elections is only the first stage of their strategy to block the presidential election in April and provoke a military coup. Shining Path's strategy then most likely would be to place itself in the vanguard of a popular front against a military dictatorship. Publicly, the populist government of President <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> has guaranteed that municipal elections will take place throughout <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>. But privately a close <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> aide, speaking in <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> on condition he not be identified, said, `` The truth is we are not in a position to guarantee the normal course of elections. I wonder how many people are going to be able to vote.'' He said <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> would need 300,000 policemen, not the 75,000 it has, to provide around-the-clock protection to current authorities and all municipal candidates. National election board officials are focusing their efforts on guaranteeing that voting takes place in a normal fashion in <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> and other major cities, where most of <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>'s population of 21 million is concentrated. A third of the national territory is under states of emergency that suspend constitutional guarantees and give the military broad powers to fight guerrillas. It is in those areas that the elections are most in doubt, but many critics of government policy say the contested regions can not be written off if <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> is going to defend its democratic system. Here in <LOCATION> Andajes </LOCATION>, situated on the dome of an 11,000-foot mountain, people feel the government has knowingly let them pass into the Shining Path's domain. Andajes is only 90 miles north of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> in a straight line, but a six-hour ride over bumpy roads that rise from the mist-shrouded desert coast and climb the empty western slopes of the Andes. With its 2,000 inhabitants, its narrow cobblestone lanes and its mud-brick houses, Andajes never received much attention in <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>. But now the villagers feel totally abandoned. `` The people live with the fear that <PERSON> Sendero </PERSON> will return,'' said village elder <PERSON> Ruben </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>. The 16-man police detachment sent to Andajes after its officials were killed withdrew in June to the town of <LOCATION> Churin </LOCATION>, an hour's drive away at the foot of the mountain. `` Most people did not sleep that first night,'' said <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jiron </PERSON>, a government health worker assigned to <PERSON> Andajes </PERSON>. `` They gathered in small groups and waited for daybreak. They began to realize they would have to accept being alone again.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RadioactiveLeak 2ndLd-Writethru a0401 11-09 0370</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Radioactive Leak, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0401,0380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Radioactive Material Leaks at Ohio Nuclear Plant</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 6th graf, `Neff said...,' with 3 grafs to UPDATE with officials
downgrading estimated amount of tritium exposure, EPA standards. Picks
up 7th graf pvs, `The plant...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES HANNAH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMISBURG, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An accident at a government-owned nuclear production plant triggered a release of radioactive hydrogen Wednesday, contaminating four workers and sending the gas into the atmosphere. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Neff </PERSON>, manager of environmental health and safety at the Mound Nuclear Production Plant, called the release of tritium minor but said it was the largest such release at the southwestern <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> plant since the 1960s. He said it was 10 times what is normally released at the plant each year. `` It's a relatively small release,'' <PERSON> Neff </PERSON> said at a news conference. `` We do n't believe we had a significant amount that went up.'' The tritium was vented into an exhaust stack and released into the air, taking a projected northwesterly path. <LOCATION> Miamisburg </LOCATION> is about 10 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>. Plant officials initially estimated that in the worst-case scenario, a few dozen residents may have been exposed to 12 millirems of tritium, the equivalent of one chest X-ray. However, plant spokesman <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Charbeneau </PERSON> later said an investigation revealed that the maximum off-site dosage was 0.051 millirems. He said a person flying in a plane across the country would be exposed to 3 millirems. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>'s standard of safe dosage is 25 millirems a year. The plant produces detonators for nuclear weapons and propulsion systems for spacecraft. The accident occurred when a quartz window in a bell jar containing tritium shattered. Workers were evacuated from the building. <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, manager of tritium technology and surveillance, said 52 workers were in the area when the accident occurred. He said six of them had contamination on their clothing. Of those six, four were found to have tritium in their system. <PERSON> Neff </PERSON> said half the tritium will pass through a person's body in 12 days. `` It's relatively low-risk, compared to most radioactive material,'' he said. About 2,200 workers are employed at the plant, operated by <ORGANIZATION> EG </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; G Mound Applied Technologies for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0100EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Conway     11-09 0199</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Conway,0206</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Dorf' Goes to Court Over `Dorf Goes Auto Racing'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dorf </PERSON>, a loveable buffoon played by comedian <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Conway </PERSON>, has played golf, witnessed the first Olympic Games, and gone auto racing. Now, <PERSON> Dorf </PERSON> is going to court. A production company is suing <PERSON> Conway </PERSON>, who plays the 4-foot-tall <PERSON> Derk </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorf </PERSON> character on videos, over the distribution of the tape `` <PERSON> Dorf </PERSON> Goes Auto Racing.'' <ORGANIZATION> J2 </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which claims to have the distribution rights, alleges in a <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> lawsuit filed Wednesday that <PERSON> Conway </PERSON> wrongly intends to sell `` <ORGANIZATION> Dorf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Goes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Racing </ORGANIZATION>'' through another company. J2 Communications seeks unspecified damages on allegations including breach of contract, breach of good faith and fraud. The <PERSON> Dorf </PERSON> character was introduced in a J2-produced and distributed video called `` Dorf on Golf,'' starring <PERSON> Conway </PERSON>'s diminutive alter-ego accompanied by a statuesque female assistant named `` Boom Boom. The video has sold more than 200,000 copies, making it one of the seven most popular videos of all time, the lawsuit says. Other <PERSON> Dorf </PERSON> videos include `` <PERSON> Dorf </PERSON> and the First Games of Mt. Olympus'' and `` <PERSON> Dorf </PERSON>'s Golf Bible.'' <PERSON> Conway </PERSON>'s telephone number was not listed, so the entertainer could not immediately be reached for comment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HorseDeaths 1stLd-Writethru a0718 11-09 0369</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Horse Deaths, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0718,0376</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hay Cubes Tainted With Rabbit Parts Kill Horses</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 8 grafs to UPDATE with investigators identifying
botulism, edit to conform. Picks up 10th graf pvs, `Feed stores...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hay tainted with parts of rabbits caught in harvesting machinery caused the deaths of at least 15 horses in <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, according to veterinarians. Veterinarians investigating the deaths say the rabbits may have been caught in machinery at a farm in <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, then shredded and pressed into cubes of hay at a processing plant in suburban Paramount. Toxin secreted by the parts produced a rare strain of botulism known as Clostridium Botulinum, type C, Dr. <PERSON> Hailu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kinde </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterinary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diagnostic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> told a news conference at the <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fairgrounds </LOCATION>. The strain, common in aquatic birds, mink, dogs and cats, last affected horses 10 years ago in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Kinde </PERSON> said. The laboratory at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, made the discovery this week while testing hay cubes that were part of a batch consumed by the affected horses, he said. Seven horses died at the <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fairgrounds </LOCATION> equestrian center, three at a Chino stable, two at the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Equestrian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, and veterinarians reported three other cases. In at least 11 of the cases, the horses were fed cubes from Paramount Cubing, investigators said. Nine of 260 horses boarded at stables in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> fairgrounds in <LOCATION> Pomona </LOCATION> have displayed the symptoms since Oct. 28, said trainer <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mayfield </PERSON>. Veterinarians in <LOCATION> Alhambra </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ventura </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> have reported similar illnesses. <PERSON> Darrell </PERSON> <PERSON> Hofmeyer </PERSON>, owner of <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cubing </ORGANIZATION>, said the company had been told by its attorney not to discuss the matter right away. Feed stores said the sale of hay cubes has fallen sharply in recent days as word about the possibility of the cubes being tainted spread. `` I have n't sold any cubes or pellets in several days,'' said <PERSON> Regina </PERSON> <PERSON> Culbertson </PERSON> of the Feed Barn in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mesa </LOCATION>. `` I really got a run of -LRB- baled -RRB- alfalfa on Saturday. Everything is gone.'' Symptoms include quivering legs, low temperature and dull eyes. The animals collapse from weakness and breathing difficulties and usually die or must be destroyed within days.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-HowRichisRich?     11-09 0139</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-How Rich is Rich?,0140</SECOND>
<HEAD>Koreans Say Rich Means Having $1.5 Million</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 How much money makes you rich? A majority of Koreans, or 60.8 percent, said in a survey released today that a person can be considered rich if they have $ 750,000 to $ 1.5 million. A majority also said they could be millionaires too, if they tried hard enough. In the poll conducted by the <ORGANIZATION> Korea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Applied </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, 51.5 percent replied, `` I also can be rich.'' Almost 75 percent of the respondents felt that wealthy Koreans had accumulated wealth through dishonest means, such as illegal investments, political ties or exploitation of workers, the institute said. The survey was a random sampling of 1,514 people conducted in September in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> among people aged 20 to 50. No margin of error was given.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0154EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TumbleweedInvasion     11-09 0438</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tumbleweed Invasion,0453</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tumbleweeds Bury Houses in South Dakota Town</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: `Oahe' in 3rd graf is cq.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOBRIDGE, S.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tumbleweeds tossed by 50-mph winds buried houses in this <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> town, and residents struggled to dig out of the prickly problem. The mayor warned residents who had tumbleweeds up to their chimneys to clear them to reduce the danger of fire. The weeds had grown thick all summer along the banks of the drought-shrunken <ORGANIZATION> Oahe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reservoir </ORGANIZATION> in north-central <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>. Winds out of the west Tuesday evening sent the weeds rolling across the prairie. `` People in the west end of town as they were sitting in their homes ... heard what sounded like rocks being thrown against their houses,'' <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Atkinson </PERSON>, publisher of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mobridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>, said Wednesday. `` They came out this morning to find out that a number of houses were buried, literally buried, with tumbleweeds. We had some homes with only the roof sticking out. `` We had people that could not get out of their driveways,'' <PERSON> Atkinson </PERSON> said. `` We had streets that were blocked, literally invaded by tumbleweeds.'' Mayor <PERSON> Darrell </PERSON> <PERSON> Bender </PERSON> urged residents to help clean up the mess. City crews cleared the brush from the streets so vehicles could pass. The cleanup was continuing today. `` It's developing into what could be a very dangerous situation,'' <PERSON> Bender </PERSON> said. `` We need to use extreme caution. I'd like to tell people not to drive through those tumbleweeds Those that have homes that are covered up to their chimneys, get those weeds cleared so they do n't start a fire.'' <PERSON> Bender </PERSON> said he had asked the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION>, which manages the reservoir system, to help in the cleanup. `` I personally feel they have a responsibility for those weeds,'' he said. `` They have done nothing to control the weeds. They're 6 feet tall down there. We're going to have this problem every time we have a west wind. I had advised them previously that they had large weeds down there, and I was worried about what was going to happen.'' Phone calls by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> to the corps went unanswered late Wednesday. <PERSON> Atkinson </PERSON> said removing the tumbleweeds will be difficult. `` Nobody knows for sure what to do with them,'' he said. `` You ca n't crush them. All you can really do is move them around.'' He said the corps planned to conduct a controlled burn to remove some of the remaining weeds. `` It was the strangest thing I've ever seen,'' <PERSON> Atkinson </PERSON> said. `` We've been buried with snow before up in this area, but this is the first time anybody can remember being buried with tumbleweeds.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0203EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-BlackOfficials     11-09 0652</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Black Officials,0669</SECOND>
<HEAD>Black Officeholders Stretch Back Over a Century</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOLORES BARCLAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>'s apparent victory in the <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> governor's race is a watershed in <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> political history, in which black politicians have had but a shadowy presence <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> would be the nation's first elected black governor, but would not be the first black American to serve as governor. That distinction belongs to <PERSON> Pinckney </PERSON> <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON>, who became governor of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> following the impeachment of <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> <PERSON> Warmoth </PERSON> in 1872. He served for 43 days until the newly elected <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Pitt </PERSON> <PERSON> Kellogg </PERSON> was sworn in. Although any number of candidates could have been drawn from the small, black middle class that had existed in the nation since its founding, a black was not elected to office until 1855, when <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mercer </PERSON> <PERSON> Langston </PERSON> was elected clerk of <LOCATION> Brownhelm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Lorain </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. The first blacks ever elected to a legislative body were <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, son of abolitionist <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, who won seats in the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION> in 1866. Most of the nation's first black elected officials won their positions during Reconstruction _ the post-Civil War period in which Southern states were reorganized so they could rejoin the Union. Blacks were allowed to vote for the first time and seek elected office. It was a time when <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wood </PERSON> became mayor of <LOCATION> Natchez </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rainey </PERSON> of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> became the first black in the House of Representatives. <PERSON> Hiram </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Revels </PERSON>, a minister, succeeded <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> senator from <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> on Feb. 25, 1870, thus becoming first black in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. But <PERSON> Blanche </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON>, also from <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, was the first black to serve a full term in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON>, the son of a <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> planter and a black woman, had been a captain in the <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. Following the Civil War, he settled in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and joined the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which largely consisted of newly franchised blacks and sympathetic and liberal whites. A shrewd and ambitious man, he was elected to the state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1868 and was named president pro tempore. When <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, a former slave and the nation's first black lieutenant governor, died, <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON> moved to the No. 2 spot through constitutional succession. There were other black lieutenant governors during Reconstruction in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. But none was ever elected governor. <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, too, served as a lieutenant governor in a Southern state. But in <LOCATION> Virigina </LOCATION> at the end of the 20th century, he is part of the political mainstream. <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON> was something of a pariah. Even as an elected official, he and his family faced racism. His children had to be escorted to high school to protect them from mobs of bigoted white youths. And because of his elegance, intelligence and ambition, white politicians considered him dangerous. His attempt to run for governor was thwarted because whites controlled the election machinery and blacks were divided. He instead ran for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION> and was elected. He also ran for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and was elected in 1873. But after three years of debate, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> refused to seat him. `` I demand simple justice,'' <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. `` I do not care so far as I am personally concerned whether you give me my seat or not. I will go back to my people and come here again; but I tell you to preserve your own consistency. Do not make fish of me while you make flesh of everybody else.'' <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON>'s case drew attention from the national press. Said the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Commercial Advertiser: `` Pinchback's presence in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is not open to the smallest objection, except the old Bourbon war-whoops of color. `` Mr. <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON> is the best dressed Southern man we have had in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> from the South since the days when gentlemen were Democrats.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0151EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MinimumWage Bjt   11-09 0642</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Minimum Wage, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Minimum Wage Increase Clears Congress; Bush to Sign</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX10</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Only President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s promised signature is needed for the first minimum wage increase in nearly a decade, following <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' lopsided approval of a bill raising the rate to $ 4.25 by April 1991. The measure _ which includes a subminimum wage for teen-agers new to the job market _ cleared the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on an 89-8 vote Wednesday, exactly a week after it passed the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> by an equally overwhelming vote of 382-37. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who struck the compromise plan with congressional Democrats last week, is expected to sign the bill before Thanksgiving, perhaps as early as next week. `` The nine-year logjam on the minimum wage is finally broken,'' Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., said after the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> vote `` The working poor are about to receive an increase, although it is not as much as they deserve.'' Labor Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, speaking for the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, said `` the 3 million American workers currently on the minimum wage will benefit.'' But she said skills training was the best way to help the working poor and urged <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to move ahead with legislation dealing with that issue. `` The minimum wage is not the pulley to pull people out of poverty,'' she said. The compromise plan will push the minimum wage, $ 3.35 an hour since January 1981, to $ 3.80 on April 1 and to $ 4.25 a year later. At the same time, it will create a new, lower wage for 16 - to 19-year-old workers who are new to the job market Democrats and organized labor long have opposed such a subminimum `` training wage'' but were forced to concede that point to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to strike the deal. In return, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> agreed to have the minimum wage reach $ 4.25 nine months earlier than he had proposed and also accepted a far more restrictive training wage than he sought earlier this year. Labor played down its concessions in calling on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to quickly sign the measure into law. `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s poorest workers have gone nearly a decade without a raise and this long-overdue step will give them a chance to lift themselves and their families out of poverty,'' <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> said. Even as they praised <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for agreeing to the compromise, <PERSON> Democrats </PERSON> said they would seek another increase heading into the 1992 presidential elections, when <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> likely will be seeking a second term. Both sides made significant concessions to reach the compromise four months after <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> vetoed an earlier Democratic minimum-wage plan. In addition to agreeing to a subminimum, Democrats and labor scaled back their final minimum-wage target; the measure <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> vetoed called for an increase to $ 4.55 an hour. The <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, under increasing pressure from <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> lawmakers seeking to avoid another veto battle heading into 1990 elections year, agreed to a timetable reaching the $ 4.25 level nine months before <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had proposed. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also accepted a training wage that can only be paid to workers 16 to 19 years old for their first three months of work experience and for another three months if certified training is provided. The provision allowing the subminimum expires in April 1993. Under the plan, the subminimum wage will be $ 3.35 on April 1 and $ 3.61 a year later. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wanted to allow the lower wage to be paid to all workers, regardless of age, for their first six months on any new job, regardless of past work experience. All eight senators voting against the measure were Republicans. They were Sens. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> <PERSON> Garn </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Nickles </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Symms </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. Three senators did not vote: <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Baucus </PERSON>, D-Mont., <PERSON> Spark </PERSON> <PERSON> Matsunaga </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallop </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wyo </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-S&amp;LConvention     11-09 0549</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;L Convention,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Weak S&amp;Ls Should Find Merger Partner or Face Regulatory Action</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thrift regulator <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Wall </PERSON> is issuing a warning to weak savings and loan institutions: Find a merger partner or face regulatory action. `` Thrifts that are undercapitalized are in very grave jeopardy,'' Wall told the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutions </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday in closing its annual convention. His agency, the Office of Thrift Supervision, estimates that 800 of the nation's 2,600 solvent <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls will fall nearly $ 20 billion short of new, more stringent capital standards taking effect Dec. 7. The agency believes 223 of the 800 are practically hopeless and within a year will join 260 failed institutions already under government control. Another segment of the 800 will meet the new standard and stay independent by retaining earnings or selling assets, <PERSON> Wall </PERSON> said. But, about 300 will stay out of the government's hands only by seeking a private merger partner. <PERSON> Wall </PERSON> said his agency stands ready to help by finding suitors, including foreign firms and commercial banks, starting with a special conference next week. `` We are calling this our ` arranged marriage' program,'' he said. The new rules require S & amp; L owners to back their lending with more of their own capital and are designed to provide a larger buffer of private money between S & amp; L losses and government deposit insurance funds. They are considered the cornerstone reform in <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L bailout legislation enacted Aug. 9. Wall warned weak thrifts not to be too choosy about merger offers, adding, `` We will not hesitate to take regulatory action.'' `` Go with what you've got ... not with the would have and could have'' or it will be too late to find a merger partner, he said. Under the bailout bill, thrifts not meeting capital standards by the end of 1994 face closure and Wall's agency is writing rules that would permit it to seize an undercapitalized thrift early, before its owners' investment is exhausted. One S & amp; L executive, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Magnolia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hattiesburg </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, said some of his colleagues at weaker thrifts have n't yet admitted they ca n't survive alone. `` There are a great number of people out there who are unwilling to face it. ... But it's going to be difficult to face the siren call of merger with a commercial bank,'' he said. Wall cited recent interest by Canadian and Japanese companies as evidence of the thrift industry's positive outlook. `` The worst is really over. We have been through the fire and emerged tempered by the experience,'' he said. In his speech, <PERSON> Wall </PERSON> did not mention the controversy swirling around his agency's handling of the failure of <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Irvine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, expected to cost taxpayers up to $ 2 billion. However, at a news conference, he defended his decision to delay seizure of <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> by nearly two years, saying he was legally required to keep it open unless it was insolvent. The staff of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> disputes that assertion, maintaining that Wall need only have determined that <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> was operating unsafely and dissipating its assets. `` We were advised at the time we did not have the -LRB- legal -RRB- basis -LRB- to seize <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> -RRB-. It was the best advice we could find,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0158EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-OilSpills Bjt   11-09 0596</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Oil Spills, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Preserves States' Power to Set Oil Spill Liability</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Pre-noon lead expected</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Outrage over the <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valdez </ORGANIZATION> oil spill helped lead to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s vote to let the states continue setting unlimited liability for oil spill cleanups, environmentalists say. But the oil industry says the measure approved Wednesday could do more harm than good to the environment and raise consumer fuel costs. `` It was clear that the <PERSON> Exxon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> was such a national insult to the environment that all the lobbying by the oil companies and special interests could n't overcome it,'' said Rep. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Matz </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Sierra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> said the spill demonstrated `` there were some serious deficiencies in the bill'' as it was originally written <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> and Rep. <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Studds </PERSON>, D-Mass., successfully inserted an amendment into a massive oil liability bill that allowed stricter state laws, despite strong oil industry opposition and several attempts on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor to soften the measure The measure would track current law which also allows states to set stricter liability limits. The House was scheduled to vote on the entire bill today, but the key vote was on the Miller-Studds amendment, which passed 279-143. `` We are dismayed and distressed that the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> has taken this gigantic step backward in environmental protection,'' said a statement issued by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> after the vote. `` Unless altered by conference committee action, we must strongly urge that the president veto this legislation,'' the industry lobbying organization said. The group said that allowing states to go beyond federal limits on the amount a company should spend for oil spill cleanup will make insurance costs for hauling oil prohibitive. `` If the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s plan is adopted into law, many responsible transporters of oil will likely be driven out of business and replaced by less financially responsible and capable shippers,'' said the institute. `` Operators involved in transportation of petroleum products may feel it's not worth the legal risks,'' Rep. <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Lent </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, said during debate on the amendment. `` Home heating oil may suddenly disappear.'' A $ 2 billion price tag has been put on the Exxon Valdez cleanup in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. That state sets no limits on companies' liability for repairing environmental damage. The House bill would limit oil companies' liability to $ 1,200 per gross ton, with a minimum of $ 10 million for large tankers and $ 2 million for small tankers. However, it would let states set higher limits. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has passed similar legislation. Twenty-eight states now have their own oil spill liability statutes, and 19 of them require unlimited liability. <PERSON> Studds </PERSON> accused the oil industry of using scare tactics. `` Make no mistake,'' <PERSON> Studds </PERSON> said. `` When it comes to state pre-emption and the oil industry, the battle lines are clearly drawn between those who are hurt by oil spills and those who cause them, between the public interest and a narrow private interest, between the average citizen and big oil.'' Environmentalists were surprised at the size of the vote in their favor, especially on a second <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> amendment that makes an oil company or carrier liable for unlimited damages in cases of simple negligence, rather than gross negligence as the original measure required. That amendment, which had been expected to be defeated, passed 213 to 207. `` What it means is that the high-priced lobbyists that the oil companies brought in do n't always do the trick,'' said <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Mehrkens </PERSON> of the Wilderness Society. The House for 14 years has repeatedly passed bills against allowing states to pre-empt the federal law.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stock     11-09 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stock,0025</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Up In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 35,657.42, up 61.83 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Thursday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0212EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-AbortionImpact     11-09 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion Impact,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Abortion Opponents Blame Own Candidates for `Waffling'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Abortion opponents, acknowledging the issue helped Democrats win this week's elections, blame their own candidates for wavering in their anti-abortion positions _ but defections already are beginning. `` The lesson that will be learned,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Steen </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Right </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> to </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, `` is that pro-life candidates can not waffle and pro-life candidates must run as aggressively on this issue as pro-abortion candidates.'' An issue that once had Democrats on the run, abortion emerged as a decisive factor in Democratic victories following a political turnabout that Republicans could n't foresee just a few months ago. Republican National Chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> conceded the issue `` made a difference'' in Tuesday's elections. `` I think the abortion issue helped me considerably,'' Democrat <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> said after claiming victory in his bid to become governor of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> against anti-abortion Republican <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>. Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, a leader of the pro-choice minority in the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> faces losses next year if it sticks to the anti-abortion position in its platform. `` I would hope that some of these elections yesterday might bring us to our senses and we would understand that the public is not on our side on this issue,'' he said after a meeting with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on the election results. Some Republicans already are signing up on the pro-choice side. In <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, GOP gubernatorial candidate <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> and a number of <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> state legislators joined Democrats in signing a petition Wednesday seeking a state constitutional amendment guaranteeing the right to abortion. <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> predicted differences over abortion could decide the primary race against his <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> rival, state <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>. <PERSON> O'Steen </PERSON> said Republican losers <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Courter </PERSON> in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> governor's race, and <PERSON> Rudolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON> in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> mayoral race, sealed their defeats weeks ahead by giving ground in their opposition to abortion. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Right </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> to </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> had abandoned both before the election, he said. `` They flip-flopped because they were scared,'' said <PERSON> O'Steen </PERSON>. The anti-abortion group blamed <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>'s strategists for failing to aggressively defend against <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>'s ads attacking him on the abortion issue, and failing to forcefully push his anti-abortion views in ads of his own. `` This is not a loss for the pro-life movement; it is a loss for <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> and the way he handled it,'' said <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Faucher </PERSON>, director of the Right to <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> group </ORGANIZATION>'s political action committee. <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> refused to concede after the unofficial final vote count showed him trailing <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> by about 5,500 votes out of the nearly 1.8 million cast. Abortion rights activists claimed partial credit for the election of Democrat <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Florio </PERSON> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON>' victory in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Both the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> races also were caught up in the potent and sometimes unspoken political crosscurrents of race. <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> and <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> are black and, while winning electoral majorities, ran well behind what polling had indicated. <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> <PERSON> Michelman </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abortion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, said there was `` no question'' that <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> would not have won without the abortion issue. She said <PERSON> Courter </PERSON>'s candidacy never got off the ground because of his anti-abortion position, and that his attempts to soften his opposition further hurt him. `` Voters yesterday proved that choice is a winning issue in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Michelman </PERSON> said. `` To politicians everywhere we say with conviction: if you're out of touch with the pro-choice majority, you're out of office. `` If <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and members of his party remain beholden to the anti-choice minority, they will pay a tremendous price at the polls,'' she said. Political analysts said the apparent turnaround on abortion was the direct result of the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s decision in July in the <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> case. In it, the court gave states broader discretion in regulating abortion and created the impression that major reversals of abortion rights were possible. The court's action invigorated supporters of abortion rights and created an opportunity for pro-choice candidates to exploit concern about a retreat in abortion rights.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0212EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Executions     11-09 0293</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Executions,0302</SECOND>
<HEAD>Six Executed For Rioting in Chengdu Following June 4 Crackdown</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Six people have been executed in the southwestern city of <LOCATION> Chengdu </LOCATION> for participating in riots in June when the government crushed the pro-democracy movement, a local official said today. The executions brought to at least 18 the number of people put to death following the military crackdown on demonstrators in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and other cities. Two people already had been reported executed in <LOCATION> Chengdu </LOCATION> for roles in three days of rioting that began June 4, when troops killed hundreds of unarmed civilians in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and police in <LOCATION> Chengdu </LOCATION> tried to break up a student sit-in. An estimated 30 people died in the <LOCATION> Chengdu </LOCATION> violence, and an entire city block, including a large department store, was burned down. It was the worst outbreak of violence in any city outside <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. The six in <LOCATION> Chengdu </LOCATION> were sentenced to death at a public rally Tuesday and immediately executed, said an official of <LOCATION> Chengdu </LOCATION>'s Foreign Affairs Office Three were charged with `` beating, smashing, looting and burning'' during the violence. The other three were charged with theft and murder. At least 12 other people have been put to death for direct involvement in anti-government demonstrations and riots throughout <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> last spring. None of the previous 12 were students, and it was not clear whether there were any students among the six executed in <LOCATION> Chengdu </LOCATION> this week. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s press rarely reports arrests or court cases involving the student-led pro-democracy movement. Reports that student leaders and soldiers who refused to cooperate in the military crackdown in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> have been executed can not be confirmed. Executions in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> are usually by a bullet to the back of the head as the person sentenced kneels on the ground.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0216EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     11-09 0781</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ag Department Says More Rural Transportation Needed</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Shortline railroads, bus service, feeder airlines and maybe a ferry or two could be possible under long-range strategy mapped out in an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report on rural transportation. But massive new federal aid to help finance such ventures? None was mentioned in the report. Cooperation at all public and private levels was urged as the key to transportation development. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> `` Buzz'' <PERSON> Fitzpatrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, head of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION>, which issued the report Wednesday, said the findings and recommendations were based on regional meetings going back two years and a national conference in <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, in Aug. 1988 `` From the very beginning, this initiative has been a cooperative activity involving a wide range of public and private agencies seeking solutions to the transportation problems of rural residents,'' he said. <PERSON> Fitzpatrick </PERSON> added the report will give rural transportation organizations a practical guide to help in planning and policy development at national, state and local levels. Although no specific mode was recommended over another, the report referred to `` passenger transportation'' generically, meaning it could include rail, bus or air travel, depending on the circumstances. The report said cooperation between public and private sectors `` is essential if rural passenger transportation is to meet the mobility needs of rural residents'' and that new approaches must be found. In mobilizing support for rural passenger transportation, the report said a national plan for rural communities to maintain and expand passenger transportation should be a top priority for action. `` Communities are an essential source of financial and volunteer support for rural passenger transportation providers,'' the report said. `` Effective community participation can generate support for continued intercity bus service and provide financial and volunteer support for rural public providers.'' The report said rural passenger needs are so diverse that a single source of funding can not be relied upon. `` Funding needs to be a joint federal, state and local government effort in conjunction with private industry,'' it said. `` Utilizing a broad range of funding sources and allowing greater flexibility in mixing available funding can provide more mobility to more rural residents.'' Copies of the report, `` Reconnecting Rural <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>: Recommendations for a National Strategy,'' are available from: USDA-OT, P.O. Box 96575, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> 20090-6575. For more information call 202?653-6305.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Total <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> vegetable output this year is up from the drought-reduced 1988 production, an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report said. The overall increase is due mostly to a 29 percent boost in processing vegetable tonnage and a 3 percent larger potato harvest. Production of processing vegetables is estimated at nearly 15 million tons, while potato output is estimated at around 370 million hundredweight. The output of fresh vegetables in 1989 is expected to be up 1 percent; mushrooms, 14 percent; sweet potatoes, 7 percent; and dry edible beans, 29 percent. Despite the strong increase in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> vegetable production, the value of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> vegetable imports is expected to be up by about 5 percent to a record level, the report said Wednesday. `` Growth in imports during 1989 stemmed from continued strong prices at the wholesale and retail levels, and continued strong consumer demand,'' the report said. `` Most of the imports are fresh vegetables, which are brought in during the winter months when <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production is limited to the southern-tier states.'' Per capita use of total vegetables rose to an estimated 336 pounds in 1988, up one pound despite drought-reduced domestic supplies. In general, increases in fresh vegetables, potatoes and mushrooms offset declines among processed items. Fresh vegetable use reached 100 pounds per capita for the first time because of larger use of lettuce and onions, the report said. `` Potato use rose from 49 pounds in 1987 to 55 pounds in 1988. This gain can be attributed entirely to large carryover stocks of fresh potatoes,'' the report said. `` Use of frozen potatoes dropped 4 percent to 44 pounds as record exports reduced the domestic supply.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> plans to be in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> next week for a couple of speeches and talks on trade issues. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> will speak to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> on Nov. 14., his office said Wednesday The <ORGANIZATION> FAO </ORGANIZATION> talk will focus on agricultural negotiations now under way under the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade and how those affect developing countries. At the meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> will speak on the need for reform in world agricultural trade. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> also plans to meet with agricultural ministers from other countries during his <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> visit, his office said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Presidents-Judges     11-09 0637</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Presidents-Judges,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Shows a President's Choice of Judges Keep Alive His Policies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A comparison of the voting records in environment cases of judges appointed by Presidents <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> supports the theory that a president's most lasting impact may result from his judicial selections. Law professor <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kovacic </PERSON> said his findings may be especially significant if President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> chooses judges of the same cast of mind as those appointed by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. In eight years, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> named 347, or 47 percent, of the nation's active federal judges, who serve life terms. By the end of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s term in 1992, <PERSON> Kovacic </PERSON> noted, `` Reagan-Bush nominees could account for as many as 75 percent of all federal Court of Appeals judges.'' When Reagan-Bush judges constitute that big a majority, <PERSON> Kovacic </PERSON> noted, they `` might be inclined over time to endorse more extreme positions in writing majority opinions'' because they wo n't feel compelled to achieve consensus with more moderate judges. In a telephone interview Wednesday, <PERSON> Kovacic </PERSON> said everyone knows about the impact of a president's choices for <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> vacancies, `` but the same kind of effects, though not quite so dramatic, can result from whom he picks for the district and circuit courts.'' `` Of all the tools at a president's disposal, this is an important one,'' he said. `` If you want to make your policies outlive your administration, this is one of the most important means for doing that.'' <PERSON> Kovacic </PERSON>'s analysis was published by the <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, a conservative research organization. <PERSON> Kovacic </PERSON> teaches at <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mason </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. He studied how appeals court judges voted on environmental cases arising from enactment of the <ORGANIZATION> Clean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> and Clean Water Acts. In 162 cases in which <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> appointees cast 254 votes, he found that <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s judges voted 54 percent of the time to increase the regulatory burden on those whose pollution emission or discharge activities were under consideration. Judges appointed by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> voted that way 43 percent of the time. On the <ORGANIZATION> key </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>, often called the country's second most important court, the differences were sharper. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> appointees voted 48 percent of the time to increase the pollution-fighting burden of parties before the court while <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> judges voted that way only half as often. `` The results are not entirely clear-cut,'' <PERSON> Kovacic </PERSON> concluded, noting that when <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> judges sat on the same panel they rarely disagreed. `` It nonetheless appears that the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> appointments on the whole succeeded in bringing less intervention-minded judges to the courts of appeals.'' The tendencies of judges are particularly important, <PERSON> Kovacic </PERSON> said, in regulatory issues where <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> often gives an administrative body, like the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, broad authority to implement comparatively general statutes and the courts find themselves overseeing their work. Other studies have reached the same conclusion about the long-term impact of judicial selections. <PERSON> Sheldon </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldman </PERSON>, political scientist at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION>, wrote last summer that the real impact of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s appointments will reach into the 21st century and likely will be reinforced by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s judges. `` For civil libertarians this means that when the country celebrates the bicentennial of the ratification of the Bill of Rights in 1991, the courts will be dominated by those hostile to a liberal reading of those rights,'' <PERSON> Goldman </PERSON> wrote. `` For judicial conservatives, this means a healthy return to government by the elected representatives of the people.'' <PERSON> Kovacic </PERSON> noted speculation that substantial numbers of Reagan-appointed judges, younger than average and often with college-age children, may quit the bench for the higher earning potential of law practice, especially if <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> does n't raise judges' salaries. `` The real test of whether the Reagan-Bush appointments will have long-lasting effects depends on whether the people they have selected will remain in those jobs,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891109-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-09-89 0221EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Panama     11-09 0523</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Panama,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panamanian Eyed for Key Canal Post, Officials Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
