<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 2334EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Gulf-Hostages     08-02 0411</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gulf-Hostages,0425</SECOND>
<HEAD>Violence Condemned, Calls for U.S. Restraint</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Hostages, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANAMA, Bahrain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> on Wednesday denounced both the Israeli kidnapping of a Shiite Moslem cleric and the killing of <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> Lt. Col. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>. The official Saudi press agency quoted `` a responsible source'' as saying <LOCATION> Riyadh </LOCATION> `` always condemns and denounces terrorist acts of all forms and of whatever methods ... These are despicable, inhuman acts.'' Arab media criticized <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> for abducting <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Karim </PERSON> <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> from south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> Friday and urged the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to show restraint amid reports of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> fleet movements in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION>. The Dubai-based <ORGANIZATION> Al-Bayan </ORGANIZATION> wrote in an editorial: `` <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has flung the doors of hell wide open.'' `` What is the objective behind the Israeli act which can only be classified as organized state terrorism?'' asked <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Dhabi </PERSON>'s state-run <ORGANIZATION> Al-Ittihad </ORGANIZATION> daily The hard-line newspaper Al-Khaleej, in neighboring <LOCATION> Sharjah </LOCATION> emirate, said `` the Zionist terrorist operation in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and its repercussions must be attributed to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy in the region and the full and unconditional <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bias toward <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>.'' The <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> newspaper Al-Rai Al-Aam cautioned the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> against a military response to <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>' purported hanging. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> does not possess many effective means for a speedy revenge of the hanging of a <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> colonel by a group operating in a country with usurped sovereignty such as <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. `` An effective military action is impossible in a country overburdened with rocket launchers, artillery, tanks, bombs, booby-trapped cars and suicide squads, which could be mobilized in any reaction to an American retaliatory strike,'' it wrote. <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION>'s leading Al-Watan newspaper said `` blame should be pinned on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> as it is the instrument of violence in the region.'' Al-Watan and other <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> newspapers, urged self-restraint in the crisis. The newspapers noted that an <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> committee announced an impasse in efforts to end <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s 14-year-old civil war. The <LOCATION> Qatar </LOCATION> newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Al-Raya </ORGANIZATION> said that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> could exploit the situation `` to direct a major blow against <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'' that could lead to its `` partition into small states after internationalization of its crisis.'' <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> voiced `` surprise and outrage'' at claims of <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>' death but blamed <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> for abducting <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> and refusing to free him <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> offered to exchange <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> and Shiite Moslem prisoners it holds for three <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> servicemen and all 16 foreign hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ally and at peace with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, urged `` all parties concerned, whether regional or international, to exercise extreme self-restraint.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     08-02 0429</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0443</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Cheers,' `13 East' Lead NBC to 58th Consecutive Ratings Win</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY BUCK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> might have flopped with its nurse drama `` Nightingales,'' but its summer nurse comedy `` 13 East'' finished in the Top 10, helping the network win another Nielsen ratings derby victory. For the week ended July 30, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Cheers'' landed in first place for the fourth time in five weeks, narrowly topping <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne. `` Cheers'' had a rating of 17.5, only one-tenth of a point ahead of `` Roseanne.'' Last week they tied for first place at 17.4. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> easily won the week for its 58th straight victory in the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> survey. The only surprise in the Top 10 was the appearance of lightly regarded `` 13 East,'' which finished 10th. Other than CBS' `` 60 Minutes'' and `` Murder, She Wrote,'' all the shows in the Top 10 were comedies. The ratings are certainly proof of the resurgence of the situation comedy, which was all but written off a few years ago. Prime-time soap operas like `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>'' and `` Dynasty'' dominated the ratings until the appearance of `` The Cosby Show'' in 1984. In the 1983-84 season the only comedy in the Top 10 was <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>.'' Comedy also dominated the second 10 highest-rated shows this past week with seven entries. Here are the Top 10: <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Golden Girls'' and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` 60 Minutes'' tied, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Wonder Years'' and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` 13 East <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> continued its summer surge in the ratings. `` Married ... With Children'' was in 29th place, `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted'' was tied for 34th and `` Totally Hidden Video'' was tied for 39th place. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> was first with an average of 10.8, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> was second with 8.9 and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> was third with 8.7. The averages since the fall season began on Sept. 19 were: <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 14.8, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 11.9 and CBS 11.8. The ratings is the percentage of the estimated 90.4 million homes in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> with television. The share is the percentage of sets in use. The <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> summer show, `` Knight and <PERSON> Daye </PERSON>,'' did not fare that well in the ratings. It was in 37th place. The lowest-rated show on the three networks was <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` American Nuclear.'' Here are the bottom five: CBS' `` Tour of Duty,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> and <PERSON> Frankie </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Trans-Antarctica Expedition'' and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` American Nuclear <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> had the highest-rated evening news show. The ratings: CBS 9.0, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 8.8 and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 8.6.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     08-02 0666</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0745</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of July 24-30. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.5, 15.8 million homes. 2. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.4, 15.7 million homes. 3. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.2, 14.6 million homes. 4. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.0, 14.5 million homes. 5. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.8, 14.3 million homes. 6. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4, 13.9 million homes. 6. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4, 13.9 million homes. 8. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 14.6, 13.2 million homes. 9. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.5, 13.1 million homes. 10. -LRB- X -RRB- `` 13 East Preview,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.3, 12.9 million homes. 11. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 14.1, 12.7 million homes. 12. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.9, 12.6 million homes. 13. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.6, 12.3 million homes. 14. -LRB- 20 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.5, 12.2 million homes. 15. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.9, 11.7 million homes. 16. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8, 11.6 million homes. 17. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` Coach,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7, 11.5 million homes. 18. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5, 11.3 million homes. 19. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 12.2, 11.0 million homes. 20. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.9, 10.7 million homes. 20. -LRB- 25 -RRB- `` Scandal In A <ORGANIZATION> Small </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Town </ORGANIZATION>,'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 11.9, 10.7 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 22. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.8. 22. -LRB- 50 -RRB- `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.8. 22. -LRB- 20 -RRB- `` In The Heat of The Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.8. 25. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.6. 25. -LRB- 35 -RRB- `` Midnight Caller,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.6. 27. -LRB- 32 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.4. 27. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.4. 29. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 11.2. 30. -LRB- 63 -RRB- `` Doctor, Doctor,'' CBS, 11.0. 31. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.8. 32. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.7. 33. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Miss Teen USA,'' CBS, 10.6. 34. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 10.5. 34. -LRB- 35 -RRB- `` Starting Over'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 10.5. 36. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.2. 37. -LRB- 73 -RRB- `` Knight & amp; <PERSON> Daye </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.1. 38. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Billionaire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>,'' Part I, _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 10.0. 39. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 39. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Totally Hidden Video,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 41. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Somerset </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gardens </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.6. 42. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 9.5. 42. -LRB- 49 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.5. 44. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` Sins,'' Part 2, _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 9.2. 45. -LRB- 98 -RRB- `` West 57th,'' CBS, 8.7. 46. -LRB- 77 -RRB- `` Heartland,'' CBS, 8.6. 47. -LRB- 72 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: Crude Awakening,'' CBS, 8.5. 48. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.4. 48. -LRB- 54 -RRB- `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.4. 50. -LRB- 61 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 51. -LRB- 65 -RRB- `` The Equalizer,'' CBS, 8.1. 52. -LRB- 47 -RRB- `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.0. 53. -LRB- 58 -RRB- `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 7.9. 53. -LRB- 65 -RRB- `` Escape To Freedom'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movie,'' 7.9. 55. -LRB- 67 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Vice,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.8. 56. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.7. 57. -LRB- 87 -RRB- `` A Winner Never Quits'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Saturday Night Movie,'' 7.4. 58. -LRB- 82 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Guillaume </PERSON> <PERSON> Show </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.2. 59. -LRB- 98 -RRB- `` Highway To Heaven,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.1. 59. -LRB- 61 -RRB- `` Hooperman,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.1. 61. -LRB- 110 -RRB- `` Cavanaughs,'' CBS, 6.9. 62. -LRB- 82 -RRB- `` The Keep,'' _ `` Movie of the Week,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.8. 63. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.5. 64. -LRB- 84 -RRB- `` Coming of Age,'' CBS, 6.2. 65. -LRB- 87 -RRB- `` Sins,'' Part 1, _ `` CBS Friday Movie,'' 6.1. 66. -LRB- 87 -RRB- `` A Man Called Hawk,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.0. 67. -LRB- 76 -RRB- `` Paradise,'' CBS, 5.9. 68. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.8. 68. -LRB- 109 -RRB- `` ABC Thursday Night Baseball,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.8. 70. -LRB- 93 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 5.7. 71. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.9. 72. -LRB- 115 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 4.6. 73. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.5. 73. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <PERSON> Mick </PERSON> and <PERSON> Frankie </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 4.5. 75. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Trans-Antarctica Expedition,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 4.3. 76. -LRB- X -RRB- `` American Nuclear,'' CBS, 4.2. 77. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` The Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.2. 78. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.3.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CourthouseHostage     08-02 0433</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Courthouse Hostage,0447</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Holding Hostage in Courtroom Kills Her, Then Self</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT WORTH, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An ex-sheriff's deputy held his former girlfriend hostage in a courtroom for nearly seven hours Tuesday, then killed himself and her, authorities said. Officials and bystanders heard two muffled shots at 9:45 p.m. from the courtroom where <PERSON> Manny </PERSON> <PERSON> Cabano </PERSON> seized <PERSON> Juanita </PERSON> <PERSON> Hermosilla </PERSON>, a county clerk who had obtained a restraining order against Cabano the day before. Paramedics and sheriff's authorities then rushed in and found Cabano dead, with a gunshot wound to the head, and Ms. <PERSON> Hermosilla </PERSON> critically wounded. Ms. <PERSON> Hermosilla </PERSON> was taken to <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> <PERSON> Hospital </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, where she died at 10:17 p.m. while undergoing emergency surgery, said <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, night administrator. Both victims were in their 40s. Cabano used a .44 - caliber pistol he'd taken to the courtroom in the suicide-murder, said <LOCATION> Tarrant </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON>. <PERSON> Cabano </PERSON> had also seized a .38 - caliber pistol from the justice of the peace in whose courtroom Ms. <PERSON> Hermosilla </PERSON> The gunman apparently went to Ms. <PERSON> Hermosilla </PERSON>'s home and opened her mail, finding court papers relating to the restraining order, before storming the courtroom, sheriff's officials said. The standoff began when <PERSON> Cabano </PERSON> grabbed the woman in Justice of the Peace <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Ashmore </PERSON>'s first-floor courtroom at the <LOCATION> Tarrant </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Courthouse </LOCATION> at about 3 p.m. Police negotiated with <PERSON> Cabano </PERSON>, sometimes through Ms. <PERSON> Hermosilla </PERSON>, via telephone during the standoff. Wise said talks with Cabano were improving about 8 p.m. and authorities thought the situation would end without bloodshed. `` Our hopes were building,'' he said. But then Ms. <PERSON> Hermosilla </PERSON> came on the line and `` she requested that she talk to her boys. That's always a bad sign.'' Wise did n't say whether Ms. <PERSON> Hermosilla </PERSON> was able to speak to her children. Police special weapons and tactics units were dispatched to the scene but left about 5 p.m., when the Sheriff's <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said they would take over, said <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> police spokesman <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Clarke </PERSON>. `` Judge <PERSON> Ashmore </PERSON> said he worked with the man and knew him. The sheriff said he worked with him and knew him,'' <PERSON> Clarke </PERSON> said. A sheriff's department dispatcher who did not wish to be identified said <PERSON> Cabano </PERSON> `` worked here as a deputy years and years ago. He then became a bail bondsman until he went bankrupt about a year ago.'' Four of Ms. <PERSON> Hermosilla </PERSON>'s five children, some in their teens, rushed to the courthouse about 5 p.m., but were taken away by several of her co-workers. Police blocked off the area and evacuated about 300 people in the courthouse and the City Administration Building across the street.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SchoolChallenge     08-02 0278</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-School Challenge,0285</SECOND>
<HEAD>Little School Out to Show Bigger Not Always Better</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROTHSAY, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This northwestern <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> town with 250 students is challenging larger districts in the state to top its attendance record and graduation rate. <LOCATION> Rothsay </LOCATION>, in fact, is willing to give $ 500 in scholarship money to the first three districts that can top its accomplishments. The challenge is aimed at districts with more than 4,000 students. `` We've been listening to things like, ` Bigger is better,' `` said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Fosse </PERSON>, a school board member and president of the <ORGANIZATION> Rothsay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which is providing the money. `` We're saying maybe that's not true. <LOCATION> Rothsay </LOCATION> is issuing the challenge in response to a legislative auditor's report issued in December saying some of the state's smallest school districts are not providing students with a good education and should be phased out `` When you read the report, it just sounds like we're doing such a terrible job with our young folks,'' said <PERSON> DuWayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Balken </PERSON>, chairman of the school board. `` We believe that's not true at all. They're very well prepared.'' School districts accepting the challenge must meet or exceed <LOCATION> Rothsay </LOCATION>'s record in average daily attendance and graduation rates over the last three school years. The challenge also includes the rate of extracurricular participation, the percentage of high school graduates who entered a post-secondary school and the percentage that earned degrees from a four-year institution, all during the last three years. School officials are confident even though they have n't checked numbers to see how <LOCATION> Rothsay </LOCATION> has fared in those categories. `` We know they're high,'' <PERSON> Fosse </PERSON> said. `` We're confident that we'll stack up well. We're waiting for a challenge.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Thatcher-Cabinet Bjt   08-02 0666</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Thatcher-Cabinet, Bjt,0687</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thatcher Humiliation of Ex-Foreign Secretary Upsets Cabinet</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP Extra</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By MAUREEN JOHNSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> has angered powerful political associates with a Cabinet shuffle that humiliated her longtime foreign secretary. It was not so much what she did on July 24 _ when 13 of the 22 Cabinet posts changed hands _ that has upset the hierarchy of the usually well-disciplined <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. It was her manner of doing it that left wounds and resentments which, some analysts believe, could mark the beginning of <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s political end. `` Many of us found what went on nauseating,'' <ORGANIZATION> Tory </ORGANIZATION> legislator <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Howell </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION> foreign affairs committee, said in a television interview. He spoke after news broke of how Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> moved aside Sir <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Howe </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s longest-serving foreign secretary since World War II, and replaced him with a virtual unknown, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Major </PERSON>. In the process, according to <PERSON> Howe </PERSON>'s aides, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> offered <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> another senior, but less prestigious job as home secretary _ without consulting the incumbent, <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurd </PERSON>. <PERSON> Howe </PERSON>, 62, turned that post down as a demotion after six years as foreign secretary. He settled for what Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s office called the `` courtesy title'' of deputy prime minister and the job of government leader in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> also accepted residence in a country mansion, <LOCATION> Dorneywood </LOCATION>, which currently is used as a weekend retreat by the third member of Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s top Cabinet trio, Chancellor of the Exchequer <PERSON> Nigel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawson </PERSON>. `` This is how regimes behave when they have begun to take power for granted,'' commented <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sunday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> columnist <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>. Off the record, government ministers were quoted as complaining that Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, who has held office for 10 years, committed a major blunder by humiliating or affronting all three of her top Cabinet colleagues. Some described the shakeup by Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> _ who has sole power to appoint <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> ministers from among her party's legislators _ as a `` shambles'' and said it reflected her increasing lack of regard for the Cabinet. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s Downing Street office took the unusual step of announcing she supported <PERSON> Hurd </PERSON> and would have kept him in an unspecified top job had <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> taken the job of home secretary. In the announcement, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> also said there will be no more Cabinet shakeups before the next general election, which must be held by mid-1992 but could come earlier. <PERSON> Howe </PERSON>, who was cheered by sympathizers when he entered the Commons after the shuffle, hastily denied a newspaper report that he planned to run against Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> for the party leadership. <PERSON> Hurd </PERSON> announced that the Cabinet was united. <PERSON> Lawson </PERSON>, known to disagree with Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> on aspects of economic policy, said nothing. `` The Thatcher Cabinet is now more divided than ever before.. not on policy, but on personality. Either they are for Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> or they are against Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>,'' wrote columnist <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cochrane </PERSON> in the pro-conservative Mail on Sunday newspaper. `` She is lucky the long summer recess is now upon us ... but the summer wo n't last forever. And the contenders for her job wo n't bide their time forever,'' he said A senior aide to Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> hinted that <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> was removed because he and <PERSON> Lawson </PERSON> pressed the prime minister to be more conciliatory about European monetary union before June's meeting of <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> leaders in <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>. At the summit, she agreed in principle to link the pound to other <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> currencies. But a dip in opinion poll ratings of the Conservative government that began in March has turned into a persistent deficit of about 10 points behind the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Furor over the Cabinet shuffle has heightened fears that Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> may be an electoral liability. With a batch of unpopular legislation due next year, including the sale of water and electricity industries to private enterprise, Conservative fears are growing that Labor ca n't be stopped this side of an election.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0215EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SAfrica-TrojanHorse     08-02 0387</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SAfrica-Trojan Horse,0399</SECOND>
<HEAD>Parents of Slain Youths Prosecute Police In ``Trojan Horse'' Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SAHM VENTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAPE TOWN, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An army officer and 12 policemen have gone on trial for murder in an unprecedented prosecution initiated by parents of two boys shot to death in 1985 by officers hidden in crates on an unmarked truck. The parents decided last year to pursue the case on their own after the attorney general for <ORGANIZATION> Cape </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Province </ORGANIZATION> declined to prosecute the policemen despite a magistrate's finding of police negligence. The trial that opened Tuesday in <ORGANIZATION> Cape </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Town </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> is reportedly the first murder case to proceed under a law allowing private citizens to press a prosecution in certain instances where the government has declined. The 1985 confrontation, which occurred during anti-apartheid unrest in a mixed-race township near <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION>, has become widely known as the `` Trojan Horse incident'' because white police gunmen concealed themselves in a what looked like an ordinary delivery truck. Footage of the incident was shown at the time on television news broadcasts in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. According to evidence at the inquest, an army commandant and two senior police officers ordered the truck into the township of <LOCATION> Athlone </LOCATION> expecting it to be a target for stonethrowers. Gunfire from the concealed policemen killed <PERSON> Shaun </PERSON> <PERSON> Magmoed </PERSON>, 16; <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Miranda </PERSON>, 11, and <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Classens </PERSON>, 21, but the magistrate ruled there was no evidence that any of the three were among a handful of mixed-race youths who did throw stones. The officers in the crates popped out of the hiding places and fired 39 rounds of shotgun ammunition at the crowd, according to the evidence. The private prosecution was instituted by <PERSON> Miranda </PERSON>'s mother and <PERSON> Magmoed </PERSON>'s father. Their lawyers are to be paid with proceeds from a fund set up last year which has received contributions from various overseas human rights organizations. Defense lawyers are being paid with public funds. The law providing for private prosecutions allows the defense to ask that the prosecutors pay the defendants' entire legal costs if the case ends in acquittal. At the start of Tuesday's proceedings, defense lawyers asked that the prosecution be ordered immediately to post a deposit of $ 360,000 to cover possible legal costs. The request was taken under consideration by the judge.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0216EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hostages-Groups     08-02 0729</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hostages-Groups,0749</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sketches of Groups Holding Hostages in Lebanon</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Hostages Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Most Western hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> are believed held by factions of <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, or Party of God, a fundamentalist <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Moslem </ORGANIZATION> group that gets considerable financial support from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> works closely with units of Iranian Revolutionary Guards, stationed in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> since <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 1982 invasion, to build influence among the 1.2 million Shiites, <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s largest sect. The factions are believed to be closely linked and may even be largely the same people using different cover names. These are the groups claiming to hold the hostages: _ Islamic Jihad, or Islamic Holy War, says it has <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, kidnapped March 16, 1985, and <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutherland </PERSON>, acting dean of agriculture at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION>, abducted June 9 of that year. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> has been held longest of the Western hostages. It demands the release of 17 comrades jailed in <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> for bombing the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and French embassies in December 1983. Some of those imprisoned are believed to be relatives of Islamic Jihad members. Speculation has arisen that Islamic Jihad also kidnapped <ORGANIZATION> Anglican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> envoy <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Waite </PERSON>, who disappeared Jan. 23, 1987, after leaving his hotel in Moslem west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> to negotiate for the release of American hostages. No claim of kidnapping has been made. _ Islamic Jihad for the <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> claims to hold three Americans kidnapped Jan. 24, 1987, from the campus of <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-affiliated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>: <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Polhill </PERSON>, a lecturer in accounting; <PERSON> Alann </PERSON> <PERSON> Steen </PERSON>, a communications teacher, and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, a visiting professor of mathematics and computer science. It demands the release of <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> and Shiite Lebanese prisoners in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. _ The <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> claimed responsibility for kidnapping Americans <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON>, acting comptroller of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION>, on Sept. 12, 1986, and <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON>, a self-styled writer and wanderer, on Oct. 19, 1986. Statements from the organization threatened the men's lives twice in 1988 _ in retaliation for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s downing of an Iranian jetliner in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> in July and if foreign soldiers were sent to <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> because of problems over the election of a president in September. It did not say they were put to death. _ The Organization of the Oppressed on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> claimed responsibility for kidnapping Marine Lt. Col. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON> on Feb. 17, 1988, while he served with a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> truce observer force, and said he was hanged Monday. A videotape was released, but there was no way to determine when it was made, and no body has been found. _ Arab Revolutionary <PERSON> Cells-Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mukhtar </PERSON> <PERSON> Brigades </PERSON> said it kidnapped <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON>, the American director of the <ORGANIZATION> Lebanese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, on Sept. 9, 1986. _ <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Moslems </ORGANIZATION>, believed to be a cover name for a faction of <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> terrorist mastermind <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Nidal </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Fatah-Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, claimed to have abducted <PERSON> Alec </PERSON> <PERSON> Collett </PERSON>, a British journalist on assignment for a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> agency. <PERSON> Collett </PERSON> was kidnapped March 25, 1985, and the group said April 23, 1986, that it hanged him because of <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> support for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> air raids on <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> eight days earlier. A videotape was released, showing a body hanging from a scaffold, but no corpse has been found. _ <ORGANIZATION> Cells </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Struggle </ORGANIZATION> claimed to have abducted <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>, a Briton decorated as a fighter pilot in World War II, on May 12, 1989. Five other Westerners are missing and believed kidnapped, but no claims of abduction have been made and nothing has been heard of them since they disappeared. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, a British journalist with the London-based <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> agency, was seized April 17, 1986, on th road to the <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> airport. <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Keenan </PERSON>, an English language teacher at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION> who holds dual Irish and British nationality, was kidnapped as he walked to work April 11, 1986. <PERSON> Alberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Molinari </PERSON>, an Italian businessman, was abducted Sept. 11, 1985, as he crossed <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s sectarian dividing line from Christian east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> to the Moslem zone. He had lived in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> for 20 years. West Germans <PERSON> Heinrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Struebig </PERSON> and <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemptner </PERSON>, who worked with the ASME-Humanitas relief group in Palestinian refugee camps near <LOCATION> Sidon </LOCATION> in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, disappeared May 16, 1989. No group has claimed responsibility, but militia leaders in the area say they are held by radical Palestinians.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-02 0932</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0968</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Conductor <PERSON> Zubin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mehta </PERSON>, annoyed by the noise of latecomers, dropped the baton to his knee a few measures into <PERSON> Beethoven </PERSON>'s `` Leonore'' overture. Obediently, the Israeli Philharmonic stopped playing. The Fine Arts Palace concert hall audience fell deadly silent, but not before chiding ushers and insulting the late arrivals, according to the government news agency <ORGANIZATION> Notimex </ORGANIZATION>. Five minutes later, <PERSON> Mehta </PERSON> began the concert again. The audience behaved for the rest of Monday's concert and <PERSON> Mehta </PERSON> apparently forgave them. After a standing ovation, he offered an encore, <PERSON> Brahms </PERSON>' Hungarian Dances.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> thinks he got a raw deal from <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> and a bum rap from <PERSON> Spike </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>. `` Given my personal circumstances and the success of my films, I've got the worst deal in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> said in the Aug. 8 issue of <ORGANIZATION> Rolling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stone </ORGANIZATION> magazine. He was upset by <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicholson </PERSON>'s potential $ 60 million payday for `` Batman,'' a payoff based on a percentage of the receipts and merchandising rather than the per-film deal that <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> signed with <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION>. `` When I renegotiated my deal with <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> a few years ago, it seemed great,'' said <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>. `` But nobody planned that my pictures would be as successful as they are. So now I've got a -LRB- lousy -RRB- deal, compared with what I could be making.'' <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> also said he was angered by fellow filmmaker <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s charges that he has failed to use his power to help other blacks in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> `` I do have a social conscience, but I ca n't walk into a studio's front office and demand, ` Hire some black people here!' <PERSON> Spike </PERSON> gets overanxious playing that militant-brother role and occasionally says some stupid stuff,'' <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Torch singer <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Hyman </PERSON> has taped a public service announcement about breast exams because of a friend's death from breast cancer and her sister's struggle with the disease. Ms. <PERSON> Hyman </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> native who still lives in the city, filmed the announcement Tuesday for <ORGANIZATION> Thomas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jefferson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Linda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Creed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Creed </PERSON>, who wrote Ms. <PERSON> Hyman </PERSON>'s hit `` Old Friend'' as well as `` The Greatest Love of All,'' died in 1986. Ms. <PERSON> Hyman </PERSON> said her friendship with the songwriter and her sister's battle with breast cancer `` gave me a lot of strength when I was asked to do this. I get breast exams every year, and I do self-exams. Not as often as I should, but I do them. It's an easy process.'' More than 142,000 women in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> develop breast cancer and about 43,000 women die of the disease each year. The videotape will be sent to television stations in the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> area.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Rutherford </PERSON> says the music and message of his solo group, <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> and The Mechanics, is becoming more defined and is distinctly different from Genesis, the pop group he helped found. `` I feel that with each album I'm getting away from Genesis,'' said <PERSON> Rutherford </PERSON>. `` There's a lot of influences that are coming through the Mechanics that have n't completely gotten out yet. We are always changing.'' Although both groups have a Top 40 sound, <PERSON> Rutherford </PERSON> sees differences. `` I think onstage we go a little more -LRB- rhythm and blues -RRB-, and that's one of the things that takes us away from Genesis,'' he said. He believes it is unfair to compare the 12-year-old Genesis and his veteran bandmates <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Banks </PERSON> to the 4-year-old Mechanics, but <PERSON> Rutherford </PERSON> said it is inevitable. Despite the good fortune the Mechanics have experienced, the group still struggles while Genesis lives in the comfort that they have fans to buy their records and attend their concerts. `` On one hand I can fly around the world with Genesis, and with the Mechanics I ca n't make any mistakes,'' said <PERSON> Rutherford </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Dangerfield </PERSON> honored the Musicians' Union strike by not appearing at <ORGANIZATION> Bally </ORGANIZATION>'s Hotel and Casino. The hotel announced Saturday that <PERSON> Dangerfield </PERSON> was to have opened Tuesday night despite the continuing strike, but representatives of Musicians' Local 369 said <PERSON> Dangerfield </PERSON> had changed his mind and agreed not to appear Aug. 1-9 as previously announced. The hotel confirmed that Tuesday. The hotel announced Tuesday afternoon it was closing its Celebrity Room, which features name stars, until the strike ends. Singer <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> had been scheduled Aug. 10-15. Musicians struck the Strip resort Thursday when <ORGANIZATION> Bally </ORGANIZATION>'s switched from musicians to taped music for its Jubilee production show. The hotel agreed to continue to use musicians to back up headliners appearing in the Celebrity Room, but the union set up pickets to protest the switch for the Jubilee show. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, scheduled to open at the Celebrity Room last week, canceled his engagement rather than cross the picket line. <ORGANIZATION> Bally </ORGANIZATION>'s is the only resort in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> that has a production show and a room featuring name headliners. The Flamingo Hilton and the Tropicana have switched from live music to tape for their production shows. The union has been picketing at both resorts.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singers <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> will be co-hosts of the 23rd annual Country Music Association Awards Show Oct. 9. The association announced Tuesday that the two-hour show, to be broadcast live on <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, will originate at the Grand Ole Opry House. Eleven awards will be presented during the program. <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> is known for hit records such as `` You Needed Me,'' `` A Little Good News'' and `` Shadows in the Moonlight.'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>' hit records include `` <PERSON> Lucille </PERSON>,'' `` The Gambler'' and `` <PERSON> Coward </PERSON> of the County.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Pepper'sSeat 3rdLd-Writethru a0805 08-02 0733</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pepper's Seat, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0805,0747</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cuban-American Wins GOP Nod for Pepper Seat; Dems Head to Runoff</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 11 grafs to UPDATE with Democratic runoff, final
results. Picks up below dash.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN SEWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cuban-born state Sen. <PERSON> Ileana </PERSON> <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON> romped to the Republican nomination Tuesday in the race to succeed the late Rep. <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON>, while a Cuban-born former city commissioner and a prominent <PERSON> Jewish </PERSON> attorney headed to a Democratic runoff. Attorney <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Richman </PERSON> claimed momentum as he narrowly led a seven-candidate field in the ethnically diverse district. Former <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> city commissioner <PERSON> Rosario </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, also Cuban-born, had been the front-runner but was criticized for late negative campaigning. She ran just behind <PERSON> Richman </PERSON>, who in his stump speech said the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> slot was `` an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> seat.'' Pepper's niece, <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON>, fell short of the Aug. 15 runoff for the District 18 seat. `` It is really incredible,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON>, who was carrying nearly every precinct with 80 percent-plus totals. `` We're quite humbled and really flabbergasted We really just hoped for a victory without a runoff.'' Elections officials said turnout was best in the <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION> precincts. The Aug. 29 special election to fill the seat Pepper had held for the Democrats since 1962 could result in election of the first Cuban-American in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. While the Democrats battle in a runoff campaign, Ms. <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON> will get help from a fund-raising visit Wednesday by Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> for the state <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and she will film a new television commercial Thursday. `` We are going to charge ahead,'' she said. `` We do n't let up for one minute.'' In unofficial returns from all 146 precincts, Ms. <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON>, 36, had 16,555 votes, or 85 percent; fellow Cuban-American <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>, 57, had 1,997 votes, or 10 percent; insurance broker <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Fleischer </PERSON>, 54, had 555 votes, 3 percent, and evangelist <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Stembridge </PERSON>, 51, had 456 votes, or 2 percent. In the heated Democratic race, <PERSON> Richman </PERSON>, 48, had 5,513 votes, or 28 percent, while Ms. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, 44, had 5,402 votes, or 27 percent. Ms. <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON>, 39, had 4,757 votes, or 24 percent. Some 1,000 Democratic absentee ballots remained to be counted Wednesday. Professor <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, 48, had 1,625 votes, or 8 percent; and real estate agent <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, 54, had 1,476 votes, or 7 percent. They are both black. Businessman <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Anscher </PERSON>, 67, had 662 votes, 3 percent, and striking <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> pilot <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosser </PERSON>, 38, had 264 votes, or 1 percent. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> has n't elected a black congressman since Reconstruction.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Pepper, a liberal champion of the elderly and poor, drew no opposition in 1988. He died May 30 at age 88, and his death left the Republicans with a 10-8 majority in the state's congressional delegation. The district includes the retirement communities of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, predominantly black neighborhoods such as <LOCATION> Liberty </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, heavily <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> neighborhoods and affluent <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION>. The elections office said the district's 100,198 registered Democrats comprised 16,028 Hispanics, 32,183 blacks and 51,987 non-Latin whites. The 71,620 registered Republicans comprised 46,738 Hispanics, 23,656 non-Latin whites, and 1,226 blacks. But the figures for Hispanics are low, because the office counts only those who were born in Hispanic nations. Unofficial estimates that include second-generation Hispanics run to about half of the registered voters. Ms. <PERSON> Lehtinen </PERSON>, an educator and conservative married to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Dexter </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehtinen </PERSON>, led candidates in fund-raising with more than $ 200,000 reported as of July 20. She avoided joint appearances with <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>, a businessman and fervent supporter of <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>, the former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> adviser who endorsed <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, whose former husband is <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, an ex-mayor of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and one of her top political advisers, was criticized in the campaign's final week for negative mailings aimed at Ms. Pepper and <PERSON> Richman </PERSON>. She was endorsed by the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>, The <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> and state <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferro </PERSON>. <PERSON> Richman </PERSON>, former <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> president, was attacked in the mailings for representing international arms dealer <PERSON> Sarkis </PERSON> <PERSON> Soghanalian </PERSON>, indicted on charges of illegally conspiring to smuggle combat helicopters to <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Richman </PERSON> called <PERSON> Soghanalian </PERSON> a patriot who has helped <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> causes. Ms. Pepper, portrayed as a naive political novice by the Kennedy forces, said she learned inside politics and government during her frequent travels with her uncle. She said 14 years as a federal probation officer gave her tough views on crime.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     08-02 0402</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0416</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW LONDON, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A trucker from <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> heading to <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> to deliver a load of rice had to make a side trip so his wife could deliver a baby boy. <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Weaver </PERSON>, 26, and her husband, <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Freitus </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Dover </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Del. </LOCATION>, were heading north on Interstate 95 Monday morning when they stopped at a rest stop in East Lyme. When <PERSON> Freitus </PERSON> came out of a <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>, Ms. <PERSON> Weaver </PERSON> had gone into labor. Freitus started driving again to look for a hospital. `` I did n't know where the first hospital was,'' she said Monday night from <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> and Memorial Hospital. `` But we saw a sign for it. Then we hoped there were no tunnels or anything.'' After Freitus maneuvered the truck into the hospital parking lot, Ms. <PERSON> Weaver </PERSON> walked into the hospital about 4:30 a.m. and gave birth to <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> 15 minutes later. The 5-pound, 12-ounce boy, due Aug. 11, was Ms. <PERSON> Weaver </PERSON>'s second child. Freitus waited for the delivery and took a picture with his new son before hopping back into his truck to make his delivery. He planned to pick her up on his return trip.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>EVANSVILLE, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A raffle offering a complete wedding and reception package drew no takers among public housing residents in this <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> city. `` It was my bright idea that maybe we would have some young lady who, rather than living with a fellow, would like to get married and did not have the means,'' <ORGANIZATION> Evansville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> member <PERSON> Jeanette </PERSON> <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> said Tuesday. The package, including gown, tuxedo, flowers for the wedding party and the traditional decor, were to be given away Monday in a raffle for more than 1,000 people living in homes owned by the housing authority. Residents could obtain free tickets by filling out a form that verified they were single. No one picked up a ticket, a disappointed <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Benton </PERSON>, who owns and operates a wedding outfitting business, got the idea for the wedding after learning of mass weddings put on by larger cities' federal housing programs. Such weddings in other cities were motivated by housing officials who wanted to stop couples from living together as a way of circumventing a federal requirement of reporting all household members' incomes. <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> reiterated that was not her motivation, adding, `` It was just something to give back to the community.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SovereigntyCommission 1stLd-Writethru a0414 08-02 0587</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sovereignty Commission, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0414,0598</SECOND>
<HEAD>Records: Businessman Led FBI To Bodies In 1964</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: DELETES extraneous 10th graf, `Warren said...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JACKSON, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> businessman was the paid informant who in 1964 led the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> to the graves of three slain civil rights workers, according to records of a defunct segregationist state agency. <PERSON> Olen </PERSON> <PERSON> Burrage </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, received $ 30,000 from the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> for this information,'' records from the <ORGANIZATION> Sovereignty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> show. The records quote their own informant. <PERSON> Burrage </PERSON>, however, denied that he had anything to do with the killings. A federal judge last week ordered the records of the commission, which tried to thwart civil rights groups in the 1950s and 1960s, be opened to the public. The judge later stayed his ruling pending an appeal. Portions of the records are included in the personal papers of former Gov. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr </PERSON>. The complete records are in the archives of the McCain Graduate Library at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mississippi </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Hattiesburg </LOCATION>. Portions were made available to The Clarion-Ledger in an agreement with the attorney general. <PERSON> Burrage </PERSON> told the newspaper Monday that he had nothing to do with the killings of <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Chaney </PERSON>, <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwerner </PERSON>. He also denied that the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> paid him for information. <PERSON> Burrage </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, said his client was tried on federal charges of conspiracy to violate the civil rights of the three men in 1967 and acquitted. `` Hey, look, you can write whatever you want to,'' <PERSON> Burrage </PERSON> said in a telephone interview with the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> <PERSON> Clarion-Ledger </PERSON>. `` I did n't have nothing to do with it. I'm not going to have anything to do with it now. `` I've been harassed for years and years on this mess. I do n't even want to talk to you about it,'' he said Commission investigator A.L. <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON>' search for the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> informant is contained in the commission's records. <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> is dead. <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> wrote a report on his investigation Aug. 6, 1964, two days after the three bodies were found in a grave at the base of a pond dam under construction on <PERSON> Burrage </PERSON>'s land southwest of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. `` I have information from a confidential source ... that Mr. <PERSON> Olen </PERSON> <PERSON> Burrage </PERSON>, a white male who owns the property where the bodies were found, and who operates a truck line out of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, is the informant who directed the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> to the spot,'' <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> said in the report. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, who was the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent in charge of the <LOCATION> Neshoba </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> investigation, said Monday that <PERSON> Burrage </PERSON> never received money for information. `` I did n't pay any money to anybody,'' <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said in an interview from his <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> home. `` I certainly do n't know anything about it.'' <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said a freelance writer working on the case during the 44 days federal and state officials looked for the three had offered a reward of $ 25,000 for information leading to the bodies. `` That was the genesis of all the talk up there,'' <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said. `` I think he was affluent enough he could have paid the reward. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> file shows an informant led agents to the dam, but <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> refused to identify the individual. `` I have never named anybody, and I do n't want to.'' The commission was created by the <ORGANIZATION> Mississippi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> on March 22, 1956, to preserve segregation in the state. The commission became inactive in 1973 when then-Gov. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Waller </PERSON> vetoed its funding. The Legislature abolished the commission and ordered its files sealed for 50 years in 1977.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0236EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Germany-Snub     08-02 0531</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Germany-Snub,0554</SECOND>
<HEAD>Leading Newspaper Chain Ends 40-Year Snub of East Germany</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROL J. WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Since East <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> was founded 40 years ago, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s largest publishing chain has snubbed its socialist sibling by placing quotation marks around every reference to the state. But starting today, <PERSON> Axel </PERSON> <PERSON> Springer </PERSON> newspapers and magazines will end the practice that has irked authorities in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Springer </PERSON> officials said. The quotation marks have cost the publishing empire journalistic accreditation in the neighboring socialist state and readership among much of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s left-leaning populace. But far from conceding defeat in the ideological battle, the publishers contend the war against the division of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> continues. `` The hope for reunification is unshaken,'' <PERSON> Manfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Schell </PERSON>, editor-in-chief of the conservative daily <ORGANIZATION> Die </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welt </ORGANIZATION> wrote today. But, in light of changes in East-West relations, the barriers to improving the flow of information between the political blocs must fall, <PERSON> Schell </PERSON> said. The giant <PERSON> Springer </PERSON> publishing network includes <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s largest-circulation daily, Hamburg-based <ORGANIZATION> Bild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zeitung </ORGANIZATION>, which sells nearly 5 million copies daily It also includes the influential <PERSON> Berliner </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgenpost </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>'s Die Welt. Despite <PERSON> Springer </PERSON>'s broad audience, its journalists have been denied accreditation to work in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> on the grounds that the company's editorial policies are insulting to the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> government. A spokesman for the East German <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said the government had no immediate comment on <PERSON> Springer </PERSON>'s reversal. <PERSON> Schell </PERSON> hinted in his editorial that the newspaper considered the dropped quotation marks a step toward gaining permission to report from <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Referring to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> as `` DDR,'' the German abbreviation for <ORGANIZATION> Deutsche </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Demokratische </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republik </ORGANIZATION>, was the protest of the publishing chain's founder, <PERSON> Axel </PERSON> <PERSON> Springer </PERSON>, who died nearly four years ago. <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s division after World War II weighed heavily on <PERSON> Springer </PERSON>, who moved his prospering business from his native <LOCATION> Hamburg </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> in 1967. After construction of the Berlin Wall in 1961, he put up a lighted readerboard to flash news from the West across the barrier. <PERSON> Springer </PERSON> also issued political and moral guidelines for the publications in 1967, and the first and foremost called for the reunification of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. From the 1949 founding of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Springer </PERSON> publications refused to acknowledge the socialist government and the quotation marks demonstrated their disdain. Die Welt administrative chief <PERSON> Jens </PERSON> <PERSON> Lueddeke </PERSON> said other West German publications also initially declined to acknowledge East German statehood, using similar quote marks or skeptical references to the government. But most dropped the practice after <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> recognized the east in 1970. <PERSON> Springer </PERSON> editors concede now that the quotation marks have now lost their meaning and in some cases simply confuse readers. Circulation of <PERSON> Springer </PERSON>'s main dailies has fallen by as much as 10 percent over the past few years, and many attribute the drop to shifts within the West German populace toward detente with nations of the Soviet-led <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION>. `` The number of people who can recall adult life in a unified <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> is a minority,'' <ORGANIZATION> Die </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welt </ORGANIZATION> editor <PERSON> Schell </PERSON> wrote. `` With this step we come to grips with the developments in East and <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, in particular the reform efforts in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Schell </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SleepStudy     08-02 0407</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sleep Study,0420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study: Working Women Sleep Less</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EAST LANSING, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Working women sleep about 25 minutes less per night than their male counterparts, though the average woman sleeps slightly longer than the average man, researchers said Tuesday. `` Working women really take it in the neck. They sleep less,'' said <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamermesh </PERSON>, professor of economics at <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and one of the authors. `` One possible explanation is that a woman who works still has to maintain a lot of household duties,'' said <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Biddle </PERSON>, assistant professor of economics at the school. `` They are n't spending much less time doing those things, and their husbands are n't sharing chores with them, so the time has to come from somewhere and often it comes from sleep time.'' Mothers of children less than 3 years old get less sleep than the average person, but being parents to children younger than 3 does n't cut into the amount of sleep fathers get, <PERSON> Hamermesh </PERSON> said. The study of the sleep habits of 1,500 people also found that people who work sleep less than people who do n't work and that for every extra hour worked, a person sleeps 15 minutes less. The more a man works, the less sleep he gets, the report said. Men who earn a higher wage per hour sleep less than lower-paid men, but that pattern fails to hold up for women. `` One reason may be that women who are already working are sleeping less already and so the margin is gone,'' he said. <PERSON> Hamermesh </PERSON> and <PERSON> Biddle </PERSON> gleaned the findings from reviewing information gathered in 1975-76 by the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> survey research division. In 1980-81, 620 members of the study group were interviewed again. <PERSON> Biddle </PERSON> said the time lapse since the data was collected should n't matter because lifestyles have n't changed significantly since then. `` Lifestyles and attitudes toward money and family are pretty much the same. Things like household habits are very slow to change,'' he said. Wide variances in the amount of time people sleep were turned up by the study. <PERSON> Hamermesh </PERSON> said 10 percent reported sleeping less than 6.5 hours a night and 10 percent reported sleeping more than 9 hours. `` Sleep is not something biologically fixed. People can substitute other activities for sleep,'' <PERSON> Hamermesh </PERSON> said. `` Although it's true we do need a certain amount of sleep, we do have some control,'' <PERSON> Biddle </PERSON> said. `` How much time is valued is going to enter into that decision.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0245EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Hank'sDaughter     08-02 0222</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Hank's Daughter,0226</SECOND>
<HEAD>Daughter of Hank Williams to Perform With Father's Band</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jett </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> will perform her own music with songs written by her father, country great <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, when she begins touring with his <ORGANIZATION> Drifting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cowboys </ORGANIZATION> band. `` It's meant to be, because a lot of strange things have happened,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, who recently won a decision by the <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> recognizing she had been cut out of her father's estate. `` I know who I am now. I know that my father wanted me and that's taken me a whole lifetime.'' She signed a deal Monday with <ORGANIZATION> Buddy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Attractions </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> to tour with the two Drifting Cowboys who still perform, fiddler <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivers </PERSON> and steel guitarist <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>. Tour arrangements were incomplete. Ms. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, whose real name is <PERSON> Cathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Deupree </PERSON> <PERSON> Adkinson </PERSON>, was born in <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> five days after <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' death on Jan. 1, 1953. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> and her mother, <PERSON> Bobbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Jett </PERSON>, were not married, and the child was raised by <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' mother, <PERSON> Lillian </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON>. After Mrs. <PERSON> Stone </PERSON>'s death the girl was put up for adoption. The <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> court decided she should share <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' songwriting royalties with <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, who is married to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Adkinson </PERSON>, will also perform songs she has written about her own life, including `` Conceived in Love.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0311EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MistakenIdentity     08-02 0317</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mistaken Identity,0330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Mistaken For Parole Violator</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RIVER EDGE, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A case of mistaken identity landed a man in jail on his wedding day, and it took the word of the reverend who was to preside at the service to get him out. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Carlstadt </LOCATION> said Tuesday he was riding with three friends on Route 4 about 3:15 a.m. Saturday when police stopped him at River Edge in northeastern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> because his car had a broken tail light. The officer checked <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON>'s driver's license and found it was expired. The officer then checked to see if <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON> had a record. A computer check showed a warrant for a <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON>, who was convicted in 1981 and 1986 on narcotics charges and was listed as a parole violator. The computer listed the wanted man's birthday as Aug. 15, 1962. <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON>'s expired license showed the same birthday, landing him in jail. He told police they'd made a mistake. `` They said, ` That's fine, but we need proof,''' he said. <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON>, who described himself as a `` Bible-believing Christian'' and said he taught emotionally disturbed children in <LOCATION> Edgewater </LOCATION>, spent about 45 minutes alone in a jail cell. He said he sang `` songs to the Lord.'' While police checked his story, <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON>'s friends rounded up character references for him. The police finally accepted the word of the Rev. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahairas </PERSON>, who was due to officiate at <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON>'s wedding later Saturday. He was released about 5 a.m. on his own recognizance in lieu of $ 350 bail on the suspended license charge, said Lt. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Starace </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> River </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Edge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. A hearing was set for Aug. 22. Ten hours after his release, <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON> and <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> were married in <LOCATION> Hackensack </LOCATION>. The bridegroom said he bore no malice toward police. `` The officers were very nice about the whole thing,'' <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON> said. `` They were just doing their job.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0156EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Lucas Bjt   08-02 0606</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lucas, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lucas Rejected; Could Get Civil Rights Job on Interim Basis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is weighing whether <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> could be named chief civil rights enforcer on an interim basis after his rejection by the Democrat-dominated <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. The idea was raised by <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan., on Tuesday after <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>' defeat in a pair of 7-7 votes that Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> labeled `` raw politics. A spokesman said <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> is studying whether <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> could be given a recess appointment to the job after <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' scheduled adjournment Friday. However, one White House official said President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> likely would not want to anger <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> so early in his term by defying the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> over <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>, who was criticized by opponents as being unqualified to become assistant attorney general for civil rights. No new names for the position are under consideration while the legality of the recess appointment option is being explored, said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>'s executive assistant. <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> said <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> and his top aides were surprised by the committee's action, saying they expected the nomination would be forwarded to the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> where they thought <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> would win confirmation. A recess appointment would let <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> serve until the term of the current <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> expires _ in 1990. The final decision on whether to go that route would be up to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, D-Del., <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> chairman, called the notion of a recess appointment a `` bad idea. Congressional and <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, said a recess appointment would touch off a confrontation between <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` In terms of where we go from here, we're now exploring our options,'' said presidential spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, who expressed disappointment over the vote. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said he did not know whether <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> discussed the idea of a recess appointment with the White House. `` No decisions have been made, however, about either Mr. <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>' future or how we might approach the job at the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said Seven of the <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s eight Democratic members voted against <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>, citing his lack of professional qualifications to head the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s civil rights division. Sen. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ariz </LOCATION>., joined the panel's six <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> members in voting for <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> The committee also rejected, on an identical vote, a motion by Sen. <PERSON> Strom </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-S.C. </LOCATION>, to send <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>' nomination to the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> without a committee recommendation. Opponents argue that <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>, 61, a black Detroit Republican who was sheriff and later chief executive of <LOCATION> Wayne </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, showed during his confirmation hearing that he was not familiar with civil rights law. <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>, who has never tried a court case, acknowledged during the hearing that he was `` new to the law.'' `` He's lacking in experience and qualifications, his managerial accomplishments are debatable,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Howell </PERSON> <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON>, D-Ala., who cast a crucial vote against confirmation But Republicans accused Democrats of racial hypocrisy by refusing to give <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> a chance to gain experience in the job. `` By rejecting him we are preaching one civil rights philosophy and practicing another,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Grassley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, noting that <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> would bring to the job his experience as a victim of racial discrimination. But <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> retorted that `` the greatest injustice is being done to <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> because of what I think is the apparent cynicism of this administration.'' `` <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> adds up to a perfect foil,'' <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> said, `` A decent, honorable black man who has had a successful career, who has demonstrated he knows absolutely nothing about the law. I think that is cynicism in the extreme.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0316EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SavingsCrisis     08-02 0669</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Savings Crisis,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration to Push for Greater Savings</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is planning a fall offensive to call attention to the chronically low <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> savings rate, with officials holding out the possibility that thrifty Americans will be rewarded with increased tax incentives. Treasury Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, aides said, will kick off the campaign with a series of speeches outlining the risks to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s global competitive position from low savings rates, which drive up the cost of capital for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> businesses The personal savings rate, savings as a percent of after-tax income, fell to a 40-year low of 3.2 percent in 1987 and increased only slightly to 4.2 percent last year. By contrast, the savings rate in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> was 16.5 percent in 1987. The administration is looking at a variety of possible solutions to the problem, ranging from broadening the tax savings offered by <ORGANIZATION> Individual </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retirement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounts </ORGANIZATION> to eliminating the double taxation on corporate dividends. The trouble is that such proposals to offer tax breaks to people who save would mean a tax loss of billions of dollars when the federal government is already straining to reduce huge budget deficits. But officials said it was likely that the administration would offer some changes in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tax law for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to consider. <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON>, testifying Tuesday before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, called boosting the low <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> savings rate `` the crucial issue for the long-term economic outlook of the country.'' Economists have long warned that the low personal savings rates, combined with the large federal budget deficits, were driving up interest rates in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and making it more expensive for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> businesses to borrow money needed to expand and modernize. <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON>, as he has done in the past, urged <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to make reducing the federal budget deficit a top priority. But he said lawmakers should also consider ways to boost personal savings to expand the pool of available capital. The <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> chairman noted that between the Civil War and World War I, <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> had the highest savings rate in the world, which helped supply the capital needed to transform the country into an industrial giant. While the personal savings rate had rebounded somewhat to 5.5 percent during the first six months of this year, <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> said more must be done to push the rate higher. <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> said officials at the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the president's <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisers </ORGANIZATION> were studying a variety of legislative proposals to boost savings, including the possibility of making changes in financial markets that would favor savers. <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Undersecretary <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Glauber </PERSON> said in an interview that the administration had a task force reviewing the savings issue and that one option being considered was revamping <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> accounts, which were scaled back in the 1986 tax law. Also being studied, <PERSON> Glauber </PERSON> said, are ways to eliminate the tax code inequity that makes it cheaper for corporations to borrow to finance expansions than to issue stock. If a corporation raises capital by borrowing, it can deduct its interest payments. But if it sells stock and distributes dividends on its profits, both it and the shareholders are taxed on those profits. <PERSON> Glauber </PERSON> said <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> would frame the issue in a series of speeches this fall as part of an overall need in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to focus more on long-term goals. He said the administration's push for a reduction in the capital gains rate would be included as one of the changes needed to lower the cost of capital to businesses. `` These are issues on which the secretary feels very strongly,'' <PERSON> Glauber </PERSON> said. `` He is going to map out an agenda in some detail and with some coherence.'' In a preview of the initiative two weeks ago, White House Budget Director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> called in a speech for both public and private belt-tightening to cut budget deficits, increase productivity, improve the education system and make other necessary sacrifices to `` adequately address the future.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0320EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Judge-Conflict     08-02 0504</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Judge-Conflict,0519</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Judge Reprimanded Over Conflict of Interest</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN SOLOMON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MILWAUKEE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge who was reprimanded for ruling on two <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> cases while owning <ORGANIZATION> GE </ORGANIZATION> stock said he will institute safeguards to prevent it from happening again. A judicial panel determined that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> violated the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Judicial Code of Ethics by ruling in the cases, according to documents obtained Tuesday by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The code requires judges to disqualify themselves from any case in which they have a personal or financial interest. In a letter, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bauer </PERSON>, chief judge of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> 7th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>, admonished <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> to `` increase your diligence in searching out any future possible conflicts'' but said no other action would be taken. `` Because the violation, unintended as it appears, gives an appearance of impropriety to the actions, we express our concern that they occurred,'' said <PERSON> Bauer </PERSON>, who oversees the <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION> district where <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> presides. <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> could have faced suspension or a recommendation that he be impeached, but <PERSON> Bauer </PERSON> said those penalties would have been too harsh. <PERSON> Curran </PERSON>'s rulings in the cases where he had holdings were reported by the AP on May 30. That report triggered the <ORGANIZATION> 7th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> review. The <ORGANIZATION> Judicial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> is made up of the 11 active appeals judges in the <ORGANIZATION> 7th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> and four district judges from the <ORGANIZATION> 7th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION>, which covers <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>. Upon being notified of the conflict, <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> publicly dismissed himself from the cases, an action that allows interested parties to reopen the cases. In a letter responding to the reprimand, <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> said he `` joined in the council's concern'' about the conflicts and `` instituted additional procedures and safeguards designed to prevent reoccurrence.'' <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> wrote he reviewed documents in both cases and `` I simply never connected up the defendant in each case with my investment. The responsibility and blame must rest solely on my shoulders.'' The AP discovered the conflicts by reviewing <PERSON> Curran </PERSON>'s annual financial disclosure statements and cross-referencing his stock holdings with his case files. The <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> review showed <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> has reported each year since 1985 that he has held between $ 15,000 and $ 50,000 in <ORGANIZATION> GE </ORGANIZATION> stock. He presided over unrelated cases involving <ORGANIZATION> GE </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> in 1987 and 1989. In both cases, he ruled in favor of GE. In the <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin </ORGANIZATION> based in <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>, lawyers are required to file a certificate identifying all interests in the case. Judges must then review that certificate and compare it against their financial records to make sure they do not have an interest. In one of the two <ORGANIZATION> GE </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> cases, <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> said a certificate of interest was not filed by either the defendant or plaintiff. <PERSON> Curran </PERSON>, 64, was appointed to the bench in 1983 by former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. His 1988 disclosure statement showed net investments between $ 648,030 and $ 1,740,000, generally in blue-chip stocks. His investments returned between $ 37,147 and $ 112,116 in 1988, including between $ 1,001 and $ 2,500 in GE dividends.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0320EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Wright'sDebut Bjt   08-02 0612</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wright's Debut, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former House Speaker Jim Wright Becomes `speaker'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX9</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, veteran speaker of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, it was his tryout to be speaker _ with a small `` s.'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, who resigned from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> two months ago under an ethics cloud, found himself sharing billing Tuesday night with a comic juggler, a magician, <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Benny </PERSON>'s daughter and a professional cat trainer. Such are the perils for the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Democrat who, after a few weeks of rest from the trauma of his resignation, is setting out on the lecture trail. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s first stop was the annual convention of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Platform </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, an organization of program organizers and talent bookers who arrange speakers and entertainment for colleges, corporations and trade groups. IPA officials describe their forum as similar to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Basketball </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> draft, where the best talent is shown off and shopped around. To an outside observer, it more resembles a meat market. Speakers at the convention in a downtown <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> hotel all have the same idea, says <ORGANIZATION> IPA </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyler </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>. `` They have something to say, and they want to be paid a buck for saying it.'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s message was a simple one: the honor of politics as a profession, and of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, where he served for 34 years, in particular. The 25-minute talk was punctuated with anecdotes about life on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, including <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s account of his well-meaning attempt to help a would-be <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> bride get a 48-hour leave for her serviceman fiance so the two could be married. He received a telegram of effusive thanks from the woman, and one from the groom that said: `` Why do n't you mind your own damn business?'' The IPA, after sitting through days of speeches and acts, is a tough audience. Several of the professional critics said <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> needed to punch up his routine a bit, perhaps adopting a more controversial topic. Others said he was better than expected _ for a politician. `` I think he'd be popular,'' said <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Antil </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` He's got insight into something we are all curious about. He had good emotion, use of quotations, range.'' But <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mellott </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Lorain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> near <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, said he'd be reluctant to book <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> because of the ethics controversy that forced him from office. `` He's going to be like <PERSON> Ollie </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>. He'll be big in the corporate world and the redneck world where they wave the American flag a lot,'' <PERSON> Mellot </PERSON> said. Another veteran conventioneer said <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> will be `` good for a few months because he's still sort of a hot item, but it wo n't take long for the star to fade.'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said his asking price will be $ 10,000 a speech, near the bottom of the range for top speakers these days, but five times the maximum he was allowed to accept for a speech while a member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is getting upwards of $ 50,000 per appearance, and <PERSON> North </PERSON>, convicted in the Iran-Contra scandal, is paid a reported $ 25,000 per speech. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said his goal in starting a new career as a public speaker is `` to help people understand <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> a little bit better and to awaken an interest in young people in public service.'' `` I'd like to overcome, to the degree possible, the cynicism that exists.'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> resigned after the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee charged him with 69 ethics violations, including allegedly using bulk sales of his book to evade limits on outside income, and improperly taking gifts from a developer friend who had a direct interest in legislation. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> contended he was innocent of the charges.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890802-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-02-89 0321EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NuclearCleanup     08-02 0650</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuclear Cleanup,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Energy Department Outlines Plan to Clean up Atomic Weapons Plants</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
