<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 2331EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Bush-Teamsters     01-17 0306</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Teamsters,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Meets with Teamsters Leaders</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> met Tuesday with leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brotherhood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teamsters </ORGANIZATION> to thank the union officials for their support in his election to the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, according to a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spokesman. The meeting included six Teamsters officials who are scheduled to go on trial next month as the result of a <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> civil suit accusing them of racketeering, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Wednesday editions. The brief session was held in the office of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s incoming chief of staff, said <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The meeting had not been publicly announced. `` The Teamsters people were meeting with <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> and the president-elect simply stopped by briefly. The purpose was to thank them for their support during the election campaign,'' she said. The meeting was set up by the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Teamsters </ORGANIZATION>, Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> said. The Post reported that <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> noted the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> case against the <ORGANIZATION> Teamsters </ORGANIZATION> but said any discussion of the case would be inappropriate in the meeting. Last June, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> filed suit in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, charging that the Teamsters were infiltrated by organized crime and urging a federal court to put the union under government trusteeship. The case is scheduled to go to trial Feb. 27 and the 18 defendants include <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> and others in the group who met with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON>, the Post reported. In 1981 and 1985, after the election of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had appeared at the union's board meetings during inaugural week to thank the organization for endorsing the Reagan-Bush ticket. According to the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, the meeting Tuesday was in lieu of a public appearance by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> at a Teamsters' board meeting, which union officials had sought.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 2338EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Jackson-Barry     01-17 0168</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jackson-Barry,170</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jackson Worried About Barry</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Rev. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has expressed concern for <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> Mayor <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>'s `` health and well-being'' in recent weeks, the <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said in its Wednesday's editions. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> told the newspaper he has talked and prayed privately with <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> and is seeking to counsel the embattled major. In a telephone interview Tuesday, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said his involvement is personal and not political. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> declined to defend or criticze <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>, whose latest controversy involves visits to a former city employee under a drug investigation at a downtown hotel, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said. `` I'm in no position to make a political evaluation of the current situation,'' the paper quoted <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> as saying. `` My first consideration is his health and well-being.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said he intends to visit with <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> this week while <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is here for the presidential inauguration. `` I know the burden of being under attack. I have been there,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. `` People are hurt and their families are hurt.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SchoolShooting 8thLd-Writethru a0803 01-17 1202</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-School Shooting, 8th Ld - Writethru, a0803,1230</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gunman Opens Fire At Elementary School; Kills 5, Wounds 30</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS lead and 16th graf, `Bruce Fernandes,' to clarify that
police now say all the dead and wounded were shot in schoolyard; SUBS 2nd
graf to CORRECT with police now giving gunman's age as 26, sted 24</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos SC3, SC4, STK1, STK3, STK7, STK8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVE LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>STOCKTON, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A young drifter wearing combat fatigues opened fire with an assault rifle at screaming children in an elementary school yard Tuesday. Five children, all refugees from <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, were killed and 30 people wounded before the gunman shot himself to death. The gunman, identified as <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON>, 26, originally of <PERSON> Stockton </PERSON>, had an `` extensive criminal history'' but police had `` no idea'' of a motive, said <PERSON> Lucian </PERSON> <PERSON> Neely </PERSON>, deputy police chief of this agricultural city 60 miles east of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. `` He was just standing there with a gun, making wide sweeps,'' said <PERSON> Lori </PERSON> <PERSON> Mackey </PERSON>, who teaches deaf children at the <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> and ran to her window when she heard what she thought were firecrackers. She said she saw a man standing in the schoolyard, spraying gunfire back and forth from a Russian AK-47 assault rifle as 400-500 pupils from grades 1-3 played at recess. She said when she realized what was happening, she took her 10 students into a rear room where they could n't be seen. `` He was not talking, he was not yelling, he was very straight-faced, it did not look like he was really angry, it was just matter-of-factly,'' she said of the gunman, whom she described as about 5-10 with short dirty-blond hair. `` There was mass chaos. There were kids running in every direction,'' she said. <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON>, also known as <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> West </PERSON>, had lived most recently in <LOCATION> Lodi </LOCATION>, about 15 miles northeast of here. Prior to that he lived in <LOCATION> Sandy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, where he purchased an AK-47 from the <ORGANIZATION> Sandy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trading </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> on Aug. 3., said <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON> Police Chief <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Punzel </PERSON> <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON>'s criminal record was mostly in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area and included narcotics and weapons violations and soliciting for sex, <PERSON> Neely </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Punzel </PERSON> said <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> had lived with an aunt and uncle in <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON> for several months until October and the aunt, <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>, `` told me he was a loner and as a child he was an alcoholic.'' He said <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> also had apparently been living in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> since leaving <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>. The gunman, dressed in battle gear and wearing a flak jacket, parked his car near the school, then set it on fire as a diversion before entering the campus through a gap in a fence at about 11:40 a.m. PST with two handguns and an AK-47 `` with a full banana clip,'' police said. He opened fire on the west side of a group of portable classrooms, then moved to the east side and continued firing across the blacktop yard, towards the main buildings about 250 yards away, <PERSON> Neely </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> was no closer than that when he shot himself in the head, <PERSON> Neely </PERSON> said. About 60 rounds were fired; in some cases, the bullets went completely through the main school building and came out the other side to fall spent on the L-shaped school's front lawn, <PERSON> Neely </PERSON> said. As police cleaned up the carnage, a large handgun and the AK-47 were seen lying on the ground near a pool of blood. Written on the pistol's handle was the word `` Victory.'' <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandes </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joaquin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, said five pupils were killed and 29 wounded in the schoolyard. A teacher was also shot. <PERSON> Neely </PERSON> said two of the dead children were dragged inside the school by teachers. At least 15 of the wounded were in critical condition, he said. <PERSON> Neely </PERSON> said the dead children all belonged to refugee families from <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. He identified them as Raphanar Or, 9; <PERSON> Ram </PERSON> <PERSON> Chun </PERSON>, 8; <PERSON> Thuy </PERSON> <PERSON> Tran </PERSON>, 6; Sokhim An, 6; and <PERSON> Oeun </PERSON> <PERSON> Lim </PERSON>, 8. <PERSON> Thuy </PERSON> <PERSON> Tran </PERSON> was from <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, the others from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. Officials said about 60 percent of the pupils at the school were from Southeast Asian refugee families. Three of the children were slain in the yard, and the two others inside the school, said Deputy Police Chief <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Tribble </PERSON>. He said at least one teacher was injured. `` There were a dozen students lying on the ground. It was very frightening,'' said <PERSON> Cheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, who rushed to the school where her 11-year-old daughter, <PERSON> LeAnne </PERSON> <PERSON> Sundstrom </PERSON>, is a pupil. <PERSON> Fernandes </PERSON> said the wounded were evacuated to eight hospitals in the area. Two helicopters and a fleet of ambulances were pressed into service to transport the victims. <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Billedo </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, a pupil at the school, described seeing a schoolmate shot. `` I just saw him fall down,'' said <PERSON> Billedo </PERSON>. `` His head hit the ground. The teacher grabbed him and dragged him inside the other classroom.'' `` Some kids were outside and some man came over here shooting like crazy. A few kids got shot,'' said <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON>, 10, a fifth grader. `` They were shooting at my classroom and at -LRB- <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON>'s -RRB- classroom at reading time,'' said another pupil, <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Costa </PERSON>. `` The bullets were hitting the walls. Everybody got scared.'' <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Griggs </PERSON>, visiting a friend across from the school when he heard gunfire, ran to the scene. `` When you see bodies lying on a playground, you know it's, you know ...,'' <PERSON> Griggs </PERSON> said, his voice trailing off. `` I tried to get a pulse, could n't get a pulse. I was hoping an ambulance would show up. It seemed to take forever.'' The school, about four blocks from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> campus, is in a middle-class residential area. Several churches are nearby. The AK-47 is a Russian design, but Chinese replicas are available in many gun stores for around $ 300. It is capable of firing about 600 rounds per minute on full automatic. Lt. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> described the AK-47 as a `` military assault rifle. You use it for one purpose and one purpose only _ to kill a human being.'' Under federal law, the purchase of a fully automatic rifle or machine gun requires a 4-6 month background check by authorities; however, a semiautomatic rifle can be bought over the counter by completing a standard form stating that the applicant has no criminal record, among other requirements. <PERSON> Punzel </PERSON> said that the AK-47 and other semiautomatic rifles can be easily converted into automatics. Other schools across the nation have been the targets for violent attacks in recent years. Last Sept. 26, a man walked into <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Greenwood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, and opened fire with a gun in a crowded cafeteria and in a third-grade classroom. Two 8-year-old girls died, and nine other people were wounded, including two teachers. The gunman, identified by police as <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, 19, of <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON>, was charged with murder and is awaiting trial. Last May 20, a young woman named <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> went on a rampage at <ORGANIZATION> Hubbard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Woods </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> school in <LOCATION> Winnetka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, killing an 8-year-old boy and wounding five other children. She fled to a nearby home where she wounded one man and then killed herself.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 2352EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SchoolShooting-Refugees 1stLd-Writethru   01-17 0348</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-School Shooting-Refugees, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0779,0350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Asian Translators Rushed in to Help Parents of Children in Shooting</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 5th graf, `In recent...,' to CORRECT that 60 percent of
children, sted 70 to 80 percent, are Southeast Asian</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STOCKTON, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Within hours of the schoolyard shootings that left five children and the gunman dead and 30 wounded Tuesday, dozens of translators rushed to assist the many Southeast Asian parents who arrived at the hospital desperate for word of their youngsters. `` I would imagine it is absolute panic. They are not sure what happened, not sure what's going on around them,'' said <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, of the <ORGANIZATION> Charterhouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> refugee program, in <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>, describing the scene translators found when they arrived at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joaquin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> General </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>. Many of the parents speak no English and were unable to ask whether their children were among those killed or wounded when a heavily armed gunman in combat fatigues invaded <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> and opened fire before taking his own life. `` They do have people on staff at the hospital, but they are so overloaded they need every extra person they can secure,'' said <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, whose organization began calling throughout <PERSON> Stockton </PERSON> for volunteers speaking Southeast Asian languages. About a dozen translators were sent to the county hospital, after officials there called for help. In recent years, thousands of <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asians </LOCATION> have settled in <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>, drawn in part by the farming and fishing that flourish in the area. School officials said 60 percent of the children were Southeast Asian refugees _ either from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>. All five of the children killed were of this background, authorities said. A Stockton woman who runs an after-school program teaching English to Cambodian refugees dispatched 25 translators, including volunteers from all over the city, to the school and the hospital, <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joaquin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> told <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> a grief center might be established at Charterhouse to help survivors, whose recovery will be complicated by the language barrier. Charterhouse is funded by the <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> and private donations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 2353EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Afghanistan-Soviets     01-17 0369</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Afghanistan-Soviets,0381</SECOND>
<HEAD>Diplomats Report Busy Soviet Withdrawal; Fresh Ammo for Afghans</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN WILDER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fully equipped Soviet troops left <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> by the planeload during the past week, but the aircraft also left tons of new arms and ammunition for the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government, diplomatic sources said Tuesday. Western diplomats, speaking in <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> on condition they not be identified further, said that at the current pace, the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s withdrawal could be completed by the end of the month `` However, for political reasons the Russians may wish to keep a military presence in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> up to Feb. 15,'' said one source. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> pledged in a U.N.-sponsored accord last year to remove all of its more than 100,000 combat troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in nine months from May 15, 1988. But the country's ruling Marxists still have not reached a settlement with Moslem rebels known as mujahedeen, or holy warriors, who have battled them for more than a decade. Diplomats said takeoffs and landings of Soviet IL-76 transport planes at <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> airport numbered about 40 between Jan. 9 and 14, or double the usual rate. Armed Soviet troops in full kit were seen boarding the planes but only after Afghan troops unloaded large quantities of military equipment and ammunition. As many as 18 SS-1 `` Scud'' missiles were transported from the airport during the period, according to reports from diplomats and Western journalists. Soviet armor has been digging into new positions north of the <LOCATION> Hindukush </LOCATION> mountains along the snowbound <LOCATION> Salang </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION> which runs some 240 miles from <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> north to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the sources said. They said that judging by convoys arriving in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, Soviet-Afghan forces apparently have been able to keep the route open despite harassment by the mujahedeen. Diplomats said workmen have been busy cutting down trees and leveling earth along the avenue that runs past the Afghan <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> and Soviet Embassy in southern <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. One source speculated that the work was to prepare an emergency airstrip next to the Soviet mission. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> continue to accuse <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> of violating the pullout accord by continuing to arm and supply the rebels, many of whom operate from bases in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 0005EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-YonkersFire     01-17 0270</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Yonkers Fire,0276</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yonkers Fire Claims Eighth Victim; Careless Smoking Could be Cause</HEAD>
<DATELINE>YONKERS, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The death toll rose to eight Monday in the city's worst fire in 24 years and authorities said a man smoking in bed may have caused the blaze that ravaged a three-story rooming house. <LOCATION> Yonkers </LOCATION> Fire Commissioner <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> said the house originally was a two-family dwelling, which had been illegally converted into a rooming house by its owner, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>. It was not immediately known if charges would be filed against <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>. <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> said the heaviest fire damage was in the vicinity of a cot used by the smoker, a man who was not identified. `` We're probably looking at smoking. The victim is reported to be a heavy smoker'' and drinker, <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> said. He said the man was intoxicated the night of the fire. The eighth person to die from injuries suffered in the Sunday fire was identified as <PERSON> Bernice </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahler </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Mahler </PERSON>'s husband, <PERSON> Harold </PERSON>, 77, and 45-year-old son, <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON>, died in the fire from burns and smoke inhalation, said Dr. <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Roh </PERSON>, the deputy medical examiner. He said an autopsy on Mrs. <PERSON> Mahler </PERSON> was scheduled for Tuesday. The other fire victims were identified as <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, 52, <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Prioleau </PERSON>, 61, <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, 28, and <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Isabelle </PERSON>, 30. Two of the bodies were found inside the front door. Authorities said the men had been unable to open the door because it had been locked from the inside and required a key to open. Seven people were injured in the blaze. Eleven to 15 people were living in the house, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 2359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-LoveDoctor     01-17 0346</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Love Doctor,0357</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gynecologist Offers to Surrender Certificate to Practice Medicine</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES HANNAH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DAYTON, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A gynecologist who faces charges from the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> in connection with what he calls `` love surgery'' has offered to surrender his certificate to practice medicine, his attorney said Tuesday. Lawyer <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said he and Dr. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> made the offer during a meeting with state officials in <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>. `` We offered to surrender the license and dispense with the hearing,'' said <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>. `` Whether they do that or not, I do n't know. Otherwise, we'll go ahead with the hearing.'' The board has charged the 67-year-old <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> with `` gross immorality'' for 41 alleged violations ranging from overprescribing drugs to performing unnecessary surgeries. Most of the charges against <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> have to do with the controversial surgery in which he rebuilt women's genital areas, allegedly to enhance their sexual responsiveness. The surgery, however, instead caused sexual dysfunction, emotional distress, infection, chronic pain, incontinence and the need for corrective surgery in many patients, the board charged. Last month, <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> sent a letter to the board denying the charges and requesting a hearing. The board tentatively set a Jan. 30 hearing date. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> predicted that such a hearing would last six weeks. And he said <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> has, in effect, retired anyway. `` He's not practicing any medicine at all,'' said <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>. `` We offered to surrender the certificate to practice medicine and surgery. I'm certain that he feels they will ultimately revoke his license. He feels it's a worthless cause.'' Calls to <PERSON> Burt </PERSON>'s office went unanswered, and no one answered the phone at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. Board spokeswoman <PERSON> Lauren </PERSON> <PERSON> Lubow </PERSON> has said the severest penalty the state board could impose would be permanent revocation of <PERSON> Burt </PERSON>'s license The board limited <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> to non-surgical medical practice last November. At least three of <PERSON> Burt </PERSON>'s former patients have each filed $ 3 million medical malpractice suits against the gynecologist. <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> has denied performing the surgery without his patients' permission The surgery was last performed in February 1987 at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elizabeth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nunsearch     01-17 0546</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nunsearch,0561</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thoroughly Modern Nuns Audition for Part in Hit Musical</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SONNI EFRON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 She wore black stretch pants, a sequined vest and a top hat. Sister <PERSON> Rena </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> did not look like a nun. Sister <PERSON> Brigid </PERSON> <PERSON> Riley </PERSON> looked the part in full Carmelite habit and veil. But she did n't act it: She took to center stage like a veteran performer and played snappy spoons to a bluegrass tune. Life imitated show business Monday as about a dozen real-life nuns showed up at the Charles Street Playhouse to audition for the musical `` Nunsense,'' a gentle spoof of convent life. Judging their performances was a panel of nun-impersonators, the show's regular cast. The habit-wearing actresses sing, clown and even tapdance in an off-beat comedy about nuns who stage a talent show to raise money to bury four of their sisters who died of botulism and are being temporarily stored in the convent freezer. The five real-life nuns judged most talented will each be given a cameo role in the show for one week in February or March. The producers billed the audition as `` Nunsearch'' and advertised for `` real nuns'' in Catholic and secular newspapers. They have promised to donate $ 2 from every ticket sold for the special shows to a charity chosen by the performing nun. `` We're constantly getting mail from nuns and priests who love the show,'' said co-producer <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Biller </PERSON>. `` We're doing it to raise some money for charity and also of course to get publicity.'' `` Nunsense,'' written by <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Goggin </PERSON>, has played in 30 <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> cities since its 1985 debut, <PERSON> Biller </PERSON> said. It's now playing in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, is entering its third season in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, he said. Some of the nuns who auditioned said they had dreamed of stage careers before taking the veil. `` I always wanted to go to <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>,'' said Sister <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuhrman </PERSON>, 37, who works with the elderly in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. `` But I just knew I belonged in the convent.'' `` When you get past 30, you start to say, I wish I'd done this, I wish I'd done that,'' she said. `` Even if I do n't make the part, at least I can say I auditioned for an off-Broadway show.'' Sister <PERSON> Marie </PERSON>, who confessed to sweaty palms, delivered a comic monologue while her sisters and her mother superior cheered her bravery. `` You see nuns on TV, they're such stereotypes of pious, holier than thou types, and they're such stuffed shirts and prudes,'' she said. `` We're not all that stuffy.'' Sister <PERSON> Rena </PERSON> was a professional dancer and even owned her own dance studio before entering the Sisters of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joseph </LOCATION> convent at age 28. Now grey-haired, she performed a jazz number to the tune of `` City Lights'' _ complete with shoulder rolls, high-kicks, and the splits for a finale. Sister <PERSON> Brigid </PERSON> of the Carmelite Sisters for the Aged and Infirm in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> said she decided to perform her wooden spoon routine in hopes of attracting more young women to her order. `` We are getting acolytes and novitiates, but not as many as we did,'' she said, adding that she believes that nuns' participation in a professional musical will show young women `` we're not just behind the walls doing our work. There is joy.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Opera     01-17 0569</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Opera,0594</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jessye Norman, Samuel Ramey Electrify Met</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: No PMs planned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two giant talents of the opera world, soprano <PERSON> Jessye </PERSON> <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> and bass <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramey </PERSON>, electrified a Metropolitan Opera audience, many of whom usually would be happy to stay away from one-act operas by <PERSON> Bartok </PERSON> and <PERSON> Schoenberg </PERSON>. On Monday night the two Americans sang <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> and Bluebeard, in English, in a striking, theatrical new production of <PERSON> Bartok </PERSON>'s `` Bluebeard's Castle. And Miss <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> did the entire job _ a tour de force _ in the Met's premiere of <PERSON> Schoenberg </PERSON>'s `` Erwartung,'' which can be translated `` Expectation.'' Both Miss <PERSON> Norman </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Augusta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Ramey </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Colby </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, have big voices, with beautiful, lush tone in all parts of the register. However much vocal control, breath, volume or musicianship is called for, they're equal to it and there's plenty more where that came from. Their characterizations _ as set by <PERSON> Goran </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarvefelt </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Bolinas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, making his Met debut _ were right on target. As the curtain goes up, newlyweds <PERSON> Bluebeard </PERSON> and <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> have just arrived at Bluebeard's dark castle. As <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> asks for the key to one door after another, she goes from a cheery, inquisitive girl to being imperially demanding. <PERSON> Bluebeard </PERSON> goes from pride to cringing, knowing what's coming and dreading it. As <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> opens doors and takes from him parts of his past, <PERSON> Bluebeard </PERSON> takes off parts of his garb, starting with the dark glasses that have given his white face a skeletal look, through fur collar, coat, cloak, shirt and finally wig. The remarkable set is by <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Schavernoch </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Gmunden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, making his Met debut. Side walls extend inward, meeting in a V, so that one does n't have to sit in the center to see the walls. One wall folds back, when <PERSON> Bluebeard </PERSON> shows <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> the world. The other wall has the doors, through which implements of torture, a battering ram, a big pile of gold and jewels and a tall tree appear. When the last door opens, revealing the three wives Bluebeard murdered, they appear as zombies who crawl forth and walk, silently. <PERSON> Bluebeard </PERSON> puts the cloak of death on <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> and she follows them, moving like a queen. Her red gown and cloak were magnificent. Lore <PERSON> Haas </PERSON> from <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, who has worked extensively with <PERSON> Schavernoch </PERSON>, also was making her Met debut. When `` Bluebeard's Castle'' was performed by the Met in 1974, the concept was nothing like this. It was almost a concert. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON> conducted with deliberate care. The orchestral music contains some chilling moments. Miss <PERSON> Norman </PERSON>'s singing was just as remarkable in `` Erwartung.'' But it's a letdown after the other opera. It's sung in German and the plot is impenetrable. `` The Woman'' is searching for a man in a forest. Once she finds a corpse and puts his hand on her skin to warm it. The next time she's at that part of the stage, the corpse is gone. Is she crazy? Did she kill him? Is she hallucinating? The same design team used the other opera's backdrop, plus three autumn trees, a park bench, flowers, candles and a grand piano. The only thing we objected to all evening was the piano and Miss Norman running between it and the bench. `` Erwartung'' is confusing enough. The Feb. 1 performance will be videotaped for showing March 31 on PBS.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Angola     01-17 0792</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Angola,0813</SECOND>
<HEAD>Legacy of War: Cripples and Stagnation</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSAN LINNEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KUITO, Angola (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Eight-year-old <PERSON> Domingos </PERSON> <PERSON> Casela </PERSON> was walking through a field to his family's small corn patch and stepped on a mine. <PERSON> Domingos </PERSON> and thousands like him are maimed reminders of a civil war neither side is able to win. The conflict has gripped <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> since independence from <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION> in 1975, causing stagnation and desolation in one of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s most richly endowed nations. Several months after <PERSON> Domingos </PERSON> stepped on the mine, he hobbled up a ramp at the <ORGANIZATION> Kuito-Bie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rehabilitation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> with a rubber-tipped metal rod in place of his lower left leg, undergoing physical therapy to prepare for the artificial limb he will wear the rest of his life. His doctors say the mine was planted by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> for the Total Independence of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION>. The U.S.-supported rebels are fighting a war of attrition against the Marxist government of the Angolan <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, known by its Portuguese initials <ORGANIZATION> MPLA </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> says it halted 13 years of aid to <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> after signing a U.S.-mediated accord Dec. 22 with <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> on withdrawal of the 50,000 Cuban troops in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and independence for <LOCATION> South-West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, also known as <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, which <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> has controlled since World War I. All South African troops in southern <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> moved back across the border to <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> when a truce between the two nations began Aug. 8. Dr. <PERSON> Sabino </PERSON> <PERSON> Salongue </PERSON>, director of the rehabilitation center in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>'s fertile central highlands, said most of amputees being treated were victims of mines planted by <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION>. Others lost limbs when gangrene set in because rifle wounds were poorly tended, he said. Visitors to <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> headquarters at <LOCATION> Jamba </LOCATION>, in southeastern <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, see amputees of the other side who stepped on mines planted by the Cuban-supported army to impede rebel advances. Many victims of the war are Ovimbundu, the people of central <LOCATION> Huambo </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bie </LOCATION> provinces who in 1960 were 38 percent of the 5 million living in a colony 14 times the size of <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Jonas </PERSON> <PERSON> Savimbi </PERSON>, 54, is an Ovimbundu. His father worked for the <ORGANIZATION> Caminho </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ferro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Benguela </ORGANIZATION>, the railway on which agricultural products and ores from <LOCATION> Zambia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Zaire </LOCATION> once rolled to the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> ports of <LOCATION> Benguela </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lobito </LOCATION>. Today, the <LOCATION> Cunje </LOCATION> railway station four miles outside <LOCATION> Kuito </LOCATION> is a mass of broken bricks and shards of blue-and-white Portuguese tiles, target of a <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> attack. Grass and wildflowers grow between the rails. Five huge steam locomotives built by <ORGANIZATION> Bayer </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Peacock </PERSON> and Co.. Ltd. of <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, rust on sidings with no place to go since <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> blew up the bridges between <LOCATION> Huambo </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kuito </LOCATION> <PERSON> Armando </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferreira </PERSON>, 54 years a railroader, still shows up at the yard each day. He said people on both sides are weary of war and eager for the railway to run again so their corn, bananas and millet can go to market and they can receive goods from the outside. An international conference is scheduled for Jan. 25-26 in <LOCATION> Luanda </LOCATION>, capital of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, to raise funds for a 10-year development plan in the <LOCATION> Lobito </LOCATION> corridor, including reconstruction of the <LOCATION> Benguela </LOCATION> railway. The conference is sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Africa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coodination </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. The cost of re-opening the railroad has been estimated at $ 300 - $ 600 million <PERSON> Kieran </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Cuneen </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> representative in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, fears potential donor nations may balk at committing substantial funds because the war has made it impossible to conduct a technical study in the region. He and others involved in development projects feel withdrawal of Cuban troops, which began Jan. 10 and is to be finished by mid-1991, could lead to more economic aid and development if the civil war also ends. President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> dos </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> says <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> will not negotiate with <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> and seeks diplomatic relations with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. His government has declared a year-long amnesty to begin Feb. 4, which spokesman <PERSON> Paulinho </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinto </PERSON> <PERSON> Joao </PERSON> says will be open to all renounce violence and accept the constitution. President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has written <PERSON> Savimbi </PERSON>, however, promising continued <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support until the government does negotiate with <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION>. Covert <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid to the rebels was blocked for a decade by a 1975 congressional amendment, but resumed in 1986 and is said to total about $ 15 million annually. A Western diplomat said <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s policy toward <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> was `` outdated'' and the Marxism espoused by the ruling ruling party was `` only skin deep.'' `` You'll see; this is not a Marxist nation,'' he said. `` Nearly all their trade is with the West. When the Cubans have left, then they'll get rid of the Russians.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-PLO     01-17 0908</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-PLO,0935</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Months Of Undeclared Cease-fire By PLO</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NICOLAS B. TATRO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s guerrillas have refrained from attacking Israeli targets for the past two months, observing an undeclared cease-fire that could give credibility to the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s peace initiative if it endures. Some <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials have called attention to the lack of <ORGANIZATION> Fatah </ORGANIZATION> operations but have expressed doubt about <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s ability or even desire to make it last. `` We have not identified any flagrant act on the part of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> against the security zone or <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> since <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> committed himself'' to end terrorism, said <PERSON> Uri </PERSON> <PERSON> Lubrani </PERSON>, a senior <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> official responsible for <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> policy. `` I think it is too early to judge'' if the truce would be lasting, <PERSON> Lubrani </PERSON> said on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio. Foreign Ministry Spokesman <PERSON> Alon </PERSON> <PERSON> Liel </PERSON> said in an interview it was `` not 100 percent clear'' whether the cease-fire encompassed only <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s own Fatah guerrillas or all <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> factions. There have been two recent infiltration attempts by Syrian-based groups, one headed by <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Nidal </PERSON> which is outside the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> umbrella and the other, the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, which is part of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. Israeli soldiers killed six of the guerrillas. The last attack by <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Fatah </ORGANIZATION> came on the eve of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s declaration of statehood in mid-November when a five-member <ORGANIZATION> Fatah </ORGANIZATION> squad took <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> soldiers and Lebanese civilians hostage for 18 hours The guerrillas shot to death one Lebanese man before surrendering. <PERSON> Anat </PERSON> <PERSON> Kurz </PERSON>, a terrorism expert at <ORGANIZATION> Tel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviv </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Jaffee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>, said in an interview that a cease-fire would have to be more enduring to overcome Israeli suspicion about the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. `` It will change people's mind if it lasts longer,'' she said. <PERSON> Kurz </PERSON> noted <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> had never renounced armed struggle or the right to attack targets in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> but said it was in <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s interest to suspend anti-Israeli attacks to give his initiative credibility, especially with Western countries. However, she said there were serious doubts among Israeli policymakers about whether <ORGANIZATION> Fatah </ORGANIZATION> could tolerate a long period of inaction without clear political gains. The center estimates <ORGANIZATION> Fatah </ORGANIZATION> has about 8,000 guerrillas, or half the total number of Palestinians under arms. Most are based in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. Many Israelis, especially those on the political right, view the 13-month Palestinian uprising in the occupied territories as a form of terrorism aimed at destroying <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Retired Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Shlomo </PERSON> <PERSON> Gazit </PERSON>, former head of military intelligence, said a <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> cease-fire would not be effective in dispelling Israeli doubts unless <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> specified its duration and made it comprehensive. `` For Israelis, it does n't matter which group stands behind an operation. The question that counts if whether attacks continue,'' he said in an interview. <PERSON> Gazit </PERSON> said the test of <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s credibility was whether he was willing or able to force dissident factions to observe a truce both in cross-border raids and in violent acts in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. `` If he ca n't, then he is no authority we should be talking to,'' said <PERSON> Gazit </PERSON>, noting <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> succeeded in forcing opponents to observe a military stand in 1981 along the Israel-Lebanon border. The de facto truce already has touched off a public quarrel between Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> and the armed forces chief of staff, Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Shomron </PERSON>, who appeared to challenge <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s policy by pointing out the de facto cease-fire <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> described as `` superfluous'' <PERSON> Shomron </PERSON>'s report to a parliament committee that <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Fatah </ORGANIZATION> and other guerrillas under his authority had `` in practice halted hostile operations'' as well as preparations for attacks. <PERSON> Avi </PERSON> <PERSON> Pazner </PERSON>, <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s spokesman, confirmed the prime minister disagreed with chief of staff over the issue and accused <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> of encouraging daily acts of terror. `` Mr. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> believes there is a lot of terrorism by <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> in the territories -LRB- <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> -RRB- and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> proper,'' said <PERSON> Pazner </PERSON>, noting a <ORGANIZATION> Fatah </ORGANIZATION> cell recently had been uncovered in northern <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. `` There are acts of terrorism daily in the territories and attempts in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, and Mr. <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> encourages those,'' he added. The hawkish premier has opposed any conciliatory move toward the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> in response to <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s renunciation of terrorism and acceptance of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> on Friday that the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> sought to replace <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and could not be trusted. `` I am sure there are those who understand that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> can not trust what the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> says. We know them too well,'' he said. The daily newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Davar </ORGANIZATION> said security officials told the <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> this month it was their assessment that certain <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> groups were liable to attempt to carry out border raids but not under the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s name. The purpose of such attacks would be to gauge the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> response, it said. For Israeli doves, <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s declarations have been enough to trigger calls for the government to agree to talk to the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. Four members of parliament participated in a conference in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> attended by <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> members but avoided face-to-face talks because of a 1986 Israeli laws outlawing such contacts. <PERSON> Yossi </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarid </PERSON>, a dovish lawmaker who supports negotiations with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, wrote in the liberal daily <ORGANIZATION> Haaretz </ORGANIZATION> this week that <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s change of principles was more difficult to achieve than a change in policy on attacks `` It's generally easier to change the pratical than the rhetorical. For <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> it is much easlier to stop engaging in terror than to announce its end,'' said <PERSON> Sarid </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 0120EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-InauguralSouvenirs     01-17 0560</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Inaugural Souvenirs,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Inaugural Souvenirs Range from $1,200 Crystal Eagle to $1 Buttons</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURIE ASSEO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There's something for everyone who wants a memento of the 41st president's inauguration, ranging from a $ 1,200 crystal eagle for high-rollers to commemorative buttons for a buck. The official sales booths do n't open until later this week, but souvenir stands along the Mall already are hawking sweatshirts and buttons with pictures of President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Vice President-elect <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. Tourists can get a sweatshirt for $ 12 or pay $ 5 for a `` Republican Integrity'' button with pictures of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Presidents <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>, <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>, <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. Two dollars will buy a gaudy button with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s faces atop a color photo of the last inaugural ceremony, while smaller buttons go for $ 1. Sales have been slow thus far, according to one souvenir salesman who said he hopes more people will be in the mood to buy trinkets as Friday's inaugural approaches. People bought many more souvenirs when President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> took office, another salesman said. `` When he was first elected eight years ago it was _ boom _ big market,'' said the salesman, who declined to give his name. `` Now -LRB- sales are -RRB- not even one-third of that.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s inaugural committee hopes to rake in the cash through a souvenir sales catalogue it mailed to 1.5 million Republicans, historians and collectors. People with a lot to spend can pay $ 1,195 for a <LOCATION> Steuben </LOCATION> crystal eagle `` depicting courage, splendor and freedom in many lands,'' according to the catalogue. A crystal ice bucket with the official inaugural seal goes for $ 175. The catalogue also offers commemorative coins, key rings, golf caps, umbrellas and playing cards. For $ 75, folks can wrap up in a terrycloth bathrobe with the inaugural seal. Spices for <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> chili, barbecue and gumbo sell for $ 2.50 each. T-shirts and sweatshirts celebrating the bicentennial inaugural's `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> to <PERSON> George </PERSON>'' theme _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ sell for $ 10 to $ 44.95 And, people can pay up to $ 60 for a red, white and blue inaugural auto license plate that is good until March 31. The inaugural committee also has contracted with Creative Photo Crafts of <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, to operate 21 sales booths along the inaugural parade route to sell items including mittens, chocolate bars and pennants. The first booth opens Tuesday, while two more open Thursday and the rest will operate only on inaugural day. `` It all depends on the weather,'' said <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Baltes </PERSON>, president of Creative Photo Crafts. Four years ago, the inaugural parade was canceled as temperatures dived toward zero. `` We're betting that the weather's going to be nice,'' <PERSON> Baltes </PERSON> said. His company will be selling more expensive items at some of the official inaugural events, including a $ 60 embroidered sweatshirt. The <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Postal Service is offering a different kind of souvenir _ inaugural stamp cancellations from several cities, such as <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, associated with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. For $ 4.95, post offices across the country are selling a Bicentennial Inaugural Memento with envelopes bearing the special inaugural cancellations. Otherwise, people who do n't get to come to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> this week must rely on the mail-order catalogue for their souvenirs. But <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s honeymoon with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> may be over by the time the merchandise arrives _ delivery on many items is expected to take up to 90 days.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-EssentialCivilians     01-17 0576</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Essential Civilians,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>DOD Audit Says Change Use Of Civilians In Combat-Essential Positions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Imagine going off to combat only to find the civilian technician who keeps your sophisticated weapons working is n't interested in sticking around. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s inspector general is warning of such a potential problem. The independent inspector general, in a 24-page audit that recently became available, says the Pentagon's procedures for designating and staffing `` emergency-essential'' civilian jobs overseas need to be overhauled. Those are jobs critical to making sure military equipment functions at the battlefront. Many of the jobs have been described previously as involving the maintenance of highly sophisticated electronic and computer gear. `` Our audit showed that implementation of DoD's programs to retain emergency-essential civilians did not afford a high degree of assurance that civilian or contractor employees would continue to perform functions and services overseas that are essential to the support of combat forces during mobilization or hostilities,'' the audit states. The people now holding the jobs `` were not informed fully of their commitment or about their benefits,'' the audit continues. Moreover, of 228 civilian DoD employees who were personally interviewed by auditors, `` 28 had not volunteered to remain on the job during crises or hostilities because of family responsibilities, and there was no evidence of contingency plans to replace these incumbents.'' `` We also found that 2 of the 228 emergency-essential positions -LRB- in this group -RRB- were occupied by persons not physically fit to serve in a war zone.'' On the flip side, some of the positions designated `` emergency-essential'' appear to be more `` desirable'' to have filled than essential _ meaning those civilians might be asked to stay in a war zone when they're really not needed, the auditors said. The number of people involved is relatively small, the auditors continued. Exact totals are n't available, but it appears the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> employs about 3,700 civilians overseas in jobs designated emergency essential, while contractors working for the military employ several thousand more. Nonetheless, the military services had better address the issue because legally, they're depending upon volunteers. `` Under current law, civilians can not be required to stay on jobs during mobilization, hostile action or an undeclared war,'' the auditors wrote. `` Unless and until the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> declares war, DoD and contractor civilian employees may remain in, or be sent to, unsafe areas overseas only on a voluntary basis.'' The audit states that <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> civilians assigned to emergency-essential jobs since 1985 are supposed to be volunteers who understand that if fighting breaks out, they'll be expected to remain at their post. `` And historically, DoD civilian employees and contractors have served in hostile areas in time of need,'' the inspector general said. `` However, there are no absolute assurances that a DoD civilian employee or a contractor's employee would honor a commitment to voluntarily remain on the job during hostilities.'' The inspector general recommended the services review the emergency-essential jobs to make sure they really are just that; establish physical and medical standards for the positions; explain the `` legal and administrative ramifications attendant to acceptance of the position''; and make sure every job holder knows his `` specific wartime duties.'' The auditors said the military should use soldiers to carry out any function that is essential to fighting. <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, the assistant defense secretary for personnel, responded to the audit by saying his office and the armed services `` concur in your assessment and endorse the positive recommendations.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     01-17 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Summer's Drought Makes Self Felt In Winter For Cattle Producers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's already a rough winter for those cattle producers who have to buy higher-priced hay and grain to make up for last year's drought-ravaged pastures and feed crops, according to <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> analysts. The financial bind of recent years has forced cattle producers to cut back herds and delay new expansion plans. That has reduced beef output sharply and sent prices to record levels at supermarket counters. It will get worse before improving, the analysts say. Cattle production prices are edging still higher, and so are consumer beef prices _ which could threaten to make family shoppers think about pork and chicken instead of beef. As of Dec. 1, according to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> surveys, hay stockpiles nationally totaled less than 90.9 million tons, down almost a fourth from more than 119.8 million tons a year earlier. Prices of baled hay, including alfalfa and other kinds, averaged almost $ 97 per ton last month, up from less than $ 65 in December 1987. Moreover, in some of the hardest-hit drought states hay stockpiles are a fraction of their year-ago level. In <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, for example, Dec. 1 inventories were estimated at little more than 2.3 million tons, compared with nearly 5.3 million tons a year earlier. Cattle production costs `` may rise modestly'' in 1989, says a report by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. Decisions to open up this year's feed grains programs to a larger acreage may ease the supply and price situation later on, but prospects will not be firmed up before July and August. Meanwhile, the agency said in the January-February issue of Agricultural Outlook magazine, 1989 beef production is expected to decline 5 percent to 7 percent from last year, the lowest level since 1980. However, larger supplies of poultry and pork are expected. That would leave this year's total meat supply at only slightly below the 1988 record, the report said. Even so, retail beef prices are expected to reach a record level. `` Rising consumer incomes and high employment rates likely will provide continued support for meat prices,'' the report said. `` A favorable economic environment will have to be maintained if record retail beef prices expected in 1989 are to be met with little consumer resistance.'' The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cattle inventory on Jan. 1, 1988, dropped below 100 million head for the first time since 1961, and the 1987 and 1988 calf crops also were the smallest since 1961. A new estimate on the size of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cattle herd on Jan. 1, 1989, will be issued by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> on Feb. 8, and may show a further decline, according to agency economists. The decline in 1989 beef output will be abetted by a continued slide in the slaughter of `` non-fed'' cattle, which includes culled cows and other animals that are sold without going through feedlots. `` But the biggest impact on total -LRB- beef -RRB- supplies will come from sharply reduced fed cattle slaughter,'' the report said. `` <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> feedlot marketings for 1989 could decline 6 percent to 8 percent, or about 2 million head.'' The winding down of the placement of new animals in feedlots last summer and fall `` may have set the stage for record prices next spring,'' the report said. Prices for Choice steers on the <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, market in 1989 could average near the mid - $ 70s per 100 pounds of live weight, up from $ 70 last year Retail beef prices rose an average of almost 5 percent in 1988, hitting a record peak last summer when they averaged $ 2.59 per pound, as measured on <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s all-cut basis. Further increases of 1 percent to 3 percent are likely this year. `` The higher price of beef relative to competing meats has always been a concern, but 1989 may test consumer demand for beef,'' the report said. Per capita consumption of all meat, including poultry, averaged 220.5 pounds in 1988 but could drop back to 217.4 pounds in 1989. Those are retail weights before home trimming, cooking and table waste is computed. Beef exports in 1988 rose 8 percent to an estimated 654 million pounds, carcass weight equivalent, the report said. And another increases is expected this year, mainly because of larger sales to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. Even so, this year's greater exports would represent only 2.8 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production. Imports of beef in 1988, meanwhile, totaled about 2.4 billion pounds, carcass weight, up 4 percent from 1987, but may decline this year because of smaller supplies in exporting countries, mainly <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>. The imports represent less than 9 percent of total <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> beef consumption.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 0029EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SovietTeen     01-17 0426</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet Teen,0439</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ailing Soviet Teen-Ager Seeks Treatment in Phoenix</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MEL REISNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Soviet teen-ager unable to find a cure in her native country for a heart condition she has had since birth arrived Monday for treatment and a tearful welcome from relatives she had never seen. Seventeen-year-old <PERSON> Oksana </PERSON> <PERSON> Hlebkyna </PERSON> received a traditional Ukrainian greeting _ a loaf of round, wholesome bread, garnished with a container of salt, and red and white flowers _ when she was wheeled into the <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> airport terminal. Six youngsters clad in traditional Ukrainian garb _ white blouses with intricate embroidery on the sleeves and dark skirts or trousers _ sang for Miss <PERSON> Hlebkyna </PERSON>. `` The name of the song is ` Long Live,''' said <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosola </PERSON>, 69, who arrived in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1955 along with his wife, <PERSON> Kateryna </PERSON>, the ailing young woman's great-aunt. Mrs. <PERSON> Rosola </PERSON>, relaying the teen-ager's thanks, said the trip to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was Miss <PERSON> Hlebkyna </PERSON>'s most coveted wish. Mrs. <PERSON> Rosola </PERSON> said surgeon <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Diethrich </PERSON> and administrator <PERSON> Theresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> and Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>., helped make arrangements <ORGANIZATION> Heart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Paula </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> said it was n't immediately known what doctors could do for Miss Hlebkyna `` We are not able to state what kind of medical problem she has, because we do n't know,'' Ms. <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> said. `` Most of the documents we received were in Russian, and none of us here speak Russian. Tomorrow morning, she will begin to undergo medical evaluation.'' Miss <PERSON> Hlebkyna </PERSON> and her mother, <PERSON> Wladymyra </PERSON> <PERSON> Lobkowa </PERSON>, made the trip from their hometown of <LOCATION> Stryj </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> last week and flew to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on Sunday, Ms. <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> and Air West airlines flew the pair for free, Ms. <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> said. Doctors at the AHI `` are prepared to donate their services if need be ... We are not making an issue of the financial arrangements,'' said Miss <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, the institute's director of acute intervention and transplant services. She said institute officials had been told <PERSON> Oksana </PERSON>'s condition was life-threatening and was affecting her lungs. `` From what we understand, she has a very abnormal heart disease. It's one that she's had since birth, and it's not feasible that she live with it,'' Miss <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> said. The <PERSON> Rosolas </PERSON> left the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> almost 45 years ago, captives of a German army. Mrs. <PERSON> Rosola </PERSON> said she did not learn until seven years ago of her grand-niece's heart problems. That knowledge spurred her efforts, ever more intense, to find a way to bring Miss Hlebkyna to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     01-17 0483</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0501</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OLDTOWN, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For 50 cents, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> O </PERSON>. `` Mutt'' <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> will let you drive a car across his <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> toll bridge. For $ 175,000, he'll throw in the bridge, too. <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> has been trying to sell the bridge for more than a year, but so far there have been no takers. `` I could probably tell them all they had to know about maintaining the bridge or who could do it,'' <PERSON> Walters </PERSON>, 69, said recently. `` I'm retired. I do n't need it.'' The one-lane, oak-plank bridge, 12 feet wide and 360 feet long, connects this western <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> town of 550 people with <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Spring </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION> Built in 1937, the bridge saves considerable time for Oldtown residents who commute to work in Green Spring and for West Virginians heading for <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>. The alternative is a 40-mile one-way trip via <LOCATION> Cumberland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, or Paw Paw, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION> The span is submerged several times a year under high water, but has survived more than 50 years of ice floes and floods. Bridge users drop their tolls into a tin cup bolted to a truncated barbecue skewer, which toll takers hold out the window of a little brick house on the <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> shore. Cars pay 50 cents, pedestrians a dime, motorcycles a quarter and tractor-trailers $ 1.50. Motorists can use the bridge free between 10 p.m. and 6 a.m. <PERSON> Walters </PERSON>, a retired excavator and mail carrier, had done maintenance on the bridge since 1954. In 1970, he bought it for $ 53,000. `` If somebody wanted to run it themself, they could make a good living,'' he said. `` I make $ 30,000 to $ 34,000 clear, and I do n't do nothing other than take the money to the bank.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At The Golden Bone Pet Resort, a dog's life is nothing to bark at. The dog and cat resort features two-room suites with waterbeds, standard rooms with upscale pet food, steam heat, color television and _ a favorite among guests _ two cookie breaks daily. For $ 6 extra, owner <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> offers a hot-oil dip in fragrant flea bath. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> opened The Golden Bone Pet Resort two months ago. Call it a poochie pad or a penthouse for pets, but please do n't call the resort a kennel `` We do n't like that word, kennel,'' <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said recently. `` I think it has negative connotations.'' The Golden Bone does n't have the high-end market cornered. <ORGANIZATION> Poochies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huntingdon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION> about 15 miles east of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> offers TVs, waterbeds and even person-to-pet phone service. `` We just had one woman with a cat here and she called from <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, just to make sure her cat's OK,'' said Poochies owner <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>. The cat was held to the phone so it could hear her master's voice. Room rates at <LOCATION> Poochies </LOCATION> and The Golden Bone range from $ 6 to $ 20 a day, almost double the cost of one-star kennels.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 0121EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-Pay 1stLd-Writethru a0410 01-17 0877</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Pay, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0410,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Reserves Big Bucks for Congress, Political Appointees</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 6th graf pvs, bgng: ``The 50 percent...''
to add details of pay proposal; picks up 7th graf pvs, bgng: ``Lawmakers
supporting...''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will receive a $ 45,500 pay raise this year if lawmakers follow President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s recommendations, while a recently hired government typist would bring home just $ 250 more The third-ranking official in the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> or another <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> agency would get a $ 42,500 raise, but a career federal specialist in the food stamp program would receive an increase of $ 682. And while a politically appointed agency bureau director would receive a $ 39,500 increase, a mid-level manager in the <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> system would only receive $ 1,263. The pay proposals in President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s budget are noteworthy for their disparity. There would be 50 percent increases for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, top political appointees and federal judges; 16.5 percent for many junior career executves; 3.6 percent for 2.1 million military personnel, and just 2 percent for the 2.5 million-strong <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> work force. In addition, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has proposed a one-year freeze in cost-of-living adjustments for military and civilian retirees. The 50 percent raises for 2,498 people _ lawmakers, judges and top executive branch personnel _ would go into effect on Feb. 8 unless both houses of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> defeat the proposal. House leaders have indicated there will be no vote in the chamber by the deadline, a non-action that would trigger the top raises automatically. Under the proposal, rank-and-file lawmakers' pay would rise to $ 135,000 from the current $ 89,500. Lawmakers supporting the pay raise have said if the increase goes through, they will give up the right to earn outside income, including speaking fees. Representatives of the government's <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> workers are careful not to oppose the raise for members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, because these same lawmakers must decide later whether to give federal employees more than the 2 percent <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> proposed. But they're not bashful about attacking the administration. `` What outrages me is that the people who are responsible for doing the work are ignored and insulted by the president,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tobias </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employees </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, representing 145,000 federal workers. `` It's the idea that some elitist group is solely responsible for accomplishing the mission of the federal government.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sturdivant </PERSON>, president of the largest federal employee union, the 700,000-member <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employees </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` I support the 50 percent. If you listen to some of the rhetoric and look at the folks who have come out against it, those are the same people who will be opposing pay raises for the people I represent.'' `` Taking cheap shots at high-level folks is not going to do anything for the people I represent.'' But <PERSON> Sturdivant </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is `` going out like he came in _ bashing federal employees in his budget proposal.'' <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>, said it is incorrect to compare the proposed 50 percent increase at top levels with the 2 percent for civil servants. He said that civil servants have received steady raises each year, and are only three to five percentage points behind inflation since 1969. The salaries of top officials, he said, are down 35-40 percent compared to inflation over the past 20 years. The administration is trying to let them recoup their losses all at once, he said. `` Common sense and logic do n't apply here,'' he commented. `` You reach tough personal choices where you want to send kids to college and cant afford to. This is the only government we've got and it ought to be well managed. We should n't buy executives on the cheap.'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Lafferty </PERSON>, spokesman for the government's personnel agency, the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Personnel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION>, said the president's budget is not the key to determining the <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> pay scales. More important, he said, is a government report due in August that will compare federal pay scales to those of similar jobs in the private sector. Based on that report, he said, <ORGANIZATION> OPM </ORGANIZATION> will make a recommendation to the president on a pay raise. Civil servants are paid under the `` general schedule'' -LRB- GS -RRB- scale, which has 18 different pay grades and 10 steps within most grades. The lowest grade, GS 1, begins at $ 10,213 and the highest, GS 18, has a single salary of $ 86,682. There's also a senior executive service for government managers. Some lawmakers believe congressional pay is an issue that must stand on its own. Among them is Rep. <PERSON> Augustus </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, who has been the chief congressional advocate of raising the minimum wage. `` We should judge the -LRB- congressional -RRB- raise on whether it would improve the quality of representation and lead to other reforms in ethical conduct including honoraria,'' the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Democrat said. `` I believe members should not have to vote on their own pay raise. If I were required to vote on it, I would vote in favor because I believe the responsibilities of a congressman certainly justify more than we're now paid. `` If a congressman does n't think he's worth the amount recommended, no law says he's got to take it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 0152EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--China-USPlanes     01-17 0166</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China-US Planes,0167</SECOND>
<UNK>China Buys Five McDonnell Douglas Jetliners</UNK>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s state-run airlines will buy five <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> MD-11 long-range jetliners under an agreement worth $ 500 million, the official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported today. <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, a subsidiary of the <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> CAAC </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-, will receive the first jet, a 349-set passenger model, in July next year, <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> said in a dispatch from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. The second plane, a cargo jet, will be delivered in December 1990 and the other three passenger aircraft will be delivered in 1992 and 1993. The official <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> on Monday quoted <ORGANIZATION> CAAC </ORGANIZATION> Vice President <PERSON> Xu </PERSON> <PERSON> Zhengle </PERSON> as saying the airlines purchased more than 200 airliners for about $ 3 billion over the past three years and plans to expand significantly over the next few years. The <ORGANIZATION> CAAC </ORGANIZATION> also flies <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airbus </ORGANIZATION> and Soviet aircraft on its major routes. <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> is now assembling its MD-82 model in <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> in a co-production agreement with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 0207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--France-USManeuvers     01-17 0157</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--France-US Maneuvers,0159</SECOND>
<HEAD>France, U.S. To Conduct Joint Mediterranean Maneuvers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will conduct joint air and sea maneuvers in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> during the first half of February, the <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> news agency <ORGANIZATION> Agence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> France-Presse </ORGANIZATION> reports. Quoting unidentified sources in the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>, the news agency said Monday that the French aircraft carriers <PERSON> Clemenceau </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Foch </ORGANIZATION> and the American carrier <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> are to participate in the exercise code-named <LOCATION> Phinnia </LOCATION>. The defense source told AFP the exercises have been planned since April and have no connection to the Jan. 4 downing of two Libyan MiG-23 jets by <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> planes in international waters off the Libyan coast. The number of troops to take part in the exercise and the precise date were not given, AFP said. Commandos from <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Rapid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> will also participate in the exercises, which are designed to reinforce cooperation, the defense official was quoted as saying.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Quayle     01-17 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayle Plans as VP Still Indefinite</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With only a few days remaining before he becomes vice president, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has given few clues about how he will carry out his new role, in effect telling Americans to wait and watch. Since the November election, the once-spotlighted <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has deliberately kept a low profile while President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> remained at center stage with personnel and policy pronouncements. Until the end of last week, the former <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator eschewed interviews, rebuffing reporters' attempts to learn what specific goals or projects he has in mind for his vice presidential tenure. His standard reply is that he wants to do <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s bidding and become a close adviser to the president. He told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, however, in an interview published Sunday, that he plans `` crusades'' in such areas as education, anti-drug and crime-fighting efforts, that could include personal visits to crime victims, drug users or school dropouts. Both <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> have said they want to build an easy-access relationship of the type <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> met privately with the president once a week and said that was generally the opportunity he used to relay his views and advice. But how much <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> might rely on <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s advice is an open question. His press secretary, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Beckwith </PERSON>, summed up the situation this way: `` <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> comes to the job with certain strengths but he also comes to learn and to work hard. It's not like he's 65 years old and has a wealth of experience across the board like <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had. On the other hand, he has a certain perspective that I think <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> values.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> will be chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> and wants to spend several hours a week on Capitol Hill, working as an administration advocate with his former colleagues. The energetic 41-year-old politician also is expected to work with the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, making the rounds of the speaker circuit, raising money and courting supporters. Although a favorite of conservatives, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has said he does not intend to be a mouthpiece for their interests with the more moderate <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> RNC </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodin </PERSON> contended that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> appeals to a Republican mainstream constituency beyond those who share his conservative ideology. <PERSON> Goodin </PERSON> noted that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> managed to raise several million dollars for the party through high-roller campaign events after weathering the spate of negative publicity following his nomination. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s focus in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> was on national defense, as a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, and on job issues stemming from his co-authorship of job-training legislation. But <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> spent most of the post-election period selecting his staff and meeting privately with officials and interest groups. Aides reject any notion that the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> team wanted to keep <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> under wraps, but say <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> himself set the low profile during the period when he wanted to establish his relationship with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` We've been sensitive to not try and handle him,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> transition communications director <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Demarest </PERSON>. Aides acknowledge that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has an image problem stemming from the post-Republican convention furor over his <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> service and poor grades in school. Opinion polls have shown that most Americans are doubtful about <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s competence to assume the presidency should anything happen to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s image is n't helped by the jokes perpetuated not only by late-night TV comedians, but by fellow Republicans. One was told recently by a close associate of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plans to issue Quayle bonds, the joke goes. `` There's no principle, no interest and they never mature.'' When President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> first took office in 1981, he assigned <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to head a commission on deregulating the government. With that commission's work mostly finished, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> apparently wo n't take on anything similar. In his campaign, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> initially said he would want his vice president to head administration anti-drug efforts, but <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was edged out of that responsibility by congressional legislation creating a separate cabinet-level `` drug czar'' post. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> last week named former Education Secretary <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> to the job.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 0213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     01-17 0950</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0988</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN DIEGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> made his debut as a news announcer for a radio station, and his dad marked the occasion with a congratulatory phone call. `` Good morning, <PERSON> Mike </PERSON>. This is your old man,'' President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> kiddingly told his eldest son in a call from the White House on Monday. `` I'm a little far away to hear your first program but I just wanted to congratulate you on the first day and wish you well,'' said the president, who was a radio sports announcer in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> in the 1930s. `` Well, thank you very much, dad,'' said the younger <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who was surprised and pleased by the call. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was hired by <ORGANIZATION> KSDO </ORGANIZATION> to deliver news and information during morning rush hour. He worked for the station for a month last summer on a temporary basis as a talk show host. `` The people of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> really liked him,'' said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Shields </PERSON>, the station's president and general manager. `` The name <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has a lot of magic in <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and that's because of his father.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version moved on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Retired <ORGANIZATION> NBA </ORGANIZATION> greats <PERSON> Walt </PERSON> <PERSON> Hazzard </PERSON>, <PERSON> Wali </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> DeBusschere </PERSON> did n't know what they were in for when they showed at `` The Cosby Show.'' They were enlisted by <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON> for a surprise game, and then lost to a group of women. The women, including Olympians <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lieberman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, defeated the men 83-80 in a taping Monday of the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> sitcom episode scheduled to be broadcast in March. <PERSON> Hazzard </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> were enlisted to appear as extras in a restaurant scene but then found out they were going to play some basketball. `` Just as the tape started rolling, out of the other locker room rolls the women's team,'' said <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> publicist <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Neagoy </PERSON>. `` None of the guys except <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON> knew they were going to play women. They were surprised.'' `` We did a lot more passing than the women. You appreciate passing when you get to be over 50,'' <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON> said later. <PERSON> Lieberman </PERSON> was on the'84 Olympic team and <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> won the gold in'88. Also on the women's team were <PERSON> Rhonda </PERSON> <PERSON> Rompola </PERSON>, assistant women's basketball coach at <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>; college player <PERSON> Anucha </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON> and <PERSON> Stephanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Givens </PERSON>, actress <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Givens </PERSON>' sister
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Nighthorse </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, D-Colo., went `` back to the blanket'' last weekend, an Indian phrase for returning to tribal settings <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, who has been making Indian jewelry since he was 12, was the featured artist at the Colorado Indian Market. Wearing Western attire and a white cowboy hat with beaded hatband, <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> talked to passers-by about art and politics. He markets his art under the name <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Nighthorse </PERSON>. Born to a <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> mother and a <LOCATION> Cheyenne </LOCATION> father, <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> is the only American Indian in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. He turns out 130 to 150 pieces of jewelry each year, most of them small rings and earrings, from a small workshop in his <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> apartment.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> mine sweeper once commanded by <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> is being converted into a floating museum. The 420-ton <PERSON> Bronington </PERSON> has been sold to a business consortium that intends to maintain the vessel as a museum portraying life aboard a mine sweeper, said <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> official <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sainsbury </PERSON>. The ship will be moored in <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION>, he told <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> on Monday. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, 40, who commanded the ship in 1976, sometimes suffered seasickness as a result of the ship's tendency to roll heavily. According to news reports at the time, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> was forced to use a bucket during a particularly heavy swell, then offered it to another pallid-faced officer, saying, `` Would you care to use the royal bucket?''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ANNAPOLIS, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neal </PERSON> is due to appear in court Friday for allegedly violating his probation by failing to perform 400 hours of community service. The 25-year-old son of actor <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON> was ordered to perform the community service as part of his sentence for a boating accident that killed a friend, <PERSON> Gian-Carlo </PERSON> <PERSON> Coppola </PERSON>, 23, the son of film director and producer <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> <PERSON> Coppola </PERSON>. <PERSON> O'Neal </PERSON> and <PERSON> Coppola </PERSON> were boating on the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> on Memorial Day 1986 when their 14-foot runabout struck a towline connecting two larger vessels. <PERSON> Coppola </PERSON> died of head injuries. <PERSON> O'Neal </PERSON> suffered minor injuries. The two were on a break from filming `` Gardens of Stone'' in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> O'Neal </PERSON>, who was acquitted of manslaughter but convicted on a negligent boating charge in his 1987 trial, received a 30-day suspended jail term, 1 -LCB- years probation and was ordered to perform 400 hours of community service in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, where he lives. Prosecutor <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Anders </PERSON> said <PERSON> O'Neal </PERSON> had carried out `` only a fraction'' of the community service requirement. He could face 30 days in jail for probation violation.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Rev. <PERSON> Jeb </PERSON> <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Magruder </PERSON>, who spent seven months in prison for his role in the Watergate scandal, says an honesty campaign sponsored by an ethics panel he heads is sure to raise some eyebrows. The $ 75,000 campaign, called `` Take an Honest Look,'' will begin Wednesday with billboard messages and public service advertising. `` Sure, there may be cynics,'' <PERSON> Magruder </PERSON> said. `` There always are.'' <PERSON> Magruder </PERSON>, executive minister at <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in suburban Marble Cliff, was chosen last year by Mayor <PERSON> Dana </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON> as the first chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Columbus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on Ethics and Values. <PERSON> Magruder </PERSON>, the deputy director of communications in the administration of <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> and deputy director of <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> to Re-elect the President in 1972, went to prison after he admitted destroying records and committing perjury in the Watergate scandal
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890117-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-17-89 0203EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Budget Bjt   01-17 0676</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget, Bjt,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Now, It's Bush's Turn To Shoehorn His Priorities Into A Budget</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
