<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 2331EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HazardousRiver     12-13 0515</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hazardous River,0530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mississippi River Found To Be Polluted And Deadly</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY FOSTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tons of pollution poured into the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> each year threaten to push up already-high death rates all along the river, said the authors of a report released Wednesday by the environmental group <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION>. `` We're seeing an obvious pattern,'' said <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornton </PERSON>, who wrote the report with <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Costner </PERSON>. `` The overall conclusion is that mortality rates in counties along the river are higher than in the rest of the nation and tend also to be higher than the rest of counties in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> states,'' <PERSON> Thornton </PERSON> said. The conclusions were drawn from a two-year review of data from state and federal environmental agencies, as well as from laboratory analyses conducted during a voyage down the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> by the <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> ship Beluga in 1988. Pollution was found from <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paul </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, to the mouth of the river. It was found in increasing amounts as the expedition continued downstream, the report said. The most severely elevated death rates occur downstream from areas of the greatest toxic discharges, including <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> and all riverside parishes in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, the report said. The report noted that some downstream communities, including <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, draw drinking water from the river. Average mortality rates in lower <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> counties and parishes, from <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, to the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, are 14 percent higher than the rest of the nation, researchers said. The river carries 213 million pounds of toxic chemicals per year as it passes <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, the report said. Beginning at the river's mouth, the Gulf of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> contains a 2.4 million acre dead zone which can not support aquatic life The report blamed pollution for decreasing fish and wildlife populations all along the river. River pollution comes from chemical manufacture, the use and manufacture of pesticides, pulp and paper mills, sewage treatment plants and hazardous waste disposal facilities, <PERSON> Thornton </PERSON> said. `` It's not a pretty report and the picture that it paints is not a pretty picture,'' said <PERSON> Costner </PERSON>. `` What we're seeing is evidence that it's time to change.'' <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> warned that without immediate action to reduce pollution in the river, as well as along its banks and in the air, the entire river region can expect more cancer and other problems. The <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> also released a report Tuesday showing that between 1987 and 1988, its member industries had reduced by 9.1 percent, or 89 million pounds, the chemical wastes they are required to report to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. Its members disposed of 924 million pounds of chemical wastes in 1988, the report said. <ORGANIZATION> LCA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Kleiner </PERSON> said the report does not include all wastes, only those required to be reported under federal Superfund regulations. He said the amount of wastes not reported under those regulations could not be determined. Chemical industry officials dispute the correlation between cancer rates and chemical releases, saying the statistics used by <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> have not been adjusted for other factors, such as poverty, race, urban locations and smoking and drinking.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 2332EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People-MissWestVirginia     12-13 0296</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People-Miss West Virginia,0304</SECOND>
<HEAD>Magistrate Drops Weapons Charge Against Miss West Virginia</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RAY FORMANEK Jr.</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> MORGANTOWN </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> _ A magistrate on Wednesday dropped a weapons charge against <LOCATION> Miss </LOCATION> <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Bittinger </PERSON>, citing a lack of evidence <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> County </PERSON> <PERSON> Magistrate </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said the 21-year-old beauty queen had a right to defend herself with a small-caliber handgun during her late night tussle with <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyce </PERSON>, 23. `` Now had she taken the gun out and held it on this woman or initiated the problem, that's different,'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said. `` But if someone has you by the hair, and you just momentarily bring it into view to scare them off, that's not brandishing.'' <PERSON> Boyce </PERSON> had alleged that <PERSON> Bittinger </PERSON> pulled a gun on her during a Nov. 7 scuffle on a city street after a traffic accident. <PERSON> Bittinger </PERSON>, in turn, filed a complaint accusing <PERSON> Boyce </PERSON> of reckless driving, battery and destruction of property. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> found <PERSON> Boyce </PERSON> guilty of all three counts and sentenced her to two terms of 120 days in the <LOCATION> Marion </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jail </LOCATION>, respectively, on the battery and property charges and 90 days on the driving offense. The sentences are to run concurrently. <PERSON> Boyce </PERSON> was freed on a $ 2,000 property bond that will allow her to remain free until Dec. 27. `` I wanted togive her time to enjoy her holiday,'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said. `` This whole thing was really just a cat fight.'' <PERSON> Bittinger </PERSON> said she wants to put the incident behind her. `` This was n't the first threat I've had from her and it's not the first threat I've had from other people,'' she said. `` I am afraid, but life happens you just have to deal with it.'' <PERSON> Bittinger </PERSON>, whose reign ends in June, said she plans to continue carrying a handgun for protection.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 2350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CharterRevision     12-13 0274</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Charter Revision,0281</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Justice Department Approves Revised Charter</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says it has no objection to the changes to the City Charter that were approved by voters last month. News of the approval came in a letter to <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> A.O </PERSON>. <PERSON> Schwarz </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Charter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revision </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, from Acting Assistant Attorney General <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> of the department's civil rights division `` Our work is now done,'' <PERSON> Schwarz </PERSON> said. `` The foundation has been laid for a more representative, fairer and efficient city government.'' <PERSON> Schwarz </PERSON>, a former city corporation counsel, noted that <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>'s letter `` calls particular attention to the fact that ` minority voters will likely have an increased opportunity to elect members of the enlarged and more powerful City Council.' `` Increasing minority representation in the city government was one of the <ORGANIZATION> Charter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revision </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>'s major goals,'' he said. Although <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> wrote that the department `` interposes no objection'' to the revised charter, he added that federal law allows the option of going to court in the future `` to enjoin the enforcement of these changes.'' The revised charter abolishes the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estimate </ORGANIZATION> and transfers its fiscal and planning powers to the mayor, the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> and other city officials. It also increases the size of the council from 35 to 51 members. The <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estimate </ORGANIZATION> had been declared unconstitutional because it gave equal representation to each borough despite wide disparities in population. <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Vallone </PERSON>, who has long pushed for abolition of the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estimate </ORGANIZATION> and a more equitable balance of power between the city's executive and legislative branches, also praised the department's decision.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0042EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CashingInonDroughtIII     12-13 1252</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cashing In on Drought III,1284</SECOND>
<HEAD>An AP Study: Cashing In on the Drought</HEAD>
<HEAD>Part III: In North Dakota, Aid `Kept the State Alive'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 The drought of 1988 hit hardest in the upper <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> _ perhaps nowhere harder than in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>. More disaster relief aid went there than to any other state. The third story in a four-part series, `` Cashing In on the Drought,'' examines how the $ 3.9 billion disaster aid program helped farmers most in need.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By SHARON COHEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DAVENPORT, N.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Grindberg </PERSON> survived the drought with a $ 45,000 dose of federal aid. But for this farmer and others, it was a give-and-take bailout: Take the money with one hand, give it away with the other. `` The guy who sold me $ 5,000 of fuel, he got paid,'' <PERSON> Grindberg </PERSON> said. `` The business that sold me fertilizer and spray and chemicals and tires, they got paid. What I'm saying is, the farmer got the money directly, but indirectly a lot of others benefited.'' The 1988 drought relief program poured more than $ 400 million into <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, the nation's most agriculturally dependent state. The money not only helped rescue thousands of farmers; many say it also kept the state afloat. `` It's what carried us through in 1988,'' said <LOCATION> Cass </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> extension agent <PERSON> Duane </PERSON> <PERSON> Hauck </PERSON>. `` If it had n't been for drought aid, the economic situation all through <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> would have been disastrous. It was the major source of income for most farmers.'' `` I do n't think too many farmers took disaster aid and bought Cadillacs and went on vacation in my area,'' <PERSON> Grindberg </PERSON> added. A study of the $ 3.9 billion disaster relief program, conducted by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> over seven months, found that outside the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> drought area, lax rules and requirements led to thousands of farmers collecting millions of dollars for nothing more serious than the normal trials of nature. But money did reach areas <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> most intended to aid, including <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, where it kept some farmers on their land and may have prevented some business closures. `` You might say it kept the state alive,'' said <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Selberg </PERSON>, another farmer in this <LOCATION> Red </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> county </LOCATION>. `` Everyone in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> in some way or another was helped.'' <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, where the drought evoked memories of Dust Bowl days with tumbleweed dancing along the barren horizon, received the most disaster dollars. More than 49,000 producers shared $ 410.2 million _ about 10.5 percent of the total package. Almost all was for crop loss. The state, the No. 1 producer of hard-red spring wheat, lost two-thirds of its 1988 crop; millions of normally golden acres withered to pathetic rows of shriveled brown stumps. But drought aid cut farmers' losses from $ 1.1 billion to $ 706 million, a <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dakota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> study found. Disaster payments reduced statewide losses to businesses, banks and households from $ 3.4 billion to $ 2.1 billion, the study said. Each farm dollar triples as it travels down Main Street into the economy. Another university survey of 466 farmers said that without drought aid, the average farmer's net cash income would have been just $ 6,300. Drought payments added $ 15,000. Disaster aid and crop insurance also were critical to other drought-ravaged states, including <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>. The five states together received nearly half the assistance allocated nationwide. Disaster aid and crop insurance pumped about $ 500 million into <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>'s economy, an <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> study said. `` There was no question it was needed to stave off a major new wave of bankruptcies and financial problems among Corn Belt producers,'' said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Edelman </PERSON>, a university economist. `` Even the drought assistance for most farmers fell well short of bringing what their income would be with normal yields, but it provided a safety net,'' he said. It was the same in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, which has struggled with an exodus of young, educated people, declining revenues, fading small towns and the loss of nearly a fifth of its farms this decade. `` From'81 through'86, the bottom pretty much fell out of everything,'' said <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Schulz </PERSON>, who farms about five miles from <LOCATION> Grindberg </LOCATION>. Good crops the next two years started to reverse the trend, but drought stalled the recovery. `` It has a demoralizing effect when you have a disaster,'' said <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Aakre </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> State economist. `` Financial aid helps to alleviate that. The last thing <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> needed is more negatives to push us down.'' Despite relief and nearly $ 200 million in crop insurance, the state still needs `` a good year to get back on our feet,'' <PERSON> Hauck </PERSON> said. `` We did n't get that in'89,'' he added, referring to continuing drought in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>'s west and south-central sections. In fact, while crops statewide are in better shape than 12 months ago, dollar losses will exceed 1988's estimated $ 530 million, <PERSON> Aakre </PERSON> said. Two reasons why: more acres of wheat were planted this year, and farmers do n't have grain reserves to sell at high prices as they did in 1988 to ease their burden. <PERSON> Cass </PERSON> <PERSON> County </PERSON> also had a better 1989 crop but expects higher losses in crop dollars. And while virtually all farmers here received government aid in 1988, far fewer will be eligible a second time. About $ 19.8 million in 1988 aid was divvied up among 1,847 farms in <LOCATION> Cass </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, the state's leader in crop acres. Wheat, corn, barley, soybeans, sugar beets and navy and pinto beans are grown here. Last year, production was 60 percent to 70 percent below normal. For <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Richard </PERSON>, a 36-year-old father of three who farms 1,000 acres near the town of <LOCATION> Horace </LOCATION>, $ 39,000 in aid, even coupled with $ 55,000 in crop insurance, amounted to `` just enough to break even. We were able to cover all our bills. That's all I had really hoped for.'' If that seems like a lot, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON>, who grows wheat, soybeans and barley, notes it costs him $ 150,000 for rent, interest, seed, fertilizer, equipment and other necessities. `` You throw a lot of expenses way ahead of what your crop is going to be,'' he said. `` Our investment in farming is tremendous compared to the average businessman. At least they have a commodity to sell. We might not.'' <PERSON> Schulz </PERSON>, who farms 6,000 acres, said that without his $ 100,000 maximum payment he might have been forced to sell equipment or lay off help. Along with crop insurance and the sale of grain reserves, he said, `` I was able to mark time in'88. ... Last year we had a break-even type of year. This year it was break-even. Next year, we're going to have to start coming around to a profit.'' <PERSON> Grindberg </PERSON>, who farms 900 acres of wheat, soybeans and barley, was in the red last year despite $ 70,000 in aid and insurance. His 1989 crop was better but still below normal; he expects to get only $ 3,000 in relief payments. <PERSON> Grindberg </PERSON>, a 40-year farming veteran who also delivers mail part-time, thinks the government last year `` pushed he panic button on this disaster thing and went too far. In'89, they went too far the other way I think.'' `` Disaster aid is political,'' he said. `` Depending on when you have the disaster depends on whether they sweeten the pot or not. If it's an election year ... they all get on the bandwagon.'' But <PERSON> Grindberg </PERSON> will persist. `` As long as the banker says go on,'' he said, `` next year's always the best year.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEXT: Crop Insurance _ Getting Farmers To Trust It</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0043EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Drought-Vignettes     12-13 0945</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought-Vignettes,0979</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drought Aid Recipients Varied in Crops and Need</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Cashing In on Drought III</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Not all who collected aid from the 1988 drought program were Midwestern farmers faced with ruin. Cotton farmers in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, lettuce growers in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> company that raised potatoes, all collected federal dollars _ completely legally _ even though, by their own admission, they could have weathered last year's drought. Here are some stories of aid that spilled beyond the boundaries of the 1988 drought:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Last year was n't so bad for Conowingo, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, dairyman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Dempsey </PERSON>. Good rains in July rescued his feed corn from six weeks of no rain, and milk prices were up. But when he heard about the disaster program, he went over his records with county officials. Two hours of paperwork and he was told he qualified for $ 1,200. `` Six hundred dollars an hour,'' <PERSON> Dempsey </PERSON> said with a grin as he milked his 140 Guernseys in his long, open barn. `` That's not bad pay. About the same as a lawyer.'' <PERSON> Dempsey </PERSON> makes no apologies about taking the money. `` It was there and I took advantage of it,'' he said. But he does n't favor a repeat of the program. `` It would make people say, I can put crops in the ground and if it does n't grow, I'll collect,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Chester </PERSON> <PERSON> Lathem </PERSON> and his family are what you might call diversified farmers. They run a real estate company; grow wheat, corn and milo; raise cattle; and own three oil wells that <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> operates on their <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Panhandle land. To participate in federal price support programs for their main crops of wheat, corn and milo, they have to set aside some acres. In 1988, they planted potatoes on 125 of those acres _ and saw hail wipe out the crop. Other crops did well. But the <PERSON> Lathem </PERSON> family was far from being knocked out of farming by hail on potatoes planted on excess acres. Their farm, formally named the <ORGANIZATION> Lico </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Partnership </ORGANIZATION>, received $ 134,087 under the drought program, legally exceeding the $ 100,000 single-farmer aid limit because the partnership is owned by four family members. The potatoes were insured and were expected to gross $ 223,600 for <PERSON> Lico </PERSON>, according to <PERSON> Lico </PERSON>'s file at the <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stabilization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. Insurance plus the disaster aid brought $ 214,153 _ without the expense of harvest, which <PERSON> Lathem </PERSON> said would have been two-thirds the cost of raising the potatoes. Still, he said he only broke even on the potato acreage. `` You bet it was necessary,'' <PERSON> Lathem </PERSON> said. `` We would n't have lost the farm over it, but we probably would have had to do some things differently. It would have been much tougher to go back and plant crops for the new year. I think it was a good program.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The 1987 growing year, plagued by heavy rain and high winds, was horrible for <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Chaves </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, cotton grower, but no disaster payment program existed to help him then. White got luckier in 1988, because of the record-setting drought in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>. Although he had a better crop in 1988, he was able to collect disaster aid. `` I had a cold, cold, cold rain and then that wind that comes down like on a runway and just cuts the cotton,'' said White. About half his cotton was wiped out last year, although his irrigated fields still yielded a healthy 355 pounds per acre and he made about two-thirds of his normal gross, based on government payment rates. Insurance paid $ 8,959, and drought aid approved by the local <ORGANIZATION> ASCS </ORGANIZATION> office paid $ 18,285 _ even though the disaster law included neither cold weather nor high winds.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Last year was not the luckiest for <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Race </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, who grows apples and corn in <LOCATION> Blairstown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>. A well that fed a special trickle irrigation system for some of his orchards dried up A pump that watered his corn failed at the height of the dry weather. Yet Race weathered the drought well; good production on other acres eased his losses. So he went to the county office with some trepidation to inquire about the 1988 drought relief program. He learned he was entitled to a payment, but he felt uncomfortable with government programs. `` It's kind of a personal pride thing. You think you're asking for welfare,'' he said. `` I was thinking some low interest loans of 4.5 percent, that would be great.'' Instead, he got cash, nearly $ 12,000. `` I sat and wondered, ` What am I going to do with $ 12,000?''' he said. `` I decided the best way to spend the money was to buy an irrigation pump.'' He spent $ 13,000 for a pump. Then came 1989 and its endless rains. `` It's been sitting out there, rusting ever since,'' Race, laughing, said of his new pump.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Noel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON> grows winter wheat in the harsh, arrid, wind-swept <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Panhandle </LOCATION>, the heart of what was once the Dust Bowl. In early 1988, the weather was dry in <LOCATION> Guymon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>, although nothing really out of the ordinary. Winds he estimated at 80-90 mph damaged 147.5 acres of irrigated wheat in February 1988. By harvest time, nothing was worth cutting, so he just plowed it up, he said. He did n't have insurance. Months later, unexpected help arrived in the form of the drought relief bill _ a program that had n't even been considered when the winds took his wheat. He collected $ 11,499. `` If the wheat had been good, we would have made twice that much,'' <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON> said. `` I'd rather have a big wheat crop than take a check from the government anytime.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CountyLiquor     12-13 0645</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-County Liquor,0661</SECOND>
<HEAD>Maryland County Sells Own Brand of Discount Liquor</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER BRANDLON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROCKVILLE, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When high school senior <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bergeron </PERSON> learned that <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> was selling its own brand of liquor, the local official of Students Against Drunk Driving was furious. `` How can a county, with its innumerable drug task forces and anti-drug campaigns, run liquor stores and, even worse, bottle its own brand of liquor?'' the 17-year-old wrote recently in a letter to the editor of a local newspaper. The question has grown old for county officials, who had hoped the furor over its <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION> brand would have died away by now, nearly two months after the discount brand of gin, vodka, rum, bourbon and Scotch went on sale in county-run liquor stores. Introduction of the house brand liquor brought out a flurry of news coverage and critical letters to the editors of newspapers. But county officials say they only received three critical letters and the issue has quieted. `` Let's put this in perspective, for God's sake. A private label does n't make anyone drink,'' said county liquor control director <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Baylin </PERSON>. `` All we're saying is if you choose to drink in <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, please shop here.'' <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> buys directly from producers, wholesaling beer and wine to retailers but handling sales of liquor through its own stores. County officials maintain <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION> is no different from house labels of other large liquor retailers. The house liquor is made by a <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> distillery, which bottles it in two sizes under the County Crest label. A 1.75-liter jug of <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION> ranges in price from $ 10.95 for vodka to $ 15.99 for Scotch _ $ 2 or $ 3 less than comparable brands, but more than the cheapest products. The affluent county outside <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, whose voters opted to control alcohol sales at the end of Prohibition, is the first local government in the nation to retail its own liquor, said <PERSON> Baylin </PERSON>, who is president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alcoholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beverages </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. According to the association, which represents governments that directly control the sale and distribution of liquor, 19 states purchase liquor and either sell to retailers or directly to the public, in addition to <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, where only <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> does so. County Executive <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON> said the sale of <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION> was in keeping with the county's goal of controlling liquor sales, as well as a source of extra revenue. Some of the revenue raised by the liquor control office pays for substance abuse programs, he added. According to <PERSON> Baylin </PERSON>, the liquor control office has netted $ 62 million above expenses in the past five years. He said it is too soon to know how much money the sale of house brand liquor will raise, but the products appear to be `` doing exceptionally well, thanks to the press.'' <PERSON> Bergeron </PERSON> said she was angered by the introduction of <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION> at a time when <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> officials have been pressing SADD to abandon its policy of neither condoning nor condemning teen-age drinking in favor of a `` zero tolerance'' stance. `` Basically, they are saying SADD is sending mixed messages when they themselves are doing that,'' said <PERSON> Bergeron </PERSON>, who is treasurer of the county's SADD chapter. `` I'm not going to listen to someone who's a hypocrite.'' The county government says controlling alcohol sales is better than permitting liquor stores on every corner. Neighboring Prince <PERSON> George </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, which does not have liquor control, has more than 140 liquor stores, compared with the 23 government outlets in <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Baylin </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> Bright, head of the Montgomery chapter of Mothers Against Drunk Driving, said there is nothing wrong with liquor control but thinks the county should not both regulate and participate in the liquor industry. `` We have enough brands to choose from without the county making its own,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HemsleyConvictions     12-13 0127</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hemsley Convictions,0140</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Convictions</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Helmsley</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a list of the convictions for which <PERSON> Leona </PERSON> <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> and her two co-defendants were sentenced:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Leona </PERSON> <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON>: _ Conspiracy to defraud the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> _ Three counts of tax evasion _ Three counts of filing false returns _ 16 counts of aiding and abetting the preparation of false returns _ 10 counts of mail fraud
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Turco </PERSON> and <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Licari </PERSON>: _ Conspiracy to defraud the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> _ Three counts of aiding and abetting tax evasion _ Three counts of aiding and abetting the filing of false returns _ 16 counts of aiding and abetting the preparation of false returns _ 10 counts of mail fraud
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HelmsleyQuotes     12-13 0193</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Helmsley Quotes,0201</SECOND>
<HEAD>Helmsley Quotes</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Helmsley</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Quotes from the sentencing of <PERSON> Leona </PERSON> <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON>:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON>: `` I am more humiliated and ashamed than anybody can ever imagine that I've been found guilty of a serious crime. ... I feel like I'm in the middle of a nightmare. `` A few years ago, I lost my only son. They dug up his grave and ripped me apart in the newspapers. I beg you, do n't let me lose <PERSON> Harry </PERSON>, too.'' `` Our whole life has been work and each other. Please do n't. We have nothing else. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>: `` The scheme was for your direct benefit. You bear the full responsibility for this scheme with all of its fraudulent permutations.'' `` Unlike many defendants who come before the court, you were not driven to this crime by financial greed, rather your conduct was the product of naked greed. Throughout its course, you persisted in the arrogant belief that you were above the law. Moreover, since the indictment and the trial, you have displayed no remorse or contrition at having committed the offenses in this case.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador-Countryside     12-13 0744</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador-Countryside,0762</SECOND>
<HEAD>Urban Offensive Brings Respite to Countryside</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO JAVIER, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The leftist guerrilla movement's decision to launch escalated attacks in the cities has brought relative calm to the countryside, for 10 years the civil war's principal theater. Both the guerrillas and the army have concentrated most of their fighters in or around <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and several provincial capitals since the rebels began their urban offensive Nov. 11. Areas controlled by the insurgents and government forces have not changed significantly, but the urban concentration appears to favor the rebels, whose organizational base always has been the forsaken hamlets and byways of this small Central American nation. Although fewer guerrillas are operating in the countryside, they appear to be able to move more openly and with less pressure from government forces. In <LOCATION> Usulutan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Province </LOCATION>, in the heavily fought-over eastern third of the country, the government forces that were observed generally were restricted to two paved highways and strategic population centers. During one day's travel in one region alone, no government troops were seen at all. Guerrillas, however, walked openly along trails and oxcart-rutted tracks through fields of corn, sorghum, soybeans and sesame. In <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <PERSON> Javier </PERSON>, a town of about 5,000 people, residents said rebels were coming and going almost daily, buying supplies, talking with townspeople and trying to recruit new fighters. `` They gather the young guys and ask them to accompany them to a meeting outside town,'' said the owner of a small business. `` After a couple hours they come back, except maybe one or two who decide to join.'' He, like others, said the rebels did not point their guns at the prospective recruits or otherwise coerce them. Even so, one of the few young men around said he hid every time the guerrillas came to town and almost no civilian males between 14 and 25 years old walked the streets. The rightist government of President <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> has accused the leftist <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> of `` kidnapping'' hundreds of young men in recent weeks, allegedly to replace losses suffered in the offensive. A five-man rebel squad encountered just south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> included two boys barely taller than their M-16 assault rifles. One, who appeared to be about 13, flashed a smile and V-for-victory sign. He said he had been a guerrilla for three months. The army has not completely abandoned the countryside. At the isolated hamlet of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palmo </LOCATION>, north of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> in the west-central part of the province, a 30-man search-and-destroy unit of an elite infantry battalion engaged and routed a guerrilla contingent. The soldiers of the Atonal battalion proceeded to burn or throw down a ravine large quantities of beans, salt, tortillas, fresh meat and clothing left behind by rebels. The guerrilla camp had also served as a factory for homemade catapults used as artillery, about a dozen of which were found and destroyed. In the southeastern part of the province near the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> coast, government forces were limited to a contingent of 6th army brigade troops in <LOCATION> Jucuaran </LOCATION> and a detachment of Marines on <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Espino </LOCATION> beach. Peasant farmers of the region know where the rebels are camped. After an hour of coffee sipping and conversation, a young woman excused herself and left a tile-roofed adobe house near <LOCATION> Jucuaran </LOCATION>. She returned a few minutes later to say she would take reporters to the rebel base several miles away. `` The offensive is irreversible,'' said `` <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON>,'' the khaki-clad, AK-47-toting regional commander in an interview beneath a tree beside a cow pasture. `` The war has entered a definitive phase, and nothing except deeper crisis and more instability can be expected.'' Some of the most destructive fighting of the urban offensive has been in working-class neighborhoods. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> acknowledged that taking the war to the cities may have alienated many of the same poor people the <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION> claims to champion. `` People in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> never really felt the war like people in the countryside. Their routine of home-to-work-to-home, the desire for stability came to cloud their vision and limit their ambition to being able to put up a new curtain in the kitchen,'' he said. `` We know war does not bring well-being. It's not that we see war as the solution in itself. It is a means, and it is the only option they have left us,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Czech-Economy Bjt   12-13 0815</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Czech-Economy, Bjt,0846</SECOND>
<HEAD>Political Freedom Doesn't Buy Czechs and Slovaks Western Goods</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MORT ROSENBLUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PRAGUE, Czechoslovakia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Huge crowds opposing a Communist government chanted, `` Demisi,'' meaning, resign. But some shifted the chant slightly to `` Devizy.'' That means foreign exchange. To Czechoslovaks, freedom to travel is an empty privilege without currency to spend abroad. Beyond their borders their banknotes in crowns are hardly worth anything. Once a year, Czechoslovaks are allowed to line up for days to buy a maximum of $ 23 at twice the official rate. Or they can buy any amount on the black market at nearly five times the rate. That is one crushing problem <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> faces in trying to retool a centrally planned socialist bloc economy into a prosperous system open to the world. There are a lot more. `` Basically, everything that was wrong before is still wrong,'' observed a Western economic analyst who spoke on the condition of anonymity. `` And things are getting worse.'' <PERSON> Dusan </PERSON> <PERSON> Triska </PERSON>, a senior economist in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>, agreed, adding a litany of crises that reformers will have to address. Western banks are lined up to lend money, and investors are milling in the wings. In <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, however, any economic solution hinges on social and political priorities. `` Above all,'' <PERSON> Triska </PERSON> said, `` we have to avoid mistakes made by <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. Before we open to the exterior, we have to open up inside. We ca n't use foreign resources until we can use our own.'' Until the war, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> had <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s sixth strongest economy, with heavy industry and some of the world's most advanced technology. During 40 years of Communism, plants were operated with little investment and shoddy maintenance. The once-strong infrastructure now needs billions of dollars worth of capital. The system operates at a loss, with no relation between costs and prices. Milk sells for half what it costs to produce. Bread is so cheap farmers use it for fodder. Since the 1968 Soviet-led invasion, <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> leaders have tried to offer 15 million Czechoslovaks the softest life in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in exchange for political submissiveness. There is a car for every 4.9 people. An average worker can buy one with 15 months' pay. Most Eastern Europeans wait years for delivery. Everyone has a job, and goldbricking is seldom grounds for dismissal. Workers are encouraged to spend weekends at vacation homes. Shops offer Italian kiwis and French cheeses. If veal is scarce, the lamb is excellent. Vacations are cheap for travelers who like <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION>. The system is rich ground for larceny, from petty to grand. Waiters sell caviar from the refrigerator. Doctors take tips for preferred service. Factory managers wheel and deal. Pressure was contained when lives were lived behind an Iron Curtain. Now that people want to travel and buy Western goods, the closed economy generates growing frustration. The hard part is that it must get worse before it gets better. Any new government will need a firm mandate. `` Someone will have to tell Czechoslovaks they have to work harder and earn less,'' <PERSON> Triska </PERSON> said. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> ca n't do that.'' Most likely, a Western diplomat noted, a coalition government will emerge. `` Coalitions are not famous for taking tough measures,'' he said. Economists agree that reform means massive layoffs and reduced control will send prices soaring. Subsidies have to be eliminated. And incompetent managers must be replaced. `` We will have to abolish many inefficient factories and gradually open to the international market,'' said economist <PERSON> Miroslav </PERSON> <PERSON> Slouf </PERSON>, a deputy mayor of <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>. `` Any new elected government will be unpopular within months.'' Speaking privately, Czechoslovak specialists wonder if any political leaders will be able to break up the forbidding mass of state monopolies for industries and services. One reformer, who asked not to be named, put it: `` These mafias of managers are too organized, too well protected. They do n't want change. There are so many ways to resist.'' The economy was shaped within the Soviet bloc when central planners prepared to parallel _ and outdo _ the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. The systems, though outmoded and largely discredited, remain intact. <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s largest employer is an uncompetitive steel industry. It makes its own version of three-quarters of the world's range of engineering items Unlike <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> borrowed little and kept up reserves. As other economies failed, it supplied their staples. With a touch of national pride, leaders subjected Socialist brothers to customs barriers. Czechoslovak economists agree they must avoid borrowing until loans can be put to use expanding earnings. Meantime, the economy needs `` devizy,'' hard currency. Tourism is a potential source. <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> is among <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s most beautiful cities. The countryside, in forests and mountains, is often dramatic. Other service industries are virgin ground for joint ventures. `` A lot is possible,'' <PERSON> Slouf </PERSON> said. `` But you only have to look at the experience of our neighbors. It will not be simple.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--LePen     12-13 0169</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Le Pen,0173</SECOND>
<HEAD>Extreme Rightist Politician Faces Criminal Charge</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Right-wing extremist <PERSON> Jean-Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Pen </PERSON> could face criminal prosecution for remarks linking a <ORGANIZATION> French </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> minister's name to <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> death camps. Court action is possible because the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, by a vote of 178-91 on Monday, lifted his immunity. The French <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> had asked the Parliament to remove the immunity of the leader of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> so he could be taken to court on charges of slandering a government minister. <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Pen </PERSON>, at a rally on Sept. 2, 1988, spoke of <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> Minister <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Durafour </PERSON> as `` Durafour-crematoire.'' Crematoire can be used to refer to the crematories where the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> burned the bodies of their death-camp victims. As a member of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, based in <LOCATION> Strasbourg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Pen </PERSON> has immunity from prosecution unless the legislature votes to remove it. Conviction of slandering a <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> minister is punishable by a jail sentence of up to three months and a maximum fine of $ 13,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Czech-Campaign     12-13 0447</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Czech-Campaign,0462</SECOND>
<HEAD>Opposition Organizing Frantically for Free Elections</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Czechoslovakia</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SYDNEY RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PRAGUE, Czechoslovakia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Less than a month after marching on Wenceslas Square demanding free elections, <PERSON> Lubor </PERSON> <PERSON> Spilchal </PERSON> is overseeing contributions and poster campaigns for the opposition. The pro-democracy movement, which swiftly overturned 41 years of <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> domination, now is frantically organizing for the elections it had long demanded. Spilchal is an activist with Civic Forum, the main opposition coalition, which is trying to gear up for elections without knowing exactly how they will take shape or when they will occur. On Tuesday, it was unclear how a new president would be selected. Under the constitution <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> has until Dec. 23 to elect a president to succeed <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> hard-liner <PERSON> Gustav </PERSON> <PERSON> Husak </PERSON>, who resigned Sunday. But some legislators want a referendum, with the people making the choice. There is also the question of when free parliamentary elections will be held. They are expected some time next year. The uncertainty, as political developments roar like a tidal wave across <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, has left everybody scrambling. Anything seemed possible. Civic Forum has opened an office at an art gallery near <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>'s old quarter and young volunteers are having trouble coping with the demand for information and requests to join `` We do n't have any idea how many people have signed up, it's something like 20,000 a day,'' said <PERSON> Jana </PERSON> <PERSON> Blazkova </PERSON>, handing a registration form to a suburban housewife `` We're so busy we have n't had time to count.'' The office is open from 10 a.m. to 8 p.m., `` but people are still coming long after we are closed,'' said <PERSON> Spilchal </PERSON>. `` We're having an invasion from the country, people coming from far away Nearly everyone makes a contribution.'' By midday Tuesday, <PERSON> Spilchal </PERSON> had received more than 10,000 crowns -LRB- $ 1,000 -RRB-, which was to be divided between a student strike fund, the Civic Forum and <PERSON> Vaclav </PERSON> <PERSON> Havel </PERSON>'s campaign for president. Civic Forum spokesman <PERSON> Lubos </PERSON> <PERSON> Dobrovsky </PERSON> said that in one month the Civic Forum office has collected the equivalent of more than $ 38,000, and that should cover expenses for about a month. Some money has been spent for thousands of posters supporting <PERSON> Havel </PERSON>, a playwright often jailed during Communist rule and now the main opposition candidate for president. The Svoboda print shop kept its presses rolling day and night Monday and Tuesday producing <PERSON> Havel </PERSON> posters. Crowds gathers as the posters were pasted up and some people tore them down to take home. A young girl from a town near <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> said she was `` taking a few to put up where I live. When they are gone I will come and get some more. It's hard to imagine free elections.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PhonyBackground     12-13 0255</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Phony Background,0261</SECOND>
<HEAD>Defendant Rejects 18-Month Offer, Gets 15 Year Sentence</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TAMPA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman convicted of passing bad checks pleaded for a lenient sentence by inviting the court to look at her sterling record as a scholar and a teacher. The judge did _ and found out she was also a liar. <PERSON> Jeanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON> was sentenced Monday to the maximum 15 years in prison on two bad check charges and one count of grand theft. The sentence was imposed after her last-ditch plea for leniency in which she noted that the state earlier had offered 18 months. The 32-year-old defendant claimed to have a bachelor's degree in English literature from Holy Cross, a master's degree from <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and six years' teaching at a <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Petersburg </LOCATION> high school. A presentence investigation portrayed what she had hoped _ a picture of a person who just made a mistake. But Hillsborough Circuit Judge <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bucklew </PERSON> noticed an inconsistency in the report _ while Ms. <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON> was earning her master's in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, she was serving jail time in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. The judge ordered further investigation. Ms. <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, sobbing before the bench Monday, admitted they were all lies, although she said she had been a teacher's aide. `` I lied to the court. I've lied to everybody in my life for a long time now,'' Ms. <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON> said. `` I tried to validate what everybody expected of me. There's no excuse, no justification.'' `` I would seriously doubt almost anything you tell me now,'' the judge said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0438EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--HonestCabbie     12-13 0084</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Honest Cabbie,0085</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cabbie Returns Lost Purse Containing $6,300</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman who left a purse containing $ 6,300 in the back seat of a taxi will get the money back thanks to an honest cab driver, police said. Wee Gan, 49, found the purse in his taxi on Tuesday and brought it to a police station, said Officer <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON>, a police spokesman. Police contacted the owner from papers found in the purse, <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON> said. Her name was not released.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Helmsley 1stLd-Writethru a0696 12-13 0950</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Helmsley, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0696,0975</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hotel Queen Leona Helmsley Gets 4 Years</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 9-10, `Mrs. Helmsley, wearing ...' with two grafs
to CORRECT her quote to ``I've been found guilty'' sted ``I am guilty''</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos NY30, NY39, NY40</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VERA HALLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Leona </PERSON> <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> was sentenced Tuesday to four years in prison and fined $ 7.1 million by a federal judge who ignored her sobbing plea for mercy and blamed the hotel queen's tax evasion on `` naked greed.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> also sentenced Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON>, 69, to three years of probation and 750 hours of community service at <ORGANIZATION> Hale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, a home for infants born addicted to drugs. Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> _ said to have boasted to a maid, `` We do n't pay taxes. Only the little people pay taxes.'' _ was also ordered to repay nearly $ 1.7 million in back taxes and bear the government's costs in bringing her to justice `` Your conduct was a product of naked greed. ... You believed you were above the law and displayed no remorse or contrition,'' <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> told Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON>. He said she shirked a `` moral responsibility to uphold the law'' that came with her position, breaking the law `` consciously and repeatedly.'' `` No person,'' he said, `` no matter how wealthy and prominent, stands above the law.'' <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> allowed Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> to remain free pending a decision on her appeal of her Aug. 30 conviction on 33 counts of tax evasion. Should her appeals fail and she goes to prison, she would be eligible for parole after serving a year and three months. Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> could have been sentenced to 127 years in prison if she had been given the maximum sentence for each of her convictions and been ordered to serve them consecutively, which is rare. Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON>, wearing a black dress with a gold pendant, told <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> before sentencing, `` I am more humiliated and ashamed than anybody can ever imagine that I've been found guilty of a serious crime. ... `` I feel like I'm in the middle of a nightmare,'' she said, her 80-year-old husband, <PERSON> Harry </PERSON>, sitting three rows away. `` I beg you, do n't let me lose <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> too,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> said, sobbing, her cheeks flushed and stained with tears. `` Our whole life has been work and each other. Please do n't. We have nothing else.'' But she was stone-faced as she left the courthouse with her husband. `` Four years in jail, you should have got more,'' shouted someone in a crowd of bystanders that stood by as she left. The sentiment was shared by many in the crowd who saw <PERSON> Mrs </PERSON> <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> as the embodiment of a greedy decade in which inside traders and savings and loan executives grabbed lucre and headlines. Since her indictment, Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> has been vilified in court and out. She was a high-profile target; her picture appears in nearly every ad for the <ORGANIZATION> Helmsleys </ORGANIZATION>' 27 hotels. The ad for <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Helmsley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palace </ORGANIZATION> describes it as `` the only palace in the world where the queen stands guard.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON>'s attorney described her as a `` tough bitch'' in opening arguments. The prosecutor, in his closing, described her `` selfishness, greed and sheer arrogance.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> and her husband were worth a billion dollars. But she was convicted of evading more than $ 1.2 million in federal taxes between 1983 and 1985 by billing personal expenses through the <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> business. Those expenses included construction of an elaborate, $ 1.1 million enclosure for the swimming pool at the <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON>'s 28-room mansion in <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, along with a $ 130,000 indoor-outdoor sound system Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> fancied after seeing a similar system at Disney World. There were other expenses: $ 58 for leg waxing, $ 21 for a membership in a crossword club, several purchases of lingerie and underwear. Employees who testified at her trial described her as a capricious, despotic boss who fired people on a whim. When she balked at paying a contractor who built an outdoor barbecue pit at the estate, an employee reminded her that the man had six children. He should have kept his pants on, she replied. These revelations led <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> to describe her as `` the wicked witch'' and developer <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> to call her a `` sick woman.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> told the judge that coverage of the trial had forced her and her husband to hide from the public in their house. Her attorney, <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Feffer </PERSON>, told <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> his client had become a `` lightning rod'' for hate mail, death threats and anti-Semitic remarks. `` She has been ridiculed, abused and humiliated in an unprecedented way, having nothing to do with her wrongdoing.'' He asked that her sentence be limited to community service at <ORGANIZATION> Hale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. Prosecutors asked for up to 15 years of prison time. Two employees were tried and convicted along with Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON>. Co-defendant <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Licari </PERSON> received 30 months in prison, three years probation and a $ 75,000 fine. Co-defendant <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Turco </PERSON>, another <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> employee, received a two-year term, three years probation and a $ 50,000 fine. Her husband originally was charged, but his case was dropped when it was found his mental capacity had diminished. During the two-hour proceeding Tuesday, <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> dozed; when his wife was sentenced, he watched alertly. To suggestions that <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> would be left alone if Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> was sent to prison, prosecutor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> DeVita </PERSON> replied: `` At the very least, Mr. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> knowingly acquiesced to Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON>'s insistence that these dealings be carried out. He more than anyone else had the opportunity to see these crimes were not committed and he did n't do it.'' The Helmsleys still face prosecution on charges of evading state taxes; no trial date has been set.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PlasticBoycott Bjt   12-13 0528</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Plastic Boycott, Bjt,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Environmentalists Criticize `Degradable' Plastic</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The label `` degradable'' is surfacing on plastic products from trash bags to diapers, but environmentalists call it a marketing ploy that should be rejected. Six environmental groups called Tuesday for a boycott of all degradable plastic products, contending there is no proof that the products will decompose in a landfill any faster than conventional plastics. `` Degradable plastics are a consumer ripoff,'' said <PERSON> Jeanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Wirka </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, a Washington-based environmental group. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Denison </PERSON> of the Environmental Defense Fund accused manufacturers of `` preying on the environmental concerns of American consumers'' to sell trash bags and other plastic items. `` Degradable plastics may be good for profits, but they are bad for the environment,'' <ORGANIZATION> Denison </ORGANIZATION> said. In recent months, an increasing number of degradable products _ from trash and grocery bags to diapers _ have cropped up on grocery shelves. Manufacturers contend the products made of a plastic compound will degrade in a relatively short time when left to sunlight and, in some cases, even in landfills. The products include Hefty and Glad trash bags and several brands of diapers. Some supermarkets also are increasingly using degradable plastic bags for carrying groceries home because environmentally concerned consumers shy away from conventional plastic bags. Biodegradable plastics are made by adding corn starch to the plastic polymer. <ORGANIZATION> Archer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daniels </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Midland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which manufactures the corn starch additive, maintains that its use will cause the plastic to degrade in a landfill `` within three to five years.'' `` The life of current landfills can be extended by 20 percent while achieving an operational cost savings of 30 percent,'' company vice president <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON> said recently when describing the degradable plastic product. `` They will not solve all our solid waste issues, but they have definite advantages if applied properly,'' said <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Draeger </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Degradable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plastics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, a St. Louis-based group made up largely of companies involved in the production or use of degradable plastics. The plastics industry is divided on the issue. `` Degradability is not the solution to the solid waste problem,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON>, general manager of solid waste management solutions at <ORGANIZATION> Mobil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Pittsford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mobil </ORGANIZATION>, which produces Hefty bags, turned to degradable bags because of consumer and competitive pressures, he said. `` We have found ourselves in the position of a strong consumer demand for degradable plastics'' and competitors are providing the product, <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. He said the plastic in Hefty bags will decompose faster than conventional plastic when exposed to sunlight, but responds no different from other plastic when buried. The plastic compound used by <ORGANIZATION> Mobil </ORGANIZATION> is different from the corn starch and plastic polymer mixture that makes up the degradable plastic products advertised as decomposing when buried. <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Mobil </ORGANIZATION> had no definitive proof that the corn starch mixture will decompose significantly faster in a landfill environment than conventional plastic. The groups calling for the boycott are the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, Environmental Policy Institute-Friends of the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, Public Citizen and the <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recyclable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Waste </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DefenseBudget     12-13 0461</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Budget,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrats, Republicans Signal Fray Over Defense Cuts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats and Republicans are clashing over the adequacy of defense cuts being weighed by the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, even as former <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials support larger reductions. A <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> hearing, held Tuesday to consider the depth of savings that might be found in the defense budget, offered a preview of the partisan clashes likely to dominate debate over the fiscal 1991 budget. While committee Chairman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>, D-Tenn., argued that military spending can be reduced well below current levels, ranking Republican <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> insisted that cutbacks must be deliberate and well studied <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON> said that as a result of the military buildup of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, this year's $ 285 billion <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget is $ 70 billion above the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> peacetime average since World War II, excluding the <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> war years. `` Those massive expenditures have ... diverted us from the enterprise of building a sounder, more productive domestic economy,'' he said. <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON>, however, warned that a reduction of the defense budget will have to occur slowly and will not necessarily be an economic panacea. `` Will it solve the problems relating to health care costs?'' he asked. `` Will it make our children study harder in school? Will it make Americans more productive?'' Former <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> McNamara </PERSON> and another one-time top <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> official called for military cuts surpassing those the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is considering. <PERSON> McNamara </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Korb </PERSON> sought to justify their separate proposals by citing a need to address domestic problems and react to the easing of East-West tensions. `` In the face of ... economic and social problems, it would be folly to spend more than we need for defense,'' <PERSON> McNamara </PERSON>, who served as <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> secretary under Presidents <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, told the committee. `` We are doing so.'' <PERSON> McNamara </PERSON> called for holding military spending to $ 290 billion in fiscal 1991, which begins Oct. 1, and cutting it gradually to $ 265 billion in 1994. <PERSON> Korb </PERSON>, assistant defense secretary for manpower and reserve policy from 1981 to 1985, said pressures created by the Gramm-Rudman deficit reduction law and Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s arms reduction proposals make the time right for cuts in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> defense outlays. `` There is no doubt that the combination of Gramm-Rudman-Gorbachev can and should drive the level of defense spending down by about 25 percent'' over the next five years, <PERSON> Korb </PERSON> told the lawmakers. Under his proposal, the defense budget would drop to $ 225 billion by 1995. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is studying cutting the projected rate of growth for <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spending by up to $ 180 billion over 1992 to 1994, reductions that would still leave military outlays above $ 290 billion for each of those years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HealthPlans     12-13 0493</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Health Plans,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bogus Health Plans May Leave Workers Without Benefits</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT GREENE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of workers risk being stuck with paying their own medical bills because of bogus insurance plans that the federal government allows but does n't police, authorities say. The <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s efforts to monitor so-called multiple employer welfare arrangements `` are sorely lacking or are non-existent,'' <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Donovan </PERSON> <PERSON> Petersen </PERSON>, deputy insurance commissioner in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state, told a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on legislation and national security on Tuesday. The arrangements, which pool health care coverage for small employers who ca n't get coverage from larger insurance carriers, were created under the federal Employee Retirement Income Security Act. States generally regulate insurance and require cash reserves to back claims, witnesses told the <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s subcommittee The health insurance arrangements generally do not maintain reserves to pay claims, said <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON>, acting inspector general for the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Petersen </PERSON> acknowledged that the reserve requirements would hurt many beneficial operators. `` With the expectation of staying afloat for a period of time through aggressive selling and slow claims payment, these fraudulent -LRB- arrangements -RRB- have become a variation of the classic Ponzi scheme,'' <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> said. Many operators abscond with the funds, leaving the workers high and dry, the two witnesses said. Some 5 million such arrangements exist nationwide, <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> said. The number of fraudulent ones is unknown. State enforcement agencies have been frustrated `` by multi-state fraud schemes, limited resources and historical unresponsiveness'' by the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Both <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Petersen </PERSON> said the operators try to escape state enforcement by claiming that the federal government has jurisdiction. But Ms. <PERSON> Petersen </PERSON> said her efforts to bring in the federal government bore no fruit. She said she was shuttled between the Office of Inspector General and the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pension </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welfare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Benefit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> until she finally gave up and used what state court action she could in an investigation begun in 1988. She said she could n't even get a list of operators. `` You are not required to obtain a license or certificate of authority to operate from the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION>,'' she said. She said she was investigating two operators. One ran programs known as the <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Timber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION>; and one ran a program known as the <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loggers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. By the time she obtained a state court order, the operator of <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loggers </ORGANIZATION> had left the state with the program funds and `` hundreds of consumers in some six states with thousands _ probably hundreds of thousands _ of dollars of unpaid medical claims and with no medical coverage.'' `` To date I know of no criminal, civil or other disciplinary action taken or planned by any division of the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> or any other entity,'' she said, adding that the operator, <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON>, has settled in <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> and is setting up another plan. Unpaid medical claims for the other companies total at least $ 100,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BudgetEconomics Bjt   12-13 0589</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget Economics, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Next Federal Budget Based on Optimistic Assumptions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration will base its next budget on an optimistic economic forecast showing moderate growth, lower inflation and unemployment holding steady, administration sources say. The sources, who spoke on condition that their names not be used, said the administration is expected to forecast that the economy, as measured by the gross national product, will expand by 2.6 percent next year. That GNP figure, based on growth from the fourth quarter of this year through the fourth quarter of 1990, is significantly higher than the outlook of most private economists, many of whom are looking for weak growth of around 1.9 percent next year. The administration sources said the GNP forecast has not received final approval from President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, but they said the number is unlikely to change significantly. The administration's economic outlook, which will be formally released on Jan. 22 along with its 1991 budget proposal, is prepared based on information supplied by economists at the <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisers </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The administration's last formal review of the economy, released in July, also projected economic growth of 2.6 percent for 1990. The sources said the predictions made in July on inflation and unemployment would be very close to the figures used in the next budget. In its July review, the administration forecast that inflation, as measured by the Consumer Price Index, would rise 4.1 percent in 1990 following a 5 percent increase this year. Through October, consumer prices were rising at an annual rate of 4.6 percent. The administration's July forecast predicted unemployment will average 5.4 percent in 1990. That prediction is also viewed as optimistic by many private ecoomists given the fact that the unemployment rate has already risen to 5.4 percent with higher joblessness expected in the months ahead as the current dramatic slowdown in growth spreads through the economy. While stressing that the final decision on the forecast has not been made, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Boskin </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisers </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` It is safe to say that because the economy has performed fairly closely to what we were forecasting back -LRB- in July -RRB- ... that unless something radical changes, it is unlikely that the macroeconomic assumptions would change very much.'' Through the first three quarters of this year, the economy expanded at an annual rate of 2.9 percent. But many analysts believe growth in the current quarter and the first three months of 1990 could dip perilously close to a recession. Blue Chip Economic Indicators, which surveys 51 economists every month, is predicting the economy will grow by 1.9 percent for all of 1990, far below the administration's 2.6 percent estimate. While the difference is small in percentage terms, every 1 percentage point of lower growth translates into $ 25 billion in lost revenue for the government, making it more difficult for the administration to meet its goal of reducing the deficit without raising taxes. For the current fiscal year, the deficit reduction target in the Gramm-Rudman law is $ 100 billion. For the 1991 fiscal year, which begins next Oct. 1, the deficit target is $ 64 billion. The actual deficit in the 1989 fiscal year was $ 152.1 billion. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, an economist with <ORGANIZATION> Aubrey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> G. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lanston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, said he believed weak economic growth will push the current deficit as high as $ 140 billion, pushing the 1991 target of $ 64 billion even further out of reach.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens-List     12-13 0725</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens-List,0817</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of Dec. 4-10. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 92.1 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.3 rating, 22.4 million homes. 2. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.2, 22.3 million homes. 3. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.5, 21.6 million homes. 4. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.0, 21.2 million homes. 5. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.4, 18.8 million homes. 6. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.9, 18.3 million homes. 7. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 19.5, 18.0 million homes. 8. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 18.9, 17.4 million homes. 9. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.8, 17.3 million homes. 10. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.7, 17.2 million homes. 11. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.5, 17.0 million homes. 12. -LRB- 12 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.5, 16.1 million homes. 13. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` Coach,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.4, 16.0 million homes. 14. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` In the Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.3, 15.0 million homes. 15. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.1, 14.8 million homes. 16. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.8, 14.6 million homes. 17. -LRB- 32 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 15.7, 14.5 million homes. 18. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` NFL Monday Night Football: Bills vs Seahawks,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3, 14.1 million homes. 18. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3, 14.1 million homes. 20. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` 20 @ 20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1, 13.9 million homes. 20. -LRB- 44 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1, 13.9 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 22. -LRB- 25 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.0. 23. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Howard </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>: Making The Case For Murder'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 14.9. 24. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.8. 25. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` Family Matters,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.3. 25. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS, 14.3. 27. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.1. 28. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` Knots Landing,'' CBS, 14.0. 29. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.9. 29. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` The Golden Child,'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 13.9. 29. -LRB- 20 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.9. 32. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` Midnight Caller,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.8. 33. -LRB- 32 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.6. 34. -LRB- 25 -RRB- `` Money, Power, Murder'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 13.4. 34. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4. 36. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2. 37. -LRB- 48 -RRB- `` Just The Ten Of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8. 38. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Doogie </PERSON> <PERSON> Howser </PERSON>, M.D.,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7. 39. -LRB- 41 -RRB- `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5. 40. -LRB- 46 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 12.4. 41. -LRB- 32 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 12.1. 41. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` Major Dad,'' CBS, 12.1. 43. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.8. 44. -LRB- 61 -RRB- `` Doctor, Doctor,'' CBS, 11.7. 44. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` My Two Dads - Wednesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.7. 46. -LRB- 54 -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 11.4. 47. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` Man Against Mob'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 11.3. 47. -LRB- 50 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 49. -LRB- 58 -RRB- `` True Blue,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.2. 50. -LRB- 76 -RRB- `` Totally Hidden Video,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 11.1. 51. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 11.0. 51. -LRB- 63 -RRB- `` Mancuso: <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.0. 53. -LRB- 54 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.3. 54. -LRB- 46 -RRB- `` Anything But Love,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.1. 54. -LRB- 50 -RRB- `` Rescue 911,'' CBS, 10.1. 56. -LRB- 63 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Falcon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 9.9. 56. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` Magical World of Disney,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.9. 56. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Night Before Christmas,'' CBS, 9.9. 56. -LRB- 63 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Jillian </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.9. 60. -LRB- 68 -RRB- `` Quantum Leap,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 60. -LRB- 73 -RRB- `` Sister <PERSON> Kate </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 60. -LRB- 60 -RRB- `` Baywatch,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 63. -LRB- 75 -RRB- `` Life Goes On,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.4. 64. -LRB- 52 -RRB- `` Famous Teddy Z,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.2. 64. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Bugs Bunny Christmas,'' CBS, 9.2. 67. -LRB- 56 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: Inside West Point,'' CBS, 9.0. 68. -LRB- 71 -RRB- `` Paradise,'' CBS, 8.9. 69. -LRB- 74 -RRB- `` Over The Top'' _ `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' 8.7. 70. -LRB- 77 -RRB- `` Free Spirit,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.4. 70. -LRB- 80 -RRB- `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.4. 72. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` Young Riders,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.2. 73. -LRB- 85 -RRB- `` Homeroom,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.4. 74. -LRB- 91 -RRB- `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 7.3. 74. -LRB- 84 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 7.3. 76. -LRB- 79 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> Cromwell </PERSON>'' _ `` ABC Mystery Movie,'' 7.2. 76. -LRB- 87 -RRB- `` Open House,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 7.0. 78. -LRB- 86 -RRB- `` Saturday Night With <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Chung </PERSON>,'' CBS, 7.0. 78. -LRB- 81 -RRB- `` Snoops,'' CBS, 7.0. 80. -LRB- 72 -RRB- `` Top Of <LOCATION> The </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 6.9. 81. -LRB- 87 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.7. 82. -LRB- 89 -RRB- `` Living Dolls,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.6. 83. -LRB- 92 -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.2. 84. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Koppel Report,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.4. 85. -LRB- 93 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Booker </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.3. 85. -LRB- 93 -RRB- `` Alien Nation,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.3. 87. -LRB- 95 -RRB- `` Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.8. 87. -LRB- 96 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.8. 89. -LRB- 98 -RRB- `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.1. 89. -LRB- 97 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-CentralAmerica Bjt   12-13 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Central America, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Peace Accord Greeted Skeptically by US Officials</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration officials say they doubt a new peace agreement signed by five <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> presidents will contribute to negotiated settlements to the conflicts in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said Tuesday the administration `` remains to be convinced'' that <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist government will live up to its renewed promises to carry out democratic reforms. `` We're certainly skeptical,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, speaking hours after the five presidents ended marathon discussions in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>. He said alleged Sandinista-sponsored violence at opposition campaign rallies has raised questions about the government's commitment to free and fair elections in February and its willingness to allow the safe return of Contra rebels from their Honduran base camps <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the fact that <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> agreed not to support the Marxist rebels in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> was `` encouraging.'' He added that the administration also was pleased to see the invitation for the Contras to register to vote if they do so before a Feb. 5 deadline. At the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, deputy spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> responded positively to the summit communique's comments on <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, noting that it expressed support for the country's embattled government and called on leftist rebels to cease hostilities immediately But two officials, speaking privately, said they doubted that the communique would have a significant impact on the thinking of the <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION> rebels. Sen. <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hemisphere </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee of the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said there is diminishing congressional support for Salvadoran President <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> based on the perception that he is unable to control the Salvadoran military. `` If there were a vote today on aid to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, at the least aid would be cut off,'' <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON> said. There is a widespread impression in the administration and on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> that the Salvadoran military was responsible for the massacre of six Jesuit priests a month ago. The communique calls for the demobilization of both the Contras and the <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION>. Nicaraguan President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> had asked for a Dec. 31 deadline for the dismantling of the Contras but his Central American colleagues rejected the request, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said. A member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democratic leadership, Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, D-Mich., demanded that the administration `` end all direct aid to the Contras _ all aid, of any type. `` The administration can no longer live with the fiction that it is supporting the peace process while bypassing the Central American presidents,'' said <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, who supported the $ 49 million humanitarian aid package when it came to a vote last April. When the presidents last met in <LOCATION> Tela </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, four months ago, a Dec. 5 deadline was set for dismantling the Contras but that target came and went with the rebels still intact. Most are deployed at camps in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> near the border with <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. On the issue of alleged Nicaraguan efforts to support the Salvadoran insurgency, <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> noted the communique asks that the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> accelerate the deployment of observers whose mandate it is to verify that countries do not interfere in the internal affairs of their neighbors. Other officials said the first <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> units, known by the initials <LOCATION> ONUCA </LOCATION>, have arrived in the region and that the operation should be at full strength after Christmas. Meanwhile, three <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members complained they were forced to cancel a planned trip to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> to inspect election preparations when they were told at the last minute it would take an additional 10 days to process their visas. One of the trio, Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> DeLay </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>, said other members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> seeking to visit <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> before the elections planned for February 25 also are experiencing difficulty in obtaining visas. <PERSON> DeLay </PERSON> and Reps. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Oxley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ohio </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>., attributed the delay to a desire by <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> to prevent them from observing alleged attacks by <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> supporters on political opponents
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0154EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     12-13 0407</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Comedy is King in Nielsen Ratings</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY BUCK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedy is still king in the <PERSON> Nielsen </PERSON>'s weekly ratings book as sitcoms held the top six spots. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Cosby Show'' was first again, and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne'' moved up to third place behind <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Cheers,'' according to the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> ratings for last week's prime-time shows. <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON>'s ratings, as well as his assurance he wants to do another season at <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, is good news for the first-place network. Despite published reports that <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> had sought his show, <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON> said he wanted to stay with <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. CBS had negotiated with producers <PERSON> Marcy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carsey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Werner </PERSON> for their services as programming chiefs and purchase of their company, which produces `` Cosby'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won the week survey by more than 2 ratings points. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> had an average of 14.2 to <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s 11.9 and CBS' 11.3. Each point is the percentage of the nation's 92.1 million homes with televisions tuned to a show. For the season, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> leads with a 15.0 average to <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s 13.3 and CBS' 12.2. Once again, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> placed its entire Thursday night schedule, plus two comedies from Saturday, in the top 10. Here are last week's top shows: <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Cosby Show'' and `` Cheers''; <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne''; <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` A Different World,'' `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' and `` The Golden Girls''; <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` 60 Minutes'' and `` Murder, She Wrote''; <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` L.A. Law'' and `` Empty Nest.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s plans to move `` Dear John'' from Thursday to Wednesday in early January could be bad news for the show starring <PERSON> Judd </PERSON> <PERSON> Hirsch </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> will replace it on Thursday with a new show, `` Grand,'' from the <ORGANIZATION> Carsey-Werner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> president <PERSON> Brandon </PERSON> <PERSON> Tartikoff </PERSON> said at a televised briefing for affiliate stations Monday that he felt `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>'' was strong enough to survive the move and would be compatible with `` Night Court. He defended giving the coveted Thursday spot to `` Grand,'' saying the show needed nurturing and that <ORGANIZATION> Carsey-Werner </ORGANIZATION> had done well. Three CBS Monday night comedies improved their ratings. `` Designing Women'' moved up to 18th place. `` Newhart'' was 21st and `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'' was tied for 26th. <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'s top-rated show is `` Married ... With Children'' in 47th place. However, the <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> shows are down in the ratings since their late summer surge when <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> ran original shows against network reruns. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> was first in the evening news ratings with 11.2 to <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' 10.2 and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s 9.9.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891213-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-13-89 0211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     12-13 0919</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,950</SECOND>
<HEAD>1989 Cotton Crop to be Smaller Than Previous Year</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
