<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 2339EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Bush-Baseball 2ndLd-Writethru a0780 08-04 0407</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Baseball, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0780,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING a0401 to correct writethru designation</HEAD>
<HEAD>President Goes to See Orioles-Rangers</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 4th graf pvs, The president, with final score; SUBS penultimate
graf with further color</HEAD>
<BYLINE>LaserPhoto BAB1 ^By MICHAEL SNIFFEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> took his wife <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> to Memorial Stadium Friday night to watch their eldest son's American League baseball team, the <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rangers </ORGANIZATION>, play the <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the 43 year-old <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> oilman who heads the partnership that purchased the <ORGANIZATION> Rangers </ORGANIZATION> earlier this year, and his wife <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> joined his parents behind home plate in the skybox of <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION>' owner <PERSON> Eli </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON>. Before the game, the president, baseball Commissioner <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON> <PERSON> Giamatti </PERSON> and American League President <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> visited the <ORGANIZATION> Rangers </ORGANIZATION>' and then the <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION>' locker rooms. The president and first lady left with the <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> batting in the bottom of the sixth inning and the <ORGANIZATION> Rangers </ORGANIZATION> ahead 6-2. The <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> ended up 6-4 losers. Spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> had said earlier it would be hard for the president to decide for whom to root. The <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION>, leading the American League East, have won during previous presidential visits this year. The president is a keen baseball fan who captained the 1948 <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> team and keeps his old first baseman's mitt in his desk. He came on opening day with Egyptian President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> and again on June 28 when he brought his 13-year-old grandson, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. His son's Rangers began the evening in fourth place in the American League West with a record of 57-49, two more victories than the <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> have in their weaker division. On a humid 91-degree night, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> shed his jacket and tie to watch the game in a white short-sleeved shirt. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who arrived earlier in the day from the family's vacation home at <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, wore a belted red tunic over a black skirt Their son, also in shirt sleeves, wore a blue <ORGANIZATION> Rangers </ORGANIZATION> cap. All three waved to the crowd before the game. The president and his wife drew cheers, but his son was hooted when he waved the <ORGANIZATION> Rangers </ORGANIZATION> cap. All drank large sodas; the president had peanuts and he and his wife also had corn on the cob. The president took time out to autograph some baseballs and occasionally they used binoculars to follow the action. The Bushes also were accompanied by <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> <PERSON> Willoughby </PERSON>, an usher in the White House residence.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 0028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PlaneEmergency 3rdLd-Writethru a0402 08-04 0772</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Plane Emergency, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0402,0794</SECOND>
<HEAD>Piedmont Pilot Says Not a Hero For Landing Crippled Plane</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: ADDS two grafs with report right landing gear might have been
obstructed also.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GREENSBORO, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The pilot who brought a crippled <ORGANIZATION> Piedmont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jet to a safe landing with one engine cowl scraping the ground said Thursday he's tried since to think of a better way of bringing in the plane. `` I landed that aircraft probably a thousand times last night to see if I could have done any better _ and I could n't,'' pilot <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuda </PERSON> said during a news conference Thursday at <LOCATION> Piedmont </LOCATION> Triad International Airport. Flight 1489 originated at <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> National </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> and was bound for <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, with a stop in <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>. It was diverted to <LOCATION> Greensboro </LOCATION> when the crew could n't get the left landing gear down. <PERSON> Fuda </PERSON> said he decided to go to <LOCATION> Greensboro </LOCATION> to avoid the more congested Charlotte-Douglas International Airport. <PERSON> Fuda </PERSON> said he liked the emergency equipment at <LOCATION> Greensboro </LOCATION> and knew <LOCATION> Greensboro </LOCATION>'s runway was as long as <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>'s He also knew a large contingent of <LOCATION> Piedmont </LOCATION> people were close by. <PERSON> Fuda </PERSON> set the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737-400 down on its right and nose landing gear, then settled the plane onto its left engine and skidded to a halt on the 10,000-foot runway, a shower of sparks coming from the dragging metal. `` I hardly knew that the wheel was n't there when we touched down,'' <PERSON> Fuda </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Fuda </PERSON> said he had no previous experience like Wednesday's in his 21 years of flying for <LOCATION> Piedmont </LOCATION>. `` I always wondered what I would do if it did happen,'' he said. Passengers aboard <LOCATION> Piedmont </LOCATION> Flight 1489, which made the landing at <LOCATION> Piedmont </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Triad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, said later they thought Fuda was a hero. `` There was no hysteria,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Kochan </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, a lobbyist who says he flies a lot. `` But there were a lot of trips to the bathroom.'' <PERSON> Fuda </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON>, said her husband does n't think of himself as a hero. `` He's just glad it worked out,'' she said. `` The whole crew did just what they were supposed to do. He says he does n't consider himself a hero.'' `` This time it worked out the way it was supposed to work. Sometimes the crew does the right things and things do n't work out as well,'' she said. `` He's pooped. I've been giving him kisses and hugs since he got home.'' Fuda was not originally scheduled to pilot Flight 1489, said his neighbor <PERSON> Donnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, a retired <LOCATION> Piedmont </LOCATION> pilot. `` He was supposed to work Friday night, but they're having a ` Farewell to <LOCATION> Piedmont </LOCATION>' party in <LOCATION> Roanoke </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- Friday night, and he wanted to go to that. So he just picked up a flight that somebody dropped.'' `` I'm waiting to see the pilot I picked it up from,'' <PERSON> Fuda </PERSON> said. The party is to celebrate Piedmo n't final flight on Saturday before its merger with <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> is completed _ to which <PERSON> Fuda </PERSON> made jocular reference: `` I have made my last and best landing for <LOCATION> Piedmont </LOCATION>,'' he said. The 94 passengers and six crew members safely jumped down emergency chutes. A rubber wheel chock found wedged in the wheel well had prevented the left main landing gear from deploying, said the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Piedmont </LOCATION> spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON> said Thursday it would be mere speculation to suggest that the chock, a triangular rubber block 30 inches long and 6 inches high used to keep planes from rolling when they're parked, was left in the wheel well at <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> National. `` There's really nothing else to say,'' <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON> added. `` The airplane's in the hangar, and we estimate it to be in service Saturday.'' Only the left engine housing was damaged during the landing, <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON> said. The 11-month-old plane's left wing and skin were unharmed. The plane's engine housing is designed to hold up during that type of emergency landing, he said. `` Apparently, -LRB- the wing -RRB- never touched the ground,'' he said. `` The engine itself is apparently undamaged, but we will remove it and replace it and run it through a complete structural check as well.'' <PERSON> Phillip </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> air safety investigator, said investigators found the chock wedged between two wheels on the left landing gear. While airline officials doubt the chock was deliberately placed, they declined to rule out any possibility pending further investigation, <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> in Friday editions quoted <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> as saying the right landing gear might also have been obstructed. Two bent hydraulic lines were found in the right wheel well, raising the possiblity that a chock might also have been stuck in the right landing gear and fallen out, <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 0833EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChineseOpposition     08-04 0176</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chinese Opposition,0180</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Opposition Group Plans Secret Parley in West</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group that aims to provide a democratic alternative to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> will hold its inaugural congress of 120 delegates from around the world next month, two Chinese exiles say. The congress will be held secretly in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> and will involve exiled student leaders and intellectuals, as well as individuals traveling surreptitiously from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, the exiles said. The two men are <PERSON> Wan </PERSON> <PERSON> Runnan </PERSON>, former chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Stone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a large computer company that is one of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s most successful private enterprises, and <PERSON> Yan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jiaqi </PERSON>, former member of the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> and a former close adviser to the deposed <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziyang </PERSON>. The pair made the announcement Wednesday in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>'s formation was announced in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> last month in response to the violent repression of pro-democracy forces in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> plans to serve as an umbrella organization for student groups, Chinese intellectuals and business executives inside <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and abroad.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 0901EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Hostages-Beckwith     08-04 0269</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hostages-Beckwith,0276</SECOND>
<HEAD>Leader in Failed Iran Hostage Rescue Attempt Urges Action</HEAD>
<HEAD>With US-Hostages, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PEGGY FIKAC</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AUSTIN, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should warn <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> that support of terrorism in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> will result in a military strike, said the ground force commander in the ill-fated 1980 <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> hostage rescue attempt. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also should pressure the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> to get information he has indicated the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> needs to rescue American hostages, to take a strong stand against terrorism, retired <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> Col. <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Beckwith </PERSON> said Thursday. `` If we do n't do this, it's going to keep on getting worse and worse,'' <PERSON> Beckwith </PERSON> said. Terrorists claimed they killed one American hostage, Marine Lt. Col. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>, on Monday, and have threatened to kill another, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON>, after <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> captured a Shiite Moslem religious leader accused of promoting terrorism. `` I'd like to see the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> be able to go in there and eliminate all of those terrorists and bring those beautiful hostages home,'' <PERSON> Beckwith </PERSON> said. `` I'd like to see us do it in such a vigorous way that we tell the rest of the world, ` Never fool with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> again.''' <PERSON> Beckwith </PERSON>, a security consultant, led troops in the aborted 1980 attempt to rescue American hostages being held by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. Eight Americans died in that mission. <PERSON> Beckwith </PERSON> criticized the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> as not being active enough since director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> died in 1987. The <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> relies too heavily on electronic wizardry and has forgotten about the need for `` a pair of good solid eyeballs, and a good human being on the ground,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 0903EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Fires-Glance     08-04 0257</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fires-Glance,0262</SECOND>
<HEAD>Western Wildfires at a Glance</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Fires Rdp</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a state-by-state look at wildfires burning in the West: <LOCATION> IDAHO </LOCATION>: Hundreds of lightning-caused fires have joined to form huge blazes in forests in the western and central part of the state, burning 98,000 acres by Thursday. Cool, moist weather overnight helped firefighting efforts. Although warmer weather is predicted for the weekend, fire bosses say there is little chance of the lightning that sparked many of the fires 12 days earlier. <LOCATION> OREGON </LOCATION>: Fires east of the <LOCATION> Cascades </LOCATION> have burned more than 93,000 acres. About 650 soldiers from <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lewis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, were brought in to help fight a 13,300-acre blaze in the Monument Rock Wilderness, 70 miles southwest of <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>. A 23,300-acre fire burned on the boundary of the Eagle Cap Wildneress area northwest of <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>. <LOCATION> CALIFORNIA </LOCATION>: More than 35,000 acres have burned, and the biggest active blaze was a brushfire in the <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> southeast of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. The 10,800-acre blaze was 60 percent contained, but was burning toward rough terrain three miles from the <ORGANIZATION> Palomar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observatory </ORGANIZATION>, which houses the nation's largest optical telescope. Scientists were forced to shut down the observatory Thursday for fear that ash would damage the instrument. <LOCATION> MONTANA </LOCATION>: An 800-acre blaze in the <ORGANIZATION> Custer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> was contained, but a fire on the Crow Indian Reservation southeast of Billings quickly spread to 500 acres and threatened two mountain cabins. <LOCATION> WASHINGTON </LOCATION>: Crews were mopped up an 850-acre forest fire in the Pasayten Wilderness near the Canadian border.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 0924EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Alexander-Gingrich 1stLd-Writethru a0469 08-04 0488</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Alexander-Gingrich, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0469,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Alexander Says He'll Expand Gingrich Allegations</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Top 9 grafs new with Gingrich quotes today; picks up 9th graf
pvs, The ethics panel.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House Republican Whip <PERSON> Newt </PERSON> <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> said today the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> congressman threatening to expand allegations of possible misconduct against him is `` almost irrational.'' Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> on Thursday made public a letter to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee in which he predicted his original complaint `` may have only scratched the surface.'' `` There could well be over 200 additional instances of potentially unethical, illegal or criminal conduct by Mr. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> said, declining to give reporters specific information on the allegations. `` I think in terms of the substance of the charges you have an almost irrational Democrat in <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, who is wandering around wildly saying things and I am comfortable after the ethics committee investigates it that they are going to say there is nothing to the charges,'' <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, R-Ga., said on <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Good Morning America'' program <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, who filed charges that led to the resignation of <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, as <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> speaker, said `` a number of very powerful Democrats said they were going to destroy me, that they would get even and, in that sense, of course I'm battling for my -LRB- political -RRB- life.'' In an interview Thursday with <ORGANIZATION> WAGA-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> lawmaker said: `` When you hear a politician say he has 200 hidden charges he may eventually file, you know he has a lot of baloney.'' <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> said he would n't file an expanded complaint against <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> until at least September. His April complaint to the ethics committee focused on an investment partnership formed by <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> to promote a book he wrote with his wife and another person. <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> accused <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> of possibly violating campaign finance law, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> limitations on outside income and a rule prohibiting receipt of gifts from people with a direct interest in legislation. The ethics panel has hired a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> law firm to recommend whether it should begin a formal investigation. <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> said other allegations could involve: _ The possible failure of <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> to disclose substantial, and potentially illegal, campaign contributions he made through his campaign committee during 1986 _ Information that contributors to the book promotion partnership were `` recipients of substantial federal grants and loan guarantees, including at least one major award under the politically controlled housing programs mal-administered by the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>. _ The propriety of <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>'s management of a former political action committee that may have raised hundreds of thousands of dollars for candidates, but only donated a miniscule portion of the money to those running for office _ Use of official stationery and congressional free mailing to promote the personal business endeavors of friends _ Improper settlement of personal and corporate debts incurred by <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>'s campaign committee and the possibility that <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> improperly enriched himself in a questionable real estate transaction
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 0937EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Hostages-Israel 2ndLd-Writethru a0501 08-04 0668</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hostages-Israel, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0501,0686</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israel Says It Awaits Further Word From Kidnappers on Swap</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: New throughout to UPDATE with Israel waiting Shiite response.
No pickup</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Hostages, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By G.G. LaBELLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials said today they will consider making a hostage exchange with Shiite Moslems in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> if they provide a list of prisoners they want freed from <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> jails. Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> told reporters in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> was `` waiting for proposals'' from the Shiites. ... `` We hope we will get some proposals and it will be the end of the crisis.'' <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s top aide, <PERSON> Avi </PERSON> <PERSON> Pazner </PERSON>, said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> was awaiting the specific list of prisoners whose freedom the Shiites seek. The list was promised in a statement from a militant Shiite faction in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> on Thursday night. After the faction, the <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, on Thursday suspended its threat to kill <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hostage <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON>, Defense Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> will examine the demands `` on a positive basis.'' The `` freezing'' of the death threat came just minutes before a deadline set by the group for killing <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON> unless <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> handed over the <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> clergyman it kidnapped last week from his home in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. Another Shiite Moslem faction that was holding Marine Lt. Col. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON> hostage said it killed him Monday because the clergyman, <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Karim </PERSON> <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>, was not freed by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio quoted <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> as saying <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> was moving closer to starting negotiations to free three captured <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. Israeli said it abducted <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> on July 28 hoping to swap him for the three soldiers. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has said it will also try to secure the release of 16 Western hostages, including <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON> and seven other Americans. Earlier today, <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> discussed with <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON>, Foreign Minister <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Arens </PERSON> and Finance Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> the demands made by the <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, an offshoot of the Iranian-backed <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, or Party of God. <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, who is also vice premier, was asked after a meeting with <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> whether <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> was actively involved in the process. `` I'm hopeful,'' he replied In its first statement, the <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> group demand that <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> be freed. After suspending the threat to kill <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON>, it also demanded that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> release `` a number of'' Lebanese and Palestinian prisoners. While the statement did not mention <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s offer to exchange <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> prisoners for Israeli POWs and foreign hostages, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials and commentators saw the halting of the threatened killing of <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON> as a sign the <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> radicals were ready to deal. `` If indeed there are real grounds for the report on a proposal for prisoners exchange, we shall examine it on a positive basis,'' <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> told reporters in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> Thursday night. Israeli officials noted the Shiite demands did not mention the Israeli air force navigator and two soldiers believed held by <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, and said <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON>'s statement was meant to solicit a specific response regarding them. <PERSON> Akiva </PERSON> <PERSON> Eldar </PERSON>, a leading columnist for the daily <ORGANIZATION> Haaretz </ORGANIZATION>, said <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials were not taking seriously demands to release prisoners from the 19-month Palestinian uprising, which could include more than 8,000 detainees. <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> told an American Jewish group that any negotiations would be complicated and lengthy, and an army general who managed <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s last prisoner exchange said it would take `` a long time and great patience'' to make a deal. Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Nativ </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> that the process would begin with unreasonable Shiite demands and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> would counter with insistence on first seeing the three soldiers believed held by <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> or allied factions. <PERSON> Nativ </PERSON> was in charge of negotiations that led to the exchange of three <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers for 1,000 Palestinian prisoners in a deal with the <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palestine-General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> in 1985. He said any negotiations over the 16 Western hostages would be more complicated because other countries were involved. The longest-held hostage is <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, who was kidnapped March 16, 1985.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 0943EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Ethiopia     08-04 0531</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ethiopia,0554</SECOND>
<HEAD>First Senior U.S. Official In 15 Years Visits Ethiopia</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ABEBE ANDUALEM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ADDIS ABABA, Ethiopia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first senior <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official to visit <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> since its 1974 Marxist revolution arrived today for talks on this nation's 27-year civil war and stability in the Horn of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, assistant secretary of state for <LOCATION> African </LOCATION> affairs, told reporters after arriving that he has `` a long agenda of issues'' he is prepared to discuss `` in a frank and fair manner.'' He is to spend two days in this strategic but impoverished nation that is the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s staunchest ally on the continent. That friendship with <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> soured once-warm relations between <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Addis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ababa </LOCATION> after President <PERSON> Mengistu </PERSON> <PERSON> Haile </PERSON> <PERSON> Mariam </PERSON> <PERSON> Mengistu </PERSON> and a clique of fellow military officers ousted the Emperor <PERSON> Haile </PERSON> <PERSON> Selassie </PERSON> in 1974 and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> became <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>'s biggest patron in 1977. <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> was expected to meet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Berhanu </PERSON> <PERSON> Bayih </PERSON> this afternoon and <ORGANIZATION> Mengistu </ORGANIZATION> on Saturday before leaving Sunday for <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>. He said that besides <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>'s civil war and regional conflicts he plans to discuss economic issues and the return of refugees in the region. He also was expected to discuss money the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> says <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> still owes from weapons it purchased years ago. Discussions on economic growth will be handicapped by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> laws that deny development aid to countries that owe money for arms and are accused of human rights abuses. <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>'s visit comes a day after <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> published a report charging that <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> is among the worst offenders in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> in failing to ratify international human rights covenants. The London-based organization's report said thousands of suspected political opponents in <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> are imprisoned for months or even years without trial and that many are tortured. Others vanish without explanation, it said. <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>'s concern for refugees involves hundreds of thousands who have fled wars in neighboring <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Somalia </LOCATION> and are living in refugee camps in <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>, while large numbers of Ethiopians have fled to <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION> to escape their country's northern civil war. Ethiopian refugees also remain in <LOCATION> Somalia </LOCATION>, where they fled a decade ago after Ethiopian troops backed by Soviets and Cubans repulsed a Somali invasion. The American official's visit comes after several appeals from <LOCATION> Mengistu </LOCATION> for improved relations. After he seized power, <ORGANIZATION> Mengistu </ORGANIZATION>'s government threw out the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> and closed the American government's information service <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> retaliated by suspending its technical assistance program, then the largest in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> also withdrew their ambassadors, leaving charge d'affaires to head their embassies. There was little contact until the 1984-85 famine, when the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was the biggest donor of emergency food. <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> initially was to visit <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> at the end of May but that trip was postponed by an attempted coup in <LOCATION> Addis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ababa </LOCATION>. He arrived from <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> where he met with President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> and reportedly discussed the civil wars in <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>. Guerrillas in northern <LOCATION> Eritrea </LOCATION> want independence from <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> while southern Sudanese want more autonomy. All the rebels belong to ethnic minorities. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> is the first <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official to visit <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> in the 15 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 0948EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Adams-Tankers     08-04 0227</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Adams-Tankers,230</SECOND>
<HEAD>Adams Says He Will Press Ahead With Adams Amendment on Double Hulls</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Brock </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> says he will press on with his proposal to require new oil tankers to be built with double hulls despite its narrow rejection by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. `` We were close and there is no stopping me now,'' <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, D-Wash., said Thursday following the 51-49 vote to table, and thus reject, his amendment to a pending bill tightening oil tanker safety regulations and creating a special fund to clean up oil spills <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' amendment would have required double hulls and double sides on all new tankers over 20,000 deadweight tons that operate in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> waters. It was prompted by the Exxon Valdez oil spill in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> earlier this year, which <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said might not have grown into the nation's largest oil spill ever if the vessel had been equipped with a double hull. The pending bill would require that the secretary of transportation study for one year the use of double hulls and require them in new tankers unless it is found they wo n't enhance tanker safety, or other structural requirements were found to be better. `` None of us are naval architects,'' said Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Breaux </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>., who moved to table <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' amendment `` I do n't think we are absolutely competent to make a final decision.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 1025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-China 1stLd-Writethru   08-04 0717</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0507,0733</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Strips Fang of Titles, But Says It Won't Jail Intellectuals</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: New throughout to UPDATE with Fang Lizhi fired from academic
post, government declining comment on report that Deng seriously ill.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELAINE KURTENBACH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> said today that its crackdown on dissent will not endanger intellectuals, but it also announced that a prominent dissident holed up in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> has been fired from an academic board. Also today, the government declined to comment on a report that senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> is seriously ill with prostate cancer. The official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> office described the report as a mere rumor. An unsigned commentary in the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> newspaper <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> said <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> will continue to respect its intellectuals' knowledge and talent, even though some participated in the recent pro-democracy movement that the government calls a `` counter-revolutionary rebellion `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> needs a strong intellectual force for modernization. ... We should thoroughly implement <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>'s policy to ` respect knowledge, respect talent' and use intellectuals to achieve the modernization goal,'' it said. The crackdown ended a period of relatively free political debate. Chinese now are urged to report on friends and family and must participate in political study sessions reminiscent of the ultra-leftist 1966-76 Cultural Revolution. The commentary called those who took part in the student movement `` scum'' and `` enemies of the party and of the people.'' It said, `` It is in the interest of the workers, peasants and intellectuals to punish them.'' `` Those who were under the influence of the wave of bourgeois liberalism ... will elevate their understanding and continue to make contributions'' to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s modernization program, the commentary said. <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> <PERSON> Lizhi </PERSON>, the dissident who evaded arrest by seeking refuge at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>, has been relieved of his position on the <ORGANIZATION> Academic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Degrees </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> under the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s Cabinet, is no longer qualified to tutor doctoral students, <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported. <PERSON> Fang </PERSON>, who entered the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy with his wife shortly after the June crackdown on the pro-democracy movement, already had been relieved of his posts at the <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dialectics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> but apparently still retains his main job at the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Observatory </LOCATION>. Several other dissident intellectuals also have been removed from peripheral positions. The government issued arrest warrants for <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> and his wife, professor of physics <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Shuxian </PERSON>, for allegedly inciting the pro-democracy protests, and has demanded that the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> turn them over to Chinese authorities. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> refused to comment on the report by <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Jiji </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> today that <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> is seriously ill with prostate cancer. Quoting unidentified Chinese sources, the Japanese news agency said the senior <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> leader's condition had suddenly worsened a few days ago. Emergency medical personnel were sent to care for him at his summer resort near <LOCATION> Bo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hai </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, east of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jiji </PERSON> said. An employee at the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said he had received many queries about <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s health but could respond. There was no answer tonight at the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s news office. <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> was last seen in public June 9, when national television showed him congratulating top army officers on having ended the pro-democracy protests. He spoke in a strong voice and appeared more alert and healthy than he had for some months. He is widely believed to suffer from prostate problems, and over the past few years there have been periodic reports he is very ill or dying. The <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Daily today said the army has chosen 36 people to travel around the country to `` tell the whole nation how they, bearing the fate of the party and the country, protected the socialist system'' by helping troops crack down on the popular student movement. The group includes soldiers, armed police and a woman who said they helped 164 soldiers hide from angry protesters. The move is part of a campaign to publicize the official version of the events of June 3-4, when troops marched through <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and fired on unarmed civilians to drive student protesters from <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> has said nearly 100 soldiers and police died and that thousands were injured, while about 100 civilians died and nearly 1,000 were injured. Chinese witnesses and Western intelligence sources said the death toll may have been as high as 3,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 1028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Hypersegregation 1stLd-Writethru a0533 08-04 0563</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hypersegregation, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0533,0583</SECOND>
<HEAD>Blacks Suffer From `Hypersegregation' in Major Cities, Study Finds</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with two grafs to RECAST and fix typo. Picks up 3rd graf.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Various forms of segregation that isolate blacks in major cities, depriving them of opportunities and resources, are creating a separate society of underachievers, researchers say. The authors of a study released Thursday by the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> call such multi-layer discrimination `` hypersegregation.'' Professors <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Massey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Denton </PERSON> say they found that hypersegregation exists in 10 cities, and that those cities account for 29 percent of the country's urban black population. <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> was found to be the most hypersegregated city. `` There is a small set of cities in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> where blacks experience more extreme segregation than believed in the past,'' said <PERSON> Massey </PERSON>, a professor of sociology and director of the school's <ORGANIZATION> Population </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. `` While the cities are small in number, they house a relatively large percentage of blacks.'' In the study _ published in today's editions of Demography, the journal of Washington-based <ORGANIZATION> Population </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Massey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Denton </PERSON> focused on five measures of segregation: _ The degree to which neighborhood percentages of minority-group residents correspond to the citywide minority percentages. _ The degree of potential contact between whites and members of the minority group where the latter live and work. _ The extent to which minority neighborhoods are clustered. _ The degree to which minorities are settled in and around the city center. _ The amount of physical space occupied by a minority group. Hypersegregation occurs when at least four of those measures apply, <PERSON> Massey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Denton </PERSON> said. Using data gathered in 1980 by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION>, the researchers used the five measures to compute housing patterns for blacks and Hispanics in 60 metropolitan areas. In <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, blacks had an index above .750 on each of the five measures. A reading of .600 is considered high, researchers say. The study found hypersegregation of blacks in nine other cities: <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Gary </PERSON>, Ind.; <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>; and <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. The researchers found no hypersegregation of Hispanics in the nation's urban areas. Housing patterns that fall into any one of the five categories are troublesome because they isolate a minority group from amenities, opportunities and resources that affect social and economic well-being, the researchers said. Language is the best and most sensitive indicator of social isolation and creation of a divergent cultures, <PERSON> Massey </PERSON> said. `` Black English vernacular is becoming more prevalent and almost a separate language,'' he noted. `` It has its own diction and structure, and it is because of isolation. The two groups do n't interact They are not sharing a common language.'' The demographics of blacks and whites are different, with blacks having a higher infant mortality rate and a shorter life expectancy, <PERSON> Massey </PERSON> said. Black child-bearing is concentrated between ages 18 and 25, while whites generally delay having children until later in life. `` It is like living in two different nations,'' <PERSON> Massey </PERSON> said. Hispanics experienced lower degrees of segregation overall. The differences in treatment of the two minority groups are not easily explained by socioeconomic factors, he said _ which leaves racism. `` Hispanics are primarily white,'' he said. `` They are apparently more accepted as neighbors than blacks. There is something about blacks that disturbs whites. It is a complex psychological process.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 1035EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Hostages-Iran 2ndLd-Writethru   08-04 0490</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hostages-Iran, 2nd Ld-Writethru,a0521,0504</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Rafsanjani Says He'll Help Solve Lebanon Problem</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Hostages, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: New thruout to ADD quotes from Rafsanjani offering to help in
hostage situation. No pickup. ADDS byline.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANWAR FARUQI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s president, <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, today said he would help find a solution to the hostage situation in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and urged the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to approach the problem in a reasonable manner, <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> radio said. `` These bullyings, arrogant approaches and tyranny will not solve the problems,'' the president said during his weekly prayer sermon at <ORGANIZATION> Tehran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` Come let us approach the problem reasonably. We too will help solve the problems there, so the people of the region can live in peace and harmony,'' he said in the broadcast, monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>. `` I tell the White House, the problem of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> has solutions, the freeing of the hostages has solutions, reasonable, prudent solutions,'' <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> said. However, <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> also said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> must take the initiative by pressuring <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to free <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Karim </PERSON> <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>, a Shiite Moslem cleric it kidnapped from south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> a week ago. If the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> responds by saying it can not do so, `` this is n't acceptable to us,'' he said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has offered to swap <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> for the 16 foreign hostages in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and three <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers held there. The pro-Iranian group <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, of which <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> is reputed to be a member, rejected such a swap. <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> is believed to be the umbrella for factions holding most of the foreign hostages. On Thursday, one of those factions, the <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, suspended a threat to kill American hostage <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON> but demanded that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> free <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> and Lebanese prisoners it holds. It did not say what would happen if <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> refused. On Monday, another faction, the Organization of the Oppressed on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, claimed it killed American hostage <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> lieutenant colonel, in retaliation for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s refusal to free <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>. `` We do not make any judgment about the group which executed the American colonel,'' <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> said. `` You can not condemn the innocent people of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> ... on the vague basis that some group has possibly killed someone -LRB- <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON> -RRB- for a crime,'' he added. <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>' captors accused him of being a spy. <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, known as a pragmatist who wants to improve <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s ties with the West, has not said whether <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> played a role in the reprieve granted <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON> A knowledgeable Shiite Moslem source in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the final word on <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON>'s reprieve came from him. The 54-year-old <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> is believed to want to end the international terrorist image <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> developed under the leadership of the late <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>. After <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s death June 3, <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> moved quickly to gain the upper hand against a radical faction headed by Interior Minister <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Akbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohtashemi </PERSON>. The radicals favor <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s anti-Western views and backing of terrorist groups abroad
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 1103EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Drownings     08-04 0253</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drownings,0261</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Children Drown When Car Runs Into River; Adults Rescued by Boat</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WYANDOTTE, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A car broke through a barrier and plunged into a river, killing four children, but two adults were rescued when passing boaters threw them life preservers, police said today. Why the car went into the <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> late Thursday was unknown, Police Chief <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothermal </PERSON> said. He said one of the survivors, <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Delisle </PERSON>, 28, was questioned Thursday night `` but was in shock and incoherent.'' <PERSON> Delisle </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Susan </PERSON>, 32, were in stable condition today at <ORGANIZATION> Wyandotte </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Justine </PERSON> <PERSON> Kimbler </PERSON>, assistant director of nursing. <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Stoneburner </PERSON> said he and a companion threw flotation devices to the adults, who had come to the surface. `` The man was so exhausted and the woman was hysterical,'' he said. `` She said ` I am not leaving without my children. Save my children, they are underwater.''' Divers recovered the bodies of the Delisles' four children from the car in less than an hour, <PERSON> Rothermal </PERSON> said. Killed were <PERSON> Brian </PERSON>, 8; <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON>, 4; <PERSON> Kadie </PERSON>, 2; and <PERSON> Emily </PERSON>, 8 months. <PERSON> Rothermal </PERSON> said <PERSON> Delisle </PERSON> would be questioned again later today. Earlier Thursday, divers recovered the body of <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Prather </PERSON>, 7, of <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, who fell from her raft in <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION> Wednesday while unsuccessfully trying to rescue her sister, <LOCATION> Cheyla </LOCATION>, 9. <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Prather </PERSON>'s body was found off <LOCATION> Sterling </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> by divers from the <ORGANIZATION> Monroe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and state police, Sheriff <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Wert </PERSON> said. Her sister's body was found Wednesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 1118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Greece-Crash 1stLd-Writethru a0494 08-04 0472</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Greece-Crash, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0494,0490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Precede ATHENS</HEAD>
<HEAD>Rescuers Crawl to Crash Site; No Survivors</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 13 grafs to UPDATE with detail from crash site. Pickup
9th pvs, ``Gelastathis told...''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NIKOS KONSTANDARAS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAMOS, Greece (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rescuers crawled on their hands and knees today to reach the site of an Olympic Airways crash, but they found no survivors from the aircraft that slammed into a mountain with 34 people aboard. The British-built Short plane crashed Thursday into 4,800-foot <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kerkis </LOCATION> on Samos island. Airline officials blamed the accident on heavy fog that covered the mountain, the highest in the <LOCATION> Aegean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>. Rescuers searched for the flight recorders, which should contain information on the plane's equipment and any conversations involving the pilot. Transport and Communications Minister <PERSON> Nikos </PERSON> <PERSON> Gelestathis </PERSON> said the plane, which was flying to the island from <LOCATION> Salonica </LOCATION> in northern <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>, carried 31 passengers, including an infant, and three crew members. All were Greek. Rescuers said they apparently were killed instantly when the aircraft hit the mountain. `` Unfortunately, we could do nothing, I checked every body I could find,'' said <PERSON> Emmanuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Karlas </PERSON>, a doctor from a village on this eastern <LOCATION> Aegean </LOCATION> island within sight of <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>'s southwestern coast. The propeller-driven plane gave no sign of trouble before it disappeared from radar screens, officials said. Only a wing and twin-tail section of the aircraft was recognizable. The front disintegrated on impact and was just a black scar on the mountainside. Police could identify only four of the charred bodies. Olympic, <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>'s national carrier, was flying in relatives to help identify victims. Helicopters could not land close to the crash site and rescuers crawled up the mountainside on hands and knees for 90 minutes in the dark. The steep terrain prevented them from carrying down the dead. `` We'll have the helicopters hoist out the human remains, `` said police officer <PERSON> Panayiotis </PERSON> <PERSON> Kourdonouris </PERSON>. Officials ruled out foul play as the cause of the crash. An Olympic official who spoke on condition of anonymity said: `` It appears that thick fog in the area at the time played the villain's role as the pilot flew blindly into the mountain.'' <PERSON> Gelestathis </PERSON> told lawmakers in Parliament today that a terrorist act was out of the question. Military teams were dispatched to the crash site after a shepherd reported seeing an explosion on the mountain. The <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> airport duty officer, <PERSON> Emmanuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Fragiadakis </PERSON>, said the control tower lost contact with the plane at about 4:55 p.m., an hour after it left <LOCATION> Salonika </LOCATION>. It was scheduled to land on Samos at 5:30 p.m. The plane disappeared from radar screens when it was 25 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Samos </LOCATION>. Olympic officials said the pilot, <PERSON> Petros </PERSON> <PERSON> Moutzoureas </PERSON>, was a veteran with an excellent flight record. They said the aircraft was bought in 1981 and was used for inter-island flights.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 1131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lebanon     08-04 0553</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon,0571</SECOND>
<HEAD>Syrian-Christian Clashes in Beirut</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MOHAMMED SALAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Syrian and <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> forces battled with howitzers, mortars and tank cannons across <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s dividing Green Line today. Police said two people were killed and seven wounded. The shelling kept many Moslems from attending their weekly Friday prayers. The latest casualties raised the overall toll to 516 killed and 2,183 wounded in the 20-week-old confrontation between Gen. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s predominantly <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> troops and Syrian soldiers in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. `` They've started early today,'' grocer <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> <PERSON> Masoud </PERSON> said as he closed his store in west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> and headed for a bomb shelter. `` What a life! We are living under the ground like the dead. We might as well die.'' A police spokesman, who can not be named in line with regulations, said the clash involved the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> district of <PERSON> Ein </PERSON> <PERSON> Rummaneh </PERSON> and the adjacent Syrian-controlled Moslem neighborhood of <LOCATION> Chiyah </LOCATION>. He said the clash started with an exchange of sniper fire then developed into an artillery duel. It was not immediately clear who started the clash. Shells crashed into apartment buildings on both sides of the <ORGANIZATION> Green </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION>, which has divided <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> into Moslem and <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> sectors since the civil war broke out in April 1975. The two fatalities occurred in the densely populated slum of <LOCATION> Chiyah </LOCATION>, a stronghold for the Syrian-backed Shiite Moslem Amal militia. Amal did not take part in the confrontation, the spokesman said. Shell explosions echoed across <LOCATION> Chiyah </LOCATION> and residents rushed to underground bomb shelters as calls were blared from mosque minarets for noon prayers. The police spokesman said the shelling of <LOCATION> Chiyah </LOCATION> did not reach the nearby slum of <LOCATION> Bir </LOCATION> <LOCATION> el-Abed </LOCATION>, where followers of the Iranian-backed <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, or Party of God, attended prayers at the main mosque. Friday is the Moslem holy day. Syrian gunners deployed in <LOCATION> Chiyah </LOCATION> fired their 130mm Soviet-designed howitzers at the Christian suburb of <LOCATION> Kfarshima </LOCATION>, southeast of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s forces maintain some artillery batteries. <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s gunners, the spokesman said, responed by shelling <LOCATION> Chiyah </LOCATION> and the Druse suburb of <LOCATION> Choueifat </LOCATION> with 155mm U.S.-designed howitzers deployed northeast of the capital. The thuds of shell blasts resounded across the bomb-ravaged <LOCATION> Lebanese </LOCATION> capital, forcing the few businesses that opened early in the morning to close. Only 200,000 people of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s original 1.5 million population still live in the city, which has been the site of ferocious shelling duels since the confrontation broke out March 8. Most of the evacuees have settled in safer areas in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, the eastern <LOCATION> Bekaa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and the Christian-controlled mountain resorts northeast of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. The confrontation broke out over a blockade imposed by <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> on illegal ports run by Syrian-backed militias south of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> for denying the ailing state treasury about $ 100 million in lost customs dues annually. The Syrians and allied Moslem and leftist forces retaliated by shelling and besieging the 310-square-mile Christian enclave, home to about one million people northeast of the capital. <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>, 54, a <ORGANIZATION> Maronite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>, escalated the confrontation with the Syrians by declaring a `` war of liberation'' against their 40,000 troops, deployed in predominantly Moslem sections of the nation. An Arab mediation committee has failed to solve <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s crisis, rooted in an effort by the Moslem majority to wrest more power from Christians, who traditionally have dominated <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> The panel blamed <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> for blocking a settlement.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 1135EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-CDC--LosingWeight 1stLd-Writethru a0463 08-04 0413</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CDC--Losing Weight, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0463,0416</SECOND>
<HEAD>Millions Of Fat Americans Aren't Doing Much About It</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 8th graf, `Overall, the...' to CORRECT that Maine, along
with Hawaii, was at the low end of the statistical range.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Disease Spreading, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BYRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There's an athletic shoe company that urges, `` Just do it.'' But when it comes to losing weight, a federal study indicates that millions of hefty Americans just do n't. The national <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday that none of 32 states in a <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> survey could report even half their overweight people taking the recommended twofold approach to losing weight: eating fewer calories and getting more exercise. The <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> estimates that 34 million Americans _ about one in four adults _ are overweight by 20 percent or more. `` The data suggest that significant numbers are eating fewer calories, but it's the physical activity that we do n't have enough people doing,'' said <PERSON> Eddas </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> epidemiologist. In the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> survey, conducted in 1987 in 32 states and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, an average of 20 percent of the overweight men reported that they were following the fewer calories-more exercise approach. For women, the percentage was somewhat better: 31 percent. An average of 44 percent of the overweight men said they were eating fewer calories, compared with 64 percent of overweight women. But only 24 percent of the men and 35 percent of the women said they were increasing their physical activity. `` Physical activity appears to be the limiting factor,'' the Atlanta-based <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> concluded in its weekly report. `` The low prevalence of increasing physical activity to lose weight may reflect the sedentary lifestyle of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> adults and the emphasis on diet as a means of weight loss without adequately addressing the benefits of physical activity.'' Overall, the percentage of overweight men trying both the low-calorie and more-exercise approach ranged from a high of 36 percent in <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> to a low of 13 percent in <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. For women, the range was from 19 percent in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, to 42 percent in <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, with all percentages rounded. Ms. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> noted that an official 1990 health objective for the nation calls for at least half of overweight adults to follow the fewer calories-more exercise regimen. `` We're not going to meet that objective in any state,'' she said. Overweight is defined as being about 20 percent above ideal body weight for the person's age.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 1139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Hostages 4thLd-Writethru a0535 08-04 0986</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hostages, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0535,1012</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Iran's Rafsanjani Offers to Help in Hostage Crisis</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 18 grafs to ADD Bush reaction, comments on report
he planned military action. Pickup 19th, `In Jerusalem...</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto PX2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA ABU-NASR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> today offered to help find a solution to the hostage situation but said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> must pressure <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to release a kidnapped Shiite Moslem cleric, Iranian media reported. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he would explore the offer `` to the fullest'' but that he did not want to raise the hopes of the hostages' families. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also refused to confirm reports he had planned to take military action if another hostage had been killed. One hostage was reported killed Monday. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, meanwhile, was awaiting a list of prisoners that a Shiite Moslem group in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> wants freed. `` I tell the White House, the problem of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> has solutions, the freeing of the hostages has solutions, reasonable, prudent solutions,'' <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> said in a speech carried on official <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> radio. `` These bullyings, arrogant approaches and tyranny will not solve the problems. Come let us approach the problem reasonably. We too will help solve the problems there, so the people of the region can live in peace and harmony,'' he said in the broadcast monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>'s comments were made during the weekly Friday prayer session at <ORGANIZATION> Tehran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. He said if the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> wants hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> freed, it must take the inititive by asking <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to free <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Karim </PERSON> <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>, a Shiite Moslem leader abducted by <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> commandos one week ago. `` We do not make any judgment about the group which executed the American colonel,'' <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> said, referring to Monday's reported slaying of Marine Lt. Col. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON> by the pro-Iranian Organization of the Oppressed on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. `` But if the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> wants to take the inititative -LRB- in freeing hostages -RRB-, it must ask <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to free the Friday prayer leader of Jibchit,'' <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> said. If the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> responds by saying it can not pressure <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> into freeing the Moslem cleric, `` this is n't acceptable to us,'' he added. Israeli commandos last week stole into Jibchit, in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, and kidnapped <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Karim </PERSON> <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>, a Shiite Moslem clergyman who is the local prayer leader. <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> also is reputed to be a spiritual leader of the pro-Iranian group <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, believed to be the umbrella for factions holding most of the 16 foreign hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The Organization of the Oppressed on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> claimed it hanged <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON> in retaliation for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s refusal to release <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> claims <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> instigated attacks on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Another pro-Iranian group, the <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, threatened to kill another <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hostage, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON>, but announced Thursday it had suspended the death order. It also demanded that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> free not only <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> but also Palestinian and Lebanese prisoners `` within days.'' The group did not say if the death sentence would be restored if <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> did not comply. There are eight Americans among the 16 foreign hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON> was acting comptroller of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION> when he was abducted Sept. 12, 1986. The hostage held longest is <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. He was abducted March 16, 1985. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was asked if the latest developments suggested a break in the hostage crisis. `` I'm encouraged, but I do n't want to get the hopes of the hostages' loved ones up once again to have those hopes dashed,'' he said. He added that had been engaged in `` an extroardinarily broad exercise of diplomacy'' over the last several days on behalf of the hostages. Had another hostage been killed, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported today that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> planned to target for attack the <LOCATION> Baalbek </LOCATION> base of 4,000 Iranian Revolutionary Guards in eastern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The guards work closely with <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>. Asked about the report, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> responded, `` If I had made such a decision, I expect this would be the last place I'd be talking about it.'' In <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> would examine the new demands `` on a positive basis.'' Four top <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> leaders, including <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> and Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzkhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, met today in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> to fashion a response to the Shiite radicals' demands A spokesman for <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> was awaiting the list of prisoners the Shiites want freed. The <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> said it was willing to transmit to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> the demands for the prisoner release. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has offered to trade <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>, 33, and other Lebanese Shiites it holds for foreign hostages and three <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers held in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> has rejected such a swap. <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Na'im </PERSON> <PERSON> Qassem </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> leader, said there had been no direct or indirect negotiations with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> on a prisoner exchange and would not be. The Revolutionary <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> granted <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON> a reprieve 45 minutes before the deadline Thursday that it had set for killing him. It was the third time the group held off on its death threat. `` Out of respect for the intervention by the parties and states with whom <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> pleaded to mediate and stop the execution, we declare the freezing of the death sentence and its substitution with an initiative,'' said a statement by the group. None of the mediating nations was named, but press reports in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> have said <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> were believed to have interceded. <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> helped secure the release of American diplomats taken captive at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> in 1979. <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, known as a pragmatist, has not commented on whether <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> played a role, but a knowledgeable Shiite Moslem source in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the final word on <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON>'s reprieve came from him. <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> is believed to want to improve ties with the West and to change <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s image as a sponsor of international terrorism.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 1146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Soviet-USShips     08-04 0517</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-US Ships,0532</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Welcome American Warships</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAREY GOLDBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEVASTOPOL, U.S.S.R. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Throwing flowers, candy and coins, more than 1,000 cheering residents of this key <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> port gave a riotous welcome today to <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> warships cruising into <LOCATION> Sevastopol </LOCATION>'s historic harbor. `` That's for ice cream when you come ashore,'' called one woman in the crowd as she lobbed a 20-kopeck coin toward the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> sailors lined along the ships' decks in their blinding summer whites. The visiting seamen, who sent dozens of round sailor hats whizzing to the whistling, waving crowd, were equally excited. `` It just feels great to be making history,'' said <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Marlatt </PERSON>, medical officer aboard the cruiser USS Thomas S. Gates. The good-will port call by the <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> and the frigate USS Kauffman mirrored a visit last month by three Soviet ships to <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, in the first such Soviet-American naval exchange in 14 years. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sixth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fleet </ORGANIZATION>'s flagship, the USS Belknap, also was to join but was diverted to be at President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s disposal during the hostage crisis in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The ships' visit to <LOCATION> Sevastopol </LOCATION> is the first since World War II. Three <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships docked in <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> in 1975. <LOCATION> Sevastopol </LOCATION>, headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fleet </ORGANIZATION>, normally is a closed city, even to Soviets. But today it opened its gates wide to greet the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> sailors. Crewmen were mobbed by beaming Soviets, handed babies to kiss, asked to pose for snapshots and given rubles, souvenirs and food. A brass band played marches and two women in traditional costume met the ship with bread and salt, symbols of hospitality. `` My whole soul is happy that we finally did this great thing and that we will be friends,'' said 18-year-old <PERSON> Zinaida </PERSON> <PERSON> Kolisinchenko </PERSON>. `` And the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> sailors, they are so attractive.'' <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Zverev </PERSON>, the military commandant of <LOCATION> Sevastopol </LOCATION>, look with bemusement at the crowd on the pier. `` We did n't expect so many people,'' he said. `` This is the biggest reception for a ship I have ever seen here.'' <PERSON> Zverev </PERSON> admitted the city is not accustomed to giving such an open welcome to Western guests, but said, `` it is appropriate given the state of our relations today.'' The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> sailors, too, commented on the strange sensation of suddenly being treated as such good friends. Aviator <PERSON> Matt </PERSON> <PERSON> Zentry </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, recalled going through recognition training to learn how to pick out Soviet ships from afar. `` And now, here were are right next to them,'' he said. `` For so long we thought of them as possible adversaries, and all of a sudden that is gone in a minute,'' said public affairs officer <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Weishautt </PERSON>. Above Count's Pier, where the American ships docked, a red banner proclaimed in English: `` Mutual understanding and trust between the people of the <LOCATION> U.S.A. </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.S.R. </ORGANIZATION> is the path to peace and security.'' The Americans will tour state farms, a vineyard, an art museum, an aquarium, a war museum, and naval installations. They will be entertained at concerts, eat meals aboard Soviet ships and play basketball, soccer and volleyball with their Soviet counterparts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 1157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Austria-Bloch     08-04 0360</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Austria-Bloch,0374</SECOND>
<HEAD>Austria Closes Its Investigation of Bloch</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government said today it is closing its investigation of <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomat suspected of spying for <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, after determining that `` <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>'s interests were not affected.'' However, Interior Minister <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Loeschnak </PERSON> also told Austrian radio that 10 politicians have been asked about their relationship with <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> and that their answers will be forwarded to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for its investigation. The Austrian-born <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> served at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> in 1980-87 and was friends with many politicians, including Foreign Minister <PERSON> Alois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mock </PERSON>. In the radio interview, <PERSON> Loeschnak </PERSON> refused to identify the Austrian politicians asked to fill out questionnaires about their dealings with <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>. He also said that <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> is leaving it up to the politicians to respond at their own discretion. Some of the 10 have promised to comply, he said without identifying them. <PERSON> Loeschnak </PERSON> said police interviewed an Austrian woman with whom <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> had an extended friendship. But their questioning yielded no evidence that the woman suspected anything about <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>'s alleged spying activities, he said. No charges have been brought against <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>, who has been stripped of his diplomatic passport and placed on administrative leave. He is under constant surveillance in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>, 54, reportedly had broad contacts with Austrian politicians and officials, and he regularly attended all kinds of diplomatic and other parties while he was economics chief at the embassy in 1980-83 and then the No. 2 until his return to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in July 1987. <PERSON> Loeschnak </PERSON> noted the American's contacts with the Austrian politicians `` have no -LRB- relevance -RRB- for <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>'s security interests.'' At a news conference July 28, <PERSON> Loeschnak </PERSON> said the suspicions against <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> are `` the affair of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> is the highest-ranking <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomat to be investigated under suspicion of collaborating with the Soviets. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials were alerted to <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>'s possible links with the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> when they intercepted an international telephone call arranging a meeting in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> in May. There, <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> was filmed exchanging briefcases with a man known as <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON>, whom the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> considers a Soviet spy. <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> says he knows <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> as a stamp collector.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 1156EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Women'sCaucus 1stLd-Writethru a0482 08-04 0518</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Women's Caucus, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0482,0529</SECOND>
<HEAD>Abortion if Vietnam of '80s, Abzug Tells Women Activists</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 6 grafs to UPDATE with Abzug remarks; picks up 4th
graf pvs: `Brown said ...; SUBS grafs 9-10 pvs, `No action' with 2 grafs
and DELETES penultimate graf to conform.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY R. SANDOK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ST. PAUL, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The battle over abortion will involve young people today as the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> War did in the 1960s, former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Bella </PERSON> <PERSON> Abzug </PERSON> told female political activists today. `` Abortion is the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> of this nation for young people everywhere,'' <PERSON> Abzug </PERSON> told the opening session of the National Women's Political Caucus' Biennial Convention. <PERSON> Abzug </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> representative from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and a founder of the caucus 18 years ago, was the first of several speakers who are expected to address the abortion issue. The caucus runs through Sunday. `` No civilized nation can be allowed to declare an unborn fetus a person under the Constitution before women are declared persons under the Constitution,'' <PERSON> Abzug </PERSON> said. On Thursday, <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> told the steering committee that the <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> lost a chance to win the 1988 presidential election by not doing more to garner votes from women. `` In fact, we blew a major gender gap that might have carried the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> candidate for president to the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said he understands `` the frustrations of working in the coalition.'' But he said those who counsel the formation of a third party `` ignore the second half of the adage that begins, ` United we stand.' `` No matter where the struggle for justice ... divided we will indeed fall and fail to reach our goals,'' he said. `` I have worked in the struggle for civil rights my entire adult life, and I do not deny the problems of advancing a cause through the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> told the steering committee of the National Women's Political Caucus. `` But the alternative is self-righteous failure. It may feel good when the first speeches are made, but it will be very, very tragic when the votes are counted.'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> told reporters later that the creation of a women's political party probably would hurt Democrats more than Republicans, but he added, `` I do n't think it's going to hurt anybody because I do n't think it's going to happen. No action similar to NOW's is expected at the National Women's Political Caucus biennial convention, according to <PERSON> Irene </PERSON> <PERSON> Natividad </PERSON>, head of the caucus The convention, which officially convened today, is expected to attract 1,500 delegates and guests. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> also touched on the battle over abortion because of restrictions allowed under a July 3 <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> and the right wing of this country threaten women's rights and all of our rights,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said. He said the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> platform supports the right of a woman to choose whether to have an abortion, as well as such proposals as an Equal Rights Amendment. An invitation to <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> to address the leaders of the non-partisan caucus was declined, <PERSON> Natividad </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 1201EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SouthAfrica 1stLd-Writethru   08-04 0497</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-South Africa, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0499,0508</SECOND>
<HEAD>Precede CAPE TOWN</HEAD>
<HEAD>Homeland Reported Cracking Down On Dissidents, Violence In Soweto</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: New thruout to UPDATE with crackdown on two communities resisting
incorporation into a homeland. No pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The black homeland of <LOCATION> Bophuthatswana </LOCATION> is intensifying its crackdown on two communities that have violently resisted incorporation into the territory, an anti-apartheid group said today. Also today, police imposed restrictions on the funeral of two slain activists in a township near <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION> and reported a series of skirmishes between police and mixed-race youths. In other incidents, police said five blacks were killed in three separate clashes in <ORGANIZATION> Natal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Province </ORGANIZATION>, where supporters of militant and relatively conservative political factions have engaged in a three-year power struggle claiming hundreds of lives. <LOCATION> Bophuthatswana </LOCATION>, one of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s four nominally independent homelands, has arrested a local leader, banned anti-apartheid groups and restricted a lawyer's access to people in the communities of <LOCATION> Braklaagte </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Leeuwfontein </PERSON>. <PERSON> Lydia </PERSON> <PERSON> Kompe </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Transvaal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> which is opposed to the tribal homeland system, said the <LOCATION> Bophuthatswana </LOCATION> government `` is still increasing its efforts against its opponents'' in the two communities. The two neighboring villages were incorporated into the homeland on Jan. 1 despite protests by many of the estimated 25,000 residents. The residents of <LOCATION> Braklaagte </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Leeuwfontein </PERSON> say they want to remain part of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and fear they will be discriminated against by the <LOCATION> Bophuthatswana </LOCATION> government because of their opposition to incorporation. The homelands are not recognized by any foreign countries. Eleven people, including nine policemen, were killed July 1 when authorities sought to break up a rally in <LOCATION> Leeuwfontein </LOCATION> arranged by residents who opposed joining <LOCATION> Bophuthatswana </LOCATION>. Thirty-three people charged with involvement in the fighting were to appear in a <LOCATION> Bophuthatswana </LOCATION> court. <PERSON> Pupsey </PERSON> <PERSON> Sebogodi </PERSON>, leader of the <LOCATION> Braklaagte </LOCATION> community, has been arrested three times this year and remains in detention, said the <ORGANIZATION> Transvaal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which was banned from <LOCATION> Bophuthatswana </LOCATION> by the homeland government. Authorities have threatened to deport the Rev. <PERSON> Eberhard </PERSON> <PERSON> Richter </PERSON>, a German citizen and <PERSON> Luthern </PERSON> missionary who has served the Braklaagte community since 1981, Ms. <PERSON> Kompe </PERSON> said. A South African lawyer representing the defendants, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutherland </PERSON>, has been ordered to apply for a visa before he can return to the homeland. The homeland has few formal border posts and usually no visa is required to visit. About 2 million blacks live in <LOCATION> Bophuthatswana </LOCATION>, which consists of seven separate pieces of land scattered across north-central <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION> regional police commissioner, Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Flip </PERSON> <PERSON> Fourie </PERSON>, imposed restrictions on Saturday's funeral of two mixed-race activists who died in a bomb blast last month. Police said <PERSON> Robbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Waterwitch </PERSON>, 20, and <PERSON> Coline </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, 22, were trying to plant the bomb in a public toilet when it exploded. <PERSON> Fourie </PERSON> said the funeral service must take place indoors and be addressed only by ordained clergymen. He said mourners can not march to the cemetery and can not display any political posters, flags or banners.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 1207EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w PM-DefenseSpending 3rdLd-Writethru a0555 08-04 0595</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Spending, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0555,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Military Spending Eliminates Funds for Two Bush Programs</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: New lead and inserts 4th graf, And in, to raise veto threat</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, deliberating less than an hour and ignoring talk of a possible veto, today approved a $ 286.5 billion military spending bill that makes wholesale changes in President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s defense program. By a vote of 312-105, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted to adopt a spending plan that slashes nearly $ 2 billion for <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wars </ORGANIZATION> from the president's request strictly limits the B-2 stealth bomber program and makes drastic cuts in the MX and <LOCATION> Midgetman </LOCATION> nuclear missiles. Despite the unusually rapid approval of the costly bill by the Democratic-controlled <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> may veto the measure. And in advance of the vote, the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> budget office said the president's senior advisers would recommend a veto on grounds the measure `` would severely compromise the administration's objective of providing adequate defense capabilities within constrained resources. `` They have conformed,'' <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said of the appropriations measure that conforms to the separate defense authorization bill the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> adopted last week. `` But that still makes it veto-bait in my opinion.'' The bill, approved as <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> rushed to complete pending business before starting a month-long recess later today, slashed $ 2 billion from classified programs that include the advanced fighter and advanced cruise missile. The money bill also incorporates the cuts the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> made in the Star Wars anti-missile program, the B-2 stealth bomber and the MX and <LOCATION> Midgetman </LOCATION> nuclear missiles in the policy-setting authorization bill. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> cut <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s request of $ 4.9 billion for Star Wars by $ 1.8 billion, imposed strict limitation on production of the radar-evading B-2, trimmed $ 502 million from the $ 1.1 billion sought for the MX rail-garrison system and eliminated all $ 100 million sought for the Midgetman. <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said he hoped that when members of the the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> meet early in September to craft a final version of the bill, the `` most egregious add-ons and deletions can be modified and limited to make it acceptable to the administration.'' But he said as they stand now, he does not support the authorization and appropriations bills and would recommend that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> veto the legislation. `` I think it will be vetoed,'' <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said. But Rep. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, complained about suggestions that <ORGANIZATION> House-Senate </ORGANIZATION> conferees will change what the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> did after the chamber `` worked its will on the defense authorization bill.'' `` That really borders on the ridiculous. The House has spoken,'' <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> said. The bill adds $ 893 million to the administration's budget for the purchase of 24 new F-14 jet fighters and 12 EA-6B Prowlers, both manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Grumman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerospace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has proposed canceling the F-14D, a carrier-based fighter plane the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> restored in its authorization bill The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> earmarked about $ 1 billion for 24 planes over two years. Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Murtha </PERSON>, D-Pa., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations defense subcommittee, criticized the increasing costs of the Advanced Tactical Fighter and favored spending money on conventional projects The appropriations bill is designed to provide the money for the defense programs approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> last week. The measure calls for $ 286.5 billion in budget authority and $ 281.9 billion in outlays, but does n't include money for the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> and military construction. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> defense authorization bill totals $ 305 billion _ $ 295 billion for the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and $ 10 billion for military nuclear programs handled by the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890804-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-04-89 1208EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-SoccerDeathsProbe 1stLd-Writethru a0527 08-04 0642</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soccer Deaths Probe, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0527,0657</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report Says Police Errors Led to British Soccer Disaster</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 8 grafs to UPDATE with policeman suspended, police
comment. Pickup 7th pvs, ``The report ...'' Another version of this story
moved on sports circuits.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN MITCHELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
