<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 2346EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-SriLanka     05-11 0504</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sri Lanka,0519</SECOND>
<HEAD>Premadasa Meets With Tamil Rebels</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEXTER CRUEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLOMBO, Sri Lanka (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Ranasinghe </PERSON> <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> and four members of his Cabinet met for the first time Thursday with Tamil rebels fighting for an independent nation and discussed ways to end the insurgency, officials said. Also Thursday, officials said <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> will help the top Sinhalese militant leader go abroad for medical treatment, a move which may pave the way for peace negotiations with the extremists. The Tamil rebellion and the resulting Sinhalese backlash have claimed more than 12,500 lives since 1983 and unleashed a wave of terror, bombings and assassinations on this once-peaceful island nation. Officials refused to reveal details of the meeting with the Tamils, which concluded for the day after a few hours. Foreign Minister <PERSON> Ranjan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wijeratne </PERSON> said <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> had received and approved a request from <PERSON> Rohana </PERSON> <PERSON> Wijeweera </PERSON>, leader of the underground <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, to allow him to go abroad for medical treatment. <PERSON> Wijeweera </PERSON>, 46, is believed to have suffered a heart attack recently. The front is an ultra-nationalist Sinhalese group which has been at the forefront of the anti-government campaign launched in 1987 to protest peace overtures made to Tamil rebels. The request from <LOCATION> Wijeweera </LOCATION> was made through <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Nuttal </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> correspondent in <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Nuttal </PERSON> said he received two telephone calls from a front member on Thursday, who said the group would be willing to hold talks with the government if <PERSON> Wijeweera </PERSON> was allowed to receive medical treatment in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. The request was conveyed to the government, he said. A government statement said <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> had not directly been in touch with the front. The front last month rejected <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON>'s offer of amnesty and seats in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> if they gave up their campaign of assassinations and calling crippling industrial strikes. An estimated 3,500 people have been killed in the campaign. The peace offer was accepted by Tamil rebels, and a five-member team is currently holding talks with the government. Tamil insurgents launched a bloody rebellion in 1983 for an independent nation in the northern and eastern regions of the country, where most Tamils live. An attempt by <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON>'s predecessor, <PERSON> Junius </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jayewardene </PERSON>, to end the rebellion by granting limited autonomy to the Tamils ended in failure after the <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tamil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eelam </ORGANIZATION>, the largest rebel militia, rejected the plan after a brief acceptance. The peace plan, signed in July 1987, also sparked a backlash among nationalist Sinhalese, who said it gave too many concessions to the Tamil minority. The plan was sponsored by <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> peacekeeping troops were later despatched to <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> to enforce an arms surrender by the Tamils. At least 800 Indian soldiers have been killed in hit-and-run attacks by the rebels since then. The Hindu Tamils, who comprise 18 percent of the country's 16 million people, say they are discriminated against by the Sinhalese majority in jobs and education. Sinhalese Buddhists make up 75 percent of the population and control the government and the military.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 2359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Panama-Americans 2ndLd-Writethru a0843 05-11 0876</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-Americans, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0843,0908</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Dependents Moving To Bases</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 10-14, `Emil Kirberg...,' with 10 grafs to UPDATE
with quotes. Pick up 15th pvs, `The plan...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto PAN6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD HERZFELDER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> diplomatic and military families headed Thursday to temporary haven on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military bases to avoid possible harassment by Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s government. `` The problem is regime-directed gangs,'' such as the group that assaulted opposition presidential candidate <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> and his two running mates on Wednesday, said <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kneebone </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Kneebone </PERSON> said there had been no direct threats against <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> personnel, but that in the past the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> government has publicized the neighborhoods where Americans live. <PERSON> Kneebone </PERSON> said he did not know if that was just propaganda, `` but the people around Wednesday were out of control.'' <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> announced that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomatic dependents would be moved to bases after the assault on <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> and his two vice presidential candidates Wednesday. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> anounced Thursday that <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> is being recalled, that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> personnel would be reduced and that both military and diplomatic dependents would be moved either to safe housing or out of the country. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> maintains 10 military installations in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, which is <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military headquarters for <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. About 10,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers are stationed in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Thursday he was sending 2,000 more `` to protect the lives of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> citizens.'' <PERSON> Kneebone </PERSON> said 105 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens work for the embassy, and the moving order affected 57 spouses and 85 children. The order does not affect 21,300 American civilians not connected with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government, many of them retired. <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> LeBlanc </PERSON>, from <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, said his daughters are away at college. He was planning to put up three families in his three spare bedrooms at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clayton </LOCATION>, 10 miles from <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. `` I've been in the service, or with the service, 25 years,'' said <PERSON> LeBlanc </PERSON>, a civilian <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> employee. `` We take care of our own.'' The <PERSON> Kirberg </PERSON> family was one of the three <PERSON> LeBlanc </PERSON> was expecting. They arrived at sunset, unloaded their suitcases in a few minutes and looked at their new surroundings. They said they'd had no trouble but they'd rather be safe. `` The Panamanians have always been friendly,'' said <PERSON> Emil </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirberg </PERSON>, who works for <PERSON> LeBlanc </PERSON>. His wife, <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyle </PERSON>, said she had been surprised by the call. `` It was worse last year and we never had a problem,'' she said. The <PERSON> Kirbergs </PERSON> said they put as much as they could into a few suitcases and left their dog with friends. `` I tried to take things that meant something to me,'' said <PERSON> Boyle </PERSON>. That included some pillows and a small chandelier. Once inside the gate, <PERSON> LeBlanc </PERSON> said his wife had sped out to rent some videos. `` I hope she gets some good ones,'' he said. `` I do n't know how long this is going to go on.'' The plan under which diplomatic dependents were moving Thursday was designed for temporary security, and embassy spokeswoman <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrell </PERSON> said it was not known how <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s decisions would affect the immediate situation. <PERSON> Kneebone </PERSON> said: `` Everybody lives in a high-rise apartment building for security reasons. People ca n't see that you've moved, as they could if you lived in a house. `` It's not like the Joads moving from <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. You just pack a suitcase for four or five days, get in your car and drive across town.'' All was calm Wednesday in one of the exclusive high-rise neighborhoods where many diplomatic families live. Almost the only vehicle moving in the hot afternoon sun was a beer truck making a restaurant delivery. Some people with pets were boarding them out, <PERSON> Kneebone </PERSON> said, but others planned to return home during the day `` to feed pets or pick up clean underwear.'' Panamanian employees of the embassy were concerned both about harassment and whether they would have jobs if the size of the staff was reduced. `` We can do with very few Americans here and that will probably create more work, rather than less, for the Panamanians,'' the spokesman said. He said the military officials were in a more difficult situation because they had more dependents to deal with. A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> said there are 10,600 military dependents in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, 972 of whom live off base. Southern Command was operating under condition `` Charlie,'' meaning <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> personnel can go into public areas of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> only on official business and in civilian clothes. <PERSON> Kneebone </PERSON> said his family was in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> because the current government had sent him a letter ordering him to leave the country. `` Since we do n't recognize that government, we opened the envelope, photocopied it, resealed it and stamped ` Returned Unopened' on it,'' he said. He said he sent his family home because he thought the expulsion order, and his refusal to obey it, made him a target <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> companies doing business in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> also should withdraw dependents. Among the larger companies with operations here are <ORGANIZATION> Texaco </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Colgate </ORGANIZATION>. A person who answered the telephone at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> said the chamber could not express an opinion or give information because `` this is a political matter now.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0001EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-WrightProbe 2ndLd-Writethru a0776 05-11 0930</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wright Probe, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0776,950</SECOND>
<HEAD>Speaker's Lawyers Seek to Dismiss Most Serious Charges</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: To update with newspaper reports, adds 5 grafs after 15th graf
previous, The ethics</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lawyers for <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> sought Wednesday to dismiss the most serious charges against him as the ethics committee moved to dig deeper into a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> gas investment that yielded huge profits for <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> last year. The ethics panel also denied a motion by the speaker's lawyers to bar the special outside counsel in the case, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> lawyer <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>, from holding private discussions with the committee, but granted other motions seeking access to witnesses and documents, said <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Susman </PERSON>, a lawyer for <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. Committee chairman <PERSON> Julian </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Calif., strongly defended <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON> against allegations from <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s camp that he has used faulty and weak reasoning in bringing charges against the speaker `` That is totally inaccurate, totally wrong and an exercise in bad judgment by the respondent's attorneys,'' <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> told reporters. At the same time, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said it would undertake an independent review of <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s business and political dealings if the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> exonerates the speaker. `` I expect the department will take an independent look,'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON>, chief spokesman for Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>, said in response to a question at a press briefing. He said such a review would cover matters brought up by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee and `` other matters that have been raised,'' such as <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s involvement in a 1985 political fund-raising effort in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. `` We are going to keep an eye on allegations made about the conduct of the speaker,'' <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> said. But the spokesman added that `` it's premature to say we are going to have any investigation.'' Asked if the department would investigate <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> if the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> disciplined the speaker, <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> said: `` The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has a different function than the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> has and we are keeping tabs on that. It would be premature to say what that's going to lead to.'' In seeking to dismiss the most serious allegations against the speaker _ that he used bulk sales of his book to evade limits on outside earned income and improperly accepted $ 145,000 in gifts from a person with a direct interest in legislation _ the lawyers charged the ethics committee is trying to hold <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> to a new, tougher standard. The charges amount to `` a house of cards delicately balanced on a series of unprecedented reinterpretations of House rules,'' they argued. The eight-lawyer defense team did not immediately challenge other charges that the speaker failed to report as gifts benefits he received from <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, developer <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mallick </PERSON>, but signaled that that issue would be contested later. On the matter of <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s gas investment, <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> said the committee, after a briefing on a series of interviews conducted last week, decided that `` there were other witnesses who would have to be interviewed'' and directed <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON> to continue investigating. The investment involves a gas well in <LOCATION> Sabine </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, near the Texas-Louisiana line, which <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mallick </PERSON> bought into for $ 9,120 last January. They sold their interest less than five months later for a $ 340,000 profit, even though the well's production had dwindled. The ethics panel also generally discussed a series of other allegations against <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> raised in recent news stories, but made no decisions on whether to formally expand the investigation to include those, <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, in its Thursday editions, reported that among the transactions that have come under scrutiny is <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s $ 100,000 investment in a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> nursing home company that later went bankrupt Published reports have said <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> was one of the few investors in <ORGANIZATION> Jewell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION> to receive payments from the company before it failed. The company's president, T.R. <PERSON> Jewell </PERSON>, is quoted in Thursday's editions of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> as saying his company provided <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> the money to pay interest on the $ 100,000 bank loan <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> used to buy his stock in 1983 <PERSON> Jewell </PERSON> said he considered the money a `` loan'' and that similar loans were available to a few other stockholders. <PERSON> Jewell </PERSON> told the <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, Star-Telegram, that <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s investment had no connection with any legislation before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and that the company gained nothing by having the powerful congressman as one of its 28 investors `` We were regulated by the state; there is n't anything he could have done to help us,'' <PERSON> Jewell </PERSON> told the Star-Telegram. Among the areas the panel is looking into is a 1985 fund-raising effort for a special congressional election in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> in which <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> took an intense personal interest. In testimony last week at a federal fraud trial in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> was linked to a political action committee which collected allegedly illegal contributions from officials of Commodore Savings and Loan, an insolvent <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> thrift. On Wednesday, three former Commodore employees testified they gave money to the <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> PAC </ORGANIZATION> and later were reimbursed by their company, either through pay increases or checks for fictional travel. Former Commodore President <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morten </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON>, his brother <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrell </PERSON>, former Commodore CEO and vice chairman of the board, are being tried on charges they misused Commodore funds to make illegal PAC contributions. East Texas First raised and spent about $ 100,000 to help Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, win a special election in 1985. A former Commodore chief financial officer testified Friday that his boss told him <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> had agreed to halt legislation opposed by the savings and loan industry if the industry raised $ 250,000 for the <ORGANIZATION> PAC </ORGANIZATION>, but <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> denied making any such statement.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Thatcher-Bush     05-11 0141</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Thatcher-Bush,0144</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kissinger Predicts Close Bush-Thatcher Relationship</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> will have as close or closer a political relationship with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> than with his predecessor <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> predicted. The former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> secretary of state made the remarks Wednesday night in an interview with <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Sky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, one of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s closest allies during his two-term presidency, is due to hold talks with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> when he visits <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> for two days starting May 31 during a European tour. <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> said: `` The relationship, good as it was between President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, will be at least as good, if not better, between President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Prime Minister <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>.'' `` Mr. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> based his relationships very much on personal intuition. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is a man who is more reflective about the conceptual matters,'' <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> added.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0128EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Shcherbitsky     05-11 0947</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shcherbitsky,0978</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brezhnev Man in Politburo Bends _ a Little</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANN IMSE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The last <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON> man on the Politburo bends enough under the pressure of reform to stay in power, but <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> has not budged from his deepest convictions. He was named Ukranian <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader 17 years ago to crack down on nationalism in the industrial and agricultural heartland of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. And he indicates nationalism is still one of his primary concerns. `` Nationalist ideas exist everywhere, but we can not allow people who stick to such absurdities to join perestroika,'' he told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. At 71, <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> is the oldest of the 12 men on the ruling Politburo and considered one of the most conservative. Except for reformist President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> himself, he is the only one left dating back to the late Soviet President <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>. <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON>, a Ukranian, also is the only party leader of a republic <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has not replaced since becoming general secretary in 1985. Reformers complain that <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> is preventing <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s changes from taking root in the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION>, a republic with a population of 50 million. But <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> made clear in written responses to questions submitted by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that he feels the earth moving under his feet. `` One can see signs of renewal with the naked eye,'' he wrote. His aides said they could not recall <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> ever responding to a foreign journalist's request for an interview. The Ukrainian leader refused, however, to take any follow-up questions, either in writing or in person. Shcherbitsky is blamed by some for covering up the radiation damage done by the <LOCATION> Chernobyl </LOCATION> nuclear power plant explosion, for restraining the local press and for arrests and harassment of dissidents whose political activities would be considered routine in the other European republics of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. He denied the charges. `` Some groups attempt to use glasnost and the public rostrum for alien propaganda, national egoism and even anti-Sovietism,'' he said. <PERSON> Schcherbitsky </PERSON> concedes the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION> is suffering from accumulated problems such as severe pollution. He said he responds to public opinion these days and, as evidence, he pointed to the scrapping of several nuclear power projects and a dam. In recent months, <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> has come under new pressures for change: <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has begun public criticism of the Ukrainian leadership, and several new reform groups have drawn thousands of people to public meetings. Six of his aides were defeated in their bids for additional positions of power in the recent election, the first in which citizens voted in large numbers against the establishment. `` I have to admit I have never run such an active and intensive election campaign,'' <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> wrote of his successful bid for a seat in the new Soviet parliament. He got 74 percent of the vote in the <LOCATION> Dnepropetrovsk </LOCATION> area, his old power base. The other 26 percent crossed his name off the ballot since there was no alternative candidate. Nine years ago, <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> smashed the <ORGANIZATION> Helsinki </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Watch </ORGANIZATION> human rights group in the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION> by arresting everyone who joined. Today those activists are out of prison, and some campaigned for his defeat in the election. Some spent a few weeks in jail for their efforts. The grassroots organizations have drawn thousands of people to meetings on ecology, expanded use of the Ukrainian language, legalization of the Ukrainian <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> and exposing the crimes of <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>. Many of them, <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> said, do n't understand that `` we need time, technology and money to make changes.'' He opposes the most general reform group, the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION>, accusing its leaders of ambition and nationalism that `` leads the way to permissiveness and national antagonism, contradicting the interests of perestroika.'' Though none of the major reform groups in the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION> is openly calling for independence, that is a growing source of conflict in several smaller areas of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Most recently, 20 Soviet Georgians died in unrest after troops broke up a pro-independence demonstration April 9. Ukrainian activist <PERSON> Oles </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevchenko </PERSON> says <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> remains in power because <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> needs him to clamp down on nationalism in the second most populous republic and because <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> voted for <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to become the Soviet leader in 1985. <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> confirmed that, `` I supported the election of <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Sergeevich </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> as general secretary.'' <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> said he has no `` principal disagreements'' with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, despite `` creative discussions'' in <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> meetings. `` A lively, friendly atmosphere has replaced artificial unanimity, and that is a clear and eloquent sign of the times,'' he wrote. <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> sprinkled his comments with references to perestroika, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reform program. He insisted the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION> is pressing ahead with farm leasing, glasnost and competitive elections, all keystones of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s plan. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is more blunt in his criticism of the Ukrainian leadership's performance. In a March party meeting, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> complained that billions of rubles poured into agriculture have been wasted. A 320 percent increase in investment in the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION> has bought only a 39 percent rise in output in two decades, he said. But <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> denied Soviet news reports that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> ordered <LOCATION> Ukrainian </LOCATION> party leaders to pay more attention to democratization and to work with progressive Ukrainian writers pressing for reform. `` <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> never raised this question,'' <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> said. He did acknowledge, however, that the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief `` expressed some critical remarks and offered advice, which we are considering.'' <PERSON> Shcherbitsky </PERSON> refused to comment on his reputation as a conservative opponent of domestic reforms, but emphasized that changes must be carefully monitored. `` After all, perestroika is harmed by sluggishness and stomping in one place, as well as by impulsive jumps and overreactions,'' he wrote.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lebanon-Shelter     05-11 0841</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon-Shelter,0877</SECOND>
<HEAD>Families Live on Nerves In Shelters During Barrages</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 For two months, residents of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> have spent much of their lives in bunkers and basements because of fierce artillery battles between Christians and Moslems. Here is a report on 10 hours in the life of one Moslem family.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By RIAD KAHWAJI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Munaymneh family and their neighbors tumbled into the underground shelter in their apartment block when a 155mm howitzer shell exploded in the street, signaling another round of fierce artillery battles in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. `` This is only the beginning,'' moaned <PERSON> Soumayya </PERSON> <PERSON> Munaymneh </PERSON>, 35, as she shepherded her two sons, <PERSON> Amer </PERSON>, 12, and <PERSON> Samer </PERSON>, 14, down the stairs on Tuesday. `` Will it ever stop?'' Most of the six families have spent most of the last two months cooped up in the makeshift 33-foot-by-19-foot shelter in the basement of the six-story block in the <LOCATION> Bourj </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Abu-Haidar </LOCATION> district of Moslem west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. The fierce artillery, rocket and tank battles that have raged between army commander Gen. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s mainly Christian forces and an alliance of Syrian soldiers and Moslem Druse militiamen have reached an intensity unprecedented in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s 14-year-old civil war. Some days, as many as 25,000 shells and rockets are fired by both sides. Mrs. <PERSON> Munaymneh </PERSON> clutched two bottles of drinking water. Her husband, <PERSON> Rafik </PERSON>, and the boys carried chairs, blankets and mattresses. `` Do n't forget anything, because we wo n't be able to come up and get it,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Munaymneh </PERSON> told the boys. Life for Christians and Moslems alike has become an endless cycle of waiting out the bombardments huddled in stuffy shelters or basement parking lots, then foraging for food and water or patching up their damaged homes and businesses during the lulls, nervously listening for the first thud of shellfire that heralds another barrage. There were 18 people in the shelter. They slipped into the routine of life underground while exploding shells and artillery guns thundered above them. The men lighted kerosene lanterns and huddled to talk politics. The women spread out mattresses in the `` sleeping corner'' and food supplies in the part of the shelter Mrs. <PERSON> Munaymneh </PERSON> called `` the dining room'' _ the area around a small cooker used to fix tea or coffee or to heat canned food. The children played cards. But everyone was tense as the explosions shook the shelter. The Munaymnehs, who are Sunni Moslems, have missed much of the recent shelling because, like thousands of other Beirutis, they fled the city. <PERSON> Rafik </PERSON> <PERSON> Munaymneh </PERSON>, a 52-year-old shipping agent, took his family to <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>. He brought them back to <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> on April 30, one day after <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> foreign ministers called for a cease-fire in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. `` We thought it was over after the Arabs announced the cease-fire, and we came back because the kids' school said it was resuming classes,'' <PERSON> Munaymneh </PERSON> said. `` Obviously, it was the wrong decision,'' he said. As the shells exploded, the children argued about the caliber and direction of the rounds. `` That's an outgoing tank shell,'' <PERSON> Samer </PERSON> said when a particularly loud blast thundered above. `` I bet it's that tank on the corner.'' <PERSON> Munaymneh </PERSON> grumbled: `` That tank's inviting trouble. The Christians will start shooting at it.'' A few minutes later five arillery rounds hit the neighborhood, one near the entrance to the apartment building. `` Oh Allah, have mercy on us!'' one of the 10 women yelled. The children screamed. `` Silence! Silence!'' <PERSON> Munaymneh </PERSON> shouted. `` We're all OK. Thank God, the shell did n't damage the shelter,'' he said. His wife and some of the other women recited verses from the Koran, Islam's holy book. The whispered prayers were drowned out by a flurry of news flashes on the half-dozen transistor radios, all tuned to different Christian and Moslem stations, reporting on which districts were getting pounded by <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s U.S.-made howitzers. The radios, the families' only link to the outside world, are kept on all the time. `` Is anyone talking about a new cease-fire?'' one of the women asked, her voice trembling. No one bothered to answer her. There have been dozens of cease-fires in the last two months. None lasted very long. The intensity of the barrage eased around midnight and <PERSON> Najwa </PERSON> <PERSON> Quoraitem </PERSON> ran up to her family's third-floor apartment to bring down some manakeesh _ Lebanese pizza made with thyme. `` You have to eat to survive _ that is, if the shells do n't get us,'' she murmured as she passed out the manakeesh. Another woman served tea. The barrage eased near dawn and the children fell asleep. The men took turns to go upstairs to check their apartments. `` The building next door took several direct hits,'' <PERSON> Munaymneh </PERSON> said when he came back. `` Some people were wounded. We'll find out exactly what happened later.'' At daybreak, the families left the shelter to return to their apartments. No one knew when the shelling would resume, only that it would. The Munaymnehs packed and headed back to <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>. Their neighbors prepared to spend another night underground.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0056EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AerostatDamaged     05-11 0276</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Aerostat Damaged,0282</SECOND>
<HEAD>Radar Balloon Damaged, Deflated by Swirling `Dust Devil'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SIERRA VISTA, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An $ 18 million Aerostat radar balloon operated by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> was damaged and deflated by swirling winds Wednesday while it was moored close to the ground, officials said. The helium-filled balloon, equipped with sophisticated look-down radar as an airborne deterrent to drug-smuggling, was struck by a dust devil, a mini-cyclone or miniature tornado, around 1:30 p.m., said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Conroy </PERSON>, a Customs spokesman in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Conroy </PERSON> said there were no injuries and there was no damage to other property at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huachuca </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> base in southeastern <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> where the balloon is tethered. Damages to the Aerostat have not been assessed yet. The Aerostat is 245 feet long, 72 feet in diameter and its hull is made of high-tech materials including Mylar and Tedlar. It weighs about 12,750 pounds, including the radar package of about 3,500 pounds, Customs officials have said. The Aerostat at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huachuca </LOCATION> was the first of a series being deployed along the U.S.-Mexico border. <PERSON> Conroy </PERSON> said one other Aerostat is in operation at <LOCATION> Deming </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, with another scheduled to go into operation at <LOCATION> Yuma </LOCATION>, `` hopefully next month.'' <PERSON> Conroy </PERSON> said the Aerostat at <LOCATION> Deming </LOCATION> has an overlapping range over the area covered by the damaged device. That, combined with military radar, Customs airborne and ground radar and air traffic control radar will make up for that on the downed balloon. Customs officials have said the balloon has been instrumental in successful tracking of several small aircraft carrying narcotics being smuggled into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. But critics have labeled the balloon a white elephant.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Afghanistan     05-11 0850</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghanistan,0847</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jalalabad Quiet after Weeks of Siege, Shelling</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 The government flew Western reporters to <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> for their first visit to the city since a guerrilla siege began March 7. Here is a report.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By SHARON HERBAUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JALALABAD, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The army says it has driven guerrillas away from <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION>, ending a nine-week siege, and on Wednesday the shelling had stopped in the 16th century city of gardens built by the Moguls. Children played in open spaces bright with lilacs. Afghan soldiers advanced up to 25 miles along two fronts in an offensive begun Sunday against Moslem insurgents surrounding the city, their commanders said. `` As you can see, <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> is alive,'' said Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Manok </PERSON> <PERSON> Mangall </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> council </ORGANIZATION> and governor of <LOCATION> Nangarhar </LOCATION> province. Leaders of the mujahedeen, the `` holy warriors'' who have fought for more than a decade, denied army claims of ending the siege, retaking the Samarkhel garrison and controlling half the road to the <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> border town of <LOCATION> Torkham </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Nabi </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammadi </PERSON>, defense minister of the guerrillas' exile government, told reporters in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>: `` It's a total lie.. baseless propaganda The siege of <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> continues. <PERSON> Samarkhel </PERSON> continues to be in the hands of mujahedeen, who also control the <LOCATION> Jalalabad-Torkham </LOCATION> road.'' President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>'s government flew 13 Western journalists to <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> to prove it controls the strategic provincial capital 75 miles east of <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION>, once known for magnificent gardens, orchards and palaces, has been under guerrilla siege since March 7. Military officials said the city, 45 miles from <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, had been pounded by 131,000 rockets and artillery and mortar shells. It lies near the Khyber Pass astride the trade routes to <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, dominating the entrances to the <LOCATION> Laghman </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kunar </LOCATION> valleys. The modern city was built in the 16th century by <PERSON> Akbar </PERSON>, grandson of <PERSON> Babur </PERSON>, who founded the Mogul empire of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. Army officials said at least 523 civilians had been killed and 3,000 wounded during the siege. They said most of the casualties occurred in the first weeks of the first major guerrilla offensive since Soviet military forces completed their withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> on Feb. 15. Doctors at <LOCATION> Nangarhar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> said nearly all the casualties were caused by rockets or shells. `` We do n't even have one patient with a bullet injury,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Hafizullah </PERSON>, director of the 260-bed hospital. Commanders of the guerrillas, who began fighting after a communist coup in April 1978, had predicted at the onset of their offensive that <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> would fall within days. They had hoped to set up their interim government in the city as a basis for international recognition as an alternative to <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>'s regime in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> The rebels are based in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and receive much of their support from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Reports from both sides have said <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> was in ruins, with nearly all the mud-and-brick buildings damaged or destroyed and the remaining residents hiding in ditches or basements. The scene in the dusty, rutted streets Wednesday suggested otherwise. Most buildings had been damaged by shellfire, but remained standing. Although shops generally were boarded shut, the city had electricity, running water and working telephones. Farmers worked in fields on the outskirts, harvesting their wheat and planting rice. Lilacs and wild flowers were in bloom and the city had an abundance of palm trees and small orchards. Children played in the sun and their elders moved about the city on bicycles and in horse-drawn carts, sharing the road with tanks, military jeeps and armored personnel carriers. Some neighborhoods were like ghost towns, however. More than 64,000 people lived in <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> when the civil war began, but many fled to <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> or to refugee camps in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. No count of how many remain is available, but some said they will never leave, despite hardship and war. `` What would we do? Where would we go? asked <PERSON> Bhargar </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, a 70-year-old doctor living in a Sikh temple. He said rockets had hit it five times, killing 24 people and wounding at least 100. Early in the battle for <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION>, the army surrendered key garrisons around the city and the guerrillas came within about six miles of the airport, which was hit by thousands of rockets. The runway was damaged, a cargo building leveled and the windows of the control tower knocked out. `` If it's necessary, planes can land, but I do n't remember when the last one landed,'' said Lt. Col. <PERSON> Jehangi </PERSON>, 42, the airport commander. Military officials have not said how many soldiers have been deployed in and around <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION>, but estimates run as high as 30,000. Nearly double that number of guerrillas were believed to surround the city at one time. When Soviet troops left <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> after nine years of involvement in the war, there were predictions that <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s conscript army would collapse Col. Gen. <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Delawar </PERSON>, army commander for the area, said of guerrilla claims of quick victory in <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> and the long siege that followed: `` There's an old Afghan proverb. When a man digs a well, he usually falls in.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-UNGuards     05-11 0215</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UN Guards,0222</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.N. Guards Told to Stand Straight and Spit Out The Gum</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER JAMES SPIELMANN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> security guards have been ordered to quit slouching, get those hands out of those pockets and spit out the gum as part of a campaign to brighten their image. A memorandum from <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connell </PERSON>, chief of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, reminds his officers they work under the eyes of diplomats and countless tourists and must observe proper military decorum. Among admonitions in his memorandum, obtained Wednesday: _ Smoking and chewing gum are forbidden while in uniform _ Carrying of bags, packages or other items while in uniform does not create a good image and is not permitted _ Leaning against walls or door jambs _ also out _ Guards with hands in pockets or thumbs hooked in belts look either lackadaisical or aggressive _ or both All members of the service must refrain from so doing. Regarding saluting, <PERSON> O'Connell </PERSON> wrote: `` There is an unacceptable lack of uniformity in this area. ... Members of the service at the rank of inspector and above will be saluted.'' Guards routinely salute Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> as their commander, but correspondents observed an outbreak of saluting since <PERSON> O'Connell </PERSON>'s memo began circulating on Friday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--NagyReburial     05-11 0162</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Nagy Reburial,0169</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hungarian TV to Carry Live Coverage of Populist's Reburial</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hungarian television will broadcast live the reburial of <PERSON> Imre </PERSON> <PERSON> Nagy </PERSON>, who was executed and interred in an unmarked grave after leading the country's 1956 anti-Soviet uprising, a newspaper reported. The remains of <PERSON> Nagy </PERSON> and his revolutionary associates were exhumed last month from the unmarked graves where they were buried in 1958. They are to be reburied on June 16. The plan underscores the current Communist leadership's willingness to acknowledge repressions that followed the popular uprising, which was crushed by Soviet forces The party has also shown readiness to appease public demands for broader democracy and economic reform. The independent daily <PERSON> Mai </PERSON> <PERSON> Nap </PERSON> quoted the television network's president, <PERSON> Gyula </PERSON> <PERSON> Bereczky </PERSON>, as announcing the plan for live coverage of the reburial He was also quoted as saying the network would broadcast a three-part documentary soon on events immediately after the Soviets moved to put down the uprising.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Welfare     05-11 0318</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Welfare,0330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ford Foundation Urges Changes In Social Programs</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, saying the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> social welfare system is out of date, has recommended comprehensive changes that include treatment on demand for drug and alcohol problems. The <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> report, entitled `` The Common Good: Social Welfare and the American Future,'' concedes that many of its recommendations face uphill political and monetary battles. The report was scheduled for release Thursday in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C </LOCATION>. Details were reported in Thursday editions of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. The Times said the <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> proposals would cost $ 29 billion beyond the $ 500 billion the federal government spends on social programs. The report recommended a tremendous expansion of the Head Start program to reach 900,000 more 3 - and 4-year-olds, and that the government pay for long-term care for the elderly The proposals would also cost the private sector an estimated $ 10 billion for employers to extend health insurance coverage for workers. The panel recommended paying for the additional programs by taxing Social Security benefits. Such a tax would raise more than half of the $ 29 billion annual cost of the recommended programs, the report said. The $ 3 million study was prepared by an 11-member panel of business, civic, labor and civil rights leaders and educators. `` We are on the right track calling attention to the country's social deficit,'' said <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shapiro </PERSON>, chairman of the panel and former chief executive of the <ORGANIZATION> Du </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> `` We know we have a hell of a fight ahead arousing people to do what needs to be done.'' One of the most ambitious proposals advocated by the panel is to provide drug and alcohol treatment `` on demand'' at an estimated $ 1 billion per year. It also called for expanding a food program, Women, Infants and Children, which now reaches half of the 6.5 million to 7.5 million people who are eligible.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w PM-SuntanStudy Bjt   05-11 0692</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Suntan Study, Bjt,0706</SECOND>
<HEAD>Expert Panel Says All Suntans Are ``Potentially Hazardous''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Those summer days spent soaking up the rays to create a glorious tan may come back to haunt sun worshippers with cancer and aged, wrinkled skin, a panel of experts said. A <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> consensus committee on Wednesday said current health studies show that suntans can lead to skin cancer, a weakened immune system and skin that wrinkles and ages before its time. Instead of uncovering to bathe in the noontime sun, the panel recommended Americans avoid the midday hours of sunlight, wear shading clothes and apply generous amounts of sunscreen lotions. Children in particular should be protected from overexposure to sunlight because skin damaged early in life is more likely to develop cancer later, the panel said in a report. `` All forms of tanning are potentially hazardous to the skin,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bickers </PERSON>, head of the panel and chairman of the dermatology department at <ORGANIZATION> Case </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>. `` Tanning is visible evidence of injury to the skin.'' <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schachner </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> paraphrased <PERSON> Noel </PERSON> <PERSON> Coward </PERSON> to note: `` Only mad dogs and Englishmen go out in midday sun. There are no healthy tans.'' <PERSON> Bickers </PERSON> said the panel recommended that: _ Everyone avoid direct exposure to sunlight, particularly during the hours of 10 a.m. to 3 p.m. when the ultraviolet rays coming from the sun are the strongest _ People exposed to sunlight should wear sunscreen lotion with a rating of 15 based on protection from ultraviolet B solar radiation The panel said ultraviolet A radiation also is hazardous, though much less so, and lotions that protect against both types of UV are best. <PERSON> Bickers </PERSON> said the panel found that lotions with a protection rating of 15 `` will assure that virtually everyone would get sufficient protection from the sun'' and that there is no evidence lotions with higher ratings provide additional protection. _ Tanning parlors should be avoided `` The panel consensus is to recommend against the use of tanning parlors for cosmetic purposes,'' said <PERSON> Bickers </PERSON>. People who do use tanning parlors should wear goggles to protect their eyes and should be aware that tanning lamps can damage the skin and cause adverse reactions in people taking antibiotics, hypertensive or anti-inflammatory drugs, the panel said. _ Though some people react adversely to chemicals contained in lotion sunscreens, the panel said the `` risk-benefit ratio'' favors the use of such lotions for people who must be exposed to the sun Said Bickers: `` Individuals in the Sunbelt should use sunscreens on a daily basis.'' _ Special precautions should be taken to protect children from damaging exposures to sunlight <PERSON> Schachner </PERSON>, an expert on children's skin, said that schools and day care centers should schedule outdoor recesses to avoid midday exposure to the sun He also said that outdoor play or lunch areas should be shaded. _ Damaging exposure to sunlight, particularly early in life, can lead directly to development of two types of common skin cancer, and there is a suggestion that sunlight may play a role in development of maglignant melanoma, an unusually vicious type of skin cancer _ Though Retin-A and other vitamin A-based compounds are widely used to treat the wrinkles in sun-damaged skin, <PERSON> Bickers </PERSON> said the panel found there was insufficient scientific evidence about `` the long-term safety'' of such products A 1978 study showed that about half a million people annually develop the common forms of skin cancer, said <PERSON> Bickers </PERSON>, but reports from skin doctors indicate `` it is highly likely that there is an increasing number of cases of non-melanoma cancers.'' He said chemicals are thought to be eroding the ozone layer of the stratosphere, thus allowing more ultraviolet radiation to reach the Earth's surface. And <PERSON> Bickers </PERSON> said the panel's research showed there are about 20,000 tanning salons in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> which are visited by an estimated one million customers. Both of these factors, he said, may be leading to increasing cases of skin cancers. The panel released the recommendations after reviewing studies and hearing testimony over a three-day period. The panel included 14 skin and cancer experts from nine states.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0158EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScienceEducation     05-11 0509</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Science Education,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>For Release 10 a.m. EDT; time set by source</HEAD>
<HEAD>Coalition Calls for Presidential Task Force on Math and Science Education</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A coalition aimed at improving the quality of science, math and technology education today recommended President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> form a White House task force on those subjects to develop a national policy. The non-profit <ORGANIZATION> Triangle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> also said the federal government should spend an extra $ 304 million in fiscal 1990, rising to $ 465 million in 1993, to promote elementary science, math and technology education improvements. The proposed presidential task force would develop a national policy, coordinate federal programs and plan a White House conference on `` Science, <ORGANIZATION> Mathematics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> for the year 2000.'' `` We have made a special effort to emphasize programs that do not require significant new funds,'' said the report released by the coalition of 80 business, labor, science and education groups. `` However, the very magnitude of the challenge the nation faces will call for some new programs and new resources.'' The action plan, designed to help <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the president develop a national policy on science education, states that `` increased investments in elementary education must be the nation's number one priority.'' Specifically, it suggests that the government start a $ 50 million grant program to help elementary schools pay for new science equipment and earmark another $ 50 million to encourage innovative approaches to science teaching. The group would also give the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> an extra $ 50 million to expand its in-service and pre-service training programs for elementary teachers. Other recommendations would require less money or none at all. Among them: _ Revamp the science curriculum to tailor it to students of different ages, interests and backgrounds, a project that should be led by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> _ Increase federal support for graduate training in the sciences and engineering, with special support to women and minorities _ Give clear instructions to schools receiving money under federal school improvement programs, totaling more than $ 1 billion a year, that their first priority must be science, math and technology education activities _ Reserve 5 percent of the nearly $ 9 billion the federal government spends on student loans, grants and scholarships for special programs aimed at attracting and retaining math, science and technology teachers at all academic levels _ Establish new federal incentives to encourage better teacher training _ Implement more stringent state requirements for science teachers _ Offer salary incentives for excellence in science and math teaching and strengthened continuing education requirements in the science area for elementary and secondary teachers The Triangle proposals are a follow-up to an earlier report that called for a sharply focused science education strategy. The group is affiliated with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Organizations represented by its officers include the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION>, E.I. <PERSON> Du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Amoco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Acoustical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Edison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> and various universities and state education groups.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     05-11 0847</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0882</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> is being sued for $ 75 million by an actress who contends he fired her from a film because she spurned his advances. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Michele </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, a 22-year-old <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> actress who performs under the name <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Michele </PERSON>, also sued <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> over her dismissal from the soon-to-be released <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> picture `` Harlem Nights.'' Ms. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> claimed that she was removed from the proposed television version of <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s hit film `` Coming to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' so she could appear opposite him in `` Harlem Nights,'' a film that he is also producing and directing. On the set of `` Harlem Nights,'' <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> `` made consistent, personal overtures'' that Ms. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> `` did not desire,'' the lawsuit said. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> tried `` to fondle and otherwise caress'' Ms. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> and had her fired `` when it became clear'' that she `` would not accede to his sexual demands,'' the lawsuit said. `` There's absolutely no basis'' to the allegations, said <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s manager, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Wachs </PERSON>. `` She was let go because of artistic differences.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON> says misunderstanding lies at the heart of most marriages. `` If the amusement park called Great Adventure had been created by me, it would have no slides or rides. ... It would simply have one married couple trying to sustain the glow of their love,'' <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON> wrote in his new book, `` Love and Marriage,'' excerpted in June's Good Housekeeping. <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON> says philosophers have long debated whether a husband and wife should go to bed angry at each other, but he has found two good reasons for making up at bedtime: `` It feels like the right moment for reconciliation and a fight is harder to sustain when one of the fighters falls asleep.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Academy Award winner <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Hackman </PERSON> and actress <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Archer </PERSON> will battle bad guys aboard a speeding train in a remake of the 1950's RKO thriller `` The Narrow Margin.'' <PERSON> Hackman </PERSON> will play a <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> district attorney trying to keep a murder witness _ Miss <PERSON> Archer </PERSON> _ safe from hit men. <PERSON> Hackman </PERSON> received the 1971 Oscar for best actor for his role as the cop <PERSON> Popeye </PERSON> <PERSON> Doyle </PERSON> in `` The French Connection.'' He was nominated as best supporting actor for `` <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> and <PERSON> Clyde </PERSON>'' and `` I Never Sang for My Father,'' and was nominated as best actor this year for his portrayal of an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent in `` Mississippi Burning.'' Miss <PERSON> Archer </PERSON> was nominated for best supporting actress last year for her role as the wronged wife in `` Fatal Attraction.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ANNAPOLIS, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Director <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON> says <PERSON> Dustin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> `` was terrific to work with,'' despite warnings he had received to the contrary. <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON>, who won a best director <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> for `` Rain Man,'' said <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> and his wife went to the hospital with <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON> and his wife when Mrs. <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON> gave birth during filming in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>. `` It caused a lot of commotion in the hospital,'' he said. `` A lot of friends of mine said it would be tough'' working with <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>, but that was n't the case, <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON> said. `` He was terrific to work with.'' <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON> also said it was fun going out on the town in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> with <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> DeVito </PERSON> during the filming of `` Tin Men'' because <PERSON> DeVito </PERSON> `` is not afraid to get out among the people.'' Even though `` Rain Man'' won him an Oscar, <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON> said `` Diner'' is probably his personal favorite `` because it was the first one'' and because he was able to write it, direct it and then film it in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, where he grew up. The director said he hopes to begin filming his newest movie in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> this summer.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Version moved on sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>SADDLE BROOK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A jury has acquitted <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION> linebacker <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> of drunken driving charges that were filed after police found him slumped behind the wheel of his car. `` The justice system works and I'm happy for myself,'' the eight-time All-Pro said. Municipal Court Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Conte </PERSON> found <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> innocent based on testimony from two doctors who said the <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> star suffered from acute food poisoning on the night of his arrest. Authorities alleged <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> was found sleeping at 3:30 a.m. March 24 behind the wheel of his Jeep, which was parked on the shoulder of the Garden State Parkway. He was charged with drunken driving despite two blood alcohol level readings of 0.09 percent. Under <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> law, 0.10 percent is considered drunk.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Baseball great <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Yastrzemski </PERSON> acquired his taste for good food on his family's <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> farm, where he says they raised their own fruits, vegetables and livestock. <PERSON> Yastrzemski </PERSON>, a recently signed spokesman for the beef industry, will soon be giving advice to recreational athletes about diet, health and staying fit. He will address the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beef </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beef </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> on Monday. In July, <PERSON> Yastrzemski </PERSON> will be inducted into baseball's Hall of Fame. During his 23 seasons with the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sox </ORGANIZATION>, he was the first <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> player to record 400 home runs and 3,000 hits.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0608EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--BrothelBuyout     05-11 0142</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Brothel Buyout,0148</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stock Offering in Nevada Brothel Fails</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Wallstreet cq</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RENO, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An attempt to create <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s first publicly held brothel has flopped for lack of interest, but the underwriter says he will try to restructure the sale of the Mustang Ranch. <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Walloga </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wallstreet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday his company had negotiated an extension of the sale until Oct. 31. Meantime, buyers of shares in the bordello will get their money back, according to a statement from <LOCATION> Walloga </LOCATION>'s company in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. Wednesday was the deadline for the 3-month-old bid to take the <ORGANIZATION> Mustang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ranch </ORGANIZATION> public through a $ 23.3 million stock offering at $ 20 a share <PERSON> Walloga </PERSON> has said his company is about $ 5 million short of its goal. The 102-room brothel 10 miles east of <PERSON> Reno </PERSON> is owned by <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> <PERSON> Conforte </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0152EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People-Moore 1stLd-Writethru a0428 05-11 0235</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People-Moore, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0428,0237</SECOND>
<HEAD>Best-Selling Author Sentenced in Tax Shelter Scheme</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 3 grafs to fix garble, picks up 5th graf pvs, `Federal
prosecutors...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BRIDGEPORT, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Best-selling author <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, who wrote `` The Green Berets'' and `` The French Connection,'' was sentenced to five years probation Wednesday for his role in defrauding the federal government of $ 5 million through the sale of illegal literary tax shelters. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Court Judge T.F. <PERSON> Gilroy </PERSON> <PERSON> Daly </PERSON> gave <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> a five-year suspended sentence and ordered him to pay a $ 500 fine and complete 500 hours of community service. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, 63, who used the pen name <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, pleaded guilty in April 1986 to one count of conspiracy to defraud the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and agreed to cooperate with the government. Federal prosecutors have said <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> conspired with <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chipman </PERSON>, former owner of the <ORGANIZATION> Hartford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hellions </ORGANIZATION> indoor soccer team, to defraud the government of tax revenues through a scheme involving the sale of royalty rights to grossly over-valued books. <PERSON> Chipman </PERSON>, who is serving an 18-month sentence in connection with the scheme, was accused of marketing five tax-sheltered investments involving six books <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> co-authored, published or loaned his name to. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> did not return a telephone call to his <LOCATION> Concord </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, home seeking comment Wednesday night. The telephone at the <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, office of <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaynor </PERSON>, went unanswered Wednesday night.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0242EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Grumpy'sTravels     05-11 0369</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Grumpy's Travels,0381</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stolen Lawn Dwarf Returned with Pictures From His Travels</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAUGERTIES, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Grumpy the traveling lawn dwarf is back where he belongs, concrete feet planted firmly on the porch, following his whirlwind tour of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and elsewhere. He even has pictures from his vacation. The 20-inch, 80-pound concrete statue of the character in the Walt Disney movie classic `` Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs,'' disappeared March 16 from <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Horne </PERSON>'s front porch. `` I could n't set my finger on it, but I felt something was missing,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Horne </PERSON> said. `` The next morning my daughter said, ` Mom, there's somebody missing.''' Bashful, <PERSON> Doc </PERSON>, Sneezy, Happy, Sleepy, Dopey and the 400-pound Snow White were safe and sound but Grumpy was gone. On April 26, a freshly scrubbed <PERSON> Grumpy </PERSON> returned, with a sign dangling from his shoulders that said `` I'm home.'' Along with the sign was an envelope with 35 photographs from his journey, many of them with captions on the back. Among the photos were snapshots of Grumpy ogling bikini-clad women from a <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> sand dune, standing in front of the Lincoln Memorial in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, and dining at <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>. `` My husband and I, we were laughing so hard at these pictures. My husband was late for work,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Horne </PERSON> said. Grumpy's travels also included visits to <LOCATION> Yankee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <PERSON> North </PERSON> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Horne </PERSON> said <PERSON> Grumpy </PERSON> has vanished before, turning up once in front of an ice cream store and in the back seat of a restaurant manager's car. `` She saw somebody looking over her shoulder and started screaming. He was just standing there with his arms folded and that snarl on his face,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Horne </PERSON> said. She said neither she nor the police had any idea who took Grumpy. She theorizes that `` it's someone with an engineering background. The printing on the back of the pictures is very similar to the type you see on blueprints.'' This year's vacation could be Grumpy's last. Mrs. <PERSON> Horne </PERSON> said she planned on having all the dwarfs cemented in place. Nevertheless, she admits to envying Grumpy's wandering ways. `` He gets to go everywhere. I never get to go anywhere.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0247EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     05-11 0342</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0357</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State police are going to use Mustangs to corral speeders this summer. <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mustangs </ORGANIZATION>, that is. The high-powered variety that can reach 140 mph. The customized cars can travel about 20 mph faster than standard patrol cars and have concealed flashing lights and antennas so they can travel incognito. `` We have people who tell us they're driving the speed limit and they're getting blown off the road,'' said <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Ledding </PERSON>. `` We're hoping these cars slow things down.'' The $ 13,000 cars feature 5-liter, V-8 engines and special tires and wheels for stability at high speeds. They will have a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> emblem only on the driver's door, but motorists wo n't be able to recognize them as police cars unless they are alongside them.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> and his bride, <PERSON> Jean </PERSON>, believe love is timeless and ageless. Timeless because their courtship lasted only two weeks. Ageless because they're both octogenarians. <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON>, 80, and his 81-year-old wife were living separate lives at Victory Village, one of two retirement communities operated by the Jewish Homes for the Aging of <LOCATION> Greater </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. They met in the dining room in March. `` We just started talking to each other. I did like her. I figured she was just about the size I wanted _ not too tall and not too fat,'' said <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON>. `` He was just a nice person to talk to,'' his wife said. `` That's all I was looking for.'' On their first and second dates, they attended Victory Village dances, just `` old-fashioned waltzes,'' <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> explained, because `` my legs are not as fit as they used to be.'' Their courtship lasted two weeks and they were married March 26. Mrs. <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> said she was `` surprised when he proposed and I accepted. He caught me at the right moment.'' He noted it `` was a little hard to propose but she made it easy for me.'' They still have n't had an argument. `` We do n't have any money to fight for,'' <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> quipped.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0609EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--BarrowSunrise 1stLd-Writethru a0448 05-11 0134</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Barrow Sunrise, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0448,0131</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sun Rises In Barrow For Long Day</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Restores EDT in 2nd graf</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BARROW, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When the sun poked above the horizon here early today it marked the beginning of about three months of round-the-clock daylight. Sunset today was at 2:06 a.m. -LRB- 6:06 a.m. EDT -RRB-, followed 34 minutes later by sunrise, said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Vise </PERSON>, acting manager of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Weather Service station here. The sun will not set again until 2:19 a.m. Aug. 2, he said. Even with the sun briefly dipping below the horizon each day recently, it virtually has been light all the time. But lifetime resident <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said the light does not bother residents of the tiny community. `` It is exciting when the sun comes back up,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0248EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Health     05-11 0446</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Health,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Exercise Keeps President in ``Excellent Health''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has been declared in sound health and advised to keep up the exercise regimen his physician says helps keep him fit. Although <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> emerged from <ORGANIZATION> Bethesda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday with an adhesive bandage on a finger, he was pronounced in `` excellent health'' by his personal physician, Dr. <PERSON> Burton </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, after his first full-scale medical checkup as chief executive. The bandage covered a cyst that was treated, and which <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> said is not a medical problem. `` President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is in extremely sound physical condition,'' <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> said in a statement issued by the White House. `` He keeps fit through a number of physical activities, which we recommend he continue on a regular basis.'' <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> led a team of physicians _ including an ophthalmologist, a urologist, a dermatologist and two allergists _ that conducted the three-hour examination. The statement said a `` sebaceous cyst'' on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s middle right finger was drained. `` The president is wearing a Band-Aid on the finger, which he can remove within the next few hours,'' <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> said. `` This cyst has been present for many years and does not present a medical problem.'' A sebaceous cyst is a benign growth on the skin that is often removed surgically. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is an avid jogger, plays tennis, pitches horseshoes, occasionally swims and uses a stationary bicycle and indoor treadmill. The White House statement said a chest X-ray, an electrocardiogram, blood samples and a urinalysis all showed normal results. Other X-rays showed mild degenerative arthritis of the hip. That condition `` has been present for several years,'' the statement said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has said the arthritis has forced him in recent years to cut down on his jogging. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> takes medication because of a severe allergy to bee stings and to control hay fever. Wednesday's medical statement said `` allergy tests showed excellent protective antibody levels.'' The White House did not make immediately available statistics from the examination, such as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s cholesterol count and blood pressure. However, deputy press secretary <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> said some additional data might be released later. <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> said Wednesday's examination showed no major changes from the results of last year's tests, which showed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s cholesterol count at 192, considered in the desirable range by the American <ORGANIZATION> Heart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. His blood pressure then was a normal 108 @ 84. More complete information was released from the May 1988 test, when <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was a presidential candidate. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> himself displayed his pleasure with the results of the physical by grinning and flashing giving a double thumbs-up sign when asked how he felt as he arrived at the White House from the hospital.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0303EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SteelImports     05-11 0487</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Steel Imports,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Agency Study Enlivens Debate Over Steel Import Quotas</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> study helps document the claim by a manufacturers' group that steel import quotas have harmed the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy, the group says. The <ORGANIZATION> ITC </ORGANIZATION> said in a report Wednesday that steel import restraints have reduced American export sales by raising steel prices. The 96-page report by the independent government agency was certain to enliven the debate over whether the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> should continue steel quota agreements with 19 nations and the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration negotiated five-year, product-by-product voluntary restraint agreements, or `` VRAs,'' in 1984 with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and other nations to limit the flow of foreign steel into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has pledged to continue the restraints in some form beyond their Sept. 30 expiration date. But with the steel industry newly profitable, opponents of the curbs believe they can make a case for ending the program, or at least narrowing its scope. The <ORGANIZATION> ITC </ORGANIZATION> said in the report that the curbs caused steel prices in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to rise by as much as 0.6 percent in 1985, 1.6 percent in 1986, 1.4 percent in 1987 and 0.2 percent in 1988. It said the weakening of the dollar overseas and other factors also contributed significantly to further price hikes. As a result of the VRA-induced price increases, the commission estimated American exports in steel-consuming industries decreased by $ 258 million in 1985, $ 673 million in 1986, $ 699 million in 1987 and $ 95 million in 1988. `` It makes no sense to renew a program that causes such harm to American competitiveness,'' particularly when the steel industry is healthy, said <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenson </PERSON>, spokesman for a coalition of more than 300 manufacturers opposed to the import curbs' extension. Applauding the report's conclusions, <PERSON> Jenson </PERSON> said American manufacturers have been `` hamstrung'' by higher steel prices. The report said recent steel price hikes `` have been distributed unevenly among categories of customers.'' Price increases were not as great for large steel purchasers as for small ones, apparently because the larger purchasers buy a great deal of their steel through long-term contracts with prices set in advance, the <ORGANIZATION> ITC </ORGANIZATION> said. The question of whether the restraints have caused steel price increases has divided American manufacturers. Last month, a coalition of 374 manufacturers led by <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Maytag </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and others was formed to lobby for continuing the quota agreements on grounds that the curbs have helped make the steel industry healthier. That coalition contends steel price increases have been caused by strong worldwide demand and shifting exchange rates. The <ORGANIZATION> ITC </ORGANIZATION> cautioned the figures reflected an `` upward bias'' because of the procedures it used. That means the effect of the import restraints on prices might have been overstated. The study was conducted at the request of the House Ways and Means subcommittee on trade.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0253EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-USMilitary-Panama     05-11 0721</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US Military-Panama,1st Ld-Writethru,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon Says American Military Following Panama Treaties</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Corrects spokeswoman's name in 2nd graf to `Wood' sted `Wod'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYNA BRENNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> armed forces are quietly forging ahead with plans to phase out their bases along the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>, despite threats in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> military intervention following this week's allegedly fraudulent election. `` In all this hubbub we are doing our job,'' Maj. <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wood </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman, said Wednesday. The 10,000 or so troops and the 14,000 dependents, however, were put on a heightened alert, urging them to `` stay close to home'' following violent demonstrations in downtown <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Col. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON>, deputy public affairs director for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, described the measure as a `` precaution,'' adding: `` It's business as usual as far as the units go.'' The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> personnel are based at 10 military installations along the 50-mile long <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canal </ORGANIZATION>, which cuts a swath through the isthmus to join the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> oceans. Their mission mandated by the 1977 <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> Canal Treaties is twofold: to protect the waterway but to prepare to turn that job over to the Panamanians on Dec. 31, 1999. A so-called neutrality treaty, however, provides an open-ended American military presence to guarantee the `` permanent neutrality and operation'' of the canal. Alleged election fraud by <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s de facto ruler, Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, sparked new waves of internal discontent and renewed speculation at home the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would send in military reinforcements. Some in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> have suggested outright intervention to topple <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s regime, although <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration sources have described that as unlikely. <PERSON> Wood </PERSON>, asked about possible plans to send added <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> troops, said: `` I ca n't speak with regard to future military activities.'' But a military source, who spoke on the condition of anonymity, said: `` As I understand it, that is not being given serious consideration.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has not recognized <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s government since last year, shortly after he was indicted on federal drug trafficking charges. American military personnel in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> for the past year have been the targets of harassment, reportedly by <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s Defense Forces troops. On Wednesday, for example, five <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel were detained. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> frequently accuses the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> of attempting to renege on turning over the canal and on getting the troops out. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, however, is making plans to move the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, which manages American military operations south of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> to the tip of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The tropical, white-washed buildings will be transferred to the Panamanians no later than the end of the century. `` There's nothing to preclude a move before then,'' <PERSON> Wood </PERSON> said. Seven sites for the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> have been announced and a decision could come by the end of July, the spokeswoman said. Under consideration are <ORGANIZATION> MacDill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> near <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Patrick </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> near <LOCATION> Cocoa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>,; <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Polk </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Leesville </LOCATION>, La,; <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> near <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION>, La,; the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Station </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Brooks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> and Fort <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Houston </PERSON>, both in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. American troops have been based in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> since shortly after the nation's independence from <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> in 1903, peaking during World War II when some 67,000 military personnel were there. Despite its stated mission to protect the canal, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military has used <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> to garner intelligence on the Sandinista government in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and the leftist guerrillas fighting in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. When the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> treaties went into effect on Oct. 1, 1979, the American military began turning over its territory and property. Bases turned over the <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> so far include <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Amador </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Albrook </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Field </ORGANIZATION>, both near <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, more than 125 military homes in the former Canal Zone, and <PERSON> Fort </PERSON> <PERSON> Gulick </PERSON>, home of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s School of the <LOCATION> Americas </LOCATION> for 35 years, which became a training school for the Panamanians. Under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> control, the school trained some 44,000 Latin American military personnel and was widely called `` the school of the dictators.'' The School of the <LOCATION> Americas </LOCATION> today operates at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Benning </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga </LOCATION>. The remaining <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> presence in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> includes the Jungle Operations Training Center at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sherman </LOCATION> along the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>, a Special Forces battalion, a military intelligence battalion, an infantry brigade, <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> and Naval operations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0329EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ImmigrationReform     05-11 0328</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Immigration Reform,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Witnesses Say Thousands Exploited, Forced Into Underground Existence</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Immigration reforms have created a `` vulnerable underclass living in the shadows of our communities,'' immigration rights activists told a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel. Thousands of undocumented aliens who do not qualify for amnesty are `` being forced into a fearful underground and impoverished existence,'' said <PERSON> Muriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Heiberger </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Immigrant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refugee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advocacy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION>. The Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986 act allowed undocumented aliens who could show they entered the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> before 1982 to apply for amnesty and prohibited employers from hiring undocumented aliens. But witnesses told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on immigration, refugees and international law the law has left many harshly exploited and with nowhere to turn. `` As the undocumented are forced further underground, the immigration law is creating everything it was supposed to eliminate _ a vulnerable underclass, living in the shadows of our communities, facing increased poverty and exploitation,'' Ms. <PERSON> Heiberger </PERSON> testified. Unscrupulous employers `` often exploit undocumented workers fearful of reporting subminimum wages, sexual harassment and unsafe working conditions,'' she said. <PERSON> Muzaffar </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chishti </PERSON>, director of the Immigration Project for the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ladies </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Garment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, said the law has had a deep impact on the so-called `` sweatshop sector.'' Employers are `` finding it easier to exploit these workers and further depress wages and working conditions,'' she said. <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Verne </PERSON> <PERSON> Jervis </PERSON> countered that those who do n't qualify for amnesty do not have to remain in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <PERSON> Jervis </PERSON> said the law was not intended `` to benefit the most recent arrivals. ... The law is doing what it intended to do'' by keeping undocumented aliens out of the work force. <PERSON> Cecilia </PERSON> <PERSON> Munoz </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Raza </ORGANIZATION> testified that spouses and children of legalized family members have had deportation proceedings initiated against them in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> and elsewhere. <PERSON> Jervis </PERSON> called that charge `` ridiculous.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890511-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-89 0240EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Panama 13thLd-Writethru   05-11 0978</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama, 13th Ld-Writethru,a0450,1019</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Government Nullifies Election After Day of Violence, Blames U.S.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS throughout with U.S. Embassy comment, U.S. dependents
moved, report that Endara injured in second attack, details. No Pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOSEPH B. FRAZIER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
