<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-India-Karnataka     04-22 0204</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-India-Karnataka,0212</SECOND>
<HEAD>Assembly in Indian State Dissolved</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The central government on Friday dissolved the legislative assembly of opposition-ruled <LOCATION> Karnataka </LOCATION> state and put the state under federal rule, news reports said. Federal Home Minister <PERSON> Buta </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> told Parliament the move in the southern state came after the <ORGANIZATION> Janata </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dal </ORGANIZATION> party lost its majority, the reports said. By law, a new state assembly must be elected within a year. The Press Trust of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> news agency said <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>'s announcement was made amid protests from opposition members. <ORGANIZATION> Janata </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dal </ORGANIZATION>, headed by former Defense Minister V.P. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, held 111 of the 222 seats in the house. It also was supported by seven independent members. <PERSON> Buta </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> said the party lost its majority after 19 legislators withdrew support. He said Gov. <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Venkatsubbiah </PERSON> reccomended dissolution of the assembly to President <PERSON> Ramaswamy </PERSON> <PERSON> Venkataraman </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> PTI </ORGANIZATION> quoted <LOCATION> Karnataka </LOCATION> Chief Minister S.R. <PERSON> Bommai </PERSON> as saying he had the support of 120 members in the house. <PERSON> Bommai </PERSON>, leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Janata </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dal </ORGANIZATION> party in the state, said wide opposition would arise if the assembly was dissolved, <ORGANIZATION> PTI </ORGANIZATION> reported from <LOCATION> Bangalore </LOCATION>, the capital of <LOCATION> Karnataka </LOCATION>. The federal government is led by Prime Minister <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Soviet-SubwayBombs     04-22 0137</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Subway Bombs,0140</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Homemade Bombs Discovered In Subway Stations</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities defused two homemade bombs, one with a timing device, found in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> subway stations, a <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said Friday. <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON> said the first device was spotted by passengers in a subway car at the <LOCATION> Paveletskaya </LOCATION> station. `` The bag seemed to belong to no one and contained a plastic bag wrapped in a newspaper,'' he said. <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> officers and subway security personnel found a pipe bomb inside the bag, <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON> said. The device was attached to an electric alarm clock and wired with batteries, he said. A similar device, without a clock, was discovered about an hour later at the Vdnkh metro station, the spokesman said. `` Both episodes appear to be linked,'' <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON> said. `` The <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> has begun an investigation.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Britain-Media     04-22 0796</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Britain-Media,0820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thatcher Accused Of Curbing Press Freedom</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MAUREEN JOHNSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Responding to demands in Parliament for curbs on press intrusions into private lives, mainly by <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s racy tabloid newspapers, the government on Friday announced an independent review panel and told editors `` to clean up their act.'' Home Office Minister <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Renton </PERSON> said the panel would report within a year. `` Editors and publishers of the national press in this country are on probation,'' <PERSON> Renton </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION>. `` They have a year or two to clean up their act.'' British media freedom, meanwhile, came under unprecedented scrutiny at an international conference on Friday, spurred by charges that Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s government has undermined the public's right to know. The announcement in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> came as the group of editors, publishers, broadcast executives and journalists debated news media freedom at a one-day seminar sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. The watchdog body, which has a membership of 2,000 publishers and editors in some 60 countries, normally focuses attention on government harassment of newspapers or journalists in Third World countries. Political charges that the <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> government has undermined press freedom, and complaints about excesses by mass circulation newspapers are the two big issues in a growing controversy about the news media in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. On the political front, editors cite a government ban on broadcast interviews with the <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, far-reaching official secrets laws and a three-year court battle over government attempts to block publication of `` Spycatcher,'' a retired intelligence agent's memoirs. But newspapers have themselves been increasingly criticized for sensational stories that boost circulations of the major tabloids, which each sell more than a million copies a day. `` What is disturbing is the fact that the government can get away with this without the public caring,'' said <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON>, editor of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s pro-conservative <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION>. `` The British public is disenchanted with the press. The chief issue is how we raise our standards so that the British public will care about the press.'' <LOCATION> Renton </LOCATION> announced the press review panel after a `` right of reply'' bill foundered Friday in the Commons for lack of government backing. The bill, put forward by a rank-and-file legislator, <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Worthington </PERSON>, sought to empower the government to force newspapers to publish corrections of errors. The bill attracted considerable support from government and opposition legislators, but <LOCATION> Renton </LOCATION> rejected it on grounds `` it would introduce a measure of government control over the press.'' Supporters accused the tabloids of what one called `` replacing journalism with voyeurism.'' `` The reporter's profession has been infiltrated by a seedy stream of rent boys, pimps, bimbos, spurned lovers, smear artists with grudges, prostitutes and perjurers,'' said <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Aitken </PERSON>, a rank-and-file <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> legislator. `` This is a cast of shame.'' Apart from racy stories about the private lives of people from TV stars to accident victims, the tabloids regularly incur the wrath of Buckingham Palace for pursuit of the royal family. At the seminar, an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> participant, <PERSON> Dana </PERSON> <PERSON> Bullen </PERSON>, director of the Washington-based <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, contrasted British and American treatment of the news media. `` Where there is an Official Secrets Act here, we have a Freedom of Information Act,'' said <PERSON> Bullen </PERSON>. <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Neil </PERSON>, editor of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Sunday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, the top-selling upmarket weekly in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, led complaints by editors and broadcast chiefs about government use of court orders. During the controversy over `` Spycatcher,'' national newsapers were barred at each stage by orders, called `` prior restraints,'' from publishing. `` There is a culture in this country against the freedom of the press because ... the government and the judges belong to the same club,'' said <PERSON> Neil </PERSON>, referring to the British establishment. `` We must have the freedom to publish and then take the consequences.'' In a series of disputes since Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> won power in 1979, the government has also clashed with television networks, usually over features and documentaries involving the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> or the intelligence services. Also, media and civil rights groups charge that a bill to reform the catchall 1911 Official Secrets Act is inadequate. One example they cite is the government's refusal to allow civil servants who leak classfied information to argue they acted in the national interest to expose a government cover-up. Earlier Friday, a British delegate at a a meeting of 35 nations to monitor a recent East-West accord on media freedom said the attitude of Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s government toward the media `` alarms us.'' <PERSON> Neal </PERSON> <PERSON> Acherson </PERSON>, a columnist in the Observer, a liberal <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> weekly, said the <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> government tradition of organized unattributable briefings by officials to domestic political correspondents conflicted with the East-West accord. The accord was signed last January by the 35 nations at the end of of the Conference on European Security and Cooperation in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0013EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Soviet-Election     04-22 0276</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Election,0283</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dissident Priest, Four Others Removed from Ballot in Moscow District</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The names of dissident priest <PERSON> Gleb </PERSON> <PERSON> Yakunin </PERSON> and four other announced candidates were removed Friday from a ballot for the new Soviet parliament, a colleague reported. <PERSON> Yakunin </PERSON>, a Russian Orthodox priest, and the four were blocked from the ballot in a central district in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> on grounds they did n't live or work in the district, said <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Popkov </PERSON>, a Christian activist who attended the district meeting at the <ORGANIZATION> ZIL </ORGANIZATION> car factory. Soviet election laws have no residency requirements. Many of those already elected to the new <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> Deputies were selected by organizations they did not belong to or from districts where they do not reside. <PERSON> Popkov </PERSON> said about 750 electors were at the district meeting, and he said they were picked `` in a crude move on the part of the top echelon'' of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. He said the head of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> agreed to meet Saturday with <PERSON> Yakunin </PERSON> and the other rejected candidates to hear their complaints. None of the five was allowed to present his platform at the meeting and no election commission member was present to count the votes, <PERSON> Popkov </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. <PERSON> Yakunin </PERSON> was suspended from his religious duties for 20 years and imprisoned for dissident activities. After more than six years in prison and exile in <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION> he was released in March 1987 and assigned to a small parish near <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Popov </PERSON> said the four other rejected candidates were two writers, a criminal investigator and a military officer. The names of 11 candidates were placed on the district ballot.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0028EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-RejectedRefugees     04-22 0269</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rejected Refugees,0276</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fifth Chartered Flight Departs South Padre Island For Central America</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BROWNSVILLE, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group of 120 refugees was put on a jetliner and returned to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> in the latest mass deportation of illegal aliens by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The flight of the INS-chartered <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737 was the fifth such flight since Feb. 21, when the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> began a crackdown on undocumented aliens crossing the <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION>. A previous charter flight of 231 aliens left <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> on March 13 and was believed to be the largest mass deportation by the INS. More than 1,300 Central Americans have been deported since the crackdown began. The refugees _ some smiling, other sulking _ were processed out of the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> detention camp near <LOCATION> Bayview </LOCATION> and filed into four buses bound for the <LOCATION> Brownsville-South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Padre </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. There were no Nicaraguans on the flight, although more than a quarter of the 1,250 detainees at the camp are from <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. Nicaraguans are the only nationality to have escaped the crackdown, thanks to a directive issued by then-Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, in July 1987. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> requested that the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> encourage asylum applications and work authorizations for refugees fleeing the leftist Nicaraguan government. Deportation for Nicaraguans must be approved by <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> D.C </ORGANIZATION>. Among the immigrants deported Thursday were 68 Salvadorans, 38 Guatemalans and 14 Hondurans. The <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> said 703 refugees applied for asylum in the <LOCATION> Harlingen </LOCATION> district since Feb. 21. Of those applicants, 72 Nicaraguans and six Salvadorans were granted asylum. The rest were detained to be sent back to their homelands.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DefenseCuts Bjt   04-22 0677</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Cuts, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Reportedly Favors Mix of MX, Midgetman</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is reportedly planning to recommend a mix of single-warhead Midgetman and multiple warhead MX missiles in a budget decision that will determine the future of the nation's nuclear arsenal. A <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> source, who declined to be identified, said Friday that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s decision was `` expected to be some kind of mix of rail garrison MX and Midgetman, but the final mix is to be determined.'' The decision represents a setback for <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>, who reportedly favored deploying only one mobile missile, the 10-warhead MX. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was supposed to make a final decision this weekend and inform <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>. <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> had urged <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to remove the nation's 50 MX missiles from their concrete silos and put them on railroad cars to be shuttled around the country _ an option known as the rail garrison MX. He reportedly wanted to cut off funding for the truck-mobile Midgetman. The decision on the missiles was one of several that must be made as <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION> tries to cut $ 10 billion from the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget. According to congressional and <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> sources, both Star Wars and the B-2 stealth bomber face the budget ax when <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> announces his choices at a congressional hearing on Tuesday. <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION> plans to scale back work on the B-2, which at recent estimates of $ 500 million per plane is the most expensive aircraft in history, while cutting funding for Star Wars. Details on the proposal for the B-2 were not immediately available, the sources, who requested anonymity, said Friday. Star Wars, of the <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Initiative </ORGANIZATION>, would be cut to $ 4.8 billion for the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> in fiscal 1990. Former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who made Star Wars his top priority, had asked for $ 5.9 billion in fiscal 1990 and $ 7 billion in 1991, a sharp increase from the $ 4.5 billion allocated for the program this year. The total defense budget stands at $ 299.2 billion _ $ 10 billion less than the budget former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> submitted in January and in accordance with the cut agreed upon a week ago by the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The defense secretary discussed the shrinking military budget at a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> meeting with the chairmen and ranking members of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committees </ORGANIZATION> and the leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations defense subcommittee. <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION>'s plan calls for the elimination of funding for the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>' V-22 Osprey troop transport aircraft, retirement of one of two aging aircraft carriers _ the <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> or the Midway _ when the <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> is commissioned in 1990. Such a retirement would maintain the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> carrier force at 14 instead of the 15 sought by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. The defense secretary is also planning to shift 24 frigates to reserve status and cancel $ 1.4 billion procurement of the F-14D Tomcat fighter jets. <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> also retained <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s plan to eliminate funding for the last two submarines in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> class, SSN688, in favor of the newer class SSN21. In addition, <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> plans to mothball a handful of B-52s; delay the Millstar program, an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>'s communications satellite program; and cancel the Army Helicopter Improvement Program. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had proposed spending $ 210 million in 1990 for Millstar and $ 299 million for the <ORGANIZATION> AHIP </ORGANIZATION>. Buys of the Blackhawk UH-60A would be reduced from 83 to 72 and purchases of the F-15E would be reduced to zero. That program had been earmarked for $ 1.7 billion in the fiscal 1990 budget. Army force structure would be reduced by 5 percent with cuts in the number of people employed at headquarters and in procurement. Those attending the meeting with <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> were <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, ranking Republican on the panel; Rep. <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>, D-Wis., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>; Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, ranking Republican on the panel; Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Murtha </PERSON>, D-Pa.; and Rep. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> McDade </PERSON>, R-Pa., the chairman and ranking member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0110EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BudgetDeficit Bjt   04-22 0612</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget Deficit, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shortfall 7.4 Percent Over Last Year; March Deficit Highest in Three
Years</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NANCY BENAC</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first half of fiscal 1989 ended with a budget deficit that is running 7.4 percent ahead of last year's, according to the government's latest report on its financial situation. For the first six months of the 1989 fiscal year, which began Oct. 1, the budget deficit totaled $ 128.43 billion, up from the $ 119.61 billion shortfall posted in the first six months of last year, the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Friday. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is estimating this year's deficit will total $ 163.3 billion, up 5.3 percent from the $ 155.1 billion shortfall posted in for all of fiscal 1988. Under the Gramm-Rudman deficit-reduction law, this year's deficit was not supposed to exceed $ 146 billion. The administration and congressional leaders last week unveiled a compromise plan designed to reduce the deficit in the next fiscal year to $ 99.4 billion, just within the $ 100 billion target for fiscal 1990 established under Gramm-Rudman. In March, the government posted a $ 35.78 billion deficit, up 22.2 percent from the same month last year and the highest monthly shortfall since May 1986. Revenues last month were up 3.9 percent from March 1988 to $ 68.28 billion, while spending of $ 104.06 billion was up 9.5 percent. Economist <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Crandall </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> R.H. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wrightson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> said last month's deficit surge was largely due to technical factors related to the timing of government payments for tax refunds and veterans' and disability benefits. He said checks totaling $ 5 billion in tax refunds and $ 2.5 billion in benefits that normally would have gone out in April were mailed out at the end of March, artificially inflating the monthly deficit figure. `` If you take out technical factors, last month was right on top of last year's number,'' <PERSON> Crandall </PERSON> said. `` This points toward an annual deficit in the $ 145 billion range, which would be better than last year and better than most people are currently expecting.'' Economist <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> DeNoon </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hanover </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> said that even setting aside the special factors that inflated March's shortfall, he expects the deficit this year to be in the range of $ 160 billion to $ 165 billion. `` Clearly, it's not doing as well as it was last year,'' he said. <PERSON> DeNoon </PERSON> said much of the worsening in the deficit so far this year has been linked to government payments to help shore up the troubled savings and loan industry. Analysts say the deficit also has increased because of higher-than-expected interest rates so far this year. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> for a year has been pushing up interest rates in an effort to slow down economic growth and thus restrain inflation. The largest government spending category last month was the military. Defense spending in March totaled $ 28.9 billion and reached $ 148 billion for the first half of the fiscal year, up 4 percent from the same period during the previous year. Spending on Social Security last month totaled $ 19.5 billion and reached $ 111.1 billion for the first six months of fiscal 1989, 5.8 percent ahead of a year earlier. Interest on the national debt totaled $ 16.5 billion last month and $ 117 billion so far this year, up 11.2 percent from a year earlier. Health and Human Services programs other than Social Security cost $ 16 billion in March and $ 82.8 billion so far in the fiscal year, up 6.9 percent from the previous year. Spending by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> last month was $ 3.8 billion and totaled $ 28.6 billion for the first half of the year, up 9.7 percent from a year earlier.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BRF--SmokelessTobacco     04-22 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Smokeless Tobacco,0184</SECOND>
<HEAD>Most North Carolina Boys Try Tobacco by Seventh Grade</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ASHEVILLE, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than a third of the first-grade boys in rural <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> have tried smokeless tobacco, and the number increases to 70 percent by seventh-grade, a study shows. The recent <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Asheville </LOCATION> study found that the most frequently stated reason for using smokeless tobacco was its taste, followed by peer pressure, a desire to feel `` grown up'' and the influence of role models such as athletes. The study used children in grades one, three, five and seven in urban and rural schools in western <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. `` It was apparent during the administration of our questionnaire that the first-graders clearly understood what oral tobacco was,'' said <PERSON> Cheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> McClary </PERSON>, co-author of the study. `` In two of the rural schools, several little boys immediately jumped up to show their containers of chewing tobacco, which they kept in their back pocket.'' State law allows a 6-year-old to buy and use smokeless tobacco but prohibits the sale of cigarettes or cigarette papers to anyone under 17.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Skinner-Flight103     04-22 0537</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Skinner-Flight 103,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Victims' Relatives Still Want Probe; Skinner Goes to Europe</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Relatives of Americans killed in the bombing of <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> Flight 103 say they are encouraged by recent government response to aviation security problems but still want a broad investigation into the incident. Transportation Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> on Friday announced rejection of calls for an independent commission to look into the Dec. 21 bombing. He then took off for <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> to meet with transportation officials in five countries, <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Ammerman </PERSON>, spokesman for relatives of nearly 200 Americans killed in the explosion over <LOCATION> Lockerbie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, expressed disappointment with the decision, saying, `` We feel there's enough information that's been uncovered that only an independent investigation can deal with appropriately.'' <PERSON> Ammerman </PERSON>'s brother, <PERSON> Tom </PERSON>, was killed in the bombing. Among concerns of the relatives are the lack of a public warning of threats against the flight, security procedures that failed to detect the plastic explosive which authorities say was believed planted by terrorists, and inadequate government response after the incident. <PERSON> Ammerman </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Demarest </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, said, however, there have been several positive developments since the relatives staged a rally and met with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and other officials in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on April 3, including steps to improve aviation security. He said the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> had agreed to escort relatives who want to visit <LOCATION> Lockerbie </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> was meeting in <LOCATION> Naples </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, this weekend with the administration's nominee to head the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, Adm. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Busey </PERSON>, who is <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> commander for <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, and next week with government and airline officials in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON>, in a news conference for foreign journalists covering <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said he would push for security initiatives that would `` encourage international travelers to retain their justified confidence in the system's safety.'' <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> carriers have given `` unbelievable attention'' to security and are the safest in the world. His spokesman, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Prosperi </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> and other transportation and security officials were flying most of the way on a government plane to meet a tight schedule but would likely make at least part of the trip aboard commercial airliners. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON>, in a letter to <PERSON> Ammerman </PERSON> rejecting the call for a separate investigation, said, `` For a variety of reasons, we do not believe formation of an independent commission is necessary or prudent.'' The letter was accompanied by a five-page outline of administration action since the Pan Am explosion. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> said he had confidence in the investigation by Scottish and West German authorities and the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and believed those responsible for planting the bomb, which investigators have said was hidden in a radio-cassette, will be apprehended and prosecuted. `` I can assure you that in my opinion the investigation is moving at full speed,'' <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> said. `` I think that eventually and hopefully in the not too distant future, the public will know the full story there.'' He said it was important not to disclose targets of the investigation or the information being sought. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> said his trip would review screening given foreign nationals hired by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airlines abroad and seek diplomatic approval for installation of devices to detect plastic explosives in airports used by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> carriers abroad.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Nicaragua     04-22 0515</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Nicaragua,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Extends Economic Sanctions Against Nicaragua</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will continue the economic sanctions against <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> that were imposed in May 1985 by former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Friday in a letter to <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> that the trade embargo will continue `` as long as these measures are appropriate,'' but also suggested the sanctions could be lifted if free elections are held February in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. `` The trade sanctions are an essential element of our policy that seeks a democratic outcome in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> by diplomatic means,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in his letter. `` The policies and actions of the government of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' he said. The ban covers imports of Nicaraguan goods into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and exports by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> firms to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> _ except goods destined for the Contra rebels who have fought for eight years to overthrow the country's Sandinista government. The presidential order also prohibits air and ship traffic between the two countries. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s order came as a group of members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, both Democrats and Republicans, sent a telegram to Nicaraguan President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> on Friday, criticizing the law <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> adopted this week to govern its elections scheduled for next February. The telegram, sent by a group led by Rep. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Guarini </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, said the law is `` biased, unfair and designed to monopolize power rather than seek national reconciliation.'' An aide to one of the sponsors provided a copy. It calls on <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> to meet jointly with political opposition leaders and come up with a new election law to comply with the peace plans adopted by the presidents of the four Central American democracies and <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Esquipulas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, in 1987 and in <LOCATION> Tesoro </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, this year. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration also has expressed strong displeasure with the new election law, contending it gives the Sandinista government and its candidates an unfair advantage. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> will dominate the electoral council that will run the elections. Internal opposition parties and the Contra rebels also have strongly criticized the new law. An administration source, who commented on condition he not be named, said the administration was particularly displeased that <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> did not meet jointly with the opposition leaders to work out an agreeable election plan, instead meeting with them one at a time and then pushing the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> proposal, a complaint also made by the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> members who sent the telegram. `` If <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> implements its <LOCATION> Esquipulas </LOCATION> commitments and holds free, fair and honest elections, I believe the emergency that prompted the prior administration to impose the trade sanctions would largely be resolved,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wrote. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s letter reviewed the trade situation with <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> since the last administration report of Nov. 9. Those signing the congressional telegram include Reps. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Spratt </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.C. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Rod </PERSON> <PERSON> Chandler </PERSON>, R-Wash.; <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> McCurdy </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>.; <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Carper </PERSON>,; <PERSON> Ike </PERSON> <PERSON> Skelton </PERSON>, D-Mo.; <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Slattery </PERSON>, D-Kan.; <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON>, D-Ga.; <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Gunderson </PERSON>, R-Wis.; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, R-Wash.; <PERSON> Beverly </PERSON> <PERSON> Byron </PERSON>, D-Md., and
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AT&amp;T-ElectronicPublishing     04-22 0493</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AT&amp;T-Electronic Publishing,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>AT&amp;T Asks to Have Restrictions Lifted</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> is seeking court permission to enter the complex of computer data, videotex, financial and other information services known as electronic publishing. A brief filed Friday with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Greene </PERSON> said the leading firms in the electronic publishing industry `` are large, financially strong corporations'' that could withstand competition from <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> T. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T also said there were other companies than <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION>, such as <ORGANIZATION> MCI </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sprint </ORGANIZATION>, to deliver data for the electronic publishers. The court order breaking up the old <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> System </ORGANIZATION> had banned <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T from electronic publishing, but the <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T brief said that in 1982 <PERSON> Greene </PERSON> stated he intended to lift the ban after seven years. <PERSON> Greene </PERSON> said the burden after seven years would be on any opponents of removal `` to show that competitive conditions clearly require the maintenance of the ban,'' <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T's filing said. <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T spokesman <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Linnen </PERSON> said the leading firms include <ORGANIZATION> Knight-Ridder </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- online database services -RRB-, <ORGANIZATION> Citicorp </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Dow </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Reuters </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- securities quotations and financial information -RRB-, <ORGANIZATION> Dun </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Bradstreet </ORGANIZATION> and TRW -LRB- credit data -RRB- and <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Sears </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- videotex services -RRB-. <PERSON> Linnen </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> had no current plans to enter the electronic yellow pages and television businesses _ two areas that are of special concern to the seven regional <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> telephone companies that were spun off from <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T in 1984 and to the broadcast and cable TV industries. `` We have no specific business plan in mind,'' <PERSON> Linnen </PERSON> said. `` We have no current plans to provide services via yellow pages, and this -LRB- court filing -RRB- is not motivated by any current plan to get into television.'' The company said `` There are now ` means other than <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T's network for the transmission of the messages of electronic publishers,' and those firms providing electronic publishing services unquestionably have ` sufficient strength to permit them to compete.' Citing <ORGANIZATION> MCI </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Sprint </ORGANIZATION>, it said `` it is beyond serious dispute that these carriers offer ample alternatives to all of the <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T interexchange transmission services used by electronic publishers.'' <ORGANIZATION> MCI </ORGANIZATION> officials did not immediately return calls for comment. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> McCloskey </PERSON>, a spokesman for one of the seven regional <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> companies, <ORGANIZATION> BellSouth </ORGANIZATION>, said company officials had not seen the filing and could not comment. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Videotex </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said if <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T could be a `` potentially very important participant'' in electronic publishing, `` and I think probably the one area to watch out is if they use this as an opportunity to get into electronic yellow pages.'' Noting that the regional <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> companies are banned from this area, he said a `` vacuum'' existed there. <PERSON> Greene </PERSON>'s breakup order, as modified, defines electronic publishing as owning, originating, compiling or editing information content that is transported over <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T's facilities. In 1987, <PERSON> Greene </PERSON> gave the regional <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> companies permission to transmit but not originate information services, which, besides electronic publishing, also include data processing and related computer services.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Sullivan-CDC     04-22 0233</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sullivan-CDC,0239</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sullivan Visits CDC, Backs TB Plan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BYRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> gave his approval Friday to a plan by federal scientists to wipe out tuberculosis in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> by the year 2010. `` I challenge you at <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> to carry out the strategies necessary to accomplish that goal,'' <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said in a speech to employees at the <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>. The contagious lung disease attacked more than 22,000 Americans last year. TB can be cured in most cases with drug therapy, but has become a growing public health problem in recent years, in part because of the spread of AIDS _ which weakens the immune system, allowing TB, among other diseases, to develop. Scientists estimate that about 10 million Americans are infected with TB bacteria, but the vast majority never get the disease. The Advisory Committee for the Elimination of Tuberculosis, created by the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> in 1987, calls for more effective use of existing prevention and control programs, development of new diagnosis and treatment techniques, and rapid transfer of new technology into widespread medical use. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, who was president of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Morehouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> before being appointed secretary of <ORGANIZATION> HHS </ORGANIZATION> by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, also visited the new national headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, across the street from the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> compound.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MonumentFire 1stLd-Writethru a0724 04-22 0333</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Monument Fire, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0724,0338</SECOND>
<HEAD>More Than 200 Homes Evacuated Near Monument Brush Fire</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 5 grafs to UPDATE with fire under control; picks
up 5th graf: ``The terrain ...</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MONUMENT, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Firefighters quelled a brush fire that erupted Friday over 1,200 acres of the <ORGANIZATION> Pike </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> and forced the evacuation of more than 200 homes in scattered subdivisions near <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>'s foothils, authorities said. There were no reports of injuries or of damage to houses, said <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Coultas </PERSON>, spokesman for the Woodmoor-Monument Fire Protection District. About 175 firefighters from 20 agencies converged on the area about 20 miles north of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> after the blaze broke out shortly after noon in the <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Herman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Estates </LOCATION>, in unincorporated <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, he said. `` We do have it under control with 20 to 30 spot fires within the perimeter,'' he said. On Saturday, he said firefighters would overhaul the fire and finish the job. The cause of the blaze was unknown, he said. <PERSON> Coultas </PERSON> said structures in three subdivisions were evacuated in front of the fire burning grass, brush, scrub oak and pines. `` The terrain has given us more fits than anything else,'' <PERSON> Coultas </PERSON> said. `` Fire tends to move up and so it's following the contours of the land, moving up the side of the mountain.'' An air tanker was dropping fire retardant on the periphery of the blaze and helicopters were pulling water from Monument Lake to drop on the fire. Another air tanker was en route from <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> to join the fire fighting. Officials said the rough terrain also was preventing workers from bringing in bulldozers to build fire lines, so axes and small hoses were being used. <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's spokesmen predicted it would take three or four days to quench the fire. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>'s rangeland fire danger was `` extreme'' as record high temperatures were reported Friday in eastern <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and the fire danger was high in the mountains.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0152EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Lebanon-Demonstration     04-22 0392</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon-Demonstration,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lebanese Seek US Help to End Fighting in Their Country</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURIE ASSEO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> must pressure <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> to stop the shelling that has killed hundreds in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> and made life for the survivors virtually unlivable, according to 2,000 Lebanese who demonstrated across from the White House. `` It's a total breakdown of everything,'' said <PERSON> May </PERSON> <PERSON> Rihani </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> consultant who visited her family in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> in September. `` No work, no school, no electricity.'' `` It's unbearable, unpredictable, unlivable'' since Syrian forces began bombarding <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s Christian enclave in early March, said <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ibrahim </PERSON>, a Lebanese-born <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> businessman who also has relatives living there. `` It's inhumane to shell ... peaceful, innocent people,'' he said. The demonstrators came to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Friday from across the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, and were organized by a variety of pro-Lebanese groups. Marching in <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> across the street from the <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> House </LOCATION>, they carried signs and sang the Lebanese national anthem amid chants of `` President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, Save Lebanon.'' The International Movement for the <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lebanon </ORGANIZATION>, an organizer of the demonstration, said in a letter to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> it was disappointed by a statement by Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> earlier this week that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> can do little at present to help <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told reporters Thursday he wished there were `` some dramatic plan'' to stop the violence. `` The problem _ the short-run of it _ how you stop this firing, the shelling, how you get factions to stop warring, has certainly in recent times defied solution,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` But we ca n't give up on it.'' Several demonstrators suggested the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> could use diplomatic or economic pressure in an effort to force <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> to withdraw its 40,000 troops from their country. At least 270 people, mainly civilians, have been killed and nearly 1,000 wounded in shelling since March 8. More than 150,000 Christians and Moslems have fled <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> out of fear of fighting or due to shortages of food and fuel. <PERSON> Elia </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarkis </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> businessman who brought his 11-year-old son to the demonstration, said he believes that if <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> withdrew, the warring Lebanese religious and ethnic factions would find a way to form a workable government. `` A federation of religious, ethnic communities ... that's the ideal new <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> that we're looking for,'' <PERSON> Sarkis </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtoninBrief     04-22 0503</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington in Brief,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Panel to Hold Hearings on Ship Accident</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> will hold hearings on the explosion aboard the USS Iowa that killed 47 seamen. Sens. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., the chairman, and the ranking Republican, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, said on Friday the hearings will begin after the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s board of inquiry completes its probe into the accident The hearings will focus on safety procedures used in the past, whether changes in the procedures are necessary and possible conditions imposed on the continued use of the 16-inch weapons found on the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> battleship, the senators said in a joint statement.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>Active-Duty Strength Drops in March</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The active-duty strength of the nation's armed forces dropped slightly last month. In all, the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> reported 2,116,889 men and women on active duty as of March 31, down from the 2,122,636 on Feb. 28, according to <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> figures released on Friday. A year ago, on March 31, 1988, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> reported 2,141,757 men and women in uniform. A reduction was ordered in early 1988 by the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. Most of the reductions were made through changes in recruiting goals, tighter re-enlistment standards and `` early out'' incentives.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>Bush Gives Medal to Philanthropist</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> awarded the congressional medal to philanthropist <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Lasker </PERSON>, honoring her for longtime support of research and education in such areas as cancer, heart disease and cerebral palsy. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, in a Rose Garden presentation ceremony on Friday, told Mrs. <PERSON> Lasker </PERSON> she was an example of what he means when he speaks of `` 1,000 points of light'' as the many components of society that work to improve life for everyone. Mrs. <PERSON> Lasker </PERSON> and her husband in 1942 founded the <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Mary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lasker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> to encourage medical research and public awareness of crippling diseases. She urged the president to beef up support for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION>, where the <ORGANIZATION> Mary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> W. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lasker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> conducts medical research. `` Cancer still kills 500,000 people a year in this country, more people than have been killed in all our wars combined,'' she said.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>Donovan Wants Government to Pay Legal Bills</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Labor Secretary <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Donovan </PERSON> is asking an appeals court panel to order the federal government to pay $ 112,281 in legal bills he says he incurred during an investigation of an alleged kickback supposedly paid <PERSON> Donovan </PERSON> in 1977. <PERSON> Donovan </PERSON> and his lawyers say the legal fees and expenses are for the period March 1987 through October 1987 in connection with the probe by independent counsel <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Silverman </PERSON>. Federal law on independent counsels provides for the government to pay legal fees if the subject of the criminal investigation is n't indicted. <PERSON> Donovan </PERSON> was cleared in the probe of accusations that he lied when he denied knowing anything about the alleged kickback scheme which involved a former supplier of <ORGANIZATION> Schiavone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Construction </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> where <PERSON> Donovan </PERSON> was working at the time.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CentralPark 4thLd-Writethru a0408 04-22 0710</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Central Park, 4th Ld - Writethru, a0408,0725</SECOND>
<HEAD>Central Park after Dark: Safe or Scary?</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 8th graf, `Four teenagers ..., to UPDATE with further arrests,
doctor's statment that victim has a chance of full recovery.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The rape and beating of a jogger has reinforced the reputation of <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> as a haven for criminals, which city officials say is an unfair stereotype of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s most famous urban park. `` Generally, crime in the park is low. It is safe to jog in Central Park,'' said police Chief of Detectives <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Colangelo </PERSON> after the Wednesday night attack by a marauding gang of teen-agers left a 28-year-old woman near death. `` There's danger in jogging anywhere,'' <PERSON> Colangelo </PERSON> said. `` But we do n't feel it's inordinately dangerous here.'' The park's reputation for illegal activity has been reinforced in recent years by several highly publicized incidents: <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>'s 1986 strangling by `` preppie killer'' <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON>, a shooting a month earlier that left a police officer, <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>, paralyzed, and a 1983 free concert by <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> that drew packs of thieves. The victim of the latest attack, an investment banker, remained unconscious on life-support systems Friday at <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, said hospital spokeswoman Aura Retamoso. The woman lost roughly three-quarters of her body's blood in the attack, and suffered a fractured skull, severe head lacerations, brain contusions, fractured facial bones and bruises from head to toe in the assault by a dozen teens, said Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kurtz </PERSON>, assistant chief of surgery at the hospital. <PERSON> Kurtz </PERSON> said that on Friday her pulse rate `` went way up'' when her mother spoke to her. `` So at some level she's processing information today which she was n't doing yesterday,'' he said. He said the next four days were crucial for her health, but added `` she has a fighting chance of making a full recovery.'' Seven teen-agers were arrested Friday and charged with attempted murder, rape and assault in the attack. Police said additional arrests were expected. <PERSON> Colangelo </PERSON> said the woman was attacked by some members of a group of 32 teens who went to the park Wednesday night to `` raise hell, attack joggers, steal bicycles.'' Within 10 minutes, they had assaulted three men, including a jogger and a homeless man. They later split up into three groups after spotting a police cruiser and terrorized at least nine people during a two-hour period. <PERSON> Colangelo </PERSON> said the youths told investigators the crime spree resulted from a pastime called `` wilding.'' `` It's not a term that we in the police had heard before,'' the chief said. `` They just said, ` We were going wilding.' In my mind at this point, it implies that they were going to go raise hell.'' `` Central Park is the focus of national attention. Every incident that happens there is news _ especially if it's grisly,'' Parks Commissioner <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Stern </PERSON> said Friday. Last year, police had reports of 51 assaults and 13 rapes in the park, compared with 71,030 assaults and 3,412 rapes citywide. Of last year's attacks in the park, a dozen involved joggers; in 1987, 13 joggers were assaulted in the park. The rape Wednesday was the third rape reported this year in Central Park, police said. Officials say the crime reports for the park are low for an area larger than the country of <LOCATION> Monaco </LOCATION>. On a busy day, hundreds of thousands of people pass through the park. Officials acknowledge the park has dangers after dark. `` It's safer to use it by day,'' <PERSON> Stern </PERSON> said. But he said, `` People should n't give up on the park any more than you would give up on air travel because of a plane crash.'' <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Lebow </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Road </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Runners </ORGANIZATION> club, tells evening joggers to avoid the northern area of the park, where the Wednesday attack occurred. That area, bordering on <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION>, has more rugged terrain and hiding places for criminals. <PERSON> Lebow </PERSON>'s warning is based on history: One of his group's members was raped in almost the same spot while jogging through the park five years ago. Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> also sounded a warning Friday about jogging: `` If you do it in some parts of this town, you're endangering your physical well-being, maybe occasionally even your life.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0154EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-StarkSailor     04-22 0301</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stark Sailor,0313</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sailor Assails Compensation Plan For Injuries</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JACKSONVILLE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A sailor injured when missiles ripped into the USS Stark as it patrolled the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> says the $ 7,500 the government is trying to get him as compensation is insulting. `` All this for $ 7,500?'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> McLeod </PERSON>, who spent more than 11 hours in the gulf nursing his injuries and fighting off sharks following the May 1987 attack. `` I'm starting to wonder was it all worth it,'' he said. `` It'd be better off as far as compensation goes to go out and get in a car wreck. <PERSON> McLeod </PERSON> heard last month that the <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> government had agreed to pay $ 27.35 million to the families of the 37 <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> sailors killed aboard the Stark, and thought he would be compensated as one of the 22 sailors injured. <PERSON> McLeod </PERSON> received a letter from the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday that said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would seek $ 7,500 for his injuries from the Iraqis. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> would not comment on the total amount being sought for the injured sailors. <PERSON> McLeod </PERSON> and the other sailors were injured when two Exocet missiles fired by an Iraqi warplane hit the Stark in May 1987. He and three other sailors were thrown from the ship by the blast. <PERSON> McLeod </PERSON>, who was awarded a Purple Heart, spent two weeks in a wheelchair before returning to light duty. `` I think it's a ripoff. It's an insult,'' he said. <PERSON> McLeod </PERSON> and his wife <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON> `` were thinking about $ 30,000 to $ 40,000 would be about right.'' The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> letter invites <PERSON> McLeod </PERSON> to submit additional information if he believes the claim is unjust. <PERSON> McLeod </PERSON> left the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> after his enlistment expired in November 1987. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> paid his hospital bills plus $ 3,200 for personal items lost on the ship.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0155EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Burma     04-22 0181</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Burma,0186</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Releases Comedian, Actor After 7 Months In Jail</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: One name Zargana is correct</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RANGOON, Burma (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Burmese comedian and actor who satirized the military shortly after it seized power have been released after almost seven months imprisonment, authorities said today. The comedian, Zargana, and the actor, <PERSON> Zin </PERSON> <PERSON> Waing </PERSON>, were freed from Insein Jail in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> on Friday. Zargana, <PERSON> Zin </PERSON> <PERSON> Waing </PERSON>, and four other actors and directors were arrested Oct. 2 but never publicly accused of any wrongdoing. The others were freed earlier. <PERSON> Zargana </PERSON> said in a telephone interview today that he was kept in solitary confinement but was not otherwise mistreated. `` The authorities explained to us yesterday why the military had to step in on Sept. 18,'' <PERSON> Zargana </PERSON> said. `` We had to promise to avoid acts that tend to cause misunderstanding between the army and the public.'' Armed forces commander Gen. Saw <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> seized power in a coup that day against the country's first civilian president in 26 years. The general's troops killed hundreds of people in crushing the nationwide street demonstrations for democracy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0156EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-22 0967</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1003</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> is the No. 1 star of television's first 50 years and the undisputed `` top gun'' of talk shows, according to People magazine. Trailing <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> in the opinion of the magazine's editorial staff were <PERSON> Lucille </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Gleason </PERSON>, <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sid </PERSON> <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON>. The magazine will publish the list in next week's edition celebrating a half century of television. The magazine echoed what ratings have shown over the decades, calling <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> the `` champion of chatter,'' an incomparable monologue artist and the `` night watchman of the global village.'' In his 26 years as host of `` The Tonight Show,'' the magazine said <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> has interviewed more than 20,000 guests and told more than 700,000 jokes before a weekly audience of about 75 million people.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON> was `` like a hungry vulture'' when the subject of money came up at the funeral of her second husband, <PERSON> Aristotle </PERSON> <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON>, according to a new book that quoted the late <PERSON> Christina </PERSON> <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON>. `` A Woman Named <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON>,'' an unauthorized biography written by <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Heymann </PERSON>, details the former first lady's spending sprees and said money was discussed at Onassis' funeral in 1975. The book is being serialized in the weekly Star, a supermarket tabloid. Mrs. <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON>' brother-in-law, Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, rode in the funeral limousine with her and <PERSON> Christina </PERSON> <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Aristotle </PERSON>'s daughter <PERSON> Christina </PERSON>, who has since died, told <PERSON> Heymann </PERSON> that <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> turned to her and said, `` Now, it's time to take care of <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON>,'' the Star reported in its Monday edition. `` It seemed almost inconceivable that <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> would choose that moment to discuss financial matters,'' said <PERSON> Christina </PERSON>. `` But it was <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON>'s hyena-like smile that drove me from the car. She was like a hungry vulture waiting to feast on my father's flesh.'' The book also says <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON> plotted with photographers to publish candid, nude photographs of his wife so she would stop complaining about tamer shots taken by papparazzi. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Tuckerman </PERSON>, spokeswoman for Mrs. <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON>, said when the first part of the series appeared last week that the former first lady would have no comment.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lucille </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON> continued to recover quickly from heart surgery earlier this week, cheered on by a flood of flowers, phone calls and faxes. `` She's going to be uncomfortable for a few days, but she's making significant progress,'' said <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON>, a spokesman at <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> The 77-year-old, zany redhead remained in serious condition Friday, three days after receiving a transplanted piece of critical heart artery. The hospital received a `` tidal wave'' of greeting cards, and its facsimile machine was churning out messages virtually nonstop for the Emmy Award-winning actress, according to Wise, who delivered hundreds to Miss Ball's husband, <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Morton </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> says a $ 100,000 gift from <ORGANIZATION> Eagle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Snacks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> is n't peanuts: he plans to use the money to turn a rundown movie house into a home for a classical repertory group. `` It will take a lot of work and a lot of money, but I think that this donation from Eagle Snacks will help stimulate the participation we need to bring great theater back to 42nd Street,'' <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> said Friday. <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> said he plans to buy the theater as part of a city plan to restore a seamy stretch of 42nd Street to a performing arts complex. He is a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Eagle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Snacks </ORGANIZATION>, a subsidiary of <ORGANIZATION> Anheuser-Busch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Princess <PERSON> Beatrice </PERSON> <PERSON> of </PERSON> <PERSON> York </PERSON> displayed her royal talents for crowd pleasing as she waited excitedly at an <LOCATION> Edinburgh </LOCATION> dockside for her father's destroyer. With a little prompting from her mother, the Duchess of <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, the 8-month-old princess waved both arms and then flung her bare legs into action Friday, wiggling in her mother's arms. The duchess, the former <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>, stood with her daughter and about 20 other relatives of men serving on the HMS <LOCATION> Edinburgh </LOCATION>. They walked up the gangplank after the destroyer docked to visit the <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION>, Prince <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>. Later, <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> carried a still-waving <PERSON> Beatrice </PERSON> back down the gangplank.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 From `` Star Wars'' to ad wars: <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>' special effects company has begun making commercials for the small screen <ORGANIZATION> Lucasfilm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION> announced Friday it had formed an advertising division that will tap the expertise that went into such movies as the `` Star Wars'' series and the fantasy `` Willow.'' The first project currently under way in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> is a series of four spots touting <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION>, the regional telephone company, said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON>, who is heading <ORGANIZATION> Lucasfilm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commercial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Productions </ORGANIZATION>. The advertisements will combine computer graphics, animation and live action _ `` a technique that's never been used before,'' <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> said. The operation will use the resources of Industrial Light & amp; <ORGANIZATION> Magic </ORGANIZATION>, the computer graphics division of <ORGANIZATION> Lucasfilm </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A longer version is moving on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Baseball slugger <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Canseco </PERSON>, who in February was ticketed for driving his car 120 mph in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, has been charged with felony possession of a loaded semiautomatic handgun. <PERSON> Canseco </PERSON> was `` totally cooperative'' when arrested Friday at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Laurel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heights </ORGANIZATION> campus while returning to his car after a medical exam, said campus police Lt. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Kurtz </PERSON>. A passerby had noticed the weapon on the floor of <PERSON> Canseco </PERSON>'s parked <ORGANIZATION> Jaguar </ORGANIZATION>, he said. <PERSON> Canseco </PERSON> was released after several hours when his wife, <PERSON> Esther </PERSON>, posted $ 5,000 bail. He will be arraigned in three weeks. <PERSON> Kurtz </PERSON> said police could find no permit on file allowing <PERSON> Canseco </PERSON> to carry a weapon but they are continuing to investigate. The 24-year-old right fielder went to the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coliseum </ORGANIZATION> later Friday and suited up for a game against the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angels </ORGANIZATION>. He has been sidelined with an injured left wrist.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0208EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     04-22 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0026</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 02; 10; 17; 24; 32; 35.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     04-22 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0087</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 02; 10; 17; 24; 32; 35.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 1-0-4-4.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 01; 09; 13; 23; 31; 32.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 02; 05; 11; 19; 36; 46. Bonus: 67324.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 03; 12; 26; 29; 44; 49. Supplementary 35.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 2-4-5-3.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 2-3-2; 7-0-2-8; 3-2-9-5-8; 3-8-6-5-2-9.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0214EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FetusProject     04-22 0294</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fetus Project,0301</SECOND>
<HEAD>Principal Removes Jars Of Fetuses From Seventh-Grader's Exhibit</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Note contents</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GATLINBURG, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A school principal prevented a seventh-grader from displaying her anti-abortion science project, which consisted of 10 jars of human fetuses, saying the award-winning exhibit was too much for his students. <PERSON> Carrie </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> placed the jars, which contained fetuses from pregnancy stages ranging from 6 weeks to 5 -LCB- months, on her exhibit table Thursday at <ORGANIZATION> Pi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Phi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, said Principal <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardiel </PERSON>. `` To an untrained eye, the -LRB- fetus -RRB- 5 -LCB- months along was definitely a child,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wade </PERSON>, curriculum director for <LOCATION> Sevier </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> schools. The girl said she got the fetuses, which were kept in preservative solutions, from her uncle, a pathologist. The girl's mother said the fetuses came from miscarriages <PERSON> Cardiel </PERSON> said he learned of the exhibit early that morning as students were setting up their projects for the school's annual science fair, which this year has the theme `` Life Science.'' `` The project was very inappropriate for the age group here,'' <PERSON> Cardiel </PERSON> said. He said he first conferred with <PERSON> Carrie </PERSON>'s mother, <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, who teaches art at the school. The project was removed from the fair after it was graded and given a blue ribbon but before classes had a chance to view it, said <ORGANIZATION> Sevier </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> Superintendent <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Parton </PERSON>. <PERSON> Parton </PERSON> said he agreed with <PERSON> Cardiel </PERSON> that most of the schoolchildren were too young to understand the ideas and points behind the exhibit. <PERSON> Parton </PERSON> also said recent, nationwide political debate over abortion played no part in the principal's decision to yank the display from the fair. The school is located in <LOCATION> Gatlinburg </LOCATION>, an <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> resort town of about 3,000 people. About 430 students in kindergarten through eighth grade attend the school.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0220EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador     04-22 0635</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador,0657</SECOND>
<HEAD>Salvador Presidential Transition Is Going Badly</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The transition from <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> government to <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON>'s rightist administration is not going smoothly. Assassinations, bombings, death-squad style murders and mass roundups of leftists have further disturbed a political climate that has been roiled by nine years of civil war. Marxist-led guerrillas have vowed to make the country `` ungovernable'' by June 1, when <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> takes office. The 41-year-old leader of the rightist <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION>, or <PERSON> Arena </PERSON>, handily defeated the centrist <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> candidate in last month's presidential election. Arena and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have blamed the rebel <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION>, for three recent assassinations of rightists and a bomb attack on the home of the vice-president-elect. Attorney General <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarado </PERSON> was slain Wednesday by a bomb placed on the roof of his car when it stopped at a traffic light. The targeting of high-profile individuals _ a tactic not routinely employed by the guerrillas in the past _ appears designed to provoke and undermine <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON>. But who is doing it and why remain unclear. The guerrillas have neither claimed nor denied responsibility for the killing of <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>. They did, however, deny responsibility for the April 14 bombing of vice president-elect <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Merino </PERSON>'s house Both <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> and <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> have blamed the recent wave of violence on guerrillas determined to provoke a harsh, repressive response from security forces. According to this view, guerrilla sympathizers in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> would point to a surge in rights abuse as reason for a cutoff of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid. <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> receives about $ 1.5 million a day in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic and military assistance _ more than any other country in the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION>. Some still-active Arena leaders have been linked to death squads that in the early 1980s killed thousands of suspected leftists. The insurgents continue to refer to <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> as `` the death-squad party.'' <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> denies the charge and <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> says the eight-year-old organization has evolved into a modern, conservative party similar to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. But <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> continues to harbor a far-right wing. Whether the <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> faction of relatively moderate and modern capitalists wins out over oligarchic and fascist-minded elements remains to be seen. `` An extremist sector of the right hopes to subjugate <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> and impose a hard military and political line,'' <PERSON> Ignacio </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellacuria </PERSON>, rector of the prestigious Jesuit-run <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said Friday. Left-leaning unions and other `` popular organizations'' have condemned what they say is an increase in repression in recent weeks. Elementary school teacher <PERSON> Cristina </PERSON> <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> was abducted from her school, tortured and killed April 5 by heavily armed men in civilian clothes acting in broad daylight, apparently confident they would not be challenged by security forces. Police and army troops on Wednesday and Thursday raided a union headquarters, the headquarters of a displaced person's group and the offices of a women's association. More than 70 people were arrested. `` The escalation of repression demonstrates the desperation being felt by the rich and powerful. They're starting to feel the effect of the war and see their riches in danger,'' said <PERSON> Tomasa </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruiz </PERSON>, a member of the directorate of the raided refugee center. `` So they declare war on the people.'' <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> said his government will act resolutely, but within the law, to ensure law and order. Defense Minister Gen. <PERSON> Eugenio </PERSON> <PERSON> Vides </PERSON> <PERSON> Casanova </PERSON>, who met Thursday with lawmakers to discuss possible legislation to combat organizations considered guerrilla fronts by the military, said he does not believe the current level of violence requires the imposition of a state of siege.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Mine </PERSON>, based in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> since last year, has reported extensively for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> from Central America.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TankerSpill 3rdLd-Writethru a0734 04-22 0751</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tanker Spill, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0734,0767</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Skimmer Gets To Work, Another Otter Center Demanded of Exxon</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 5 grafs to UPDATE with Soviet tanker not getting
any oil Friday; picks up 6th graf pvs, `A total...</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto VDX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL JENKINS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VALDEZ, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Soviet skimmer swung into action Friday but collected no oil as a number of fishing boats waged their own, low-tech fight against <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s worst oil spill. While the 425-foot <PERSON> Vaidogubsky </PERSON> plied the rough seas off the <LOCATION> Kenai </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> shook his head in disgust over his 53-foot fishing vessel with its holds full of oil sucked from Resurrection Bay. `` I got all the evidence of the oil spill you could want right here,'' said <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON>, 29, of <LOCATION> Kasilof </LOCATION>. `` It's death and destruction. People look at it and it makes them sick.'' <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON>'s boat, Sea Quest, was docked in a contamination zone of <PERSON> Seward </PERSON>'s small boat harbor while state and <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> officials debated what to do with the 7,500 gallons <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> said he sucked up in 16 hours Thursday. The Soviet skimmer spent Thursday testing its equipment and steamed for <LOCATION> Gore </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> where large pools of oil have gathered. <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Donohoe </PERSON> said the Soviet skimmer was to begin retrieving its first oil today. A total of 48 skimmers, most in the 36-foot to 42-foot range, were working on stretches of oil floating in <LOCATION> Prince </LOCATION> <LOCATION> William </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sound </LOCATION> and the Gulf of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. Heaviest concentrations were in the sound, at <LOCATION> Gore </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> Kenai </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION> and on the west side of <LOCATION> Kodiak </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. Local fishermen have been pulling their boats up to oil contained by plastic booms, dipping the crude up with scoops and buckets and then stacking the buckets on the sterns of their boats. <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> petty officer <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said delays unloading the oil were widespread and slowing progress on cleaning up the oil. He declined comment on whether more barges were needed and referred the question to <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, a spokesman for the oil company in <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION>, said four barges in Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> and another near <LOCATION> Seward </LOCATION> had a combined capacity of almost 8 million gallons. Another barge was to join them, he said. Another Exxon spokesman, <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Beathard </PERSON>, acknowledged there were long delays in loading recovered oil from skimmers onto the barges. He blamed that on the thick consistency of recovered oil, which he likened to taffy. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> also was under attack from environmentalists upset with the oil company's reluctance to open a sea otter treatment center at <LOCATION> Seward </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said Friday it had written <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> strongly re-emphasizing the need for a second treatment center in addition to one at <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION>. Spokesman <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Batten </PERSON> said his agency first asked for a center April 7, and asked that it be completed by Sunday. `` We're not really in a position where we can order them to do it, but we finally felt compelled to put it in writing,'' he said. <PERSON> Batten </PERSON> said the service is expanding its effort to rescue oil-coated otters off the outer coast of the <LOCATION> Kenai </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>. The Center for <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> estimated about 200 oiled sea otters have been found along the southern shoreline of the peninsula by fishermen. Altogether, the Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> has observed 3,406 dead shore birds, 409 dead sea otters and four dead bald eagles. `` The devastation yet to come from the Exxon Valdez spill could be enormous,'' said <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> McManus </PERSON>, president of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, D.C.-based environmental group as he pressed for the second otter center. The Exxon Valdez rammed Bligh Reef March 24 and spilled 10.1 million gallons of oil it had loaded in <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION>, the southern terminus of the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> pipeline. Delays in responding to the spill contributed to its spread, and some of the oil seeped out of the sound into the Gulf of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and moved southwest to the Kenai Fjords National Park. The ecologically sensitive region is home to large populations of marine mammals and seabirds. Biologists say thousands of birds and hundreds of sea otters have died, although an exact figure is unobtainable. The oil continued to spread southwest Friday to <LOCATION> Kodiak </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> and beyond, said <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> McGee </PERSON>, a spill cleanup coordinator for the <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Kodiak </LOCATION> is the No. 1 fishing port in the nation as well as home of the world's largest concentration of brown bears, many of which are just emerging from winter hibernation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890422-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-89 0157EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China 6thLd-Writethru   04-22 1058</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China, 6th Ld-Writethru,a0401,1096</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Thousands Who Packed Square Demanding Democracy Depart</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with nine grafs to UPDATE with students leaving square
without incident after 15 hours of unrest, details. Picks up graf 7 pvs,
`Party general ...' EDITS to conform.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos BEJ6,10</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
