<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-VoinovichCampaign     04-28 0160</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Voinovich Campaign,0163</SECOND>
<HEAD>Voinovich In Governor's Race</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Voinovich </PERSON> entered the 1990 governor's race Thursday, promising <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> the same leadership that he said made <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> a municipal success story over the past decade. `` <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> is off of the rocks and on a roll. Our neighborhoods are better, our jobs are up and the jokes are down,'' said <PERSON> Voinovich </PERSON>, an unsuccesful 1988 Republican <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> candidate, one-time lieutenant governor, former state representative and <LOCATION> Cuyahoga </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> auditor. <PERSON> Voinovich </PERSON>, 52, brushed aside questions about his defeat in the Sentate race last year by Democratic Sen. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, whom <PERSON> Voinovich </PERSON> accused during the campaign of being soft on child pornography. <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> Chairman, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruvolo </PERSON>, revived past complaints of negative campaigning by <PERSON> Voinovich </PERSON> against <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> last fall and said he wishes the mayor `` the same success he had last year.'' Gov. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON>, a Democrat, is barred by the state constitution from seeking a third consecutive term.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0005EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-DownedJet     04-28 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Downed Jet,270</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Iraq Downed Egyptian Jet By Mistake</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An Iraqi soldier shot down an Egyptian jet fighter by mistake last week as it descended to land in <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> for an air show, a published report here said. The two Egyptian fliers ejected safely before the plane crashed, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in Friday's editions. The Iraqi government had invited <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> to fly its home-built Alpha fighter-bomber to <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> for the air show, but apparently word of the invitation had not reached the soldier who, armed with shoulder-fired missile, downed the unfamiliar jet, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said. The newspaper cited secret intelligence reports making the rounds of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government offices here as the source of the story. The Alpha jet was developed by French and German aircraft firms. <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> has purchased Alpha kits from <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and assembles the fighter-bomber in a plant south of <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION>. The jet has a top speed of 600 mph. Two years ago, in another case of mistaken identity, an Iraqi pilot in a Mirage F1 bomber shot two Exocet missiles into the USS Stark, killing 37 sailors aboard the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> frigate in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. Iraqi officials said the pilot mistook the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ship for an Iranian vessel. Also, the USS Vincennes downed an Iranian Airbus on July 3, 1988, killing 290 people, as it flew over the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> where <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ships were protecting neutral ships during the Iran-Iraq war. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> said it attempted repeatedly to contact the plane for identification, and when it got no response, the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> destroyed the plane with a surface-to-air missile.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r e PM-APonTV-MisterRogers     04-28 0852</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP on TV-Mister Rogers,0871</SECOND>
<HEAD>Miniseries Making Neighborhood Debut</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto PG5 Sent April 26.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCIA DUNN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The miniseries comes to `` Mister <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>' Neighborhood'' next week, and the show's cardigan-clad creator promises a message as gentle and reassuring as ever The three-part musical, titled `` <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON> the Short-Neck Giraffe,'' tells the story of a young giraffe who yearns for a long, graceful neck like all the other giraffes. She eventually grows, <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> confided, `` not on the outside, but on the important side.'' `` It's very much like the usual message of the Neighborhood, that you can be acceptable as you are,'' he said, smiling. `` It's not so much the outsides of us that are important. A song sung by <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON> and her friend <PERSON> Hazel </PERSON> the elephant sums it up best, according to <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION>. `` You're much more than a neck, <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON>. And you're much more than a trunk, <PERSON> Hazel </PERSON>. A chicken's more than a peck, and there's more than a smell to a skunk,'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> quietly sang during an interview at <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>'s WQED-TV, home to his children's programs for the past 35 years. The special week of new programs gets under way Monday on <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> stations with a trip to the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wild </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Animal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, where viewers are introduced to real-life giraffes and elephants. On Tuesday, <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION> visits a film processing lab to have his animal photographs developed. The miniseries, which features a cast of 15, elaborate animal costumes and five sets, runs Wednesday through Friday. <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> gently guides his young audience from one day to the next, summarizing the main events and hinting at what might lie ahead for <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON>. In the Neighborhood of Make-Believe, where animals sing, dance and play the trombone, <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON> is befriended by <PERSON> J.R. </PERSON>, a shy giraffe who overcomes his problems by helping <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON> conquer hers. He accomplishes that with help from <PERSON> Hazel </PERSON> the elephant, who advises him to `` just let your heart speak.'' `` There is n't a time that I see the scene in which <PERSON> J.R. </PERSON> talks and sings with <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON> ... that I have n't gotten chills up my spine,'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said, tapping his right hand against his back. `` And this is something I've worked with for years. There's something so redemptive about someone who is trying so hard to help somebody else. <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION>, 61, wrote `` <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON> the Short-Neck Giraffe'' for a French class assignment at <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Rollins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in 1950. He named <PERSON> J.R. </PERSON> the giraffe after fraternity brother <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Reardon </PERSON>, who went on to sing with the Metropolitan Opera and was a frequent guest on `` Mister Rogers Neighborhood.'' <PERSON> Reardon </PERSON> died a year ago, and the miniseries is dedicated to him. <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> set the story to music in the late 1950s, and about 1,000 records were pressed. Writer <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Head </PERSON> transformed `` <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON> the Short-Neck Giraffe'' into a poem for children in 1975. For years, <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> tried to have the musical produced on stage or as an animated film. `` I still think it would be great for animation and a stage production,'' he said. `` But I thought unless we get it out on the air, I do n't think anybody's going to know about it.'' The story <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> wrote 39 years ago is vastly different from the musical airing next week. It is the Neighborhood's 13th musical. `` At the end of the -LRB- original -RRB- story, when people are telling <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON> that they like her just the way she is, she raises her head to look at them because she has n't really heard this message before and her neck starts to grow. And it grows and grows and grows until her neck is as tall as everybody else's,'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said. In the musical, <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON>'s neck remains short. `` I think it shows how much we've grown,'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said. `` You know, you do n't have to look like everybody else to be acceptable and to feel acceptable. And wishes do n't always come true. `` Because for a year and a day I've been wishing, she sang. That was one of her first songs. Her wish was for a longer neck, she thought. But really her wish was to have people like her exactly as she is. So often what we say we're wishing for is n't necessarily what is behind the wish. This is very philosophical.'' Will pre-schoolers be able to grasp such a serious message, even in such a light-hearted setting? `` Maybe not in words, but let their hearts speak to them the way <PERSON> Hazel </PERSON> said to <PERSON> J.R. </PERSON>, ` Just let your heart speak,''' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said. `` I think that that's the way an awful lot of communication takes place.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Elsewhere in television: REAL-LIFE DRAMAS _ <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> has scheduled the made-for-TV movie about the real-life rescue of little <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> McClure </PERSON> from a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> well for May 21. <PERSON> Beau </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Hingle </PERSON>, <PERSON> Roxana </PERSON> <PERSON> Zal </PERSON> and <PERSON> Patty </PERSON> <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> star. ... Production is set to begin on `` The Preppy Murder,'' a two-hour `` docudrama'' for <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> about the case of <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON> who was convicted in the death of <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> following what he said was an accident during `` rough sex'' in Central Park. The movie will air sometime later this season.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0120EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Notebook     04-28 0648</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Notebook,0678</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reporter's Notebook: Students March To `Frere Jacques'</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-China, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Frere Jacques'' never sounded so revolutionary. `` Lying to the people, lying to the people, very strange, very strange,'' hundreds of students sang in place of the usual lyrics of the French children's song. Unlike American anti-Vietnam War marchers of the 1960s, who were serenaded by a generation of rock and folk singers, thousands of Chinese students who marched for democracy have a limited repertoire of marching songs. Most of the time they stick to the national anthem, with its stirring call to the masses to `` arise,'' or the Internationale, the theme song of the international communist movement. But they mix it up a bit with `` Frere Jacques'' and the nursery rhyme `` Baa Baa Black Sheep.'' Only the words were different. `` We did n't have time to write our own songs,'' said one student leader. `` Besides, it's easier to sing when you know the tune.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Police kept their cool but some lost their hats and shoes in skirmishes with students who pushed through their lines toward <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>. When the dust settled after the students pushed through the first line of police, one officer was seen wandering around in his socks, wailing, `` My shoes, my shoes.'' An old woman finally found one of his black cloth shoes and returned it. A student later produced another. In the final standoff before students surged into Tiananmen Square, one worker snatched the hat off an officer's head and tossed it into the crowd. Someone caught it and tossed it back like a frisbee. The officer's arms were linked with his comrades to form a human barricade, so a student politely plunked it back on the policeman's head
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is a model to many of the students. One student described <PERSON> Hu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yaobang </PERSON>, the ousted <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader whose death sparked the recent protests, as `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>.'' Another said American student protests in the 1960s against the Vietnam War inspired him and his classmates to take to the streets, despite the fact that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> at that time was <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s Enemy No 1. The question most often asked by students was: `` Do n't <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> students demonstrate, too?''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The first thing the people noticed was the tinkling of a bell, then a shaved head and finally a gray robe. A <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monk had come to the demonstration. Walking slowly, shaking his prayer bell, the monk blessed the crowd, which parted before him. `` I feel in my heart for you, all of us support you,'' he said. `` Religion has suffered much in this country. I had to thank you for supporting freedom.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Many of the bystanders carried cameras, anxious for souvenirs of the rare day. But good views were hard to get in the constantly moving crowd, forcing some dedicated photographers to climb trees and bus stop signs. One middle-aged man handed his camera to a youth standing on a bicycle and pleaded with him to `` snap the whole roll.'' The roof of one shanty crumbled under the weight of camera-happy spectators and they came crashing down in a cloud of dust. The crowd roared with laughter and nobody seemed hurt.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Most of the police who withdrew in the face of the huge, insistent crowd did so gracefully. About 50 police who had been roughly pushing back bystanders on a side street abruptly formed a line and trotted off down the street. The crowd shouted, `` Thank you'' and surged forward. A few traffic police caught up in the melee simply took off their uniform white cross-chest straps and belts, climbed over a fence and melted into the crowd. Other police crouched on their haunches at the side of the road, heads in their hands, and smiled wearily as the crowd passed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Entrepreneurs     04-28 0402</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Entrepreneurs,0413</SECOND>
<HEAD>What Makes a Successful Entreprenuer? MIT Just Might Know</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 What makes a successful entreprenuer? A recent <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> survey reports that many are immigrants, the offspring of self-employed parents and hold advanced degrees. The survey of 99 <ORGANIZATION> MIT </ORGANIZATION> graduates who will be honored by the university Saturday night provides some insight into the men and women who give upthe security of a salary to take a chance on their own business. As part of the institute's 128th anniversary, it will honor the 99 sociology consultants, financial managers and computer technicians for their `` hard work, foresight and courage.'' Collectively, they have created 100,000 jobs in the state and 250,000 worldwide in fields that range from women's apparel to geotechnical engineering. The cumulative sales of their companies total $ 25 billion annually. According to the survey, 73 percent earned an educational degree above the bachelor level, and 33 percent went on to doctorate or post-doctorate work. Sixteen percent founded their companies while they were still at school, 34 percent set up shop within five years of graduating and 23 percent opened for business between six years and 10 years after graduation. Two percent founded their companies more than 20 years after graduation. The survey said more than half were the children of parents who founded their own companies. Many of the companies had inauspicious beginnings in basements or rough neighborhoods with minimal staff and equipment. But some of the entrepreneurs had more colorful starts. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Abt </PERSON>, founder of the social sciences consulting firm <ORGANIZATION> Abt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION>, built ship models and sold them to <ORGANIZATION> Saks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fifth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Avenue </ORGANIZATION> when he was only 12. <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> `` Doc'' <PERSON> Edgerton </PERSON>, whom the institute called `` the father of flash photography,'' attempted to market his first strobe equipment through <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, but <ORGANIZATION> GE </ORGANIZATION> was n't interested The three most important lessons the entrepreneurs said <ORGANIZATION> MIT </ORGANIZATION> taught them were problem solving, the importance of hard work, confidence and the belief that anything is possible. And when these busy people take the time to relax and enjoy success, most said they enjoyed tennis, skiing, sailing, music and art and reading. In the advice department, the entrepreneurs recommend that aspiring business adventurers begin by identifying a market opportunity and matching it with an appropriate technology, select partners with talents that complement their own and remember that the success of the enterprise rests with the performance of its employees.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FusionFollowup     04-28 0376</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fusion Followup,0388</SECOND>
<HEAD>Another Scientist Sees Evidence of Possible Cold Fusion</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new experiment confirms observations from the controversial cold fusion research announced last month, giving `` very encouraging'' evidence for fusion, a scientist says. The new experiment generated more power than it consumed and showed two other signs of possible fusion, said researcher <PERSON> Uziel </PERSON> <PERSON> Landau </PERSON>. But results so far are only preliminary and `` we stop short of saying that we see fusion,'' said <PERSON> Landau </PERSON>, a professor of chemical engineering at <ORGANIZATION> Case </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>. Fusion is the nuclear reaction that powers the sun, and some scientists hope to harness it as an environmentally benign power source. It occurs when the cores of two hydrogen atoms fuse. Last month, researchers announced at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION> that they had produced fusion at room temperature with a simple apparatus. Conventional fusion research uses extremely high temperatures and complex machinery. Since the announcement, some scientists have reported similar results while others said their attempts to confirm the work failed. <PERSON> Landau </PERSON> worked with two large test tubes, each containing a small palladium rod to act as one electrode, and a titanium-coated platinum mesh to serve as the other. The electrodes were placed in a bath of so-called heavy water, in which hydrogen is replaced by a chemical cousin called deuterium. The liquid also contained lithium, <PERSON> Landau </PERSON> said Thursday in an interview. According to proponents of cold fusion, the reaction occurs in one of the electrodes when current is applied. <PERSON> Landau </PERSON> said his apparatus produced three possible signs of fusion. One was that the apparatus gave off 8 percent to 30 percent more power than it consumed, with the output given off as heat, he said. The apparatus also produced bursts of extremely tiny particles called neutrons. And the heavy water solution showed about a doubling of its initial concentration of tritium, which is a form of hydrogen, <PERSON> Landau </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Landau </PERSON> said he did not test for production of helium, a product of fusion. Future experiments will use ordinary water rather than heavy water, <PERSON> Landau </PERSON> said. Scientists say that can help rule out the possibility that a chemical reaction, rather than a nuclear reaction, produced the experimental results.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-28 0936</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0969</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Acuff </PERSON>, the 85-year-old `` king of country music,'' would like to continue performing despite an earlier announcement that he's considering retiring, the general manager of the Grand Ole Opry says. <PERSON> Acuff </PERSON>, best known for `` The Wabash Cannonball,'' was honored earlier this week with a special humanitarian award at The <ORGANIZATION> Nashville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Networks </ORGANIZATION>' Viewers' Choice Awards. `` I seem to be a burden on other people,'' the fiddler-singer said after receiving the award. `` I have to be helped through the crowd like a baby. I have to be treated like a baby.'' But <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Durham </PERSON>, Opry general manager, said <PERSON> Acuff </PERSON> has told him he wants to remain on stage where he has performed for presidents and plumbers alike. `` The only health problem I'm aware of is his loss of vision,'' <ORGANIZATION> Durham </ORGANIZATION> said. `` But he still sees, and he wants to work all the shows this year.'' `` He has to depend on someone to help him, and to a person who's been so active, that's a tough adjustment,'' <ORGANIZATION> Durham </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Acuff </PERSON> has entertained on the Opry's radio show for 51 years. For more than 20 years, he made overseas trips to entertain <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> armed forces at Christmas.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer <PERSON> Lena </PERSON> <PERSON> Horne </PERSON> says she'd like to get married again, but doubts she can find a good match. `` The women's movement came a little late in my life,'' Ms. <PERSON> Horne </PERSON>, 71, says in the Sunday issue of Parade magazine. `` I find many women who do n't have the need I do. They want to be independent, see somebody when they feel like it, maybe _ but otherwise, a man is not convenient in their lives. `` I envy that, but I would like to be married,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Horne </PERSON>, whose husband, bandleader-arranger <PERSON> Lennie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayton </PERSON>, died in 1971 after 24 years of marriage. Still, `` I doubt whether I could make a successful marriage now. I've worked out the way I am,'' she added. `` Unless _ unless the man was absolutely unique, one who could match my experiences. Maybe ... if he was a man who has had as many metamorphoses in his life as I've had.'' Ms. <PERSON> Horne </PERSON>, who has released a new album titled `` The Men in My Life,'' lamented that people think `` women in their 70's have no desire to be desired.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The British rock group <ORGANIZATION> Pink </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Floyd </ORGANIZATION> will play five concerts in June at <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s Olympic stadium. The band said the Soviet government made the performances possible by offering to fly in the group's more than 300 tons of stage equipment. Dozens of lasers, computerized lighting systems, circular screens, videos, fireworks, smoke effects and a model of a flying pig, one of the band's trademarks, will be used in the show. `` We have always had a reputation for not cutting corners, trying to put on the best show possible, sparing no expense and producing some surprises,'' said guitarist <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilmour </PERSON>. Soviet officials asked the band to play <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> when <PERSON> Gilmour </PERSON> and fellow band member <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> traveled to the capital last November to watch the Salyut 7 spaceship blast off with their album aboard. `` The Dark Side of the Moon'' is one of the biggest-selling records ever made.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gil </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaham </PERSON>, a young violinist summoned from school in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> to replace veteran <PERSON> Itzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Perlman </PERSON> at two <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> concerts, won plaudits from the audience and flowers from the orchestra. `` This is something I've never had before,'' <PERSON> Shaham </PERSON> said in his dressing room at the Royal Festival Hall after Thursday's performance The audience had called him back four times and cheered him after his performance of the difficult Violin Concerto No. 1 by <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruch </PERSON>. <PERSON> Shaham </PERSON>, 18, was reciting the prologue from <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Chaucer </PERSON>'s `` The Canterbury Tales'' in an English examination on Tuesday when he was called out and asked to fly to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> the next day for two concerts because <PERSON> Perlman </PERSON>, the Israeli virtuoso, was ill with an ear infection <PERSON> Shaham </PERSON> promptly took three days off school. `` I was nervous because I felt I could not fill in for <PERSON> Perlman </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Shaham </PERSON> said. `` I last played the <PERSON> Bruch </PERSON> in December and the <PERSON> Sibelius </PERSON> in the summer.'' `` But the funny thing is,'' he added, `` I had some bizarre premonition about this. On Monday I changed the strings on my Guadagnini -LRB- violin -RRB-, which I always do before a concert, although I was n't booked for any concert this week.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> says <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s President <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> is destroying that country's cultural heritage by razing villages and replacing city buildings with `` a uniform and deathly mock modernity.'' In an unusual royal criticism of a foreign leader, the 40-year-old heir to the British throne said he was appalled at `` the awful specter of an entire society _ not just certain districts _ losing its roots and its ancient communities.'' `` The 20th century has witnessed some strange aberrations of the human spirit but few can match the activities of rulers who boast about their patriotism and then systematically undertake the destruction of the cultural heritage of their people,'' <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> said at an architecture exhibition on Wednesday. `` President <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> has set about destroying the cities and villages of his country and replacing them with blocks of flats -LRB- apartments -RRB- which are a repetition of failed 1960s social engineering mixed with the atmosphere of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Orwell </PERSON>'s ` 1984,''' he added. <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> plans to demolish thousands of villages, as well as historic churches and old cemeteries, to create an ideal communist state of industrial centers and gain more farmland for use by state-owned collective farms.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0158EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan'sRetirement Bjt   04-28 0730</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan's Retirement, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Once-Visible President Sinks From Sight</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When organizers at <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> invited <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to give a speech last month, fewer than one-fourth of the 10,000 tickets were sold in advance and the former president agreed to waive his $ 50,000 fee. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who commanded vast audiences until he left office in January ago, is now out of the limelight, retired into the select club of former presidents that includes <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>. Occasionally, the former president pops back into the news. Both President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Vice President <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> visited him this week in <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. And his name came up more negatively in repeated references during the Iran-Contra trial of former White House aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>. Would one have expected a less reclusive retirement given <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s popularity during his two-term tenure? Probably not, agree president watchers. They differ, however, on whether it's the nature of the man or the nature of the system which is responsible. `` It's not unusual and not at all atypical historically for a former president to slip from sight,'' said <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hess </PERSON>, a presidential scholar at the <ORGANIZATION> Brookings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>, an independent think tank. The advent of a new president is accompanied by a flurry of media attention and public curiosity, <PERSON> Hess </PERSON> said, and the former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> occupant generally just drifts away from power, <PERSON> Hess </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, 78, works in his offices atop a <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> skyscraper, say his aides. He writes speeches on such favorite topics as the need for a line-item veto, a balanced budget amendment and an end to the two-term limit for presidents. He has joined the board of the conservative magazine <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION> and also is planning to write his memoirs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has been virtually mum on the presidency of his successor, and he is rarely mentioned in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. One way for former presidents to step back into the limelight is to take a shot at their predecessor. Thus, <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> made the news in 1981 when he criticized <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s budget proposal for placing too much emphasis on defense spending and not enough on domestic programs. `` But most ex-presidents are obliging and they stay out of the hair of the current occupant of 1600 <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ginsberg </PERSON>, a professor of government at <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also has been careful to avoid criticism of his predecessor. Last month, White House Chief of Staff <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> admonished aides to refrain from unfavorable comparisons of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Some former presidents have made a comeback several years later, returning to vogue once a historical perspective of their presidency has been established. Such was the case with <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>, who left office in 1953 an unpopular leader but was seen in a far more favorable light in the 1960s and until he died in 1972. Presidents who can not bear the obscurity of retirement are rare. <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> did n't want to be an ex-president so he ran against fellow Republican <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> in 1912. His run split the Republican vote, and gave Democrat <PERSON> Woodrow </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> the White House. `` <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is not about to upstage <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Korologos </PERSON>, a lobbyist and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> friend who once served the <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> administrations as a legislative aide. `` <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> did more for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> than any other president has done for his VP, and now he knows it's time to get out of the picture,'' he said <PERSON> Ginsberg </PERSON> and several other scholars and consultants believe <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> aides are particularly anxious that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> maintain a low profile for the time being. `` <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> lived in <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s shadow for eight years. Now he needs to establish himself as an independent and distance himself in some ways,'' <PERSON> Ginsberg </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> himself does n't mention his predecessor very often as he seeks to move subtly away from some of the domestic and foreign policies known as the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> legacy. For example, in reaching a compromise agreement with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on aid to the Nicaraguan Contras, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> effectively killed future military aid to the rebels _ a cause dear to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s heart. `` It's a mark of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s respect for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> that he has bitten his lip and avoided statements even on the things he felt so passionately about like the Contras,'' said <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Eizenstat </PERSON>, who served as <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s domestic policy adviser and is now a political consultant.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0159EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Politics-Glance     04-28 0580</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Politics-Glance,0609</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Government Structure At A Glance</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Soviet-Politics, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is an outline of the structure of the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and government: PARTY STRUCTURE: The <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> holds political power in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, but President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has proposed changes that allow some contested elections to form a legislature that may exercise significant political power. The Communist Party's power is centered in the Politburo and the Secretariat of the party's <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, which has 5,000 elected members, is supposed to be the party's supreme organ, and ordinarily meets every five years. The congress elects the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, made up of 250 to 300 of the country's top leaders. It now has 251 members. The Central Committee normally meets about twice a year to approve policies and formally elects the members of the Politburo and the Secretariat, the two highest party bodies. Since March 11, 1985, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> been general secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, head of the Secretariat and leading member of the Politburo. Since Oct. 1, 1988, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> also has been the nation's president, holding top party and government jobs
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The Secretariat: This Communist Party body is responsible for running social and economic spheres as well as party personnel and ideology, and wields tremendous power over implementation of policy. Politburo membership and a seat on the secretariat traditionally have been considered necessary to gain the top party job. There are now 10 secretaries, including <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The Politburo: <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> runs meetings of the Politburo, the party's most powerful body. It now has 12 full members and eight candidate, or non-voting, members. The Politburo normally meets every week.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 GOVERNMENT STRUCTURE: The Supreme Soviet: The 1,500 members are elected from a single slate of approved candidates and theoretically make up the top government body in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. But it has traditionally met only twice a year to ratify policy set by the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Under a reform pushed through by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, the Supreme Soviet will become a smaller body _ with about 500 members _ that meets several months a year. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> says he wants it to be more active, handling operational questions the party apparatus has assumed over the years and leaving the party to decide policy questions. But the Supreme Soviet has not met under the new format, and the extent of its powers is uncertain. The Presidium of the Supreme Soviet: The presidium, which has 37 members, is the collective presidency that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> leads as chairman. Presidents of each of the 15 Soviet republics are members. The presidium has the power to issue government decrees when the Supreme Soviet, or parliament, is not in session. But the presence of Politburo and regional party leaders in its membership ensures its actions have prior top-level approval.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Council of Ministers: The council, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s Cabinet, is responsible for day-to-day operation of government ministries such as agriculture or transportation. It is headed by Premier <PERSON> Nikolai </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryzhkov </PERSON>, a full member of the Politburo.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 CONGRESS OF PEOPLES DEPUTIES: The <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peoples </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION> is a new 2,250-member body consisting of 1,500 deputies elected from geographical organizations and 750 elected from the party and its affiliates, social, professional and trade union organizations. The congress, which was elected in the first multicandidate balloting, is empowered to choose the president and the Supreme Soviet from among its members, amend the constitution, and review the president's choice for premier.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Afghanistan'sMan Bjt   04-28 0741</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghanistan's Man, Bjt,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Loneliest Diplomat in Town?</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ostracized by the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, confined to the city limits, <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s top diplomat in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> leads a frustrating existence. <LOCATION> Miagol </LOCATION> _ the first, last and only name of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s charge d'affaires _ is hoping the recent pullout of 115,000 Soviet troops from his country will ease some of the isolation imposed on him by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. But he is also realistic. The Soviet-educated economist invited Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> to his embassy's reception Thursday evening marking the 11th anniversary of the revolution that brought to power a Marxist-oriented government and resulted in the 1979 Soviet invasion. `` They said he could n't come, unfortunately,'' <PERSON> Miagol </PERSON> said with a skeptical laugh. Very few Americans attended the reception, which drew mostly diplomats from Soviet bloc and other communist and socialist countries. For a man who has to ask permission every time he wants to leave the city _ and is usually turned down _ <PERSON> Miagol </PERSON> was remarkably cheerful at an interview in the resplendent red-brick mansion which doubles as residence and embassy. `` Physically our life is good,'' he said, `` but morale is difficult.'' <PERSON> Miagol </PERSON>, one of 15 children, does not know how old he is but estimates his age at about 40. `` My mother said there was snow on the ground, but she did n't know in what year,'' he said. <PERSON> Miagol </PERSON> arrived here 10 months ago with his <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> wife and two children. When he asked to travel to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> by car to attend the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> meetings of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> last fall, he was told to go by plane. When he asked permission to drive to the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>'s recreation compound outside <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, he was denied `` They said it was too far. But people from other socialist embassies also have 25-mile limit, and they are allowed to go,'' <PERSON> Miagol </PERSON> said. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and other countries impose 25-mile travel limits on diplomats from countries deemed unfriendly. `` This makes me nervous,'' <PERSON> Miagol </PERSON> said. He spends his days reading messages received by telex from <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, dealing with administrative matters relating to his three-man embassy and keeping in touch with the extensive community of Afghan exiles in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. His only contact with the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is through <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gookin </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Protocol </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, whom he sees about twice a month. `` I give him my opinions,'' <PERSON> Miagol </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Gookin </PERSON> listens politely _ `` he's a very nice man'' _ and conveys <PERSON> Miagol </PERSON>'s views to <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> experts. But <PERSON> Gookin </PERSON> refused to accept a written message from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s leader <PERSON> Najibullah </PERSON> congratulating <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on his inauguration as president and expressing his hopes for improved relations, <PERSON> Miagol </PERSON> said. `` They told me to put the envelope in a window for letters'' at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, he said. <PERSON> Miagol </PERSON> said he used the same window to deliver a second message several weeks ago asking the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to stop arming the <ORGANIZATION> Mujahedeen </ORGANIZATION> rebels. The rebels, backed by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, fought the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> occupation for nine years and are now locked in a civil war with <PERSON> Najibullah </PERSON>'s Soviet-backed government. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> continues to view <PERSON> Najibullah </PERSON> as a hardline Marxist and fails to see that he is gaining acceptance by Afghans as the only viable choice for leading the war-wracked country, <PERSON> Miagol </PERSON> said. `` They must learn from the mistakes of the Soviets, who did n't understand the Afghan people,'' <PERSON> Miagol </PERSON> said Neither the Soviets nor the Americans understand that Afghans can not embrace Marxism, he said. `` It is not right with our culture, with our religion,'' said the Soviet-educated Moslem. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> withheld recognition from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s government after the Soviets invaded, contending it was not elected democratically and does not represent the Afghan people However, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> continued to function in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, serving as a listening post in the Soviet-run country. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> recognizes many governments that are not democratic, that are fascist dictatorships,'' <PERSON> Miagol </PERSON> said. At least <PERSON> Najibullah </PERSON> was elected to office _ `` maybe not like <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> elections,'' but in accordance with <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s constitution, he said. Once, the Soviets were considered the bad guys in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and the Americans were the good guys, <PERSON> Miagol </PERSON> said. Now, the Soviet tanks and troops have left and they are sending wheat, flour and oil, while the Americans send missiles to the Mujahedeen. `` If the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> continues this, <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> will of course be pro-Soviet,'' <PERSON> Miagol </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     04-28 0869</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,870</SECOND>
<HEAD>Budget Deal Eliminates Some, Not All, USDA Uncertainty</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 1990 budget compromise worked out between the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> earlier this month has eased some of the pressure for cutting farm subsidies but the turmoil is far from over. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> still has a way to go before settling on a spending package for the fiscal year that will begin Oct. 1, and <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> budget experts say farm programs still are expected to be pared. The compromise reached two weeks ago calls for $ 2.4 billion to be whittled from agriculture functions that are covered in the federal budget, says <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON>, deputy director of <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s budget office Initially, he said Thursday in an interview, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> budget proposals were identical, calling for a $ 2.9 billion cut in fiscal 1990 for agriculture-related programs. The major target in the original Reagan-Bush budget proposals was the package of farm programs operated by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Commodity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Credit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a variety of price and income support mechanisms that soared to record spending levels during the 1980s The CCC cuts alone would total $ 1.9 billion. To help <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> show less of a deficit on paper, part of that is to be accomplished administratively by paying about $ 800 million in advance `` deficiency'' payments to farmers early, so they show up on this year's budget rather than in the 1990 budget. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> announced the early payments on April 18, pointing out that the move would `` provide some extra money to farmers'' as they head for the fields this spring. Although <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did not mention that the move also would help reduce his 1990 budget deficit figure, the early payments had long been planned _ in both the initial <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> budget proposals _ as a way to save money next fiscal year. But that still left $ 1.1 billion to be cut from the CCC operations if the 1990 reduction goal of $ 1.9 billion for <ORGANIZATION> CCC </ORGANIZATION> was to be met. One of the simplist ways to cut CCC some more would be a further reduction in crop target prices used to compute payments to farmers. However, that would have required legislation by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to give <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> authority to tinker with the payment formula. <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON> said the mid-April agreement between the administration and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> calls for a CCC reduction next year of $ 600 million, or little more than half the $ 1.1 billion remaining to be cut. But a solution was found. As it turned out, $ 500 million in `` savings'' for 1990 would come from another change that will require legislation. This involves the financing of the <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Credit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> and would be used to offset further reductions in CCC costs. For many years the <ORGANIZATION> FCA </ORGANIZATION> enjoyed independent status as a federal agency, and its annual spending was `` off budget'' and not counted in the government's overall balance sheet of receipts and outlays. But after the farm credit problems of the 1980s forced <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to crack down on the huge system of federal land banks, production credit associations and other institutions overseen by <ORGANIZATION> FCA </ORGANIZATION>, the agency's budget has been part of the regular process. <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON> said that although <ORGANIZATION> FCA </ORGANIZATION> is not part of the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, it is part of the `` agriculture function'' used in budget planning. Thus, it was agreed during the compromise deliberations to move <ORGANIZATION> FCA </ORGANIZATION> once again `` off budget'' and thereby `` save'' $ 500 million. So, with $ 800 million shuffled from one year to another and $ 500 million moved off budget, that leaves $ 600 million in cuts for next year's CCC programs still to be made to reach the $ 1.9 billion in cuts for next year. Exactly how remains to be settled. Additionally, <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON> said, the compromise calls for releasing $ 500 million from a food stamp account held y the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION>, a fund that has been building up since food stamps were initiated in the early 1960s. The money accumulated because some stamps are lost, destroyed, forgotten or otherwise not used to buy groceries. They were never redeemed, although the government still has cash on hand just in case. By releasing the food stamp account, the government will have use of the money _ and the 1990 budget can be trimmed by a further $ 500 million, making a total `` savings'' of $ 2.4 billion claimed by the negotiators. Some have complained that the budget cutters may target their work too much on farm programs, but <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said on April 18 that while agriculture `` has taken a hit, so has a wide array of programs across the board. And I think what we've done here is fair.'' Others have said <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> farm programs could stand even further pruning, pointing out that spending on those programs is still high although there have been sharp reductions in recent years. In 1984, for example, CCC spending on commodity programs _ including feed grains, wheat, rice, cotton, tobacco, dairy, soybeans, honey and wool _ was about $ 7.32 billion. In 1985, costs jumped to $ 17.7 billion and then rose to a record $ 25.8 billion in 1986. Commodity program spending dropped to $ 22.4 billion in 1987 and since has declined to an estimated $ 13.8 billion this year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-OscarEpilogue Bjt   04-28 0627</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Oscar Epilogue, Bjt,0642</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Rain Man' Continues to Bask in Oscar Afterglow</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HORN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The outlaw Snow White has disappeared and the copyright lawsuits have been shelved, but the real impact of the 61st Academy Awards has not diminished in the month since the curtain fell on the glitzy ceremony. `` Rain Man,'' winner of five major trophies, including best picture, has enjoyed a record-breaking post-Oscar surge, and a number of lesser victors have profited handsomely from their awards. `` Rain Man,'' the reigning domestic box-office champion with revenues of $ 156 million, is now <ORGANIZATION> MGM-United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Artists </ORGANIZATION>' highest-grossing film ever, and is expected to be its biggest international hit, too Meanwhile, best foreign film winner `` Pelle the Conqueror'' is selling tickets at a brisk pace across the country, and sales for best original song `` Let the River Run'' from `` Working Girl'' have skyrocketed. `` A Fish Called <PERSON> Wanda </PERSON>,'' which won an Oscar for best supporting actor, is No. 1 on the home video-rental charts. Most post-Oscar publicity focused on the Oscar telecast's opening production number in which an unauthorized Snow White impersonator presented material so strange Disney promptly sued for copyright infringement In addition, a group of 17 producers, actors, directors and writers complained to the Academy that the show, with all its hype and glitz, `` was an embarrassment to both the Academy and the entire motion picture industry.'' The note, dated two days after the March 29 show, was sent to <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON> and the Academy's board of governors. `` It is neither fitting nor acceptable that the best work in motion pictures be acknowledged in such a demeaning fashion,'' said the letter, signed by <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON>, <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Donen </PERSON>, <PERSON> Blake </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Lumet </PERSON>, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Peck </PERSON>, <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> and others. But the performance by `` Rain Man'' has transcended the flap over the telecast. `` Rain Man'' has taken in $ 127 million internationally, and the story of a scheming car salesman learning to love his autistic brother will likely surpass all of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Artists </ORGANIZATION>' `` Rocky'' sequels and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> features in foreign receipts. `` A year ago, when we planned the release of this picture, we felt with the cast and the director and the story structure, that we had a major chance for Academy nominations and awards,'' said <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> MGM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>. `` So we planned the foreign release so that we would be breaking on the screens around the world at the time the nominations were announced and the awards were given. So the strategy worked perfectly and the picture has just bombarded the marketplace.'' `` Rain Man'' is now playing in more than 50 countries, <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> said. In 6 -LCB- weeks of release in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, `` Rain Man'' has grossed in excess of $ 25 million. The movie's Oscar triumph _ it also won best actor for <PERSON> Dustin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>, best director for <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON> and best original screenplay for <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Bass </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrow </PERSON> _ has boosted many of the film's related performers. <PERSON> Valeria </PERSON> <PERSON> Golino </PERSON>, the movie's co-star, now is inundated with scripts and has just completed the coming feature `` Torrents of Spring.'' For other movies that might have faded without any Oscar hype, the Academy Awards have given them a fresh jolt of momentum. `` Upon winning the Academy Award, we've found that a lot more people are interested in ` <PERSON> Pelle </PERSON>' and in -LRB- the film's star -RRB- <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Von </PERSON> <PERSON> Sydow </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>, national sales manager for `` <PERSON> Pelle </PERSON> the Conqueror'' distributor <ORGANIZATION> Miramax </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said `` <PERSON> Pelle </PERSON>,'' with $ 1.9 million in the bank to date, is now playing in such cities as <LOCATION> Winsted </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Fargo </PERSON>, <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Orem </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, not bad for a 2 -LCB- - hour film about Swedish immigrants working on a turn-of-the-century farm and speaking not one word of English
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SeniorJudges-Pay Bjt   04-28 0782</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Senior Judges-Pay, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Non-Working Senior Judges are Obstacle for Judicial Pay Raise</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL J. SNIFFEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Five congressmen put a trio of leading judges on notice: the pay raise so vigorously sought by federal judges may well depend on denying it to senior judges who do no judicial work. `` Pay raises should be reserved for those who work,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kastenmeier </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Wis </LOCATION>., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> courts subcommittee His message was echoed by four <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> colleagues at a hearing Thursday. They were taken aback by testimony from the judicial leaders, who are seeking a 30 percent pay raise for all federal judges. <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Circuit Judge <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Coffin </PERSON> depicted a federal bench demoralized over the loss of a 51 percent pay raise earlier this year, but he displayed no willingness to compromise in response to complaints over pay that members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> hear when they go home to the voters. `` I have never seen so many judges at all levels, in all courts, and in all parts of the country so disheartened as I do today,'' <PERSON> Coffin </PERSON> said. `` Ours is a lunar landscape with all of the stark and ominous silhouettes that the term implies.'' He called Feb. 7, the day <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> defeated the pay raise, `` Black Tuesday.'' But Rep. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Coble </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>, replied, `` Many voters in my district do not regard it as Black Tuesday, and I'm one of them.'' Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wis </LOCATION>., said, `` One catalyst for that defeat was the front page story in most of the nation's newspapers that former Chief Justice <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Burger </PERSON>'' and other senior judges who do no judicial work would get the raise He said he went to four town meetings in his district at that time `` and I heard about that 50 times if I heard about it once.'' Then he offered the three judges what he called `` a little bit of friendly advice: the senior judge situation must be resolved if you want a pay raise. ... And I've not seen much in the way of constructive suggestions from you.'' Rep. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Sangmeister </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ill </LOCATION>., said he too was peppered with objections at town meetings after the news stories `` I was faced with the Burger question,'' <PERSON> Sangmeister </PERSON> said. `` And I was not able to defend that.'' Earlier this year, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reported previously unpublished federal figures from 1987 that showed that 20 percent of 306 senior federal judges did no judicial work. These include <PERSON> Burger </PERSON>, who since he stepped down has spent his time chairing the celebration of the bicentennials of the Constitution and <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> of Rights. An <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> survey of all senior judges in February and March of this year found that 17 percent of 277 senior judges did no judicial work. The <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> survey credited judges for dormant cases still on their dockets, which the earlier government data had not. Coffin and his colleagues told the subcommittee it would be unfair to deprive non-working senior judges of pay raises by, as Coffin put it, `` suddenly changing the rules after a lifetime.'' He said only three of the non-working seniors were under age 70; 16 were in their 70s, 20 in their 80s, two in their 90s and two in their 100s. <PERSON> Kastenmeier </PERSON> asked whether these non-working senior judges should n't go into full retirement. <PERSON> Kastenmeier </PERSON> and the subcommittee's ranking Republican, Rep. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Moorhead </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, introduced a bill earlier this month to require that senior judges carry a 25 percent workload to qualify for raises. Those senior judges who did less work would get their last full salary and cost-of-living increases, but no raises above that. At the hearing, <PERSON> Kastenmeier </PERSON> announced that he and <PERSON> Moorhead </PERSON> had agreed to the judges' request to introduce in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> a 30 percent pay raise and annual cost-of-living increases for judges. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has proposed a 25 percent pay raise for judges. A 51 percent raise tied to equal increases for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and top executive branch officials died earlier this year in the face of public uproar. Currently, judges who reach 65 with 15 years experience can resign and keep for life the full salary on their last day of work. They get no cost-of-living increases but are allowed to resume the private practice of law. Currently, 14 have done this. Alternatively, at that age and experience, federal judges may opt for senior status and do as much or as little work as they like. These senior judges still pick up all the pay raises given to active judges, and like active judges they ca n't have private law practices. The number of judges in this category hovers near 300. There are about 700 active judges.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0247EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Soviet-Military     04-28 0596</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Military,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kremlin Will Publish Defense and Space Spending Data, Scientist Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Kremlin will publish long-promised figures on the Soviet defense and space budgets by the end of the year, says <PERSON> Roald </PERSON> <PERSON> Sagdeyev </PERSON>, a leading <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> rocket scientist who is prominent in the reform movement. Soviet military spending is being cut 1.5 percent this year, far short of the 14.2 percent cut announced by Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in January, said <PERSON> Sagdeyev </PERSON>, who is a member of the Supreme Soviet, or parliament. Defense spending will go down another 7 percent in 1990, and the cuts will reach 14.2 percent the following year, he said, although the total amount of the cuts remained unclear. `` We have promised that the absolute figure would be given in the fall,'' <PERSON> Sagdeyev </PERSON> told a group of reporters Thursday. <PERSON> Sagdeyev </PERSON> declined to specify how he knew that military spending figures would be disclosed by year end, but he is thought to be part of a group of scientists and intellectuals who advise <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> on foreign policy. <PERSON> Sagdeyev </PERSON> was also elected in balloting March 26 to represent the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> in the newly created <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peoples </ORGANIZATION>' Deputies, which will have the twin functions of electing a <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> president _ almost certainly voting <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> a new five-year term _ and selecting a new smaller parliament. The issue of Soviet military spending is murky. For years, Western analysts have complained that figures for Soviet defense spending were distorted because prices are set by the state, and the cost of expensive armaments could be vastly underestimated in official statistics. An indefinite delay in implementing price deregulation has led Western analysts to say that even more complete disclosure of Soviet military spending can not be accurate, since Soviet leaders themselves do not know the true cost of weapons. A study released last weekend by the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said that Soviet military spending had risen by 3 percent in 1988. The <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> found strong evidence, however, that last year `` <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> took several actions that evidently were intended to lay the groundwork for future military cuts.'' Furthermore, the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> concluded, the 14.2 percent cut in military spending announced by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> last January probably will lead to much larger cuts than the 500,000 troop reduction he announced at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> last December. <PERSON> Sagdeyev </PERSON>'s description of the 14.2 percent defense cuts as gradual suggested that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> wants to make them as part of arms control agreements with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Sagdeyev </PERSON>, in a wide-ranging discussion, also released the text of a hitherto undisclosed resolution he said was passed by the <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> last week describing the deaths of 20 demonstrators in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> as a `` criminal act'' that endangered to Kremlin reforms. <PERSON> Sagdeyev </PERSON> was one of three members of the Soviet academy, along with human rights activist <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> historian <PERSON> Dmitri </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Likhachev </PERSON>, appointed to a parliamentary investigating panel. `` The tragic events in <LOCATION> Tbilisi </LOCATION> -LRB- capital of <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> -RRB- confirm the sad fact that perestroika is in danger,'' said the resolution, using the Russian name for <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms. Special uniformed troops under the Soviet <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>, or MVD, were responsible for using poisonous chemicals, shovels and clubs to suppress the demonstrations in <LOCATION> Tbilisi </LOCATION> on April 9, killing 20 people, the statement said. `` This unusually cruel act has evoked the deep indignation and outrage of our entire society,'' said the resolution, which <PERSON> Sagdeyev </PERSON> said was passed at a meeting of the entire <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> April 21.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0246EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Shuttle-GraphicLaunch     04-28 0513</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shuttle-Graphic Launch,0527</SECOND>
<HEAD>Atlantis Astronauts Rely on New Graphics-Oriented Monitors</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Space Shuttle, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>, designing systems in which three or four seconds `` is forever,'' has developed a graphics-oriented computer program to help flight controllers react to launch emergencies. Atlantis, with five astronauts aboard, was scheduled to launch at midafternoon today. In the seconds and minutes after liftoff, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> is to make its most extensive use of a flight control system which highlights potential hazards with colorful displays. Past mission managers had to sort through mind-numbing columns of data on black-and-white monitors that date back to the Gemini era of the 1960s. The new system, inaugurated at <ORGANIZATION> Mission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> after the 1986 Challenger disaster, gives <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> controllers three or four more seconds to order a shuttle into an emergency landing in case of a sudden failure after liftoff. `` Three to four seconds in a lot of different failure modes is forever,'' says senior <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> controller <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Muratore </PERSON>. From typewriter-style keyboards, controllers can now punch up graphics that trace the shuttle trajectory, duplicate cockpit instrument displays and even mimic the horizon as the astronauts see it from inside their rising space ship. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> is designing artificial intelligence programs to help plug its `` brain drain'' as thousands of experienced Apollo era employees retire. The generic name for such programs is `` expert systems.'' <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> has begun implementing its expert system at the <ORGANIZATION> Mission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> center in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> as part of a multimillion-dollar improvement program scheduled for completion in 1991. <PERSON> Muratore </PERSON> is in charge of developing the system. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> hopes expert systems can capture the knowledge of veteran employees to help younger workers do various jobs. <PERSON> Muratore </PERSON> predicted his system will cut months off the minimum time of two years that controllers must spend in training before being assigned to a flight. `` They have to make a mental picture of what's going on with the shuttle,'' <PERSON> Muratore </PERSON> explained. `` We took some senior controllers and learned how they built their mental models, then programmed the computer to do that for them.'' When shuttles returned to flight in September, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> installed the expert system to help engineers pinpoint trouble in the orbiter's three main engines. It ran in tandem with the traditional system. `` We were prepared to take actions'' based on the new program, <PERSON> Muratore </PERSON> said. `` I do n't know of any other case where somebody has built an expert system and then put life and property on the line that way.'' Since then, <PERSON> Muratore </PERSON> said, the system has become a `` primary tool'' for four controllers who monitor communications, engines, mechanical systems, and guidance and navigation. With the system <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> is phasing out, controllers decipher multiple pages of data displayed on their computer screens, all while monitoring dozens of blinking console lights _ each of which can signal two or more safe or unsafe conditions. In the old system, flight information is stored in two computers and displayed on every controller's console. By comparison, <PERSON> Muratore </PERSON>'s system divides the data among individual consoles, shaving precious seconds off the processing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0245EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Shuttle-Glance     04-28 0135</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shuttle-Glance,0142</SECOND>
<HEAD>Key Facts and Figures About Shuttle Flight</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Space Shuttle, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here, at a glance, are the facts and figures about the 29th space shuttle flight: Spaceship: Atlantis, on its fourth flight. Launch: Between 2:24 p.m. and 2:47 p.m. EDT today. Orbit: 184 miles above <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. Landing: At <ORGANIZATION> Edwards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, scheduled for Tuesday. Crew: <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Capt. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, 44, commander; <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Col. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Grabe </PERSON>, 43, pilot; <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cleave </PERSON>, 42; <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thagard </PERSON>, 45, and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Maj. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, 36. Major goal: In the first space shuttle planetary mission, the crew is to propel the <ORGANIZATION> Magellan </ORGANIZATION> spacecraft on a 450-day journey to orbit and map the planet <PERSON> Venus </PERSON>. Next mission: <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> in August with a classified <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> payload.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0244EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;Ls     04-28 0707</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;Ls,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Panel Wants S&amp;L Owners to Put up More Money</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> members who want savings and loan owners to put up more of their own money when they make loans will be fighting to preserve a legislative victory when they resume work next week on President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s bailout proposal. After hours of debate, the panel voted 36-15 Thursday to require S & amp; L owners by January 1995 to risk $ 3 of `` tangible'' or `` real money'' capital for every $ 100 they lend. Treasury Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> praised the action in a statement released after the vote, even though the deadline is 3 -LCB- years later than the June 1991 date sought by the administration. `` Requiring S & amp; Ls to put their own capital at risk ahead of the taxpayers' money is the only way to prevent in the future the unsound business practices that contributed to the current crisis,'' <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is proposing to spend at least $ 157 billion over 10 years, the bulk of it from taxpayers, to close or merge failed S & amp; Ls. He also wants to restructure the regulatory system, spend $ 50 million a year to investigate and prosecute fraud in S & amp; Ls and boost capital requirements. Assistant Treasury Secretary <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Mullins </PERSON> said the panel's adoption of a 3 percent layer of protection between S & amp; L loans that could go sour and federal insurance funds was more important than the timetable for achieving it However, consumer groups are worried about a subsequent amendment, sponsored by Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> McCollum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Fla </LOCATION>., that would permit thrift institutions to continue to risk depositors' funds in subsidiaries involved in high-risk investments such as junk bonds and commercial real estate `` It's a pretty critical loophole,'' said <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, a lobbyist for the Consumer Federation of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. `` It erodes what was just passed.'' The administration had proposed that institutions raise extra capital to back those subsidiaries and the committee chairman, Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, had attempted to compromise by giving institutions five years to come up with the money. However, the committee voted 26-24 to adopt <PERSON> McCollum </PERSON>'s measure. He argued that without it many institutions now operating safely and profitably with subsidiaries would not be able to raise the extra capital. Another amendment, sponsored by Rep. <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, D-Mass., would permit federal regulators to count mortgage servicing contracts as capital Such contracts, which pay institutions to collect monthly payments from homeowners on behalf of investors who own the mortgages, provide a steady source of income and can be sold if an institution is closed. The overall capital measure has a series of interim targets, beginning June 1, 1990, when the tangible capital standard would become 1.5 percent. It would move to 2 percent in January 1992, 2.25 percent in January 1993 and 2.625 percent in January 1994 before reaching the full 3 percent a year later. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> committee's standard is substantially stricter than the bill passed last week by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, which would require 1.5 percent tangible capital by June 1991. Current law provides for a 3 percent standard, but contains many accounting loopholes that count intangible assets such as `` goodwill'' as capital. At the end of last year, more than a third of the solvent <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls' $ 60 billion in listed capital was composed of goodwill, which represents the value an institution's customer loyalty and name recognition Critics argue that goodwill evaporates when an institution fails and thus provides no protection to government deposit insurance funds. According to the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, about two-thirds of the nation's 3,000 S & amp; Ls can meet the 3 percent tangible standard. Some of those that do not should be able to raise the money, but about 245 may have to seek merger partners, it said. Institutions failing to meet the standard would be subject to growth restrictions and closer regulatory supervision. Rep. <PERSON> Floyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Flake </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, said he intends to offer an amendment Monday that would provide more favorable treatment of goodwill. He and others, including the powerful chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rules </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, Rep. <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., argue that it is unfair to wipe out the goodwill because during the early 1980s regulators permitted the accounting break to otherwise healthy institutions in exchange for taking over ailing thrifts
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0243EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BaldnessDrug     04-28 0353</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Baldness Drug,370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anti-Baldness Drug Works on Growth Genes, Researchers Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM BOVEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Researchers for a <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> pharmaceutical company say the anti-baldness drug minoxidil appears to stimulate the genes that make hair grow. Minoxidil `` not only affects growing cells, but affects cells that make hair-shaft protein,'' <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Groppi </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a research with the <ORGANIZATION> Upjohn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Kalamazoo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, said Wednesday. `` Minoxidil affects gene activity that affects the growth of the -LRB- hair -RRB- shaft.'' Knowledge gained from study of minoxidil's effects on genes could have implications for research into genetically based diseases, such as sickle-cell anemia, said <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Buhl </PERSON>, also an <ORGANIZATION> Upjohn </ORGANIZATION> researcher. Marketed by <ORGANIZATION> Upjohn </ORGANIZATION> under the trade-name Rogaine, minoxidil was originally developed for use internally to control blood pressure. <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> last year approved the drug for use externally as a treatment for baldness. Although the drug is approved for sale, scientists have n't clearly understood why minoxidil promotes hair growth <ORGANIZATION> Upjohn </ORGANIZATION> researchers had theorized that the drug improved the flow of blood to the hair roots, thereby stimulating growth. However, the <ORGANIZATION> Upjohn </ORGANIZATION> research, released at the annual meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investigational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dermatology </ORGANIZATION>, suggested the drug had a more basic effect on hair growth. <PERSON> Groppi </PERSON> said he believes minoxidil's effect on the genes is particularly strong. `` I ca n't think of -LRB- a drug -RRB- offhand that has such a potent effect on gene expression,'' he said. Another scientist, however, was skeptical that the <ORGANIZATION> Upjohn </ORGANIZATION> finding represented a significant advance. `` It could well be that it does affect those genes, but there are very many stimulants on the cells that control genes,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON>, biology professor at the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Cambridge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. `` That does not set minoxidil apart.'' Although the drug may affect hair follicles, there is no reason to believe that the drug would have similar effects on other types of cells, <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON> said the research would have been more convincing had it identified a specific gene or group of genes affected by the drug. <ORGANIZATION> Upjohn </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Kaye </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said the researchers had n't identified a specific gene
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0240EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PlaneDoorHearing     04-28 0437</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Plane Door Hearing,0447</SECOND>
<HEAD>United Did Not Fully Inspect Ill-Fated Cargo Door</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NICHOLAS K. GERANIOS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A hearing on why a cargo door tore off a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> 747, killing nine passengers, ended without conclusive evidence on the cause of the February accident southwest of <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> listened for three days to a list of missteps by <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, and grilled aircraft designers from The <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, but no culprit emerged. `` The hearings here were extremely helpful,'' <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> investigation, said Thursday. `` We gained a lot of good information.'' He declined to make any conclusions, but said the information will be analyzed for several months before the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> issues a final report identifying the probable cause of the accident, <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said. The cargo door and part of the fuselage tore off <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> Flight 811 as the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 was climbing to 23,000 feet on Feb. 24. Nine passengers were sucked out of the plane over the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>, 85 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> as the plane headed for <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> via <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>. Speculation has focused on a possible malfunction in the locking mechanism of the cargo door, which remains on the bottom of the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> has not decided whether to retrieve the door. On Thursday, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> officials said they failed to fully inspect a cargo door after electrical repairs were made two months before the accident. A <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> executive said mechanics made a partial inspection of the cargo door after it was repaired Dec. 23 in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. That was a coincidence, because the company has testified it was unaware it was under federal regulations to do a full inspection of the doors. `` I am convinced the check ... verified that the door was working,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Doll </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> vice president for technical services. He added, however, that the inspection was not as thorough as the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> required. In other testimony, an <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> inspector who oversees <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>'s 31-plane 747 fleet said he was not aware of the problems with the 800-pound cargo door The inspector, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Batiza </PERSON>, also said the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> had failed to ensure that <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> complied with a federal rule that took effect July 1, requiring airlines to inspect cargo doors after they were manually operated because of electrical problems. <PERSON> Batiza </PERSON> testified that he had not found any deficiencies in <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>'s maintenance program recently, even though <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> officials have acknowledged they were unaware of the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> rule on cargo door inspections and were not in compliance for about nine months.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0240EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WrightProbe     04-28 0766</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wright Probe,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Committee Plans Second Attempt at Questioning Gas Well Investors</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> sent an $ 8,000 check this week to pay the costs of chartering a campaign airplane four years ago from an associate of the owner of a <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> savings and loan institution. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, who on Thursday lost his bid to make an early presentation of his case before the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee, said the failure to pay the bill earlier was an `` oversight.'' In another matter Thursday, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee rescheduled the testimony of five Texans involved in a gas drilling venture that yielded huge profits to <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. The five were threatened with a contempt citation if they fail to show up for a second time. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s office this week filed a correction to his campaign financial report for 1985 to disclose the reimbursement. Aide <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> said he did n't ask the owner of the plane, <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Hood </PERSON>, why he suddenly called this week for the money. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s office was notified of the unpaid bill on Tuesday after Hood learned that the Wall Street Journal was inquiring about the matter, according to knowledgeable sources. According to a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> source who spoke on condition of anonymity, <PERSON> Hood </PERSON> was an associate of <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaubert </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gaubert </PERSON>, owner of a <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> savings and loan institution, arranged the charter for <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s campaign, the source said. The trip June 30 to July 2, 1985, included <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> and others. The tour of seven <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> cities was in preparation for a November fund-raiser, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s office said. The ethics committee has decided against pursuing charges that <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> improperly lobbied federal S & amp; L regulators to go easy on <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> thrifts, including <PERSON> Gaubert </PERSON>'s. But <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s involvement in S & amp; L issues has figured in the panel's determination of whether he improperly took gifts from people with a direct interest in legislation governing the industry. On <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s request to make a personal appeal to the ethics panel, its chairman hinted strongly for the first time Thursday there will be no such opportunity until <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> appears at a disciplinary hearing expected to come late next month. `` No, there has not been an agreement reached'' on a speedy hearing, said the chairman, Rep. <PERSON> Julian </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Calif. `` I assume he would appear at the disciplinary hearing. At a two-hour meeting Thursday behind closed doors, the panel heard an account from <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> and Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> of their trip early this week to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, when they were `` stood up'' by the participants in the gas well venture. The panel then ratified <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>'s ruling that a subpoena for the witnesses was valid and enforceable, the chairman said. The testimony is scheduled for next week. `` Without any question, the committee lost round one, but there'll be more of this fight before it's over,'' said <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>, the panel's senior Republican. The committee is seeking to wrap up loose ends in its 10-month investigation of <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, who has been formally charged with 69 instances of violating House rules. The charges allege that <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, improperly accepted some $ 145,000 in gifts from a <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> business partner who had a direct interest in congressional legislation and that he used bulk sales of a book he wrote to circumvent <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> limits on outside earned income. But before finishing its preliminary inquiry into charges against <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, the panel wants to know whether a gas well that produced a financial bonanza to the speaker's blind trust amounted to a gift from people with an interest in legislation. Part of the inquiry also will focus on whether <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s blind trust, which the ethics committee approved when the trust was established in 1987, was truly insulated from <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. Mallightco, an investment partnership of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> real estate developer <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mallick </PERSON>, and their wives, turned a $ 9,120 cash investment into a $ 340,000 profit in one day last May, boosting the value of the partnership just a month before <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s blind trust sold its interest. The amount of money involved aroused the curiosity of the ethics panel, and subpoenas were issued for <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> financier <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaffe </PERSON>, his son M.D. -LRB- <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Jaffe </PERSON>, and three others involved in the transaction. The five failed to show up Tuesday for a scheduled interview at a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> hotel. <ORGANIZATION> Stanley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brand </ORGANIZATION>, their <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> lawyer, argued in a letter that the subpoenas were too broad, violated his clients' right to privacy and were irrelevant to the ethics panel's inquiry The committee overruled Brand and ordered the witnesses to come to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for interviews on May 3 and 4, <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890428-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-89 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Budget     04-28 0585</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Panel Sends $1.17 Trillion Budget to Floor</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
