<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 2350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AxSlayingsTrial     10-03 0358</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ax Slayings Trial,0370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brom Convicted of First-Degree Murder for Family Ax Murders</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROCHESTER, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A teen-ager accused of killing his parents and younger brother and sister with an ax was found guilty on Tuesday, his 18th birthday, of four counts of first-degree murder. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Brom </PERSON>, tried as an adult, had pleaded innocent by reason of mental illness. The Olmsted County District Court jury deliberated about four hours and 45 minutes before returning the guilty verdicts. Brom showed no emotion as the verdict was read shortly after 9 p.m. He was charged with four counts each of first - and second-degree murder in the February 1988 slayings The first-degree murder convictions mean that jurors believe the slayings were premeditated. The trial will move to a second phase Thursday to determine whether <PERSON> Brom </PERSON> was mentally ill at the time and therefore not responsible for his actions. `` Obviously, coming in we knew that phase one was not the strong part of the case for us,'' <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> attorney <PERSON> Terrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> had agreed that <PERSON> Brom </PERSON> committed the murders but argued that they were not premeditated, said the defense would show that Brom `` is and was mentally ill.'' If Brom is found to have been sane when the murders occurred, he faces a life imprisonment sentence with no chance of parole for 17 -LCB- years on each of the four counts <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Brom </PERSON>, 41, suffered 22 ax wounds in the slayings at the <PERSON> Broms </PERSON>' rural <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION> home; <PERSON> Paulette </PERSON>, 41, suffered 18 wounds; 13-year-old <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> had eight wounds and 11-year-old <PERSON> Ricky </PERSON> had nine, Dr. <PERSON> Kathryn </PERSON> <PERSON> Berg </PERSON> testified Tuesday. Olmsted County Attorney <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmitz </PERSON> in his closing argument said the number of times each victim was struck by the ax could in itself be enough to prove premeditation. The prosecutor also reminded jurors that <PERSON> Brom </PERSON> had many conversations with friends in the months before the murders in which he discussed killing his family. Brom did not testify. <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> argued that <PERSON> Brom </PERSON>'s discussions with friends were fantasy. `` The ` plan' consisted of a series of disjointed, illogical, fantasy-like thoughts, flitting in and out of the mind of <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Brom </PERSON> intermixed with thoughts of suicide,'' <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 2337EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-MississippiCongressional     10-03 0282</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mississippi Congressional,0289</SECOND>
<HEAD>Republican, Democrat Advance to Congressional Runoff</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Election Rdp</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JACK ELLIOTT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JACKSON, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Democratic state senator and a Republican political aide forced each other into a congressional runoff Tuesday, capturing the top two spots in a special election to fill the seat of the late Rep. <PERSON> Larkin </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. Democrat <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> and Republican <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> easily took the top two spots in the three-way race, leaving a stunned state Attorney General <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> trailing by more than 15,000 votes. The special election was scheduled after <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> died in a plane crash Aug. 13. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> and <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> will face each other in an Oct. 17 runoff. Democrats have been hoping to strip the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> of a seat it has held for more than 16 years. Unofficials returns showed <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> with 51,383 votes, or 42 percent, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> with 45,623, or 37 percent, and <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> with 24,497, or 21 percent. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, 36, who ran unsuccessfully for the same seat in 1988, surprised the better-known <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, who finished third in the home county where he was district attorney for 12 years. `` We felt all along that we charted a course down the middle that if there was a runoff we would be favored by each side,'' <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said. `` There were a lot more people who voted Democratic than Republican.'' <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, 37, who was criticized for wanting to leave the attorney general's office after only 21 months in office, said he would support <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> in the runoff. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, 45, a longtime aide to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Trent </PERSON> <PERSON> Lott </PERSON>, said his campaign had `` come from nowhere to be here tonight.'' He promised his supporters `` two weeks of excitment.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 2342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-US-Panama 9thLd-Writethru a0835 10-03 1159</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Panama, 9th Ld-Writethru, a0835,1,100</SECOND>
<HEAD>``Nothing's Changed'' After Failed Coup, Bush Spokesman Says</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS grafs 15-16 bgng: ``But according,'' with report of
coup support authorized last year.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> declared Tuesday that the attempted coup against <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was not `` some American operation,'' and he wants `` to see democracy in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> succeed.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s spokesman said the government would continue seeking <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s ouster. `` Nothing's changed. Everything remains the same. We'll continue to press for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s removal'' and his arrest to stand trial in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on drug charges, said spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. Late Tuesday, after a day of sorting out conflicting reports on the coup attempt, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials had determined it had failed. Soon after, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s officials claimed victory in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Though the overthrow attempt, by members of the <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>, failed after a morning gun battle at the forces' headquarters, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the attempt `` shows the opposition to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> within <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> It shows there is a strong faction at least within the PDF -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- that felt he should be removed.'' `` We did not take any action that would have constituted direct involvement,'' said <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. `` We had helicopters that were in the air observing and we had some troops around one of the causeways there to protect access and rights and so forth.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> himself told reporters emphatically, `` There were rumors around that this was some American operation and I can tell you that is not true.'' Greeting Mexican President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> for a State dinner at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was asked if he were disappointed that the coup failed. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> stated emphatically, `` I want to see democracy in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> succeed.'' Tuesday night, Sen. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>, introduced legislation authorizing the president to use the armed forces to remove <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> from power and bring him to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The president, meanwhile, refused to speculate on whether he should have used the military to intervene. `` I know the facts and some of the critics do n't,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in response to questions at the White House dinner. The chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> for not making it a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> operation _ for not sending <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops to help the insurgents. `` Here you have brave people in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> ... trying to rid themselves of a drug dealer and a thug who's taken over their country,'' said the chairman, Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., after an hour-long classified briefing from <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> officials `` And for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, with all of our strength and force and all of our belief in democracy, to stand by _ two miles away as the crow flies _ and do nothing, and allow these people to fail, personally I think is wrong.'' But according to an article in Wednesday editions of the <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, it was opposition from <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> a year ago that defeated a plan approved by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to finance, train and supported disaffected Panamanian officers in an attempt to overthrow <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> objected that the effort was too close to the election, might amount to authorizing assassination and might result in the deaths of many Americans, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>'s account quoting unidentified `` well-placed'' sources. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official, <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON>, informed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> after the president met with the visiting Soviet defense minister that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s forces appeared to be prevailing. `` He just said ` OK,' and went into another meeting,'' said <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. The spokesman said visiting <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON>. in a meeting earlier Tuesday with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had `` emphasized the integrity of the various countries in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, and we have respected that integrity and have not intervened.'' The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, like the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration before it, has called repeatedly for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s ouster. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, speaking to reporters before the outcome in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> was clear, appeared intent on influencing the situation in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in favor of the insurrectionists. Asserting that he hoped his words would be `` conveyed instantly'' to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` We have no argument with the Panamanian <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>. We've had good relations with the Panamanian Defense Forces. `` Our argument has been, as have many other countries, with Mr. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> who aborted the democratic will of the people of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. And that's where our argument was and that's where our argument is.'' Last May, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had told reporters, `` I would love to see them get him out.'' Asked then if he were calling for the Panamanian Defense Forces to overthrow <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> replied, `` We'd like to see him out of there, not just the PDF, the will of the people of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. ... I would add no words of caution. The will of the people should be implemented.'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> acknowledged that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had some advance word that a coup attempt might be afoot but said he was unaware of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s fate or even his whereabouts. `` We had some indications this sort of thing was in the works, but until it happens, you never know,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. He characterized the prior information as `` rumblings.'' Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would move quickly toward normalizing relations with <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> if <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is deposed but added that any such step would be impossible so long as <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> remains in power. After <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was indicted by two <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> grand juries on drug smuggling charges in February 1988, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration imposed a series of economic sanctions in a bid to oust the general, who is commander of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s military forces. Among other actions, the administration froze all Panamanian assets in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. For the past 19 months, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has not recognized the Noriega-led government as the legal authority in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was first alerted about the gunfire by <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Adviser </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scowcroft </ORGANIZATION> shortly before the president met with Mexican President <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>. Then, <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON> gave a briefing to both <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> jointly, although details in late morning remained sketchy, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. About 50,000 Americans live in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, including more than 12,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel attached to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Southern Command. At the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, deputy spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> said <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> citizens living in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> were being asked to stay at home. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> put its troops and civilians on the isthmus on <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alert </ORGANIZATION>, its highest level of readiness. American troops in combat gear took up positions 600 yards from the barracks in downtown <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Pentagon spokesman <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> were not involved in any way in the disturbance. He added, `` Our facilities down there are locked up; they are secure.'' The American military personnel in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> have been ordered to stay put and not to travel on roads outside the U.S.-owned facilities, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said. The headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> command is about one-half mile from the scene of the shooting and mortar fire, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 2352EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Bush-Soviet 2ndLd-Writethru a0749 10-03 0741</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Soviet, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0749,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Defense Minister Yazov Discusses Arms Control With Bush</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDs: Incorporates INSERT 19th graf: ``After a,''</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 from a0801 1st Ld, which did not have the additional material incorporated into a0749. Pls disregard a0801.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet Defense Minister <PERSON> Dmitri </PERSON> <PERSON> Yazov </PERSON> conferred with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Tuesday on the prospects for reducing nuclear and conventional arms and assured the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people they need not fear the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The Soviet defense minister was kept waiting a half hour as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> got a briefing from national security adviser <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON> on the attempted coup in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. The president was informed after the Oval Office session with <PERSON> Yazov </PERSON> that the attempt to oust Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> apparently had failed. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> broke his usual practice of refusing to answer questions during photo opportunities by telling reporters the fighting in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> was not `` some American operation.'' The president asked <PERSON> Yazov </PERSON> to `` pay my respects to President <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>,'' and said the recent talks with Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> were `` very fruitful.'' `` We are satisfied. We've got some problems still,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, but `` things are moving in the direction we wanted.'' <PERSON> Yazov </PERSON>, emerging 30 minutes later, offered his own rosy assessment of the outlook for arms control. The burly, beribboned general told reporters: `` The main point of my discussions with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president was the question of arms control, the question of reducing conventional armed forces and weapons and the question of promoting a relationship between our two militaries and our two nations.'' Speaking in Russian, <PERSON> Yazov </PERSON> said: `` The Soviet people are cherishing the best sentiments and feeling towards the Americans. We were comrades at arms during the Second World War and we succeeded in winning a great victory. And now we have no grounds, no reason whatsoever, to go into confrontation -LRB- against -RRB- each other.'' Asked if this meeting had furthered the prospects for an arms pact, <PERSON> Yazov </PERSON> smiled and said, `` Well, I do n't think I could really assure success at the negotiations within half an hour.'' But he added, `` Our negotiating teams are working in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. I think we are moving forward step by step to the ultimate conclusion of agreements on the questions. Anyhow, we are counting on progress.'' White House Press Secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said afterward <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had `` reiterated his support for perestroika,'' the Soviet process of reorganization into a more open society, and `` expressed his desire to conclude agreements on conventional forces in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and on chemical weapons as soon as possible and his hopes for progress in START,'' the Strategic Arms Reduction Talks. If <PERSON> Yazov </PERSON> was perturbed at being kept waiting and having events in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> intrude on the Oval Office meeting, he did not show it. Asked if the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> favored the removal of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> from power, <PERSON> Yazov </PERSON> said, `` I am not prepared to talk on the issue because I am not aware of what happened in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. ... We have not talked about it at all. I ca n't tell you anything more.'' <PERSON> Yazov </PERSON> said he and <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> were hoping to reach agreements on several steps to improve the rapidly warming relations between the leadership of the Soviet and American armed forces. `` We are thinking of expanding our exchanges in the military field next year and we are going to draft a whole program which will be designed to promote better understanding between our two militaries and between our peoples,'' he said. Earlier, <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> took <PERSON> Yazov </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Gettysburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, about 62 miles north of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to see the battlefield where Union troops repulsed Gen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s Confederate soldiers in a bloody three-day battle in July 1863 that marked one of the turning points in the American Civil War. <PERSON> Yazov </PERSON> is a Civil War buff. After a two-hour tour of the battlefield and viewing its famous landmarks like Devil's Den and the Wheat Field, <PERSON> Yazov </PERSON> said, `` I wish we would not have any battlefields like this one in the future,'' The <ORGANIZATION> Gettysburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported. <PERSON> Yazov </PERSON>'s busy schedule called for speeches Tuesday at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Myer </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, near the Pentagon and before the Council on Foreign Relations in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, a private group. <PERSON> Yazov </PERSON> will visit <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pendleton </LOCATION>, a Marine training base in <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, on Wednesday, and <ORGANIZATION> Luke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> on Thursday. On Friday he will tour <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bragg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, then return to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for a news conference with <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-ElectionGlance 2ndLd-Writethru a0832 10-03 0291</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Election Glance, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0832,0299</SECOND>
<HEAD>With AM-Election Rdp</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 5 grafs to UPDATE with final figures in Mississippi,
Jackson winning in Atlanta. Pick up 6th graf, `Cleveland: City ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 A brief look at Tuesday's elections around the nation: <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> HOUSE = _ <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>: Democratic State Sen. <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> and Republican <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, a longtime aide to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Trent </PERSON> <PERSON> Lott </PERSON>, advanced to an Oct. 17 runoff in a race to succeed the late Rep. <PERSON> Larkin </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> had 42 percent of the vote to 37 percent for <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and 21 percent for state Attorney General <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>. MAYORS = _ <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>: Former Mayor <PERSON> Maynard </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who served from 1974 to 1982, reclaimed the mayor's office by defeating City Councilman <PERSON> Hosea </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> and four longshot candidates by a 5-to-1 margin _ <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>: <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON> and state Sen. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> won the top two spots in a non-partisan mayoral primary and advanced to a Nov. 7 runoff. <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON> captured 37 percent to <PERSON> White </PERSON>'s 25 percent; the remainder was split by three other candidates. _ <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>: Mayor <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Goddard </PERSON> was favored to win a fourth term in his race against state <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Burton </PERSON> <PERSON> Kruglick </PERSON> and real estate broker <PERSON> Norris </PERSON> <PERSON> Inman </PERSON>. Voters also were considering a proposal to build a downtown baseball stadium. _ <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>: Mayor <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Schultz </PERSON> was trying to become the first mayor to be elected to back-to-back terms since the city switched to a mayor-council form of government 15 years ago. He had seven challengers. OTHER = _ <LOCATION> Escondido </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>: A state Assembly runoff featured a write-in campaign by an anti-abortion Republican, <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyles </PERSON>, who opposed the pro-choice positions of the regular party nominees, Republican <PERSON> Tricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> and Democrat <PERSON> Jeannine </PERSON> <PERSON> Correia </PERSON>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SchoolDisturbance     10-03 0243</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-School Disturbance,0250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Riot Closes Brooklyn High School</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 200 students protesting a teacher's alleged racial remark rioted in a <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> high school Tuesday, closing the school and injuring one police officer, officials said About 1,000 students gathered in front of <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> Williamsburg </LOCATION> section after officials closed it because of the incident. About 100 police officers tried to disperse the crowd, and were met with scattered incidents of bottle throwing. A policewoman was slightly injured when she was struck on the head, said police spokesman Officer <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallagher </PERSON>. Four students were arrested on disorderly conduct charges and one of them also was charged with disorderly conduct, <PERSON> Gallagher </PERSON> said. Last week, `` during an African History class, the history teacher made a remark that offended the students,'' <PERSON> Gallagher </PERSON> said. The exact nature of the remark was not known. The teacher is white. About 75 percent of the school's 3,100 students are Hispanic and 22 percent are black, said <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sobrino </PERSON>, who declined to comment on the remark. About 50 students met with the school's principal, <PERSON> Sonia </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON>, on Tuesday, and went to the school's auditorium after the meeting to voice their dissatisfaction. Ms. <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> did not return repeated calls for comment. Shortly before noon, the group swelled to approximately 200 students, who rampaged through the hallways of the school's third and fourth floors, breaking glass, before leaving the building, <PERSON> Gallagher </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EugeneFodor     10-03 0379</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Eugene Fodor,0391</SECOND>
<HEAD>Violinist Enters Guilty Plea, Placed On Probation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EDGARTOWN, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Violinist <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Fodor </PERSON> said he hopes to rebuild his life and career now that he's been placed on probation for pleading guilty to a drug-related break-in. `` I regard this event as a major turning point in my life,'' <PERSON> Fodor </PERSON> said Monday after a <LOCATION> Dukes </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> court hearing. `` Of course I'm relieved that this ordeal is over,'' he said. `` The experience has been a frightening and profound one. What I want to do now is get back to my music and my life.'' <PERSON> Fodor </PERSON>, 39, of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, pleaded guilty to breaking into a <PERSON> Martha </PERSON>'s Vineyard motel room, where he was found July 27. A search of the room found a bottle containing more than 20 grams of cocaine, a hypodermic needle with a small amount of heroin and a dagger, authorities said. A county grand jury met Monday morning and returned indictments of breaking and entering, possession of heroin and cocaine and possession of drug paraphernalia. After lawyers on both sides conferred, <PERSON> Fodor </PERSON> pleaded guilty to the break-in charge, which carried a maximum penalty of six months in jail. Judge <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Cross </PERSON>, however, placed <PERSON> Fodor </PERSON> on three years' probation, in which he must continue a drug treatment program and will be subject to random testing <PERSON> Fodor </PERSON> pleaded innocent to the other charges, and they were placed on file, pending completion of probation. `` This should n't have been treated as a serious criminal matter and it was n't,'' defense attorney <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Altman </PERSON> said. `` <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Fodor </PERSON> has been to a treatment center and has turned his life around.'' Born in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Fodor </PERSON> began playing violin at age 8. He has performed at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, where in 1974 he became the first American medalist at the Tchaikovsky Violin Competition. After <PERSON> Fodor </PERSON>'s arrest, family members and colleagues said his drug use had begun recently, and followed the trouble he had building on his early celebrity. `` This was a very important experience actually in his life,'' <PERSON> Altman </PERSON> said. `` He was feeling down in the dumps and he turned toward drugs.'' <PERSON> Altman </PERSON> said <PERSON> Fodor </PERSON> has undergone seven weeks of treatment, and couselors say his progress has been good and they are confident he can remain drug free.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpaceShuttle     10-03 0368</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Shuttle,0376</SECOND>
<HEAD>NASA to Set Space Shuttle Launch Date Today</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Launch Decision Not Expected Until Late Afternoon</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOWARD BENEDICT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Aerospace Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Barring unforeseen problems, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> was ready today to set the launch date for space shuttle Atlantis and its nuclear-powered planetary payload. Shuttle managers were assessing the readiness of the orbiter, the payload, the worldwide tracking network and other elements during a two-day meeting that began Monday. No difficulties surfaced during the first day, officials reported. Oct. 12 is the opening day of a launch opportunity when <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> and Jupiter are aligned properly for sending the <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> spacecraft to that distant planet. The launch opportunity closes Nov. 21. Atlantis' crew of five astronauts is to dispatch <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> on a six-year journey to <LOCATION> Jupiter </LOCATION>. When the spacecraft reaches there in 1995, it will fire a scientific probe into the Jovian atmosphere and then orbit the planet for two years of scrutiny. Because <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION> will be powered by two generators fueled by plutonium-238, three citizens' groups last week sued in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, to prevent the launch. The groups contend that a launch accident could spread poisonous plutonium over a heavily-populated area of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> has said the `` highest probability of launch area release of plutonium due to a shuttle accident is less than 1 in 2,500 and such a release would have no appreciable adverse health effects on the population.'' The agency notes similar generators have flown on 22 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> space vehicles, including five manned Apollo moon missions, and that in three instances the well-protected devices survived severe in-flight accidents. Judge <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Gasch </PERSON> has asked the citizens' groups and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> to file briefs in the case on Wednesday and Friday, respectively. He set a hearing for Oct. 10, the day the countdown would begin for an Oct. 12 launch. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Gagnon </PERSON>, coordinator of the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>, one of the three opposing groups, said last week that if the lawsuit is not successful, his organization plans `` to put people into the launch area to sit on top of the launch pad in an effort to stop the launch.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-ElectionRdp     10-03 0494</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Election Rdp,0509</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jackson Runs in Atlanta; Other Races in Mississippi, Cleveland, Phoenix</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MITCHELL LANDSBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Maynard </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was a strong favorite to reclaim his old job today, while <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> Republicans tried to retain a congressional seat that was left vacant when Rep. <PERSON> Larkin </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> died in a plane crash. In <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, five candidates battled in a primary election to succeed Mayor <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Voinovich </PERSON>, who is quitting after a decade in office. Incumbent mayors were running in <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>, <PERSON> N.M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>'s first black mayor, said he was poised for a `` huge victory'' in his bid to reclaim the seat he held from 1974-82. Few observers expected him to be disappointed. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> would succeed <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, who followed him in office and who now is exploring a bid for governor. Young, like <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> before him, is prohibited from seeking a third consecutive term. The most prominent among <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s five opponents was former City Councilman <PERSON> Hosea </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, who entered the race late after <ORGANIZATION> Fulton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Lomax </PERSON> dropped out. Further south, two Democrats and a Republican were running in the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> special election to fill the seat left vacant by <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>'s death in August. The freshman Republican had served less than eight months. State Attorney General <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, one of two Democrats running, is the best known of the three candidates and was considered by many to be the front-runner. The others are Republican <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, who has been an aide to Sen. <PERSON> Trent </PERSON> <PERSON> Lott </PERSON>, R-Miss., and state Sen. <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> If no candidate wins a majority, a runoff will be held Oct. 17. The winner will represent an 11 -LCB- - county district in southeastern <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> that has been in Republican hands since 1972 and is the only <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> seat in the state's five-member <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> delegation So far, Democrats have won four of six special elections to fill <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> seats this year. In <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Voinovich </PERSON>'s departure to run for governor led to a free-for-all among five officeholders. <PERSON> Voinovich </PERSON> has endorsed the lone Republican in the race, <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. <PERSON> Perk </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, the school board president and son of a former mayor. The other candidates, all Democrats, are Court Clerk <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonanno </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Cuyahoga </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hagan </PERSON> and state Sen. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>. The two top vote-getters will advance to the Nov. 7 general election. In <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>, three-term incumbent <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Goddard </PERSON> was the favorite in a three-way non-partisan race, but the mayoral election was somewhat overshadowed by a ballot issue on construction of a downtown baseball stadium. Although <PERSON> Goddard </PERSON> favored the stadium, polls showed him far in front of two challengers, state <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Burton </PERSON> <PERSON> Kruglick </PERSON> and real estate broker <PERSON> Norris </PERSON> <PERSON> Inman </PERSON>, while the stadium measure was trailing. In <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>, Democrat <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Schultz </PERSON> faced eight challengers in his attempt to become the first mayor to be elected to back-to-back terms since the city changed to a mayor-council form of government 15 years ago.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CancerInfections     10-03 0426</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cancer Infections,0439</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study: Fat Bubbles Help Fight Lethal Infection in Cancer Patients</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOUSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cancer patients who can not be treated for lethal infections with a standard drug may become treatable if the drug is enclosed in microscopic bubbles of fat, a study suggests. The bubbles carry the drug to the sites of infection with less problem from the side effects that now limit its use, said researcher <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez-Berestein </PERSON>. He reported a study of treating patients with the help of the fat bubbles, called liposomes, at an <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> science reporters conference Monday. While there are several types of liposomes, the most widely tested consists of multiple layers of fat arranged like the structure of an onion. Liposomes can be used for targeting anti-fungal drugs because they are consumed by white blood cells called macrophages, which infiltrate sites of infection, said <PERSON> Lopez-Berestein </PERSON>, of the M.D. Anderson Cancer Center in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. His study involved a powerful anti-fungal drug called amphotericin-B. Its use is limited by its side effects, which include severe chills and fever. Those side effects were less frequent and less severe when the drug was enclosed in liposomes and given to 46 people with infections. Most had become infected as a complication of leukemia, but some were heart transplant patients. Transplant patients are vulnerable to fungal infections because of therapy to suppress their disease-fighting immune systems, which is aimed at keeping them from rejecting their hearts, <PERSON> Lopez-Berestein </PERSON> said. Forty of the study's patients had previously failed to respond to amphotericin-B and other anti-fungal drugs given conventionally, because of allergy or side effects, he said. In the study, 24 patients showed a complete reponse to the liposome-encapsulated drug, remaining free of the infection for six months or more, he said. The 22 other patients failed to respond. The work will be published in a medical journal, he said. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Higuchi </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION>, an authority on methods for delivering drugs, called the results interesting. `` It seems to me there are real possibilities there,'' he said in a telephone interview. Treating fungal infections is particularly important in leukemia patients because anti-cancer therapy must be stopped during such infections, <PERSON> Lopez-Berestein </PERSON> said. The cancer treatment inhibits the immune system, encouraging more infections, he said. Liposomes also have been shown to improve effectiveness and reduce side effects of a standard cancer drug in animals, <PERSON> Lopez-Berestein </PERSON> said. They also may prove useful for attacking the virus that causes acquired immune deficiency syndrome after it has infected macrophages, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 0025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     10-03 0409</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0430</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Black Rain' Takes Movie Ticket Derby</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HORN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The international thriller `` Black Rain'' was No. 1 in national box office receipts for the second-straight weekend, and two movies starring <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Barkin </PERSON> finished in the top five. `` Black Rain,'' starring <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> as a policeman tracking a Japanese fugitive, grossed $ 6.5 million last weekend. `` Sea of Love,'' featuring <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Pacino </PERSON> and <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Barkin </PERSON>, was second with $ 6.2 million. In third with $ 2.7 million was the comedy `` Uncle Buck,'' with <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Candy </PERSON> as an obnoxious relative asked to babysit for his nephew and two nieces. `` Parenthood,'' with <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> heading an ensemble cast, finished in fourth on sales of $ 2.6 million. In fifth with $ 2.4 million was the debut of `` <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Handsome </PERSON>,'' teaming Miss <PERSON> Barkin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Rourke </PERSON> in a moody drama about a disfigured criminal. `` When <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Met </PERSON> <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> ...,'' the romantic comedy featuring <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Crystal </PERSON> and <PERSON> Meg </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> as best friends who become lovers, was in sixth with earnings of $ 2 million. In seventh was the <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> <PERSON> Vietnam </PERSON> movie `` In Country,'' with admissions of $ 1.369 million. Next was the independent film `` sex, lies and videotape,'' which collected $ 1.368 million. `` Turner and <PERSON> Hooch </PERSON>,'' a police comedy featuring <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanks </PERSON> and a drooling dog, was ninth with $ 1.3 million. In 10th was the action-adventure sequel `` Lethal Weapon 2,'' which gathered $ 1.23 million. Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> 1. `` Black Rain,'' Paramount, $ 6.5 million weekend gross, 1,610 screens, $ 4,039 per screen, $ 19.2 million total gross, two weeks in release. 2. `` Sea of Love,'' Universal, $ 6.2 million, 1,323 screens, $ 4,655 per screen, $ 30 million, three weeks. 3. `` Uncle Buck,'' Universal, $ 2.7 million, 1,710 screens, $ 1,580 per screen, $ 53.2 million, seven weeks. 4. `` Parenthood,'' Universal, $ 2.6 million, 1,384 screens, $ 1,900 per screen, $ 81.7 million, nine weeks. 5. `` <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Handsome </PERSON>,'' Tri-Star, $ 2.4 million, 812 screens, $ 3,002 per screen, $ 2.4 million, one week. 6. `` When <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Met </PERSON> <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> ...,'' <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2 million, 1,162 screens, $ 1,688 per screen, $ 80.8 million, 12 weeks. 7. `` In Country,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.369 million, 606 screens, $ 2,260 per screen, $ 1.5 million, three weeks. 8. `` sex, lies and videotape,'' <PERSON> Miramax </PERSON>, $ 1.368 million, 534 screens, $ 2,563 per screen, $ 17.2 million, nine weeks. 9. `` Turner & amp; Hooch,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.3 million, 1,062 screens, $ 1,238 per screen, $ 65.5 million, 10 weeks. 10. `` Lethal Weapon 2,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.23 million, 1,131 screens, $ 1,085 per screen, $ 141.9 million, 13 weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 0025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Romania     10-03 0258</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Romania,0266</SECOND>
<HEAD>Romania's Ceausescu Proposes Warsaw Pact Intervention in Poland</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> proposed that forces of the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact military alliance intervene to stop <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> from forming a government headed by non-communists, a Hungarian official says. The pro-Solidarity Polish newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Gazeta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wyborcza </ORGANIZATION> said Friday that <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> had received such a proposal from <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> leaders, who staunchly oppose the wave of reform sweeping the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc. <PERSON> Geza </PERSON> <PERSON> Kotai </PERSON>, secretary in charge of international affairs of the Hungarian party, said his party had rejected the proposal. His remark came in an interview with the party newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Nepszabadsag </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Gazeta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wyborcza </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> called in the Polish ambassador in August to complain about the planned formation of a Solidarity-led government in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. It said <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> decided to turn to the leaders of the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact to `` jointly act in favor of preventing a serious situation in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, in favor of defending socialism and the Polish nation.'' The article did not say if <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> had appealed to other members of the seven-nation alliance led by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kotai </PERSON> said, however, the <ORGANIZATION> Hungarian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> received a call for intervention `` and we gave a definite rejection.'' Solidarity journalist <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> became leader of the Polish government last month, the first non-Communist prime minister in the Soviet bloc. The Hungarian <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> is among the most liberal in the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc. It has agreed to hold free elections by June and says it will yield power and join the opposition if it loses.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     10-03 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0426</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EAU CLAIRE, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thank God for Tuesday garbage pickups. They saved <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Tiedemann </PERSON> $ 5.2 million. Mrs. <PERSON> Tiedemann </PERSON> had never purchased a lottery ticket before last week, and last weekend she discarded her first ticket stub, thinking she'd lost. But watching a television report Monday, Mrs. <PERSON> Tidemann </PERSON> recognized the winning numbers and fished her ticket from the bottom of the garbage can. Fortunately, pickup was scheduled for today, she said. `` Never in a million years did we expect to win,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Tiedemann </PERSON>, 22. Mrs. <PERSON> Tiedemann </PERSON>, who works in a shoe factory, and her husband, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON>, told reporters they had no immediate plans on spending the money. `` I have n't the slightest idea. We'll put it into the bank and sit on it,'' said <PERSON> Tiedemann </PERSON>, 26, a machinist. The couple married in April and recently bought a house. Mrs. <PERSON> Tiedemann </PERSON> said she bought the <LOCATION> Lotto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> ticket at a convenience store last week, playing the numbers 8 and 18 because they were the month and date of her birthday. The four other numbers _ 26, 30, 42, and 46 _ were selected at random, she said. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Clausius </PERSON>, a lottery spokesman, said the couple will receive 20 annual installments of $ 192,175 after taxes.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HIGH POINT, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The thing that went bump in the night at <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>'s house turned out to be a 7-foot boa constrictor. `` I do n't want to wake up like that again,'' <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> said. `` I'm still scared It was something to see.'' The snake apparently was resting on a piece of plywood in the rafters of <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>'s basement. As it crawled away, the plywood fell and hit the basement floor. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> went down to investigate about 6:30 a.m. Monday and found himself face to face with the snake. `` My first thought was to kill it, but I said, ` no, I could n't do that,''cause if I had swung -LRB- a shovel -RRB- and missed, no telling where it might have gone. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON>, called police, but when Officer <PERSON> Sherry </PERSON> <PERSON> Lingerfelt </PERSON> arrived, she did n't feel real comfortable about handling the creature. So Ms. <PERSON> Lingerfelt </PERSON> called her sergeant, <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroud </PERSON>. The snake did n't scare <PERSON> Stroud </PERSON>. <PERSON> Stroud </PERSON> got hold of the snake's head and he and Ms. <PERSON> Lingerfelt </PERSON> put it into two large plastic garbage bags and brought it to the police station. Police said they would auction the the snake if its owner does n't show up.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 0055EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp Bjt   10-03 0764</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Supreme Court to Consider Rolling Back Miranda Warning Rights</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> boasted about his experience as a killer to two fellow jail inmates who said they wanted to help him escape, he did n't suspect he was incriminating himself in a 2-year-old unsolved murder. <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>' statements are the focus of a potentially important <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> case that could roll back the rights of criminal suspects to be given so-called Miranda warnings. The high court, beginning what promises to be another controversy-laden term Monday, agreed to use the <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> case from <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> to decide whether undercover agents may elicit confessions from jailed criminal suspects. The justices said they will hear arguments by <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> officials seeking to use <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>' statements to prosecute him for murder. In its normally busy opening session, the court issued orders in more than 1,000 cases _ denying review to most and agreeing to study 22 that will be among more than 150 disputes to be decided by the end of the term in July. The court heard arguments in a <LOCATION> Yonkers </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, desegregation case in which four city councilmen were held in contempt for opposing a plan for attracting subsidized housing to the city's white neighborhoods. The justices also are looking ahead to a term in which they have agreed to decide thorny right-of-privacy arguments in three abortion disputes and the high court's first `` right to die'' controversy. In other action on the first day of its term, the court: _ Agreed to decide whether police nationwide may use sobriety checkpoints in trying to curb drunken drivers The court will review rulings by <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> courts striking down that state's sobriety checkpoint program as an unconstitutional invasion of privacy Courts in other states have upheld virtually identical police tactics. _ Agreed to use a multimillion dollar dispute over the <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitchcock </PERSON> classic, `` Rear Window,'' to resolve key copyright issues _ Said they will decide in an <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> case whether public employers may be forced to put aside partisanship when hiring, promoting and transferring employees _ Left intact <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>'s revocation of a $ 300,000-a-year tax break for a men-only golf club that has counted presidents and members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> among its members _ Refused to spare an evangelical Christian group in <LOCATION> Lenox </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, from having to return $ 5.5 million donated by a wealthy ex-member _ Allowed states to criminally prosecute employers accused of neglecting the health and safety of their employees The justices, without comment, let stand a ruling in an <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> case that federal workplace regulations do not bar such state prosecutions. In the <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> case, the court could weaken its famous 1966 Miranda ruling that requires police to warn suspects of their right to an attorney and to remain silent. An <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> appeals court ruled in November that police violated <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>' rights when they planted an undercover agent in jail to question him about a murder. <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> was charged with fatally shooting <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephenson </PERSON> on Nov. 8, 1984, in <LOCATION> Fairview </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION>. Police lacked a suspect in the murder in 1986 when <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON>, an inmate at <ORGANIZATION> Graham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Facility </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Hillsboro </LOCATION>, told authorities he had information about the homicide. Police then placed <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON> and undercover narcotics officer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Parisi </PERSON> in the <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jail </LOCATION> on March 31, 1986. <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> was being held there awaiting trial on a charge of aggravated battery unrelated to the homicide. <PERSON> Parisi </PERSON>, using the alias <PERSON> Vito </PERSON> <PERSON> Bianco </PERSON>, wore motorcycle garb and told <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> he was interested in planning an escape. Then <PERSON> Parisi </PERSON> asked <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> whether he had ever `` done someone,'' a phrase the appeals court said was intended to elicit information about any killings in which <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> took part. The appeals court said <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> recounted in detail the killing of <PERSON> Stephenson </PERSON>. A state judge ruled in 1987 that <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>' jailhouse statements to <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Parisi </PERSON> about the <PERSON> Stephenson </PERSON> killing could not be admitted as evidence. But state officials said the Miranda ruling only should protect suspects against police coercion, and that there was no coercion in <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>' case. But the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> appeals court said the Miranda ruling applies whenever a suspect is in custody, `` even when the purpose of the custody is unrelated to the purpose of the interrogation.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled in 1980 that law enforcement officials can not hire jailhouse informants to induce criminal defendants in custody to make incriminating statements. The justices in that ruling relied on their own 1964 decision _ handed down two years before <PERSON> Miranda </PERSON> _ that barred government agents from eliciting incriminating information from defendants entitled to a lawyer's help during interrogation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CleanAir Bjt   10-03 0811</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Clean Air, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Agreement Reached to Stiffen Auto Emission Requirements</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Clean air legislation is gaining momentum in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, following a breakthrough agreement that would apply <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s tough auto tailpipe standards to the whole country starting with 1994 models. The 22-0 vote Monday in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> environment subcommittee came after two powerful lawmakers _ Reps. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, D-Calif., and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Mich </LOCATION>. _ shook hands and ended a bitter dispute over the auto <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, the champion of environmental groups, and <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, the auto industry's best friend in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, said Monday they would oppose any attempts to change the agreement. Their pact virtually ensures new, tough auto pollution controls because the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s clean air legislation is even stricter than the compromise The auto industry was quick to express its displeasure with the proposed exhaust standards. <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Poling </PERSON>, chief operating officer for <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, said the standards `` are not feasible and ... would improve air quality by less than 1 percent compared with the president's proposal.'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Ayres </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION>, called the vote `` a genuine step forward'' and `` a signal to the industrial community and others that achieving clean air will take a commitment from all interests to do their part.'' The coalition includes environmental groups and their allies. The <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> requirements, tougher than the rest of the country's, would be phased in beginning with 1994 models and be complete in the other 49 states by 1996 _ at an average cost to consumers of nearly $ 100 per car, according to <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> estimates. The emissions disputes have helped keep clean air bills in a legislative bottleneck in past years, and threatened to torpedo President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s clean air bill, which the subcommittee vote amended. The compromise followed extensive private negotiations over the past week that involved <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> and a number of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> colleagues who said they were tired of a clean air stalemate that has lasted a decade. The last major clean air law changes were passed in 1977. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration accepted the compromise reluctantly and expressed hope for quick progress on other portions of the bill in <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>'s subcommittee. `` This opens the gates to the passage of clean air legislation _ if not this year then next year,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, who added that the tailpipe compromise would help lawmakers reach agreement on other parts of the legislation. Added Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.M. </LOCATION>, `` We still have an enormous amount of work to do.'' White House deputy press secretary <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> said the Dingell-Waxman provisions, though tighter than what the president proposed, are `` really not too far away from ours.'' He said the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> would `` have to see what comes out'' of the committee before commenting further. <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> said, `` Today's action goes to an extreme which will bring virtually no significant benefits over what the bipartisan bill provides, but will mean huge costs to the consumer and high risks for the industry.'' Following the agreement, lawmakers differing over the makeup of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposed clean fuels program for autos intensified efforts to reach a compromise. Also remaining are differences over sharing the cost of acid rain reduction; a `` cap'' on acid rain growth that could slow power plant expansion; and the extent of controls on virtually unregulated airborne toxic chemicals. The Dingell-Waxman agreement is mainly designed to reduce ozone pollution. Motor vehicles account for nearly half of the nation's pollution from ozone, a highly reactive gas that is the prime ingredient of smog and which can cause breathing difficulties Ozone is produced by the reaction of hydrocarbons from unburned fuel with nitrogen oxides, another vehicle pollutant, in the presence of sunlight. Warm weather speeds the reaction. The key provisions of the compromise: _ Beginning with 1994 models, cars and light duty trucks could emit 0.25 grams per mile of non-methane hydrocarbons for five years or 50,000 miles, whichever comes first; and 0.31 grams per mile after that up to 10 years or 100,000 miles The current federal limit on these emissions is 0.41 grams. _ For carbon monoxide, the limit would be 3.4 grams per mile in the five-year, 50,000-mile period, the same as current law; and 4.2 grams after that up to 10 years or 100,000 mile period _ Beginning with 1994 cars and 1995 light-duty trucks, emissions of nitrogen oxides would be held to 0.4 grams per mile, the current <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> limit The standard would be phased in over two years, 40 percent the first year and 100 percent the second. The current federal limit is 1 gram per mile. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> would have to decide by Dec. 31, 1999, whether to tighten the requirements further. If the administrator did nothing, tough standards originally proposed by <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> would take effect automatically Jan. 1, 2003.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 0212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Prof-Scholarship     10-03 0125</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Prof-Scholarship,0131</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Professor Leaves $1.2 Million for Scholarships</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VALDOSTA, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A professor known for her frugal lifestyle and concern for students has left <ORGANIZATION> Valdosta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> $ 1.2 million for scholarships. College President <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON> said the school received the money recently from the estate of <PERSON> Gertrude </PERSON> <PERSON> Odum </PERSON>, who died Feb. 26, 1988, at age 89. `` She lived in a very small house and lived very frugally,'' said <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON>. `` I think there's no question she desired to save her money and help the students she loved so much.'' Her husband, attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Odum </PERSON>, died several years earlier. A native of <LOCATION> Shenandoah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Odum </PERSON> joined the faculty in 1921, rose to head the English Department and became a professor emeritus in 1965.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 0104EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Fed-InterestRates     10-03 0755</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fed-Interest Rates,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Economists Believe Fed Will Resist Pressure to Cut Interest Rates</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Interest rates are likely to show little change for the rest of this year despite <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration pressure on the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> for lower rates aimed at boosting economic growth, many economists believe. These analysts look for interest rates, including mortgage rates, to move up and down in a narrow range in coming months as the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> tries to steer the $ 5 trillion <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy along a path of moderating growth and moderating inflation. Policymakers at the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> gathered for a closed-door strategy session today of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Open </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Market </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, composed of members of the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> board in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and five of the 12 <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> regional bank presidents. While the results of their deliberations will not be publicly disclosed for six weeks, many economists were predicting that the central bank will decide to make no changes to its current credit stance. These analysts believe that the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> is on the verge of achieving its hoped-for soft landing, whereby growth slows just enough in the second half of the year to keep inflation in check but not enough to topple the country into a recession. `` The country is on a moderate but sustainable growth course. It is exactly the kind of low-altitude flying that the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> has been seeking,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, chief economist of <ORGANIZATION> Aubrey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> G. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lanston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a government securities dealer. Because of the belief that the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> will not fiddle with its monetary controls, analysts were looking for little change in interest rates in coming months. Banks' prime lending rate, which serves as a benchmark for many business and consumer loans, was expected to hold at 10.5 percent. Long-term rates, reflected by <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>'s benchmark 30-year bonds, were expected to trade in a narrow range between 8 percent and 8.5 percent. Mortgage rates, which have been on a roller coaster this year, were expected to stabilize as well, right around the current level of 10.16 percent. Fixed-term mortgages hit a high this year of 11.22 percent in April and fell as low as 9.68 percent in early August before rising slightly in recent weeks. The administration, however, is convinced that further rate declines are needed to improve the economic outlook next year. Both <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Boskin </PERSON>, the president's chief economic adviser, have made comments recently about the need for the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> to lower interest rates. In remarks that were endorsed by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> complained that the central bank was keeping interest rates too high and would have to bear the blame if the country topples into a recession next year. The administration apparently is also unhappy because it believes the central bank should be doing more to support last week's agreement by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and six other economic powers to drive the dollar lower as a way of improving <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s huge trade deficit. Lower interest rates in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would push the dollar down because dollar-denominated assets would be less attractive to foreign investors. A lower dollar makes <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> exports more competitive on overseas markets. `` There is a good deal of domestic political and international heat on the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> to ease policy further in order to push the dollar lower to keep exports strong and the economy strong over the remainder of this year and next year,'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinai </PERSON>, chief economist at the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, agreed, saying, `` This administration wants very much to avoid any slowdown in an election year'' next year when 435 House districts and one-third of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seats are at stake. After a yearlong credit-tightening effort, the central bank eased credit slightly in June and July in the face of mounting signs that the record seven-year economic expansion was in danger of faltering. Since that time, however, much of the data on which the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> based its decision has been revised to show the economy was not that weak in the spring and summer. Many economists believe the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> would actually be tightening credit now if it had not been for various reports showing that inflation, which spurted ahead early in the year because of higher energy and food costs, was moderating as well. <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Latta </PERSON>, an economist with <PERSON> DRI-McGraw </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, said she was not looking for the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> to ease further unless economic growth in the final three months of the year falters much more than is currently expected.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 0116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ForeignAdoptions     10-03 0380</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Foreign Adoptions,390</SECOND>
<HEAD>Americans Adopting More Foreign Babies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Americans are adopting nearly 50 percent more foreign babies than they did a decade ago, a private adoption group says. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Adoption </ORGANIZATION>, said Monday the increase was not surprising, with as many as a million American couples unable to have children of their own and only about 50,000 children available for unrelated domestic adoptions. But these adoption also show the underlying altruism of Americans, <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said, noting that many foreign children were adopted even when more American babies were available. The rise in foreign adoptions accounted for a large percentage of the overall adoption increase in recent years, he said. Americans adopted 10,019 foreign babies in 1987, the most recent year for which Immigration and <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> statistics were available. That was a 46 percent increase over 1977 when there were 6,854 foreign adoptions, <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said. However, <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> complained that there are children within the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> who are n't adopted because of `` a new racism'' by adoption agencies. These agencies often try to find parents who match the child, both of the same race, or the same mix as the baby's natural parents. That can result in willing parents being denied a child because they are of a different race, he said. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s comments came as his committee released its `` Adoption Factbook,'' the second such book it has produced, compiling national facts and figures on adoptions, adoption laws and regulations and listing sources of information and help. Other than the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION>, the federal government no longer collects adoption statistics, said <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, so his group is seeking to fill that gap. The committee describes itself as a private organization that encourages adoption but takes no stand on abortion. The first book covered adoptions through 1982, and the new edition brings the figures up to 1986, except for the foreign babies, which include 1987. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said that 7,614 of the 1987 foreign adoptions were from <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, while only 122 were from <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Females were slightly in the majority at 56 percent. The most common country of origin was <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, he said, and the state where the largest share found new homes was <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 0109EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     10-03 0977</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1018</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FOXBORO, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mick </PERSON> <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> joined some fans in a short jam session in the parking lot of Sullivan Stadium before a sold-out Rolling Stones show. Eighteen fans from <LOCATION> Biddeford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, were sitting around their rented camper playing Stones songs Sunday when a guy in a hooded sweatshirt and sunglasses came by. When the hood and glasses were lifted, <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> emerged. `` Is there a word that carries more of an impact than ` shocked?''' asked <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, 27. `` It was mind-blowing,'' he said. `` <PERSON> Mick </PERSON> made several lifetime dreams happen.'' <PERSON> Linn </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanzman </PERSON>, a publicist for the Stones tour, confirmed that <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> participated in the session. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> and friend <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON> said <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> wandered up to the group as they were singing `` You Ca n't Always Get What You Want.'' `` We started to stop -LRB- singing -RRB-, but he motioned to us to keep going,'' <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON> said. `` I thought, ` If he wants to hear it, fine.''' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> handed the 46-year-old rock star a percussion instrument, and suggested he sing a verse or two. `` Where are we?'' <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> asked. `` The drugstore,'' said <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, referring to a verse in the song. <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> picked up the song, and for the next five minutes <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON> and their friends got to accompany their hero. `` <PERSON> Mick </PERSON>'s voice was great,'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said. `` He did ` You Ca n't Always Get What You Want' during the concert, but he sounded better on our version.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version moved on sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Evert </PERSON>, who said good-bye to Grand Slam tennis after last month's U.S. Open, became the first woman and first tennis player to be nominated for the Farewell to Sport Award. <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Dapper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> also announced Monday that basketball's <PERSON> Kareem </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul-Jabbar </PERSON>, baseball's <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmidt </PERSON> and football's <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Landry </PERSON> were finalists for the award, which honors retirees for a career of `` competitive excellene and community service.'' The awards will be presented Feb. 10. <PERSON> Evert </PERSON>, 34, won 18 events on the Grand Slam tour _ six <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Opens, seven French Opens, three Wimbledons and two Australian Opens _ and a record 157 singles titles. She still plans to play minor tournaments and exhibitions in coming months. <PERSON> Abdul-Jabbar </PERSON>, 42, played a record 20 seasons for the <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bucks </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lakers </ORGANIZATION> and set records for points, Most Valuable Player Awards, games and minutes played and blocked shots. <PERSON> Landry </PERSON>, 65, coached the <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cowboys </ORGANIZATION> their first 29 years, leading them to two Super Bowl victories in five appearances and a record 20-straight winning seasons. He was fired last February. <PERSON> Schmidt </PERSON>, 40, retired in May. The <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Phillies </ORGANIZATION>' third baseman hit 548 home runs, seventh best in baseball history, and won three MVP awards.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>RADNOR, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Culp </PERSON> says he made <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON> an actor, putting his own career in jeopardy to save their mid-1960s `` I Spy'' show and <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON>'s future with it. `` <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> was not much of an actor when I first met him, and he struck me as the angriest man alive,'' <PERSON> Culp </PERSON> said in this week's TV Guide magazine. `` He had this tremendous chip on his shoulder, as if the world owed him a living.'' <PERSON> Culp </PERSON> said <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON>'s performance in the first episode of the television show did n't impress <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> <PERSON> Tinker </PERSON>, then <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> programming chief, and he canceled the show. <PERSON> Culp </PERSON> said he defended <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON> and pressured <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> to give the series another chance. `` I was convinced <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> was going to be right for the part,'' <PERSON> Culp </PERSON> said. `` People only had to be patient. I knew it was risky to go out on such a limb, but I was sure I could make Bill an actor overnight by rewriting the scripts for him. So I told <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON>: ` If <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> gets rid of <PERSON> Bill </PERSON>, they'll have to get rid of me, too.''' Cosby wo n't talk about the matter and Tinker has trouble recalling the events, TV Guide said. But the show's executive producer, <PERSON> Sheldon </PERSON> <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON>, disagreed with <PERSON> Culp </PERSON>'s comments on the early cancellation order, saying <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> had a year's commitment. `` The show could n't be canceled,'' <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> said. But he added, `` There were some doubts about <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON>'s acting _ he had only been a stand-up comic.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>RENO, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former first lady <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said she was not prepared for the intense scrutiny that comes with being the president's wife, but she's looking forward to releasing her version of her White House years. `` You never stop being hurt by the stories, but you do stop being surprised,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. `` I figure after eight years of everybody having their say it was my turn. Eight years is a long time to live under a microscope and have things misinterpreted,'' she said. Her book, `` My Turn,'' will be released soon. Filling in for her husband, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> spoke Monday at the the annual <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grocers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> meeting. The former president is `` doing very well,'' she said, recovering from skull surgery to remove water on his brain that developed after he was thrown from a horse.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Glenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, rehearsing the role of <PERSON> Martha </PERSON> in a revival of `` Who's Afraid of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> Woolf?'' says she was inspired by seeing a theater legend play the role in the early 1960s. Miss <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 53, winner of Oscars for `` Women in Love'' in 1970 and `` A Touch of Class'' in 1973, was a young actress looking for a break when she saw <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Albee </PERSON>'s play open in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> with <PERSON> Uta </PERSON> <PERSON> Hagen </PERSON> as <PERSON> Martha </PERSON> and <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> as <PERSON> George </PERSON>. `` I literally do n't remember breathing throughout the entire evening,'' she said. `` There was an extraordinary power to the play and the performances were nothing short of astonishing. `` When you see performances like that, it truly is inspirational.'' The play opens a 10-week engagement Thursday at the Doolittle Theatre, with <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lithgow </PERSON> as <PERSON> George </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 0120EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     10-03 0575</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Time to Move to Marketplace With Farm Products: Senators</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's time to move from the lab to the marketplace with products such as ink made from soybeans and biodegradable plastics made from corn starch, say two senators whose legislation would speed the process. `` We can make literally thousands of environmentally safe, innovative new products from the renewable resources grown on American farms,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.D. </LOCATION>, who has teamed with Sen. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Iowa </LOCATION>, on the Alternative Agricultural Research and Commercialization Act. The measure combines legislation they had introduced separately. In moving his bill through the last <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON> said he found the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> `` minimally oriented'' toward finding new commercial products for crops. `` Current research being conducted at <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> is too often directed at improving yields of existing crops,'' he said Monday, noting problems with overproduction. `` This bill will change that research emphasis and aid in the development of markets for the new products being created.'' `` We can make ink for soybeans instead of petroleum,'' <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> said. `` We can make red dye that wo n't cause cancer out of sunflower hulls. We can make degradable plastics out of corn starch instead of crude oil. We can make insulation from milkweed instead of fiberglass.'' Coincidentally, the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industrial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crops </ORGANIZATION> is holding a convention this week to exchange ideas on new uses for farm products in <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, the home of the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s research center doing work in this area The problem with <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s program is unreliable funding. Sometimes there's money and sometimes there is n't. The Conrad-Harkin bill would provide $ 10 million in 1990, $ 20 million in 1991, $ 30 million in 1992, $ 50 million in 1993 and $ 75 million for the next six years. Once research and development are completed, the bill provides for technical and financial assistance to businesses to help commercialize the products through regional centers around the country. <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>'s original bill was sponsored by Rep. <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Penny </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Minn </LOCATION>., in the House It passed in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, but did n't get to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor last year. <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON>'s bill passed the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> three times, but did n't get through the House. The new legislation is widely supported and awaiting hearings in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> aides say the plan is to pass it as separate legislation, but keep open the option of attaching it to the 1990 farm bill.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> resumes hearings Wednesday on <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Cason </PERSON>, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s controversial nominee for assistant secretary of agriculture for natural resources and the environment. <PERSON> Cason </PERSON> was questioned for four hours Sept. 27 about decisions he made while a high-ranking official at the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Those decisions have drawn strong criticism from environmentalists. Key among the issues was a report on the effects of logging in national forests on the survival of the spotted owl. <PERSON> Cason </PERSON> denied accusations that he sought to hide a report that said the owl would be greatly endangered by the harvesting of old-growth trees in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION>. If confirmed, <PERSON> Cason </PERSON>'s duties would include overseeing the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. Groups that endorse <PERSON> Cason </PERSON> include the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cattleman </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Timber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Multiple-Use </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION>, a pro-development group that supports private uses of public lands He is opposed by the <ORGANIZATION> Wilderness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 0122EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SovietPsychiatry     10-03 0726</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet Psychiatry,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Experts Oppose Readmitting Soviets to Psychiatric Association</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet efforts to curb psychiatric abuse, including an independent monitoring commission, are not enough to warrant readmitting <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychiatric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> experts say. The Soviets recently acknowledged that political and religious dissidents were incarcerated in psychiatric institutions _ a <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> charge they long denied _ and in an unusual move sent a diplomat to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Monday to testify about their reforms. The Soviet `` All-Union Scientific Society of Psychiatrists ... is doing its utmost to implement and translate into reality the needed reforms in the field of medical care and psychiatric health,'' said <PERSON> Georgi </PERSON> <PERSON> Markosov </PERSON>, a counselor at the Soviet Embassy. `` To prevent the use of psychiatry for non-medical purposes as well as to assure maximum openness in specific cases of misuse of psychiatry, an independent commission has been established, which is composed of eight persons,'' <PERSON> Markosov </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on health and the environment. `` The commission is independent from the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> or any -LRB- Communist -RRB- Party or state organs,'' he said, reading a statement from the Soviet psychiatric society. Before this year, it was rare for Soviet officials to testify before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, but since January, about a half-dozen have done so. Despite the Soviets' effort to present their best case for readmission to the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychiatric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, subcommittee chairman Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, D-Calif., and other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> experts said the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> has not gone far enough The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Delegation to Assess Soviet Psychiatry, which visited the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> this year, reported to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that `` while some victims have been released, forced incarceration under the guise of treatment for insanity remains an institutional problem,'' <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> said. `` Perhaps even worse, the perpetrators of these abuses remain in key leadership positions in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> psychiatry,'' <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> said. Besides formation of the independent commission, <PERSON> Markosov </PERSON> detailed reforms including: _ New regulations that led to dropping 736,000 people from so-called psychiatric registration lists <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> experts said the lists contained 10.2 million names and were used for job screening. _ New rules that bar forcible commitment to a psychiatric institution without the consent of patients or their relatives, unless the patient poses a physical danger `` Psychiatrists who wrongly hospitalize mentally healthy persons may be sentenced to a two-year prison term,'' he said. _ Abolition in the <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> federation, the largest of the 15 Soviet republics, of two laws often used against dissidents _ A ban on the use of sulphazine, a drug made of pulverized sulfur that has been injected into political dissidents, causing extreme pain, fever and disorientation Western experts say it has no medical value. Most of the steps had been publicized previously, but the existence of the commission was not known in the West, said another witness, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Reddaway </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> professor who was a member of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> delegation that visited the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> this year. `` It remains to be seen whether it is indeed vigorous and independent,'' said <PERSON> Reddaway </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychiatric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which supported the work of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> delegation, has voted to oppose readmission of the Soviet group to the world body, which is scheduled to meet in <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>, on Oct. 11-16. The world body condemned Soviet practices in 1977 and the Soviets withdrew in 1983, facing almost certain expulsion. `` It is my sincere hope as well as the hope of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychiatric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> that there will be a time in the near future when we can wholeheartedly welcome the <ORGANIZATION> All-Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychiatrists </ORGANIZATION> and Narcologists of the <ORGANIZATION> USSR </ORGANIZATION> into the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychiatric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>,'' testified <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Mercer </PERSON>, head of international programs for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> organization. `` It is also our concern that, unfortunately, this time has not yet arrived,'' <PERSON> Mercer </PERSON> said. Soviet health officials who in the past sent dissidents to psychiatric institutions remain in senior government posts, said <PERSON> Reddaway </PERSON>, and they could resume their abuses if there is a conservative reaction along the lines of the crackdown in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> this summer. The officials he mentioned were <PERSON> Yevgeny </PERSON> <PERSON> Chazov </PERSON>, the health minister; <PERSON> Nikolai </PERSON> <PERSON> Zharikov </PERSON>, last year appointed the head of the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychiatrists </ORGANIZATION> and Narcologists; <PERSON> Georgy </PERSON> <PERSON> Morozov </PERSON>, who for decades has headed the <ORGANIZATION> Serbsky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> where many political dissidents have been held in psychiatric care, and <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Churkin </PERSON>, chief psychiatrist of the ministry of health.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891003-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-03-89 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SovietHumorists     10-03 0424</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet Humorists,0438</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets: Take Our Humor _ Please</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto AB1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By YVETTE H. BLACKMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SCHENECTADY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
