<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 2359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Steinberg 4thLd-Writethru a0718 03-24 0980</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Steinberg, 4th Ld - Writethru, a0718,1005</SECOND>
<HEAD>Steinberg Sentenced To Maximum</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 9th graf, ``I feel ..., to UPDATE with
Nussbaum reax; SUBS 25th graf, `Steinberg would ..., with 2 grafs to clarify
that Steinberg would get time off only for good behavior, eligible for
parole in 7 years.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY31, NY39, NY42</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SAMUEL MAULL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> was sentenced Friday to the maximum 8 1-3 to 25 years in prison for killing his illegally adopted daughter in a case that riveted national attention on the problems of domestic violence. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, a disbarred attorney, spoke about the charges for the first time just before he was sentenced by state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothwax </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> on his manslaughter conviction for the 1987 death of 6-year-old <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>. <PERSON> Rothwax </PERSON> recommended against parole. `` His extraordinary narcissism and self-involvement, his extreme need to control everyone ... led him to become the instrument of <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>'s death,'' <PERSON> Rothwax </PERSON> said before passing sentence. `` There is nothing in the record to mitigate the extreme callousness and harshness of his conduct.'' <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> denied hitting the girl and said she received `` constant love.'' `` Those children were not locked in a house of horror,'' <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> and the infant boy he also adopted illegally. But Assistant District Attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCusker </PERSON> told the court <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>'s death resulted from <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s `` life of violence, selfishness and self-gratification at the expense of other people.'' `` Mr. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> has shown not one ounce of remorse for killing <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> McCusker </PERSON> said. `` I understand the meaning of remorse,'' said <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, 47, who did not testify at his trial. `` I have remorse about losing my life.'' `` I feel that pain every day,'' <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> told the judge, adding that the loss belongs to all those `` whose life <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> touched -LRB- and received -RRB- the love that she gave.'' <PERSON> Hedda </PERSON> <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>, <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s battered companion, watched the sentencing on television at the <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> office of her attorney, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON>, who quoted her as saying, `` How can he stand there and lie with such a straight face?'' `` He just got up there and lied and she's furious,'' Ms. <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON> said of Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>'s reaction to <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s statements. `` He was weaving together this totally untrue and fantastic rendition of what happened.'' <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> was convicted Jan. 30 of first-degree manslaughter in <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>'s death but was acquitted of the more serious charge of second-degree murder. He had received the child at birth from an unmarried teen-ager and raised her as his own rather than fulfilling his promise to arrange for the baby's adoption. On Nov. 2, 1987, <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> was taken unconscious from the <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION> apartment <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> shared with <PERSON> Hedda </PERSON> <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>. A 16-month-old boy also was found and eventually returned to his natural mother. <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> died three days later; murder charges were filed against <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>. Charges against Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> were dropped when prosecutors said she was `` so physically and mentally incapacitated on the night of the murder that she was not criminally responsible for <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>'s death.'' In testimony against <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> described an 11-year relationship with him that included beatings, brainwashing, food deprivation, bizarre punishments and drug use. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> told the judge <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> received `` constant nurturing, constant caring, constant love'' and desribed their relationship as `` joyous, superb, delightful.'' <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> said he regretted a delay in medical attention that may have contributed to <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>'s death. `` I feel I should have sensed when I came home a need for medical attention,'' he said. `` If there was anything wrong with <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> when I left, I would not have left.'' He denied hitting the child, but said, `` I do n't deny that during the course of administering CPR, OK, I could have caused some'' injury. He dispassionately discussed the technical aspects of <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>'s bruises. `` The testimony established <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> was basically a fine human being,'' defense attorney <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Reich </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> had a `` happy and cheerful nature'' and never hit <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>, <PERSON> Reich </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> smiled, chuckled and fidgeted while his lawyers offered lengthy presentencing motions. Behind them sat <PERSON> Michele </PERSON> <PERSON> Launders </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>'s biological mother, and <PERSON> Grace </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Smiegel </PERSON>, the grandmother of <PERSON> Travis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s other illegally adopted child. Both women cried when the sentence was delivered and Mrs. <PERSON> Smiegel </PERSON> nodded in approval. `` It's a lie,'' Ms. <PERSON> Launders </PERSON> said after <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s declaration of mourning. `` I do n't believe he feels anything. I do n't think he has the capability to feel for anybody but himself.'' Four jurors and an alternate from the trial also attended the sentencing. `` I think he deserved the maximum,'' said juror <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Jared </PERSON>. `` Society should be protected from him,'' said juror <PERSON> Helena </PERSON> <PERSON> Barthell </PERSON>. `` I think he's a very violent person who committed a terrible, heinous crime.'' Under the general practice in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> would serve a maximum of 16 years and eight months _ two-third of the legal maximum _ if he earns time off for good behavior. Technically, <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> will be eligible for parole in seven years because he has served 16 months of the 8 1-3-year minimum term since he has been held without bail from the time of his arrest on Nov. 2, 1987. <PERSON> Reich </PERSON> said a notice of appeal was filed Friday, adding, `` We're very optimistic It is fair to say this was just round one.'' <PERSON> Rothwax </PERSON> received hundreds of letters _ from adoptive parents, childless couples and people abused as children _ urging him to give <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> the maximum term in <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>'s beating death. `` We had recommended that he get the maximum. Few defendants have so richly deserved that recommendation,'' District Attorney <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgenthau </PERSON> said later. `` We hope the case serves as a catalyst to stem child and drug abuse.'' Court sources said the letters came from around the country and as far away as <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. None of the letters recommended leniency for <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, the sources said; some demanded the death penalty, which <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> does not have.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MountainLion     03-24 0278</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mountain Lion,0286</SECOND>
<HEAD>Investigators Seize Mountain Lion in Long Island Apartment</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DEER PARK, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 50-pound mountain lion was seized Thursday in a one-bedroom <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> apartment, where it had spent the last few months `` running around, bouncing off the furniture,'' a state spokesman said. `` It was fully clawed, not an ideal pet for an apartment,'' said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Florence </PERSON>, an officer with the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION>. He said the owner, whose name was not made public but who lived in <LOCATION> Deer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, `` called our wildlife unit last Monday and said he wanted to turn the cat in.'' The owner said he had bought it as a 3-month-old kitten and `` thought it would be a neat thing to have'' but then it apparently outgrew its cuteness, <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION> said. The owner was charged with possession of an endangered species. `` The cat was just being kept in his apartment,'' <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION> said. `` He kept it in a small room. He put it on a leash when we got there.'' `` He had a dog in there and the 50-pound mountain lion in there running around, bouncing off the furniture,'' said <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Drossel </PERSON>, general manager of the <ORGANIZATION> Long </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Game </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Manorville </LOCATION>, where the cougar was taken. `` She's in very good shape, like a big tabby.'' He said the cat, 6 months old and 18 inches high, about a third of its full-grown size, had all its teeth. <PERSON> Drossel </PERSON> said the farm would keep the cat as a favor for the state until the <ORGANIZATION> DEC </ORGANIZATION> decided what to do with it. `` It's not like they could take it to <LOCATION> Bide-A-Wee </LOCATION> and hope some one adopts it,'' <PERSON> Drossel </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0208EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-AIDS-Stats     03-24 0246</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-AIDS-Stats,0266</SECOND>
<HEAD>CDC Statistics On U.S. AIDS Cases</HEAD>
<UNK>Eds: Please note that, in this new monthly version of the CDC's AIDS
statistics, the category for year-to-date cases has been eliminated. The
CDC no longer provides that figure.</UNK>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest monthly statistics on acquired immune deficiency syndrome in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, as reported this week by the national Centers for Disease Control:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Number of Cases</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Total cases reported since June 1981: 88,096. Total deaths: 50,670, or 58 percent of all cases.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Transmission Categories</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Homosexual or bisexual males: 53,317, or 61 percent. Intravenous drug abusers: 17,392, or 20 percent. Homosexual male and drug abusers: 6,225, or 7 percent. Heterosexual cases: 3,804, or 4 percent. Transfusion or blood cases: 2,347, or 3 percent. Hemophilia patients: 929, or 1 percent. Children of parents with AIDS or at risk: 1,126, or 1 percent. Undetermined transmission cause: 2,956, or 3 percent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Age and Race</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Childhood cases -LRB- under age 13 -RRB-: 1,440, or 2 percent. Cases among whites: 50,462, or 57 percent. Cases among blacks: 23,518, or 27 percent. Cases among Hispanics: 13,300, or 15 percent. Cases among Asians or Pacific Islanders: 517, or 1 percent. Cases among American Indians or Alaskan natives: 100, or 0 percent. -LRB- NOTE: These statistics are through Feb. 28 and have been rounded to the nearest whole percent. Cumulative totals are for AIDS cases reported since June 1981, and include 75 cases subsequently found to have occurred prior to that date. -RRB-
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0411EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FlyBaby     03-24 0212</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fly Baby,0218</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Gives Birth While Husband Flies Plane</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CLAY CENTER, Kan. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> did n't have a lot of options when his wife went into labor next to him. He was busy flying a small airplane over northwest <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> when his wife, <PERSON> Sara </PERSON>, gave birth. `` <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> is a calm person,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> said. The Hills were flying the four-seater <ORGANIZATION> Cessna </ORGANIZATION> about 300 miles from their home in <LOCATION> Phillipsburg </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> on Wednesday evening, where they had arranged for the baby's delivery at Memorial Hospital. They were about 40 miles short when Mrs. <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> gave birth to a girl weighing 5 pounds, 8 ounces. `` I talked to our county nurse a couple of weeks ago just in case something like this might happen,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> began making arrangements for an emergency landing at Clay Center when his wife went into labor. `` Nobody could seem to understand what he was saying,'' said <PERSON> Pam </PERSON> <PERSON> Spicer </PERSON>, co-owner of Spicer Aircraft. `` So he finally just said, ` Code Red' and there were ambulances and police cars all over the place.'' The couple's third child, <PERSON> Shiree </PERSON>, was `` the prettiest little girl you ever saw,'' said one ambulance driver. Mother and daughter were taken to <LOCATION> Clay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, where both were reported doing fine.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MinimumWage Bjt   03-24 0584</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Minimum Wage, Bjt,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Minimum Wage Battle Shifts To Senate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House passage of a plan to raise the minimum wage shifts the partisan battle to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, where the leading proponent of an increase is urging President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to refrain from further veto threats while <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> settles on a final bill. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted 248-171 Thursday in favor of legislation that would raise the minimum wage from the current $ 3.35 an hour to $ 4.55 by October 1991, with the first increase taking effect later this year. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> then joined the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on an Easter recess that ends April 3. High on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> agenda when it returns is a bill sponsored by Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., that would raise the minimum wage to $ 4.65 by 1992 <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> has said he is open to amending his bill, and in a statement issued after the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote he asked <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who has threatened to veto any attempt to raise the hourly minimum above $ 4.25, to keep an open mind until the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> agree on a bill. `` This is an excellent opportunity for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the administration to demonstrate that they can work together and in doing so achieve a fair increase in the minimum wage and an honest training wage,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has insisted that a six-month sub-minimum training wage covering all newly hired employees be created in any legislation to raise the minimum wage, a provision he said will help offset potential job losses caused by raising the minimum. Sponsors of the House bill, while disputing <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> projections of massive job losses, added a provision allowing a sub-minimum wage to be paid to new hires for two months provided it was their first job. That falls far short of the White House demand and, with <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> also opposed to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s training-wage proposal, that issue likely will be a major sticking point in any attempts to reach a compromise. Several Republicans insisted that Democrats were going to have to give in to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ who appears to have the votes to sustain a veto _ or let a ninth year pass without any change in the minimum wage. `` The question is do you want a bill or do you want a political issue?'' Rep. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Gunderson </PERSON>, R-Wis., said during an unsuccessful <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> effort to substitute <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposal for the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leadership's `` If you truly want to raise the minimum wage this is the only game in town.'' But Democrats argued they had given enough by cutting the final increase from $ 4.65 an hour to $ 4.55 and by adding the new-hire wage. As amended, the House bill would boost the minimum wage to $ 3.85 an hour on Oct. 1, to $ 4.25 on Oct. 1, 1990, and to $ 4.55 a year later. The provision for the new-hire wage, to be pegged at 85 percent of the minimum wage, would expire Sept. 30, 1992. It also would expand exemptions allowing small businesses to pay wages lower than the minimum wage and would allow employers of workers who earn tips to pay them 50 percent of the minimum wage, down from the current 60 percent. Current law exempts service businesses with annual sales of less than $ 362,000 from the minimum-wage law; the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> bill increased that level to $ 500,000. The provision is rarely used, however, because of confusing regulations lawmakers say will be simplified in conference committee if the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> passes a minimum-wage bill.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0413EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Fruit-Cyanide Bjt   03-24 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fruit-Cyanide, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chilean Grapes Returning _ at Higher Prices</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fresh Chilean grapes are being trucked across the country today after a two-week absence from store shelves because of a cyanide poisoning scare, industry leaders say. Consumers may see slightly higher prices on the produce initially, but prices are expected to drop back to pre-scare levels in a couple of weeks when supply catches up with demand, they said. Losses to Chilean exporters and to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> fruit importers as a result of the cyanide scare over grapes and other produce are estimated at $ 240 million, <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bown </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Chilean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exporters </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday. Some of those losses may be offset by a plan being developed by the Chilean government to compensate <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> importers, wholesalers and retailers as well as Chilean growers and exporters, <PERSON> Bown </PERSON> said. Officials at the Chilean embassy in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> did not return telephone calls for comment on the plan Thursday. An estimated $ 50 million to $ 75 million worth of Chilean fruit is being destroyed under the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>'s advisory that was issued after the agency on March 12 found traces of cyanide in two grapes from <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> Earlier in the month an anonymous caller to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassy in the Chilean capital of <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION> had threatened to inject cyanide in export fruit. Some 2 million to 3 million crates of the fruit _ grapes, berries, pears, nectarines, peaches, melon and apples _ had been removed from store shelves or was being held in warehouses until the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> concluded last week that it would have to be destroyed because it could not be readily inspected. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> then announced a plan for stepped-up inspections of Chilean fruit at the docks and on ships to clear the way for the Chilean exports to get back into the stores with safety assurances. <PERSON> Bown </PERSON> said the Chilean fruit industry is anticipating a `` sustained level of consumer demand'' in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and is doing all it can to ensure that fruit coming from <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> will be `` fresh, nutritious, of premium quality and available at a reasonable price.'' The reason, he said, is simple: `` The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> is by far our biggest and best customer _ and we want to keep it that way.'' Exporters are concentrating their efforts on returning table grapes to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> markets, since they constitute 70 percent of Chilean fruit exports. Pears and nectarines will follow, and should be on some store shelves by the weekend, <PERSON> Bown </PERSON> said. There was no estimate when other fruits may begin appearing. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> has been holding up distribution until laboratory tests can give inspectors a better idea how to see evidence of cyanide tampering. Prices initially may be `` slightly higher'' than they had been before the scare began because of pent-up demand, said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carstens </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Produce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which represents 65 companies that import Chilean fruit. `` When you return fruit to the pipeline, the initial demand will be very, very strong and ... the initial impact of the first few days might be perhaps slightly higher in terms of our prices to the retailers,'' he said. Speaking for retailers, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Tryon </PERSON>, director of produce for 3,200 Super Valu stores and president-elect of the <ORGANIZATION> Produce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marketing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said: `` We wo n't see dramatic increases in costs.'' Neither Bown nor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Holzworth </PERSON>, general counsel for the <ORGANIZATION> Chilean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exporters </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, would discuss details of the Chilean government's plan for compensation. <PERSON> Holzworth </PERSON> said the Chileans are negotiating with the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> on a line of credit so that <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> can `` set up a financial structure that will allow importers working with their buyers to get the fruit -LRB- that must be destroyed -RRB- out of the pipeline'' and get new shipments of fresh fruit back in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> stores.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0212EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DroughtRelief     03-24 0464</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought Relief,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lawmakers Say USDA Ignoring Current Drought Conditions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Farm state lawmakers say the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> is mishandling last year's emergency drought relief and ignoring this year's arid, potentially disastrous conditions on the High Plains. Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarpalius </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Democrat and member of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on wheat, soybeans and feed grains, said the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Panhandle </LOCATION> is extremely dry, yet he ca n't find out `` from anybody'' what `` we can do to help our farmers.'' At a hearing Thursday, an angry Rep. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Kan </LOCATION>., said the central part of the country is `` blowing away ... and I ca n't get any damn answers,'' because of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's slow pace in filling key policy jobs at `` People are crawling out of train wrecks faster ... than they're getting people on board,'' <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> said during a subcommittee hearing on <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s handling of the $ 3.9 billion drought bill <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Hertz </PERSON>, administrator of <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stabilization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, countered that farmers receiving drought benefits do not face an undue paperwork burden. He also said he does n't believe the agency has suffered during the transition to the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration. As of Feb. 28, more than 558,000 producers have received disaster payments and emergency feed assistance amounting to more than $ 2.7 billion, <ORGANIZATION> Hertz </ORGANIZATION> testified. The amount paid to date represents 70 percent of what the agency anticipates will go to farmers stricken by the devastating drought of 1988, he said. <ORGANIZATION> Hertz </ORGANIZATION> said he was not aware of efforts at <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> to draft 1989 drought relief, although subcommittee chairman Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON>, D-Kan., said it's `` no secret the central part of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is blowing away right now. <PERSON> Sarpalius </PERSON> said he supports another drought-relief bill this year, because <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Panhandle </LOCATION> wheat crops are `` burned up'' and decimated by insects. Livestock also has suffered. <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Kika </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> la </PERSON> <PERSON> Garza </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, said drought conditions extend from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. `` The dust is blowing. ... The seed wo n't germinate,'' said de la <PERSON> Garza </PERSON>, asking <ORGANIZATION> Hertz </ORGANIZATION> to determine whether farmers must plant seed when they know it wo n't germinate in order to collect disaster relief. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivinius </PERSON>, an Elgin, <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION>, wheat producer and secretary-treasurer of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wheat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Growers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> needs to consider extending drought disaster assistance. <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chandler </PERSON> <PERSON> Keys </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, director of congressional relations for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cattlemen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> had `` problems, misunderstandings, foul-ups, and general disregard for the intent of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>'' when promulgating regulations for emergency livestock feeding programs under the drought bill. `` For all the good intentions in the drought bill, it may be for naught with many livestock producers because of the lack of good follow-through and good faith on the part of the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Keys </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Resegregation     03-24 0658</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Resegregation,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Integration Gains in Danger, Report Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Southern schools are the nation's most integrated as a result of court orders and federal compliance plans dating from two decades ago, but a new report says clear signs of erosion are threatening their achievements. <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> `` show major increases in segregation and have joined the list of the nation's most segregated states for black students,'' said the study released Thursday by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Other Southern and border states, including <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, are experiencing gradual declines that may reflect a failure by many fast-growing districts to update their desegregation plans, the report says. The report, based on federal statistics, cited encouraging trends in black-white integration through mandatory city-suburban busing plans in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> and elsewhere. But the picture was uniformly grim for Hispanics. `` Hispanic students are becoming more highly segregated in virtually every part of the country and among each major subgroup,'' the report said. Hispanic students are increasingly isolated in center cities with declining white enrollments, it said, and have been largely ignored by the government agencies and civil rights groups that brought about the desegregation of black schools. `` The march to school integration is certainly not over, and school systems are finding no quick and easy solutions,'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Oglesby </PERSON>, president-elect of the association, said in issuing the study of desegregation trends from 1968 to 1986. At the national level, the study found that school desegregation remained relatively stable in the 1980s `` in spite of the harsh attacks by the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and the widespread impression that the policy was being abandoned.'' Nevertheless, the study said, the federal government should `` end its attacks on school desegregation and its efforts to dismantle plans that are stable.'' Other positive steps would be to resume research on effective desegregation techniques and offer assistance to districts trying to desegregate, it said. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Orfield </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> professor and co-author of the study, suggested that the nation make a concerted effort to achieve residential integration which would automatically result in integrated local schools. He also said rapidly developing areas should update their desegregation plans. The report uses federal statistics to rate regions, states and cities on their desegregation efforts. <PERSON> Orfield </PERSON> said it is not meant as a commentary on the quality of education in particular communities, but noted there is `` a very strong relationship'' between high minority student populations, low test scores and high dropout rates. The study said Hispanic segregation has always been worst among Puerto Ricans in the <LOCATION> Northeast </LOCATION> but statistics show alarming trends elsewhere. The percentage of Hispanic enrollment in 90-percent-to-100 percent minority schools rose from 6.8 percent in 1968 to 23.5 percent in 1986 in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>, and from 11.7 percent to 24.7 percent in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. The growing proportion of Hispanic students and the lack of major desegregation litigation `` suggest a future of continuingly increasing segregation,'' the report said. For blacks, the most segregated states are <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> while integration is at its highest levels in the South. `` We made the largest effort in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> and it had the largest impact, but we're beginning to see in the 1980s a slow resegregation of the South,'' <PERSON> Orfield </PERSON> said. The most striking example of the trend is in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, the report said. The percent of the state's black students attending schools with white majorities fell by 8 percent in the 1980s; the proportion of students in highly segregated schools rose by 9.3 percent in the 1980s; and the percent of white enrollment in a typical black student's school fell almost to the level of 1970, `` before the implementation of the large urban busing orders.'' In contrast to the black and Hispanic experiences, the study says Asian students are not segregated. The average Asian student attends a school with a majority of whites, 20 percent Asians and 25 percent blacks and Hispanics.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0215EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     03-24 0886</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Winter Winds Skim Tons of Soil from Great Plains</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fierce winds have eroded nearly 4.7 million acres of land in the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> this winter, one of the most extensive losses on record, according to an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> survey. `` Much of this damage is due to the drought,'' Wilson Scaling, chief of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Soil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday. `` We went into the wind erosion season with poor cover in much of the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> because of the drought. Then this winter, we've had a combination of no snow cover and high-velocity winds in many areas.'' Scaling said 88 percent of the acreage damaged was cropland, with rangeland accounting for most of the remainder. The <ORGANIZATION> SCS </ORGANIZATION> surveys <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> damage annually from Nov. 1 through the following May 31, a seven-month period when winds are highest and soils are driest. The damage to 4.7 million acres was through February. Scaling said the northern plains were hard hit, with <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> showing damage to nearly 1.4 million acres, about 30 percent of the 10-state total. Losses in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> have been greater than at any time since <ORGANIZATION> SCS </ORGANIZATION> began the regular surveys in 1955. Agency records go back to the mid-1930s, but figures for some of those years were obtained from other sources. The worst damage was done to about 16 million acres in 1954-55, although the old Dust Bowl probably exceeded that in the early 1930s before annual figures were compiled. But the 1987-88 season was bad, too, with more than 13 million acres damaged in the region. Another was in 1980-81 when the agency reported 12.5 million acres. Land is considered wind-damaged when the effects of wind are apparent to the eye. By that time, according to conservationists, the erosion rate has reached about 15 tons per acre a year, usually at least three times faster than is `` tolerable,'' or naturally replaceable. A loss of five tons per acre translates into a layer of soil about the thickness of a dime spread over one acre. Scaling said farmers used emergency tillage on more than a million acres to help reduce the blowing by roughing the surface exposed to wind. <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> accounted for 80 percent of the emergency tillage, about 880,000 acres. In addition to the land damaged during the four-month period, Scaling said more than 22.5 million acres were `` in condition to blow'' as of March 1, the most in 32 years. Highest on the list are <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, he said. According to the survey, which was made in 541 counties of the region's 10 states, here is the state-by-state breakdown comparing damaged acres in November, December, January and February with the same four months of 1987-88:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Northern Plains</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 _ <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, 1,393,625 acres this season and 793,181 in 1987-88 _ <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, 81,180 and 68,485 _ <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, 474,200 and 813,680 _ <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, 407,980 and 360,520 _ <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, 474,863 and 223,966
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Southern Plains</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, 154,550 and 119,400. <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, 520,905 and 82,600. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, 54,600 and 11,150. <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, 85,565 and 48,708. <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, 1,047,791 and 893,865.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new 55-page handbook has been designed by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to help farmers, shippers and local communities cope with the loss of railroad service. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> `` Buzz'' <PERSON> Fitzpatrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, head of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday the handbook contains information on rural rail assistance from a number of sources and summarizes regulations as these apply to rail abandonments. `` Many of the light-density branch lines being cast off are located in agricultural regions,'' he said. `` Without rail transportation, the marketing options of local producers are limited.'' The topics include abandonments, alternatives to abandonment, and guidelines for evaluating the possibility of small railroad operations. Information is included for potential buyers who have little or no railroad experience. <PERSON> Fitzpatrick </PERSON> said many, if not all, of the major railroad companies have programs or plans for assisting in line sales. And many of those have worked with rural communities and shippers to explore ways of retaining rail service. This information is also in the handbook, he said. Copies of the booklet are being sent to federal, state and local organizations involved in rural railroad service assistance, he said. A limited supply is available free of charge for general distribution. For more information, contact: <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Batson </PERSON>, USDA-OT, P.O. Box 96575, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, 20090-6575. Or call 202?653-6108.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says egg production is down about 6 percent from a year ago, mostly reflecting a sharp cutback by producers because of low prices last year. Total production during the first three months of the marketing year that began Dec. 1 was estimated at 16.7 billion eggs, down from 17.7 billion a year earlier, the department said Thursday in a report. As of March 1, laying hens totaled 271 million, down from 282 million a year ago. The March 1 flock included about 232 million hens producing eggs for consumer use, and 38.9 million producers of hatching-type eggs. The department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> says 1989 egg production is expected to be down around 2 percent from last year because of the reduction in laying hens. Producers cut back flocks in response to the lowest net returns since <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> began estimating those figures in 1972, the agency said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0414EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NewLook     03-24 0633</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-New Look,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Soviet Ambassador Exudes Glasnost</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Over spicy Thai shrimp and piquant vegetables in a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> restaurant jam-packed with reporters, Soviet Ambassador <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dubinin </PERSON> exuded glasnost and good cheer. Superpower relations are on the upswing, and <PERSON> Dubinin </PERSON> was all smiles _ except on <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s plan to extend the range of short-range nuclear missiles. `` It's unacceptable, at any rate not for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> but for the process we are talking about,'' <PERSON> Dubinin </PERSON> said. `` It's just something which is going against the mainstream of peaceable development of the world. It's something which goes against the process of disarmament.'' His tone of voice serious, <PERSON> Dubinin </PERSON> added: `` There's absolutely no need to do it, because we have begun in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> a historic process of reducing forces, unilaterally by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and multilaterally in negotiations.'' In any event, <PERSON> Dubinin </PERSON> said, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> will not modernize its own battlefield nuclear weapons. `` We are strongly in favor of beginning negotiations to eliminate this class of weapons, too,'' he said. Indeed, Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is on a disarmament offensive, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and its allies are caught up in the process. A treaty in 1987 banned all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet intermediate-range nuclear missiles. Negotiations have begun in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> between <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact to reduce tanks, antiaircraft artillery and possibly other conventional armor in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. And <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is unilaterally cutting Soviet defense spending, withdrawing six tank divisions from <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, and has announced a projected reduction of 500,000 troops overall. <PERSON> Dubinin </PERSON> fielded questions with ease after reading a prepared, boilerplate speech. English is his fourth or fifth language, but <PERSON> Dubinin </PERSON> needed only occasional help from an interpreter. And when he was done, he gave an interview in <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> to a journalist from <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> for good measure. Soviet news conferences, here and in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, have become a frequent occurrence. A few weeks ago, <PERSON> Dubinin </PERSON> called in American reporters at the Soviet embassy and answered their questions for nearly two hours. At the session Thursday at the <LOCATION> Thai </LOCATION> restaurant, <PERSON> Dubinin </PERSON> said the Soviets would be willing to reduce their military aid to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> _ a bone in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> throat _ as part of a peaceful settlement in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. He said Jews were free to leave the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, or to return, if they wished, and even leave again. Perhaps, he suggested with a smile, they were coming and going `` for the love of travel.'' <PERSON> Dubinin </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> accepts as a `` reality'' the growing union in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and said his government wants to develop `` a normal relationship'' with the 12-country community. And he declined to criticize the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration for delaying a resumption of negotiations to reduce long-range nuclear missiles. `` The delay is a delay,'' he said. `` It's absolutely clear. But we understand the new administration needs some time to get things together. It's understandable.'' The <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> plan to make <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Lance missiles more powerful also is running into obstacles within the Western alliance. West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, with support from some other allied leaders, is seeking a delay. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is determined to go ahead, but still has to convince <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, whose chance for re-election next year may hinge on the missile issue in a country where disarmament forces are strong. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, is unlikely to fund the modernization with <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> on the fence. Soviet criticism of the <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> plan could deepen the division within the alliance. Whatever the outcome, <PERSON> Dubinin </PERSON> said the Soviets would not modernize their own battlefield nuclear weapons. The ambassador spoke with the confidence of a government that seems to believe momentum is on its side.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schweid </PERSON> has covered U.S.-Soviet diplomacy for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1973.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Quayle-SDI     03-24 0372</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle-SDI,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayle Endorses `Brilliant Pebbles' Defense Missile Technology</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has become the administration advocate for the strategic defense concept known as `` brilliant pebbles,'' a method of seeding outer space with satellites that track and destroy missiles. In a speech Thursday to the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> stressed the relatively small size, comparative low cost and fast schedule for development of the satellites. Cost, complexity and pace of development are among the issues raised by critics of the Star Wars program. `` In short, if tests of the brilliant pebbles concept show the promise that is expected, it could revolutionize much of our thinking about strategic defense,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said in his speech. The brilliant pebbles technology relies on thousands of small satellites that would float freely in space, tracking incoming missiles and destroying them by colliding with them. The system, based on research under way at the <ORGANIZATION> Lawrence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Livermore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION>, has been touted by the retired director of the <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wars </ORGANIZATION> program, Lt. Gen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrahamson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, however is the first high ranking administration official to speak out on brilliant pebbles. Others have declined to say whether the concept might re-focus <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> research on the strategic defense initiative. <PERSON> Abrahamson </PERSON> urged the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> in February to embrace the technology, saying it offered better performance and dramatic cost reduction over other techniques. Brilliant pebbles could be used in an opening phase of the Star Wars system at a cost of not more than $ 25 billion, according to <PERSON> Abrahamson </PERSON>. One administration official, speaking on condition of anonymity, on Thursday said that while no decisions have been made on whether to go with brilliant pebbles, it `` certainly is a very attractive prospect and one that is being looked at closely.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> also said that despite the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s internal changes under President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, `` I know of nothing that has occurred since 1983 that should change our thinking about strategic defense.'' The Pentagon has estimated that a first-phase Star Wars system using both ground-based and space-based weapons and sensors would cost about $ 69 billion. Critics say the system probably would be far more expensive and would n't work anyway.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DyingBrothers     03-24 0572</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dying Brothers,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brothers with Terminal Disease See Bush, Tour Capitol</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Showing <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerstler </PERSON> pictures of his five children, Rep. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Armey </PERSON> explained how each has a different personality. One son, <PERSON> Armey </PERSON> said, is a worrier. `` Does he worry about dying?'' asked one of the Gerstler brothers in a quiet, small voice. <PERSON> Armey </PERSON> deftly changed the subject, and to the amazement of the brothers from DeSoto, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, presented them with a flag that had flown over the Capitol a day earlier. `` Is it ours?'' asked <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON>, 10. `` Where'd you get it?'' asked <PERSON> Nick </PERSON>, 9. `` Do we get to keep it?'' And so began, <PERSON> Armey </PERSON> promised, a great adventure for two children with <PERSON> Duchenne </PERSON>'s muscular dystrophy, a rare form of the disease that usually takes the life of its victims by the age of 15. With their parents, <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Penny </PERSON>, pushing their wheelchairs, <PERSON> Armey </PERSON> in the lead, and <PERSON> Nick </PERSON>'s twin sister, <PERSON> Angelee </PERSON> scampering ahead of everyone, the little convoy set out to explore the Capitol in the dim light of evening, when the click of heels on the tiled floors resonates through the empty corridors. The brothers rubbed the feet of <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>' statue for good luck, saw where machine gun bullets grazed across a table in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> chamber three decades ago, and blood stains that had seeped into a marble staircase during a shootout involving a <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> congressman and newspaper reporter in the early days of 1890. While on the floor of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> chamber, <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> asked <PERSON> Armey </PERSON> if the lawmakers leave a lot of trash littered about at the end of the day. `` They talk a lot of trash,'' said <PERSON> Armey </PERSON>, a Republican from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. `` But they do n't mess the place up.'' `` You ca n't call anybody a bad name,'' <PERSON> Armey </PERSON> said, explaining how congressmen ask each other `` Will the gentleman yield?'' when they want to talk. `` We do n't say shut up,'' said <PERSON> Armey </PERSON>, whose office arranged for special tours for the boys during their week in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, including visits to the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and a visit Thursday with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the Oval Office. The boys said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> showed them pictures of his new puppies, and each child received an autographed picture of the president. <PERSON> Angelee </PERSON> was given a stick pin with the presidential crest. The boys got tie clips. They gave the president a picture taken from above, of children in one of their schools lined up to spell `` Drug Free,'' and stories from <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> and <PERSON> Angelee </PERSON>'s fellow third graders. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> asked them about their tour of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, sponsored by the non-profit `` A Wish for Wings'' in <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, which helps children with life-threatening illness live out a wish that would otherwise have been financially impossible. `` Meeting the president was an extra bonus,'' said the boys' mother as the family shivered outside the White House in chilly weather and no coats `` We were really thrilled,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Gerstler </PERSON> said the family had expected warmer weather, and the jackets they had brought were n't dressy enough for the White House. She said the trip to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> was the boys' first choice for their Wish with <ORGANIZATION> Wings </ORGANIZATION>, ahead of <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> and all the Nintendo games ever made. The boys are A students with a big interest in social studies, she said.. `` I like the building,'' <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> said of the Capitol `` It's big. I like the statues, all of the detail.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0416EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     03-24 0856</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0894</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOCA RATON, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former first lady <PERSON> Rosalynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> says her daughter's political activism came as a surprise. Mrs. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> told a <ORGANIZATION> Nova </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> luncheon that the country met <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> as a shy pre-teen and watched her grow into a college activist protesting apartheid and the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>. `` Actually, <PERSON> Amy </PERSON>'s activism surprised us, because she's basically a very shy person,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said Wednesday. `` We do n't always agree with her, but we're proud of her. She's only been arrested four times.'' <PERSON> Amy </PERSON>, 21, is studying art at a <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> design school.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>GALLATIN, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> is considering a request to remove <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandrell </PERSON> <PERSON> Boulevard </PERSON> signs from a two-mile section of highway because the country music star has moved 15 miles away. <PERSON> Jeannie </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Gallatin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, said she believes the two large signs should be removed `` if the posts can be used to advertise civic groups or for some other fashion.'' The signs, costing a total of $ 10,000, were erected in 1983 along the stretch of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> 31E about five miles from <PERSON> Mandrell </PERSON>'s former palatial home on <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hickory </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>. The singer moved to <LOCATION> Joelton </LOCATION> last year. `` There are no hard feelings because she left,'' <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> said. City council members studied the matter Tuesday night, and will discuss it again April 4. <PERSON> Jeannie </PERSON> <PERSON> Ghent </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the performer, said there will be no ill feelings if the signs come down. `` We were so honored when they made that stretch of road, but with her moving out, we do n't blame <LOCATION> Gallatin </LOCATION> at all,'' she said. `` We were honored by the time we had it.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MIDLAND, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Filming has begun for a depiction of the rescue of toddler <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> McClure </PERSON>, who was pulled from an an abandoned well 58 hours after tumbling in. But little of her west <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> city will be seen in the production that <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> will broadcast May 21. The filming of `` Everybody's Baby: The Rescue of <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> McClure </PERSON>'' began Thursday in the back yard of a suburban <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> home, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Interscope </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Productions </ORGANIZATION> said. The hospital and city hall are the only sites in <LOCATION> Midland </LOCATION> being used. The shaft will be recreated in a <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> film studio. The cast includes <PERSON> Patty </PERSON> <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> as a victim's assistance volunteer; <ORGANIZATION> Beau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bridges </ORGANIZATION> as <ORGANIZATION> Midland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Czech </PERSON>; <PERSON> Roxana </PERSON> <PERSON> Zal </PERSON> as <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON>'s mother, <PERSON> Cissy </PERSON>; and <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Oldham </PERSON> as <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON>'s father, Chip. Toddler twins <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jennie </PERSON> <PERSON> Loesch </PERSON> will take turns portraying <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON>. The 1987 rescue of <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON>, trapped for 2 -LCB- days in a 22-foot-deep water well when she was 18 months old, brought worldwide attention to <LOCATION> Midland </LOCATION> as it was broadcast on national and international television.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SANTA MARIA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Globe-circling aviator <PERSON> Jeana </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeager </PERSON> is planning an educational fund-raising flight that will stop in all 50 states and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s 10 provinces. <PERSON> Yeager </PERSON>, who in 1986 helped fly the experimental aircraft Voyager non-stop around the world, told reporters at <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Maria </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> on Thursday that she and pilot <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Mersky </PERSON> will be flying to benefit the <ORGANIZATION> Youth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Experimental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Funds will be used to aid the aviation education in both countries. The flight will begin in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> in July and end in <LOCATION> Oshkosh </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, in August.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>YAKIMA, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress Meryl Streep has neither accepted nor rejected an invitation from apple processor <ORGANIZATION> Tree </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Top </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> to view Alar testing, her agent's office said. Tree Top, the nation's largest apple juice maker, issued its invitation Tuesday. It wants Ms. <PERSON> Streep </PERSON> to visit its headquarters and view how it tests to make sure Alar is not present in its products. `` I have no idea if she is aware of the invitation,'' <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, who works for agent <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohn </PERSON> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, said during a telephone interview Thursday. She said Ms. <PERSON> Streep </PERSON> will be out of the country until Tuesday, plans to attend the Academy Awards on Wednesday, and will leave the country again the next day. Tree Top, based in the <LOCATION> Yakima </LOCATION> suburb of <PERSON> Selah </PERSON>, contends that the nationwide Alar controversy _ with Ms. <PERSON> Streep </PERSON> as a vocal opponent of the suspected carcinogenic farm chemical _ has been a `` blanket indictment'' of the entire apple industry. Tree Top for years has rejected Alar-treated apples for its own products, but contends that the nationwide scare is hurting its sales.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>GRAND RAPIDS, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Convicted Watergate figure <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Colson </PERSON> says prison ministries like the one he started 13 years ago are the only way to fight crime. About 30,000 inmates at 550 state and federal prisons have been through <PERSON> Colson </PERSON>'s Prison Fellowship seminars, he said Thursday. During the next three years, 60,000 more inmates will go through them, he said. The program, which is in prisons in 34 countries, has about 22,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> volunteers, some of whom are reformed criminals. `` The secular world has to take notice,'' said the 57-year-old <PERSON> Colson </PERSON>, who addressed about 250 prison chaplains and church pastors from across <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Calvary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. `` This is the only way we're going to deal with crime.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0733EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Oscar-Auction     03-24 0750</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Oscar-Auction,0768</SECOND>
<HEAD>As Commercialism Creeps In, Academy Fights To Save Oscar Integrity</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HORN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Free enterprise has collided with the Academy Awards, and everybody's trying to pick up the pieces. With Oscar statuettes selling at auction for more than $ 10,000 and a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> trophy company casting alleged Academy Award clones, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> is scrambling to make sure <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON>'s golden sheen is n't tarnished by <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> hucksterism. `` If you know about an infringement and fail to object to it, you risk having your trademark become public domain,'' said <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, the Academy's executive administrator, in explaining the lawsuits the organization has filed to protect its beloved hunk of electroplated pewter. But despite the Academy's crusade against crass commercialism, this year's awards ceremony will feature a new merchandising wrinkle: Some 800 limousines delivering the most famous stars to the Oscar telecast will be equipped with door-mounted coolers jammed with <ORGANIZATION> Diet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coke </ORGANIZATION>, Coca-Cola Classic and other <ORGANIZATION> Coca-Cola </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> beverages. When the limo doors swing open in front of the Shrine Auditorium and the celebrities tumble out, the <ORGANIZATION> Coke </ORGANIZATION> logo will be on display in front of an audience that includes millions around the world. `` It seemed like a good marketing opportunity,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Coca-Cola </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ira </PERSON> <PERSON> Gleser </PERSON>. `` The Academy approached our local bottler in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and said we're going to have a lot of thirsty people.'' But even as the Academy embraces this new intrusion of merchandising, it has lashed out at whatever else it considers a blemishing of the Oscar name. When <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, the distributor of `` Rain Man,'' published newspaper advertisements touting the film's Oscar nominations before the nominations were even announced, the Academy issued a harsh statement condemning <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>'s promotional gamble. After the ads appeared, `` Rain Man'' collected nine nominations. `` We regard this as a serious matter, and we have communicated our concern,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON>, president of the Academy. For nearly 50 years, the Academy has maintained strict security around both the nominations and the award winners. It also has envisoned the statuette itself as something of an icon. So auctioning the Oscar has greatly distressed the Academy. The Collector's Book Store, local sponsors of monthly entertainment memorabilia auctions, has sold off seven Oscars in the past year, including the best picture trophy for 1951's `` An <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>'' -LRB- $ 15,760 -RRB-, <PERSON> Marlon </PERSON> <PERSON> Brando </PERSON>'s best actor prize for 1954's `` On the Waterfront'' -LRB- $ 13,000 -RRB- and the black and white interior decoration Oscar for 1941's `` How Green Was My Valley'' -LRB- $ 17,715 -RRB-. None were sold by the original recipients; heirs or friends who had later received the trophies put them on the block. When <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Willits </PERSON>, the book store's owner, announced that he would hold a February auction for the 1957 best-picture trophy for `` Around the World in 80 Days,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> said enough, initiating a court action that, for now, has blocked any future trophy sales. The Academy insists that a contract signed by <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> winners mandates that they will not sell the trophies without first offering them to the Academy for a nominal fee. `` But now that the word is out that these awards are worth $ 10,000 to $ 50,000, people are reluctant to sell them back to the Academy for $ 10,'' <PERSON> Willits </PERSON> said. `` The Academy has created something of great value here. This is the most famous award in the world _ the most instantly recognizable award. The Nobel Prize might be a greater honor, but people know more about what an Academy Award looks like. `` And they're very limited, too. There's not too many of them around. ... Twenty years ago, you would n't have a movie poster in your living room unless you were a college student. Now, you can go into <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> homes and there's a movie poster, and the darn thing's worth $ 10,000 or $ 20,000 dollars.'' When the Academy won a court order temporarily blocking future auctions, <PERSON> Willits </PERSON> decided to sell his store. `` It seemed to be the final straw. I do n't like lawsuits,'' he said. `` I'm getting older and I'd like to write movie scripts.'' Yet the <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> has lost its most recent attempt to save its trophy's integrity: A copyright infringement suit brought against the <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Festival </ORGANIZATION> was dismissed March 16 in a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> federal court. The Academy had claimed the Lone Star Statuette, designed and built by <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s Creative House Promotions, was `` practically identical'' to the Oscar. The court found otherwise.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0736EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-HouseMinimumWageRollCall 3Takes   03-24 0485</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-House Minimum Wage Roll Call, 3 Takes,</SECOND>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the 248-171 roll call Thursday by which the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted to increase the minimum wage to $ 4.55 an hour by October 1991. A `` yes'' vote is a vote to approve the bill. Voting yes were 226 Democrats and 22 Republicans. Voting no were 24 Democrats and 147 Republicans. Y is a yes vote. N is a no vote. X denotes those not voting. Present denotes those who voted they were `` present'' at the time of the vote but did not vote `` yes'' or `` no'' on the issue. There are three vacancies in the 435-member House.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ALABAMA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bevill </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Erdreich </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Flippo </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Callahan </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ALASKA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican _ Young, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ARIZONA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>, <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republicans </PERSON> _ <PERSON> Kolbe </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Kyl </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON>, N; Stump, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ARKANSAS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Y. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Hammerschmidt </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>CALIFORNIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Anderson, Y; <PERSON> Bates </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Beilenson </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Berman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Bosco </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Boxer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dellums </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dymally </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Fazio </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Lehman </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Levine </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Matsui </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Mineta </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Pelosi </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Roybal </PERSON>, Y; Stark, Y; <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, X. Republicans _ <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> N </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION>, N; <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Dornan </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Dreier </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Gallegly </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Herger </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Lagomarsino </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> McCandless </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Moorhead </PERSON>, N; Packard, N; <PERSON> Pashayan </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Rohrabacher </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Shumway </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>COLORADO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION>, N; <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hefley </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>CONNECTICUT</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Gejdenson, Y; <PERSON> Kennelly </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Rowland </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Shays </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>DELAWARE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ Carper, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>FLORIDA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Fascell </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gibbons </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hutto </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Lehman </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, Y; Pepper, X; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bilirakis </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Goss </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> James </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> McCollum </PERSON>, N; <ORGANIZATION> Shaw </ORGANIZATION>, N; <PERSON> Stearns </PERSON>, N; Young, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>GEORGIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Barnard </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Darden </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hatcher </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Rowland </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>HAWAII</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Akaka </PERSON>, <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republican </PERSON> <PERSON> _ </PERSON> <PERSON> Saiki </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>IDAHO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Y. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Craig </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ILLINOIS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Annunzio </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, Y; Costello, Y; <PERSON> Durbin </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lipinski </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Poshard </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Russo </PERSON>, Y; Sangmeister, Y; Savage, X; <PERSON> Yates </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ Crane, X; <PERSON> Fawell </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hastert </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Madigan </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Michel </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>INDIANA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <LOCATION> Hamilton </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Jontz </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McCloskey </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Sharp </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Visclosky </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Burton </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hiler </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>IOWA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Nagle </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Grandy </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lightfoot </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>KANSAS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Slattery </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Meyers </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Whittaker </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0737EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-HouseMinimumWageRollCall 1stadd   03-24 0402</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-House Minimum Wage Roll Call, 1st add,</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: Whittaker, N.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>KENTUCKY</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Hubbard </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Mazzoli </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Natcher </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bunning </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON>, N; <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>LOUISIANA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Huckaby </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Tauzin </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Holloway </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Livingston </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MAINE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republican </PERSON> <PERSON> _ </PERSON> <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MARYLAND</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Byron </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Cardin </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hoyer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McMillen </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Mfume </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bentley </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Morella </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MASSACHUSETTS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Atkins </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON>, Y; Early, Y; <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Markey </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Mavroules </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Moakley </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Neal </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Studds </PERSON>, Y. Republican _ <PERSON> Conte </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MICHIGAN</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Carr </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Conyers </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Crockett </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, Y; <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, Y; <PERSON> Hertel </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Kildee </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Traxler </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Wolpe </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <LOCATION> Broomfield </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Henry </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Pursell </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Schuette </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Upton </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Vander </PERSON> <PERSON> Jagt </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MINNESOTA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Oberstar </PERSON>, Y; <ORGANIZATION> Penny </ORGANIZATION>, N; <PERSON> Sabo </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Sikorski </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Vento </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Frenzel </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Stangeland </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Weber </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MISSISSIPPI</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Espy, Y; <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Whitten </PERSON>, <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republican </PERSON> <PERSON> _ </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MISSOURI</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Clay, Y; <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Skelton </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Volkmer </PERSON>, Y; Wheat, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Buechner </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Emerson </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Hancock </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MONTANA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ Williams, <ORGANIZATION> Y. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Marlenee </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEBRASKA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Hoagland </PERSON>, <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republicans </PERSON> <PERSON> _ </PERSON> <PERSON> Bereuter </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEVADA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Bilbray </PERSON>, <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republican </PERSON> <PERSON> _ </PERSON> <PERSON> Vucanovich </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW HAMPSHIRE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republicans _ <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW JERSEY</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Dwyer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Florio </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Guarini </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Pallone </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Payne </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Roe </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Torricelli </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Courter </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Gallo </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Rinaldo </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Roukema </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Saxton </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW MEXICO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republicans </PERSON> _ <PERSON> Schiff </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Skeen </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW YORK</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Downey </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Engel </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Flake </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hochbrueckner </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> LaFalce </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lowey </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Manton </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McHugh </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McNulty </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Mrazek </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Rangel </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Scheuer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, Y; Slaughter, Y; <PERSON> Solarz </PERSON>, Y; Towns, Y; <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Boehlert </PERSON>, Y; Fish, N; <PERSON> Gilman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Horton </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Houghton </LOCATION>, N; Lent, N; <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Molinari </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Paxon </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NORTH CAROLINA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Clarke </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Lancaster </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Neal </PERSON>, Y; Price, Y; Rose, Y; Valentine, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Ballenger </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Coble </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> McMillan </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NORTH DAKOTA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Dorgan </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-HouseMinimumWageRollCall 2ndadd   03-24 0385</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-House Minimum Wage Roll Call, 2nd add,</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: Note Wyoming's 1 seat in the House is vacant</HEAD>
<HEAD>WASHN: Dorgan, Y.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>OHIO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Applegate </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Eckart </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Feighan </PERSON>, Y; Hall, Y; <PERSON> Kaptur </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Luken </PERSON>, X; Oakar, Y; <PERSON> Pease </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Stokes </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Traficant </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> DeWine </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Gillmor </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Gradison </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Kasich </PERSON>, N; <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION>, N; <PERSON> McEwen </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Oxley </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Regula </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Wylie </PERSON>, X.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>OKLAHOMA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ English, N; <PERSON> McCurdy </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Synar </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Inhofe </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>OREGON</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ AuCoin, Y; <PERSON> DeFazio </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Wyden </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>PENNSYLVANIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Borski, Y; <PERSON> Coyne </PERSON>, Y; Foglietta, Y; <PERSON> Gaydos </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Kanjorski </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Kolter </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Kostmayer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Murtha </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Walgren </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Yatron </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Clinger </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Coughlin </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Gekas </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Goodling </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> McDade </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Ritter </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Schulze </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Shuster </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Weldon </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>RHODE ISLAND</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republicans _ <PERSON> Machtley </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>SOUTH CAROLINA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Derrick </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Spratt </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Tallon </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Ravenel </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Spence </LOCATION>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>SOUTH DAKOTA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>TENNESSEE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Clement </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, Y; <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, Y; <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Quillen </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Sundquist </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>TEXAS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Andrews, Y; <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Bustamante </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, X; de la <PERSON> Garza </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Frost </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, Y; Hall, N; <LOCATION> Laughlin </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Leath </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON>, X; Pickle, Y; <PERSON> Sarpalius </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Stenholm </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, X -LRB- by tradition, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> speaker seldom votes -RRB-. Republicans _ <PERSON> Archer </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Armey </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Barton </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Combest </PERSON>, N; DeLay, N; Fields, N; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>UTAH</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republicans </PERSON> _ <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Nielson </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>VERMONT</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican _ <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>VIRGINIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Olin </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Payne </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Pickett </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Sisisky </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bateman </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Bliley </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Parris </PERSON>, N; Slaughter, N; <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WASHINGTON</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Dicks </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McDermott </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Swift </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Unsoeld </LOCATION>, Y. Republicans _ <LOCATION> Chandler </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WEST VIRGINIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Mollohan </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Rahall </PERSON>, Y; Staggers, Y; Wise, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WISCONSIN</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Kastenmeier </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Kleczka </PERSON>, Y; <ORGANIZATION> Moody </ORGANIZATION>, Y; Obey, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Gunderson </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Petri </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WYOMING</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Vacant.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<NOTE>End House-Minimum Wage Roll Call _ 3 Takes</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0245EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Spain-Expo'92     03-24 0801</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spain-Expo '92,0821</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ancient Seville Hopes For Economic Revival In Columbus Celebrations</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD LORANT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEVILLE, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Columbus </PERSON>' discoveries in the New World brought riches to this ancient city in southern <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>. Five centuries later, <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION> is doing it again. This time it is Expo'92, an exhibition commemorating <ORGANIZATION> Columbus </ORGANIZATION>' voyages It will run for six months and end on Oct. 12, 1992, 500 years to the day the explorer reached land in the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>. Expo'92 is a gamble by <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>'s Socialist government to catapult one of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s most beautiful and most neglected cities into the 21st century. On an island across the <LOCATION> Guadalquivir </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> from the old city's narrow streets and shaded patios, construction workers labor under a warm sun to transform about 600 acres of largely barren space into the biggest international exposition ever held The monastery where <PERSON> Columbus </PERSON>' remains were once buried is being restored as the <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> Royal Pavillion, where King <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> expects to greet dignitaries from the 88 countries, including the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, that have signed up to take part in Expo'92. A new railroad station will be built on the tracks that run by the site and a bullet train will carry passengers to the exhibition in half the three hours' time it takes now. But right now <LOCATION> Seville </LOCATION> is snarled in traffic as work progresses on dozens of new bridges, roads and other public works that must be completed by opening day, April 20, 1992. In addition to the $ 922 million the government has budgeted for administrative costs and on-site construction, authorities will pour an estimated $ 5.6 billion into public works projects to improve roads, railways and airports throughout southern <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>. `` <LOCATION> Seville </LOCATION> is going to have a difficult time, because it's a small city for so much construction,'' said <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Almodovar </PERSON>, who coordinates public works funded by the regional Andalusian government. `` We've got to ask residents for patience and compassion because after 1992 this is going to be the most important city in southern <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> added. The government of Prime Minister <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Seville </LOCATION>, has billed Expo'92 as the starting point for the city's economic renaissance <PERSON> Angel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ojeda </PERSON>, the Andalusian autonomous regional tax commissioner and a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Expo </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> '92 </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>'s board of administrators, said the project is expected to break even on the proceeds from entry fees, royalties, pavillion rental and sponsors' contributions. Once the administrative capital of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>'s overseas empire, <LOCATION> Seville </LOCATION> now presides over <LOCATION> Andalusia </LOCATION>, the country's poorest region, where unemployment runs at about 30 percent compared to the national jobless rate of 18.7 percent. A recent study by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> estimated the exhibition will generate 130,000 construction jobs over the next four years. About 7,000 other people will be needed to keep Expo'92 running. Forty million people are expected to visit the exhibition, which will leave <LOCATION> Seville </LOCATION> with an Olympic stadium, a communications center, a huge municipal park, several theaters and hundreds of new buildings that organizers hope will house a research and development complex. <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> will be the host of the 1992 Summer Olympics. Six high technology companies _ <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Alcatel </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Telefonica </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Espana </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Fujitsu </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Rank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Xerox </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Siemens </ORGANIZATION> _ have signed contracts to convert their pavillions into research and development and job-training centers after the fair ends. The Expo'92 <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> has what it calls the `` 1993 Plan,'' a post-exhibition project to cut travel time between <LOCATION> Seville </LOCATION> and the coastal resort areas of <LOCATION> Malaga </LOCATION> to the southeast, <LOCATION> Huelva </LOCATION> to the southwest, and <LOCATION> Cadiz </LOCATION> to the south, rather than massive investments in hotels in <LOCATION> Seville </LOCATION> itself. The number of hotel beds in <LOCATION> Seville </LOCATION> will be doubled, however. `` It's better to improve communication with the <LOCATION> Huelva </LOCATION> coast, which will be 45 minutes away, than build hotels in <LOCATION> Seville </LOCATION> that are forced to close in 1993,'' said <PERSON> Jacinto </PERSON> <PERSON> Pellon </PERSON>, general director of the <ORGANIZATION> Expo </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> '92 </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. Three luxury hotels are planned for the Expo'92 site, along with an `` Expo City'' of residential units for people who come here to set up the exhibitions Expo'92 project has not missed any construction deadlines so far, and public works coordinator <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> said contracts called for all the major public works to be finished on time. But <PERSON> Pellon </PERSON> said poor administrative coordination has held up approval of <LOCATION> Marina </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sevilla </LOCATION>, a private, $ 69.6-million complex that includes a civic center, 300-room hotel, a marina and shopping center on about 40 acres of public land along the river. <PERSON> Marina </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Sevilla </PERSON>'s managing director, <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Moya </PERSON>, said if the city and central governments do not approve the development by May 1 investors will reconsider the project. Among the investors is Management Resources of <LOCATION> Tustin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, which has pledged a 33-percent stake.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890324-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-89 0247EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EmbattledGoode     03-24 0782</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Embattled Goode,0802</SECOND>
<HEAD>Once A Rising Star, Philadelphia Mayor Faces Big Problems</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE LINDER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
