<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 2327EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-SatanicVerses 3rdLd-Writethru a0760 02-21 1003</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Satanic Verses, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0760,1033</SECOND>
<HEAD>Diplomatic Battle Escalates Over Khomeini's Death Sentence</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 25th graf `Publishers in...' to UPDATE
with U.S. sales, ad. Pickup 26th pvs, `In a letter...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KERIN HOPE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> recalled all its ambassadors from European Common Market nations Tuesday and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> expelled an Iranian envoy as the diplomatic battle grew over <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s death threats against author <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he supported the retaliatory moves by the European countries. However offensive <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>'s book, `` The Satanic Verses,'' may be to Moslems, `` inciting murder and offering rewards for its perpetration are deeply offensive to the norms of civilized behavior,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> does not have diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> noted existing economic sanctions against <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and said: `` I do n't know where we'll go from there.'' In <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION>, Foreign Minister <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said Tuesday that <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> is withdrawing its charge d'affaires from <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> for consultations on the death threats issue, but is leaving one diplomatic representative in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s diplomatic recall was in response to Monday's decision by the 12 nations of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> to withdraw their envoys from <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> for consultations Iranian parliament speaker <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> called the <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> move `` a big mistake.'' `` The <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> decision ... is a clear sign which proves claims that the issue of this blasphemous book ... is a plot designed by Western imperialism to fight true Islam,'' <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION> quoted him as saying. `` We do not fear such threats. ... We are prepared to follow our own path at a cost,'' said <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>. The confrontation over <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> appeared to be eroding efforts by some Iranian officials, including <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, to strengthen ties with more nations despite opposition by fundamentalist hard-liners. Although <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> was not quoted as endorsing the death sentence, his comments indicated Iranian leaders were closing ranks in the face of retaliation for <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s death call. President <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Khamenei </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> ally, said Friday that <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> might be pardoned if he repented and apologized. <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>, a Moslem himself, apologized the next day, but <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> ignored the overture and renewed the death threat. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s deputy foreign minister, <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Javad </PERSON> <PERSON> Larijani </PERSON>, said Tuesday that although <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> stood by its statements on <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>, it had not dispatched death squads to kill the author. `` We have not closed the door on negotiations nor have we opened the door for confrontation,'' <PERSON> Larijani </PERSON> said in an interview with <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION>. At the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> appealed to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to spare the lives of <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> and his publishers. The 41-year-old Indian-born author has been in hiding with his wife in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, where he lives. The Common Market nations stoppe short of breaking relations with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> but said that in addition to recalling top diplomats, they would suspend high-level visits to and from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, a market member, went a step further by recalling its entire embassy staff. On Tuesday, it announced it was expelling the Iranian charge d'affaires and his aide. `` It is neither possible nor sensible to conduct a normal relationship with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>,'' Foreign Secretary Sir <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> followed the Common Market and recalled their ambassadors, and <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> threatened to cancel a trade mission to <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> next month unless the death warrant were rescinded. <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> summoned the Iranian ambassadors to their nations to express disapproval of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s actions. Moslems say `` The Satanic Verses'' blasphemes their religion by portraying the prophet <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON>'s wives as prostitutes and suggesting that he wrote the Koran, the holy book of Islam, rather than receiving it from God. The novel was met with critical acclaim when <PERSON> Viking </PERSON> published the 547-page book in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> in September. It was not until last week, on the eve of its publication in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, that <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> ordered Moslems to track down <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> and kill him. Publishers in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> then canceled plans to publish the book. Bookstores in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and many in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> pulled the novel from their shelves. Many independent booksellers continued to stock the novel, however. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported that based on last week's sales `` The Satanic Verses'' will be listed as the second best-selling hardcover fiction book in the March 5 issue of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Book </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION>. A full-page advertisement Wednesday in the Times announcing publication of the book proclaimed: `` Free people write books, free people publish books, free people sell books, free people buy books, free people read books.'' The ad was signed by the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishers </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Booksellers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. In a letter Tuesday to Premier <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON> of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, the more than 500 authors in the French chapter of the international <ORGANIZATION> Pen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> called for publication of `` The Satanic Verses'' and said they were confident authorities could assure the publishers' safety. In <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, internationally acclaimed novelist <PERSON> Guenter </PERSON> <PERSON> Grass </PERSON> said a group of 24 writers will publish the book under an agreement with the publisher, which said last week it feared for its employees. In <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION> daily <ORGANIZATION> Borba </ORGANIZATION> stopped printing excerpts from the novel after anonymous callers threatened `` violent reprisals,'' according to a newspaper employee who spoke on condition of anonymity. Former Israeli lawmaker <PERSON> Shmuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Flatto-Sharon </PERSON> invited <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> to stay in his 27-room home in a <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> suburb, and offered to buy the rights to the novel in the countries where publishers have balked. `` We have a lot of problems here but security is not one of them,'' <PERSON> Flatto-Sharon </PERSON> said. In the British <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lords </ORGANIZATION>, Lord <PERSON> Paget </PERSON> raised the possibility of a nuclear strike against <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> if <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> were murdered. `` Is there nothing we can do when the ayatollah is going around saying ` who's afraid of the big bad bomb?''' he asked. Speaking for the government, Lord <PERSON> Trefgarne </PERSON> replied: `` We seek an improvement in our relations with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and not a descent to the jungle.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 2344EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Afghanistan 1stLd-Writethru a0695 02-21 0716</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Afghanistan, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0695,0739</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Prime Minister Returns To Government Post</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 10 grafs to ADD Shiite background of Kishtmand and
UPDATE with rebels trying to break deadlock on forming interim govt. Pick
up 8th pvs, `The guerrillas'...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SHARON HERBAUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sultan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Kishtmand </PERSON>, a ranking member of the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s Politburo and a hard-liner, Tuesday took over many of the duties of prime minister, government sources said. Moslem guerrillas, meanwhile, fired a salvo of rockets into the Afghan capital, killing one person and injuring three others on the ninth anniversary of an uprising against the Soviet-backed government. <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Hasan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharq </PERSON> stepped down as prime minister Monday, and a 21-member <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> took power. State-run <ORGANIZATION> Kabul </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Kishtmand </PERSON>, who served as prime minister for seven years until May 1988, is in charge of supervising the government's council of ministers. Government sources, speaking on condition of anonyumity, said this means the 52-year-old Kishtmand will effectively be the prime minister. The return to power of of <LOCATION> Kishtmand </LOCATION>, the only prominent Shiite Moslem in President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>'s government, is seen as another move by <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> to consolidate the power of his communist government. Shiites make up only 17 percent of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s population, but they account for about 40 percent of the refugees from which many of the guerrillas are drawn. <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> appointed <ORGANIZATION> Sharq </ORGANIZATION>, a non-communist, as prime minister last May in an unsucessful bid to seek a power-sharing agreement with the Moslem guerrillas. In <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, a committee of Afghan field commanders and scholars sought to reach a consensus Tuesday on the makeup of an interim government for <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. More than 400 delegates to a special Afghan council or `` shura'' canceled Tuesday's session while the committee wrestled with a blueprint for a provisional government. The commanders and scholars took over the job of nominating an interim government after guerrilla leaders, paralyzed by differences between moderates and fundamentalists, failed to break a deadlock Monday. The guerrillas' rocket attack on <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> was the first since Thursday, when at least seven people were killed. The <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said the fatal rocket in Tuesday's assault hit near a government refugee office in northern <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. Three other rockets hit southeastern <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, but there were no reports of casualties. The guerrillas hold most of the countryside and are trying to close in on the cities, which mainly are held by government troops. At the headquarters of the secret police, the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> displayed a huge cache of arms and explosives and said the guerrillas had planned to use them Tuesday to attack buildings and bazaars. Many had markings from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. Officials said others were made in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, where the most powerful guerrilla groups are based. <PERSON> Moammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Omar </PERSON>, a state security agent, said the weapons were seized Monday in a well in eastern <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. Business was brisk at some shops in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> Tuesday, but others were closed to mark the anniversary of the anti-Soviet uprising. The 1980 revolt occurred two months after Soviet troops entered <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> to bolster a Marxist government. Soviet soldiers fired on Moslem protesters who emerged from their homes shouting `` God is Great!'' Dozens of people were reported killed. Among the weapons displayed by the government were plastic explosives that agents said came from <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, Chinese-made hand grenades, British mortar shells, Egyptian rockets, Italian fuses for mines, Swedish circuit testers and <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> rifles. There also were political pamphlets. One, printed in English and the local language <LOCATION> Dari </LOCATION>, said: `` We will contine our Jihad -LRB- holy war -RRB- until the withdrawal of the last Soviet soldier.'' The final Soviet troops, once estimated at more than 100,000 in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, withdrew last Wednesday under a U.N.-mediated accord. Over the weekend, <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> declared a state of emergency and shook up his government to consolidate control. In <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> Tuesday, an investigator appointed by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> said both sides in the civil war continue to violate the human rights of Afghans. Austrian law professor <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Ermacora </PERSON> said reliable reports suggest dfghan police still widely use torture and mistreatment as part of interrogations. His report also listed alleged incidents, cited by `` a variety of corroborating sources,'' in which rebels had killed more than 100 Afghan soldiers and civilians since September.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 0031EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     02-21 0823</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Massive Conversion of Grain to ``Gasohol'' Still a Dream</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The old dream of wiping out grain surpluses by turning corn into fuel-grade alcohol is a long way from coming true, but progress continues, according to industry and farm officials. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Growers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, for example, says ethanol blends will be introduced this fall in the <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, area to comply with the state's new clean air law. Blended fuels, basically 10 percent ethanol and 90 percent gasoline, are said to cut automobile carbon monoxide emissions by as much as 25 percent. Another alternative is petroleum-based MTBE, or methyl-tertiary-butyl-ether, which can reduce emissions by 10 percent. The corn producers said <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> initiated the nation's first fuels program using ethanol and MTBE blends a year ago and that `` the success of the <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> program was instrumental'' in passage of <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>'s clean air law. An estimated 340 million bushels of corn were used to produce 800 million gallons of ethanol for fuel blending last year, with blends representing 8 percent of all gasoline sales in 1988, the association said. The Renewable Fuels Association, a Washington-based trade association representing the ethanol industry, said more than 8.4 billion gallons of ethanol-gasoline blends were sold in 42 states last year. The association said more than 60 ethanol plants are operating in 23 states, representing a private investment of more than $ 2.5 billion. Ethanol use in gasoline to make `` gasohol'' was spurred by the second oil embargo by <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> countries in the late 1970s, the association said, and by a rush of subsidies from the federal and state governments. The fervor at the time also prompted hopes that burdensome grain surpluses could be used as feed stock, thus bolstering the nation's farm economy as well as contributing to the fuel supply `` What is even more significant is that this superior record of growth has been sustained through good economic conditions and bad,'' the association said. `` This past year, unusually high grain prices caused by the drought and near-record low oil prices threatened to severely weaken this industry.'' But while three plants were forced to shut down temporarily, `` little production capacity was lost and sales have remained quite strong.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has not viewed ethanol possibilities with the enthusiasm of the corn and industry associations. There are economic problems that wo n't go away simply because ethanol sounds like a good idea, says the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. `` Ethanol gained support as it also promised environmental benefits and new markets and uses for corn and other surplus crops,'' the agency said in a recent background paper. `` But the sense of urgency over the need to develop alternative fuels dissipated as petroleum prices declined.'' But public attention once again is being drawn to alcohol fuels to help reduce pollution, ease dependence on foreign oil and to provide a greater market for farm crops. `` Compliance deadlines of the Clean Air Act passed and the standards are still unmet,'' the report said. `` <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> petroleum imports have increased to the high levels of the early 1970s.'' As to the future, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> analysts said ethanol's success will depend on energy, environmental, agricultural and trade policies. Those are factors that will determine the prices, costs and competitiveness of the ethanol industry. `` The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> fuel ethanol industry was created by a mix of federal and state subsidies, loan programs and other incentives,'' the report said. A handful of large plants produce most of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ethanol, the report said. The eight largest, owned by five companies, accounted for nearly 75 percent of the operating capacity in 1986. `` Ethanol is exempt from 6 cents of the 9-cent -LRB- federal excise -RRB- tax through September 1993,'' the report said. `` At the 10 percent blending rate ... that exemption is effectively a 60-cent-per-gallon subsidy. Many states provide similar financial incentives averaging 20 to 30 cents per gallon.'' The federal government also helps with loan guarantees to encourage plant construction, but `` most of these plants have not been successful,'' the report said. Only one of the three plants with loans guaranteed by the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> was operating and paying off its loans by early 1988. At <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, spokesman <PERSON> Marlyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Aycock </PERSON> said loan guarantees for 11 plants were initially obligated but that only three are currently in operation. <PERSON> Aycock </PERSON> said FmHA has made no ethanol loans since 1984 and that the maximum had been reduced by half, from $ 20 billion per plant to $ 10 million. The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> background report said the production of ethanol so far has `` not significantly affected income for farmers participating in government commodity programs. `` Moderate levels of ethanol production would only slightly affect total farm revenue and income,'' the report said. `` It is unlikely that modest increases in ethanol production would drive market prices for corn to exceed current target price levels -LRB- in the federal commodity programs -RRB- within the next 8 to 10 years.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 0530EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Toddler-Superman     02-21 0157</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Toddler-Superman,0163</SECOND>
<HEAD>3-Year-Old Imitating Superhero Jumps From Window</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CRESTLINE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 3-year-old boy who wanted to fly like <PERSON> Superman </PERSON> made a 25-foot dive out of a second-story window but escaped injury, a fire official says. The boy had just finished watching `` Superman'' on television Monday when he made the leap, said <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Crest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION>. `` Luckily, he took his pillow with him,'' <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said. `` Pretty tough little kid.'' The mother said she heard the boy crying and found him outside, dressed in diapers and a T-shirt. The boy, whose name was withheld, was examined at <ORGANIZATION> Mountain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arrowhead </LOCATION> and released, said an employee there who refused to give her name. `` I'm just glad the boy was OK,'' <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said. `` Apparently the mother was pretty convinced that the boy was trying to fly.'' <LOCATION> Crestline </LOCATION> is a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> community 60 miles northeast of downtown <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 0531EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Skier-Deer     02-21 0142</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Skier-Deer,0147</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teen Collides With Deer at Ski Resort</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WEST DOVER, Vt. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 16-year-old skier ran into more than loose snow on the slopes of a southern <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> ski resort. She ran into a deer. <PERSON> Andrea </PERSON> <PERSON> Spieth </PERSON> hit the deer Monday while skiing with her family at the Mount Snow Ski Resort. `` It ran across the trail,'' she said, `` and I ran right into it.'' The <LOCATION> Barrington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>, high school junior fell, but the deer kept going as several other skiers and a ski instructor watched. <PERSON> Spieth </PERSON> said colliding with the deer was like running into a rock. Physicians who treated her for a sprained ligament in her thumb `` thought I was crazy'' when she told them how she acquired her injury. `` But somebody called up and confirmed it _ that they saw a girl hit by a deer.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-YankeeGoHome     02-21 0823</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Yankee Go Home,0844</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anti-Americanism: A Minority View Perhaps, But No Longer A Whisper</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KELLY TUNNEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Anti-American protesters are challenging <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s policies toward the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and sparking more <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> criticism here than at any time in four decades. From student radicals yelling `` Yankee Go Home'' to farmers denouncing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agriculture imports, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Koreans </LOCATION> are venting their frustration and anger at one of their oldest allies. When President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> visits <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> next Monday, he will find what one newspaper warns is a society `` quite different'' from the one he saw as vice president in April 1982. `` Do n't Come to <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>!'' yell radical students, punctuating the words with raised, clenched fists. Criticism of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is no longer relegated to private conversation. <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> flags are torched and effigies of Uncle <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> or <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> are burned. Some 12,000 angry farmers battled thousands of riot police with clubs and firebombs outside the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> this month and denounced the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for trying to force open <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s agricultural market Radical students staged a series of attacks on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> facilities to demand an end to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> influence. They vowed to hold nationwide anti-government, anti-U.S. demonstrations to coincide with the president's visit. `` Arson, violence, destruction and lawlessness can not be tolerated,'' said President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-woo </PERSON> in demanding an end to protests. Every <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president since the Korean War except <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> has visited <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> but none has come during a time of more public animosity against <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> policies. Businessmen, laborers, and students who have never thrown a firebomb are heard to complain that <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> is victimized by unfair trade pressures and rude, <ORGANIZATION> Yankee </ORGANIZATION> arrogance. When asked their nationality by a Korean, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens rarely acknowledge that they are American. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassy and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military have cautioned citizens against wearing clothing which labels them from the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.A. </ORGANIZATION> `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is no longer a sacred cow,'' said a western diplomat, requesting anonymity.'' <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is no longer the patron saint of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has played roles in past dictatorial governments and we oppose the visit of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>,'' claims a labor alliance demanding investigations into corruption and human rights abuses of the past U.S.-supported authoritarian government. A few weeks ago, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> said it was considering closing its cultural center in the provincial capital of <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION>, 180 miles south of <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, because of repeated violent attacks and concern for the safety of its staff. <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION> was the scene of a bloody nine-day civil uprising in 1980. Many opposition and dissident figures claim the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> shared responsibility for the <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION> incident by acquiescing in a military-backed <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> government plan to quell the uprising. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> denied the charge. Although public protests appear outwardly to have scant impact on relations and radicals have little public support, government leaders warn that growing anti-American sentiment could endanger <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s interests in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The government lost no time in apologizing publicly for the <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION> center attacks and appealed to radical students `` not to damage traditional Korea-U. friendship.'' The assistant foreign minister, <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Suk-kyu </PERSON>, reflects the thinking of many when he says anti-Americanism `` is a minority view and a passing phenomenon, despite loud voices and anti-American activists.'' More than half of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s 40 million people have been born since the Korean War ended 35 years ago, and long time observers link the intensity of anti-American feeling to the age of the participant. The younger the person, the more likely he or she is to feel the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has taken its relationship with <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> for granted. The Korean peninsula has been divided into the capitalist south and the communist north since the end of World War II in 1945. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> helped <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> fight the 1950-53 Korean War against the north and keeps 42,000 troops stationed in the south under a mutual defense pact. Radical students and dissidents feel the presence of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops stand in the way of unification talks with the north and have demanded the withdrawal of all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces. They also demand the halt to this year's joint <LOCATION> U.S.-South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> military exercises called `` Team Spirit.'' A more realistic relationship is needed between the two governments, say both protesters and some politicians, a relationship which recognizes <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s economic potential and place in global politics. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>'s leading trade partner. <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> sold <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> goods worth $ 8 billion more than it bought from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> last year. Considerable pressure has been placed on the Koreans to liberalize their import regulations to help balance the deficit. Anti-American comment became acceptable socially after last fall's Olympic Games when South Koreans of all ages had their frustration and resentment against the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> stoked by what they regarded as unruly behavior of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> athletes and biased coverage by <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BadTimesonBayouII     02-21 1211</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bad Times on Bayou II,1246</SECOND>
<HEAD>Part II: Economic Reform Comes Hard In Populist Louisiana</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 When the oil and the good times were flowing, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s populist system of government seemed to make sense. Give the people a free ride and let the businesses pay. Now oil has crashed, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> has suffered through four years of economic depression, and economists say recovery is n't possible without a new system. A reformist governor is trying to do just that, but breaking with the populist past does n't come easy. This second of two parts of `` Bad Times On The Bayou'' explores this <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> revolution.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>By SCOTT McCARTNEY</NOTE>
<NOTE>Associated Press Writer</NOTE>
<DATELINE>BATON ROUGE, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 34-story <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> state capitol casts a long shadow over the white marble statue of <PERSON> Huey </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON>, but these days, it seems the statue is casting the longer shadow. `` An unconquered friend of the poor,'' the inscription on Long's adjacent tomb says, `` who dreamed of the day when the wealth of the land would be spread among the people. The populist ideas of `` the Kingfish,'' who governed from 1928-1932, still influence the fiscal structure of the state. Spread the wealth, protect the poor. Homeowners receive a $ 75,000 property tax exemption, making the average home tax free. Automobile license plates cost only $ 3 a year. City councils ca n't raise taxes without a vote of the people. Businesses bear much of the burden through taxes and fees. But the way of doing business that <PERSON> Huey </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON> helped build is crippling the state now, economists say. Without the oil windfall, state and local budgets ca n't be balanced. Schools and hospitals are suffering. Unemployment has soared. And new businesses are scared away by the tax structure. `` It's ironic. What is supposed to be good for the people now acts to their detriment,'' said <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION> economist <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>. Added business leader <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Schreiber </PERSON>, director of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>' World Trade Center: `` We've got to change We can not do business in the old ways. ... Painful as it is, it's forced us to wake up.'' But waking up is n't easy in the land of `` The Big Easy,'' as <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> is called. After a string of legislative victories and a fierce round of budget cutting and borrowing, Gov. <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>'s initial attempt at overhauling the tax structure failed in the state House. The Harvard-educated conservative Democrat has, in his own words, `` poked every bear in the forest'' while inciting a revolution in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>. He won education reform, campaign finance reform, tort reform, worker's compensation reform, even unemployment insurance reform. But when it came to fiscal reform, when it came to dismantling the last vestiges of the populist past, <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> lost. Ca n't a family's home be the one thing that's not taxed, <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>'s opponents asked `` I believe in paying our own way. That is a break from <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> tradition,'' <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> said. `` It does n't come easy.'' Along the way, <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> is also compiling a spectrum of political enemies ranging from populists to labor unions to teachers. Public opinion polls are divided on the maverick reformer. The question remains, what happens if he ca n't complete the revolution? `` It would be more of the same. We'd be a slave to <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> ... a wasteland, a welfare state,'' <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> said, adding that people with the means to move away would do so. Politicians, he said, `` are beginning to realize that.'' Fiscal reform has become the vortex of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s struggle to climb out of a depression that began when the price of oil fell by more than half in 1984-85. Tens of thousands lost jobs, and both businesses and workers left the state. And taxes on oil _ which used to account for 40 percent of the <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> state budget _ plummeted. The state, long known for its big spending ways, had n't put anything aside for dry years. It had n't spent much on developing a strong economic base, outside of oil. In fact, it had n't even had a balanced budget in the 1980s until <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> took office 10 months ago _ even though it has a balanced budget law. It's debt reached $ 2 billion. `` We could not make the payroll the week after I took office,'' <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> said. Now, state promoters, planners and business leaders all buzz with talk about <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s recovery _ if there is fiscal reform. `` When the price of oil was $ 40 a barrel, hardly anybody worried,'' said <PERSON> Schreiber </PERSON>, the businessman who chaired a governor's task force on labor `` Having all these advantages made everyone in the state very lazy. <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> has not been competitive in business,'' <PERSON> Schreiber </PERSON> said. `` It's only really now that the state is pulling its act together.'' The day after reform failed last October, two companies considering <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> announced plans to build in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Other businesses considering a relocation or expansion in the Bayou State are holding off until they see if reform passes, said <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s chief of economic development, <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> Wall Street bond brokers set out informal guidelines for what would be necessary to raise the state's bond rating, currently just one notch above junk bonds. Low bond ratings means the state must pay higher interest on its debt. <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> has accomplished all but one item _ fiscal reform, said his chief of staff, <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON>. `` They watch us very closely,'' he said. The battle will probably be waged this spring when <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> comes back to the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> with a plan. Last time, his package passed the state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, but came up 10 votes short of the necessary two-thirds margin in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. The opposition focused on <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>'s plan to cut by two-thirds the $ 75,000 homestead exemption _ the nation's highest. It was led by a county tax assessor, <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Chehardy </PERSON>, who saw reform as an attempt to raise taxes and cripple the average homeowner. `` People in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> read horror stories in other states where property taxes did go wild,'' said <PERSON> Chehardy </PERSON>. `` Government taxes everything. Ca n't there be one thing in life a person can have without being taxed?'' <PERSON> Chehardy </PERSON> says lawmakers should cut the budget, and if there are any tax increases, taxpayers should get a chance to vote. But <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> and his top aides insist the budget has been cut so much _ more than $ 500 million _ that further reductions could cripple the state. Already, they worry about the declining quality of care at state-financed charity hospitals and the ability of cities like <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> to get by without the traditional state support. And the next fiscal year budget has a projected deficit of $ 734 million. The total budget is $ 4.2 billion, but only $ 2.2 billion is discretionary spending _ money that is n't tied to court orders or debt payments. `` Cutting that much -LRB- $ 734 million -RRB- would shut more and more hospitals, cut transportation money and higher education,'' said Commissioner of Administration <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Stine </PERSON>. `` That is, in my mind, shutting down government.'' Still, the early talk of next June's budget is a revolutionary concept by itself in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, a state that at times balanced its budget for only three-quarters of the year and hoped oil prices would go up.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> is the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> regional reporter, based in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NorthTrial-Keker     02-21 0661</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North Trial-Keker,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lead Prosecutor a Creature of the Courtroom</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-North Trial Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Keker </PERSON>, the lawyer prosecuting <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> in the Iran-Contra trial, has a reputation for intuitively making the right move in a courtroom. In a civil lawsuit, lawyers for a bank abruptly asked one of <PERSON> Keker </PERSON>'s clients whether he would waive the attorney-client privilege of confidentiality. Reacting to the unorthodox request, <PERSON> Keker </PERSON> quickly said his client _ an investor who alleged he had been defrauded _ would agree to a waiver if the bank was willing to waive the same privilege covering conversations with its attorneys. The bank backed down. Representing an insurance company accused of overcharging its customers, <PERSON> Keker </PERSON> on cross-examination asked an expert witness to select from a stock of well over 100 files the one he considered to be the most egregious example of overcharging. Robert A. <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Nest </PERSON>, a partner in <PERSON> Keker </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> law firm, recalls that <PERSON> Keker </PERSON> spent a minute familiarizing himself with the contents of the file selected by the expert and `` then proceeded to tear the witness apart.'' `` Two things about <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Nest </PERSON>, his tenacity and his intuition. `` He does n't let a point drop. He will fight all the way to whatever is there. `` He's remarkably intuitively skilled in a courtroom. It's a great athlete's intuition, to know where the ball is and where everything is on the field. <PERSON> John </PERSON> has that kind of intuition. He has an ability to respond to the evidence.'' <PERSON> Keker </PERSON>'s ability `` to kind of sense where the witness is going'' is `` a rare skill in today's lawyer,'' said <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Nest </PERSON>. `` So many of us take deposition after deposition and there's nothing to predict.'' <PERSON> Keker </PERSON>'s weaker points? `` He has as many weaknesses as the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> 49ers,'' said <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Nest </PERSON>. The North case will be <PERSON> Keker </PERSON>'s first as a prosecutor, but his abilities as a defense lawyer translate easily to the other side of the courtroom, says <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> McGivern </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, chief assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney for the northern district of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. `` He's always been aggressive and he can bring that aggression to the prosecution side,'' said <PERSON> McGivern </PERSON>. `` He's aware of the moves of a defense lawyer, having been one himself.'' In short, <PERSON> Keker </PERSON> `` can try a case there's no doubt about that,'' said <PERSON> McGivern </PERSON>, who as a prosecutor has been involved in several cases in which <PERSON> Keker </PERSON> has been a defense attorney. A Vietnam War veteran who served in the Marines and was wounded in combat, <PERSON> Keker </PERSON> is a graduate of <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> and a founding partner of <ORGANIZATION> Keker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Brockett </PERSON> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. He has successfully defended movie maker <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> in a civil lawsuit and won a case in which his client, a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> society figure and architect, was accused of vehicular manslaughter. After the Iran-Contra affair erupted in 1986, <PERSON> Keker </PERSON> sought work with independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> John </PERSON> felt there was an important lesson here for Americans who care about the democratic process and he was intent in participating in the investigation for that reason,'' said <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Nest </PERSON>. <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Nest </PERSON> said <PERSON> Keker </PERSON> had concerns that those involved appeared to have been `` hiding the ball, running foreign policy without the consent of representatives of the people.'' `` The political and legal implications struck me as enormous,'' <PERSON> Keker </PERSON> said of the Iran-Contra episode in an interview last year with The Los Angeles Times. <PERSON> Keker </PERSON>, 45, has more than 15 years as a trial lawyer and relishes the role. `` When you go to court,'' he told the Times, `` you get a chance to be a hero, which is a thing that most people repress the desire for. You also get a chance to fail enormously. `` That sort of edge is something that people who are trial lawyers usually like. You get a chance to do the right thing. You get a chance to do it in a stylish way.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ForeignAid Bjt   02-21 0638</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Foreign Aid, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Agency Calls for Reshaping of Aid Program</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The federal foreign aid agency says the time has come for a radical reshaping of the way the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> allocates the billions of dollars a year it passes out to other nations. The recommendation was contained in a 158-page report issued Monday by the administrator of the <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON>. `` The challenges of today's problems, and tomorrow's, can not be met with yesterday's solutions, suitable as they may have been to yesterday's problems,'' the report said. The study, which made no specific recommendations for policy changes, said the aid program no longer seems able to fulfill its original mandate of helping poor countries achieve the transition from dependency to self-sufficiency. Somewhere between 1949 and the present, the original concept of aid as a transitional means of helping countries become self-sufficient has been lost, it said. `` Is today's <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign aid fostering healthy development towards independent prosperity _ or simply postponing the day of reckoning for governments unwilling or unable to take the politically painful steps needed for their own development?'' the report asked. `` All too often, dependency seems to have won out over development,'' the report said. A principal conclusion calls for `` radically reshaping'' future official assistance programs to face new realities and to coordinate government assistance with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> private sector involvement in providing humanitarian aid, education and overseas investment. This reshaping `` must be both an immediate concern and a major long-term national priority. Nothing less will serve the national interests of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' the report said. <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> noted in comments to a group of reporters that no country has `` graduated'' from less developed to developed status in the past 20 years. All this is in sharp contrast to the Marshall Plan of the late 1940's and early 1950's when an ambitious <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid program helped put <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> on its feet and then was terminated. One problem highlighted by the report is that `` succeeding Congresses and administrations, prodded by the dominant crises _ and interest groups _ of the moment, have piled differing and often conflicting foreign assistance objectives on top of each other.'' This `` dizzying'' array ranges from winning friends for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, to alleviating poverty, to countering the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and to finding markets for American farm products, the report said. In a December speech, Rep. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, D-Ind., a member of a bipartisan <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> task force on foreign aid, said the 33 separate statutory objectives for foreign assistance `` are so numerous that they do not provide meaningful direction. `` All of these 33 objectives may be worthy. I probably voted for most of them. ... However, a program that pursues all objectives risks accomplishing none of them,'' he said. Complicating fulfillment of these objectives has been a decline in the amount of aid appropriated from $ 19 billion in 1985 to $ 14 billion this year, <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> said. The Woods report suggested that developmental success has less to do with foreign aid levels than with the internal policies of recipient countries. `` Where development has worked, and is working, the key has been economic growth,'' it said. `` And this is largely the result of the individual nations making the right policy choices and making the most of their internal human and material resources.'' The report said growth-oriented policies `` are a constant among success cases, regardless of the level of aid they have received _ which are sometimes greater and sometimes less than the levels received by developmental laggards.'' It said the `` impressive development of first <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and later <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> is proof positive that the right donor program and guidance, when matched by the right recipient policies, can result in a smooth transition from dependence to self-sufficiency.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bayou-RoemerQ&amp;A     02-21 0752</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bayou-Roemer Q&amp;A,0771</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Every Bear In The Forest, I've Poked'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Bad Times On Bayou II</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Since taking office in May, Gov. <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> has balanced a state budget for the first time in the 1980s. He's steered a package of reforms through the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>, including political campaign reform and education reform. Yet he lost his most important battle _ overhauling the state's populist taxing structure. Here, in excerpts from an interview with <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> regional reporter <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON>, <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> discusses his goals and concerns for <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> from his <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, office.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Question: What are you trying to do to this state? It seems like there's a revolution going on. Answer: It really is. ... We inherited the highest unemployment rate in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and a budget that was in shambles for a variety of reasons. For example, the price of oil in last year's budget was $ 21 a barrel. Oil never saw $ 21. It was a phony figure which exasperated the deficit. We've got it -LRB- oil, which is currently around $ 17 a barrel -RRB- at $ 13.80. That's how tough we are. ... As a result, I think the business community in the state and outside of the state knows that something's happening in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>. Our unemployment rate is beginning to go down. It was above 12 percent when I took office. It's now about 9.5. Q: Is it the attitudes in the state that you're bumping up against? A: We had a state, and I love <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, but we had a state where big money beat big ideas, and that's a loser. We're trying to reverse it. It's not done. We've got a ways to go. We need to rewrite our tax code to give businesses incentives to grow jobs. I tried ... I failed by a close margin. We'll try it again, and win it. When we do that, all of the ingredients will be in place. ... Watch us. I want to warn <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and the other states of the <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION>. Watch us. Q: Is it fair to say what you're really doing is throwing out the past, throwing out the populist government, throwing out the legacy of <PERSON> Huey </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON>? A: Right, in part. I want to be fair to <PERSON> Huey </PERSON> because he had many great points. <PERSON> Huey </PERSON> built the roads in this state to tie farms to market. He gave children free textbooks. So when we say we're breaking with the past, I really do n't think of <PERSON> Huey </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON> I do think of the populist strain where there's something for nothing and everybody else pays the bill. We are trying to break from that. ... I believe in paying our own way. That is a break from <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> tradition. It does n't come easy. Q: What would happen if tax reform does n't pass? A: It would be more of the same. We'd be a slave to <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>. We'd be a slave to how many times <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> can get together and jack the price around. We'd be a wasteland, a welfare state. Those who are without hope, those who are without means, wo n't move _ they ca n't, they're stuck. Those with an education, with financial mobility, are going to vote with their feet. They're going to leave. And for the first time the politicians are beginning to realize that. Every bear in the forest, I've poked. Now is the time to do it. There are some who think that if I do my job right, I could never get elected to another public office. Q: Do you believe it? A: Might be true. Q: Do you care? A: I do n't. ... I would be totally satisfied four years from now to prop my feet up on the desk and say, ` Well done.' Q: Do you think things can turn around that quickly? A: Yes, in terms of public perception and attitude. That's the real fight. The fight is not the unemployment rate that goes up and down with national trends and a lot of things out of our control. You'll see an improvement over four years and fairly dramatic. But what needs to turn around is attitude. I found many people in this state who had given up, who felt <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> could not change, who felt that we were a slave to our past, who felt that the populist politicians owned <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>. They're beginning to realize now that we are winners. Not me, we. This state's a winner.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SuperpowerTriangle     02-21 0739</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Superpower Triangle,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sino-Soviet Warmth Causes No American Concern</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Not so long ago, <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> policy-makers would be concerned about the forthcoming Sino-Soviet summit, the first one in 30 years. But that's no longer the case and the meeting is not likely to blemish President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s trip to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> this weekend. `` If Sino-Soviet rapprochement contributes to the stability of the region and the globe, then it is all to the good,'' said one old <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> hand who is helping plan <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s trip. Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s scheduled visit to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> in May will end the Sino-Soviet rift and highlight Kremlin concessions on the three points the Chinese have said were preventing improved relations for a decade. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s meeting with senior <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiao-peng </PERSON> will be the first Sino-Soviet summit since <PERSON> Nikita </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON> met with <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse-tung </PERSON> in 1959. <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> and <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON> later argued over ideology, and Soviet and Chinese troops clashed in the 1960's and 1970's along the 4,670-mile border. The reason the Chinese are welcoming the Soviet leader, and that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> does not object, is the marked shift in <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> foreign policy in the four years <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has been in power, according to scholars and government experts. Before agreeing to meet with the <LOCATION> Russians </LOCATION>, the Chinese wanted the Soviets out of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, the Vietnamese out of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> and a reduction of Soviet troops along the border. The Kremlin has met or started to meet all of those conditions. The last <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> soldier left <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> last week, ending a bloody and futile nine-year occupation. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, a close military ally of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, has removed some of the more than 100,000 troops it sent into <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in 1978 and agreed to negotiations over withdrawing the rest. In 1987, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> withdrew 12,000 of its troops from <LOCATION> Mongolia </LOCATION>, on the Chinese border, and last December <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> announced unspecified further reductions in the estimated 50,000 troops remaining there. The Sino-Soviet summit, in short, derives from <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s efforts to change Soviet policies and to make friends rather than enemies around the world `` There could be a summit only if the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> changed its pattern of behavior from the last two or three decades,'' said <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, a fellow at the Russian Research Center at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` The things that brought the Soviets and the Chinese together are the same things that brought the Soviets and the Americans together,'' said <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, a specialist on Soviet relations with Asian nations. A <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> specialist on <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, who spoke on condition he not be further identified, noted that `` both the Chinese and the Soviets have stressed that the normalization of their relations will not affect their ties with any other country,'' in other words, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. If the Soviets fully meet the conditions laid down by the Chinese, said the government expert, `` that will be a big plus for stability in the region.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, announcing his trip to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, indicated that the time had passed for the kind of geopolitical maneuver that opened the door of U.S.-Chinese relations in the 1970's, the `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> card'' played by then-President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> against the Kremlin. `` Well, I do n't know what signal it sends in that regard, but let me just remind you that I'm the one who does not believe in ` playing the Soviet card,' or ` playing the <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> card,''' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said on Jan. 28. The most recent senior <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official to visit <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, then-Defense Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON>, said in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> last September that `` we think the relaxation of tensions between <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> would be healthy for world peace and stability.'' A report from the conservative <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> concluded that `` a <LOCATION> Beijing-Moscow </LOCATION> summit need not bode ill for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> does not necessarily gain if Chinese-Soviet relations remain cool, nor does the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> necessarily lose of those relations improve,'' wrote Heritage analyst <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> B </PERSON>. Brick. Relations between the communist giants has already improved in recent years, noted Brick, and the two are natural trading partners, with similar economies, a long border, and natural resources that the other needs. Under a bilateral trade pact signed in 1985, said <LOCATION> Brick </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has become <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s fifth largest trading partner, with barter exchange rising from $ 260 billion in 1981 to $ 1.8 billion last year, and expected to reach $ 6 billion by 1990.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SickSwedes     02-21 0667</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sick Swedes,0687</SECOND>
<HEAD>More and More Swedes are Calling in Sick</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CECILIA LONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More and more Swedes are calling in sick from their jobs and authorities say they plan to try to find out if they are faking. Abuses in one of the world's most liberal welfare systems may be costing billions in sick pay. A recent study by the Swedish Employer's <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said the average Swedish worker in industry missed 27 days a year for illness in 1987, compared with 18 days in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, 16 in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and 11 in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. A recent opinion poll indicated that 86 percent of those questioned suspected their colleagues of cheating. Official statistics show that sick pay costs have increased by 50 percent over the past three years. <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s sick pay plan has traditionally been based on the honor system. Under a 1987 reform, blue-collar workers joined other wage earners in being entitled to 90 percent of their pay when they are off sick, starting from the first day they stay home. The government handles the payments, but most of the money comes from taxes paid by employers. In the Swedish system, an employee who is ill calls his <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> and later signs a form stating the nature of the illness. A doctor's certificate is required only if the worker is home for a week or more. One form of abuse is simply for an employee to call in sick when he's not. However, authorities say it's even more common for workers to file for sick pay and go to work anyway, getting sick pay in addition to regular pay. It's difficult to check. `` If I knock on the door and nobody opens, what is my proof?'' <PERSON> Yvonne </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroberg </PERSON>, a local official, said recently on Swedish television. She suggested more telephone checks with employers rather than home visits by inspectors. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> described another scheme in a report late last year. It said some people collect payments for sick leave, parental leave and student grants for the same period. <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Gustaf </PERSON> <PERSON> Scherer </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, said on television his organization would increase its supervision. In <LOCATION> Bandhagen </LOCATION>, south of <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION>, the local office started a three-week campaign to check all claims on certain days. Sick leave, pensions and various other social benefits are expected to cost 20 percent of the gross national product this year. Illness benefits last year amounted to $ 5 billion, $ 120 million more than <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> paid for defense. One option under study is to let employers take over sick payments for those absent from work up to two weeks, saving the government money and paperwork. The employer would then claim a refund from the authorities. Unions have opposed the plan. <PERSON> Margareta </PERSON> <PERSON> Svensson </PERSON> at the blue-collar <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Confederation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unions </ORGANIZATION> said it would permit employers to put pressure on employees. `` There would be people who would not dare to be -LRB- off -RRB- ill if their employer controlled'' sick payments, she said. Since benefits are administered locally, there is no official overall picture of cheating nationwide. A random check by insurance offices in the west coast town of <LOCATION> Halmstad </LOCATION> indicated 20 percent of all sick claims were false, and the figure was 15 percent in neighboring <LOCATION> Varberg </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Svenska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dagbladet </ORGANIZATION> said. Another study reported by the <ORGANIZATION> Dagens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nyheter </ORGANIZATION> newspaper said a three-day check of claimants in the northern province of <LOCATION> Jamtland </LOCATION> showed all 180 cases were valid. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>'s report said illness claims, valid or not, varied strongly by location. The 10 districts with the highest absenteeism were low-income suburbs of <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s three largest cities. The head of the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Rinkeby </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION> suburb inhabited mostly by immigrants, topped the list, with an absentee rate almost twice as high as the national average. `` People out here have heavy, monotonous, dangerous and boring jobs,'' said <PERSON> Gun </PERSON> <PERSON> Britt </PERSON> <PERSON> Johansson </PERSON>, head of <PERSON> Rinkeby </PERSON>'s social insurance office.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Korea     02-21 0562</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Korea,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Wants Seoul To Lower Trade Barriers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will use his upcoming trip to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> to reaffirm the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commitment to that country's security while seeking improved access for American products in South Korean markets, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials say On the final leg of a trip that also will take him to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plans to spend 4 -LCB- hours in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> capital. There, he will meet with President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> Tae-woo and other officials and visit some of the more than 40,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops stationed in the country. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> departs Wednesday for <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, where he will attend Friday's funeral of Japanese Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> He will spend two nights in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> before flying to <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> on Monday. Although <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials are delighted with the political and economic development of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> in recent years, there is growing impatience over South Korean barriers to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> exports, including beef and fruit. The result is a lopsided trade imbalance in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s favor _ about $ 10 billion last year on total two-way trade of slightly more than $ 30 billion. `` <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> has free access to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> markets. <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> should now open up,'' said one <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official, who spoke on condition that he not be identified further. Another irritant in the relationship between the two countries is the large <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military presence in the capital area. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> officials have been engaged in discussions designed to ease the frictions. There is a small but determined radical movement in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, which is driven primarily by anti-Americanism. The radicals have attacked the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cultural center in <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION> several times over the past month. A principal rallying cry recently has been opposition to the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> visit. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> is a far different country today from the one which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> saw in 1982, his last visit there. The country's unpopular military dictatorship has been replaced by a democratically elected government, and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> now ranks among the world leaders in economic growth rates. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has made a major contribution to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s prosperity, accounting for 34 percent of the country's exports It is quite a change from the situation in the country during the decade after the armistice ended the Korean War in 1953, when the destitution there was such that some <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials recommended suspending all economic assistance, considering the country's future prospects to be beyond hope. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> has been playing an increasingly active role internationally, establishing trade and diplomatic ties in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and hosting the Olympic Games last September. Last fall, <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> began making peace overtures to <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and asked then-President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to complement <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s steps with gestures of his own. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> responded by liberalizing rules for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomatic contact with <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Koreans </LOCATION>, encouraging cultural exchanges between the two countries and easing restrictions on tourist travel and the export of humanitarian items to <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. A subsequent exchange of notes included a <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> proposal for formal diplomatic discussions, which the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> regarded as unacceptable because it undercut <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s position. Still, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have been encouraged by an apparent easing of tensions recently on the peninsula, an area long viewed as having the potential for an outbreak of <ORGANIZATION> East-West </ORGANIZATION> hostilities because of the major stake that both superpowers have there.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Polisario     02-21 0332</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Polisario,0344</SECOND>
<HEAD>Guerrilla Front to Meet Moroccan King for Second Time</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Polisario guerrilla front says it will hold a second round of talks next week with <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Hassan </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> to discuss extending a truce and a political solution for the disputed <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sahara </LOCATION>. Polisario leader <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdelaziz </PERSON>, speaking to a news conference Monday, also dismissed the newly declared five-nation union of north African Arab states as unviable as long as the conflict over <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sahara </LOCATION> is unresolved. `` It is like building houses on a volcano which can erupt at any time,'' <PERSON> Abdelaziz </PERSON> said, speaking through a translator. The leaders of <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mauritania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION> declared the union on Friday, but did not disclose details on how it will function. One likely result would be a suspension of aid and support by <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> for the Polisarios' 13-year war to free <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sahara </LOCATION> from Moroccan rule. <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION> annexed most of the former <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> territory in 1976. <PERSON> Abdelaziz </PERSON> said he received word Sunday that <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Hassan </PERSON> had agreed to meet a <LOCATION> Polisario </LOCATION> delegation next week, but the date and venue was not set. The king first met the Polisarios for two days in early January. The guerrillas later declared a cease-fire for February to improve the climate for the five-nation summit in <LOCATION> Marrakech </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Abdelaziz </PERSON> said. Asked if the truce could be extended, he said he hoped the meeting with <PERSON> Hassan </PERSON> `` will be an occasion to transfer the truce into a political agreement.'' He said the Polisarios would not relinquish the demand for sovereignty over all of <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sahara </LOCATION>, and rejected the idea of autonomy under a Moroccan flag. The options which should be put to the inhabitants in a referendum are `` total independence or integration into <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION>. For us, the only choice is total independence,'' he said. The Polisario delegation was in <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> as guest of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. It was to meet Prime Minister <PERSON> Ingvar </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlsson </PERSON>, opposition leaders and Swedish <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> officials.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 0022EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TrumpBashing     02-21 0923</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Trump Bashing,0946</SECOND>
<HEAD>Donald Trump _ Hero Or `Short-Fingered Vulgarian'?</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY SCHWARTZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> can buy hotels, he can buy football teams, he can buy casinos and airlines. But he ca n't buy respect. Spy magazine calls him a `` short-fingered vulgarian.'' Cartoonist <PERSON> Berke </PERSON> Breathed takes <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>'s brain and installs it in the skull of <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> the Cat, the foul feline of `` Bloom County.'' A Daily News columnist writes that when she needs cheering up, she watches `` <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> do something silly.'' The Stand Up <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> comedy club devoted a night to ridiculing <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>. For two hours, comics drew laughter with readings from `` Trump: The Art of the Deal'' and took their own potshots _ suggesting, for example, that he bought a Parisian landmark and renamed it the `` Arc de Trump.'' The 43-year-old billionaire does not believe he deserves this tidal wave of derision, which rises along with his success and prominence. But <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> _ who declined to be interviewed _ thinks he understands it. `` Those who do n't like me do n't know me, and have never met me,'' he told <ORGANIZATION> Time </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION>. `` My guess is that they dislike me out of jealousy.'' Not so, say <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>'s detractors. They dislike him on merits. `` He's just an everyday slob with too much money. He just does n't have enough taste to keep his name off of things,'' said Breathed The sequence about <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>'s transplanted cerebrum, Breathed said, is born of his conviction that <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> `` looks too smooth and polished on the outside. He should look like <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> the Cat.'' <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> is no stranger to the funny pages; he also appeared within the past year in `` Doonesbury.'' <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Trudeau </PERSON> showed <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> tossing casino chips from the deck of his 282-foot yacht, the Trump Princess, to small boats below. This obviously was not the `` quality'' image <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> wants to project. `` I did pretty well in school, but for the life of me, I really ca n't understand what ` Doonesbury' is about,'' <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> has said. He suggested <PERSON> Trudeau </PERSON>'s wife, television's <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Pauley </PERSON>, `` has a lot more talent than he does.'' Critics have found fault with <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>'s taste. When he announced last month that he intended to close that Plaza Hotel landmark of bogus Hawaiiana, Trader <PERSON> Vic </PERSON>'s _ a closing that he delayed when the threat of the bar's demise improved business _ <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> said he was doing so not because of any hostility to Samoan Fog Cutters and similar drinks, but because the bar was tacky. `` Wildly tacky,'' riposted <ORGANIZATION> Village </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> reporter <PERSON> Guy </PERSON> <PERSON> Trebay </PERSON>, `` is Trump Tower, with its mean escalators and pink marble vastness. Does <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> think a waterfall wall is the acme of subtle design?'' Critics have found fault with <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>'s ego and penchant for self-promotion. Daily News columnist <PERSON> Gail </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, writing about a new board game based on <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>'s wheeling and dealing, noted that `` Trump _ The Game'' contained `` approximately nine million photos of <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>.'' The game is meant `` for players 12 and up, and I suppose there could be worse things to give your 12-year-old than a game that encourages him to act like <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>. ` Uzi: The Crack Dealer,' for example,'' she mused. Critics have found fault with <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>'s dedication to building glitzy buildings in a city where homelessness and poverty are endemic. One group staged a brunch for the homeless this month in front of the Plaza, along with a `` public shaming'' of its owner. <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> did not attend. But the reigning champion of <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> bashers is Spy, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> satire magazine, and <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> has reacted with irritation and vitriol. In September, <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> claimed Spy was in dire straits and would be out of business within a year; now each issue contains a countdown of `` our death foretold.'' Last week, an outraged <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> claimed that the father of a Spy executive had suggested Spy would ease up on <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> if the <ORGANIZATION> Trump </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shuttle </ORGANIZATION> offered the magazine to passengers; Spy said this was a joke. The irreverent and irascible magazine is fixated on the Big T _ on the `` eerily stiff hairdo'' of <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Ivana </PERSON>; on <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> himself, who was mentioned derogatorily in all 10 issues last year and whose picture was compared in the March issue with the first police sketch of Son of <PERSON> Sam </PERSON>. Each year, Spy lists the 100 most annoying people, places and things in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. One year, <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> was No. 1; one year, he was No. 3. Last year, he was Nos. 10, 14, 21, 26 and 30, subdivided into <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>, Candidate; <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>, Acquirer; <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>, Boxing Promoter; <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>, Author, and <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>, Fixer of Things We'd Almost Rather Leave Broken. `` We do n't hate him, we despise him,'' Spy said this month. But why? `` He's ... sort of a polyester guy in a 100 percent cotton world,'' froths Editor <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Graydon </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>. `` He represents a sort of mass-market, fake sophistication. In a city that invented real sophistication, his kind is driving the real stuff out.'' <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> is just warming up. He dismisses <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> as a `` sort of show-and-tell child'' who insists on splattering his name everywhere he goes. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> knows that <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> has become a celebrity _ his face on the covers of news magazines, his book a bestseller. To some, he is a capitalist hero. `` The folks who watch motivational cable shows late at night _ to them he's a hero,'' <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said. `` To anybody who cares about <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, who does n't like brass, he's no hero.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 0056EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Kenya     02-21 0497</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Kenya,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kenyans Lobby Congress To Maintain Aid</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Kenyan diplomats are lobbying <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to block a threat by several congressmen to limit aid to <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> because of alleged human rights abuses. The effort follows some acerbic criticism by the head of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel that appropriates money for foreign aid. `` It will be a cold day in you-know-where before this committee earmarks money for <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>,'' said Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Obey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Wis </LOCATION>., at a recent hearing on human rights in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> `` Earmarking'' is a method <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> uses to guarantee that select countries receive a certain amount of foreign aid, making them immune from administration attempts to shift assistance to other priorities. The bulk of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign aid is earmarked for about 20 countries, leaving the administration little room for maneuvering with the aid. Economic aid for <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> has been earmarked for the past three years. Skillful efforts by <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> and its lobbyists last year brought the military component of the assistance under the protection of the earmark too, despite Obey's objections. <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> got $ 15 million in military aid, which accounts for about 60 percent of all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military assistance to sub-Saharan <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, and an additional $ 45 million in economic and development funds. <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> supporters in the administration and on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> cite the access granted by the strategically placed country to <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> ships at <LOCATION> Mombasa </LOCATION> and to <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> planes at its airfields as reason enough for the financial support. But since last fall, when the aid was appropriated for fiscal year 1989, several other congressmen have joined Obey, head of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations subcommittee on foreign operations, in criticizing what they view as <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>'s deteriorating human rights situation. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, a member of Obey's committee who also serves as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> caucus in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, issued a statement at the same hearing critical of <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>, which had been a `` shining star in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and a model for its neighbors over many years,'' had been turning in a different direction in recent years, resulting in an erosion of its human rights record. Specific charges against <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> by human rights groups, as well as the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s annual international human rights report, include the stifling of political opposition by banning political parties and jailing dissidents. Critics also object to recent constitutional amendments that allow President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> arap </PERSON> <PERSON> Moi </PERSON> to dismiss judges and to detain criminal suspects without trial for up to 14 days. But Kenyan Ambassador <PERSON> Denis </PERSON> <PERSON> Afande </PERSON> said critics fail to understand that <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> is acting strictly within the bounds of its own constitution and laws. `` <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> is trying very hard to respect the rule of law,'' he said in an interview. `` The criticism here is very demoralizing to my people.'' Other African nations have much worse records than <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>, he said, and many Kenyans feel their country is being picked on unfairly. `` We were very surprised by all this,'' <PERSON> Afande </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 0000EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ChemicalLeak 1stLd-Writethru a0681 02-20 0527</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Chemical Leak, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0681,0536</SECOND>
<HEAD>Homes Evacuated After Chevron Plant Chemical Leak</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Subs grafs 10-11, `He estimated ... he said' with three grafs
to UPDATE with quotes, evacuation to continue until at least 7 a.m.; picks
up 12th graf pvs: `At least ... '</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PORT ARTHUR, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As many as 7,000 people were evacuated from their homes Monday after a leaking crude oil tank at a <ORGANIZATION> Chevron </ORGANIZATION> plant created a noxious cloud of gas with traces of hydrogen sulfide, officials said. More than 20 people were treated and released at hospitals for minor reactions to the fumes, most for fume inhalation, officials said. <ORGANIZATION> Chevron </ORGANIZATION> officials said they were monitoring air quality in the area of the leak since it was discovered in the early afternoon, and described the gaseous release as a miminum health hazard that created a terrible odor. `` Most crude oils in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> have sulphur in them, and that means their gas containes hydrogen sulfide, which is listed as one of the hazardous chemicals,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Chevron </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON>. Hydrogen sulfide is a flammable, poisonous gas with a characteristic odor of rotten eggs. `` We're doing continuous monitoring and we're finding that there's nothing there that is hazardous to health and we're also finding that the hydrocarbon smell in the air is lessening,'' <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> said. `` But the odor got so strong that the city emergency response unit decided to go ahead and evacuate people downwind of it,'' he said. Authorities described the evacuation as the largest in recent years in this coastal city, a heavily industrial area near the <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> border. `` We've had some real bad fires at these plants where people were injured and killed, but even then we never had an evacuation of this magnitude and I've been here 28 years,'' said <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arthur </LOCATION> police Sgt. <PERSON> Cedric </PERSON> <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON>. Sgt. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON> estimated late Monday that 5,000 to 7,000 people were evacuated from a densely populated 14 - by 17-block area on <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arthur </LOCATION>'s west side About 3,000 people were being housed at three schools that were opened as emergency shelters, he said. Officials decided after a late meeting with <ORGANIZATION> Chevron </ORGANIZATION> officials that the evacuation would continue until at least 7 a.m. Tuesday, <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON> said. `` It appears the spill is under control, but the odor is still present and we're going to keep it evacuated until then,'' he said, adding that <ORGANIZATION> Chevron </ORGANIZATION> tests show a mimimal amount of hydrogen sulfide is present. At least 24 people were examined at local hospitals as a result of the leak, officials said. `` As far as I'm aware, plans are just to treat and release them,'' said Doctors Hospital spokesman <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bleyhl </PERSON>. `` Nobody suffered anything really bad.'' A <ORGANIZATION> Chevron </ORGANIZATION> employee discovered the leak around 1:30 p.m. Monday, officials said. The leaking tank has a capacity of about 300,000 gallons, but its exact content was not known because it was connected to an automatic pump that fed into a refining unit, <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> said. Crews were using vacuum trucks Monday evening to remove the spilled crude from a ditch surrounding the tank, but <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> estimated the task could take two or three days to complete.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF---Canada-Mine     02-21 0132</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF---Canada-Mine,0137</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gold Mine Cave-In Kills Three</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TIMMINS, Ontario (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A cave-in in a gold mine shaft killed three miners in this northeastern <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION> city, the mine manager said. The three bodies were brought up from a depth of 1,200 feet about five hours after Monday's accident, said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Perry </PERSON>, general manager of the Placer Dome mine near the <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> border. One member of a four-man mining crew, who was above ground when the cave-in occurred, had reported his fellow miners missing, <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> said. Union and mine officials said they would conduct separate investigations into the cause of the cave-in. It was the second fatal accident in a year at the mine, which began operating in 1910. A worker was killed in May when he fell down an ore chute.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890221-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-21-89 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TobaccoPapers     02-21 0701</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tobacco Papers,0717</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tobacco Research Secret Since 1950s Released</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN GALVIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
