<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 2326EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Nicaragua-US 1stLd-Writethru a0785 06-22 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua-US, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0785,0627</SECOND>
<HEAD>Precede: CARACAS</HEAD>
<HEAD>Cardinal Drops Out of Mediation Effort Between Nicaragua and U.S.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: LEADS throughout to UPDATE with cardinal unable to arrange
US-Sandinista talks; opposition asking cardinal for help. No pickup. Changes
byline. ^By FILADELFO ALEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cardinal <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> y <PERSON> Bravo </PERSON> said Thursday he was unable to set up conciliation talks between <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, as requested by President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>. Also Thursday, Foreign Minister <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Escoto </PERSON> accused the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government of spreading `` systematic lies'' to discredit <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and its preparations for free elections in 1990. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> publicly asked <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> y Bravo, the Roman Catholic Archbishop of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>, on Monday to act as a go-between in setting up the talks with the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration resolve its differences with <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist Sandinista regime. The cardinal said he would think about it, but <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Rudi </PERSON> <PERSON> Boone </PERSON> on Tuesday rejected the offer. He said an improvement in relations would depend on a number of factors, including `` an end to Nicaraguan support'' for leftist guerrillas in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Boone </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, also said <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> should hold free and fair elections under international supervision and enter into of a genuine dialogue with opposition groups before the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agrees to sit down and talk. Referring to <PERSON> Boone </PERSON>'s statement, <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> <PERSON> y </PERSON> <PERSON> Bravo </PERSON> wrote <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> saying that `` for the time being it is not possible to enter into a process of mediation ... because one of the parties has officially set conditions for the dialogue.'' <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> read the <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> y <PERSON> Bravo </PERSON>'s letter at a news conference, expressed thanks to the cardinal, and said he will `` insist through other venues with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government and President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to accept a dialogue with <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> cut off all aid to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> in 1980, started supporting Contra rebels the next year and slapped an economic embargo on this nation in 1985 to pressure the Sandinistas to hold free and fair elections and sever military ties with Soviet bloc nations. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> administrations have argued that Soviet and <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> military aid to the <LOCATION> Sandinistas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s help to the Salvadoran guerrillas is threatening security in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The Sandinistas claim they have been providing only moral support to the Salvadoran rebels. An attempt by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> to hold talks in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> in 1984 ended in deadlock, with the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration accusing the Sandinistas of failing to negotiate in good faith. The 14-party <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opposition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday asked <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> y Bravo to try and set up talks with the Sandinista government to try and resolve these differences. But the cardinal, himself a sharp critic of the Sandinistas, did not respond immediately. Earlier Thursday, Foreign Minister <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Escoto </PERSON> accused the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration of spreading `` systematic lies'' to discredit <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and denied allegations by Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> that <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> is allying itself with <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> to form a three way anti-U.S. alliance. Speaking in <LOCATION> Caracas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>, where he was attending a Third World meeting, <PERSON> D'Escoto </PERSON> said: `` I would take anything a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government official says with a ton of salt. Systematic lying is an instrument of their foreign policy. The only thing he -LRB- <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> -RRB- needs for his opinions is his mouth.'' <PERSON> D'Escoto </PERSON> also denied recent allegations by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> about <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s election procedures and said the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> were `` strictly complying with the agenda for the elections in February 1990. Critics have said the government stacked a national election board, which will supervise the balloting process, in favor of the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>. Also, as of June 1 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens were required for the first time to get visas to enter <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, making it difficult for American observers to be there.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 2329EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-India-Pilots     06-22 0297</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-India-Pilots,0307</SECOND>
<HEAD>Indian Authorities Interrogating U.S., German Pilots</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities are interrogating two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and two West German pilots after Indian air force fighters forced down their small planes near the Pakistani border, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> identified the Americans as <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Haile </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 57, of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilmore </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Rocksprings </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The two, making an around-the-world trip in a Beechcraft Bonanza, were intercepted by the Indian jets on June 16 and forced to land at <LOCATION> Bhuj </LOCATION> airfield in western <LOCATION> Gujarat </LOCATION> state, a <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said. The spokesman, who can not be identified under briefing rules, said the two men were traveling with two West Germans, whose Beechcraft also was ordered to land at <LOCATION> Bhuj </LOCATION>, about 500 miles southwest of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>. A West German Embassy official, speaking on condition of anonymity, identified the Germans pilots with only their last names as <PERSON> Kuhlmann </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kuffner </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said the planes had strayed about 310 miles off the assigned course and intruded into restricted airspace over <LOCATION> Bhuj </LOCATION>, a marshy wasteland near the border with <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. Civil aviation authorities cleared the planes to fly from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION> via <LOCATION> Bombay </LOCATION>, he said. The pilots were first questioned by air force officers and later handed over to federal intelligence officers, he said. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> offical said a consular officer attended the interrogation. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Privacy Act prevented disclosing more information about the pilots, said the official who can not be identified under briefing rules. Haile and <PERSON> Gilmore </PERSON> departed from the suburban <PERSON> Addison </PERSON> airport in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> three weeks ago. Haile, the owner and president of a Dallas-based engineering firm, has flown around the world twice and is an experienced long-distance pilot, according to his wife, <PERSON> Joan </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 2345EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HUDProbe-Austin 1stLd-Writethru a0732 06-22 0659</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-HUD Probe-Austin, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0732,0675</SECOND>
<HEAD>HUD Looking Into Apparent Diversions in Austin Project</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 5 grafs after 6th graf, `Lee refused...,' to UPDATE
with developments in Indianapolis. Picks up 7th graf, `Last week...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AUSTIN, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal investigators are looking into the apparent diversion of up to $ 90,000 in housing funds intended for poor families living in federally subsidized apartments here, it was reported Thursday. The money was supposed to cover rent and utility bills in 1986 to early 1988 for five families who lived in the housing complexes known as <ORGANIZATION> Interregional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Apartments </ORGANIZATION>, the Austin American-Statesman said. The 99 apartments were shut down by the city in September because of building code violations. `` It may be a while before we can get to it, but it is scheduled for investigation,'' said <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, the Housing and Urban Development regional inspector general in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>. `` Right now, it's waiting in line with a lot of other cases,'' <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> said. `` It's a question of time and manpower.'' <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> refused to say who might have diverted the funds, saying it's their policy not to comment on ongoing investigations In another development, <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> officials in <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> said Thursday that almost a third of the $ 257,012 that federal auditors said might be missing from the agency's office here has been found. Payments have been received or documentation found for $ 80,046.95 from the sale of five foreclosed homes during a 4 -LCB- - year period, said <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Shelley </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Indianapolis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> office In a June 13 report, federal auditors identified 16 <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> transactions for which the agency had n't received payment. Auditors said the proceeds, plus $ 30,486 in damages, should be paid to the government. Authorities and <ORGANIZATION> Indianapolis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Realty </ORGANIZATION>, which handled closings on the sales, are looking for documentation of the remaining 11 transactions, which brought $ 176,965.50, officials said. If the transfer of the money ca n't be documented, <PERSON> Shelley </PERSON> said, the government stands to get its money either from <ORGANIZATION> Indianapolis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Realty </ORGANIZATION> or its bonding company. Last week, a private escrow agent from <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> nicknamed `` <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> HUD'' told <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> she diverted millions of dollars from government housing programs. The agent, <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrell </PERSON>, admitted to investigators that she did not forward at least $ 5.5 million to the federal housing agency, saying she donated much of the money to charitable projects to provide housing for the poor. In <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>, the principal owner of the <ORGANIZATION> Interregional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Apartments </ORGANIZATION> is <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> investor <PERSON> Benard </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lifshutz </PERSON>, who said he was aware that some subsidies were taken but he was not involved. Another partner in the project, listed in city records as <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> McGinnis </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>, could not be located, the newspaper said. <PERSON> Lifshutz </PERSON> said he and <PERSON> McGinnis </PERSON> are no longer business partners and he had not spoken to <PERSON> McGinnis </PERSON> in months. According to a letter from the city to the <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> inspector general, the apparent diversion of federal utility subsidies took place between August 1986 and February 1988. Former acting City Manager <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ware </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> members in a memo last year that the exact amount of money taken was hard to determine because the owners' records for those years `` are virtually non-existent.'' City staff at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, which administers the federally subsidized housing program, said they believe the amount was $ 80,000 to $ 90,000. The department staff first learned of the problem when Interregional tenants complained that their electric, gas, and water services were being disconnected. City records show that dozens of the apartments were overrun with rats and cockroaches; contained exposed and damaged plumbing and wiring; had holes in some of the floors and ceilings; and could not meet minimal city building and safety codes. Police records also show that by 1986 the apartment complexes had become a center of criminal activity, including prostitution and drug dealing. At one point, police records show, one tenant at <ORGANIZATION> Interregional </ORGANIZATION> offered `` drive-up curb service,'' making drug deals through an apartment window.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 2345EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BoyingtonBust     06-22 0247</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Boyington Bust,0252</SECOND>
<HEAD>Monument Dedicated to War Ace `Pappy' Boyington</HEAD>
<DATELINE>YUMA, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Military officials and former comrades of Col. <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> `` Pappy'' <PERSON> Boyington </PERSON> dedicated a life-size bust Thursday at the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Station </ORGANIZATION> here to honor the late World War II ace. <PERSON> Boyington </PERSON>'s widow, <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and son, <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, attended the ceremonies at the base, the home of VMA-214, the <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheep </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Squadron </ORGANIZATION>. The nickname for the group originated around the idea that members of the squadron, formed in the <LOCATION> Solomon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> in 1942, were misfits. <PERSON> Boyington </PERSON> shot down 28 aircraft while fighting in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Theater </LOCATION>, and his squadron accounted for a total of 197 Japanese planes. Shot down Jan. 3, 1944, over <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Boyington </PERSON> spent the rest of the war in a prisoner-of-war camp in <LOCATION> Omori </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. He was mistakenly presumed dead during the war and awarded the Medal of Honor _ the nation's highest decoration for military valor _ posthumously. <PERSON> Boyington </PERSON> died Jan. 11, 1988. The bust was the idea of his longtime friend, <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> `` Hap'' <PERSON> Halloran </PERSON>, who said attending <PERSON> Boyington </PERSON>'s funeral at <ORGANIZATION> Arlington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cemetery </ORGANIZATION> gave him the desire to do something special to commemorate his friend. <PERSON> Halloran </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> fighter pilot, was shot down over the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> in January 1945 and met <PERSON> Boyington </PERSON> in a prisoner-of-war camp. `` To see him in real life was a comforting thing. I know probably nothing would happen to us'' because <PERSON> Boyington </PERSON> was there, <PERSON> Halloran </PERSON> said at the ceremonies.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 2348EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PlaneFatal     06-22 0171</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Plane Fatal,0176</SECOND>
<HEAD>California Plane Crash Kills Three</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTA CLARITA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A single-engine plane that snagged a wire above a 500,000-volt power line crashed Thursday afternoon, killing three people and injuring a fourth. The pilot of the French-made TB-21 <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> reported engine trouble shortly before the 2:13 p.m. crash near <LOCATION> Placerita </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canyon </LOCATION> about 30 miles northwest of downtown <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> said. The survivor, a teen-age girl, was in critical condition at <ORGANIZATION> Henry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mayo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newhall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Valencia </LOCATION>, said hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Ingram </PERSON>. The pilot and two other passengers were killed. None of the victims' names was immediately released. The four-seat plane hit a static wire, which protects the power line from lightning, said <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Fraudenburg </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION>. The plane missed the power line itself, which carries enough electricity for the needs of 3 million people, <PERSON> Fraudenburg </PERSON> said. DWP crews were assessing the damage to determine if the cable needs to be replaced, <PERSON> Fraudenburg </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 2348EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-LaRouche-Congress     06-22 0293</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-LaRouche-Congress,290</SECOND>
<HEAD>LaRouche Announces Plans to Run for Congress</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALEXANDRIA, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Convicted felon and four-time presidential candidate <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> announced plans Thursday to run for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> next year. <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, 65, a <LOCATION> Loudoun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> resident, wants to represent <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s 10th District, which includes <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, half of <LOCATION> Fairfax </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Loudoun </LOCATION> counties. After filing his intent to run for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> with the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on June 8, <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> became the first Democrat to announce plans to go after incumbent <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> representative <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON>'s seat. <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> was convicted in January in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION> on charges of mail fraud, conspiracy to commit mail fraud and conspiracy to defraud the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. He was sentenced to 15 years and is appealing the conviction. He ran for president as an independent in 1976 and as a Democrat in 1980, 1984 and 1988. Asked whether he could serve his constituents well from jail, <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> said `` I think this is a very turbulent period of history. I could pop out of prison just as quick as I popped in.'' <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> has maintained since his conviction that his trial was political. <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> and his associates were convicted for a scheme in which they used a fundraising operation to solicit `` loans'' from people that they did n't pay back. They failed to report the transactions to the government. As a convicted felon <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> wo n't be eligible to vote for himself, but he does meet constitutional requirements to run for the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitz-Hugh </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elections </ORGANIZATION> secretary. <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> is over 25, has been a <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> citizen for more than seven years and is an inhabitant of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. He and five associates are at the <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION> jail awaiting assignments to federal prisons.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Porn-Eviction     06-22 0241</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Porn-Eviction,0248</SECOND>
<HEAD>City Buys Adult Book Store Lot to Evict It</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DELRAY BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The city has purchased the ground under an adult book store and plans to evict the business when the lease expires next month. The $ 257,400 purchase capped a drive by residents and other business owners in the area to shut down <LOCATION> Delray </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Book </LOCATION> and Video, which they complained sported racks of nudie magazines and sexually oriented videos. The <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> in this oceanside town midway between <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> finally agreed to buy the property, and City Attorney <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Thiele </PERSON> announced completion of the sale Tuesday. The store's lease expires at midnight July 31. <PERSON> Thiele </PERSON> said he would not waste any time in shutting down the business. `` It is my intention to put chains and a padlock on the doors at 12:01 a.m. August first,'' <PERSON> Thiele </PERSON> said. The city plans to resell the property as soon as possible, placing a deed restriction on it that would prevent another adult entertainment establishment from moving there. Before the city sells the property, however, officials want to annex the unincorporated land into the city, Commissioner <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarty </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Manya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which owns the bookstore, said he did not want to talk about the city's plans or any legal action the company might take. `` What's done is done,'' <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON> said. `` If the city wants to buy -LRB- the property -RRB-, that's their mistake.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 0551EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--SurfboardArrest     06-22 0147</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Surfboard Arrest,0154</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cop Borrows Surfboard to Arrest Car Thief Suspect</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COCOA BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A detective hopped on a surfboard to reach a car thief who had jumped into the ocean while fleeing police, authorities said. The man ran away after he was stopped for speeding Tuesday, said Sgt. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Granger </PERSON>. He resurfaced and eluded police twice on foot before being spotted swimming in the ocean behind a hotel. After he ignored officers' orders to come ashore, plainclothes detective Lt. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Muldoon </PERSON> borrowed a surfboard and went after him. A 41-foot <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> utility boat fished the two from the surf about 150 yards offshore and took them to Port Canaveral. Police then delivered the man to the <ORGANIZATION> Brevard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Sharpes </LOCATION>. The man, who has refused to identify himself, has been charged with resisting arrest and auto theft, authorities said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RanchoSeco     06-22 0266</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rancho Seco,0274</SECOND>
<HEAD>Utility Votes to Take Private Bids to Restart Nuke Power Plant</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SACRAMENTO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The operator of the <LOCATION> Rancho </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Seco </LOCATION> nuclear power plant has decided to accept bids for a private takeover of the facility, despite a referendum that called for its shutdown. The 3-2 vote by directors of the <ORGANIZATION> Sacramento </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Municipal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Utility </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday angered many of the activists who have fought for years to shut down the plant, which has nearly a continuous history of operating problems. On March 2, the directors had voted unanimously to abide by the results of the June 6 referendum, in which voters turned down an advisory measure endorsing the <ORGANIZATION> Sacramento </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Municipal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Utility </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION>'s plans to keep the plant running. The plant was taken off line June 7 and so far about 400 contract workers have lost their jobs. Utility directors voting with the majority argued that voters merely had forbidden <ORGANIZATION> SMUD </ORGANIZATION> from operating the plant. Divestiture of Rancho Seco `` remains a viable option ... that could free this community from the staggering costs of decommissioning,'' said <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Buonaiuto </PERSON>, president of the utility's board of directors The utility estimates it will cost about $ 200 million to close the plant. Sacramentans for Safe Energy, an anti-Rancho Seco group, has said it will sue to stop efforts to transfer <LOCATION> Rancho </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Seco </LOCATION> to private businesses that might continue to operate it. `` We will wait and see what happens in the 10-day period'' that the utility set to accept bids, said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Remy </PERSON>, an environmental attorney affiliated with the group. `` Our position still is that enough is enough.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SedenoAppointment     06-22 0097</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sedeno Appointment,0099</SECOND>
<HEAD>New AP Correspondent Named for San Diego</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN DIEGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Sedeno </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> correspondent in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, for three years, has been named correspondent in charge of the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> bureau. The appointment was announced Wednesday by <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Chief of Bureau <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lippman </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sedeno </PERSON>, 27, joined the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> in 1984 and became <LOCATION> Harlingen </LOCATION> correspondent the following year. He is a native of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angelo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, and a graduate of <ORGANIZATION> Angelo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Sedeno </PERSON> was a copy editor for the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angelo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Standard-Times </LOCATION> before joining the AP.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Heat     06-22 0560</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Heat,0583</SECOND>
<HEAD>Weather Warm Again _ Britons Try to Cope</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GRAHAM HEATHCOTE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Parasols have been placed over tropical orchids, swamp crayfish have crawled out of a canal, and race goers have collapsed with sunstroke at <LOCATION> Royal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ascot </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> is in the midst of a heat wave and Britons _ notorious for never being accustomed to coping with an occasional hot summer or cold winter _ are doing the best they can. The heat since mid-May has pushed up demand for water in many areas by 50 percent. In parts of <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION> and along the Welsh border in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, many homes are without water main supplies. `` Even if this dry spell breaks, it is unlikely to help,'' said spokesman <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Derwent </PERSON> of Southern Water. He said water reserves were at near-crisis levels before the heat wave because of a mild winter and the longest spring in memory. As of today, people who use sprinklers or hoses to water their gardens or wash their cars are threatened with a $ 620 fine by the <ORGANIZATION> Lee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which supplies parts of north <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. Bans on such use were already in force in other parts of the country. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Valley </PERSON> said Wednesday it was sending out patrols and hiring extra staff to look for violators because demand by its customers has risen from 60 million gallons a day to 85 million gallons. The tough measures followed weeks of television advertising by the publicly run water boards seeking to attract potential investors prior to privatization. Now that the heat's on, they are running out of water. One town actually ran out. Tankers had to deliver water to <LOCATION> Nelson </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Lancashire </LOCATION>, where officials blamed the drying-up mostly on avid gardeners leaving hoses spouting all night. Quirks of the heat ranged from officers at <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Heathrow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> firing pistols to drive off flocks of swifts attracted by swarms of insects, and trout dying at a fish farm in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yorkshire </LOCATION> when their pond dried up. Human casualties resulted, too. Thirteen people drowned last weekend trying to cool off in lakes, rivers, canals and pools. When the Royal Ascot race meeting opened Tuesday, ambulance workers said they treated more than 50 people for mild sunstroke or fainting, reviving them with orange juice and ice cubes. The weather was a degree or two cooler Wednesday after temperatures in southern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> hit 88 degrees on Tuesday, the hottest June day in 13 years. It was already almost as hot in May, when orchids at the Chelsea Flower Show were shielded with umbrellas so they would n't wilt. Hundreds of creatures hitherto unknown to Londoners crawled out of the <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> in the capital's <LOCATION> Kensal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION> district. They were identified as Central European swamp crayfish, seven inches long, all waving legs, claws and whiskers. No one knew how the mud bugs got there, but <PERSON> London </PERSON> <PERSON> Zoo </PERSON> said they must have bred in large numbers as a result of unusually high temperatures. Borough authorities in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> appealed to householders to take a bucket of water a day to young trees in the streets facing `` water starvation.'' The trees were planted after a hurricane in 1987 felled an estimated 15 million trees in southern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> said Tuesday that pests like aphids threatened to reach `` epidemic levels'' in gardens and on farms.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-EastBlocQuarrels Bjt   06-22 0890</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-East Bloc Quarrels, Bjt,0916</SECOND>
<HEAD>Historical Rivalries Reappear Among East Bloc Neighbors</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALISON SMALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Almost every day, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s state-run media carry a new report about privation in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> or a purported shooting on the heavily guarded border between the two countries. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> are allies in the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact military alliance, but not even a summit of their Communist leaders last August could ease the tensions between them. Their relations illustrate the depth of many historically rooted quarrels now reappearing in the Soviet bloc that includes <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION>. For centuries, <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> has been a volatile region of shifting political allegiances and changing borders. A violent history has made nationalism a powerful force and left many ethnic groups in the area with a long list of grudges against neighbors. World War I broke up the once vast Austro-Hungarian Empire and World War II left the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> dominant in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Authoritarian Communist governments took power after the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> swept in and ended <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s reign. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, following the model laid down by <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>, used to exert pressure on East European Communist parties to maintain outwardly friendly relations. With <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> as <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leader, those pressures eased. Until recently, traditional conflicts among ethnic groups with different languages and cultures lay mostly dormant under slogans trumpeting the international solidarity of socialism. Now, the Soviets are preoccupied with their own economic and social woes, and the ethnic tensions are bubbling across the borders. The East European allies, grappling with Kremlin-led calls for democratic reforms, are reopening old wounds. Current quarrels vary from ideological differences over the pace of governmental reforms in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and other countries to territorial disputes, minority rights and even cross-border pollution. <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> have argued over their common border and fishing rights in the <LOCATION> Baltic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> has angered <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION> by sending chemical waste wafting across the <LOCATION> Danube </LOCATION>; and customs wars have flared in a region strapped for consumer goods. In November, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> annoyed the entire bloc by slapping restrictions at 48 hours' notice on the export of just about every consumer product Soviet bloc visitors might envy in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>'s relatively well-stocked shops Poles were especially outraged by measures that included confiscation of purchases intended as Christmas gifts. Polish travelers felt that the Czechs were deliberately reviving a historical enmity between the two populations. The customs crackdown was designed to protect living standards that have helped <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>'s hard-line leaders keep outward peace with a population disgruntled ever since the 1968 <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION> invasion crushed <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON>'s reformist government. But the action immediately touched off retaliations throughout the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc. Each country, including the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, slapped export bans on any consumer goods popular with tourists from elsewhere in the region. That conflict has since died down. The most serious dispute involves <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>. Simmering throughout the 1970s, it broke into the open in late 1986 over the seemingly innocuous issue of a Hungarian history book on <LOCATION> Transylvania </LOCATION>, a mountainous region ruled by <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> for centuries but ceded to <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> after World War I. Under President <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> is trying to eradicate the separate identity of ethnic minorities, and it immediately accused <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> of publishing the history with the aim of reviving claims to <LOCATION> Transylvania </LOCATION>. At first, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> played calm on the diplomatic front, while media and intellectuals whipped up emotions at home. Hungarians have given refuge to tens of thousands of Romanians since January 1988, when <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> broke a Hungarian-Romanian treaty obliging it to send back defectors, some of whom braved border gunfire to escape. Besides playing to proudly nationalist Hungarians, <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION>'s handling of the dispute served to underline <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s reformist politics and to ally it with the West at international forums on human and minority rights Other East bloc neighbors have since begun to take more heed of the sizeable Hungarian minorities left in their territories. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> recently improved educational opportunities for its small Hungarian minority and allowed more visits across the common frontier. <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s 900,000 ethnic Hungarians have also received better treatment. These improvements were overshadowed, however, by <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>'s quarrels with <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> over a Hungarian television interview with <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION>'s suspension of work on a joint dam and power project. Police crackdowns on anti-government protests in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> in January and the subsequent jailing of leading dissident author <PERSON> Vaclav </PERSON> <PERSON> Havel </PERSON> drew public protests from intellectuals in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, where Prime Minister <PERSON> Mieczyslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Rakowski </PERSON> pointedly attended two <PERSON> Havel </PERSON> plays banned in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>. A Hungarian TV interview with <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON>, virtually a non-person in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> since he was expelled from the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in 1970, further rankled <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s leaders. <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> ignored their protests and broadcast a second part of the interview anyway. Tension increased last month when <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> called a two-month halt to its work on a joint <LOCATION> Danube </LOCATION> dam project that has been a subject of an environmental controversy since its inception in 1977. <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> again strongly protested the move. This time, however, it seemed as if an East bloc row might lead to domestic protests. When prime ministers <PERSON> Miklos </PERSON> <PERSON> Nemeth </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Ladislav </PERSON> <PERSON> Adamec </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> met to discuss the power project, <PERSON> Adamec </PERSON> took a conciliatory tone in an effort to defuse tensions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MassachusettsDeportation     06-22 0273</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Massachusetts Deportation,0281</SECOND>
<HEAD>Massachusetts, Federal Officials Agree on Plan to Deport 1,000 Illegal
Aliens</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DIAMOND</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A policy reversal by Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has led state and federal officials to agree on a plan to deport about 1,000 illegal aliens held in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> prisons. In 1985, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> issued an executive order forbidding state investigators from working on deportation cases unless ordered to do so by a court. That order was portrayed as gesture of good will toward illegals at a time when the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration was cracking down. Under the new policy agreed to Tuesday, the state will work with <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> officials to identify and deport inmates of the crowded state and county prison system who are in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> illegally. When possible, the state will work `` aggressively to get these people out on the next plane,'' said Human Services Secretary <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, who oversees <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>' correction system. Regional <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> director <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Cobb </PERSON>, who met Tuesday with <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> to work out the plan's details and has criticized <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' order, called the agreement `` a step in the right direction.'' About 1,300, or 10 percent, of the approximately 13,000 inmates in state prisons are illegal aliens, according to <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>. Of the 1,300, about 1,000 are eligible for immediate deportation. Most of the inmates involved have been involved in drug dealing, and come from <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, according to <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>. Some convicted of particularly violent crimes, including four men serving sentences for the rape at <ORGANIZATION> Big </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dan </ORGANIZATION>'s tavern in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION> in 1984, will remain in prison, <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 0040EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:AnneFrank     06-22 1134</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Anne Frank,1165</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anne Frank Anniversary Commemorated in New Book</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` Am I only fourteen? Am I really still a silly little schoolgirl? Am I really so inexperienced about everything? I have more experience than most; I have been through things that hardly anyone of age has undergone.'' _ <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, April 28, 1944.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By HILLEL ITALIE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> turned 13 on June 12, 1942. She received a blue blouse, roses, a bottle of slightly fermented grape juice, a party game, a plant, a dish of sticky molasses, a bowl of truffles and a homemade strawberry tart. She was also given a squarish book, commonly used to collect autographs, with a red and white checked cover. <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> began keeping a diary. What began as an adolescent's longing for self-knowledge evolved into a lasting document about the destruction of human life, the tragic loss of innocence and unfathomable hatred of the Holocaust. Forced into hiding by the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> chronicled her days with uncommon humor, perceptiveness and faith in the goodness of people. `` The Diary of <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'' stands as a moving, tangible document, and has sold millions of copies around the world. <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> died at the <LOCATION> Bergen-Belsen </LOCATION> concentration camp in 1945, and would have been 60 this year. A critical edition of her diary has been released in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> by <PERSON> Doubleday </PERSON>. A popular student at a Jewish school in <LOCATION> Amsterdam </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> was a pretty, dark-haired girl, outspoken in class and admired by many boys. Yet the diary would prove to be her most cherished friend.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 `` I have darling parents and a sister -LRB- <PERSON> Margot </PERSON> -RRB- of 16. I know about 30 people whom one might call friends _ I have strings of boy friends, anxious to catch a glimpse of me and who, failing that, peep at me through mirrors in class. I have relations, aunts ad uncles, who are darlings too, a good home, no _ I do n't seem to lack anything. `` But it's the same with all my friends, just fun and joking, nothing more. ... We do n't seem to be able to get any closer... Perhaps I lack confidence, but anyway, there it is, a stubborn fact and I do n't seem to be able to do anything about it.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 While hiding from the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> was transformed from a playful girl of 13 to an insightful, compassionate, even spiritual 15-year-old. On Jan. 6, 1944, she recalled a dream about a boy from school: `` I awoke at this point, while I could still feel his cheek against mine and felt his brown eyes looking deep into my heart, so deep, that here he read how much I loved him and how much I still love him. Tears sprang into my eyes once more, and I was very sad that I had lost him again. ...'' In another dream, she saw her late grandmother and a friend from school. `` ... Granny appeared as a guardian angel; then followed <PERSON> Hanneli </PERSON>, who seems to be a symbol to me of all the sufferings of all my girlfriends and all Jews. When I pray for her, I pray for all Jews and all those in need. ...'' Prepared by the <ORGANIZATION> Netherlands </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> for War Documentation, the book includes essays on the Franks before and after they went into hiding, the events surrounding their capture, and how the diary reached publication. The new edition contains three versions of the diary: <PERSON> Anne </PERSON>'s first and second drafts, and the original published work, which combines the two But commemorating her birth was not the only reason for the reissue. The book also offers a strong rebuttal to accusations made over the years that the diary was fake, a shameless exploitation. In the late 1950s, right-wing newspapers in <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> published attacks on the diary, insisting the ideas expressed were far too sophisticated for a teen-age girl. In the mid -'70s, a German publishing house began distributing pamphlets repeating charges that <PERSON> Otto </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, <PERSON> Anne </PERSON>'s father, had written the diary with the help of a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Upon <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s death in 1980, the original manuscripts were turned over to the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> war documentation institute; work on the critical edition began the following year. One of the book's editors, <PERSON> Gerrold </PERSON> <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> der </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroom </PERSON>, insisted in a recent interview that the diary is indeed authentic `` We asked the Dutch forensic laboratory of the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>, which does the same work for police, to check the paper and ink. They found that all the paper and all the ink, were very common for the first half of the 1940s,'' he said. `` They also compared the letters before the war, postcards, etc., that she had written to her grandmother in <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>, with the handwriting in the diaries. They found that the same person wrote everything.'' The <PERSON> Franks </PERSON> lived in <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, until 1933 when they emigrated to <LOCATION> Amsterdam </LOCATION> after <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> took power. The Nazis occupied the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> in 1940, and began imposing ever harsher anti-Jewish laws, forcing Jews to wear a yellow six-pointed star. When the SS, the Nazi military police, issued a call-up notice to <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> in July 1942, the family was forced into hiding. For more than two years, the <PERSON> Franks </PERSON> and four others were holed up in a `` Secret Annexe,'' located upstairs from <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s warehouse in <LOCATION> Amsterdam </LOCATION>. They relied on friends, notably <PERSON> Miep </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Gies </PERSON>, to bring them food and supplies, and prayed that the Allied troops would liberate their country before the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> could find them. Police raided the annex on Aug. 4, 1944, and the prisoners were sent off to <LOCATION> Westerbork </LOCATION>, a Jewish transit camp. <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> and her sister, <PERSON> Margot </PERSON>, were later shipped to the notorious death camp, <LOCATION> Auschwitz </LOCATION>, and eventually to <LOCATION> Bergen-Belsen </LOCATION>, where they contracted typhoid fever and perished within days of each other in the winter of 1945. Their mother died at another camp. After the arrest, <PERSON> Miep </PERSON> <PERSON> Gies </PERSON> gathered up <PERSON> Anne </PERSON>'s papers and kept them under lock and key. When <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> returned to <LOCATION> Amsterdam </LOCATION> in June 1945, he headed straight for the Gies home and was presented with his daughter's journals.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 `` I see the eight of us with our ` Secret Annexe' as if we were a little piece of blue heaven, surrounded by heavy black rain clouds,'' <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> wrote on Nov. 8, 1943. `` The round, clearly defined spot where we stand is safe, but the clouds gather more closely about us and the circle which separates us from the approaching danger closes more and more tightly.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 In 1947, a Dutch edition of the diary was published to overwhelming acclaim. The book has since been printed in more than 30 countries, including <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iceland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Timber-Economics     06-22 1491</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Timber-Economics,1525</SECOND>
<HEAD>Northwest's Timber Jobs Declining In Changing Economy</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARNARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GRANTS PASS, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When GIs came home after World War II, the nation looked to the great forests of the <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> for lumber to build their houses. <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> mills responded, and still supply more than a third of the lumber and plywood used in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` There was always that one more shining hill covered with trees to the west,'' said <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> budget officer <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>. `` Now we find there's a <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> and we fell into it.'' From the western slope of the Cascade Range to the shore of the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>, this is the home of the Douglas fir, the towering king of the ancient forests whose structural strength tops all other lumber. It is also home to the Northern spotted owl, a 14-inch bird that could face extinction because, with rare exceptions, it wo n't nest or hunt anywhere but the dwindling virgin forests that are most prized for timber. While logs are tied up in the legal battle over how much of the national forests can be cut without killing off the spotted owl, record amounts of raw timber grown on private and state land are being shipped for premium prices to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> without ever seeing the inside of an American mill. `` If a log is of export quality, and is available to be exported, it will be exported,'' said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Mayr </PERSON>, owner of the <ORGANIZATION> Mayr </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> mill in <LOCATION> Hoquiam </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mayr </PERSON> has been reduced to counting his supply in months instead of years while watching a stream of logs being loaded onto ships in <LOCATION> Grays </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION> `` We want to put out logs to the highest value market In recent years the highest value has been offshore,'' said <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, operations manager for <ORGANIZATION> Weyerhaeuser </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Coos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, where the region's leading exporter of raw logs has started a new mill to produce metric-dimension lumber for the Japanese home-building market Companies can generally get 25 percent more for export logs than they can in the domestic market, said <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> economist <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Flora </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. Boom-and-bust cycles were known to the timber industry before the spotted owl entered the spotlight, but for the first time the pinch is from a shortage of logs rather than rising mortgage rates and dips in the housing market. Eighteen years ago, <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Wentworth </PERSON> stopped off in the coastal town of <LOCATION> Gold </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> to see some friends on his way to college to study forest management. Now he's 37, a husband and father, and one of the 300 workers at Gold Beach Plywood who will be out of a job this summer when the mill shuts down. `` I got sucked into the mill because it was such good wages,'' <PERSON> Wentworth </PERSON> said. `` I kick myself in the butt now.'' Thirteen other wood products mills in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> have closed this year, putting nearly 2,000 people out of work as the industry enters a new era of high-priced timber in short supply. A referendum Tuesday in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> calls for a ban on exporting state-grown logs and asks <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to make permanent an annually renewed ban on exporting logs grown on federal land. `` The mill is old and inefficient,'' said <LOCATION> Gold </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> mill manager <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Saunders </PERSON>. `` It would take about $ 3 million to bring it up. Why should we put in that kind of investment without knowing there is a stable supply of timber?'' The shortage of timber does n't come as a surprise, but its magnitude does. In 1976, <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> forestry professor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Beuter </PERSON> reported that little mature timber was left on private land and that the industry would have to depend on national forests, home to most of the old-growth timber, to make it to the next century, when second-growth trees planted before World War II would be ready for harvest. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, director of resource services for <ORGANIZATION> Seattle </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Simpson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Timber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, had expected harvests in national forests to decline about 20 percent in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> this year as the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> revised its long-range management plans He now fears it could drop 50 percent because old-growth forests have been ruled off-limits because of the spotted owl. `` Historically, a lot of the impetus for the management of federal lands in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> was to settle the West and develop it,'' said <PERSON> Beuter </PERSON>, now a consultant in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>. `` We are sort of at the end of that era now. We are at the point of recognizing that cutting more timber is n't going to create new cities and new economic opportunity in the West. In fact, we are coming around to where saving the forests may create new economic opportunity.'' <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitelaw </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> economics professor, has been a leading proponent of the idea that the Northwest has more to gain from preserving its blue skies, green forests and clear water than from exploiting its resources. `` Most Oregonians receive two paychecks,'' he said. `` One is in dollars. The other comes from the environment. By accounting for all other amenities, I estimate that the environmental paycheck is worth $ 1.3 billion. The paycheck from the timber industry is $ 1.5 billion.'' In 1988, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> national forests supplied 5.4 billion board feet of timber, a third of the region's total harvest from all lands. Where the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> management plans used in the 1980s allowed the annual harvest of 5.5 billion board feet, the limit in the 1990s will be closer to 4.7 billion. Unlike owners of private forests, the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> by law may cut no more timber than it can grow back. It also has to provide for the needs of fish, wildlife, campers, hikers and water quality. Where it once had to answer only to the timber industry, the service now has a crowd of watchdogs panting over its shoulder. The governors of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> want to be sure there is enough timber to sustain the rural economy. Environmental groups demand preservation of old-growth forests. Academics have started offering new management techniques that follow the lead of nature. And there is new unrest inside the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> DeBonis </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Willamette </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> timber sale planner, has organized the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employees </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ethics </ORGANIZATION>, with a mailing list of about 200. <PERSON> DeBonis </PERSON> wrote in February to <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> claiming the agency is in bed with the industry. `` The question we need to ask concerned citizens is, ` Why should the national forests be sacrificed to an overzealous and greedy industry that liquidated their own lands to make a fast cut?''' he said. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s staff is preparing a detailed response to <PERSON> DeBonis </PERSON>' letter, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Narlock </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> `` Maybe we need some of these things talked about It was a gutsy move on his part.'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> has acknowledged that the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> has taken a beating in the courts under the National Environmental Policy Act, evidence <PERSON> DeBonis </PERSON> cites for his argument that too many trees are being cut. While loggers tie yellow ribbons to their trucks and demand more timber, the grim truth is jobs are disappearing, spotted owl or no spotted owl. `` The biggest source of change in employment has been the modernization and automation of the forest products industry,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Wilderness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> economist <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Olson </PERSON>, who produced a study concluding the decline in timber jobs in the <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> has little to do with cutting old growth in national forests. <LOCATION> Flora </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> economist, said in the 1970s he figured each 1 million board feet of timber translated into eight timber jobs. That's now down to 1.5 jobs in the high-tech mills and four to five jobs overall. Timber is virtually extinct as a factor in the economies of <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, but still vital in small cities and towns that grew up with it. <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>'s 68,700 wood-products jobs _ almost all of them outside the <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION> area _ account for 5.2 percent of the state's employment <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s 41,800 timber jobs account for 2.1 percent of its employment. In 1986, the most recent figures available, timber accounted for just 6 percent of <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>'s gross state product at $ 2.5 billion and 2.2 percent of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s, at $ 1.6 billion. But <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> economist <PERSON> Con </PERSON> <PERSON> Schallau </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Corvallis </LOCATION> argues timber has a greater impact than that, because it accounts for 38 percent of <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>'s basic economy _ bringing in outside dollars _ and 18 percent of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s. While economists may differ over timber's importance, they agree the places that will be hurt worst are towns like <LOCATION> Gold </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, population 1,500, with a payroll of $ 6 million from Gold Beach Plywood. `` If you live in a big city you've got a lot of choices,'' <PERSON> Wentworth </PERSON> said, `` but if you live here you've got to work in the brush or the mill.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Timber-NewMill     06-22 0539</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Timber-New Mill,0553</SECOND>
<HEAD>Weyerhaeuser's Got All-New Attitude for Export Lumber</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Timber-Economics</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARNARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COOS BAY, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One tip that <ORGANIZATION> Weyerhaeuser </ORGANIZATION> is taking bold steps with its newest sawmill is the bed of pansies in the log yard. <ORGANIZATION> Weyerhaeuser </ORGANIZATION>, a leading exporter of logs to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, has gone a step further to produce precision-sawn, metric-dimension lumber for Japanese home builders, for whom the appearance of wood for traditional post-and-beam construction counts more than the structural strength valued in the American market. `` We want to put out logs to the highest value market. In recent years the highest value has been offshore,'' said operations manager <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>. So the company scrapped an aging mill in North Bend on the southern coast and converted a cedar plant here into ts mill of the'90s, called CBX. `` We're pulling out all the stops,'' said superintendent <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickey </PERSON> as he showed off the paved log yard, laser-guided saws, flowers and a new management style that emphasizes teamwork. `` We're spending $ 1 million on the upgrade. But high-tech also means fewer jobs. When <ORGANIZATION> Weyerhaeuser </ORGANIZATION> announced the CBX project in January, <PERSON> North </PERSON> <PERSON> Bend </PERSON> employed about 200 and produced about 65 million board feet a year, about 3 jobs per million board feet. The CBX crew of 69 can produce 45 million board feet a year, or 1.5 jobs per million feet. The mills that survive the current shakeup in the industry must be extremely efficient, and <PERSON> Dickey </PERSON> expects his hand-picked crew to lead the way. `` We're aiming to have this site be the model for the industry.'' To emphasize that point, <ORGANIZATION> Weyerhaeuser </ORGANIZATION> has installed catwalks for visitors. `` All the major Japanese trading companies have been here once or twice,'' said <PERSON> Dickey </PERSON>, who is learning Japanese. While <ORGANIZATION> Weyerhaeuser </ORGANIZATION> took the obvious steps of upgrading the physical plant at CBX, it also is going where no sawmill has gone before in its contract with the International Woodworkers of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. `` Basically, it lets people work as teams rather than in individual job situations,'' said <PERSON> Milo </PERSON> <PERSON> Summerville </PERSON>, field representative for IWA Local 3-261. `` Sometimes you have to give something like this a trial period to see if it will work.'' Lumber grader <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Esch </PERSON> is enthusiastic about being able to rotate through three positions rather than sticking to one job. `` It's kind of like being an immigrant in a new country,'' he said. <PERSON> Cheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Howell </PERSON>, an 11-year veteran of the company, scored well on a hand-eye coordination test, and was cross-trained to run bark-stripping machinery and giant loaders in the yard. `` Before it's done, I expect to know how to run everything in here,'' she said. The first shift starts at 6:30 a.m., with workers and managers joining in 10 minutes of exercises, followed by as much as 45 minutes of talk as the crew helps make management decisions. To emphasize teamwork, <ORGANIZATION> Weyerhaeuser </ORGANIZATION> scrapped an old cleanup contract and made everyone, including <PERSON> Dickey </PERSON>, responsible for keeping the mill clean. <PERSON> Dickey </PERSON> is happy to get away from the old-style management approach he calls `` big brain-little brain.'' `` Generally you get dissatisfied employees because they are starved for information,'' he said. `` We're giving them a big piece of the operation.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Timber-NewForestry     06-22 0641</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Timber-New Forestry,0655</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Techniques Approximate Old-Growth Forest</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Timber-Economics</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARNARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GRANTS PASS, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the rugged Illahe country where gold miners still pan creeks running into the <LOCATION> Rogue </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Siskiyou </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> is trying techniques from a movement known as the New Forestry. `` I see it as a major philosophical change rather than an incremental change,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> scientist <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON>, a leading spokesman for the movement. `` In terms of forestry practice, it is revolutionary.'' The New Forestry is gaining credibility in the midst of debate over how much national forest can be logged while preserving the old growth ecosystem. Pressure to log these forests has increased as private lands have been overcut. `` We need to make this crisis the basis for not just resolving the issue of how much old growth to leave, but perhaps more important, how do we manage our commodity lands over the long term,'' <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> said. `` People are looking for ways to harvest the forest and provide jobs, yet keep values that are important to the public,'' said Gold Beach District Ranger <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. `` The public is interested in old-growth forest, interested in the species that inhabit the old growth forest. `` We think there is an opportunity for these New Forestry techniques to provide that middle ground.'' While most national forests in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> still are developing 10-year management plans, the <ORGANIZATION> Siskiyou </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> has fit the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forestry </ORGANIZATION> into its plan with a goal of balancing production against a healthy forest. The key to New Forestry is to save more of the forest's parts so what is left after logging has the best chance of surviving radical climate changes a growing number of scientists predict will come within the next 50 years. On the <LOCATION> Siskiyou </LOCATION>, the New Forestry is the basis for plans to start logging in the next couple years the 7,100 acres known as the Illahe Project, about 40 miles west of Grants Pass in southwestern <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>. `` As we move out from that large block of old-growth forest into areas previously harvested, we feather out the impacts,'' said <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. `` We'll leave a certain amount of old-growth trees per acre. That number increases as you get closer to the undisturbed block of old growth forest.'' That differs radically from traditional practice of clearcuts of 20 to 40 acres scattered throughout the forest in hopes of diluting the impact. As scientists have learned more about how pieces of the forest interact they have found that scattered clearcuts fragmented the ecosystem, breaking it into pieces too small to function. They also have found it valuable to leave corridors linking the pieces of forest. Instead of clearcutting, New Foresters will leave dead trees and some live trees standing to give animals places to feed and live. Some logs will be left to rot and restore organic material to the soil. Planners say the New Forestry will mean a 5 percent cut in timber production over the 130-year harvest cycle. No decision has been made on how to approach slash burning, in which debris left by clearcutting is burned to return minerals to the soil, reduce fire danger, and make it easier to plant seedlings, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. When it comes to replanting logged-over land, the New Forestry suggests restoring the mix of species that were cut, to maintain a diverse genetic base more able to withstand future climatic change, rather than filling the land with one commercially valuable species such as Douglas fir. <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> forestry professor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Perry </PERSON>, also part of the New Forestry movement, said, `` The point is that whatever you do to take trees off it has got to be consistent with the adaptations of the forest that have evolved over millenia to cope with disurbance.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DavisAppointment     06-22 0147</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Davis Appointment,0152</SECOND>
<HEAD>Enterprise News Editor Named at AP Washington Bureau</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> has been named news editor for enterprise in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> bureau of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The appointment was announced Wednesday by <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Chief of Bureau <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolman </PERSON>. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, 38, has been the supervisor of the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> news report for afternoon newspapers. He previously was the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s news editor in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, and correspondent in <LOCATION> Montpelier </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vt. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> will coordinate enterprise coverage from the nation's capital, including direction of <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s special assignment He also will direct planning for the afternoon news report. A second <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> news editor, <PERSON> Carole </PERSON> <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON>, handles the bureau's coverage of breaking news. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> is a native of <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, and a graduate of <ORGANIZATION> Dartmouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. He joined the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Montpelier </LOCATION> in 1978 after working for the <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION> -RRB- Valley News.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SicilianShocker     06-22 0817</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sicilian Shocker,0842</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teen-age Novelist Shocks Sicily With Story of Sex and Sexism</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FRANCES D'EMILIO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In small towns in <LOCATION> Sicily </LOCATION>, where just looking at a man can get a woman labeled `` loose,'' <PERSON> Lara </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardella </PERSON> is being called all kinds of names for telling how it is to grow up female and Sicilian. The 19-year-old native of <LOCATION> Licata </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sicily </LOCATION> _ population 45,000 _ is also selling a lot of books. Her novel `` Volevo I Pantaloni'' _ `` I Wanted Pants'' _ has been <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s best-selling paperback since early spring. <PERSON> Cardella </PERSON> wrote it at night, longhand in a notebook, in her parents' house, and submitted it in an Italian contest for young, unpublished writers. She says she did n't expect to win, let alone get published. She did both. <PERSON> Arnoldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondadori </PERSON>, the Italian publishing giant, has already sold the film rights for the book, which at 121 large-type pages, is more a novella than a novel. <PERSON> Cardella </PERSON> also did n't expect insulting telephone calls and scornful looks from townspeople who felt ridiculed by the book. When she came out of her house one day with a French TV crew, paramilitary police had to protect her from a crowd shouting curses, she recalls. `` Some of my friends stayed by me. Some of them left me,'' she said in a recent telephone interview from her home. `` My sister was forced to change schools. Few of my parents' friends remain.'' The small town in her scathing story could be <PERSON> Licata </PERSON> or hundreds of other coastal towns or mountain villages in <LOCATION> Sicily </LOCATION> _ or, for that matter, the rest of rural southern <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. Telling the story is 16-year-old <PERSON> Annetta </PERSON>. She is not an autobiographical character, <PERSON> Cardella </PERSON> says, but embraces the experiences of many of her girlfriends whose modest attempts at liberation _ like kissing a boy in public _ sometimes ended in beatings or being kept at home under even tighter supervision. <PERSON> Annetta </PERSON> wants to wear pants like men. Or at least be able wear her skirts short, like her friend <PERSON> Angelina </PERSON> who used to live in the more liberal north. <PERSON> Annetta </PERSON> asks her mother how she can get pants. `` Her reply, innocent, revolutionized my adolescent life,'' <PERSON> Annetta </PERSON> says. `` She told me, ` I pantaluna falli purtari e masculi e buttani.''' The Sicilian dialect translates: Men and whores wear pants. <PERSON> Annetta </PERSON> then sets out to learn how to put on lipstick, sway her hips so boys will notice her and lie to her parents so they'll let her go to an afternoon party _ at <LOCATION> Angelina </LOCATION>'s house, naturally _ where there are more boys than girls and no parents. At the party she meets a boy named <PERSON> Nicola </PERSON>. The next day an uncle sees Nicola kissing <PERSON> Annetta </PERSON>. She is beaten up by her father and renounced by her mother, who's so busy weeping from shame she quits cooking dinner. Wanting to eat again, her father arranges for <PERSON> Annetta </PERSON> to stay with an uncle, even though her parents know the uncle sexually molested her when she was 10 years old. `` Woman is wife, woman is mother, but she is not a person,'' <PERSON> Cardella </PERSON> writes. Most of <PERSON> Licata </PERSON>'s residents who protested the book did n't read it, she says. <PERSON> Cardella </PERSON>'s detractors became even more enraged when she went on a nationwide TV talk show and derided one of southern <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s most sacred rituals, the Sunday afternoon `` passeggiata,'' or stroll, taken after the day's big meal. Girls walk hand in hand, around and around the main square. Boys cluster in groups and ogle the girls, who have mastered the art of looking chaste and sexy at the same time. Older folks sit on the sidelines to make sure all the boys and girls exchange are looks. After the television show, <PERSON> Cardella </PERSON> told another interviewer the mayor met her on the street and said: `` You need to be straightened out.'' <PERSON> Cardella </PERSON> regrets blurting out on television that `` 99 percent'' of Sicilians are backward. `` I love <LOCATION> Sicily </LOCATION>. It's so beautiful, it's stupendous. But the idea that people wo n't denounce violence is wrong. ... Violence exists. ... I think it's wrong a woman ca n't go to a disco.'' In general, she says, girls are more repressed in the poorer towns and neighborhoods. <PERSON> Cardella </PERSON> says her parents were very strict with her, just `` like the others.'' `` But I tried to educate them, to make them see I was n't doing anything wrong,'' and now, she says, they support her in her battle against repression. `` People say I'm impulsive. That I want to change things too quickly. But I do n't want to wait 100 years. I do n't want to know my daughter will have the same problems I did.'' Enrolled in the literature department of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palermo </ORGANIZATION>, she studies at home and says when she marries her boyfriend, she'll move to <PERSON> Gela </PERSON>, his town, 25 miles from <LOCATION> Licata </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Fugitives     06-22 0595</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Fugitives,0612</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Fugitives Find It Hard to Hide</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-China, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Many of the leaders of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s now-quelled demonstrations for political reform have fled their homes, changed their names and appearance, and obtained false identification. Still the arrests mount, dramatizing how difficult it is to hide from authority in this tightly controlled society despite <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s huge size and 1.2 billion population <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> <PERSON> Gang </PERSON>, the sixth student on a wanted circular of 21 to be arrested, fled to <LOCATION> Hebei </LOCATION> province just south of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and introduced himself as <PERSON> Zhang </PERSON> <PERSON> Shun </PERSON>, unemployed worker. But he was discovered by sharp-eyed civilians who thought his skin was too white to be the worker he claimed to be. Even in ordinary times, a fugitive can be easy to spot. In small villages, an outsider clearly stands out. In big cities, neighborhood committees staffed by women with spare time keep a close watch on comings and goings and make sure people register overnight guests with the police. Housing is cramped and many people live in just one or two rooms around a common courtyard, making it virtually impossible to hide a fugitive. Official identification is always required to travel in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, but controls have been sharply increased since the June 3-4 military crackdown. Soldiers are checking identification and searching the bags of travelers at the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> train station. At night, soldiers stop most cars at major intersections, check the ID of drivers and sometimes search the cars. Plainclothes police are out in strength, sometimes betraying themselves by suspicious squawks from under their clothing or too-careful inspection of passers-by. Two recently stopped a young <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> woman as she walked down the street because she resembles a wanted student leader. They let her go after checking her identification. Many work units have appointed people to take charge of security. Any newcomer looking for temporary work is likely to be scrutinized far more carefully than usual. Customs officials have been ordered to be especially alert for fugitives seeking to leave the country. This week, officials at the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> airport arrested four people with alleged `` ties to the counterrevolutionary rebellion,'' according to Wednesday's <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Daily. Two of them, <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoqiu </PERSON>, 27, and <PERSON> Lu </PERSON> <PERSON> Zhuru </PERSON>, 29, had tickets for <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. The women were caught because an official noted their passports had false border entry stamps. It turned out the passports belonged to two other women, who had left <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and mailed the passports back. But the passports lacked entry stamps, so Miss <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> and <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Lu </PERSON> allegedly faked them. The greatest threat to student activists and other protesters on the run is the intense nationwide government propaganda campaign that apparently has convinced many people the crackdown was justified. When the government called on TV viewers to help find a man accused of rumor-mongering and flashed his picture on the screen, two women quickly stepped forward to point him out. When student activist <PERSON> Zhou </PERSON> <PERSON> Fengsuo </PERSON>'s name was placed on the wanted circular, his sister and brother-in-law turned him in. Newspapers and broadcasts repeatedly have called on the public to report `` rebels,'' creating the temptation to report a neighbor and win the praise and possibly the favor of authorities. That can be important to obtaining housing and other scarce goods. Even people who might be disposed to ignore that the next-door neighbors are harboring a stranger face the pressure of knowing that if they do n't report it, someone else probably will. Then they will come under suspicion for having been silent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SchoolCalendar     06-22 0867</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-School Calendar,0890</SECOND>
<HEAD>In New York, a School Year to Regret</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICK HAMPSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the school year that ends next week the city's 940,000 public school students have been taught lesson after lesson about larceny, bribery, weapons possession, sexual harassment, drug abuse and political corruption Their teachers have included the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> school board members who allegedly stole a baby grand piano from a school, and the one who lived in a box near a highway; the 5-year-old student who brought a loaded pistol to school, and the 11-year-old found with $ 4,000 worth of crack in his lunch bag; the principal arrested for buying crack near his apartment and the veteran teacher arrested for snorting cocaine in a school teachers' parking lot; and the voters of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, who avoided school board election polls as if they were plague wards. The students also learned something about the absurdity and futility of life when the man charged with transforming this depraved curriculum, Schools Chancellor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, suddenly dropped dead. As the year ended, the lessons seemed to be piling up faster than anyone could master them. On Tuesday alone: _ The statewide Regents achievement test in chemistry was canceled after copies of answer sheets were stolen and hawked like baseball programs A copy even turned up on the front page of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, which said it took a reporter all of 15 minutes to locate a student who would sell a copy. _ An undercover investigator reported that he was able to vote 33 times at 33 different voting sites in last month's local school board elections He simply registered under dozens of fake names. _ An appeals court reinstated a law barring school employees and political officeholders from the boards, thus voiding the election of about 18 officials Even by local standards, it was a bad year. The 1988-89 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> school calendar included: Sept. 30: Students learn they must wait a half a year _ until January _ to get some supplies, despite a program to give teachers money to speed up delivery. Oct. 25: <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>, alarmed by the rising number of weapons in schools, announces plans to spend $ 2.8 million on metal detectors. Nov. 9: <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> school principal <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnwell </PERSON> is arrested by police who say he bought two vials of crack near his <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> apartment. <PERSON> Barnwell </PERSON> previously had been suspended three times, and once logged 100 unexplained absences or late arrivals in a single school year. Nov. 14: A <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> school aide tells authorities she was transferred and denied a promotion because she rejected the sexual advances of a local school board member. Nov. 23: <PERSON> Green </PERSON> suspends the local school board in the <LOCATION> Morrisania </LOCATION> section of the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION>, citing a grand jury investigation into allegations that some board members used and distributed illegal drugs, stole school equipment and extorted political contributions from teachers, principals and other employees. Nov. 30: Newspapers report that a <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> school board member lived for several weeks in a cardboard box alongside a highway, and has since disappeared entirely. She continued to receive $ 125 a month board stipend even though she had not attended a board meeting for six months. Dec. 9: An <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> school district superintendent and a school board member are alleged to have used a secret school fund to pay for personal expenses, including a `` sweet 16'' party and a Tiffany bracelet. The district was singled out by the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> last year as a national model. Jan. 13: A 5-year-old kindergartner is found carrying a loaded .25 - caliber pistol in the cafeteria of a <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> elementary Jan. 20: Four Bronx school board members and a former district superintendent are indicted on a variety of criminal charges. One board member is charged with soliciting bribes from a textbook publisher. March 14: The head of a <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> local board is indicted on charges that he sought a bribe from an acting assistant principal to allow her to hold her job after she failed an exam; an 11-year-old <PERSON> Bronx </PERSON> student is arrested after he is caught with 411 vials of crack in his lunch bag. May 2: Despite a campaign to get out the vote, only 7 percent of eligible voters turn out for neighborhood school board elections _ the lowest turnout since the elections began two decades ago. Despite reports of rampant corruption and cronyism, the vast majority of incumbents are re-elected. May 8: <PERSON> Barnwell </PERSON>'s case ends in mistrial; reassigned, he continues to draw $ 61,000 annual salary. May 10: <PERSON> Green </PERSON> dies in an asthma attack only 14 months after becoming chancellor. May 23: A third-grader at a <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> school finds 19 crack vials on a urinal. June 19: State auditors say half the complaints of corruption received by the <ORGANIZATION> central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> apparently were never investigated. As the school year ended, all of the local school boards in the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> were under investigation _ two had been suspended _ as were six others around the city. One hundred and twenty-four teachers and administrators had been fired or faced disciplinary action. Statistics on school violence were still being computed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890622-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-22-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ChipConsortium 1stLd-Writethru a0792 06-22 0681</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Chip Consortium, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0792,0694</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Chip Venture Planned To Combat Japanese Dominance</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS last graf with 2 grafs to UPDATE with reax from Japanese
officials in Tokyo. A longer version moved on the financial wire.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANTHONY MARQUEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTA CLARA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
