<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 2325EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Norway     10-02 0314</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Norway,0325</SECOND>
<HEAD>Norway Coalition Agrees To Topple Labor Government</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OSLO, Norway (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three opposition parties agreed on a basic platform for a new non-socialist coalition and stand ready to topple the minority government of Prime Minister <PERSON> Gro </PERSON> <PERSON> Harlem </PERSON> <PERSON> Brundtland </PERSON>, an opposition leader said Monday. The emerging coalition was expected to submit a no-confidence motion in Parliament this month if Mrs. <PERSON> Brundtland </PERSON> refuses to resign, the national news agency <ORGANIZATION> NTB </ORGANIZATION> said. <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Syse </PERSON>, who probably would become prime minister under the new coalition's plan, declined to reveal details of its platform until the three parliamentary groups review and approve the recommended policies. `` Lots of work remains to be done, including distribution of ministerial posts,'' <PERSON> Syse </PERSON> said on national <ORGANIZATION> NRK </ORGANIZATION> radio. The alliance of Conservative, <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> and Center parties won a total of 62 seats in the 165-seat parliament in Sept. 11 elections. Mrs. <PERSON> Brundtland </PERSON>'s Labor party won 63 seats, and the <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Left </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, allied with <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION>, won 17. There was one independent. The right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Progress </ORGANIZATION>, with 22 seats, held the balance of power. Its chairman, <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hagen </PERSON>, says he would support a no-confidence vote against Mrs. <PERSON> Brundtland </PERSON>, but would not pledge future loyalty to the new coalition unless his party became a full partner. `` We are ready to present such a no-confidence motion, if necessary,'' <PERSON> Syse </PERSON> said in a radio interview. Mrs. <PERSON> Brundtland </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION>'s central board on Sunday she will decide the future of her government only after seeing the opposition's platform. The three non-socialist leaders demanded she resign as early as possible `` in order not to delay the coalition's and the Parliament's work,'' <ORGANIZATION> NTB </ORGANIZATION> reported. `` She can chose to step down after Labor has presented its 1990 state budget proposal to the parliament on Oct. 12, or she risks being toppled by a general no-confidence vote on Oct. 24,'' the agency said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 2327EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Tate     10-02 0233</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Tate,0239</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former SMU president Willis Tate Dead at 77</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>, who served as president of <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> for nearly 20 years, died of an apparent heart attack while on a trip with his wife in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, the school announced Monday. He was 77. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>, who died Sunday night, was the university's president from 1954 to 1971 and again from July 1974 to October 1975. He retired as chancellor in 1976 and since then had served as president emeritus of <ORGANIZATION> SMU </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> was an all-conference tackle and an honorable mention All-American in 1931, when <ORGANIZATION> SMU </ORGANIZATION> won the <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> football championship. He received his bachelor degree of arts in 1932 and his master's of arts in sociology in 1935, both from <ORGANIZATION> SMU </ORGANIZATION> After serving as teacher and school principal in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> returned to <ORGANIZATION> SMU </ORGANIZATION> in 1945 as assistant dean of students. `` He will be remembered as the protector of academic freedom during the difficult times in the 1950s and 1960s and as a strong supporter of curriculum reforms,'' said <ORGANIZATION> SMU </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Pye </PERSON>. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> also presided over the establishment of <ORGANIZATION> SMU </ORGANIZATION>'s School of the Arts and the launching of doctoral programs on campus. He and his wife, the late <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Estes </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>, had two children. Tate is survived by <PERSON> Marian </PERSON> <PERSON> Cleary </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>, whom he married in 1988, his two children and three grandchildren.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 2342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r e PM-APArts:MysteryTrain     10-02 0491</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Mystery Train,0506</SECOND>
<HEAD>Elvis Presley Haunts Jim Jarmusch's New Movie</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HILLEL ITALIE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON>'s involvement in the plot of <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarmusch </PERSON>'s new movie, `` Mystery Train,'' was a mystery to the filmmaker. The writer-director of `` Stranger Than Paradise'' and `` Down by Law'' says he started with a few characters, like he always does, and came up with the idea for shooting the movie in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, home of Presley's Graceland mansion and <ORGANIZATION> Sun </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION>, where `` The King'' first recorded. `` He snuck in there; you got to watch out for him,'' said the director at a recent press conference after the film's preview at the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Film Festival. `` When I first came to Memphis I went to Graceland immediately. By the time I left <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, I was so sick of Elvis I never wanted to hear about him again.'' But for now, questions about <PERSON> Jarmusch </PERSON> and Presley are unavoidable. <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> is everywhere in `` Mystery Train,'' named after an old blues song that Presley recorded at Sun. His music is on the soundtrack, his pictures hang in hotel rooms, characters see his ghost and <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON>, a working-class Englishman played by rock' n' roller <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Strummer </PERSON>, is even nicknamed `` Elvis. `` Mystery Train'' is broken into three segments, which take place in the same time frame: A young Japanese couple visit <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> to see Graceland and Sun; a young Italian woman, recently widowed, and a talkative stranger share a hotel room for one night; and three buddies are forced to leave town when <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> kills a liquor store clerk. `` The Japanese couple are fans, they're kind of an audience,'' <PERSON> Jarmusch </PERSON> says. `` As the story progesses, the way <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> is treated changes somwewhat. By the third story, <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON>'s saying, ` That guy is everywhere.''' Fans of <PERSON> Jarmusch </PERSON>'s earlier films will quickly recognize the director's dark humor and fondness for characters usually found only in barrooms and poolhalls. `` Mystery Train'' is, however, <PERSON> Jarmusch </PERSON>'s first movie shot in color. `` I have to write very visually,'' he said. `` When I start to visualize the film, I make an intuitive decision and I stick to that. I ca n't say why. If you ask someone whether they dream in black and white or color, they ca n't say why. `` I have future projects and I already know that some are color and some are black and white.'' <PERSON> Jarmusch </PERSON> did say he will continue to make low-budget films outside the Hollywood studio system. He recalled a conversation with producer <PERSON> Dino </PERSON> <PERSON> DeLaurentiis </PERSON>. `` He asked me, ` Why do you make amateur films instead of professional ones?' I asked what made a film amateur or professional. He said any film that costs more than $ 5 million is professional. `` I guess I'm still making amateur films.'' The cast includes <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Bracco </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Aviles </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nicolette </PERSON> <PERSON> Braschi </PERSON> and rhythm' n' blues stars Screamin' <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rufus </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>. `` Mystery Train'' is scheduled for a mid-November release by Orion Classics.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 2343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AryanMarch     10-02 0760</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Aryan March,0784</SECOND>
<HEAD>Town That Founded Klan Now Reluctant Host to White Supremacist March</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Mcdonald is cq</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CONNIE CASS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PULASKI, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Strip away the orange ribbons, and <PERSON> Pulaski </PERSON>'s courthouse square could be a movie set for an archetypal Southern town, where a Confederate hero stands on a pedestal and pickup trucks sport <LOCATION> Dixie </LOCATION> flags. But the orange `` brotherhood color'' affixed to storefronts, lampposts, car antennas and coat lapels is meant to make sure no one confuses <LOCATION> Pulaski </LOCATION> residents with the white supremacists who plan to march through town Saturday. `` These people are outsiders and this county is a victim of rape by these groups,'' said author <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Mcdonald </PERSON>, who owns a farm in the area and helped organize the anti-march campaign. Restaurants, stores and markets have agreed to close for the day throughout the town of about 8,000 people 90 miles south of <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>. Residents have been asked to stay off the streets, and churches have planned activities to keep children and teen-agers away from downtown. The racists are attracted to <LOCATION> Pulaski </LOCATION> by the town's role in the history of the <ORGANIZATION> Ku </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Klux </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Klan </ORGANIZATION>. The group was founded in <LOCATION> Pulaski </LOCATION> in 1865 as a reaction to what community leaders saw as a threat by carpetbaggers and former slaves after the Civil War. It was disbanded four years later after the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> passed an anti-Klan law. The modern Klan was formed outside <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> in 1915 by a former minister who added Jews and Catholics to the group's list of enemies. The Klan began marching in <LOCATION> Pulaski </LOCATION> annually in 1986 to protest the Martin Luther King national holiday. The parades typically draw fewer than 100 marchers. Community leaders say as long as the racists obtain the proper permits and follow other rules they ca n't be stopped. `` It started out as 35 to 40 old boys putting on their bed sheets and marching around the square haranguing,'' said <PERSON> Mcdonald </PERSON>, author of the `` Fletch'' mystery novels. `` These people considered the town's silence tacit approval. Nothing could be further from the truth.'' Town leaders decided it was time to act when the Aryan Nations of <LOCATION> Hayden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, announced plans to march here this year. The group advocates the formation of a whites-only country. Ten members of an Aryan Nations splinter group were convicted of racketeering in 1985 in a plot to overthrow the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government that involved murder, bank robbery and armed confrontations. `` We're just not going to let our town be taken over by bigots and hate mongers,'' said <PERSON> Bettie </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>. Both sides claim <PERSON> Pulaski </PERSON>'s Civil War hero, <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, a 21-year-old Confederate scout who was hanged after refusing to reveal the name of a Rebel spy. Ms. <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON> helped wire an orange wreath to the hands of a statue of <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> on the town square. The white supremacists will lay a wreath also. `` He's our only hero, and they want to take him,'' Ms. <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON> said. The Rev. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON>, pastor of the Church of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> Christian-Aryan Nations, said the march was set on the day after <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>' birthday to honor `` white heroes.'' `` <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> was a hero of our people and nobody has ever honored him,'' <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Butler </PERSON>'s group claims several hundred members across the country, but he did not know how many to expect on Saturday. `` All members of our race are welcome,'' he said when asked whether Klan members and skinheads would march. He said the town's condemnation `` does n't bother us a bit.'' Police Chief <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> said at least 50 state and local officers will monitor the march. Residents concede that <LOCATION> Pulaski </LOCATION> is no utopia of racial equality. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> McNairy </PERSON>, president of the local branch of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Colored People, described race relatons as `` average.'' <LOCATION> Giles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> is about 20 percent black. Ms. <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON> noted that the local country club has no black members. `` I think this whole thing will draw attention to some areas we have not examined closely enough before,'' she said. Businessman <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Massey </PERSON> made his protest on the side of a building he owns. A bronze plaque commemorating the birth of the <ORGANIZATION> KKK </ORGANIZATION> has hung there for 72 years. This month he turned the plaque to the wall. `` If we just took it down, it really would n't say anything,'' <PERSON> Massey </PERSON> said. `` This was my way to say we ca n't just turn our backs on the other signs of bigotry and hatred as if they were n't there.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 2343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Peru-Violence     10-02 0354</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Peru-Violence,0364</SECOND>
<HEAD>Peruvian Leftists Bomb Lunch Counter, Continue Killings in Highlands</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MONTE HAYES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LIMA, Peru (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Leftist rebels dynamited a lunch counter two blocks from where <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> sits, seriously wounding eight breakfasting policemen and two other customers, police said. Also Monday, <ORGANIZATION> Maoist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shining </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Path </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas shot to death the deputy administrator of the highland city of <LOCATION> Huancayo </LOCATION> and a companion, bringing to 13 the number of people killed in political violence since Saturday, police said. The violence struck as <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> prepared to act as host at a meeting of <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> foreign ministers next week prior to two meetings of Latin American presidents. In <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>, rebels threw a dynamite bomb onto the tin roof of a lunchroom in a public market where policemen were eating. The explosion ripped open the roof and shattered the small restaurant's counter and lunch tables Police said rebel assassins killed <PERSON> Flavio </PERSON> <PERSON> Llerena </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Huancayo </LOCATION>'s deputy administrative chief, and an unidentified man accompanying him as they walked along a street in the major Andean city 140 miles east of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> Rebels killed four policemen Sunday night in an attack on the police post in <LOCATION> Palpa </LOCATION> 42 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Ica </LOCATION>, the desert town 185 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> where the presidents of <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> are to meet on Oct. 11. Police at the post drove away the attackers, killing two rebels, police said. In Ica the same night, Shining Path gunmen broke into the house of <PERSON> Oswaldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Aspilcueta </PERSON>, a state university rector, and killed his wife, police said. They said the rebels apparently were after <PERSON> Aspilcueta </PERSON>, a member of <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>'s legal <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. The Shining Path split from the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in 1970 and took up arms in 1980. It views party members as traitors to its dogmatic version of Maoism. Also on Sunday night, Shining Path rebels killed the deputy mayor of <LOCATION> Huamachuco </LOCATION>, a town in <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Libertad </LOCATION> department 290 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>. On Saturday guerrillas shot three people to death, two in <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Negro </LOCATION>, 160 miles east of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>, and one on the outskirts of <LOCATION> Huancayo </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SatanicVerses     10-02 0668</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Satanic Verses,0685</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rallying Against Rushdie at the Royal Albert Hall</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After chants of `` <PERSON> Allahu </PERSON> akbar!'' echoed in the cavernous Royal <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, the audience was told passages from `` The Satanic Verses'' would be read aloud and those who could n't take it had two minutes to leave No one stirred. Then a tall man with a white beard and skullcap took the podium and fired the latest salvo in the year-long Moslem campaign against the novel and its author, <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>. In a worldwide effort to suppress a novel they consider blasphemous, Moslems have rioted, burned books, gone to court and threatened to kill <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>. The author, born a Moslem in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, now lives in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. Many who condemn him have turned to <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Deedat </PERSON>, a 72-year-old Moslem scholar from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> with a simple message: Read the book. It may be a painful experience, <PERSON> Deedat </PERSON> says, but Moslems who know what the novel says have a much better chance of convincing Westerners their cause is just. He does not feel the blasphemy argument will convince Westerners `` The Satanic Verses'' should be suppressed, but he believes they would be more responsive if they knew what the book says about <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> and the West in general. To prove his point, he regaled the 6,000 Moslems in the Royal <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> on Sunday afternoon with four-letter words extracted from the 547-page novel. <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> is abusing his adopted country, <PERSON> Deedat </PERSON> declared, so the Moslem argument should go like this: `` Admitted that <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> has many filthy, dirty and obscene things to say about Islam and its heroes and heroines; but sir, do you know what he has to say about you, his benefactors and protectors?'' <PERSON> Deedat </PERSON> has an engaging, folksy manner and the voice and vigor of a man half his age. He argues cogently, in simple language, and has a keen eye for Western hypocrisies. Citing a newspaper report about <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> lawmakers demanding that American actor <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Rourke </PERSON> be barred from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> for using a four-letter word to describe Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s policies, <PERSON> Deedat </PERSON> expressed confidence they would feel the same about <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>. Applause greeted his presentation, but at least one listener spotted an apparent flaw and expressed it during question time. The young man said <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> would not ban the book, however insulting, because its `` people are tolerant.'' Another troubling matter for questioners was the death sentence imposed on <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> by <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, the Iranian revolutionary patriarch who died in June. <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> went into hiding after <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> issued his declaration Feb. 14. Deedat deflected questions on that subject, saying it required an entire two-hour lecture by itself. In an interview afterward, he said the death threat had become a political issue: `` One group wants to take a certain stand which is against another group. I'm not interested in groupings. I'm interested in the best way to solve a problem. To many questioners, the problem was how to interpret the death sentence. A young woman described hardships encountered at school because of her attempts to defend the Moslem attitude toward <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>. Someone else suggested <PERSON> Deedat </PERSON> was in conflict with the Koran, the Moslem holy book, if he did not support killing <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>. Sunday's gathering underscored contrasts in modern, multicultural <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>: Arabic chants of `` God is Great!'' in a hall built as a monument to the traditional British way of life; young men in jeans and T-shirts kneeling on the lawn at the foot of the ornate Albert Memorial across the road, praying to <LOCATION> Mecca </LOCATION>; stalls selling prayer mats, Korans, alcohol-free perfumes and cassettes of <PERSON> Deedat </PERSON>'s remarks It was a placid scene, but a Moslem weekly distributed Friday outside the <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> had expressed the undercurrent of unease. `` Peaceloving Moslems fear that a time shall come when the British public would begin to identify an average Moslem as a terrorist and feelings of hate could ruin the otherwise peaceful coexistence,'' it said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 2349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-AfghanTouristTown Bjt   10-02 0811</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghan Tourist Town, Bjt,0847</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ancient Afghan Capital Now Seeks Tourists</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NEIL MacFARQUHAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BALKH, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There is fresh, white lettering on the battered sign welcoming tourists to this ancient capital _ once visited by <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> the </PERSON> <PERSON> Great </PERSON>, by <PERSON> Marco </PERSON> <PERSON> Polo </PERSON>, by <PERSON> Tamerlaine </PERSON> and by hippies tramping through <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. Now, the main square is filled with armed militiamen and an armored personnel carrier is parked 20 yards away. The square bristles with Kalashnikov rifles and rocket-propelled grenade launchers, carried by militiamen who left the mujahedeen rebels to join the government. There has been no fighting for months. But residents of this northern town hate the unruly militiamen and say they smoke hashish, demand goods at half price and prey on people traveling after dusk. It is part of President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>'s policy of giving weapons, money and local autonomy to those who leave the Pakistani-based rebel coalition that is trying to topple his government in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. Fear of the militias is not unique to <LOCATION> Balkh </LOCATION>. In the refugee center in <LOCATION> Mazar-e-Sharif </LOCATION>, a provincial capital 11 miles east of <LOCATION> Balkh </LOCATION>, 12 people said they were attacked by a government militia when they crossed the border from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. They said they lost watches, turbans, and cash. In <LOCATION> Balkh </LOCATION>, an officer in the local army garrison acknowledged the militias were beyond control and warned visitors to be out of town by 4 p.m. `` The roads just are n't safe after 5 o'clock,'' said taxi driver <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Ibrahim </PERSON>. `` The bandits stop you and take money, watches, sometimes the car itself.'' <LOCATION> Balkh </LOCATION>, one of history's crossroads, has seen conquerors before. But by the time of the 1978 revolution it was a backwater, a quiet camping site on the hippie trail to the subcontinent and the <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Balkh </LOCATION>'s past reads like a who was who of <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. In the 5th centrury B.C, it became the capital of the first Aryan empire, before they moved on to <LOCATION> Persia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. The Greek historian <PERSON> Heroditus </PERSON> put <LOCATION> Balkh </LOCATION> in his chronicles. <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> the Great paused long enough on a 4th century B.C. march to <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> to marry <PERSON> Roxane </PERSON>, the daughter of a local tribal chief. The Arab forces that arrived in 645 were so stunned by its beauty they called <LOCATION> Balkh </LOCATION>, `` mother of all cities.'' <PERSON> Ghengis </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON> razed <LOCATION> Balkh </LOCATION> and put all residents to the sword in 1220. <PERSON> Marco </PERSON> <PERSON> Polo </PERSON> visited the ruins in 1275, and <LOCATION> Tamerlane </LOCATION> crowned himself emperor in the rebuilt city in 1359. But those were <LOCATION> Balkh </LOCATION>'s last halcyon days. Centuries of fighting gave the city a bad name. So when the northern provinces became part of emerging <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in 1866, the new capital was put at <LOCATION> Mazar </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Tamerlane </LOCATION>'s massive mud brick walls melted like a sand castle, and much of the glorious mosque built in 1597 crumbled. But its blue-tiled dome and a triumphant arch in the circular, shady park at the town's center made it an idyllic spot for young Westerners tramping across <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> was a main drug haven from 1970 to 1973, when the previous hashish capital of <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION> required all travelers to show a minimum $ 500 in cash. `` They were always stoned,'' said a toothless old man. `` But in those days, people smoked hashish secretly,'' the old man said. `` Now they do it openly.'' Did he mean the militia men swaggering nearby? `` Do n't ask me, I stay in the mosque,'' he said. Until seven months ago, when the Soviets withdrew their troops, the residents lived in fear of rocket attacks and fighting. No one is quite how many were killed on both sides, but residents think more than 1,000 people died. The road to <PERSON> Mazar </PERSON> was unsafe. Many of the surrounding wheat fields reverted to desert, their irrigation systems collapsed and their owners fled. The population of the area droped from 80,000 to 60,000. `` One or two years ago it was very dangerous here,'' said <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Isar </PERSON>, who has sold boiled chickpeas in the park for 20 years. `` The opposition groups used to attack with rockets. Now that they have joined with the government, it is peaceful.'' Farmers have started cultivating again in the past year, but the town still has a menacing air. Militiamen roar around in trucks, raising streams of dust over the broad, unpaved streets. Voices drop when the townsmen talk about the militia. `` They take things or pay only half the money,'' whispered the chickpea seller. `` The people hate them.'' `` People are afraid of the militia, they do n't accept them,'' said <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Nadr </PERSON>, 30. `` They switch sides all the time.'' The only hotel was commandeered by a militia group that joined the government three years ago. At the edge of town a request to walk on the still massive remnants of <LOCATION> Tamerlane </LOCATION>'s walls is discouraged. `` There could be mines,'' the government escort said. No one expects tourists back soon.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--UnderControl     10-02 0149</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Under Control,0152</SECOND>
<HEAD>Firefighting Exhibition Goes Awry</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Many a face was red when a team of auxiliary firefighters taking part in an exhibition watched as the fire they were supposed to put out spread to a wider area, the national news agency reported. The firemen were showing off their skills Monday in response to an `` emergency'' during the launching of the Safety Month Campaign at the compound of the <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>. But instead of applause, they got laughs. They had tried to extinguish several burning planks in a drum of gasoline but the blaze instead spread to a grassy area, the <ORGANIZATION> Bernama </ORGANIZATION> news agency said. This would not have occured had the firemen used foam instead of water, said a <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. The firefighters finally managed to put out the fire when one removed the planks from the drum.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r e PM-APonTV:TabloidRatings     10-02 0779</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP on TV: Tabloid Ratings,0796</SECOND>
<HEAD>In the Tabloid TV Battle, `Current Affair' and `Hard Copy' Fight
for No. 1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HORN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first reports from the new tabloid television wars are in, and `` A Current Affair'' and `` Hard Copy'' both have opened strongly while `` Inside Edition'' and `` USA Today on TV'' appear doomed. In this fall's jammed field of reality-based shows, other early casualties look to be `` Crimewatch Tonight,'' `` Trial by Jury'' and `` USA Today Weekend.'' According to the initial <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Syndication </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> ratings, <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>'s nightly `` A Current Affair'' was the seventh most popular syndicated show at the start of the new television season. Finishing ahead of `` Entertainment Tonight'' and `` Donahue'' in the ratings, `` A Current Affair'' was seen in more than 6.9 million homes, the survey said. `` Every time a new show starts like ` Hard Copy,' ` Inside Edition' or ` Crimewatch Tonight' it becomes more competitive,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON>, co-executive producer of `` A Current Affair.'' `` But the strange thing ... is that when ` Inside Edition' started we never had better numbers. So far, in the first week against ` Hard Copy,' we've done the highest numbers we've ever done.'' <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> said `` A Current Affair'' has attempted to fight off its challengers by trying to `` give more serious thought to the stories we do. You try to avoid doing the celebrity rip-offs and the easy <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; A shock-value stories.'' He said critics who blast `` A Current Affair's'' coverage of news and personalities as tawdry are n't fair to the show's intent. `` The worst kind of criticism that's written says that shows like ` A Current Affair' seek to horrify, shock and offend,'' <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> said. `` Because if somebody shocks and horrifies and offends me on a regular basis, I'm going to turn off. And I wo n't let my kids to watch it, either. Because it debuted Sept. 18, `` Hard Copy'' was not included in the first Nielsen syndication report. But the news-oriented program, once entitled `` Tabloid,'' has performed strongly in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, according to its producers. Furthermore, `` Hard Copy'' consistently has boosted some stations' ratings from four months ago, the show's representatives say. In <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, for example, `` Hard Copy'' is delivering to WVIT an audience 60 percent larger than `` Win, Lose or Draw'' did in May. `` For a new show, we got off to a pretty solid start,'' says <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Monsky </PERSON>, executive producer of `` Hard Copy.'' `` We came off the blocks very quickly. Right now we have to prove to the people who did tune us in that what they got was just a little bit of what they could get.'' In its first few weeks on the air, `` Hard Copy'' has reported exclusives on <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> and the death of her husband and the bombing of the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> airliner over <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>. `` I think our intention is very clear. At the top of the show, we want to be very close to what's going on,'' <PERSON> Monsky </PERSON> said. `` And then we want to go deeper and deeper in trying to explore the widest possible range of the people involved.'' The top five shows in the syndicated market for the week ending Sept. 17 are, in order, `` Wheel of Fortune,'' `` Jeopardy,'' `` The <PERSON> Oprah </PERSON> <PERSON> Winfrey </PERSON> Show,'' `` The Cosby Show'' and the weekend version of `` Wheel of Fortune.'' `` Inside Edition'' finished at No. 22, `` USA Today'' landed at No. 32 and `` Crimewatch Tonight'' was No. 46. `` Trial by Jury'' was No. 62 and the weekend version of `` USA Today'' was No. 77. In one strange twist, the makers of `` Inside Edition'' have discussed the possibility of inviting celebrities on the show to rebut any distortions written about them in the supermarket tabloids. However `` Inside Edition'' is revamped, though, it seems likely it will be replaced by `` 30 Minutes.'' Producer <PERSON> Av </PERSON> <PERSON> Westin </PERSON>, a veteran of <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, has joined `` Inside Edition'' maker King World Productions to create the new syndicated news magazine. New reality shows added to network schedules all have debuted poorly. Of the 81 shows covered in last week's regular Nielsen survey, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Primetime Live,'' hosted by <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Donaldson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>, finished 49th. CBS' `` Rescue 911,'' with <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Shatner </PERSON>, landed in 55th. And CBS' `` Saturday Night With Connie Chung'' came in 71st.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Elsewhere in television: <PERSON> BURNETT </PERSON> RETURNS ... Production has opened for `` <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> and Company,'' a new <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> comedy program that will star <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON>. The series, which has no announced debut date, marks Miss <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON>'s first ongoing role in series television in 10 years ... SEARCH FOR BISMARK ... `` National Geographic Explorer'' will broadcast exclusive footage of Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON>'s search of the World War II battleship Bismark on Oct. 29 in a one-hour documentary
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 0010EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador-Rights Bjt   10-02 0898</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador-Rights, Bjt,0926</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reports of Rape, Beatings by Police Endanger Peace Process</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ILOPANGO, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It had been almost a week, and 21-year-old <PERSON> Julia </PERSON> <PERSON> Mendoza </PERSON>'s crying was done. But her mother, <PERSON> Maria </PERSON>, who had listened stoically to her daughter's account of rape by a policeman of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>, could contain herself no more. She sobbed when <PERSON> Julia </PERSON> described the soft-voiced rapist zipping up his pants and saying, `` Maybe that will make you want to collaborate.'' Allegations of mistreatment of prisoners have abounded since the rightist government of <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> took office June 1 and began to move against what they called `` guerrilla fronts'' _ public organizations that sympathize with or support guerrilla positions on some or many issues. The rebels, over the <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>'s clandestine radio, called the police `` animals'' for the alleged rapes `` This is too much to stand for,'' they said. The insurgents warned that continued repression and rights abuse will endanger a preliminary peace process begun last month in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> with talks between government and guerrilla representatives. `` Just as we have been flexible and broadminded in order to negotiate, we are likewise completely disposed to, and capable of accompanying the struggle of the entire people, and to take hold of the flagpole of democracy and peace and carry it forward to drive it into the heart of those who only want war,'' said the rebel high command. Asked about the accusations, Maj. <PERSON> Mauricio </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> <PERSON> Caceres </PERSON>, head of the armed forces press committee, said: `` All commanders take pains to ensure that a prisoner's human rights are respected, because they know these people will come out of the police stations alleging this and that kind of abuse in order to make us look bad.'' In what they called a response to escalated repression, the guerrillas last week launched their first nationwide offensive since May. Seventy-eight people were killed or wounded in the combat, adding to the toll of a 10-year-old civil war that has taken 70,000 lives. It was visiting day at the women's prison six miles east of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> sat outside next to <PERSON> Julia </PERSON> behind a backboard on the cement basketball court as she told her story. <PERSON> Julia </PERSON> <PERSON> Mendoza </PERSON> is one of three women at <LOCATION> Ilopango </LOCATION> jail who say they were raped at <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> headquarters after their arrest the night of Sept. 18 following a demonstration that turned violent. The National Federation of Salvadoran Workers sponsored the march, during which police were taunted by masked demonstrators wielding iron bars and two city buses were set afire. Authorities released 25 of 64 arrested demonstrators, but seven women and 32 men were held. Dr. <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Maldonado </PERSON>, a forensic specialist who examined 37 of the 39, found corroboration of the rape allegation only in Miss <PERSON> Mendoza </PERSON>'s case. The government and armed forces say prisoners like <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Mendoza </PERSON> are leftist guerrilla operatives masquerading as labor activists and that they invent accusations of torture and abuse to slander authorities. The workers federation, known as FENESTRAS by its Spanish initials, in fact espouses a political agenda identical to that of rebels who have waged war against a succession of U.S.-backed governments. But union and peasant organizations, as well as local and international rights groups, say the fact that an individual might support guerrilla positions does not strip him of the right not to be tortured, raped or summarily executed. <PERSON> Maldonado </PERSON> found bruises, cuts and scrapes on 20 of those arrested after the Sept. 18 march. All said they were beaten during interrogation. All said their interrogators belabored them about alleged membership in guerrilla units and insisted they provide names of cohorts. Superior Court Judge <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Morales </PERSON>, in charge of the unionists' cases, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that many of the injuries could have been inflicted with billy clubs during the suspects' The New York-based <ORGANIZATION> Lawyers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION>, after a four-month study of justice in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, said in a report this year, `` We have identified a pattern of psychological as well as physical abuse of detainees.'' The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, in its 1989 human rights report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, said of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>: `` Reports of abuse by arresting forces continue .... Instances of severe beatings, rape, choking, injection with drugs and electric shock were reported.'' The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said the allegations `` are extremely difficult to prove or disprove.'' <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> said that's because the judiciary depends entirely on the police forces for investigations. `` We receive many allegations of rape, but they never get anywhere,'' he said. `` In Miss <PERSON> Mendoza </PERSON>'s case, practically speaking, resolution would be impossible. She was blindfolded and can not identify the man. And the same National Police that are accused of committing the crime would be in charge of investigating it.'' He suggested creation of a police force responsible solely to the judiciary to avoid such conflicts of interest. `` Just having an investigative arm separate from the executive branch would be great progress,'' he said. Members of the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> were accused of raping and beating detainees after the April arrests of dozens of members of refugees organizations considered guerrilla fronts by authorities. Col. <PERSON> Rene </PERSON> <PERSON> Emilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Ponce </PERSON>, chief of the joint chiefs of staff, promised an investigation. After repeated requests by the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> <PERSON> Caceres </PERSON> reported that the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> had investigated itself and found no wrongdoing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 0013EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Archaeology Bjt   10-02 0729</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Archaeology, Bjt,0748</SECOND>
<HEAD>Another Construction Project Turns Into An Archaeological Dig</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALLYN FISHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After 16 years of haggling, a license was granted for widening a road next to the wall of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. But work was halted days later when a bulldozer uncovered a Byzantine bathhouse no one knew existed. It's a typical hazard for developers in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, a city that dates back some 3,500 years and where a shovel put in the ground almost anywhere can turn up archaeological artifacts. `` We have an overload of history here,'' said <PERSON> Aharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Meir </PERSON>, a city archaeologist. `` That's what makes <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> different. If you do n't bother to check, you can simply bulldoze important findings away.'' <PERSON> Meir </PERSON> supervises the archaeological dig launched where construction crews have temporarily ceased building a 820-foot stretch of the new <LOCATION> Mamilla </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION>. The finds so far indicate that contrary to earlier belief, the roughly square-mile walled city may have once extended beyond the current walls, <PERSON> Meir </PERSON> said. The new road runs near the <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Jaffa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gate </LOCATION>, built by the Turkish ruler <PERSON> Suleiman </PERSON> the Magnificent in the 16th Century. Although long considered a possible archaeological site, the area was never excavated by researchers. For years, it was off limits as a battlefield or ceasefire zone between Israeli and <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> armies. After <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> captured it and the rest of east <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> in the 1967 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war, other sections of the city were given priority by archaeologists. One example was `` King <PERSON> David </PERSON>'s City,'' near the holy <ORGANIZATION> Al </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aqsa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mosque </ORGANIZATION>, and the Wailing Wall remnant of the ancient Jewish temples. At the <LOCATION> Jaffa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gate </LOCATION>, excavators have dug more than 2,000 years into the past, stopping when they hit bedrock that indicated they had found the earliest settlement. Two structures so far uncovered _ a bathhouse and a large public building yet to be identified _ have been tentatively dated from the Byzantine period of the Roman Empire, or about the 4th century. Also discovered by <PERSON> Meir </PERSON>, helped by several dozen <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> laborers, is an intricate web of water cisterns, apparently part of an aqueduct system that supplied the ancient city's water. `` These may not look like stupendous finds, but they provide little important tidbits of information about what life was like. If we give up these little things, we would miss the larger picture,'' <PERSON> Meir </PERSON> said. As he spoke hundreds of vehicles crawled at a snail's pace above on the main road, which has been temporarily narrowed to two lanes. <PERSON> Meir </PERSON> said the planned road would likely be completed eventually, but the section adjacent to the dig may have to be diverted or lifted onto an overpass that would allow tourists to see the ancient ruins underneath. Under a city ordinance, contractors must sponsor an archaeological survey of any building site if historical relics are found during construction. Usually, a compromise is worked out so building can continue. The new road is part of a $ 250 million project to build a hotel, apartment buildings and a shopping plaza in <LOCATION> Mamilla </LOCATION>, a predominantly <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> quarter before <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 1948 independence war. Several plans for developing <LOCATION> Mamilla </LOCATION> have been shelved since 1973 amid huge disputes between planners and environmentalists. Among other complaints, the environmentalists expressed fears the new road could increase pollution, causing damage to old buildings. In the current project, a compromise was struck in which the planned road was narrowed from six to three lanes and several old structures were spared being leveled. Officials of the <ORGANIZATION> Karta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>, developers of <LOCATION> Mamilla </LOCATION>, said they hoped the latest delay will not last beyond the end of the month so they can meet their building schedule. But they take it philosophically. `` In some places they make a fuss over remains only 100 years old, here we're talking about things dating to 2,000 years,'' said <PERSON> Karta </PERSON>'s deputy director, <PERSON> Yaacov </PERSON> <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON>. The latest complication in the <LOCATION> Mamilla </LOCATION> plan is typical of what most building projects in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> have faced in the last two decades, ranging from housing developments in the Jewish Quarter of the <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> to the <ORGANIZATION> Hebrew </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> campus on Mt. Scopus. Last year, preparations for a shopping mall were halted when excavators found two prehistoric farming villages from the Bronze Age at the city's southern outskirts. A compromise to allow building of the mall is reportedly being worked out.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SovietEconomy Bjt   10-02 0744</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet Economy, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Union: Nuclear Superpower With Third World Economy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is a nuclear superpower saddled with a Third World economy and that situation wo n't change any time soon, even with <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reform efforts, many Soviet experts believe. If anything, these analysts said, the Soviet economy is in worse shape now than when <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> launched his perestroika, or restructuring program. He is facing the need to slash a huge budget deficit in half while at the same time coping with an economy which went into a nosedive in the spring even as inflation was heating up. `` The Soviet economy has fallen behind,'' said <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Wachtel </PERSON>, an economics professor at <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` When you take off the tight controls of a command system, you lose the threat over people and you get a drop in productivity unless you replace it with something else, like market incentives.'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s economic troubles were the subject of discussions which took place in conjunction with the <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> meetings a week ago between Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> and Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>. One of the officials at that meeting, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Zoellick </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> aide to <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, will be traveling to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> with <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> from Oct. 7-11 for continued discussions on the Soviet economy. Officials said the Soviets are studying a wide variety of ideas such as restoring faith in the Russian ruble by backing the currency with gold. The fact that the Soviets are calling for advice from <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON>, a disciple of anti-communist philosopher Ayn Rand, has not gone unnoticed as a sign of how intent <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is in introducing change. An official from the central bank of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Gosbank </LOCATION>, attended the annual meetings this year of the 152-nation <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monetary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has said it would like to join the two international lending agencies, a move that would make the Soviets eligible for economic assistance of the type already being received by <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, two communist countries already in the <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>. While officials of both organizations stressed that they do not have any formal application from the Soviets before them, they did not dismiss out of hand the idea of Soviet membership down the road. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Feinberg </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Overseas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, a Washington-based research group, said he believes that integrating the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and other Eastern European countries into the world economy could be a central purpose for the <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> in the next decade. The two organizations, formed 44 years ago, originally had the mission of rebuilding the war-torn economies of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Feinberg </PERSON> said full membership for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> probably will not occur for three to four years, given the need to iron out such problems as opening the historically secret Soviet economy to greater review by foreign banking experts. But <PERSON> Feinberg </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> could begin sooner to provide policy assistance to the Soviets. `` The <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> possesses expertise in the areas in which the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> badly needs guidance _ money and banking, price reform and exchange and trade relations,'' he said. Many experts believe that the economic assistance program currently being developed for <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and its new Solidarity-led government could serve as a blueprint for helping the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. But officials say it would be wrong to underestimate the enormity of the task in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. `` We should n't be looking for miracles. There is no panacea for the Soviet economy,'' said <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Pelzman </PERSON>, an economics professor at <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. He said the basic problem is that the Soviet society has no memory of how a market-based economy works. `` You can bring in foreigners, but that is not the same as having local entrepreneurs to call on,'' he said. `` The Soviets have had 67 years with no business class.'' <PERSON> Pelzman </PERSON> said <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will be forced to begin building up a foreign debt in order to import consumer goods as a way of demonstrating to a skeptical public that his economic policies can produce benefits for ordinary citizens. `` If he can stock the stores, he has bought himself a couple of years. But if he ca n't satisfy local consumers, then he is out of luck,'' <PERSON> Pelzman </PERSON> said. `` The opposition will move in and say <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s program is not working.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 0014EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BeachedWhales     10-02 0215</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Beached Whales,0222</SECOND>
<HEAD>Six Sperm Whales Freed After Beaching, One Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COVEHEAD, Newfoundland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rescue crews freed six sperm whales that beached on Prince <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Island </PERSON>'s north-shore national park, but one of the huge sea mammals died. As a crowd of hundreds watched Sunday, federal fisheries officers sent divers to tie slings, one at a time, around the tails of the creatures, which ranged in length from about 40 to 65 feet. A jet-ski took the line to a waiting <ORGANIZATION> Parks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canada </ORGANIZATION> boat, which then towed each whale out about 300 feet then tried to keep it from returning to the beach by circling it. The shoreside crowd let out a rousing cheer as the first surviving whale blew a high spout of water upon reaching the open ocean. Fisheries officers said they believed the dead whale drowned. It was not known what caused the whales to become trapped between two sandbars, but a fisheries spokesman said one possibility was that the sound of a jackhammer working on a nearby bridge might have attracted them. Whales have been known to beach themselves trying to answer the distress calls from other beached whales. The beaching was reported early Sunday. Covehead is near the eastern end of the national park between <PERSON> Brackley </PERSON> and Dalvay beaches.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 0022EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Democrats'Agenda     10-02 0662</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Democrats' Agenda,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: The Democrats Get Tough</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Suddenly, newly aggressive Democrats on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> are trying to paint President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> into a corner labeled `` timid.'' Democrats are displaying a greater willingness to challenge the adequacy of the president's policies and to spell out stronger _ and generally more expensive _ Democratic alternatives. Led by <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, Democrats are spelling out an alternative <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> agenda on issue after issue while portraying <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s programs as inadequate, his funding proposals anemic and his entire approach as unacceptably `` timid.'' The effort is leaving Republicans grumbling that they are being whipsawed in a political bidding war in which `` one-upsmanship'' is the principal weapon. Although the signs have been building, <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, the national Democratic chairman, appeared to fire the starting gun last week when he told fellow Democrats it was time `` to start taking on <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.'' Accusing <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> of `` timidly following the prevailing winds'' of announcing ambitious programs and lofty goals without providing the means to pay for them, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> called on the president to begin `` matching his actions to his charming words.'' In <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> and many other Democrats have been challenging <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on nearly identical grounds and in very specific terms. Recent examples: _ Democrats in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> as well as the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> demanded sharply increased aid for helping non-communist forces build democracy in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, billions of dollars beyond the $ 218 million <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wants to spread over three years Deputy Democratic Leader <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> calls the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> approach `` pathetically timid.'' _ Democrats, challenging the adequacy of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s commitment to the war on drugs, led a successful fight to boost spending by $ 1.1 billion, earmarking most of the additional money for prevention and treatment _ <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> is leading a new Democratic drive to spell out a plan to improve the quality of American education, to take the luster from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s claim to be `` the education president,'' and to underscore the historic <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> contribution to public education _ The majority leader has named a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> task force to chart ways to broaden housing opportunities, address the problems of the homeless and highlight Republican scandals in the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> _ Democrats are battling <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s bid to reduce capital gains taxes They want to revive Individual Retirement Accounts to help average Americans save for education, housing and retirement. `` There's going to be a lot more of that kind of thing,'' says Sen. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>. `` We're not just going to be standing around waiting for the president to act. `` You are going to find a more active, more aggressive party in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON> said. `` You may see us move even before the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> does.'' <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON> and many other congressional Democrats say there is a distinct advantage in having a coherent position on as many issues as possible in order to build up bargaining chips in negotiations with the White House. And some Democrats are fearful of being bruised if the effort results in a head-to-head confrontation with a president pledged not to raise taxes. There is a lot of political gamesmanship in all of this. Some Republicans say the name of that game is, `` me-too, only more so.'' `` It's clear they've decided that the honeymoon is over with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, and that they need a way to counteract his popularity,'' says an adviser to a senior <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republican. `` And the only thing they can come up with is, ` be tougher, be more aggressive, take shots at <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.''' `` It's a do-more-then-they-are strategy, a one-upsmanship strategy,'' he said. `` As we see it, the hidden agenda is to somehow make <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> raise taxes.'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, who has been majority leader for only nine months, has been under increasing pressure by other Democrats to get out in front on policy matters, to become far less timid himself in confronting the president. As his apprenticeship ends, he is clearly attempting exactly that.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 0025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-NomineeBlocked 2ndLd-Writethru a0743 10-02 0461</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nominee Blocked, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0743,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Nominee Blocked By Senate Panel While It Studies HUD Funds</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Editing throughout to include more detail</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> panel is delaying confirmation of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s nominee to head the <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> while it investigates work done by his auditing firm, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> sources say. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Banking, <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> is examining the relationship between nominee <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Clymer </PERSON>'s suburban <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> accounting firm and an economic development organization nearby, according to <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> aides who spoke only on condition of anonymity. The organization, the <ORGANIZATION> Delaware </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Partnership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, is the subject of a broad audit by the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Inspector General <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said in an interview Friday. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> panel unanimously backed <PERSON> Clymer </PERSON>'s nomination on Sept. 8, but has since put a `` hold'' on sending it for a vote for the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Clymer </PERSON>, 42, is the former vice chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Southeastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> UMTA </ORGANIZATION> assists state and local governments in improving mass transportation systems. He has declined requests to be interviewed about the matter. The local partnership, which has received $ 500,000 in <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> grants in the past year, was founded in 1983 by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Curt </PERSON> <PERSON> Weldon </PERSON>, R-Pa., who has said he is not involved in its daily affairs The congressman ordered a consultant to investigate the partnership earlier this year when it was disclosed that several of <PERSON> Weldon </PERSON>'s campaign supporters had received no-bid contracts Of particular interest to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> panel are no-bid contracts that the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> Inquirer reported were awarded to <PERSON> Clymer </PERSON>'s firm by the partnership to audit its books <PERSON> Clymer </PERSON> has been <PERSON> Weldon </PERSON>'s campaign treasurer in the last three elections. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunleavy </PERSON>, the consultant retained at <PERSON> Weldon </PERSON>'s request, said in his report to <PERSON> Weldon </PERSON> that this year's contract given <PERSON> Clymer </PERSON>'s firm was properly bid However, the <ORGANIZATION> Inquirer </ORGANIZATION> reported that <PERSON> Dunleavy </PERSON> said that previous year's contracts with <PERSON> Clymer </PERSON>'s firm were not awarded through competitive procurement policies required by the federal government. The newspaper said federal money was used. In his report to <PERSON> Weldon </PERSON>, which has been made public, <PERSON> Dunleavy </PERSON> also said the partnership misspent $ 125,000 in federal funds on ineligible items such as a promotion film and advertising. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Tancredi </PERSON>, a top official of the partnership, resigned in July after coming under fire for his handling of the organization's finances. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, the inspector general, said <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> was conducting a general audit of the partnership that was `` not limited in any way, shape or form.'' <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> was doing another audit in <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> when `` a combination of things occurred concurrently'' that convinced it of the need to look into the partnership, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said. He declined to be more specific.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-VOA-Angola     10-02 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-VOA-Angola,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Voice of America Solves Angola Broadcasting Problem</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> says it's taken care of a Catch-22 situation in which its broadcasts to <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> were disturbed by a radio station run by U.S.-backed rebels. But Rep. <PERSON> Mervyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Dymally </PERSON>, D-Calif., says he wants to know exactly what happened this summer when `` The <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cockerel </ORGANIZATION>,'' a station experts say was set up by the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>, interrupted Portuguese-language broadcasts by the <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION>, the U.S.-government-supported station that serves overseas listeners <PERSON> Dymally </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on international operations, said last week he'll raise the issue in panel hearings this year. `` I wrote a letter of protest about it,'' he said. `` The need is great for the <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> to have at this time unhindered and unhampered access to its consumers in <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Dymally </PERSON> said in a letter. The problem with the broadcasts is an outgrowth of the conflict in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> where the rebels headed by <PERSON> Jonas </PERSON> <PERSON> Savimbi </PERSON> are battling the Soviet-backed government in <LOCATION> Luanda </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Savimbi </PERSON>, who is visiting the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> this week, receives American government money to finance his group, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> for the Total Independence of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, known as <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> operates the black cockerel resistance station, which <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Bender </PERSON>, a professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, said is a `` CIA-supported clandestine radio station.'' Initial reports, first published in <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> last month, said the <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> station blocked 12 minutes of an Aug. 18 <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> broadcast that included four minutes of a speech by Angolan President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> dos </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON>. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connell </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, the parent agency of <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION>, said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials do not believe the <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> station intentionally fouled <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> broadcasts. `` We do n't consider it jamming,'' he said. But the two stations used frequencies that were close to each other so the <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> listener could hear the rebel station's broadcasts at the end of the <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> program. `` You could hear their signature. It sounds like a rooster crowing,'' he said. To eliminate confusion, <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> changed frequencies, he said. <PERSON> Jardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Muekalia </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, denied the rebels interfered with the <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> broadcasts. But he charged that <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION>'s reporter in <LOCATION> Luanda </LOCATION> had prepared biased reports designed to imply the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> favored the Angolan government. <PERSON> O'Connell </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> has dismissed the notion the reporter is not objective. `` We have been pleased with what he has done. We have not seen any bias,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 0029EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GIBill     10-02 0592</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-GI Bill,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>GI Bill Running out for Vietnam-era Veterans</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT GREENE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Many <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> era veterans who want to take advantage of the GI <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> to further their educations will soon run out of luck. The GI bill program that covers people who served during <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> ends Dec. 31. A new GI bill has taken its place, but only the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans who remained on active duty from June 1985 through June 1988 may benefit. According to Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>., 250,000 veterans are affected Many are GIs who stayed in the military but left before the end of June 1988. Although legislative efforts have been made to extend the benefits, neither veterans' committee in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> or <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is taking up the measures. `` It's a damn shame this is going to come to an end and is going to hurt so many <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans who have made the military a career,'' said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Egan </PERSON> of the 35,000-member <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> Veterans of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> VVA </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Egan </PERSON>, like <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of the Non-Commissioned Officers' Association, argue that the veterans being squeezed out of the programs are the ones who `` carried'' the military during the 1970s, when it was plagued by low enlistment and low morale. The 153,000-member <ORGANIZATION> Fleet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, representing career enlisted personnel in the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, has urged an extension of benefits. Neither of the two major veterans' groups, the American Legion or the Veterans of Foreign Wars, spoke out on the issue in a recent <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee hearing on the GI bill. Rep. G.V. `` Sonny'' <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, opposes extending benefits under the so-called `` Cold War'' GI bill. The <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> Democrat says the bill is too costly, unnecessary to help veterans readjust 14 years after the war, and unneeded for a group of people who had already made a career choice _ for the military. `` It's time to move on to a new bill designed to recruit and retrain rather than just reintegrate,'' said committee spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Holley </PERSON>. The GI bill that expires Dec. 31 followed the Korean War GI bill and the pioneering World War II GI bill. There was also a Veterans' Educational Assistance Program for people who enlisted from 1977 to 1985. The program offered a maximum benefit of $ 225 monthly and was based entirely on the enlistees' contributions. The <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> era bill is the most used, having served 8.1 million veterans, compared with 7.8 million for the World War II program. The <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> bill, with no contributions, pays a maximum $ 376 million monthly benefit to full-time students with no dependents. The maximum eligibility is 45 months. The Veterans' Affairs Department said in February that 750,000 people were eligible for benefits under the Vietnam-era bill and 60,000 were currently enrolled. The new program relies partly on pay deductions from recruits. It pays $ 250 to $ 300 a month for up to three years, reflecting the three years of active duty required for eligibility. A person is eligible for up to 10 years after discharge. Those who entered the service during <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> could take advantage of the new program if they served three years of active duty starting June 30, 1985, when the bill took effect. The <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> vets were not required to make further contributions. But <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> of the 160,000-member <ORGANIZATION> NCO </ORGANIZATION> group said the service regulations force many career non-commissioned officers to retire, and many lost eligibility because they had to quit before the end of June 1988.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 0037EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0729 10-02 0731</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0729,0754</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: AMs separates on Dapporto moved as a0699, on Fairbank as a0748,
on O'Meara as a0744.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>William Fairbank</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>STANFORD, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Fairbank </PERSON>, a professor emertitus of physics at <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> who pioneered in low-temperature superconductivity, died Saturday after a heart attack. He was 72. <PERSON> Fairbank </PERSON>'s first experiment in superconductivity _ the ability of some materials to offer no resistance to an electrical current if they are cooled to near absolute zero _ was in 1947 with his brother, <PERSON> Henry </PERSON>, also a physicist. <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Fairbank </PERSON>'s influence on physics included the university's development of the superconducting accelerator, in which superconductivity is achieved at two degrees above absolute zero. That led to the first demonstration of a free electron laser. <PERSON> Fairbank </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> on Feb. 24, 1917. He graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Whitman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and earned his Ph.D. from <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1948. Before joining <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> faculty in 1959, he taught at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Amherst </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, and worked on the staff of the Radiation Laboratory at the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Carlo Dapporto</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comic actor <PERSON> Carlo </PERSON> <PERSON> Dapporto </PERSON>, known in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> as the King of the Joke, died of a heart attack Sunday at a clinic in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, the Italian news agency <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION> reported. He was 88. <PERSON> Dapporto </PERSON> was known for the roles he played in a series of films in the 1950s and for his appeances on variety shows on radio and television. His greatest success came in the <PERSON> Ettore </PERSON> <PERSON> Scola </PERSON> film `` La Famiglia -LRB- The Family -RRB-.'' He portrayed an old man in a role written for him by <PERSON> Scola </PERSON> and played opposite his son <PERSON> Massimo </PERSON>. He is survived by his son.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Harold R. Fatzer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOPEKA, Kan. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Chief Justice <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fatzer </PERSON> was found dead of a self-inflicted gunshot wound to the head Saturday at his <LOCATION> Topeka </LOCATION> home. He was 79. <PERSON> Fatzer </PERSON>, who served on the <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> from 1956 to 1977 and was chief justice from 1971 to 1977, was state attorney general from 1949 to 1954. <PERSON> Fatzer </PERSON> attended <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Washburn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> in 1933. He was <ORGANIZATION> Edwards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> attorney until 1941, when he became chief counsel for the state <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welfare </ORGANIZATION>. After serving with the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> in World War II, <PERSON> Fatzer </PERSON> was elected to his own two-year term as attorney general in November 1950, and was re-elected in 1952 and 1954. He was appointed to the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on March 1, 1956, with 10 months remaining in his third term as attorney general. He served on the high court until he retired in September 1977.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Walter A. O'Meara</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Meara </PERSON>, an advertising man who served the <ORGANIZATION> OSS </ORGANIZATION> as well as the 1952 presidential campaign of <PERSON> Adlai </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevenson </PERSON> and became a best-selling author, died Friday in <LOCATION> Cohasset </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. He was 92. His best-sellers among his 16 books included `` Grand <LOCATION> Portage </LOCATION>,'' a novel based on the life of fur trader <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Harmon </PERSON>, and `` <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> Gothic,'' a mystery novel. A native of <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, he graduated from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin </ORGANIZATION> at Madison with a journalism degree in 1920. After working at the <ORGANIZATION> Duluth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> O'Meara </PERSON> joined the <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> advertising agency in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. He later worked for <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bowles </PERSON> advertising in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. During World War II, he was chief of planning for the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, predecessor of the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>, and headed the information department for the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Price </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. He was media director for <PERSON> Adlai </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevenson </PERSON>'s 1952 presidential campaign. <PERSON> O'Meara </PERSON> left advertising in 1950 to pursue his writing career.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Christine Word Atkinson</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MORELAND, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> Word </PERSON> <PERSON> Atkinson </PERSON>, a retired elementary school teacher and mother of humorist <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> Grizzard </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, died Sunday of scleroderma. She was 77. Mrs. <PERSON> Atkinson </PERSON> taught first-grade pupils at various elementary schools in <LOCATION> Coweta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> for 20 years before retiring on disability in 1972. Her son, a syndicated columnist for the <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal-Constitution </ORGANIZATION>, is the author of several books. Miss Word married <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Grizzard </PERSON> <PERSON> Sr. </PERSON> in 1941. They later divorced, and <PERSON> Grizzard </PERSON> died in 1970. She married H.B. <PERSON> Atkinson </PERSON> in 1954. Surviving in addition to her son are two sisters, <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> and </PERSON> <PERSON> Una </PERSON> <PERSON> Word </PERSON> <PERSON> Coutee </PERSON>, both of <PERSON> Norman </PERSON>; and a brother, Dr. <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Word </PERSON> <PERSON> of </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowden </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Truman'sFDR     10-02 0707</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Truman's FDR,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Truman Pictures Roosevelt as God-like, But Flawed by an Ego</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> says he regarded his mentor, <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>, `` almost as a god'' even though <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> had an ego that sometimes got him into political trouble. In fact, the 33rd president says about the 32nd, <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>'s ego was a factor which compelled him to break a tradition as old as the republic and run for a third and fourth terms. <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> discusses his boss in a posthumous book, `` Where the Buck Stops,'' to be published late this month by <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Books </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. It is edited by his daughter, <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>, who says her father wanted its publication withheld until after he and wife <PERSON> Bess </PERSON> were dead so that he could be completely candid. The book gives <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>'s assessment of <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> as a strong leader but weak administrator and as a president whose ego sometimes led him to mistakes. He cites one big example: <ORGANIZATION> FDR </ORGANIZATION>'s `` court-packing'' plan of 1937. <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> wanted <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to give him the power to enlarge the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, which had been striking down one New Deal program after another. <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> writes that he supported <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>'s plan out of his knowledge from history that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had changed the number of justices over the years. But <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> says <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>'s ego led him to overestimate his power and led to the most severe setback of his presidency. `` I did n't agree at all with <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>'s obvious feeling that he had become so popular and so powerful that he could go ahead and push through anything, even an unprecedented plan like that one, without help and without bothering to try to convince people opposed to the plan that he was right,'' <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> writes. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> lost a bill that might have been very helpful to the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people because <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>'s ego misinformed him and made him believe he could win on his own.'' <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> also says that he was troubled when <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> decided in 1940 to ignore the two-term tradition and seek a third term. He agreed with <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> that the threat of war made it the wrong time to change leaders, but he says FDR was motivated by the belief he was the only person in the country capable of leading it. `` I thought there might have been a partially wrong reason involved: that he was n't doing it only because he felt it was best to keep the same experienced man in place, but that he might also have felt that he was the only possible man who could lead our country to victory in the war,'' <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> writes. At another point, <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> says, `` I guess that was his principal defect, that growing ego of his, which probably was n't too minuscule to start with, though perhaps it was his only flaw.'' For all that, <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> says he admired Roosevelt enormously. He cites his record in fighting both the Depression and the war, and asks: `` Is n't that enough to make us think of him almost as a god?'' `` He was a very, very pleasant man and a great conversationalist,'' he writes, `` with marvelous flashes of humor in almost everything he said, and he had a personality that made people feel close to him.'' <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> also pictures <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> as `` a first-rate executive, never afraid to make those decisions he made'' but a weak administrator `` because he just was n't able to delegate authority to anybody else.'' He said, `` I was always of the opinion that he ought to have restraints, as every president should have, and I sometimes argued with him myself when he wanted to go too far or when he set out to do something strictly on his own and without the agreement or help of others.'' Historians have written that <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> were not close and <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> did not keep his vice president informed, despite his failing health. FDR died early in his fourth term without even telling <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> about the atom bomb. <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> accepted <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> as his running mate in 1944 after becoming wary of Vice President <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON>'s left-wing inclinations. <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>, a senator from <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, was widely respected for thoroughgoing investigations he had conducted into wasteful war contracts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CongressRdp     10-02 0798</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress Rdp,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrats Say They Have Senate Votes to Kill Capital Gains Cut</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic leaders claim they have the votes in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to kill President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s capital gains tax cut but concede a watered-down version may get through <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> this year. Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> predicted Sunday that the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> probably will vote this week to repeal the <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> catastrophic health care coverage that it enacted only last year. `` I hope personally that the program is retained on a modified form,'' <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, D-Wash., said on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Meet the Press'' program `` But ... there are a great number of Republicans and some Democrats in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> who are in favor of repeal. If I were guessing today, I think it probably would be repealed.'' <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, also appearing on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, likened the House-passed version of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s cut in capital gains taxes to the cocaine-based drug crack and said flatly that the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will not enact it. `` It is so bad, so wrong for the economy,'' he said. `` It will do for the deficit what crack does for the user: a quick short high followed by a long, painful depression.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> plans this week to consider an alternative proposed by Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, and endorsed by a majority of <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> which would instead restore partial tax deductibility for contributions to Individual Retirement Accounts. In other congressional action this week: _ The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> will take up a long-awaited bill to protect the nation's waterways from oil spills similar to the Exxon-Valdez tanker accident in March that dumped 10 million gallons of crude into <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> _ Negotiations continue between <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> conferees on a dozen appropriations bills needed to finance government programs in fiscal 1990, which began Sunday A major sticking point is how much the government will spend on Star Wars in fiscal 1990: The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has appropriated $ 3.7 billion but the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> wants to spend only $ 3.1 billion. _ Competing child care measures, both targeted primarily to low-income families but one with the potential of being expanded to eventually subsidize day care for the middle class as well, will be considered by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> _ The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Government Operations subcommittee on employment and housing continues its investigation into scandals at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> with a return appearance by self-described influence-peddler <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Manafort </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said Sunday he is positive that the 27-month capital gains tax cut approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> last week will not win passage in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. However, he said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s `` irresponsible position ... makes it extremely difficult to prevent any tax cut from occurring.'' The House-passed measure would reduce from 33 percent to 19.6 percent the maximum tax rate on profits from the sale of stocks and other investments until 1992. The rate would then climb back up to 28 percent with assets indexed so that any gains attributed to inflation after that point would not be taxed. Economists predict the cut will generate some $ 9.4 billion in deficit-reduction revenues over the next three years. After then, revenue would fall and worsen the deficit by a total of $ 21 billion over the following five years, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Taxation. `` I'm confident that this so-called yo-yo _ on two years, off two years _ and the way in which it's constructed can not pass,'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> acknowledged that many Democrats favor enacting a differential for taxing such profits at rates less than those for wages, interest or dividends. `` Whether or not they will coalesce behind any plan along with Republicans, I do n't know,'' he said. `` It will be very close on some other plan.'' Regarding catastrophic health care, <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said he is confident the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will retain key benefits under the program, although it may change how they are financed. The administration has opposed changing or repealing the program. The wealthier among the 33 million elderly Americans covered by the program have balked at having to pay premiums this year of up to $ 800 to cover the hospital and physicians' bills for those with lower incomes. <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> also said <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> likely will not complete action by an Oct. 16 deadline on a deficit-reduction bill, which would include any tax measure or changes in catastrophic care coverage. That is the date when broad spending cuts in both military and domestic programs will be triggered automatically unless <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> comes up with $ 6 billion in new revenues or programs for fiscal 1990. `` We might have some few days in which there would be a technical sequestration, that is an across-the-board cutting through executive order of all the accounts ...,'' <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> said. `` I do n't think that's going to be a permanent situation.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891002-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-89 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-StarWars     10-02 0472</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Star Wars,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Members Doubt Senate Rationale on Star Wars</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
