<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0010EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-StubbornCitizen     01-14 0379</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stubborn Citizen,0391</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vietnam Vet Refuses to Prove Citizenship, Loses Job</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FONTANA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Elmore </PERSON> figures he proved he's an American by serving in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, so he refuses to document his citizenship to keep his job. That refusal got the 40-year-old machinist fired Friday, the deadline his boss set for filling out a government form employers have to keep to prove all their workers are citizens or legal <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> residents. `` When I was 18 years old, they sent me a draft notice. They knew I was a citizen then,'' <PERSON> Elmore </PERSON> said. His boss, <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> of S & amp; D Specialties, said he wishes he could keep <PERSON> Elmore </PERSON> in the $ 12-an-hour job making parts for hydraulic cylinders. But if he did, the company would risk a $ 500 fine for failing to keep the new form required by the <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. `` They did n't give me a lot of options. It's a federal law,'' <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> said. The law is part of the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986, which extended amnesty to illegal aliens who can prove they're longtime <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> residents The law also imposed the employer penalties in hopes of cutting the influx of new illegals. <PERSON> Elmore </PERSON> acknowledged the government did n't want much: He was supposed to fill out the form and supply driver's license and Social Security numbers. `` It's a matter of principle, all right,'' he said. He ignored the form during the six months he's been working in this town 50 miles east of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. But <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> decided he had to set a deadline, and the men agreed Friday would be <PERSON> Elmore </PERSON>'s last unless he did the paperwork. <PERSON> Elmore </PERSON> went to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> as an <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> enlisted man in 1969 and said the government should have taken military service into account. Immigration and <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> said the service ca n't make exemptions for veterans. `` Does he want to cooperate and help us control our border?'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> asked. `` He did serve his country, and this is another way of helping his country.'' <PERSON> Elmore </PERSON> does n't have any firm plans for a job hunt. One thing's for sure: He wo n't take a job if they ask him to fill out the immigration form `` I do n't think I will,'' he said. `` I really do n't.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CaveMarathon     01-14 0362</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cave Marathon,0370</SECOND>
<UNK>Italian Researcher Descends Into Cave for Isolation Experiment</UNK>
<DATELINE>CARLSBAD, N.M. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 27-year-old Italian researcher has begun months of isolation in a Plexiglas enclosure inside Lost Cave as part of an experiment. `` Ciao!'' <PERSON> Stefania </PERSON> <PERSON> Follini </PERSON> called out Friday as she grinned, waved and descended a 20-foot ladder. Pioneer Frontier Researches and Explorations, an Italian team of speleologists and researchers under the direction of <PERSON> Maurizio </PERSON> <PERSON> Montalbini </PERSON>, hopes their experiment will yield knowledge about the effects of long-term space travel. Joining her underground for a brief farewell party were <PERSON> Montalbini </PERSON>, team physician <PERSON> Andrea </PERSON> <PERSON> Galvagno </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> representative <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodbar </PERSON>, and several friends. They shared wine, and Ms. <PERSON> Follini </PERSON> sang a few songs and played the guitar before her guests left her alone in the cave, and its entrance was sealed. Ms. <PERSON> Follini </PERSON> then began to make herself at home in the 100-square-foot enclosure she had not seen before Friday. The room in which she plans to study English and practice judo is sparsely furnished with a red metal chair and a table holding two computers. It has 400 books. The cave is adapted so that Ms. <PERSON> Follini </PERSON> will be isolated from sound, sunlight and human contact _ even the sound of a human voice _ for at least four and probably five months. She will be monitored by a video camera and brain electrode implants. <PERSON> Montalbini </PERSON> called her isolation `` a long and lonely circumnavigation, not of the world, but of a single mind _ your own.'' Supplies pack shelves from floor to ceiling. Her bed consists of several foam pads spread across the wooden floor. Her chemical toilet is secluded from the camera's view. A five-month food and water supply are stored in the cave. While electrode implants monitor her brain waves, Ms. <PERSON> Follini </PERSON> will place blood and urine samples in a container to be pulled to the surface. The samples will be tested for immunology, endocrinology and hormones at three U.S.-based medical centers. <PERSON> Montalbini </PERSON> said the tests would come at random intervals to keep Ms. <PERSON> Follini </PERSON> from knowing how much time elapses. Officials say an essential element of the experiment will be her time perception.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WheatCrop Bjt   01-14 0593</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wheat Crop, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Greater Demand Pushing Up Prices, Planting Plans</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rising demand and easier federal curbs are encouraging the nation's wheat farmers to boost production this year, beginning with nearly 6 million acres more of winter wheat for the 1989 harvest. The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Friday that winter wheat plantings last fall totaled 54.5 million acres, up 12 percent from 48.8 million acres seeded for last year's harvest. Winter wheat is planted in the fall and harvested the following year. It accounts for about three-fourths of the total <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat output. Production was cut last year by drought, and brisk export demand has helped reduce stockpiles. With greater demand, prices have risen substantially the past year. Also, farmers are being required to idle only 10 percent of their wheat base acres for 1989 in order to qualify for government price supports, compared with 27.5 percent previously. `` All states increased acreage from 1988 except <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Dakotas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>,'' the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said in its report. `` <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> are unchanged.'' In <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, the largest producer, wheat plantings jumped 22 percent to 12.4 million acres. Nationally, the 54.5 million acres of winter wheat planted for 1989 is the largest acreage since 57.8 million acres were planted for the 1985 harvest, according to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> records. In a supply-and-demand analysis, officials said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> total wheat stockpile on June 1, the beginning of the 1989-90 wheat marketing year, could be whittled to around 534 million bushels, less than half the 1.26 billion bushels in the June 1, 1988, inventory. It was more than 1.82 billion bushels on June 1, 1987. Export subsidies and other government programs have helped boost wheat sales to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and other foreign buyers. Total shipments in 1988-89 are expected to be around 1.5 billion bushels, more than double the 700 million bushels needed to cover <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> domestic food requirements. Meanwhile, wheat prices at the farm have risen to a predicted range in the current marketing year of $ 3.60 to $ 3.75 per bushel, on the average, compared with $ 2.57 in 1987-88 and $ 2.42 in 1986-87. A comparable situation has developed for some other grains hit by last year's drought. Corn prices, for example, were forecast at an average of $ 2.30 to $ 2.70 per bushel in the 1988-89 marketing year that runs through August, compared with $ 1.94 last season and $ 1.50 in 1986-87. Another report showed the Dec. 1 inventory of corn at 7.07 billion bushels, down 28 percent from a year earlier. The wheat inventory, at 1.71 billion bushels, was down 32 percent from Dec. 1, 1987. Soybean stocks as of Dec. 1 were reported at 1.37 billion bushels, down 22 percent from a year earlier. A review of overall 1988 crop production showed relatively minor adjustments in <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s previously announced harvest figures, with the exception of corn. Last year's corn harvest was reported at 4.92 billion bushels, up from 4.67 billion bushels estimated last November. Even so, the 1988 corn harvest was down 30 percent from 1987 production, with the drought-reduced yield averaging 84.6 bushels per acre, compared with the record level of 119.4 bushels per acre in 1987. The 1988 harvest of all wheat was a decade low of 1.81 billion bushels, down 14 percent from 1987, and soybeans last year totaled 1.54 billion bushels, 20 percent below 1987 production. Cotton output, at 15.4 million bales, was up 5 percent from 1987 and was the most in seven years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-RuralFlights     01-14 0497</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rural Flights,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>DOT Reconsidering Cutback In Rural Air Service</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Transportion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is taking a second look at a plan it introduced last month that would force some small airlines to eliminate unprofitable routes in sparsely populated areas. <ORGANIZATION> DOT </ORGANIZATION> cited budget restraints when it proposed sharply curtailing its `` Essential Air Service'' program. Under the program, the federal government subsidizes flights to and from about 150 small cities that would probably not otherwise have air service because the routes are not moneymakers. On Friday, <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Paris </PERSON> said an announcement could be made as early as the beginning of next week about changes in the <ORGANIZATION> DOT </ORGANIZATION> plan. He would not elaborate, but another department official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said: `` There is something under consideration. There is movement to responding to a congressional request.'' He added, `` Nothing has been signed yet, and it's not a decision until somebody signs it.'' The original proposal was swiftly attacked by lawmakers from <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> and other states that would be especially hard hit. Sen. <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Rockefeller </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said the reductions would be `` a fatal blow'' to the economic growth efforts of some communities, and Rep. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Kan </LOCATION>., said the plan could mean the end of commuter air service in The original DOT action was in response to a $ 6.6 million shortfall in the air service program's appropriation for the 1989 fiscal year. The department proposed four likely plans for coping with the cuts. One of them, considered the harshest by some, would cut 53 cities entirely out of the program. One-third of those cities are more than 100 miles from the next nearest airport. In defending the cuts, the department has pointed to little-used flights that receive subsidies in remote areas. For example, the government spent $ 379,000 in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> last year to keep flights going between <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moultrie </LOCATION> that averaged one passenger. The route would probably be eliminated if the subsidy ends. But <PERSON> Rockefeller </PERSON> said ending subsidies to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> cities could do more than simply inconvenience passengers who would have to travel to another airport further away. `` For rural areas, there is a direct link between adequate air service and economic development,'' <PERSON> Rockefeller </PERSON> said. `` One of the first questions business leaders ask when they come to look at rural areas is: ` What's the air service like?''' In <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, the cutbacks could mean the end of flights in and out of <LOCATION> Beckley </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Clarksburg-Fairmont </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Elkins </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Morgantown </LOCATION>. In releasing the plan on Dec. 14, the <ORGANIZATION> DOT </ORGANIZATION> said it hoped it could take effect on March 1, following a public comment period. <ORGANIZATION> Exec </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> II </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, which operates in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, said in a letter to Rep. <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Leath </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>: `` From our standpoint, any cut in the <ORGANIZATION> Essential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> program would be devastating. Exec Express II has been rebuilding air service in communities which have not had adequate service in the past.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0040EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iran-Contra     01-14 0553</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan, Bush Fight Subpoenas To Appear In Former Aide's Trial</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> are challenging subpoenas from <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>, while prosecutors say <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s continued demand to use classified information is an effort to torpedo his upcoming trial on charges stemming from the Iran-Contra affair. The government filed a motion in federal court Friday to quash the subpoenas for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, whose testimony is being sought by <PERSON> North </PERSON> as part of the fired <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide's defense. Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said <PERSON> North </PERSON> `` has not made the requisite showing of relevance, materiality and need for specifically identified information that he seeks to obtain'' from <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said that in accordance with an offer made last Sept. 28, the president will consider furnishing appropriate information with written answers to `` reasonable written questions'' from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> and that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` joins that offer.'' <PERSON> North </PERSON> served the subpoenas Dec. 22. `` The spectacle of a former or sitting President being subjected to peremptory judicial process may chill foreign governments in the way they deal with the President now and in the future,'' the government said in the motion to quash the subpoenas for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to appear at the trial. North's lawyers, meanwhile, served the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> with subpoenas for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to turn over various personal papers for use by the defense, said department spokesman <PERSON> Loye </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>. Earlier in the day, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> dismissed the two central charges alleging that <PERSON> North </PERSON> illegally diverted more than $ 14 million in U.S.-Iran arms sale proceeds to the Nicaraguan rebels. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> had filed a motion Jan. 5 seeking to have the two charges dropped, citing <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s `` insistence on introducing classified information in his defense'' and the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's refusal to release material the judge ruled that <PERSON> North </PERSON> would need at trial. North's attorneys said proof of their client's innocence is contained in classified material. Twelve criminal charges remain against <PERSON> North </PERSON>, and the issue of dealing with classified information in open court remains a problem. Attorneys for both sides held closed-door morning and afternoon sessions with <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> on classified information as it relates to the remaining counts. The attorneys will resume the closed-door discussions next Tuesday. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> said in a court filing Thursday that the remaining charges can be tried `` without opening the door for'' North `` to use reams of classified information'' and that <PERSON> North </PERSON> should be barred from seeking to prove `` a host of irrelevant matters for the sole purpose of scuttling the entire case'' by using national security grounds to do so. However, defense attorney <PERSON> Brendan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said last week, `` classified information pervades the remaining charges as well.'' Nine of the counts focus on charges that <PERSON> North </PERSON> concealed from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and former Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> his efforts on behalf of the Contras. Four of the nine deal with alleged concealment of a diversion of money to the Cntras from the administration's secret arms sales to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. North also is accused of illegally accepting a $ 13,800 security system at his home from co-defendant <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>, converting to his own use at least $ 4,300 in traveler's checks from <LOCATION> Contra </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Calero </PERSON> and conspiring to defraud the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> of tax revenue in connection with charitable contributions supporting the Contras.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0040EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Exports     01-14 0440</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Exports,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Verity Says US Products Below World Standards</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Outgoing Commerce Secretary <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Verity </PERSON> says many American products are below world standards of quality and the Japanese are two years ahead in developing salable products from American inventions. Blaming antitrust laws for a large part of the problem, <ORGANIZATION> Verity </ORGANIZATION> urged President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to prepare for `` economic warfare'' in the 1990s. `` What's going to be on the top burner of the 1990s for the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is trading, and how is <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> going to make sure it will be the number one player,'' <ORGANIZATION> Verity </ORGANIZATION> said Friday in a last speech for `` Export Now,'' a campaign he has pressed in his 18 months in office. As President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> retires next week, <ORGANIZATION> Verity </ORGANIZATION> will follow. An old friend of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> from the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> oil industry, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON>, has been named to succeed him. `` The reason that many American products are not selling abroad is very simple: because they do n't have sufficient quality to do it,'' he said. He told how his family company, <ORGANIZATION> Armco </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, had been a big supplier of sheet steel to the American auto industry, but had to work five years to produce steel that would meet the standards of <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION>, the Japanese auto-maker. <ORGANIZATION> Verity </ORGANIZATION> says antitrust laws discourage cooperation of American companies, creating a barrier to more effective competition. `` It -LRB- should -RRB- be possible for high technology companies or other companies to get together, not only just research together, but develop and produce together and market together and then compete,'' he said. `` That's what has to happen if we're going to stay in some very important markets including the semiconductor market ... or high definition television, or super-conductivity, and there's much more coming down the path.'' This country has some marvelous technology, but it is less expert at transforming theoretical discoveries into products that can sell, he complained. `` The Japanese can do this two years quicker than we can,'' he said. `` This is a serious problem if we develop a technology but if the Japanese take our technology and use it and we're two years delayed in getting into the marketplace ... That's going to be disastrous to this country.'' <ORGANIZATION> Verity </ORGANIZATION>'s criticism of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> industry was not the first from a high figure in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>, who was deputy to former <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, has criticized what he called a `` corpocracy'' in American business for what he saw as lack of initiative. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> is to be secretary of State under President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> will head the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People-Sadler 1stLd-Writethru   01-14 0405</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People-Sadler, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0796,0415</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Green Beret Ballad' Singer Barry Sadler Center Of Guardian Dispute</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 5th graf, `The 48-year-old...his guardian,' to CORRECT
year Sadler had No. 1 hit to 1966 sted 1965.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DWIGHT WOODWARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer-songwriter <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Sadler </PERSON>, brain-damaged from shooting, was ordered Friday to undergo psychiatric evaluation by a judge who may appoint a guardian for the `` Ballad of the Green Berets'' singer. Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON> filed a restraining order preventing <PERSON> Sadler </PERSON> from being moved against his will from <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, and said <PERSON> Sadler </PERSON> must be evaluated by Jan. 20 to determine if he is competent to make his own decisions. The judge said he will decide after the evaluation if the court has jurisdiction to make <PERSON> Sadler </PERSON>'s mother his guardian. `` If he is competent, maybe we do n't need a guardian,'' said <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON>, adding that <PERSON> Sadler </PERSON>'s 24-year-old son, <PERSON> Thor </PERSON>, would be allowed to visit his father Friday. The 48-year-old author and singer-songwriter, whose `` Ballad of the Green Berets'' was a No. 1 hit in 1966, is at the center of competing legal bids from his mother and son to become his guardian. A judge in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, on Tuesday named <PERSON> Thor </PERSON> as temporary guardian, but <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON> said that judge agreed Friday to the psychiatric evaluation. <PERSON> Sadler </PERSON>, who was shot in the head in <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> in September, checked out of <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Wade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> hospital Sunday against medical advice. <PERSON> Sadler </PERSON> left after he learned hospital officials planned to send him back to a <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> <LOCATION> VA </LOCATION> hospital, said his attorney, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Meissner </PERSON>. <PERSON> Thor </PERSON> <PERSON> Sadler </PERSON> said, `` 30 percent of his brain was destroyed when the bullet went through it. ... I do n't know if he is capable of making decisions.'' <PERSON> Meissner </PERSON> said Friday that <PERSON> Sadler </PERSON> is mentally competent and wants his mother, <PERSON> Blanche </PERSON> <PERSON> Bebe </PERSON> <PERSON> Sadler </PERSON>, appointed guardian to help him conduct his affairs. A hearing is set in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> Wednesday on a petition filed Jan. 10 by <PERSON> Sadler </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Lavona </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON>, and children, <PERSON> Thor </PERSON>, <PERSON> Baron </PERSON> and <PERSON> Brooke </PERSON>, asking the court to appoint one of them guardian and return <PERSON> Sadler </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> police reports indicate <PERSON> Sadler </PERSON> was shot by accident when a gun fell out of his pocket and went off while he was riding in a taxi, his son said. <PERSON> Sadler </PERSON> also is the author of more than 20 books, featuring <LOCATION> Casca </LOCATION>, a mercenary con demned to everlasting life until the Second Coming of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NerveGas-Arrest     01-14 0562</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nerve Gas-Arrest,0580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Customs Official Says Destination Of Nerve Gas May Never Be Known</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL J. WAKIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEWARK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities have identified <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> as a possible destination for a planned illegal shipment of nerve gas, but the final arrival point may never be known, a <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> official said. `` We do n't have to know -LRB- it -RRB- to make a case'' against two men charged Thursday with trying to export the deadly gas, said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mercier </PERSON>, head customs investigator in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>. Prosecutors must only prove that the Korean-American and British business men tried to circumvent licensing requirements in exporting restricted materials, he said Friday. The charge carries a maximum five-year prison term and a $ 250,000 fine. `` I'm hopeful that through investigation, or whatever else,'' the destination would be positively determined, <PERSON> Mercier </PERSON> said. But he pointed out that the deal never went through. `` It's not as though there's a trail for us to follow,'' he said. Authorities said Friday they are trying to learn the identities of two other people accused of plotting with the suspects. <PERSON> Juwhan </PERSON> <PERSON> Yun </PERSON>, 48, was arrested Thursday at what he thought would be a meeting with an arms supplier, who was actually a <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> undercover agent. He has been ordered jailed pending a bail hearing Tuesday on charges of conspiring to illegally export sarin, a nerve gas. An arrest warrant was issued for <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Caplan </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> businessman who authorities said was seeking to obtain the gas _ $ 5 million worth in the form of 500 quarter-ton bombs _ from <PERSON> Yun </PERSON>. The possibility of his extradition is being studied, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> prosecutors said. The complaint filed in federal court accusing <PERSON> Caplan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Yun </PERSON> said the men met Jan. 9 about the gas deal with two other people in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. `` During the course of the meeting, <PERSON> Yun </PERSON> called the undercover agent twice and asked him for more detailed information about the sarin,'' the complaint said. The complaint also detailed discussions between <PERSON> Yun </PERSON> and K.Y. <PERSON> Joo </PERSON>, identified as a close business associate of <PERSON> Yun </PERSON> and the head of <ORGANIZATION> Kwang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trading </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. Authorities said <PERSON> Yun </PERSON> and <PERSON> Joo </PERSON> discussed at least three missile and military radar equipment deals that apparently involved <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> as a destination. Authorities also said that at one point during negotiations <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> was to be the recipient of the sarin. The complaint said that during a meeting Jan. 4 between <PERSON> Yun </PERSON> and the agent, the agent asked <PERSON> Yun </PERSON> `` if a final destination is the country with the ` I' in it and <PERSON> Yun </PERSON> answered yes.'' But that could not be verified, said First Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chertoff </PERSON>. <PERSON> Caplan </PERSON>, identified as president of <ORGANIZATION> Domino </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> and Domino Avionics, was described in British court as a former military consultant. <PERSON> Caplan </PERSON> could not be reached for comment. Messages left at his <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> offices were not returned. <PERSON> Yun </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dratch </PERSON>, also failed to return phone messages. Concern over the potential spread of chemical weapons has intensified recently. At a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> conference in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> on Wednesday, more than 140 nations reaffirmed the 1925 <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> Protocol banning the use of chemical arms. <PERSON> Yun </PERSON>'s arrest came the same day the West German government reversed itself and said it suspected German companies helped build a Libyan plant the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> believes is a chemical weapons factory. <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> says the plant will produce medicine.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SpeedLimit Bjt   01-14 0487</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Speed Limit, Bjt,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Death Toll Up 352 On Highways With 65 mph Limit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rural interstate highway accidents killed 352 more people than a year earlier in states where the speed limit was raised to 65 mph, while death tolls on other roads decreased slightly, according to a government report. The 19 percent increase in deaths occurred over a period that varied for each state, depending on when drivers were allowed to go faster, said the report Friday by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Traffic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. Congress authorized the increased limit beginning April 2, 1987, and 38 states have adopted it for their rural interstates. Highway deaths in those states on urban interstates and other roads where the 55 mph limit remained totaled 21,366 for the same period in 1986 and 21,231 in 1987, the report said. Fatalities in states that raised the speed limit increased by an average nearly three times as high as in 10 states that kept the limit at 55 on all roads, the report showed. But the safety administration, in releasing the first of three planned annual reports, said there were `` substantial variations'' among the states and some such as <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> actually showed fewer deaths on rural interstates after new speeds were posted. The report also said there was not enough evidence to determine the speed limit's long-term impact on highway safety. Critics of the higher speed limit said the increased death toll was enough reason to return to the 55 mph limit nationwide. `` This report can be summed up in two words: speed kills,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations transportation subcommittee, who has opposed the increase. Overall, 373 more people died on rural interstates in 1987 than in 1986, the report said. Of those, 352 were in states that raise the speed limit and 21 in states that did not. The highway safety agency, in its 67-page report, said rural interstate fatalities account for only 5 percent of Americans killed in road accidents, and the increase had only a small impact on overall traffic fatalities which total about 46,000 a year. The report noted that 24,000 people are killed each year in crashes where alcohol is involved and 8,000 are pedestrians hit by vehicles. `` <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> continues to believe that setting speed limits is a matter for state legislatures to decide based on their review of available fatality and injury data, actual experience and local conditions,'' the report said. It noted that <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> experienced large increases in fatalities after raising the limit to 65 but states that did not also had significant increases. They include <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. States that increased the speed limit to 65 and had overall decreases in traffic fatalities included <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0108EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     01-14 0849</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0886</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Although <PERSON> Angela </PERSON> <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON> has insisted she's leaving the popular detective program, `` Murder, She Wrote,'' negotiations are under way to keep her in the role of <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Fletcher </PERSON> Universal TV spokesman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Crutchfield </PERSON> said <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON>'s contract would expire soon. `` She only came aboard for five years,'' he said. Her one-hour show, which debuted in September 1984, has frequently been CBS' most popular series. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> LeMasters </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday that `` heated'' negotiations were being conducted between Miss <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON> and Universal TV, the show's producer. Last fall, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON> said she wanted to end the series to do movies and return to <LOCATION> Broadway </LOCATION>, where she won four <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> awards.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SANTA ANA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, who suffered from the Watergate tapes, is at the center of a more recent taping incident. Orange County Supervisor <PERSON> Gaddi </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON> now admits he recorded a call from the former president last month. In <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, taping a telephone conversation without the consent of both parties is a misdemeanor. <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON>, a former police officer, acknowledged taping <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> after earlier denying it, but said Thursday that <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> gave his permission. He said <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> knew he was being taped by the telltale beeps coming from his machine. `` I considered it a private matter, a memento for me and my family,'' <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> aide <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON> never asked permission, but <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> knew he was being taped because of the beeping and did n't object <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> called <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON> to thank him for making a speech at the Dec. 2 groundbreaking for the <ORGANIZATION> Nixon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presidential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Yorba </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Linda </LOCATION>, 30 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SAO PAULO, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Pele </PERSON>, the retired king of Brazilian soccer, said in an interview published today that he quit a government public relations job to avoid `` lying'' about his country. <PERSON> Pele </PERSON>, who retired as a player in 1977, last year resigned as goodwill ambassador for the government tourism agency <ORGANIZATION> Embratur </ORGANIZATION>. In an interview with the <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Jornal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> do </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brasil </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Pele </PERSON> said he quit because he was embarrassed by questions about violence and street crime in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>. `` I just could n't go on lying any more,'' he said. <PERSON> Pele </PERSON>, 48, said the last straw came when <ORGANIZATION> Embratur </ORGANIZATION> asked him to promote a Brazilian perfume in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` I was paid to defend <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and not to sell perfume,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Country music singer <PERSON> Ricky </PERSON> <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON> leaves Monday for a 15-day USO tour that will include seven shows for American military personnel. He will be joined by country singer <PERSON> Suzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bogguss </PERSON> for <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organizations </ORGANIZATION>' performances in <LOCATION> Okinawa </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and at an installation in the <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>. The shows will be taped for a special on <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nashville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> on cable TV. <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON>' hits include `` Country Boy'' and `` Heartbroke.'' He was voted entertainer of the year in 1985 by the Country Music Association.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WESTPORT, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The food company owned by actor <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> will be donating $ 5 million to charities this year, a spokesman said. <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Own </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> was started in 1982, and after this year's donations, will have given $ 20 million to charities, said A.E <PERSON> Hotchner </PERSON>, executive vice president and treasurer of the Westport-based company. Charities getting donations include Aging in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, Research to Prevent Blindness, Students Against Driving Drunk, the Alzheimer's <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, Save the Children, and <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Friends </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION>, he said Friday The company's products include salad dressing, spaghetti sauce, popcorn and lemonade.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>COLUMBIA, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Dillards </ORGANIZATION>, a bluegrass band popular in the 1960s, have reunited to launch their first tour in 23 years. The Dillards gained fame as the musical Darling family on `` The <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> Show.'' Their tour began with a concert here Thursday night. The idea for a reunion tour originated last year when <PERSON> Denver </PERSON> <PERSON> Pyle </PERSON>, who played the Darling family patriarch on the <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> show, suggested a Darling family reunion. `` We had so much fun we decided to take the opportunity to find out if we could do it as well as we used to,'' said bassist <PERSON> Mitch </PERSON> <PERSON> Jayne </PERSON>. `` We're all still alive, and we all like each other, so we're one of the few bands anywhere that can still get together. Other members of the band are banjo player <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Dillard </PERSON>, mandolinist <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>, guitarist and vocalist <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Dillard </PERSON> and newcomer guitarist <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooley </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After months of wrangling, negotiations over <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Barenboim </PERSON>'s contract as artistic and musical director of the new Opera-Bastille broke off and the job was declared vacant. <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Berge </PERSON>, chairman of the board of the multimillion-dollar Opera-Bastille complex currently under construction in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, said Friday he was sorry an agreement could not be reached with <PERSON> Barenboim </PERSON>, `` a man whose talent I admire and respect.'' The conflict centered on money and the number of performances by <PERSON> Barenboim </PERSON>, 46, an Israeli, he said. <PERSON> Barenboim </PERSON> said he planned to take legal action. `` In any case I have not resigned; the contract is not interrupted, it is broken.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-USNewsCase     01-14 0471</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US News Case,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Appeals Court Upholds Ruling Against US News Retirees</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURIE ASSEO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 200 retirees of <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; World Report have lost another round in their court claim that they were underpaid $ 100 million in profit-sharing benefits. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> on Friday upheld a lower court decision that said the retirees were paid a fair value for their company stock before 1982, even though employees who held stock when the news magazine was sold two years later received much more per share. The 230 plaintiffs, who retired between 1974 and 1982, were paid an average of $ 100 a share, said their attorney, <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Raywid </PERSON>. The magazine's 1984 employees got $ 2,842 a share when <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> was sold, according to court papers. `` We think the opinion is wrong,'' said <PERSON> Raywid </PERSON>, who added there is a `` substantial likelihood'' it will be appealed. The three-member court effectively said companies `` can sacrifice the interests of past employees and retirees'' to benefit current and future employees and maintain employee ownership, he said. Under the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> profit-sharing plan, when an employee retired the company could exercise its option to buy the employee's stock shares. According to court papers, employees who retired in 1973 received $ 65 a share, while the value rose to $ 470 for those who retired in 1981. The magazine was sold for $ 176 million in 1984 to media and real estate magnate <PERSON> Mortimer </PERSON> <PERSON> Zuckerman </PERSON>. <PERSON> Raywid </PERSON> said the plaintiffs had received a total of $ 5.5 million for their stock but believed they would have gotten $ 100 million more if they had been given full value. The plaintiffs contended the company that appraised the magazine's value improperly classified retirees' stock as a minority interest rather than a majority interest, which would have carried a higher premium. In addition, the plaintiffs said the appraiser placed an unfairly low value on property <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> owned in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> D.C </LOCATION>. However, the <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> upheld the decision to give the retirees' stock a minority status, saying it was `` entirely consistent'' with the profit-sharing plan's rules and with federal law. The court also affirmed the property valuation, saying much of the land was being used as a parking lot and development had not been expected at the time. A major objective of the profit-sharing plan was the perpetuation of employee ownership, the appellate court said, adding that the law does not set an exclusive goal of maximizing benefits. `` The plaintiffs were not the only beneficiaries of the plan,'' the judges said. `` Indeed, the worst that can be said of the plan is that it was administered to favor a rolling class of future beneficiaries over those present and past.'' Ruling in the case were Circuit Judges <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> and <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     01-14 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0025</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 1; 3; 16; 28; 30; 35.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0121EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     01-14 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0087</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 1; 3; 16; 28; 30; 35.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 6-5-1-4.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 02; 05; 06; 11; 22; 28.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 03; 13; 23; 25; 29; 37. Bonus: 46677.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 13; 16; 30; 40; 44; 48. Supplementary 14.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 0-5-8-3.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 2-9-2; 9-6-6-5; 0-7-2-4-6; 0-4-6-2-5-5.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0128EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-Threat     01-14 0374</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Threat,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bomb Threat Against White House Minutes Before Reagan Arrival</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL PAGE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s helicopter landed at the White House minutes after a bomb threat was received by a White House operator, an administration aide said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, returning late Friday from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on the last working trip of his presidency, landed on the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lawn </LOCATION> on schedule at 11:15 p.m. EST after the Secret Service went over the area with bomb-sniffing dogs. The president entered the executive mansion without incident, White House press aide <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Sowry </PERSON> said. About 15 reporters and television crew members, on the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lawn </LOCATION> to cover the usually-routine helicopter landing, were removed to the White House press office moments before the presidential helicopter arrived. Press officials on duty had no information about the exact nature of the threat or whether it was actually directed at the White House complex. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was returning from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, where he had spoken at the annual dinner of the Knights of <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>, a Roman Catholic civic organization that helps the poor. It was his last official working trip out of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> as president. Aides at the White House did not know if <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had been informed of the threat. Secret Service officials could not immediately be reached for comment. `` Several minutes before the helicopter was supposed to land the White House operator received a bomb threat and passed that on to the Uniformed Division -LRB- of the <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Sowry </PERSON> said. `` When the president landed, the place had already been swept.'' Earlier, during <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s speech in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, a man who said he had a package for the president was detained at the <LOCATION> Waldorf-Astoria </LOCATION> while police and <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> officials inspected the package and others in his car. No explosives were found. The package he carried turned out to be a photo album and the packages in the car were personal belongings, police said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> left the hotel slightly behind schedule and by a different route after it was determined that no explosives were present, said <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> police Capt. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON>. The man, who was not immediately identified, was taken to an office in the hotel and questioned by police and <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-InternationalStudy Bjt   01-14 0536</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-International Study, Bjt,0551</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report Urges Colleges To Expand Study-Abroad Programs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE MITGANG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fearing a loss of the nation's competitive edge, a group of college officials is seeking ways to double the number of students studying abroad and include more business and science majors. Members of the Council on <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> met privately in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on Friday to discuss ways to expand study-abroad opportunities for less-affluent youngsters and encourage students to attend programs in places other than just <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. The meeting followed release of a council report in December which found fewer than 5 percent, or about 50,000, of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> college students studying abroad each year, while some 350,000 foreign students attend <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> schools. `` Citizens of other nations are learning more about us than we are about them and each year are doing so in increasing numbers,'' said the 28-page report, `` Educating for Global Competence.'' `` We have quite rightly welcomed these students to our own shores but have failed to encourage our own students to go abroad,'' it said. The report warned that failure to expand study-abroad opportunities would mean `` we will irreversibly diminish the world status of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Woodbury </PERSON>, chancellor of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maine </ORGANIZATION> system, said in an interview that the council decided to establish a Committee on Unrepresented Groups to help schools develop study-abroad opportunities for such groups as business and law students, and poor and minority youngsters. `` We plan to get poor students better information on what the costs are,'' <PERSON> Woodbury </PERSON> said after the meeting. `` There's a common belief that study-abroad progams will cost more. In fact, many programs do not involve extra cost.'' According to the report, only 3 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> high school graduates and 5 percent of college graduates have meaningful proficiency in a second language. Thirty-three states do n't require foreign language study in high school, and 34 states do n't require world history. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is one of the few industrialized countries where students can graduate from college without studying a foreign language. `` If you look at the attitude of colleges here, international study has never been a very big part of the curriculum. It's just a ` good thing to do,' rather than a part of the mainstream,'' said <PERSON> Woodbury </PERSON>. The majority of students studying abroad are white, affluent females from highly educated families, according to the report. Most are liberal arts majors and spend less than six months in foreign programs. Relatively few students majoring in business, public health, science or math take part in such programs, said the report. <PERSON> Woodbury </PERSON> said his own school started an exchange program with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in 1987 involving 15 Soviet and 15 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> students each year. The <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maine </ORGANIZATION> system is also trying to establish an exchange program in which business students could work as interns in Japanese companies, he said. The council, established in 1947, is a non-profit organization based in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> which fosters student exchange programs. Former <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Fulbright </PERSON> serves as honorary chairman.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Copies of the report are available for free from the Council, Department G, 205 East 42nd Street, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> 10017.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-757Order     01-14 0338</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-757 Order,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cross-Wiring Check Ordered For Boeing 757s</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cross-wiring found in cargo hold emergency systems of two <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 757 airliners prompted federal aviation authorities to order inspections of all the aircraft within the next three days. The order late Friday was similar to one issued for <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737s 48 hours earlier involving critical engine fire and vibration warning systems. The two `` airworthiness directives'' were unrelated, however. The earlier order was prompted by speculation the pilot of a British <ORGANIZATION> Midland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> 737 that crashed Sunday, killing 44 people, might have been confused by false wiring into shutting down his only good engine. The Times of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> reported Friday, however, that investigators were certain there was no wiring problem, and neither <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nor British airline officials reported finding such a problem on any other aircraft. Tests of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> 737s have to be completed by Sunday morning. The latest `` airworthiness directive'' by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> gives airlines 72 hours to check whether cross-wiring in cargo holds might cause sprinklers to go on in the wrong cargo area in the event of a fire. The problem had been discovered in two of the aircraft, said <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrar </PERSON>. He said no details were available on how the problem was found or on which airliners, but he said neither involved an actual fire or accident. The order involving 757s `` is not really relevant to the British crash except that the subject is also miswiring,'' <PERSON> Farrar </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> said 205 of the 757s are in service worldwide, with 119 of them used by four <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airlines: <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION>. `` The miswiring means that if the flight crew got a warning indicating a fire in the forward cargo compartment and pushed the button to activate the fire extinguishing system for that compartment, it would activate the system in the aft cargo compartment,'' and vice-versa, said an <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> statement. The checks were not expected to disrupt any scheduled flights.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Fauntroy-Probe     01-14 0500</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fauntroy-Probe,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fauntroy Denies He was Contacted On Ethics Probe</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD KEIL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 District of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Del </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON> is denying he has been contacted by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Ethics <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> chairman over putting the son of an <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> representative on the congressional payroll while the son was running for state office in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, citing a congressional source, reported Thursday that Rep. <PERSON> Julian </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Calif., chairman of the ethics committee, had written <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON> asking him to explain his hiring of <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>, the son of Rep. <PERSON> Gus </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>, D-Ill According to the source, who spoke only on condition of anonymity, <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> asked <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON> what duties <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> performed, and if <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> had regularly reported to work. A federal investigation into the case began last month after The <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> reported <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> was on <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON>'s payroll at the same time he was running for the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> legislature. According to sworn affidavits submitted to <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elections </ORGANIZATION> officials, <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> said he had fulfilled state requirements by living continuously for two years in the legislative district he sought to represent. That period covered the time he was on FauntrAroll. House rules, meanwhile, require a congressional employee to report regularly to work. <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON>, in a statement he issued to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> on Friday, disputed the portion of the story that described <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>'s letter According to the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON> asserted that <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> had not written him about the Savage affair. But the congressional source, contacted again by the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> after <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON> iso denial, on Friday reconfirmed and amplified his original description of the letter. The source stated a letter from <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> was received by <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON>'s office during the last week of December, and added that <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON>, <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON>'s staff director, had been preparing a response However, it could not be learned whether <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> completed his letter, whether <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON> had seen it, or whether a response had been sent to the Ethics panel. <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON>'s staff refused repeated efforts by the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> _ which included several telephone calls to <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON>'s office and a visit there by a reporter _ to obtain the statement, Repeated efforts to reach <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> Friday were unsuccessful. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, the staff director of <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> office, said the congressman was traveling out of state and would not return to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> until Wednesday. She said he had not left a telephone number where he could be reached, and had not been calling in for messages. Savage earned $ 21,398 while on <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON>'s payroll from September 1987 through June 1988. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> is conducting a preliminary investigation into the case, a <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official confirmed Thursday. In the prepared statement, <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON> also said his staff had been told by members of <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>'s personal office staff and Ethics <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> officials that no such letter existed. Ethics committee officials were unavailable for comment Friday afternoon. Neither <PERSON> Gwendolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, legislative director in <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> office, nor <PERSON> Andrea </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON>, his <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> press secretary, could be reached for comment
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0155EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF-CharityBonanza     01-14 0128</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF-Charity Bonanza,0131</SECOND>
<HEAD>Couple Turns $1.30 From Charity Into $500,000</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTIAGO, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A poor man and his wife went to the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>'s human rights agency for help and were handed 400 pesos, the equivalent of $ 1.30. They converted it to $ 500,000 by playing the lottery. Officials at the Church's <PERSON> Vicary </PERSON> of Solidarity said Friday the couple were given the handout last week when they went there for help to return home in northern <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> after coming to <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION> to visit a sick daughter. Two days later, they went back to the vicary to say thanks. The man used 75 cents of the sum to bet on the weekly national soccer lottery and won $ 500,000. <PERSON> Vicary </PERSON> officials said the couple asked not to be identified.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0159EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NicaraguanRefugees Bjt   01-14 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nicaraguan Refugees, Bjt,0635</SECOND>
<HEAD>Not All Nicaraguans Welcoming The Newcomers</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto MH2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILL LESTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of Nicaraguans and other Central Americans seeking a promised land are pouring into this haven for immigrants, but some who settled in the area after the 1979 Sandinista revolution are wary of the newcomers. `` Some of the Nicaraguans here have mixed feelings about those who stayed with the Sandinistas,'' said <PERSON> Maritza </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrera </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Nicaraguan-American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>. `` They are people from the farm areas, with a different orientation,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Pallais </PERSON>, a Nicaraguan priest who runs the <ORGANIZATION> Nicaraguan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION>. The Central Americans began arriving from southern <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> by the busload Thursday and Friday following a federal judge's ruling that the government could not keep them there while their applications for political asylum were being processed. Since the judge's decision Monday, some 400 people have come here, bringing the two-month total to about 2,000, most of them Nicaraguans. Officials expect about 100,000 more over the next 18 months. <PERSON> Pallais </PERSON> said the new group is different from the first wave of Nicaraguans that settled in southern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Arguello </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Nicaraguan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bankers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, disagreed, saying the time has come to forget the differences that separate the first group from the second. `` The bottom line is we are all Nicaraguans,'' he said. `` Back in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, there was no in-between. Here we just have to forget it. ... The objective is to help all Nicaraguans.'' The latest group is coming to town with no guarantee of food, shelter or social services, and officials are warning there will be very little support once they arrive. <PERSON> Isidoro </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuevas </PERSON>, the Cuban-born mayor of <LOCATION> Sweetwater </LOCATION>, a heavily Nicaraguan city in western <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, said his city will have trouble absorbing the aliens. `` We've been trying to gather clothes and food to pass it on to them,'' he said. `` But there are many dwellings shared by more than one family already. People are sleeping on the front porches, sleeping on the couches.'' In <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, about 250 immigrants have been staying in a sports stadium, but the <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> baseball team arrives Jan. 25 for spring training, and the immigrants will have to be relocated, most likely to private shelters and churches. Mayor <PERSON> Xavier </PERSON> <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> sought an emergency meeting with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, and other officials urged President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who is fishing in the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Keys </LOCATION> this weekend, to come to see the situation for himself. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told reporters he would examine immigration policy when he takes office. He said the newcomers are `` causing an overburdening of facilities like schools and hospitals, and this is a sorry commentary on what's happening in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has to be generous, but no one community can suffer an overload without some support in some way,'' he said. A delegation of community leaders visited southern <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> on Friday to warn those awaiting transportation to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. `` If people come down there -LRB- <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> -RRB-, they need to know that they're going to have to fend for themselves,'' <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Assistant </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Manager <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Ojeda </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Harlingen </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. He estimated the <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> area has 75,000 to 125,000 Nicaraguans, along with thousands of other recently arrived Central Americans. More than 30,000 Central Americans passed through south <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> in 1988 seeking political asylum, according to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The best way for <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> to deal with the influx would be to allow more of the immigrants to get work permits, <PERSON> Arguello </PERSON> said. `` With work permits for every Nicaraguan, the private sector can step in and help,'' he said. `` We do n't want to create a welfare society.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0222EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TeamstersTrial     01-14 0566</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Teamsters Trial,0581</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teamsters Officials Convicted In Payroll-Padding Case</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto CD1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOROTHY GAST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Teamsters international vice president, convicted of embezzling union funds in an alleged `` ghost employee'' scheme, returns to court Tuesday to learn whether he must relinquish his many union positions. Indicted in May 1986 with the late Teamsters President <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Presser </PERSON>, <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON>, 66, was convicted in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Friday of embezzlement, labor racketeering, conspiracy to commit racketeering and filing false statements with the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. He could be sentenced to up to 46 years in prison and fined up to $ 70,000. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, 52, recording secretary of Local 507 in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Presser </PERSON>'s home local, was convicted of labor racketeering, conspiracy to commit racketeering and embezzlement. He faces a penalty of up to 45 years imprisonment and a fine of up to $ 60,000. <PERSON> Presser </PERSON>, who became president of the 1.6-million member union in 1983, died of brain cancer July 9 and was never tried. <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> declined comment after the verdict. <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>'s most powerful Teamster, <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> is president of the <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teamsters </ORGANIZATION>, leader of <ORGANIZATION> Teamsters </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> 41 in northeast <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and president of Teamsters Local 507 and Bakery Workers Local 19. The two locals share offices and have a combined membership of about 12,000 people. Judge <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> dismissed the jury until Tuesday. At that time, attorneys say, the jurors will be asked to consider whether the two men have to forfeit their union posts. No sentencing was scheduled. Union officials convicted of any of several felonies, including embezzlement, are required to relinquish their union positions for 13 years, according to <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Crino </PERSON>, area administrator for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>. But <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cambria </PERSON>, attorney for <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON>, said other things are considered and that the jury will deliberate those points Tuesday. <PERSON> Presser </PERSON>, <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> had been accused of being involved in embezzling $ 700,000 from the union between 1972 and 1981 to pay so-called `` ghost employees'' who did n't work for the money. <PERSON> Cambria </PERSON> said the verdict is puzzling because under the racketeering counts, <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> was convicted only of keeping two of four alleged `` ghost employees'' on the payroll for three pay periods. The racketeering counts that <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> was convicted of accused <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Presser </PERSON> of embezzling up to $ 43,500 to pay <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> and up to $ 8,800 to pay <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Argie </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> was accused of being a `` ghost employee,'' and <PERSON> Argie </PERSON> was an unindicted co-conspirator who testified he did little, if any, work. `` I ca n't really make sense of the verdict at this point,'' <ORGANIZATION> Cambria </ORGANIZATION> said. `` We're going to have to determine if it -LRB- the verdict -RRB- can be set aside because it was internally inconsistent.'' <PERSON> Presser </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> were <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> informants, court documents indicated. <PERSON> Presser </PERSON>'s former attorney, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Climaco </PERSON>, has said that <PERSON> Presser </PERSON>'s defense would have been that he was authorized by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> to hire the `` ghost employees'' to enhance and protect his image as an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> informant. During the trial, <PERSON> White </PERSON> rejected <LOCATION> Cambria </LOCATION>'s motion asking that documents regarding <PERSON> Presser </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> informant activities be released. `` We were deprived from putting in the entire <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> aspect of this because <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> took that with him and the agents who are still alive declined to testify,'' <PERSON> Cambria </PERSON> said. One of <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>' attorneys, <PERSON> Rocco </PERSON> <PERSON> Russo </PERSON>, said he thought there were `` several inconsistencies'' in the verdict and declined to elaborate.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0237EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ShipCollision     01-14 0118</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ship Collision,0122</SECOND>
<HEAD>13 Fishermen Presumed Dead In Ship Collision</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fishing boat and a coastal ferry collided early today off the <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> peninsula </LOCATION>, and 13 fishermen were missing and presumed dead, maritime police said. The accident occurred in dense fog when the 2,904-ton Queen ferryboat and the 95-ton Changyoung No. 7 collided off the southern city of <LOCATION> Yosu </LOCATION>, the police said. The fishing vessel capsized. Patrol boats that rushed to the area found no traces of survivors, police said. The ferry, carrying 120 passengers and 30 crewmen, sustained no damage and arrived later in its destination of <LOCATION> Cheju </LOCATION>, the nation's southernmost island, police said Authorities blamed the fog for the accident.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Germany-Libya Bjt   01-14 0538</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Germany-Libya, Bjt,0555</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Probe Of Company Suspected In Libya Plant Scandal</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Retransmitting to restore Bjt designation</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRENCE PETTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A West German company that <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION> officials contend exported goods to <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> to help it build a suspected chemical weapons plant is being investigated by a <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> prosecutor. The new probe compounds official embarrassment over a scandal that has dominated West German politics for two weeks. The <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s vice chairman, <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> Baum </PERSON>, called Friday for a federal criminal probe. Government officials conceded Friday they had received intelligence reports in October that indicated German companies may have helped build the plant in <LOCATION> Rabta </LOCATION>, about 40 miles outside the Libyan capital of <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION>. Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s spokesman, <PERSON> Friedhelm </PERSON> <PERSON> Ost </PERSON>, had said earlier <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> knew nothing of alleged West German complicity in the project until <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> brought it up during <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s visit to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in November. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> contends the plant is on the verge of full-scale production of poison gas. <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> claims it is a pharmaceutical plant. At the same news conference at which <PERSON> Ost </PERSON> spoke, <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Karl-Heinz </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> den </PERSON> <PERSON> Driesch </PERSON> said investigators had found no evidence against West German companies that would stand up in court. <PERSON> Werner </PERSON> <PERSON> Botz </PERSON>, chief prosecutor for the <LOCATION> Offenburg </LOCATION> region in the <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Forest </LOCATION> area, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that he opened the new investigation into Imhausen-Chemie of <PERSON> Lahr </PERSON> after reading a detailed report in this week's Stern magazine. The Hamburg-based magazine cited what it said were official documents and witnesses in its article, which accused Imhausen-Chemie, the now defunct I.B.I. Engineering of <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Pen </PERSON> <PERSON> Tsao </PERSON> medical supply of <LOCATION> Hamburg </LOCATION> of being deeply involved in the <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> project. Stern alleged that Imhausen-Chemie provided `` everything that is needed to build a chemical plant'' to I.B.I., which the magazine said in turn shipped the materials to <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> under forged bills. The article also mentioned involvement by the <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Link </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> NV </ORGANIZATION> firm of <LOCATION> Antwerp </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>. The director of that company, <PERSON> Jozef </PERSON> <PERSON> Gedopt </PERSON>, was arrested in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> on Wednesday and charged with forging shipping documents on goods delivered to <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>. A woman who answered the telephone at <ORGANIZATION> Imhausen-Chemie </ORGANIZATION> on Friday said the company would have no comment on the new developments. Attempts to reach the company's owner, <PERSON> Juergen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hippenstiel-Imhausen </PERSON>, were unsuccessful. News reports have said <ORGANIZATION> Imhausen </ORGANIZATION> is on a foreign business trip. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> on Thursday said authorities had uncovered new documents implicating West German companies and said investigators were giving them a thorough look. West German law requires companies exporting hazardous materials, arms or their components to obtain licenses from the <ORGANIZATION> Economics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>. However, officials from that ministry have said the legal situation regarding transfer of technology or consultation varies from case to case. A West German delegation was in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> the past week to examine <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s evidence on the plant's purpose and alleged West German involvement. Nearly two weeks ago, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said they suspected Imhausen-Chemie. The <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> audited the company and announced last week it had found no evidence of illegal exports. On Wednesday, government sources confirmed a criminal investigation of I.B.I.'s activities and said customs authorities had seized company documents.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0315EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     01-14 0588</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0609</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JUNEAU, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The letter could n't have come at a better time for <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. Just as legislators were preparing to cut the budget or impose new taxes in the wake of declining oil revenues, Money magazine came to the rescue. `` Let that alarm clock ring, State of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. You're financially independent and do n't ever have to work again!'' the magazine proclaimed in a letter addressed to the state. `` Dear S. <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>: What a thought! To be so rich that you could do whatever you want. Whenever you want. Virtually anywhere you please,'' the letter continued. <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> has won a chance at the magazine's $ 2 million `` Double-Your-Million Sweepstakes'' drawing, offered to attract new subscriptions. Because computers know only what they're told, and because a state office in <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION> is on a mailing list under `` State of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'' and the magazine used that list for its promotion, the contest letter ended up in the state mailroom. `` If we win this and every other sweepstakes, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> will be over its budget troubles,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramseur </PERSON>, a spokesman for Gov. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowper </PERSON>. The letter also includes a warning often heard in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>: `` Remember, millionaires who handle their money badly are n't millionaires for long.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 You've heard of `` <LOCATION> L.A </LOCATION>. Law?'' Well, how does `` La. Law'' strike you? <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Schultz </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> television, said Thursday that <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Fischer </PERSON>, the co-creator and former co-executive producer of the hit prime time show about a <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> law firm, is writing a two-hour movie pilot for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> about a woman district attorney in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Schultz </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> is interested in the project as a potential weekly series for the spring or fall. The network has the option to order 13 episodes if it approves the script for the pilot, he said. <PERSON> Fischer </PERSON>, through her secretary, declined to provide details on the as yet untitled project. <PERSON> Tesa </PERSON> <PERSON> Laviolette </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> and Video, said it is her understanding that the program would explore <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION>' close-knit business and social structure. She described it as having a `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>'' flavor with a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> twist.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEWARK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Triskaidekaphobiacs worried about Friday the 13th. Everybody should beware this weekend, a psychic says. Triskaidekaphobiacs are people who are afraid of the number 13. Friday the 13th has come and gone, but <PERSON> Mom </PERSON> <PERSON> Balaam </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> psychic and astrologer who is `` Like the Night With A Thousand Eyes,'' according to her ads, said the entire weekend may be dangerous. She said the alignment of the sun and moon would cause fights between couples, especially if one of them was born on a `` bad'' day _ most of which fall between the 15th and 19th of December, January, February, April and June. `` Those people could be in a lot of trouble,'' she said. `` A person born on a bad day is going to have a really bad day when the planets and the stars are wrong. With this weekend looking the way it is, right after Friday the 13th, I'd say stay indoors and watch yourself.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Rhonda </PERSON> <PERSON> Spiritualist </PERSON>, who bills herself as `` A True Psychic,'' was optimistic. She said Friday the 13th had no more likelihood of bestowing bad luck on people than July 7, 1977, or 7-7-77, had of bringing good luck. `` It's just another day,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Spiritualist </PERSON> said. `` People should n't worry about things like that. They should just go ahead and try to be happy with life.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0455EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--BushThreat     01-14 0172</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Bush Threat,0177</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Arrested For Threatening Vice President</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOCA RATON, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man was arrested after he made death threats against President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who is vacationing in the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Keys </LOCATION>, authorities said. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON>, 37, of <PERSON> Boca </PERSON> <PERSON> Raton </PERSON> was arrested in his apartment Friday after he made telephone threats against <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> agent <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Nozneski </PERSON> said. No weapons were found in <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON>' apartment, <PERSON> Nozneski </PERSON> said. Court documents quote <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON> as saying, `` If I see him, I'll kill him.'' <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON>, who described himself as an unemployed musician, was charged with threatening the life of the president. A threat made against the president or vice president is a federal felony punishable by up to five years in prison. <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON> was in the custody of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Marshal's office Friday night in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Nozneski </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON> was ordered by the court to undergo psychiatric evaluations. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is fishing in the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Keys </LOCATION> this weekend before returning to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Sunday to prepare for his inauguration Jan. 20.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0339EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-KingBirthday     01-14 0610</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-King Birthday,0628</SECOND>
<HEAD>King Day Dedicated By Many to Peace, Non-Violence</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Communities planned celebrations and other events Monday to honor slain civil rights leader <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, including a candlelight peace march in suburban <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> and an anti-apartheid demonstration in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. King's birthday will be observed as a federal holiday Monday in all but six states, including <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, where it will be business as usual at state offices. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, a mural painted by high school students depicting non-violence was unveiled Friday, and Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> mayor spoke of the `` grace and glory'' King brought to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, the celebrations `` help us keep Dr. <PERSON> King </PERSON>'s dream alive and provide opportunities for all people to renew their commitment to work for a society in which there is one standard of equality and human rights,'' said state Sen. <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Vaughn </PERSON>. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> King </PERSON>'s legacy has helped advance racial equality. `` Tremendous progress has been made over the last 20 to 25 years,'' he said Friday. `` There are more minorities who are elected officials, there are more minority businesses, more professionals.'' But he noted the high poverty and school dropout rate among minorities. A symposium was planned Sunday and Monday at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> to honor King's work. <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, speaker of the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Assembly </LOCATION>, was to give the keynote address Sunday and <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, a close associate of King's, was scheduled to speak Monday. The end of King day will be marked by a candlelight peace march at <LOCATION> Roeper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Country </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bloomfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, a wealthy northern suburb of <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, 26 teen-agers moved into the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> African </LOCATION> consulate Friday for a weekend anti-apartheid protest to mark King's birthday. The students, none of them black and ranging in age from 13 to 19, occupied a hallway outside the consulate's third-floor office, singing songs such as `` We Shall Overcome'' and other protest anthems. The crowd blocked at least one person from entering. They said they would camp in the hallway until Monday, when fellow protesters planned a march at the building to commemorate King's birthday and to denounce <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s system of racial segregation. The mural unveiled Friday at the <ORGANIZATION> Bronx </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> was inspired after a student at the school was killed in 1987. Ten students painted, kept journals and did research about non-violence for the 10-month project. `` This is a world they'd like to change and make more peaceful,'' said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON>, the school principal. The mural depicts Indian peace leader <PERSON> Mohandas </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>, <PERSON> King </PERSON>, a sign saying `` end segregation in public schools'' and two hands shaking, one black, one white. In <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, federal and city offices will be closed Monday but all state offices will remain open. King's birthday was a state holiday in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> for a brief time. Former Gov. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON>, a Democrat, created the holiday by executive order in 1986 after the Legislature refused to act. But, as one of his first official acts as governor, <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> rescinded the order before the first holiday could be celebrated. The action touched off the first major controversy of his short-lived administration. <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> said he acted because Attorney General <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Corbin </PERSON>, a fellow Republican, had said that <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON>'s order was illegal because a holiday requires legislative approval as well. Democratic Gov. <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON>, who succeeded <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> following his impeachment and removal from office last year, is on record in favor of a King holiday, although she has not followed <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> in creating one by executive order.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890114-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-14-89 0340EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GoetzSentencing Bjt   01-14 0638</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Goetz Sentencing, Bjt,0653</SECOND>
<HEAD>Goetz Gets One Year in Jail For Subway Shooting</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SAMUEL MAULL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
