<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 2327EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PlaneCrashes 1stLd-Writethru a0785 06-20 0273</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Plane Crashes, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0785,0275</SECOND>
<HEAD>Seven Killed in Two Small Plane Crashes</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES throughout with three more bodies found in South Carolina.
No pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 A twin-engine airplane en route from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> crashed in rainy weather Tuesday, killing four people, and three others died when a small plane crashed in the rugged White Cloud Mountains in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. The Beechcraft Duke en route to the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> crashed about 5 p.m. near Interstate 26 on the 2,300-acre site of the <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eastman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kodak </ORGANIZATION> plant in central <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Lexington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. `` Everything was routine,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. `` All of a sudden, they lost radar contact.'' One body was found within an hour of the crash and rescue workers found the other three bodies in the plane about 9 p.m., Ms. <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> said. The rescue workers waited for <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> investigators to arrive on the scene before entering the wreckage. `` We had pieces of the plane scattered a quarter-mile away,'' she said. The victims had not been identified late Tuesday, Ms. <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> said. In <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, the twin-engine, six-seat <ORGANIZATION> Piper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aztec </ORGANIZATION> was en route to <LOCATION> Challis </LOCATION> when it crashed in mid-afternoon. The flight had originated in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and stopped in <LOCATION> Wenatchee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, chief of the <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> Division of Aeronautics in <LOCATION> Boise </LOCATION>. The cause of the crash was not immediately known, but snow, hail, wind and rainstorms were reported in parts of central <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> at the time. The names of the victims were being withheld until relatives could be notified.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 2336EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People-Fonda     06-20 0169</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People-Fonda,0174</SECOND>
<HEAD>Actress Jane Fonda Spends Night Alone On Mountain After Losing Group</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FRESNO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> spent the night alone on a mountain after becoming seperated from her companions while hiking in Sequoia National Park, park officials said Tuesday. <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON>, who was unharmed, did n't panic when she realized she was lost Sunday, said her publicist, <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivers </PERSON>. She wrapped up in an insulated blanket and ate a sandwich while she waited for help to arrive, he said. <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> hiked ahead of her six companions and apparently took a wrong turn during the day hike, said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Tweed </PERSON>, a spokesman for the park about 40 miles east of here. Her companions notified park officials when she failed to show up at <LOCATION> Moose </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, their destination, or at their <ORGANIZATION> Pear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> base camp, <PERSON> Tweed </PERSON> said. A helicopter crew found <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> on top of a mountain early Monday morning, and reunited her with her friends at the base camp. The group hiked out together, <ORGANIZATION> Tweed </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0001EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Thatcher     06-20 0871</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Thatcher,0895</SECOND>
<HEAD>Elections Set Off Alarms for the Thatcher Revolution</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The alarms that have been sounding for months turned to a clamor over the weekend, telling Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> that her revolution is in trouble. Strikes, inflation and interest rates _ the economic diseases Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> has fought for 10 years to eradicate _ are haunting <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> again, and now comes a trouncing for her <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in European <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> elections. The government, while admitting its dismay, insists this does n't mean the end for Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s free-market crusade It says voters always use elections to the European Parliament to register protest against governments in midterm, and that the turnout of 36 percent is too low to shape lasting judgments. Nonetheless, the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> is jubilant, having won its first national election victory since 1974. Labor has emerged with 45 of the 78 mainland British constituencies and the <ORGANIZATION> Tories </ORGANIZATION> 32, fully overturning the 45-32 advantage the <ORGANIZATION> Tories </ORGANIZATION> held in the 1984 Euro-election. Labor, having revamped some of its more stridently left-wing policies to broaden its appeal, has `` been making steady progress since early this year,'' said the party's foreign policy chief, <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaufman </PERSON>. `` I like the pace of it _ do n't want to go too fast, do n't want a surge that can fall again'' before before <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s next election which must be held by June 1992, he said. On Thursday, <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> won both seats in two special elections for vacancies in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION> _ in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Glasgow </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>. Conservatives called both districts `` safe'' Labor seats that the party should have won. In the <ORGANIZATION> Vauxhall </ORGANIZATION> district of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoey </PERSON> increased the party's majority In <LOCATION> Glasgow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> halted a challenge by the Scottish <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, and its candidate <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> won with a reduced but respectable majority. Former Prime Minister <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Heath </PERSON>, an outspoken <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> foe in the <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, believed she was in serious trouble, saying: `` If after 10 years of government you've still got nearly 2 million unemployed, you've got an overall deficit on your trade and other dealings of 15 billion pounds -LRB- $ 23 billion -RRB-, you've got interest rates up to 14 percent and you've got inflation up to 8.3 percent and rising, then people are bound to say ... is this really what we want?'' Energy Secretary <PERSON> Cecil </PERSON> <PERSON> Parkinson </PERSON> said: `` We recognize all those things. We agree that inflation is a great curse. We're tackling it, and one is n't popular while one is serving up the medicine.'' The inflation is widely ascribed to Thatcherism's own success in reviving the economy through tax cuts, deregulation, selling nationalized industries, abolishing foreign currency controls and curbing trade union rights. The result has been a national spending spree, a sharp increase in the trade deficit, bigger wage demands and higher interest rates. The unrest triggered by rising wage demands has raised the number of worker days lost to strikes from 38,000 in December to 82,000 in April. Wage increases are running at 9.3 percent, compared with 7.5 percent two years ago. On Wednesday, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> faces its first national rail strike since 1982. A wage-inflation spiral would be a nightmare for any government. But even more trouble awaits Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> over her plans to shake up the legal, teaching and health services, her widely unpopular property tax reform and her insistence on privatizing the national water and electricity industries. Voters may also have been put off by her combative stance toward the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, which she has portrayed as a bureaucracy bent on forcing socialism down the British throat. `` I think the general public are fed up with Euro-bashing,'' said <PERSON> Heath </PERSON>. Despite Thatcherism's difficulties, no neutral observer is ready to write her off. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> has hit low patches before, her supporters say, yet she remains the only <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> prime minister in more than 160 years to win three consecutive elections. Strikes may be recurring, but the number of days lost is nothing near the 30 million in the last year before she ousted Labor in 1979. Inflation has yet to approach the double-digit permanency of the years immediately before Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s ascent. Many voters seem to feel that having spent 10 years tackling <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s real problems, she is now attacking non-existent demons. On issues like health and water a widespread feeling prevails of `` if it ai n't broke, do n't fix it.'' <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>, writing in the pro-Thatcher Sunday Times, said the Euro-vote, and the surprising 15 percent share of the vote won by the environmentalist <ORGANIZATION> Green </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, reflected a yearning for a community spirit that has suffered in the hardheaded enterprise culture favored by Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>. Everywhere, he said, voters were distressed by what they perceive as a deregulating spirit gone too far _ from the government's refusal to impose dog licenses to combat a wave of dog attacks, to the ease with which entrepreneurs can knock down historic buildings and put up bland office blocks Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, he concluded, `` must reconstruct late-Thatcherism and must do so urgently.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Marcus </PERSON> <PERSON> Eliason </PERSON>, The <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> news editor, has been covering <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> for 5 -LCB- years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Namibia     06-20 0708</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Namibia,0726</SECOND>
<HEAD>Namibia Changing Fast as South Africans Withdraw</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD PYLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OSHAKATI, Namibia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 3,000 people cheered and surged onto the road outside the <LOCATION> Ondangwa </LOCATION> refugee camp when buses carrying 170 returning exiles finally arrived. Most wore the red, blue and green colors of <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> South-West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Africa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, which fought for 23 years to win <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s independence from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. In the rush to welcome the new arrivals, few noticed a South African army truck convoy passing at that moment, its drivers grim-faced as they threaded their way toward home. The scene last week symbolizes the changes taking place in <LOCATION> Ovamboland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s populous northern tier, as the territory tries to put a 23-year bush war behind it and move toward peace and independence. The situation, say local residents and frequent visitors, has changed swiftly and dramatically since <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> agreed in December to a plan under which it will give up <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s last colony, which it has held for 74 years. The deal also provides for U.N.-supervised elections to set up a new government. Despite a flare-up of border fighting that stalled the plan in April, the South African military presence, which once numbered 50,000 troops, has been steadily cut to about 15,000, with more leaving daily. At the main military base in <LOCATION> Oshakati </LOCATION>, once known as `` White City,'' scores of houses now stand empty, and the only South African soldiers in evidence at the base are paratroopers manning the gate. <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> officers occupy the former headquarters buildings. By road and rail, scores of armored vehicles used in the guerrilla war are being sent back to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. Others, still caked with mud from jungle patrols, line base parking lots. Among those requisitioned by <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> officials for use by their own forces are at least 10 Casspirs vehicles. In the hands of the hated Koevet -LRB- Crowbar -RRB- anti-insurgency police, the hulking vehicles came to symbolize the harsh South African law enforcement polices. Repainted white with big `` <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION>'' letters on the side, the Casspirs will be used by the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> police monitors, whose job is to watch and handle complaints about the conduct of the <ORGANIZATION> South-West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>, of which <ORGANIZATION> Koevoet </ORGANIZATION> is now a part. The most stunning change, say some residents and visitors, is the sudden and omnipresent visibility of <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> after years of government suppression. The nationalist movement, considered likely to win a majority in the elections scheduled for November, draws its largest support in this region of bushland, farms and scattered settlements, home to nearly half of <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s 1.4 million people. Although the internal political wing of <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> could legally operate while the guerrilla unit was outlawed, this popular support remained largely hidden in the years of warfare. Even displaying the SWAPO flag often brought harassment and brutal South African treatment. Now the flag flutters openly from homes, roadside liquor stores and garages, even atop a concrete water tower near the Angolan border where, until a few weeks ago, South African soldiers manned machine guns. The exiles, said by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> to number 41,000, are returning to <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> aboard U.N.-chartered flights from neighboring countries to register for the November vote, the first step toward setting up an independent government. Some observers say they have been surprised by the speed of the South African withdrawal and by the lack of visible bitterness on the part of the departing forces. However, a barely concealed resentment remains among many white residents of northern <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> about what is taking place _ especially the demonstrations in support of <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION>, which many believe is determined to impose a Marxist regime if it wins the two-thirds majority needed to control the new government in the November elections. `` Are you going to write the truth about this -LRB- mess-up -RRB-?'' one German-speaking resident asked a journalist at the base guest house. Reports persist in the community that the <ORGANIZATION> Koevoet </ORGANIZATION>, although officially integrated into the regular police, still holds several <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas as prisoners and continues to intimidate and brutalize <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> supporters in the countryside. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION> police superintendent who commands the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> police monitoring contingent, said he had been unable to pin down `` rumors'' about prisoners.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Vietnam-Glasnost     06-20 0776</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Vietnam-Glasnost,0803</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vietnam Puts Limits On Its Version Of Glasnost</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENIS D. GRAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HANOI, Vietnam (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 While Soviet citizens openly take their leaders to task and Poles vote in free elections, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s Communists fire an editor who prints a short story about the human failings of an 18th century emperor <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, the communist world's third most populous nation with about 52 million people, has set definite limits on free expression and political change while moving to liberalize its economy. The list of taboos ranges from public criticism of top leaders and key policies to portraying the late revolutionary leader <PERSON> Ho </PERSON> <PERSON> Chi </PERSON> <PERSON> Minh </PERSON> in anything but a heroic light. In a recent interview, Deputy Premier and Foreign Minister <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> <PERSON> Co </PERSON> <PERSON> Thach </PERSON> said a multiparty system is out of the question in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and said current economic reforms will prevent pro-democracy uprisings like the one in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. `` We advocate broadening democracy and reaching a consensus through debate, but we do not tolerate pluralism,'' party chief <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Linh </PERSON> said in a speech in March. <PERSON> Linh </PERSON> and <PERSON> Thach </PERSON> are key architects of `` doi moi,'' or renovation, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s version of Soviet glasnost and perestroika. <PERSON> Doi </PERSON> moi flowered after <PERSON> Linh </PERSON>'s rise to power in late 1986, especially in southern <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, where resentment of Marxist rule is sharp and widespread. Journalists began to report on corruption and incompetence, and their exposes got some high-level officials fired. Books and magazines proliferated, some challenging the tolerance of the political system, others offering once forbidden sexual fare. But about six months ago, a backlash took shape. Either reformist leaders were trying to placate hard-liners, or the old guard simply felt things had gone too far. Western analysts say that, rather than take the broader Soviet road, the Vietnamese have opted for <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s `` give the people videos but no votes'' approach. But unlike in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, advocates of democracy have been mostly confined to debate rather than street action. Many have seized upon the firing of magazine editor <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ngoc </PERSON> last December as a cause celebre. The editor of the relatively radical and popular Literature and Art was pressured to quit after publishing several short stories by a controversial writer, <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> <PERSON> Huy </PERSON> <PERSON> Thiep </PERSON>. One depicted Emperor <PERSON> Quang </PERSON> <PERSON> Trung </PERSON>, a national hero who routed the Chinese two centuries ago, as a man of common foibles and frailties. <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinh </PERSON> <PERSON> Thi </PERSON>, secretary of the Writer's <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said controversy within the 450-member organization has been `` so fierce that people forgot politeness.'' <PERSON> Lai </PERSON> <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> <PERSON> An </PERSON>, a prominent literary critic, described <PERSON> Ngoc </PERSON>'s dismissal as a move by conservatives to deter doi moi `` Skeptical books about our party, socialism are not allowed. Those who tarnish national figures will be severely criticized,'' he said in an interview. Nonetheless, changes have been substantial. More than a decade ago, political prisoners abounded, teen-agers wearing jeans were suspect, and foreign journalists were escorted to meet what some Vietnamese disdainfully call `` ornamental intellectuals,'' or government mouthpieces. <PERSON> Thach </PERSON> said recently that 94,000 inmates of re-education camps had been released over the past 10 years and only 120 political prisoners remained. Relations between state and religious groups have improved. In February, the government allowed a group of prominent academics critical of education standards to open <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s first private university, <ORGANIZATION> Thang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Long </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. In the arts, one recent film, `` The Woman of the River,'' contrasts a decent ex-official of the fallen <LOCATION> Saigon </LOCATION> government with a Communist revolutionary who turns to corruption after the war. Although an anti-war novel has yet to appear, the experiences of the Vietnam War and other conflicts are handled with more human feeling in some recent fiction. <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Huu </PERSON>'s forthcoming novel, `` The Humorless Colonel,'' tells of a young officer who dies in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> because of his father's unbending military attitudes. In the past, war novels invariably depicted cardboard characters going cheerfully to their deaths for the Communist cause. While more strident voices are heard in the south, artists and intellectuls in the north do not appear intent on hurtling doi moi forward or dismantling the socialist state. `` Writers and artists must be given more freedom but liberty does n't mean destroying all gains of the past,'' <PERSON> Huu </PERSON> said. `` Writers should not be disruptive.'' Western diplomats also point out that while many students are disgruntled, an organized, pro-democracy movement among them does not appear to exist. Neither has an institution like the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> emerged around which opponents to the existing order could rally. Said one envoy in the Vietnamese capital: `` I do n't want to make any predictions, but I do n't think the Communist Party here will be challenged in the streets for several years as in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0055EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Iran-Cities     06-20 0102</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Cities,0105</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran Plans to Build New Cities</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> plans to build 12 new cities to house its soaring population, the official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reports. The agency, monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION> on Monday, quoted Housing Minister <PERSON> Serajeddin </PERSON> <PERSON> Kazeroni </PERSON> as saying research was needed to develop construction methods so more people could own homes. <PERSON> Kazeroni </PERSON> was quoted as telling the daily newspaper Ettela'at that cheaper homes should be built that would consume less energy. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s population has risen over the past decade from 33 to 50 million and is growing at the rate of 2.5 million annually.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-PolishPolitician     06-20 0714</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Polish Politician,0739</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Who Stopped Solidarity Juggernaut Admired for Making Money</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DANISZEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PILA, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It took a free-spending entrepreneur to deprive Solidarity of a clean sweep of the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc's first freely elected legislative chamber. A Communist-backed businessman. <PERSON> Henryk </PERSON> <PERSON> Stoklosa </PERSON>, who has made millions processing dead animals, edged out <PERSON> Piotr </PERSON> <PERSON> Baumgart </PERSON>, an activist of the independent farmers' union Rural Solidarity, in Sunday's runoff, unofficial returns showed Monday <PERSON> Stoklosa </PERSON> had drawn the Communist coalition's biggest pre-election crowd _ 50,000 people at <LOCATION> Pila </LOCATION> stadium for free sausages and beer and a drawing with prizes including a tractor, a color television and a videocassette recorder. Tickets for the drawing had been handed out free in the province's myriad small agricultural villages beforehand. <PERSON> Stoklosa </PERSON> will be a minority of one in the new 100-member <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> that is to convene next month along with the more powerful lower house, or Sejm, which the ruling Communists dominate because opposition candidates were only allowed to run for one-third of its seats. A visit to <LOCATION> Pila </LOCATION> on Sunday gave some hint of <PERSON> Stoklosa </PERSON>'s assets. On the streets of the 70,000-resident western provincial town _ unusually prosperous - and tidy-looking by Polish standards _ soldiers from nearby military bases strolled arm-in-arm with girlfriends eating ice cream cones <PERSON> Stoklosa </PERSON>'s moustachioed face stared out at passers-by from election posters plastered nearly everywhere, in store windows, walls and road overpasses. There were also posters attacking <PERSON> Baumgart </PERSON> as an interloper because he comes from <LOCATION> Szczecin </LOCATION>, about 90 miles away. A journalist for Solidarity's <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION> estimated <PERSON> Stoklosa </PERSON> put 200 million zlotys -LRB- $ 235,000 -RRB- into the campaign. It was believed to be the most expensive political campaign ever launched for an individual in postwar <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. In the nearby town of <LOCATION> Smilowo </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Stoklosa </PERSON>'s Farmutil company is headquartered, the polling station was doing a brisk business Sunday in an apparent show of local pride in the town's favorite son. But <PERSON> Stoklosa </PERSON> himself was absent. Attending to business first, he was at an international trade fair in <LOCATION> Poznan </LOCATION>. His Farmutil company, located on 345 acres at the end of a specially built road in <LOCATION> Smilowo </LOCATION>, gives a shiny neat appearance. But it belches an obnoxious odor over the rolling landscape, as dead farm animals and meat plant scraps are boiled down into fats and fodders for delivery by <PERSON> Stoklosa </PERSON>'s truck fleet to customers around <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. An employee, speaking as flies buzzed around, said the stench would disappear as soon as a new hermetically sealed processing system is completed. The 210-worker plant has sprung up in the past seven years. <PERSON> Stoklosa </PERSON> left his job as <PERSON> Pila </PERSON> tourism director and was kicked out of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> during Solidarity's 1980-81 heyday for alleged mismanagement. The plant now produces mainly fodder for animals, but plans are for it to expand into poultry raising, fertilizer production and slaughtering. The company makes an estimated 3 billion zlotys -LRB- $ 3.5 million -RRB- annually and published reports say <PERSON> Stoklosa </PERSON> as a result can tool around town in either one of two new Mercedes. `` He's got everything he could want in life, and now he wants other people to have more too,'' said <PERSON> Henryk </PERSON> <PERSON> Mocho </PERSON>, a Stoklosa campaign worker. `` He has very good organizing ability. He is the man who started this whole enterprise from nothing, and now people can make a good living here.'' <PERSON> Marian </PERSON> <PERSON> Malecki </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Pila </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Solidarity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> passed Sunday afternoon quietly at the opposition's empty campaign office with <PERSON> Leszek </PERSON> <PERSON> Woznicki </PERSON>, his former jailmate from 1982, the year thousands of Solidarity activists spent time in jail after authorities crushed their movement. They anticipated <PERSON> Stoklosa </PERSON>'s win, but treated it philosophically. `` We are aware that <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> does not begin and end at <LOCATION> Pila </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Malecki </PERSON> said. No matter what the outcome, the local committee would share in Solidarity's `` great success'' because it elected one other <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> candidate and two members to the <ORGANIZATION> Sejm </ORGANIZATION> from the city, he said. <PERSON> Wozniaki </PERSON>, a Solidarity activist at the town's largest industry, a light-bulb factory, said his forces were outgunned by <PERSON> Stoklosa </PERSON>'s massive poster campaign and Western-style gimmicks He blamed a lack of money, paper and printing machines and suggested Polish-Americans send more material aid to Solidarity next time. `` Tell them that a free <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> depends on them too,'' he said, only half-jokingly.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF---Chile-Smog     06-20 0123</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF---Chile-Smog,0127</SECOND>
<HEAD>Emergency Plan To Reduce Smog in Santiago</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTIAGO, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government has ordered a rotating shutdown of more than 130 factories and banned 50 percent of all buses from <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION>'s streets to reduce smog that has reached dangerous levels. Announcing the emergency measueres on Monday, Transport Minister <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> said the use of private and commercial cars in the capital also will be restricted with one out of five autos barred from the city streets daily. That restriction will be enforced according to the last digit on the license plates. <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> said some 130 Santiago-area factories found to be polluters will be required to shut down for 24 hours on a rotating basis, 50 factories at a time.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--KhomeiniShrine     06-20 0111</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Khomeini Shrine,0113</SECOND>
<HEAD>Khomeini Shrine Becoming Center Of New Township</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The burial place of <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> in south <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> will become one of <ORGANIZATION> Islam </ORGANIZATION>'s largest shrines, set in parkland and linked with major highways, a local official says. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, quoted the district's mayor, <PERSON> Hassan </PERSON> <PERSON> Tayrani </PERSON>, as saying Monday that 148 acres around <LOCATION> Beheshte </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zahra </LOCATION> cemetery would be purchased for the complex. The highways now being constructed will link the cemetery with central <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>, and to <LOCATION> Qom </LOCATION>, the theological center of <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Islam </ORGANIZATION>, where <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s revolutionary and religious patriarch, taught for years. <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, 86, died June 3.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0026EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-VanCliburn 1stLd-Writethru a0725 06-20 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Van Cliburn, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0725,0429</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pianist Resumes Performances After 11-Year Hiatus</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 5 grafs to UPDATE with end of performance, 13 curtain
calls. Picks up 5th graf pvs, `Cliburn played...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON BEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After an 11-year hiatus, pianist <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Cliburn </PERSON> resumed his public performances Monday night to thunderous applause with a concert dedicated to two late friends. The audience called the pianist back to the stage 13 times after he completed his program of <PERSON> Liszt </PERSON>'s Piano Concerto No. 1 and <PERSON> Tchaikovsky </PERSON>'s Piano Concerto No. 1. <PERSON> Cliburn </PERSON> ended the evening with four encores. `` This is a very sentimental evening for me,'' <PERSON> Clibuurn </PERSON> told the audience before the performance. `` This is an evening of remembrance of two wonderful friends.'' The pianist dedicated the concert at the open-air <ORGANIZATION> Mann </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Music </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> to <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Ormandy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fredric </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ormandy </PERSON>, who died in 1985, was music director of the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orchestra </LOCATION> for 44 years. <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador, headed the summer concert festival at the music center from 1949 until his death in 1987. <PERSON> Cliburn </PERSON> played with <PERSON> Ormandy </PERSON> and the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> musicians within weeks of gaining world fame for winning the first <ORGANIZATION> Tchaikovsky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Competition </ORGANIZATION> in 1958. The relationship yielded numerous concerts and recordings. He also played in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> in 1978, the year he quit performed publicly, weary from a schedule that included 100 concerts a year. He said he chose the Liszt to honor <PERSON> Ormandy </PERSON>'s Hungarian background. The program concluded with <PERSON> Tchaikovsky </PERSON>'s Piano Concerto No. 1. <PERSON> Cliburn </PERSON> spent the morning practicing with the orchestra and the afternoon shopping in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. `` It's so good to be back with the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orchestra </LOCATION>. It seems like I never left,'' <PERSON> Cliburn </PERSON> said after the practice session. Among his favorite venues, <PERSON> Cliburn </PERSON> always listed <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>'s theater in <LOCATION> Fairmont </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, where he would often play to the audience long after the orchestra musicians had left for the night. Proceeds from Monday night's concert will help finance the orchestra's free summer series, which <PERSON> Ormandy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> began. <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> <PERSON> Condon </PERSON> of Princess <PERSON> Anne </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, who traveled with <PERSON> Cliburn </PERSON> for six months two decades ago for a film project, said the years dropped away from the pianist in profile. `` You would never know it has been 11 years since he appeared before an audience like this,'' <PERSON> Condon </PERSON> said. Since 1978, he had performed in public only twice _ in December 1987 and in January 1988 for private gatherings honoring, respectively, Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and the Bob Hope Cultural Center.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0103EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     06-20 0621</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0647</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Ghostbusters Sequel Hot at Box Office</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD DE ATLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Ghostbusters II'' zapped through a record by collecting $ 29.4 million in its first three days as the summer of'89 kept going like gangbusters at the nation's box offices. The <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION>' film's $ 8.3 million on Sunday was the biggest non-holiday Sunday ever, according to <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which tallies box-offce receipts. `` We are thrilled with the opening weekend's record breaking results and we anticipate that ` Ghostbusters II' will play very strongly in the coming weeks,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>'s new chief, <PERSON> Dawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Steel </PERSON>. The previous three-day record was set earlier this month by `` Indiana <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and the Last Crusade,'' which earned $ 21.2 million in its second week. It also easily topped <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>'s previous three-day record of $ 13.6 million for `` Ghostbusters'' in June 1984. Since the debut of <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>'s and <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Aykroyd </PERSON>'s paranormal investigators, <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> has been spooked by several cinematic clunkers, most recently `` True Believer,'' `` The Adventures of Baron Munchausen'' and `` Physical Evidence.'' The company's only hit in recent years was 1987's `` La Bamba.'' The true test for ` Ghostbusters II'' comes Friday, when it will compete with the much-hyped `` Batman.'' <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON>'s `` Indiana <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and the Last Crusade'' kept up its charge, selling $ 11.7 million in tickets last weekend to claim second place on the box-office charts. In just four weeks, it has grossed more than $ 122 million. `` Dead Poets Society,'' the bittersweet prep school drama, earned $ 9.1 million to pass `` Star Trek V: The Final Frontier'' and move into third place. `` Star Trek V,'' the first film directed by star <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Shatner </PERSON>, slipped badly from first to fourth place on sales of $ 7.1 million. In fifth was `` See No Evil, Hear No Evil,'' with <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, with $ 2.5 million. The baseball movie `` Field of Dreams,'' starring <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Costner </PERSON>, finished in sixth with $ 2.4 million. In seventh was the wrestling film `` No Holds Barred,'' with $ 1.7 million. Rounding out the top 10 were `` <ORGANIZATION> Road </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>,'' with $ 1.5 million, `` Pet Sematary'' with $ 1.2 million and `` K-9'' with $ 1 million. Since Memorial Day weekend, weekend box office revenues have grossed $ 247.3 million, compared with $ 220 million for the period last year, an increase of 11 percent, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Krier </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which tallies the box-office receipts. `` The gross is n't distributed quite the same,'' he said. `` Last year there were more pictures playing and the gross was more evenly distributed. This year the grosses are concentrated in the top two or three movies.'' Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by Exhibitor Relations, with distributor, weekend gross, number of screens, average per screen, total gross and number of weeks in release. 1. `` Ghostbusters II,'' <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, $ 29.4 million, 2,327 screens, $ 12,229 per screen, $ 29.4 million, one week. 2. `` Indiana <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and the Last Crusade,'' Paramount, $ 11.7 million, 2,327 screens, $ 5,039 per screen, $ 122.3 million, four weeks. 3. `` Dead Poets Society,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 9.1 million, 1,091 screens, $ 8,343 per screen, $ 22.4 million, three weeks. 4. `` Star Trek V: The Final Frontier,'' Paramount, $ 7.1 million, 2,202 screens, $ 3,247 per screen, $ 31.2 million, two weeks. 5. `` See No Evil, Hear No Evil,'' Tri-Star, $ 2.5 million, 1686 screens, $ 1512 per screen, $ 38 million, six weeks. 6. `` Field of Dreams,'' Universal, $ 2.4 million, 1,077 screens, $ 2,265 per screen, $ 44.2 million, nine weeks. 7. `` No Holds Barred,'' New Line, $ 1.6 million, 1,327 screens, $ 1,339 per screen, $ 12 million, three weeks. 8. `` Road House,'' <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.5 million, 1,435 screens, $ 1,069 per screen, $ 23.8 million, five weeks. 9. `` Pet Sematary,'' Paramount, $ 1.2 million, 923 screens, $ 1,365 per screen, $ 52.7 million, nine weeks. 10. `` K-9,'' Universal, $ 1 million, 970 screens, $ 1,055 per screen, $ 36.7 million, eight weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-JuneauGoats     06-20 0387</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Juneau Goats,0397</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mountain Goat Herd to be Returned to Mount Juneau</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRIAN S. AKRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JUNEAU, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After years of absence, mountain goats will be returned to the steep slopes of <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION> with the help of tranquilizers, helicopters and thousands of dollars in donations. Volunteers plan to relocate at least 10 wild goats from a remote site south of <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION> or the Olympic Peninsula of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in late summer or early fall. The goal is to restore a herd of goats that can be viewed by residents and tourists in downtown <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION>, which sits in the narrow valley between <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Roberts </LOCATION>. `` If all goes well, in a year or two or five we'll have a population that will create splinter groups to proliferate in valleys from <LOCATION> Taku </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Inlet </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Berners </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>,'' said project coordinator <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, a member of the state Fish and Game Board. `` <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION> used to be goat habitat,'' <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said Monday. `` Goats were there quite commonly back in the mining days, the early days of <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION>.'' However, overhunting led to the goats' disappearance near the <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> city. Although goat hunting has been banned in the area for several years, the goats have never returned. Since the <ORGANIZATION> Juneau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> began soliciting money for the project in February, it has collected about $ 9,500 in money and services _ enough to start the project, <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> hopes to have $ 12,000 by the time the relocation begins, and said he has been encouraged by the public response. Donations have included helicopter time from a local charter outfit, a $ 1,000 check and $ 30 worth of quarters that a little girl collected in a bag. If the goats can not be captured south of <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Whiting </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, the volunteers will turn to the <LOCATION> Olympic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION> where the goat population has become a nuisance. `` We actally gave the goats to the Olympic Peninsula in the first place. We would be getting the same stock back,'' <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said. State wildlife officials will tranquilize the goats, which will be transported to the mountain by helicopters. Officials hope to get at least three males and seven females to ensure that the population grows. Radio collars will be put on some of the goats so their movement can be monitored.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     06-20 0476</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0492</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the belief that these are vinegar's salad days, a bus driver has brought out a book entirely on the centuries-old food seasoning. `` Vinegar is something more than just to put in your salad,'' <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Diggs </PERSON> said at a news conference Monday flanked by various vinegars. One displayed was the gourmet's balsamic, which can cost up to $ 30 for a few ounces. <PERSON> Diggs </PERSON> believes his 259-page book `` Vinegar'' is the most complete ever written on the subject. Vinegar, from the French word for `` sour wine,'' is the end product of fermentation. Anything that can be fermented into alcohol _ including fruits, grains, orange juice, molasses, honey _ can be made into vinegar. The tome covers vinegar's history, commercial production, how to make it at home, and medicinal uses. `` To remove a freckle, apply vinegar,'' the author prescribes. Soda mixed with vinegar will deal with heartburn, while hay fever can be combated by inhaling horseradish and vinegar several times a day. <PERSON> Diggs </PERSON> even has a chapter on vinegar trivia. `` If one dreams about vinegar, it signifies jealousy or a quarrel,'' he advises, and `` Never give vinegar away or your luck will go with it.'' The author, a Zen Buddhist, said he planned to use profits from the $ 24.95 book to establish a monastic hermitage. He also expressed gratitude to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>'s Municipal Railway for helping make his book possible. `` I wrote a lot of the book on the bus,'' he confided.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FAIRFIELD, Idaho (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Summer is coming to central <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Camas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prairie </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroud </PERSON> once again has his eye on Soldier Mountain's last patch of snow _ and on his friends <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> and Wes Fields. As they have for more than a decade, the three have placed bets on when the final remnant of winter will disappear. With dinner for the winner at stake, it's a bet that nature has not always been allowed to settle. <PERSON> Stroud </PERSON> is betting again that the snow will still being visible on Aug. 10, but he knows a lot can happen by then. Faced with losing several years ago when the snow was nearly gone days before his target date, <PERSON> Stroud </PERSON> sent his two sons up the mountain to stretch white sheets on the ground. Sheets can look a lot like snow from 10 miles away, but someone picked them up early and <PERSON> Stroud </PERSON> lost. Another year, <PERSON> Stroud </PERSON> was ready to collect a free meal because a tiny patch of snow was visible the afternoon before the day of reckoning. But the next day, the mountain looked bare. As it turned out, <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> had driven into the high country with Fields to shovel dirt over the snow patch. Winning that bet cost them about $ 500, but as Fields said, `` Winning is the thing, you see.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugTesting Bjt   06-20 0822</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Testing, Bjt,810</SECOND>
<HEAD>NLRB, Supreme Court Issue Major Rulings On Drug Testing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's private employers now have expanded authority to require drug tests of job applicants, while railroads and airlines have greater power to test those already on the job. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> says private employers may decide unilaterally to require drug testing of job applicants, although they still must negotiate with unions if they want to test their employees, The board's decision came Monday, the same day the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled in a more narrowly defined case that railroads may require tests for workers without first bargaining with unions. The decisions regarding existing workers appeared at odds, but they involved two separate labor laws, the Railway Labor Act that applies only to rail and airline workers, and the National Labor Relations Act which governs other labor contracts. The court case, a victory for <ORGANIZATION> Conrail </ORGANIZATION>, followed earlier rulings in which railroads and airlines won the right to test workers for drug and alcohol use, principally on grounds of concern for public safety. The <ORGANIZATION> NLRB </ORGANIZATION> case covers far more industries. One attorney involved with the <ORGANIZATION> NLRB </ORGANIZATION> decision said he expected it to lead to a proliferation of job applicant testing requirements. `` People who had been taking a sit-back-and-wait approach may now go ahead'' with pre-employment screening, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dennison </PERSON>, vice president for labor relations for the <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> newspaper of <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>. `` There's been a lot of interest. We've had a lot of inquiries.'' Labor Department figures show that about 11.05 million union members worked in the private sector last year, along with 1.1 million workers who are not members of unions but whose jobs are covered by union contracts. A department study released in January said that just 3 percent of the nation's private-sector employers had drug-testing programs, although 43 percent of businesses with 1,000 or more workers had testing programs. The Newspaper Guild had challenged the <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>'s policy of testing job applicants for drug and alcohol use without first seeking to negotiate such a policy with the union. An administrative law judge sided with the Guild in 1987, but the <ORGANIZATION> NLRB </ORGANIZATION> overturned the part of the judge's decision relating to pre-employment testing. Since applicants for union-represented jobs at the newspaper were not yet members of the union, `` We find that drug and alcohol testing of applicants for employment is not a mandatory subject of bargaining,'' the board said. It did, however, uphold a portion of the judge's decision requiring the newspaper to provide the union with the names and addresses of applicants who were offered jobs but did not take them, including those who refused to submit to testing. The board said the Guild was entitled to the information to monitor <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> hiring practices for any signs of discrimination. The union, as part of its challenge of the policy, said male applicants were allowed to provide urine samples without being observed, while female applicants were required to give the samples partially unclothed and in the presence of a nurse. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> case involved <ORGANIZATION> Conrail </ORGANIZATION>'s 1987 decision to check for drugs as part of a urinalysis administered to workers periodically and when they return to work after absences. The tests were adopted in 1976 but prior to 1987 were used only to check for health problems such as diabetes. Railway unions said adding the drug test was a `` major'' labor-management dispute under the federal Railway Labor Act, and therefore was a bargaining issue. Minor disputes may be settled by the railroad without negotiations with the union, although any decision is subject to arbitration. `` <ORGANIZATION> Conrail </ORGANIZATION>'s well-established recognition of the relevance of drug use to medical fitness substantially weakens the union's claim that <ORGANIZATION> Conrail </ORGANIZATION> now, for the first time, is engaging in medical testing that reveals facts about employees' private off-duty conduct,'' Justice <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackmun </PERSON> said in writing for the court. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>, a lawyer who represented the railroad unions, said he hopes <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will act to protect workers' rights by assuring drug tests are reliable and accurate. In another drug-testing case, the <ORGANIZATION> NLRB </ORGANIZATION> ruled Monday that a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> company violated labor law when it decided in 1986 to require all employees who were injured on the job and required treatment to submit to tests. The <ORGANIZATION> Johnson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bateman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a manufacturer of concrete pipes, contended that a `` management rights'' clause in its contract with the <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> union allowed it to implement the policy. But the board, siding with the union, said there was no evidence that drug testing was among the issues covered by the clause, which allowed the company to make certain work rule changes. `` The instant drug-alcohol testing requirement is a mandatory subject of bargaining,'' the board said. Company officials were not available for comment Monday, according to a receptionist in their office, and the company's lawyer also was not at his office Monday afternoon
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0154EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp     06-20 0673</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Should Protect Workers' Rights in Drug-Testing, Lawyer Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> should step in to protect the privacy rights of workers who face drug testing as the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> expands some employers' authority to require such tests, a union lawyer says. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>, an attorney who represented railway workers in a case the high court decided Monday, said he hopes <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will help workers by assuring drug tests are reliable and accurate. `` That's really what labor is concerned about,'' he said. <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> said in the long run federal legislation could be more significant than Monday's ruling in determining how drug tests will be conducted. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Savelson </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> lawyer whose firm represents airlines, said the ruling is unlikely to have much impact beyond the railroad and airline industries. `` Collective bargaining will still be required'' before most employers can adopt drug tests, he said. The justices, in their first decision focusing on drug testing in private employment, ruled, 7-2, that railroads that already require physical examinations for workers may require drug tests as well without bargaining with unions over the issue. The court said <ORGANIZATION> Conrail </ORGANIZATION> _ the <ORGANIZATION> Consolidated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rail </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> _ acted legally when it unilaterally decided to use urinalysis tests to check for drugs. The court based its ruling on an interpretation of the federal Railway Labor Act. That law applies to airlines as well, but the ruling may have limited impact for other industries covered by separate federal legislation. The justices, in two key decisions last March, said workers in sensitive government jobs or entrusted with public safety in federally regulated work may be forced to undergo the tests. <ORGANIZATION> Conrail </ORGANIZATION> decided in 1987 to check for drugs as part of a urinalysis administered to workers periodically and when they return to work after absences. The tests were adopted originally when <ORGANIZATION> Conrail </ORGANIZATION> was formed in 1976. But their primary purpose before 1987 was to check for physical fitness, not the presence of drugs. For example, the tests would reveal whether an employee had diabetes or other health problems. Railway labor unions said adding the drug-screening component is a `` major'' labor-management dispute under the Railway Labor Act, and therefore must be submitted to union-management negotiations. Minor disputes can be settled unilaterally by the railroad, although any such decision by an employer is subject to arbitration. Justice <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackmun </PERSON>, writing for the court, said the drug-screening change is minor because `` the action is arguably justified by the terms of the parties' collective bargaining agreement.'' Justices <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Thurgood </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> dissented. Monday's decision overturned a ruling by the Philadelphia-based 3rd <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> that barred <ORGANIZATION> Conrail </ORGANIZATION> from conducting the tests without evidence that particular workers engaged in drug abuse. The railroads said the need for drug testing is underscored by an accident at <LOCATION> Chase </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, on Jan. 4 1987, in which an <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION> passenger train collided with <ORGANIZATION> Conrail </ORGANIZATION> locomotives, killing 16 and injuring 174. The <ORGANIZATION> Conrail </ORGANIZATION> engineer and brakeman later were found to have been using marijuana. The railroads also cited studies that estimated 25 percent of railroad workers drink alcohol on duty. The studies said between 1975 and 1985, alcohol and other drugs were responsible for 37 deaths, 80 injuries and $ 34 million in property damage. In other action, the court: _ Refused to reinstate former <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> Gov <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandel </PERSON>'s 1977 mail-fraud conviction, thrown out five years after he completed a prison term. _ Refused to kill a nine-year-old lawsuit in which the <ORGANIZATION> Catawba </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribe </ORGANIZATION> claims ownership of 225 square miles of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> _ Rejected an appeal by a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> woman facing criminal charges in an attempted faith-healing of her four-year-old daughter who died of meningitis _ Struck down, by a 6-3 vote, a <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> law aimed at assuring that beer sold in the state costs no more than it does in three neighboring states _ Refused to hear an appeal by <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Randall </PERSON>, a professor and writer threatened with deportation from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for supporting communism
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0154EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MissileAgreement     06-20 0377</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Missile Agreement,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Missile-Engine Contractor, On Time, On Budget, Out of Contract</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM BOVEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> says a cruise-missile engine agreement with a <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> company will be canceled even though the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> found the deal led to lower prices. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> will cancel the agreement with <ORGANIZATION> Williams </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Walled </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, on grounds that it should not have committed the service to future contracts, <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON> wrote last week to Sen. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, D-Mich. `` For each of the past 10 years, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> has submitted competitive prices well below those of its competitor for production engines,'' <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON> wrote `` We do believe that the fact of competition has benefited the taxpayer by creating an added incentive to lower prices.'' He said <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> has exceeded its reliability goals and delivered every engine ahead of the contract date. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> in 1978 signed an agreement that would allow a competitor, <ORGANIZATION> Teledyne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, to use <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' technology to build cruise-missile engines for the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. In return, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> guaranteed it would buy 240 engines a year from <ORGANIZATION> Williams </ORGANIZATION>, plus 25 percent of any additional purchases up to 1,200 engines annually. <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON>, in an April letter to <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, had written that the decade-old agreement with <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> was `` severely limiting our contracting options and decisions, in a manner which we believe inconsistent with sound procurement policy and the public interest.'' <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON> also said in April that <ORGANIZATION> Teledyne </ORGANIZATION>'s prices had become `` very competitive'' with <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> beginning last year. The April letter was made public by a whistle-blower group called the Project on Military Procurement. <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> released last week's letter <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s cancellation of the 1978 agreement `` in no way implies criticism of <ORGANIZATION> Williams </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>'s integrity or performance.'' `` We appreciate the emphasis on ethics that has always been part of <ORGANIZATION> Williams </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>'s management, and we consider it an outstanding <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> contractor,'' <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON> wrote. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman Lt. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> said Monday he could not immediately comment on the two letters. <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> said that even though the agreement was still being canceled, `` There are some real differences'' between <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON>'s April letter and what he wrote last week `` Maybe he recognizes that his first letter was really not the most accurate reflection of the situation.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0155EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WalterMears     06-20 0857</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Walter Mears,890</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gephardt and Political Odds</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WALTER R. MEARS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The odds were heavily against <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> when he sought the White House. Now he's on another track, and the odds are on his side. One day, the new leader of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democratic majority can almost certainly become the 50th speaker of the House. As his party's floor leader, he is in the job that has produced the last 12 speakers. Rep. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>'s promotion from majority leader to speaker two weeks ago opened the leadership spot for <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> to win. It's not the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, but it's not bad work. And of course, <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>'s options are open. He's ruled out a presidential bid in 1992. But at 48 he's got plenty of time to change political goals again. With a 258-175 majority over the Republicans _ in an era when incumbents seldom lose _ the Democrats are likely to be electing speakers for quite a while. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, who begins his speakership at 60, give the Democrats a new-look team that blends the get-along skill of the legislative insider with the political savvy of the national campaigner. And <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> was known as an able congressional politician before he tried to go national. Third man in the leadership is the new Democratic whip, Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, the first black to win a top leadership post, proved able and adept as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> where he held what had been a wavering Democratic line against the lure of Reaganomics. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> turned aside questions about his future presidential ambitions by saying the voters made that call for him in 1988. But he clearly had been planning another bid for the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> in 1992 until the swift and unforeseeable shakeup that opened his path to the leadership. That came when Rep. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, the Democratic whip, announced that he was resigning rather thn undergo an ethics investigation into a 1986 junk bonds deal. He was in line to succeed <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> as majority leader with the resignation of Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> left the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday, his 47th birthday. A few weeks earlier, <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> had mused aloud about the personal and financial demands of another bid for the presidential nomination, saying he had not decided whether to take them on in advance of 1992. He said he knew that would require him to get started soon and he did n't like that idea. The question, he said then, was whether he could effectively pursue his policy goals in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Now, as majority leader, he intends to. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> said after winning the leader's job that he agreed with Speaker <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> on the priority agenda, including ethics and campaign reform. Then he turned to the economic issues that were the themes of his 1988 campaign. `` In my humble opinion, <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is beginning to be in a state of decline,'' said <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, who pressed issues of trade and productivity during his presidential run. `` And we as Democrats have to lead ... Even though the presidency is held by a different party, and even though getting our consensus together on the Democratic side is always difficult to do.'' <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> entered the Democratic presidential field as an early advocate of tax reform and a champion of protectionist trade legislation. `` It's your fight, too,'' was his message to the voters. The seasoning he gained and the scrutiny he faced as a presidential candidate will serve <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> well in his new role. Like Senate Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, who ran twice for the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, he knows the techniques of national politics better than colleagues who have done all their campaigning in home districts or congressional cloakrooms. Both he and <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> won the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses, the leadoff events of the 1988 campaign, then foundered and were finished by the March 8 Super Tuesday primaries. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> quit in time to file for reelection to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> from his <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> district, saying he'd done his best, made his mistakes and had no complaints or alibis. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> faced sharp challenges in 1988 campaign debates for changing his positions over the years on such issues as a constitutional amendment to ban abortion, on school busing, on Reaganomics. He said change was evidence of growth, of seeking better ways to do things. That explanation plays better in the congressional world of compromise and consensus than in the presidential campaign arena. Now he's tried both, and says he is not going to use the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leadership as a stepping stone to anything else. `` You ca n't be an effective majority leader and be running for president,'' he said. As for the odds: The last sitting <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> member to vault directly to the White House was Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Garfield </PERSON>, in 1880. Not since 1919 has the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> majority elected a speaker who did not serve first as his party's floor leader.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     06-20 0838</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Worst Wind Erosion in 30 Years Sweeps Over Great Plains</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Wind erosion over the winter inflicted its worst damage in three decades on the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>, ripping away topsoil over 14.3 million acres, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says. `` The big reason for the increase is the drought,'' soil conservation service chief Wilson Scaling said Monday. `` Not only was it dry but it meant we went into the wind erosion season with inadequate vegetative cover and little residue to protect the soil from blowing.'' He said the last time the May-November wind erosion season wrought so much damage on the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> was when 15 million acres were damaged in 1954-55, when the department first began to keep such records. In the worst day of the season, winds of up to 80 miles an hour swooped through on <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> on March 14, damaging 4.8 million acres. <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> was the hardest hit state, with more than 5 million acres damaged. It was a record for the state. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> was second with 2.3 million acres harmed and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> followed with almost 2 million acres damaged. More than 90 percent of the damage is on lands being used for crops. The rest is on rangeland. Wind erosion damage last year uprooted soil from some 12 million acres. The department said farmers used emergency tillage on 3 million acres, a system under which topsoil with sufficient moiture is roughened to prevent blowing. More than half of the emergency tillage was in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Here is a list of the amount of acres damaged in each <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> state: <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> 1,832,000; <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> 191,600; <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> 2,297,700; <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> 678,600; <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> 552,700; <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> 1,403,700; <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> 5,126,300; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> 118,000; <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> 111,900; <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> 1,979,600.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Wheat production in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> should fall slightly below previous estimates for the next year, suggesting supplies already reduced by last year's drought will remain tight, the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> says. With world stocks already at their lowest in more than a decade, prices could be somewhat skittish in the crop year that began June 1, responding sharply to changes in growing conditions and import demand, the department said. A drop of $ 10 a ton in the price of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat in recent weeks represents an example of this sensitivity, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said in its monthly World Grain Situation and Outlook report. Despite such fluctuations, however, prices should remain strong on the whole, the department said. It said the overall strength in prices combined with an improvement in crop prospects in some of the traditional importing countries is expected to reduce world demand from the level of a year earlier. The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> said the major change will come in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, where wheat imports are expected to decline by around 20 percent to 12 million tons. Estimated exports by the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> remain the same as previously, but the forecast of production has been lowered to reflect a smaller than expected crop of durum, the wheat used for pasta. The report said that might mean increased <ORGANIZATION> EC </ORGANIZATION> imports of North American durum and might even trigger a cutback in Italian semolina exports to <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The European Community estimate was for 77.8 million metric tons, down from 78.5 million last month. The estimate of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production was 55.2 million, down from 55.8 million in last month's report.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Parrot lovers and other buyers of exotic birds are getting a stern warning from the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> to make certain their pets meet federal import requirements. The warning has been brought on by an outbreak of exotic <ORGANIZATION> Newcastle </ORGANIZATION> disease among 17 <ORGANIZATION> Amazon </ORGANIZATION> parrots, sun cockatoos and other birds owned by a <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> collector. Seven of the parrots were purchased from a <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> dealer on May 19 and became ill. They and 12 other birds were dead by June 14. Meanwhile, the collector had sold some of the birds to five pet stores and a number of individual purchasers. The birds were tested by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterinary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratories </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ames </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, operated by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inspection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. They were found to have exotic Newcastle disease. To prevent further spread of the disease, the collector's 60 remaining birds were destroyed, the department said. It said it will pay the collector more than $ 45,000 in indemnities for the destruction of his collection. Exotic Newcastle disease is a virus that is deadly to all birds and could be a major problem for the commercial poultry industry, although no commercial flocks have been infected yet. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Slagle </PERSON>, acting director of the inspection service, said smuggled birds enter the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> by the hundreds following the winter breeding season and often carry exotic Newcastle disease without showing symptoms. He said exotic birds imported into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> must be declared to federal inspectors, carry appropriate permits and enter a mimimum 30-day quarantine. The Agriculture Department tests them for disease during that time.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush     06-20 0679</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Draws Lesson for US Students From Chinese Events</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Top prospects uncertain; presidential scholars cermony at 2:30
p.m. EDT</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, drawing a lesson for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s youth from the struggles of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s students in <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, is urging young people to devote their lives to democratic ideals and community service <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was honoring 121 of the nation's top high school seniors, the 1989 Presidential Scholars, at the White House today, after making a quick journey by helicopter Monday evening to deliver a commencement address at <ORGANIZATION> Cheltenham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Wyncote </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa </LOCATION>. There, in a steamy gymnasium packed with 2,500 people, he delivered a message intended for all 2.5 million seniors graduating from high school this June, not just Cheltenham's 331. `` We do not have to stand in front of tanks in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, thank God. But we do have to summon the same courage to confront the evil that exists in the world,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. He told the <LOCATION> Cheltenham </LOCATION> graduates they were the heirs to a legacy of American sacrifice, from <LOCATION> Bunker </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Bastogne </LOCATION>, `` where we upheld the tenets of democracy,'' and from the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> to the <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>. `` Today I ask you to take a risk for a cause larger than ourselves,'' he said. `` It is the cause of helping others and thereby <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. It is the cause of democratic ideals.'' He said brave people are struggling in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> for basic human rights and freedoms that `` our ancesors secured for us _ and that we too often take for granted.'' Recalling the solitary young man who briefly stopped a column of tanks in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> on June 5, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` That vivid, unforgettable image illustrates how precious is the freedom that is <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s secret weapon and her shield. He called volunteerism and community service `` central to our fabric as a nation, and as a people. No, they are n't as dramatic as the profiles in courage of <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>, the gulags and Tiananmen Square. `` But they reflect the same sense of sacrifice and of concern ... for country, decency, our fellow man,'' he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plans to keep the spotlight on youth and altruism on Wednesday at the White House when he announces details of the `` YES to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> Initiative.'' The acronym stands for Youth Entering Service. `` We will refute those who speak of a ` me' generation. Instead this program can build a cathedral of the spirit, and help yours become a global ` we' generation,'' he told the seniors. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has previously announced plans to ask <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to invest $ 100 million over four years into a YES Foundation to encourage young people to perform community service. He will head the foundation. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was introduced at <LOCATION> Cheltenham </LOCATION> by <PERSON> Hang </PERSON> <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON>, a senior graduating with top honors who came to this country as a refugee from her native <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> in 1975. Her mother still lives there. `` Each of us has come to this moment in a different way,'' she said. `` Our commencement is both a common achievement and a unique one. In some ways these ceremonies are like thousands of others being held across the nation.'' But, she added, they were also `` unique because of this class ... this school ... this community'' _ and the commencement speaker. The 330 <ORGANIZATION> Cheltenham </ORGANIZATION> seniors had to yield some graduation tickets and curtail their own speeches to make room for the president and his entourage. `` Half of us were excited,'' said <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorman </PERSON>. `` But there were those who thought it is more important for more of the relatives to come than the president.'' But another senior, <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Cherry </PERSON>, said, `` It's the greatest thing that could happen to a senior class.'' Each graduate got a handshake from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, and many of the girls stole a kiss as well. The graduates wore blue and gold robes, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was in academic garb himself. <PERSON> Cheltenham </PERSON>'s alumni include baseball star <PERSON> Reggie </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>; <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Meyers </PERSON>, an architect of the Social Security system, and Dr. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, a Nobel Prize winner for medicine.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0218EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BlackHeartbeat     06-20 0491</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Black Heartbeat,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Finds Black Men Have Faster Heart Rates Than White Men Under
Exercise</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Black men experience a faster heartbeat at moderate exercise than do their white counterparts, a finding that may account for the greater incidence of high blood pressure and heart disease among blacks, according to a <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> researcher. Dr. <PERSON> Lars </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ekelund </PERSON>, an associate professor of medicine at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION>, said an analysis of treadmill stress tests conducted as part of a national study showed black men tended to have about eight more heartbeats a minute than white men at the same levels of exercise. `` We found a difference that was highly significant,'' said <PERSON> Ekelund </PERSON> in an interview Monday. `` If you take those eight beats, it corresponds to about a 30 percent increase in risk for coronary heart disease.'' The increased heartbeat rate during exercise could also explain why blacks tend to have more hypertension, or high blood pressure, and more strokes than whites, he said. Resting pulse rates, taken before the exercise, showed no significant difference between the races. <PERSON> Ekelund </PERSON> said a weakness in the study is that only 83 black men participated while 2,548 white men were counted. A much larger study is needed, he said, to confirm the data. <PERSON> Ekelund </PERSON> said the pulse rates probably are a fundamental genetic difference between the races in their response to exercise. This difference, he said, may be important when evaluating the cardiac health of a black male. Higher heartbeat rates usually suggest a person is less fit, but for a black male the higher rate may be normal. `` It suggests we should apply different norms for black males compared to whites,'' said <PERSON> Ekelund </PERSON>. If the same norms are used for a black person as for a white person, he said, the difference in heartbeat rate would make a black man appear less fit than he actually is. The study is based on data collected from men between the 20 and 69. None of the test subjects had detectable heart disease when the tests were administered. The data was adjusted, said <PERSON> Ekelund </PERSON>, for differences in age, weight and other factors which can affect individual heart rates. <PERSON> Ekelund </PERSON> said the research agrees with an earlier study that monitored the blood pressure of boys while they played stressful video games. That study showed black youths tended to have higher blood pressure in response to the excitement of the game. `` This suggests that blacks may inherit an increased response to stress which may explain their higher prevalence of hypertension,'' he said. The data used in the study was collected by the National Heart, Lung and <ORGANIZATION> Blood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> as part of a national research effort by 10 clinics. A massive amount of data was collected in the 1970s and is still being analyzed. <PERSON> Ekelund </PERSON> presented the research finding Monday at the <ORGANIZATION> Second </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> on Preventive Cardiology.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HeartDisease     06-20 0691</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Heart Disease,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Heart Disease Death Rates Declining In West, Up in Eastern Europe</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Heart disease death rates have been retreating for almost three decades in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> industrialized countries and experts at an international conference say they still do n't know why. `` There is one less coronary -LRB- heart attack -RRB- every minute in this country,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Lenfant </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heart </ORGANIZATION>, Lung and <ORGANIZATION> Blood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. `` We have witnessed a significant decrease in heart disease. But the cause of this decline is not clear.'' <PERSON> Lenfant </PERSON> said the decline in heart attacks in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> started in the 1960s, when the rate of death from cardiac disease was more than 400 per 100,000 persons. The rate is dropping at a steady annual rate and now is about 330 per 100,000 persons. `` It keeps going down and there is no sign of its leveling off,'' <PERSON> Lenfant </PERSON> told reporters Monday at the <ORGANIZATION> 2nd </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> on Preventive Cardiology. He said the reasons could be a reduction in smoking, better diets, more exercise or better treatment. But it would take a large, comprehensive study to pinpoint the exact reason for the change. `` The decline in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> -LRB- of heart disease deaths -RRB- is extraordinary,'' said Dr. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedewald </PERSON>, associate director for disease prevention at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION>. `` But the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> still has one of the highest rates in the world.'' <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, which already has one of the lowest rates of cardiac disease in the world, is also experiencing a decline in death rates. Dr. <PERSON> Hirotsugu </PERSON> <PERSON> Ueshima </PERSON>, a researcher at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cardiovascular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Osaka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, said that in 1970 there were 120 cardiac disease deaths annually per 100,000 persons over age 60 in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. That rate now has dropped to 100. For those age 50 to 59, the rate has dropped from 60 per 100,000 in 1970 to 40 at present. `` It is still going down,'' said <PERSON> Ueshima </PERSON>. People in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, he said, are now eating more animal fat, thought to be a risk factor in heart disease, but this has had no apparent impact on rate of heart disease. `` Even though there is more meat -LRB- a source of animal fat -RRB- in the diet, it is still lower than the American diet,'' he said. Japanese get about 25 percent of their calories from fat, compared to about 38 percent in the American diet, he said. Healthier hearts, however, are not universal. A <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> study released at the conference shows deaths among men from heart disease rose steeply between 1970 and 1985 in nearly all of the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> countries where data is available. The study included only industrialized countries and did not include trend data from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION> led the rate of reported increase with heart disease death rates shooting up by 62 percent. By comparison, in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> during that same period, the rates declined by 36.5 percent. Even with the increase, however, <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION> still has a lower rate of heart disease mortality for men, about 297 per 100,000 persons, than the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>, the report says. The male heart disease death rate in other countries included increases of 30 percent in <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>; 36.9 percent in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>; 42.8 percent in <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>; 19.5 percent in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>; 18.1 percent in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, and 14.4 percent in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Deaths among men from heart disease declined throughout western and northern <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, and also in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. An exception was <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, where the rate increased by 0.8 percent. Except for <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>, heart disease death rates declined for women in all of the reported countries. The rates for women declined most remarkably in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, both with drops of about 50 percent. In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the death rates for women dropped by 33.8 percent and stood at 119 per 100,000. According to the report, the lowest rate of death due to heart disease was among women in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, where the rate was 41 per 100,000. The highest was among men in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> where the rate was 438 per 100,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0222EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Toxics-Database     06-20 0419</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Toxics-Database,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Cancer Chemicals, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Information on what hazardous chemicals are being released from nearby industrial plants will soon be as close as the home computer or a neighborhood library, says the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> unveiled its computerized database for toxic chemical releases on Monday and said that in the coming months the information _ which will be updated yearly _ will be available in microfiche as well as computer disc and magnetic tape. The inventory of releases, which is based on information provided the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> by each company, also may be obtained through ToxNet, a computer information system of the National Library of Medicine. Access to ToxNet will cost $ 25 an hour and be accessible by home computers 24 hours a day. A 1986 law, which took effect last year, requires industry to supply information each year on what toxic chemicals are being released from plants. The requirement covers 328 hazardous chemicals. It took the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> nearly a year to develop the computer database, but <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Elkins </PERSON>, director of toxics at the agency, said the job is likely to be easier and quicker next time around. Industry is scheduled to submit its second round of data at the end of this month, covering releases in 1988. The first set of data was submitted nearly a year ago, reflecting releases in 1987. `` We have tried to make the computerized inventory as ` user friendly' as possible,'' said <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> database allows a person to focus on a single industrial plant and learn what toxic releases into the air, water, or soil the plant has reported to the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> during the latest reporting year. The system includes a variety of indexes including type of chemicals, names of plants, and locations of plants down to counties, cities and postal zip codes, officials said. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said the computerized database or microfiche will be made available to more than 1,400 federal libraries and local public libary systems so that at least one library in every county will have the data available. In addition, the database on computer disc or magnetic tape will be for sale through the Government Printing Office or the National Technical Information System -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> NTIS </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Editors: For more information about the toxic chemical release inventory contact the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, -LRB- phone: 800-535-0202 -RRB-; <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- phone: 703-487-4650 -RRB-; <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- phone: 301-496-6531 -RRB-; the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION> Government Printing Office, -LRB- phone: 202-275-2091 -RRB-
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890620-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-20-89 0224EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-ToxicChemicals-List     06-20 1130</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Toxic Chemicals-List,1000</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Cancer Chemicals, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
