<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 2330EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-NewVietnam 2ndLd-Writethru a0719 01-18 0911</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-New Vietnam, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0719,0936</SECOND>
<HEAD>Marines Visit Battlefield with Former Enemy</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS graf after 2nd graf, ``Don't go...' to ADD that Americans
wanted to point out where mines may be. Pick up 3rd pvs, `As the...'</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Six former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Marines are visiting <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> as volunteers to help get rid of mines they planted more than 20 years ago. Here is a report on their journy by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Esper </PERSON>, who spent 10 years covering the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> War for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> and is on his second reporting trip there since then.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE ESPER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CON THIEN, Vietnam (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Six former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Marines visited their old battleground with a man who had been their enemy, walking carefully to avoid unexploded mines laid more than 20 years ago. `` Do n't go off the road. It's very dangerous. A lot of people have been killed by mines,'' Col. <PERSON> Ho </PERSON> <PERSON> Minh </PERSON> <PERSON> Thanh </PERSON> told the Americans, who came as volunteers to help get rid of mines they had sown as young soldiers. The Americans were not carrying any equipment, but they wanted to point out likely sites where mines may be concealed. As the Marines moved out on their patrol into the past, trudging along the red dirt road of the Alpha 3 artillery base, <PERSON> Thanh </PERSON> confirmed their suspicions that mines remained, despite assurances by <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> ambassador that all had been cleared. <PERSON> Thanh </PERSON> said the region he commands in central <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> still is laden with dangerous, unexploded shells and many of the 100,000 land mines planted in the late 1960s by the 11th Marines, an engineer battalion to which five of the visitors belonged. `` We lost a lot of people, even children. People are still being injured and killed,'' <PERSON> Thanh </PERSON> said during the tour Tuesday. At another base at <LOCATION> Gio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Linh </LOCATION>, scores of poor women and children hacked in the ruins with hoes and shovels despite the danger, searching for valuable scrap metal from shell casings. <PERSON> Thanh </PERSON> said soldiers and civilians had tried to clear the mines from around <ORGANIZATION> Alpha </ORGANIZATION> 3 so rubber trees could be planted, but there were too many. He agreed with <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Spanos </PERSON>, a 39-year-old police lieutenant from <LOCATION> Rosemont </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, who organized the 10-day inspection trip, that something should be done. `` Can we go back and relay that information to your people in <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION>?'' <PERSON> Spanos </PERSON> asked the colonel. `` Would that be OK?'' `` Thank you. We appreciate that,'' <PERSON> Thanh </PERSON> said. `` That's why we're here,'' said <PERSON> Spanos </PERSON>. The American reported to <PERSON> Thanh </PERSON> that the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> told him in a letter it had offered to help clear mines and dispose of unexploded shells, some fired by the North Vietnamese and some by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers and their South Vietnamese allies. `` What the response was, I do n't know,'' <PERSON> Spanos </PERSON> said. `` Thank you very much for your good intentions,'' <PERSON> Thanh </PERSON> replied through the interpreter who translated their remarks for each other. On a visit by the Americans to the Vietnamese <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Mission in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> three months ago, Ambassador <PERSON> Trinh </PERSON> <PERSON> Xuan </PERSON> <PERSON> Lang </PERSON> told <PERSON> Spanos </PERSON> all the mines had been cleared but the former <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION> were welcome to visit as tourists. That is how they traveled, in a van provided by the <ORGANIZATION> Vietnam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tourist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION>, unofficial goodwill ambassadors whose expenses are being paid by an anonymous benefactor. `` I knew damn well not all of those mines had been taken out,'' said <PERSON> Nate </PERSON> <PERSON> Genna </PERSON>, 41, of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. `` We laid over 100,000 in a relatively small region.'' The region included a string of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bases just below what was then the demilitarized zone dividing <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> north and south at the 17th parallel. The country was reunited by <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s victory in April 1975. `` I think there has been a reconciliation,'' <PERSON> Genna </PERSON> said. `` It's not after every war that guys come back who actually did the work and try to do something about it It's a load off my mind. I had my doubts all along. This is awful, all these years later.'' <PERSON> Spanos </PERSON> said: `` We've accomplished everything. We found out the Vietnamese would not let us off this road for our safety, and that it has been confirmed by a Vietnamese commander who served in this area who still is in the army, who is still aware and has acknowledged that there are mines in this area and people are still being injured, still being killed.'' He said he would send full reports to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Vietnamese governments saying there are serious mine problems at three of the four bases they visited: Alpha 3, <PERSON> Con </PERSON> <PERSON> Thien </PERSON> just to the west and <LOCATION> Khe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sanh </LOCATION>, where <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Marines withstood a 77-day siege in 1968. On their visit to <LOCATION> Khe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sanh </LOCATION>, the former Marines were restricted to the main road because of mines and unexploded shells. <PERSON> Spanos </PERSON> said his report would call attention to the dangers of <PERSON> Gio </PERSON> <PERSON> Linh </PERSON>, the easternmost base, where the women and children risked death for a possible prize. Their journey stirred memories for the Americans. Marines put the first protective shield of mines around Alpha 3 at Christmas 1967, said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, 41, of <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Noe </PERSON>, 40, of <LOCATION> Stoughton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, looked at the red dirt and said: `` There was a lot of heavy combat at this base, as there was at <PERSON> Con </PERSON> <PERSON> Thien </PERSON> and Gio Linh ... We ran operations along the <ORGANIZATION> DMZ </ORGANIZATION>. A lot of guys died up around here.'' His voice trailed off and he he walked away to weep alone.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 2335EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Bundy 2ndLd-Writethru a0870 01-18 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bundy, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0870,0730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Martinez Won't Delay Execution, Says Bundy Trying To Bargain For
Life</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 15th graf, `Hilyer said ..., to CORRECT spelling of Keppel,
sted Kibbel.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED BIRK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> will not bargain with convicted killer <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> to delay his scheduled execution in exchange for details of several unsolved murders in other states, Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> said Wednesday. An attorney and adviser for <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>, scheduled to be executed Tuesday, asked for a reprieve of up to three years so <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> could talk to law officers. Officials from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> have asked to interview Bundy but have not sought any delay. Before his capture in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> was on the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s most-wanted list as a suspect in as many as 36 sex-related murders or disappearances of young women in the <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION>. The governor, who signed <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s death warrant Tuesday shortly after the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> refused to hear his appeal in the 1978 murder of a 12-year-old <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> girl, said <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> was once again trying to foil justice. `` We're not going to have the system manipulated,'' said <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>. `` One of the things to be made clear here to law enforcement, which I think they realize more than anyone else what <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> has done, is you do n't negotiate with a murderer. You do n't negotiate with a killer.'' He promised to make Bundy available to any law agency in the days remaining before his execution. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s civil attorney, <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Sarasota </LOCATION>, told the governor's death-penalty lawyer, <PERSON> Andrea </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> <PERSON> Hillyer </PERSON>, that <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> was committed to revealing all he knew about unsolved murders. <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON> did n't specify about which cases he had information. `` <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> feels morally compelled as he faces death to do the right thing in terms of resolving any investigations,'' she said. `` While it may satisfyingly close the book on the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> cases, the immediate execution will effectively cripple law enforcement agencies around the country.'' <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> said he had no patience for any more appeals. `` He has been in jail for 11 years. He certainly could have come clean in other occasions, but he has used the court. Now all of a sudden, he wants to tell the truth,'' said <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> always has insisted that he is innocent of any murder. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>, 42, also is under death sentences for fatally bludgeoning two <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> sorority sisters. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> attorney, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, said he's not involved in any attempt to delay the execution by talking about other cases, but was planning an appeal on the question of <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s sanity <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> filed an emergency appeal through state <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, and a hearing has been scheduled for Thursday morning, a court clerk said. <PERSON> Hillyer </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Keppel </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state attorney general's office planned to talk with <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>, who is suspected in up to 20 killings and more closely linked to eight killings in that state. She added that an official from the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Violent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crime </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Quantico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, wanted to interview <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayward </PERSON> said he is sending Detective <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Couch </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> on Saturday in hopes of interviewing <LOCATION> Bundy </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hayward </PERSON> said he hoped <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION> law student, could help authorities locate the bodies of any <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> victims. `` He has n't indicated he'd say a word to us, but there's always that long shot, that last-second chance that he'll say ` Ah, bring them in, let's see what's on their minds,''' <PERSON> Hayward </PERSON> said. Also announced Wednesday was <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s decision, reversing himself, to grant a news media interview, and <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s request for a personal interview with <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>, host of a <LOCATION> Pomona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, - based radio show called `` Focus on the Family. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON> said he has exchanged letters with <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> for the past two years. He did n't know what <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> might want to talk about but hoped that if <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> has information about any other killings he would reveal it to help ease the victims' families. `` When a man is looking death in the face, he does n't waste words and I want to hear what he has to say,'' said <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>, who said his 30-minute radio show is carried on 1,300 stations in 26 countries.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 2341EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-InauguralDinners1stLd-writethru a0869   01-18 1184</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Inaugural Dinners 1st Ld-writethru, a0869,1200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: To update with Bush quotes, top 8 grafs new, picks up into 2nd
graf previous, ``Inside''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 2,500 wealthy Republican partisans, unmindful of chanting protesters outside, feasted on a $ 1,500-a-plate dinner of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> crab and mushroom-stuffed veal Wednesday night and cheered <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s declaration that `` I'm gon na try my level best to be a good president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The president-elect and his vice president-to-be, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, toured three black-tie inaugural dinners two days before they take the oath of office, and by the time they reached their final stop at Union Station, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, with a laugh, that `` We're exhausted.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> thanked the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> faithful for helping him get elected Nov. 8 and for their financial support that opened the four days of inaugural festivities to thousands of `` just plain folks.'' `` I hope you enjoy the celebration,'' he said. `` We've earned it together.'' After he was toasted with champagne and serenaded by the Whiffenpoofs, the famed glee club from his <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> alma mater, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> drew a roar of approval from the crowd when he said he would try to be a good president and `` work for all the people of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' Said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: `` You've given me a chance and I'm not going to let you down.'' Then <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> stepped down from the podium and shook hands with scores of well-wishers followed by his wife, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>, and the Quayles, during their half-hour appearance. Before the dinner started, several hundred protesters demonstrated outside Union Station for three hours and chanted at arriving limousines `` Food For The Poor, Not The Rich,'' and `` What About The Homeless?'' Inside Union Station, the black-tie guests expressed little concern about the message the demonstraters were shouting. `` I feel it's ridiculous,'' said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> business executive. `` They hold these staged events every time Republicans get together and it's in very poor taste.'' `` The people here have probably contributed more as individuals and corporations to the welfare of this country than anybody else,'' said <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>, oilman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hewgley </PERSON>. `` If they want to celebrate, then, by <PERSON> God </PERSON>, they're entitled to.'' Several hundred protesters demonstrated for three hours, shouting at the limousines that pulled up to the main entrance at Union Station with inaugural dinner guests, but dispersed peaceably as the dinner began in mid-evening. Three hours before the start of the Union Station dinner, several hundred street people enjoyed a `` counter Inaugural banquet'' of hot chili and rice, tortilla chips, salad and apple cider on the plaza in front of Union Station. While they ate off of paper plates, the homeless listened to guitar players and watched a pro-abortion street theater featuring a man in tennis shoes wearing a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> mask and a sign reading, `` I oppose abortion'' hanging around his neck. Protesters organized by a group called, `` The Counter-Inaugural Coalition for a Peoples' Agenda,'' carried placards reading, `` Food, Not Bombs,'' `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Knew </PERSON>'' and `` The Skies Are for Stars, Not War.'' Another sign under a huge peace symbol read, `` Now Appearing In a Four-Year Show, Son of <LOCATION> Reaganstein </LOCATION>, co-starring Big Bird.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> were guests of honor at the lavish dinners attended by more than 2,500 Republican stalwarts and fat-cat contributors. The black-tie crowd was so large the dinners were held at Union Station and the nearby Pension Building and Corcoran Gallery of Art. For $ 1,500 ticket, each invited guest was to hear brief remarks by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> at the three dinner sites and feast on a four-course dinner. Outside of Union Station, Park Police Sgt. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kass </PERSON> banished a half dozen conservative Republican counter-demonstrators for lack of a permit. The leader of the group, <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Delgaudio </PERSON>, 34, executive director of the private, ultra-conservative activists group known as `` Public Advocate,'' said he wanted to show `` there's a better way than openly, political negativism.'' He said his demonstrators were to welcome the black-tie dinner guests with <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> flags and signs reading, `` Welcome Non-Liberals.'' Several homeless people paused between spoonfuls of chili to say that the $ 2.25 million in proceeds from the inaugural dinners should be spent to provide food, additional shelters, job training and subsidized public transportation for <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s street people. Referring to the inaugural diners, <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> <PERSON> Carrington </PERSON>, a 30-year-old homeless person, said, `` I think maybe they should eat the same thing we're having so they'll know what it's like.'' Said <PERSON> Ronnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, 38: `` They done robbed most of it from us.'' He said the inaugural dinner proceeds should be used for the homeless because `` a lot of them have given up.'' More than 1,000 people were served at the counter-inaugural dinner at Union Station. As guests began arriving shortly before 7 p.m., several hundred of the people at the counter-inaugural banquet began shouting, `` What about the homeless'' and `` 50,000 dead from AIDS. Where was <PERSON> George </PERSON>?'' Although the Park Police allowed the demonstration to spread closer to the train depot than the demonstrators' permit allowed, the protestors remained 100 yards from the entrance where the invited guests were emerging from their cars and were barely audible from that distance. At about 7:30 p.m., one half hour before the Union Station banquet would get officially underway, the Park Police received reinforcement and barricades which were set up in front of the demonstrators. Park Police Sgt. <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON>, asked whether the barricades had been planned in advance, said, `` I'm not in on these decisions, but I imagine it was spontaneous because of the crowd's activity ... we ca n't have the police spread out or people can sneak through. We should have had them up there before.'' There was no indication that any of the invited guests to the Union Station dinner were even aware of the demonstration. None of them came over to see what is going on. At the majestic <ORGANIZATION> Corcoran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gallery </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION>, dinner guests who also paid $ 1,500 each were serenaded up a royal blue carpeted stairway by violins playing, `` This Could Be The Start of Something Big.'' Elegantly attired guests wandered through art displays ranging from modern neon art to traditional American pieces. The gallery was hung with blue bunting with white stars and large arrangements of red roses decorated the corridors. Among the guests at the Corcoran gala dinner were <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s longtime friend and Commerce secretary-designate, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON>'s socialite wife <PERSON> Georgette </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON>, like Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was dressed in a black-and-white gown. Also among the guests were Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>., and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s son, <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON>, and his wife, The younger <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he was having fun, but mostly waiting for Friday's swearing in of his father. `` The rest will be fun,'' he said, adding, however, `` the one we will all be looking forward to will be Friday - an incredibly proud moment for all of us.'' His wife, who wore a fitted, strapless black gown with a brocade bodice, said she had never seen <PERSON> George </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> so excited as they have been with the inauguration approaching. `` They're like two kids,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 0042EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SeattleGrowth     01-18 1113</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Seattle Growth,1144</SECOND>
<HEAD>Traffic, Pollution Spur Citizens' Movement To Curb Growth</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RENEE SCHOOF</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Brazil-EvadingLaw     01-18 0759</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Brazil-Evading Law,0776</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brazil Boat Disaster Sparks Outcry Against Impunity Of Rich</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report. ^By LISA GENASCI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The sinking New Year's Eve of an overcrowded tourist boat off <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Janeiro </LOCATION> has sparked a nationwide outcry against what many Brazilians feel is the impunity of the rich and powerful and a general disrespect for law. In public demonstrations, Brazilians have made the tragedy, in which 52 passengers and crew died, a forum to rail against a widespread sense that in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> people in the right places can get away with lawbreaking _ from running red lights to hiring professional killers. `` Some of the worst vices of the Brazilian soul came to light the moment the boat sank: facility to bribe, irresponsibility and the failure to assist fellow citizens in trouble,'' the newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Jornal </ORGANIZATION> do Brasil of <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Janeiro </LOCATION> said in an editorial. There has been no accurate count of the number of revelers on the Bateau Mouche when it capsized and sank on its way to an annual fireworks display off <LOCATION> Copacabana </LOCATION> beach. A widely accepted figure is 150. The flat-bottomed river boat was built to carry 20 passengers. Survivors claim it was dangerously overcrowded and listing badly in rough water and that lifejackets were not readily accessible. There are accusations _ as yet unproved _ that <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> guards who inspected the Bateau Mouche just two hours before it went down were paid off to allow it to venture into the open sea. The navy and the police are bickering over which group should investigate the sinking. There is widespread fear that no one will be held responsible _ as happened so often before here in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s largest country, in highway and maritime tragedies, fires and collapses of buildings and freeways. In 1981, for example, two riverboat sinkings in <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> waters claimed about 500 lives. Both resulted from overcrowding, yet no one was ever prosecuted. `` The sinking of the Bateau Mouche is a portrait of our reality,'' political commentator <PERSON> Alexandre </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> said in a syndicated newspaper column. `` We were already irresponsible, now we are becoming inhuman.'' `` There is a cultural tradition of disregarding security norms, of negligence,'' said <PERSON> Evaristo </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Moraes </PERSON>, a lawyer for the owners of the Bateau Mouche. `` We need to look at our mentality, which believes that laws are always flexible.'' <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Moraes </PERSON> added, however, that in the case of the boat disaster, `` I am convinced my clients had no responsibility whatsoever.'' Indeed, one of the owners of the boat initially told reporters that `` panic among the passengers'' was the cause of the tragedy. <PERSON> Paulo </PERSON> <PERSON> Soares </PERSON>, a son-in-law of the Bateau Mouche's 50-year-old captain, <PERSON> Camilo </PERSON> <PERSON> da </PERSON> <PERSON> Costa </PERSON>, who drowned, told the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>, `` <PERSON> Camilo </PERSON> did n't want to go out He called us to say the boat was overloaded and the sea was too rough. But he had no choice. He would lose his job if he did n't sail.'' Brazilians are proud of what they call `` jeitinho,'' or a `` little way'' of cutting through red tape, avoiding a traffic ticket or eliminating a problem that has become intertwined with self-definitions of national character. There is a whole professional category known as `` despachantes,'' whose job consists basically of paying off the right people. A recent prime-time TV soap opera, `` Vale Tudo -LRB- Anything Goes -RRB-, drew ratings of 80 percent with its portrayals of greed, conniving, corruption and deceit among it principal characters. But it is n't exclusively a lack of respect for laws that has generated a sense of impunity in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, said Deputy Justice Minister <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Eichenberg </PERSON>. `` This also has grown from a tremendous lack of human and material resources,'' he said. `` We often are physically and financially unable to enforce the law.'' Many Brazilians are determined that the Bateau Mouche case not be forgotten. Theater and movie personalities _ outraged by the drowning of the well-known actress <PERSON> Yara </PERSON> <PERSON> Amaral </PERSON> _ along with <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> city </LOCATION> councilmen and other well known figures have organized to demand that police determine responsibility in the sinking. Brazilians also have rallied around the shooting death in December of the internationally known ecologist <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Mendes </PERSON>, who sought to defend the <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION>'s ecology and its poor peasants against the interests of powerful landowners. Many employ private gunmen to eliminate enemies. According to <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, the London-based human rights organization, about 1,000 peasants, ecologists and <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> priests, who defend landless farmers, have been killed in land disputes in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> since 1980. Only three cases have been prosecuted, the organization says.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HollywoodHomecoming     01-18 0707</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hollywood Homecoming,0727</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagans' Return Is the Talk of Hollywood</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Army in 4th graf is cq</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> returns to his beloved <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> as the toast of <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, reinvigorating the social scene with the stature of a popular two-term president who never forgot his show business past. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> do n't hide their eagerness to step out of the national spotlight and re-enter a private world among friends. The president has said: `` Every time I come home I say to myself, ` Why did I ever leave?''' Their affluent friends are no less eager. `` It's tough to beat a former president living in your midst. They are now going to be the superstars in the <LOCATION> Bel-Air </LOCATION> circuit,'' entertainment industry observer <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Archerd </ORGANIZATION> said. `` Hollywood feels it sent one of its own to the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and now he's returned as the most popular president in history. He's one of us,'' said TV producer <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Willenborg </PERSON>. <PERSON> Merv </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barron </PERSON> <PERSON> Hilton </PERSON> set the social tone by throwing a $ 25,000-a-table homecoming gala earlier this month. The <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> will be a star attraction Feb. 23 at the <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Hope Award presentations honoring <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> and a Valentine's Day party is on tap for Mrs. `` They will really re-invigorate things,'' dance man <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> predicted. <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> said the social calendar is already topsy-turvy. `` I'm sure they will be the leaders of everything that happens here,'' he said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> never forgot <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, where he starred in motion pictures and led the <ORGANIZATION> Screen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Actors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION>. Throughout his eight years in the White House he delighted in spinning show business yarns. There are those who hope <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s fondness for his old vocation will lead him back to the screen. Actress <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> said a script has been written for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to play her ex-husband on `` Dynasty'' if he chooses, and <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> suggested the Reagans might make a movie together. But one longtime <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> friend said television and movies are n't part of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> post-presidential agenda `` I think the idea of him being interested in an acting career is absurd,'' said the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> confidant, who spoke on condition that his name be withheld. `` I do n't think he will do anything in entertainment.'' However, the same source said the nation may hear <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on Saturday morning radio again, expressing his thoughts and opinions on issues facing the country. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> expects to be inundated with requests to make speeches on `` the mashed-potato circuit'' and has offered himself up as a foot soldier in what he calls the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> <PERSON> Brigade </PERSON> of his successor's supporters He and Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> also have plans to write memoirs and push their pet causes. Not everyone is happy the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> are back in town. Residents of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> View </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Terrace </LOCATION>, 20 miles north of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, have been fighting to keep the <ORGANIZATION> Nancy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reagan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> for drug rehabilitation out of their neighborhood. Homeowners fear the center, an extension of Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s `` Just Say No'' anti-drug crusade, will bring addicts into the area and endanger residents. During the recent <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> welcome-home gala, which raised $ 1 million for the center, residents marched outside with signs reading, `` If you really care, put it in <LOCATION> Bel-Air </LOCATION>.'' That affluent hillside enclave is the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s new neighborhood. Although they are keeping their <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION> ranch as a retreat, they intend to spend most of their time in their new $ 2.5 million <LOCATION> Bel-Air </LOCATION> home. Perched in hills among $ 10 million-plus mansions, the 6,500-square-foot ranch-style home is modest by neighborhood standards. Little can be seen behind an electronic iron gate leading to 668 Saint Cloud Rd. A guard shack was constructed recently, a chain link fence was thrown up over vintage stone walls and roof-mounted cameras scan the property. The address was changed last summer from 666 Saint Cloud because of connotations surrounding the number 666, believed by some to be the symbol of the devil. Tourists clutching $ 5 maps to stars' homes ply the winding roads aboard tour vans or in rental cars. So far, little notice has been paid to the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> house _ the real stars are the `` Beverly Hillbillies'' mansion and the home of entertainer <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Germany-Draft     01-18 0128</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Germany-Draft,0131</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government To Lengthen Military Service</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> has lengthened its compulsory military service from 15 months to 18 months, a move the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> say could jeopardize East-West disarmament efforts. Following Tuesday's announcement by the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>, the Free Democrats, a minority party in Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s coalition government, also expressed reservations and asked that the move be delayed Given that about 400,000 more draft-age men than needed are now available, the opposition says extending service time is unnecessary. The Social Democrats also point to a lessened threat from the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc. The armed forces now have about 495,000 members. Men aged 18 through 28 are subject to be drafted and about half of those in service are draftees.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0777 01-18 1039</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0777,1072</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: ADDS Cruickshank Garcia and Sheatsley; Separates moved for AMs
as a0669 on Wilson, a0736 on Bentsen, a0756 on Allott, a0763 on Probst
and as a0762 on Cruickshank Garcia. Probst also moved on the business wire.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos MCA1,DN2,DN5</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Trey Wilson</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Trey </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, a character actor who appeared on stage and screen in recent hits from `` Raising Arizona'' to `` <PERSON> Bull </PERSON> <PERSON> Durham </PERSON>,'' died Monday of a cerebral hemorrhage at age 40. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> also appeared in `` A Soldier's Story,'' `` F-X'' and `` The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on <LOCATION> Carroll </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>.'' Two other films _ `` Welcome Home'' and `` Miss Firecracker'' _ have not yet been released, along with the just-completed `` Great Balls of Fire,'' the <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> story. He appeared on stage in `` The Front Page'' at <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, `` Custom of the Country'' at the Second Stage and `` The Debutante Ball'' at <ORGANIZATION> Manhattan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Theater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>. His Broadway credits included `` <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Pan </PERSON>,'' `` Tintypes,'' `` The First'' and `` Foxfire.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Lloyd Bentsen Sr.</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>EDINBURG, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sr. </PERSON>, an early developer of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>' Lower <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> whose son, Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, was the Democratic vice-presidential candidate last year, was killed Tuesday in a traffic accident. He was 95. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> held nearly 50,000 acres of farms and six ranches scattered over a <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> empire he started in 1920. By the 1970s his holdings ranged from farm, cattle, oil, gas and nursery operations to control of six banks, stock in other banks and land sales entimated at $ 1 million a month. Although he had sold his bank holdings, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> continued farming, running 5,000 head of cattle, operating a nursery, taking in oil and gas revenues and managing a real estate business.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Gordon Allott</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ENGLEWOOD, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Allott </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> senator, died Tuesday of cancer at the age of 82. <PERSON> Allott </PERSON> graduated from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> in 1927 and from its law school in 1929. During World War II, he was a major in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Allott </PERSON> served terms as <PERSON> Lamar </PERSON> city attorney, district attorney and <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>'s lieutenant governor from 1951-1955. He was also vice chairman of the state <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parole </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Allott </PERSON>, a Republican, served three terms in the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> from 1955 to 1973. He also worked on the Appropriations and Interior committees. <PERSON> Allott </PERSON> was the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> sponsor for the <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Basin </LOCATION> Storage Act of 1968, which provided for construction of five <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> water projects and the Central Arizona Project.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Gerald Probst</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SALT LAKE CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Probst </PERSON>, 65, a decorated World War II pilot who later rose through the corporate ranks to become chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Sperry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, died Sunday. The cause of death had not been determined as of Tuesday. <PERSON> Probst </PERSON> joined the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> in 1942 and commanded a B-24 bomber in World War II missions over <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. He was awarded the distinguished flying cross and the air medal with three oak leaf clusters. <PERSON> Probst </PERSON> joined <ORGANIZATION> Sperry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Univac </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paul </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, in 1961. He was named to positions of increasing responsibility over the next decade, being promoted to a divisional presidency in 1971. <PERSON> Probst </PERSON> became corporate vice president in 1974, executive vice president in 1975, and company president in 1980. He was elected chairman of the board of <LOCATION> Sperry </LOCATION> in 1982. <PERSON> Probst </PERSON> was named chairman and chief executive officer of <LOCATION> Sperry </LOCATION> in September 1986 when the $ 5 billion computer and defense systems company merged with <ORGANIZATION> Burroughs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> to form <PERSON> Uinsys </PERSON>. He retired a few months later but continued to serve as a member of <ORGANIZATION> Uinsys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>'s advisory board.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>George Tweed</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GRANTS PASS, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Tweed </PERSON>, a World War II <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> radioman who eluded Japanese forces on the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> island of <LOCATION> Guam </LOCATION> for more than two years and became the subject of a movie, died Monday in a car accident in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> at age 86. When Japanese forces overran <LOCATION> Guam </LOCATION> in 1941, Tweed and several others slipped into the jungle rather than surrender. He became the lone survivor after the others were captured and killed. Tweed managed to elude Japanese soldiers for two years and seven months, providing information to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> forces that recaptured the island in 1944. He was awarded the Legion of Merit. His story was told in the book `` <ORGANIZATION> Robinson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crusoe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USN </ORGANIZATION>,'' and the 1962 movie `` No Man is an Island,'' starring <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> as Tweed.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Fred Cooper</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ORLANDO, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, an editor with the <ORGANIZATION> Sanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION>, died Tuesday of lung cancer. He was 58. <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> was editorial page editor of the newspaper He worked for the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times-Picayune </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Evening Star early in his career. <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> spent 15 years as sports information director at <ORGANIZATION> Stetson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> DeLand </ORGANIZATION> and earlier was a psychological warfare writer with the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. Most recently, <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> played a key role in development of the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> Sports Hall of Fame and helped cover sports events for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Jorge Cruickshank Garcia</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Congressman <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruickshank </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, co-founder and leader for two decades of the <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, died Tuesday of a brain tumor Tuesday at age 73. With the late <PERSON> Vicente </PERSON> <PERSON> Lombardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Toledano </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cruickshank </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> helped found the party in 1948 and had been its secretary-general since 1968. <PERSON> Cruickshank </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> was serving his fourth term in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, representing <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s Federal District, similar to the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He was a senator from 1976-1982.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Paul Sheatsley</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheatsley </PERSON>, an expert in the field of survey research, died Sunday after a long bout with empheysema. He was 72. <PERSON> Sheatsley </PERSON> began his career in survey research as an interviewer for the Gallup organization. He joined the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opinion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> in 1942 and directed the center's <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> office until 1961, when he became head of the research center's main office in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. He was president of the research center from 1967-68. He supervised a number of innovative studies, including one on the public reaction to the assassination of President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> in 1963. He was known for his work in survey design and methods and in health care and race relations research.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ChristmasTreeNest     01-18 0158</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Christmas Tree Nest,0160</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bird Confused By Mild Winter Raises Family In Christmas Tree</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A blackbird confused by <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s unseasonably mild winter is raising a family in a Christmas tree outside a department store _ two months out of season. `` From the size of the chicks it looks as though the mother must have laid its eggs on Christmas Day,'' said <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hands </PERSON>, assistant general manager of the store in <LOCATION> Cheltenham </LOCATION>, western <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. `` The tree will stay until the young are able to fly.'' <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Evening </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standard </ORGANIZATION> newspaper ran photographs on Tuesday of the nest and its three chicks, the parent and the tree on a balcony under the headline, `` Early bird catches the warm.'' Meteorologists say high pressure over southern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> is forming a barrier to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s chills. Wildlife watchers report hedgehogs refusing to hibernate, frogs starting to spawn in waters that usually would be frozen, and migrant birds like warblers staying on.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 0710EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--LoudParties     01-18 0160</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Loud Parties,0164</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rowdy Parties Could Mean Hefty Fines under Proposed Ordinance</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SOUTH LAKE TAHOE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 People who throw parties that get out of hand could find themselves in trouble with more than the neighbors. A bill that got its first reading Tuesday by <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tahoe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> would let the city bill people for the police time involved if somebody calls the police to the same address twice. The measure would let the party-thrower be charged up to $ 500. Council member <PERSON> Neva </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> voiced the only opposition to the measure, saying the city already has laws to deal with disturbing the peace and adding that she thinks there are people who will complain even when a party is n't loud enough to warrant it. Besides, she asked, `` What fun is a party with no noise, anyway?'' The ordinance is scheduled for a second reading Feb. 7. If approved then, it will become law 30 days later.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-FornicationCase     01-18 0362</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fornication Case,0373</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Orders New Trial in Church Fornication Lawsuit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RON JENKINS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OKLAHOMA CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Oklahoma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday reversed a $ 390,000 judgment won by a woman who was publicly branded by her church for having sex outside of marriage. But the court left open the possibility that the woman could recover damages for actions taken by church elders after she sought to withdraw from membership in the church. The <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> court ruled <PERSON> Marian </PERSON> <PERSON> Guinn </PERSON> could not recover for any civil wrongs committed against her by church elders while she was still a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Collinsville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christ </ORGANIZATION>. Justice <PERSON> Marian </PERSON> <PERSON> Opala </PERSON> wrote the majority opinion sending the case back for a new trial. Four other justices concurred, two dissented and two others dissented in part. <PERSON> Opala </PERSON>'s opinion held that the First Amendment did not protect church elders from potential liability for acts that occurred after the woman withdrew her church membership. The decision said it could be found that the elders went `` beyond the bounds of decency'' by going against the woman's wishes and announcing to the congregation the woman's `` sin of fornication'' when she declined to publicly repent. `` We hence hold there is competent evidence to support the jury's conclusion that the elders had intended to inflict emotional harm on parishioner,'' the opinion said Elders of the <LOCATION> Collinsville </LOCATION> church, located north of <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> northeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, filed the appeal after a <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> jury in March 1984 awarded Ms. <PERSON> Guinn </PERSON> $ 205,000 actual damages and $ 185,000 punitive damages. The registered nurse and divorced mother of four sued in 1981, when elders of the church disclosed she had committed the `` sin of fornication.'' The church argued elders had a right, outlined in the Bible, to discipline members. The elders were identified in the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling as <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitten </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Moody </PERSON> and <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> Cash. The court said the woman had implored the elders in a letter not to mention her name in church, except to say she had withdrawn from membership. The elders told the woman that withdrawing from the church was not possible and could not halt disciplinary action against her.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     01-18 0959</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0994</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Malden </PERSON> says he hurt his Yugoslav immigrant parents when he changed his name from <PERSON> Mladen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sekulovich </PERSON>, and his efforts to put the family name into his work have n't always helped, either. `` I think I hurt my folks when I dropped ` Sekulovich,''' he said. `` They were proud people. And if you've noticed in my films and TV series in the past eight years, you'll know that somehow I've worked in the name ` Sekulovich.''' <PERSON> Malden </PERSON> has appeared in films such as `` On the Waterfront'' and `` <PERSON> Patton </PERSON>,'' and in the TV series `` Streets of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>.'' `` I could n't figure how to get it in in one show where there was a row of cells with each prisoner's name above the door. I had them put ` Sekulovich' on one. My father called me up and said indignantly, ` Son, no <PERSON> Sekulovich </PERSON> was ever in prison!''' <PERSON> Malden </PERSON>, who is teaching acting classes at <ORGANIZATION> Vanderbilt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> for two weeks, took the name <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> from his maternal grandfather and came up with <PERSON> Malden </PERSON> by rearranging `` <PERSON> Mladen </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Country music singer <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Travis </PERSON> avoided serious injury when he ran his car into a ditch in trying to avoid another car, police and his publicist say. <PERSON> Travis </PERSON>, 29, was shaken up in Tuesday's accident in rural <LOCATION> Cheatham </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, west of <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, but he was n't seriously hurt, publicist <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Shriver </PERSON> said. His manager, <PERSON> Lib </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatcher </PERSON>, was with <PERSON> Travis </PERSON> and also was shaken up, <PERSON> Shriver </PERSON> said. The pair were traveling to a high school to promote a new booklet on teen-age problems called the Youth Yellow Pages. <PERSON> Shriver </PERSON> said <PERSON> Travis </PERSON> likely would continue with appearances today on the <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION> show `` Late Night With <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Letterman </PERSON>'' and Thursday night at the nationally televised Presidential Inaugural Gala on CBS.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TORONTO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Songwriter <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Lanni </PERSON> had few expectations when his band Sheriff broke up in 1985, so he was surprised when their song `` When I'm With You'' suddenly reached the Top 10. `` It's an exaggerated case of going into your closet, going through an old suit and finding some money in it,'' <PERSON> Lanni </PERSON> said. `` All of a sudden my past is paying dividends.'' The song was a modest success in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> while Sheriff was performing but failed in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> before its recent revival. <PERSON> Lanni </PERSON> and another Sheriff member, <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hassel </PERSON>, formed the duo Frozen Ghost after the breakup. Two other Sheriff members, lead singer <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Curci </PERSON> and guitarist <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> DeMarchi </PERSON>, have been working as couriers in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>. `` It sure beats what we've been doing for the past few years,'' <PERSON> Curci </PERSON> said of having a hit record. He said he, <PERSON> DeMarchi </PERSON> and drummer <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> hope to get back the band's name and tour.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Statler Brothers, the country music quartet, resume performing in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> this weekend after a six-week break but have decided not to compete against the Super Bowl. `` We've learned there are certain dates when you should n't schedule anything,'' Statler member <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Reid </PERSON> said Tuesday from his office in Staunton, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> `` They are Christmas, Thanksgiving, Halloween night and Super Bowl Sunday. The group, whose hits include `` Flowers on the Wall'' and `` Maple Street Memories,'' has scheduled concerts in <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, but will rest on Sunday when <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> plays <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> in the Super Bowl in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ST. PAUL, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Astronaut <PERSON> George </PERSON> `` Pinky'' <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> told students in his native <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> he would gladly trade places with them for the chance to `` experience what's going to happen in your lifetime.'' <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, who was aboard last fall's Discovery mission that returned Americans to space for the first time after the Challenger disaster, joined <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> flight director <PERSON> Michele </PERSON> <PERSON> Brekke </PERSON> in speaking to students as part of NASA-Minnesota Business Day at the Capitol. `` If you would like to trade places with me _ I've done a lot of fun things in my life so far and I plan on doing a lot more _ I will be glad to trade places with you, no questions asked, just for the chance to be able to experience what's going to happen in your lifetime,'' <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said. In response to questions, <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said it `` is a great feeling'' to walk in space and that the earth `` looks mostly blue -LRB- from the water -RRB-, white -LRB- from the clouds -RRB- and the ground looks mostly brown'' when viewed from space. <PERSON> Brekke </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> graduate, said she had dreamed of becoming an astronaut but was not accepted into the program. She said she found a ground career with <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> to be `` just as much fun.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version moved on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>OAKLAND, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, who is advising major league baseball on how to recruit more blacks for high-level jobs, is suing the <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> <PERSON> Post-Dispatch </PERSON> for allegedly putting his byline on a story he did n't write. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California-Berkeley </ORGANIZATION> sociology professor, is seeking $ 1.2 million in damages in the suit filed last Thursday in <ORGANIZATION> Alameda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Post-Dispatch </ORGANIZATION> Managing Editor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Lipman </PERSON> said Tuesday he had not seen the lawsuit and could not comment on it. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> claims the Jan. 4 article was written by a <ORGANIZATION> Post-Dispatch </ORGANIZATION> sports writer who interviewed him in July 1987. He contends the story misquoted him and misrepresented his feelings about conditions facing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> blacks. The suit said the article contained statements such as, `` Ninety-nine percent of murders are black people killing black people,'' and `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> can not carry 30 million dispossessed, deprived and disenchanted black people on its back.'' The newspaper ran an editor's note after the article appeared saying the use of <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>' byline was misleading but standing behind the accuracy of the contents.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SchoolShooting-Gunman 1stLd-Writethru a0atedPress 01-18
0480</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-School Shooting-Gunman, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0418,0490</SECOND>
<HEAD>School Gunman Described as Loner And Childhood Alcoholic</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: CORRECTS gunman's age in lead and name to Purdy in 11th graf
bgng ``However.''</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-School Shooting</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB BAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANDY, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 26-year-old drifter with a long criminal record who launched a mute, murderous assault on a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> elementary school Tuesday was described by his aunt as a loner and childhood alcoholic, police said. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> purchased an AK-47 rifle in this <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION> suburb several months ago, then returned to his hometown of <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, where he used the gun to kill five children and wound 29 others, along with a teacher, at <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> before taking his own life, authorities said. <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON>, who went by the alias of <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> West </PERSON>, had lived with an aunt and uncle in <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON> from the first of July until late October, said <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON> Police Chief <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Punzel </PERSON>. He later moved to <LOCATION> Lodi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, where he listed his mailing address under the name of his grandmother, <PERSON> Julia </PERSON> <PERSON> Chumbley </PERSON>, although he did not live with her, authorities said. `` I'm shocked. It's just horrible. I do n't understand why and I probably wo n't ever know why,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Chumbley </PERSON>, a 63-year-old retired cannery worker. `` It troubles me to think that such a terrible thing can happen. It's like a nightmare. This sort of thing happens to others, not you. Your own grandson.'' <PERSON> Stockton </PERSON> is about 15 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Lodi </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Punzel </PERSON> said <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON>'s aunt, <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>, `` told me he was a loner and as a child he was an alcoholic.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> said through a closed front door at her residence that she was too upset to talk to reporters. Her next-door neighbor, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, 45, said she met West when he lived with his relatives last summer. `` He seemed like a real nice young man,'' she said. `` He was here looking for work.'' However, <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> had an `` extensive criminal history,'' mostly in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area, said <PERSON> Lucian </PERSON> <PERSON> Neely </PERSON>, deputy police chief in <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>, an agricultural city 60 miles east of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> had no criminal record in <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Clackamas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, authorities said. <PERSON> Neely </PERSON> said <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> originally was from <PERSON> Stockton </PERSON> and that he had purchased the gun at the Sandy Trading Post Aug. 3. <PERSON> Punzel </PERSON> said Mrs. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> told him <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> left <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> for a job as a boilermaker in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. That job fell through and he went to <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Tenn </PERSON>. The aunt and uncle last heard from <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> at Thanksgiving, when he was in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Punzel </PERSON> said. His mother lives in <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and his father was killed in 1980 or 1981 when he was struck by a car as a pedestrian, <PERSON> Punzel </PERSON> said. State Division of Motor Vehicles records identify <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> as 5-foot-11, 150 pounds, with blue eyes and blond hair, said spokesman <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-OvertownDisturbance 7thLd-Writethru a0404 01-18 1300</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Overtown Disturbance, 7th Ld - Writethru, a0404,1334</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Trouble After Night of Rioting Sparked by Police Shooting</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Subs 1st graf to UPDATE with eight shot. Subs 6th graf, `Authorities
said' to UPDATE arrest figure. Subs 14th graf, `Sporadic gunfire' with
two grafs to UPDATE with details of shootings.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos MH6, MH10, MH13, DO1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD COLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Looting and vandalism spread Tuesday and eight people were shot, one fatally, in the second day of rioting sparked by the fatal shooting of an unarmed black motorcyclist by a white policeman. Schools were closed, a professional basketball game was canceled, and some fans were stranded in the arena. Snipers fired at police, who cordoned off a 130-block area of the predominantly black <LOCATION> Overtown </LOCATION> neighborhood. After nightfall, authorities told law-abiding citizens to remain indoors and began a block-by-blok sweep. `` For the sake of our city, I appeal to every citizen regardless of race to stay calm, get off the streets and stay in your homes, said <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Xavier </PERSON> <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> in a televised appeal Tuesday night. `` We are arresting people and we are being a lot more aggressive in the enforcement of the law and I think we have to be,'' <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> added. `` I do n't think this will continue after today.'' Authorities said <LOCATION> Overtown </LOCATION>, just north of downtown, was largely quiet after police entered. By 11:30 p.m., about 150 people had been arrested, mostly for looting. But the violence already had spread to <LOCATION> Liberty </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, a separate black community several miles to the northwest, where looting and gunfire continued Tuesday night. Police said they made an arrest in the fatal shooting of a young black man in <LOCATION> Liberty </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> at 10:20 p.m., but had n't determined if it was related to the rioting. Officer <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON>, wearing a bulletproof vest, was shot in the vest at 9:30 p.m. by a sniper who was later arrested on top of a three-story building. <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> was not seriously injured. Plans were made for up to 500 National Guard troops to be mobilized within two hours if the violence continued, said <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON>, a spokesman for Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>. Top police officials said the tough stance would not bring a violent reaction because only a few people were violating the law. Trouble erupted again Tuesday afternoon when a white man in a luxury car reportedly fired into a crowd of blacks in the area, wounding one person before driving away. `` All I know is that one person was hit in the side,'' police spokesman <PERSON> Angelo </PERSON> <PERSON> Bitsis </PERSON> said, adding that the unidentified victim was hospitalized in fair condition. Sporadic gunfire continued throughout the day. Police said officers rescued one shooting victim while under fire, returned fire at another man, injuring him in the leg, and shot an alleged sniper in the leg. Another man was shot in the thigh in a gun battle between two men in a store and a gang of looters. Later, a man with a bullet wound in his leg was arrested when he showed up at a hospital for treatment. An eighth person was shot in the leg in <LOCATION> Liberty </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. About 25 youths shattered car windows outside the <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arena </LOCATION> on the border of <LOCATION> Overtown </LOCATION>, where the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Basketball </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heat </ORGANIZATION> was scheduled to play the <ORGANIZATION> Phoenix </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Suns </ORGANIZATION> Tuesday night The game was canceled. A meat truck was looted and one white motorist was beaten after his car broke down in <LOCATION> Overtown </LOCATION>. The car of <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> photographer <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Pesetsky </PERSON> was burned and he was roughed up by a mob but not seriously hurt when he attempted to take pictures of the crowd that had gathered near the site of Tuesday's shooting. Police fired tear gas at the crowd and in turn were pelted by rocks and bottles. They then sealed off a several block area and shots could be heard from within. `` I saw someone coming around a building and throwing rocks, and I said ` Let's go, get out of here,''' <PERSON> Pesetsky </PERSON> said. At least one car also was burned in <LOCATION> Liberty </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> announced that it would open an investigation into Monday night's shooting to determine whether there were civil rights violations, <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> bureau spokesman <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiszynski </PERSON> said. `` I ca n't tell you how long it will take, but it will be an extensive and thorough investigation and it will be done as promptly as possible,'' <PERSON> Kiszynski </PERSON> said. Meanwhile, a passenger on the motorcycle who was injured when the driver crashed into a car after the shooting died Tuesday at <ORGANIZATION> Jackson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> of massive head injuries, spokeswoman <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Baderman </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON>, one of the targets of rock and bottle throwing Monday night, spent Tuesday meeting with black leaders and residents of <LOCATION> Overtown </LOCATION>, a neighborhood of rundown, low-slung apartment buildings and trash-strewn vacant lots, just north of downtown <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. `` People are angry, people want a full explanation of what happened,'' said <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON>, who also expressed particular concern about the damage to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>'s image less than a week before the city is host to the Super Bowl. At least two buildings and three cars were burned in the rioting, which broke out about two hours after a white police officer shot and killed a black motorcyclist being chased for a traffic infraction. No damage estimates were available. Authorities said seven civilians and three of the 280 police officers called to the scene were injured. Police guarded a 130-block area of <LOCATION> Overtown </LOCATION> on Tuesday, warning motorists who passed through that they could not be guaranteed protection. Six schools were closed and some buses were rerouted, but authorities refused to declare an evening curfew. The disturbance recalled the bloody 1980 riot in adjacent <LOCATION> Liberty </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> that also was linked to the death of a black motorcyclist at the hands of white officers. A similar disturbance broke out in 1982 when a black man was shot to death only a few blocks from where the latest incident began. On Monday, <PERSON> Clement </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON>, 23, died following a police chase that started just after 6 p.m. <PERSON> Bitsis </PERSON> said <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> and a passenger on his motorcycle sped past a police officer, who gave chase. Then the motorcycle headed down a street where another officer, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>, was taking a report from a crime victim. `` He heard the radio transmission and saw the motorcycle coming in his direction,'' <PERSON> Bitsis </PERSON> said. `` As the motorcycle either approached him or went by him, he fired his shot.'' The bullet hit <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> in the head, killing him, and the motorcycle then crashed into a car. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON>, 24, a passenger on the motorcycle, died Tuesday. By 8 p.m. an angry crowd had surrounded the police and news media vehicles gathered at the spot, and the violence began, with rocks and bottles thrown at police, reporters and their cars. Crowds of up to 100 people roamed the streets, smashing windshields, burning vehicles, looting some stores and occasionally firing weapons at police. <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>, 29, a four-year veteran of the force, was automatically suspended with pay pending an investigation into whether he used excessive force. Many in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>'s black community said they were tired of police violence, saying nothing has changed despite promises by <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> and other officials who courted black votes. <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> strongly denied that the attention paid to newly arriving Nicaraguan refugees had created ill-will in the black community, but black leaders did not agree. `` In this tremendous influx of refugees from Central and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, the African-Americans have felt cheated. We felt we were losing our place in the city,'' said <PERSON> Johnnie </PERSON> <PERSON> McMillian </PERSON>, president of the <LOCATION> Miami-Dade </LOCATION> branch of the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION>. The scene of Monday's disturbance was about 15 miles from <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Robbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Stadium </PERSON>, site of the Super Bowl. But the <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bengals </ORGANIZATION> are staying less than a mile away, at the Omni Hotel.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SchoolShooting-Weapons 1stLd-Writethru a0801 01-18 0474</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-School Shooting-Weapons, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0801,0478</SECOND>
<HEAD>Easy To Purchase AK-47 in Oregon, California</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: CORRECTS gunman's name to Purdy in 2nd graf and fixes style
on semiautomatic, without hyphen; adds one graf on cost of the gun in Los
Angeles area.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SALEM, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A semiautomatic rifle such as the AK-47 that was used in the <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, school shootings Tuesday can be easily purchased at <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> gun stores _ without even the waiting period required to buy a handgun. The gunman, identified by police as <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON>, had bought the rifle from the <ORGANIZATION> Sandy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trading </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> on Aug. 3, according to <ORGANIZATION> Sandy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Punzel </PERSON>. Authorities say <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> opened fire in an elementary school yard, killing five youngsters and wounding 30 people before killing himself. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Imel </PERSON>, owner of PAWS gun shop in <LOCATION> Salem </LOCATION>, said there is no waiting period under <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> law to buy rifles or shotguns, unless they are fully automatic. There is a five-day wait to buy a handgun, while police agencies check for criminal records. A buyer is required to sign a form issued by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alcohol </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tobacco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Firearms </ORGANIZATION>. The form requires the buyer to provide identification and attest that he is not under indictment, has not been convicted of a crime punishable by more than a year in prison and is not a fugitive from justice. A buyer also must attest that he is not an unlawful user of narcotics, has not been found mentally defective or been committed to a mental instutition, has not been discharged dishonorably from the armed forces, is not an illegal alien and has not renounced <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizenship. People must be at least 18 to purchase rifles and shotguns and 21 to buy handguns. There are some other requirements, including that a prospective buyer not have been adjudged mentally ill or be an ex-convict, <PERSON> Imel </PERSON> said. Purchases of automatic weapons are more complicated, he said, because federal law requires extensive background checks and registration of the weapons. The procedure usually takes several months before a buyer can receive the gun, <PERSON> Imel </PERSON> said. In <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, anyone can purchase a semiautomatic weapon by completing a form and showing a driver's license or other proof of residency in the state. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Deputy Attorney General <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ashby </PERSON> said that even in legal semiautomatic condition, an AK-47 can fire at a rate of 400 rounds per minute, and that conversion to automatic firing, while illegal, is relatively easy on many semiautomatic models. Sales of the Soviet-designed AK-47s have become intensely controversial in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> because of their use by the increasingly violent street gangs in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and other communities. In the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area, models of the AK-47 that have been manufactured in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> sell from $ 299 to $ 329 at sporting goods stores, and are often advertised on sale.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 0152EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     01-18 0470</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0490</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Rain Man' and `Twins' Remain At Top</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD DE ATLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Brotherly sagas `` Rain Man'' and `` Twins'' maintained the top two positions in box office receipts for the fifth consecutive weekend. `` Rain Man,'' starring <PERSON> Dustin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> as an autistic savant kidnapped by his brother, portrayed by <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruise </PERSON>, was No. 1 last weekend with $ 10.1 million in ticket sales. `` Twins,'' with <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> DeVito </PERSON> and <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwarzenegger </PERSON> as reunited twins who had been separated at birth, brought in $ 6.7 million. It was the third straight weekend that the films finished in that order. The previous two weekends, `` Twins'' finished ahead of `` Rain Man.'' `` Beaches,'' starring <PERSON> Better </PERSON> <PERSON> Midler </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Hershey </PERSON> as two women with an inseparable friendship, earned $ 5.1 million for third place last weekend as <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> widened its distribution. In fourth place was `` Accidental Tourist,'' earning $ 4.8 million, followed by `` Working Girl'' with $ 4.5 million. `` The Naked Gun: From the <ORGANIZATION> Files </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Squad </ORGANIZATION>'' earned $ 4.4 million in its seventh week of release. `` Mississippi Burning,'' a fictionalized account of two <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents investigating the real slaying of three civil rights workers in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> during the 1960s, also went to wider distribution last weekend and took seventh place with just over $ 4 million. `` Deep Star Six,'' about a giant crab that devours undersea explorers, made a weak debut in eighth with $ 3.3 million. `` Dirty Rotten Scoundrels'' was next with just over $ 3 million and `` <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> and Co.'' with $ 1.9 million. No major releases were announced for this week, with theater owners anticipating the usual poor box office during Super Bowl weekend, said <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Krier </PERSON>. Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by Exhibitor Relations, with distributor, weekend gross, number of theater screens, average per screen, total gross and number of weeks in release. 1. `` Rain Man,'' <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 10.1 million, 1,482 screens, $ 6,823 per screen, $ 69 million, five weeks. 2. `` Twins,'' Universal, $ 6.7 million, 1,630 screens, $ 4,140 per screen, $ 73.4 million, six weeks. 3. `` Beaches,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 5.1 million, 706 screens, $ 7,309 per screen, $ 6.2 million, four weeks. 4. `` Accidental Tourist,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 4.8 million, 954 screens, $ 5,107 per screen, $ 13.4 million, four weeks. 5. `` Working Girl,'' 20th <ORGANIZATION> Century </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION>, $ 4.5 million, 1,140 screens, $ 3,960 per screen, $ 29.6 million, four weeks. 6. `` Naked Gun: From the Files of Police Squad,'' Paramount, $ 4.4 million, 1,765 screens, $ 2,494 per screen, $ 60.1 million, seven weeks. 7. `` Mississippi Burning,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION>, $ 4 million, 551 screens, $ 7,417 per screen, $ 5.7 million, six weeks. 8. `` Deep Star Six,'' TriStar, $ 3.3 million, 1,117 screens, $ 2,960 per screen, $ 3.3 million, one week. 9. `` Dirty Rotten Scoundrels,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION>, $ 3 million, 1,490 screens, $ 2,021 per screen, $ 31.1 million, five weeks. 10. `` <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.9 million, 1,410 screens, $ 1,360 per screen, $ 45.9 million, nine weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 0155EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FriendlyTakeover Bjt   01-18 0749</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Friendly Takeover, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Time for Goodbyes for Reagan Veterans</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Through her window, she can see the tourists on <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> Avenue gawking through the wrought-iron fence at the White House. She can scan the stream of visitors arriving to see the president. She sits at the center of a universe of prime ministers, senators and heroic warriors who will headline the evening news. For only one more day, <PERSON> Leslye </PERSON> <PERSON> Arsht </PERSON> will sit in the little cubicle in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wing </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, dealing with the affairs of _ and sometimes speaking for _ the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Then, at the stroke of 12 on Friday, she turns in her pass and is out. `` There's life after the White House,'' says Ms. <PERSON> Arsht </PERSON>, her voice the least bit uncertain. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, a company town if there ever was one, 4,307 <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration jobs are up for grabs. Some who hold those jobs will stay where they are, but many more, like <PERSON> Leslye </PERSON> <PERSON> Arsht </PERSON>, find themselves on the job market. It is the friendliest of takeovers, this quadrennial rite, compared to the agony that occurs when a Democrat turns the White House over to a Republican, or vice versa. Not for 156 years has a president handed the reins to the man who served him as vice president. Yet, while the Bushites are n't exactly storming the gates, it's a traumatic time for many. As <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> flies off into the sunset, he leaves behind many loyal workers who wonder why they are suddenly out, while others stay on. The answer, of course, is that people work hard in a campaign, and the jobs that serve as rewards are in great demand. `` We had our turn; now it's their turn,'' says Ms. <PERSON> Arsht </PERSON>, who came from the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> two years ago with <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> when he became <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s spokesman. She has been deputy press secretary, a job that will go to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>. `` I'm a Texan, a lifetime supporter of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>,'' she says. `` It's a bittersweet time.'' Outside her door in the White House press office is a huge box being filled with files for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Archives </ORGANIZATION>. The work of the press office goes on, but it's obvious that things are being readied for the big change. On Friday, the rooms will be mostly empty, the cupboards bare, the walls nude. It wo n't be as stark as, say, when <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> left town eight years ago, because <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> will stay on to serve <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as chief spokesman. In one part of the office, a cardboard box is marked `` Do not throw away. This is not trash.'' In the hallway, a photo gallery that has been dominated by pictures of <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has undergone a subtle turn: The pictures of the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> have been augmented by photos of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. One of those who is leaving is <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerrard </PERSON>, the closest thing the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> has to an institutional memory. Ms. <PERSON> Gerrard </PERSON> came into the White House 25 years ago with <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, as a fresh-from-college secretary after the assassination of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. She has stayed, serving as the press secretary's secretary, through <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, and she is ready to live a life without the endless workdays and the constant crises. `` I now want to be able to control my own schedule,'' she says. She knows what the incoming <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> staffers will soon learn, that `` in the press office, you have to hit the ground running. There is nothing to prepare you for what you find when you get here.'' Indeed, reporters were pressing <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> on Tuesday about where they will get information after noon on Friday. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> and <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> will be the only veteran hands remaining in the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration. The rest of the press office staff will come from the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> team. Many of them will see the inside of the office for the first time when they come to work on inauguration day. `` It's a matter of sensitivity,'' <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> says. `` Nobody wants to have the new person watching over their shoulder.'' Many of the people leaving spent the weekend packing their own belongings. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, too, was seen by <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> last week putting some things into a box. `` The president and first lady have been packing for some time,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. `` They have shipped most of their private goods to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> already.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890118-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-18-89 0202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     01-18 0865</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,870</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets, Chinese Make US Wheat Purchase</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
