<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 2346EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Angola-SouthAfrica 1stLd-Writethru a0810 02-12 0423</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Angola-South Africa, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0810,0433</SECOND>
<HEAD>Angola Claims South African Troops Violated Peace Accord</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 2 grafs to note that report monitored in Lisbon;
picks up 3rd graf `The Pretoria...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LISBON, Portugal (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> said its troops killed 40 South African soldiers who crossed the border, violating a regional peace agreement, the Angolan news agency <ORGANIZATION> ANGOP </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. The Marxist government protested to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> about the incident that also left seven Angolan soldiers dead, said the report monitored in <LOCATION> Lisbon </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION> government rejected the charge and requested an immediate meeting of a commission monitoring the peace accord to discuss the matter. The Angolan <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> statement issued Saturday said South African troops on Wednesday crossed into <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> from neighboring <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> in support of Angolan rebels, <ORGANIZATION> ANGOP </ORGANIZATION> reported. The Angolan government troops drove the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africans </LOCATION> back to the Namibian frontier after heavy fighting that ended early Friday, <ORGANIZATION> ANGOP </ORGANIZATION> reported. It said 40 South African soldiers were In <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION>, the South African <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said it replied `` in the strongest terms'' to the allegations contained in a protest note sent by <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>'s government. In the statement Sunday, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> said it was on standby to attend an urgent meeting of the monitoring commission in <LOCATION> Luanda </LOCATION>, the Angolan capital, to discuss <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>'s allegations. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said last week it had no evidence that any South African troops entered <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. South African military authorities say their forces are strictly observing the U.S.-brokered peace agreement signed in December. The agreement bars South African military aid to the anti-Marxist rebels in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and calls for independence of <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> from South African control. The peace accord established a joint commission, comprised of South African, <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> and Angolan representatives, to monitor observance of the various provisions. As part of the peace agreement, about 50,000 Cuban troops were to withdraw from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, where they have been helping the government fight the rebels belonging to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> for the Total Independence of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. The rebel group rejects the peace accords and has vowed to continue fighting until the Angolan government agrees to share power. The area where the fighting reportedly took place is near a stretch of the border between <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> which does not have monitoring posts called for in the peace agreement. The rebels said Saturday that 275 government soldiers died in heavy fighting last week when 4,000 guerrillas clashed with the Angolan army in southern <LOCATION> Cuando </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cubango </LOCATION> province. The rebels denied South African troops participated in the fighting.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 2346EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a AM-BRF--BundyMeeting     02-12 0169</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Bundy Meeting,0172</SECOND>
<HEAD>Investigators To Discuss Bundy Killings</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Retransmiting to restore overline.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police officers from states where <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> killed or may have killed will meet next week at the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s Behavioral Science Laboratory in <LOCATION> Quantico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> died in the electric chair in <LOCATION> Starke </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, on Jan. 24 for the 1978 murder of 12-year-old <PERSON> Kimberly </PERSON> <PERSON> Leach </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. One of the key figures expected at the week-long gathering is <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Hagmeier </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent who interviewed <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> extensively and sat in on many of the interviews <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> gave in the week before he The number of known Bundy victims is between 23 and 30, based on the confessions he gave in the days before his death. Some law enforcment officials believed he committed many more murders than those he confessed to. States in which <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> confessed to killings include <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, but other states with unsolved killings have also expressed interest in the former law school student.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 2347EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Poland     02-12 0383</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Poland,0395</SECOND>
<HEAD>Walesa Adviser Warns Followers Against Wildcat Strikes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An adviser to Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> warned Sunday that the banned union would be blamed for wildcat strikes and called on supporters to show discipline and reject such actions. At a church frequented by <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, the Rev. <PERSON> Henryk </PERSON> <PERSON> Jankowski </PERSON>, an adviser to the Solidarity chief, suggested the strikes were provocations at a time when the union is trying to win status during its crucial talks with the government. The talks began Feb. 6. A strike at a steel mill in southern <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> has not received support from Solidarity or the government-sanctioned OPZZ trade union alliance. `` No one will claim responsibility for the currently organized strikes, not the OPZZ, not the left and not the right,'' <PERSON> Jankowski </PERSON> said. `` So again, Solidarity will be blamed. `` I understand that at this moment the life of the Polish family is very difficult. Today all the more so we are obliged to show a certain discipline,'' he said. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> did not attend the Mass at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brygida </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> where <PERSON> Jankowski </PERSON> spoke and he did not authorize the statement, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> and church officials said later. After the Mass, attended by 4,000 people, about 500 people staged a protest march to the train station. Demonstrators chanted `` Solidarity'' and `` Down with Communism'' and some threw stones at riot police shepherding the march toward the station. Police blocked the marchers and at one point charged them but did not use their riot truncheons. A strike at the <LOCATION> Laziska </LOCATION> steel mill in southern <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> that began Friday over wages also continued, the state-run news agency <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> said. A Solidarity spokeswoman said workers at the mill said their action was spontaneous and not led by any union. The state <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> news service Sunday reported the end of a three-day strike led by the <ORGANIZATION> OPZZ </ORGANIZATION> at two departments of the Marceli Nowotko steel plant in <LOCATION> Ostrowiec </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Swietkrzyzskia </LOCATION> in central <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. Workers who had opposed the distribution of the plant's pay agreed to continue with the present pay system until May 15, when wages will be reevaluated, <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> said. A strike over pay by transport workers in <LOCATION> Piotrkow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Trybunalski </LOCATION>, a central Polish provincial city of 80,000 people, continued. The strike began Friday and is backed by the official trade union OPZZ.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 0019EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Bolte     02-12 0141</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Bolte,140</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Army Vice Chief of Staff Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALEXANDRIA, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolte </PERSON>, a four-star general who was the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s vice chief of staff during the mid-1950s, died Saturday. He was 93. <PERSON> Bolte </PERSON>, who retired from active duty in 1955, was a company commander in World War I. As a major general in World War II, he commanded the 34th Infantry Division in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. After the war he served as Army Ground Forces chief of staff and chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Inter-American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. He was the Army commander in chief in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in 1952 and 1953. He served as <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> vice chief of staff, the number-two position in the service, from October 1953 until his retirement in April 1955. His decorations included two Distinguished Service Medals, the Silver Star, the Legion of Merit and the Purple Heart.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 0028EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Italy-PLO     02-12 0161</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Italy-PLO,0166</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thousands in Rome Express Support for Palestinian State</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 30,000 Italian and <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> demonstrators waving banners and chanting slogans marched Saturday to support creation of a Palestinian state, Italian news agencies said. The agencies said the march, organized by the <ORGANIZATION> Italian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION>, was led by students waving the <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> flag and holding portraits of <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>. The demonstrators gathered outside the basilica of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> the Lateran to hear a speech by <PERSON> Nemer </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammad </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> representative in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. `` We want <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION> to return to being the land of peace,'' <PERSON> Hammad </PERSON> told the demonstrators. The 14-month-old Palestinian uprising in the Israeli-occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> has left at least 380 Palestinians and 15 Israelis dead. Near the end of the peaceful demonstration a group of about a hundred protestors burned an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> flag and called for armed struggle in the occupied territories.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 0024EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Marine-Spy     02-12 0341</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Marine-Spy,0351</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Feds Still Convinced Ex-Marine Was Spy; Man Says No</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Marine says he was coerced into signing a confession admitting he was a spy, but the government maintains that <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Bracy </PERSON> is a liar who gave away secrets for sex while in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> reports. In an interview to be aired Sunday on the network's `` 60 Minutes'' program, <PERSON> Bracy </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, told correspondent <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> that he was forced to sign a confession and that Naval investigators knew it was false. `` As I said, the things that they put in that statement that they accused me of doing I know never happened,'' <PERSON> Bracy </PERSON> said. The government had just uncovered a spy for sex scandal in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in 1987 when <PERSON> Bracy </PERSON> was interrogated. In the confession, which he later recanted, he admitted a sexual relationship with a <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> cook at the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. He also confessed to allowing <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> agents roam in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. In the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> interview, <PERSON> Bracy </PERSON> denied that he slept with the <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> woman and said he never allowed <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> agents into the embassy. <PERSON> Bracy </PERSON> at one time faced a military court-martial but all charges were dropped when military lawyers concluded they did not have any corroborating evidence to prosecute. He was discharged from the <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION> last spring. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reporter and the author of a new book on the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> spy scandal, also was interviewed by <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bracy </PERSON> allowed <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> agents into the embassy's computer nerve-center where they planted electronic listening devices. As a result, <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> contends that 25 Soviet citizens who worked for the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> were exposed and later executed. <PERSON> Bracy </PERSON> denied the charge, saying he did not have access to the computer room. But <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Pender </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investigative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> agent who interrogated <PERSON> Bracy </PERSON>, told <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> he is convinced that <PERSON> Bracy </PERSON> was a spy for the Soviets while stationed in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. `` It's my feeling that <PERSON> Bracy </PERSON> has been a liar all his life,'' <PERSON> Pender </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a AM-BRF--PasadenaCommissioning 1stLd-Writethru a0640 02-12
0179</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Pasadena Commissioning, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0640,0177</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nuclear-Powered Submarine Commissioned</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf to CORRECT that submarine will not be the first
to carry cruise missiles. Picks up 3rd graf pvs, `Thirty-five protesters
...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GROTON, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nuclear-powered attack submarine USS Pasadena joined the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s fleet Saturday during commissioning ceremonies that spurred a peaceful demonstration by anti-nuclear weapons protesters. Adm. <PERSON> Carlisle </PERSON> <PERSON> A.H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Trost </PERSON>, chief of naval operations, praised the <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION> as the `` most capable attack submarine in the world.'' The submarine was built at the Electric Boat shipyard here. Thirty-five protesters from various New England-based anti-nuclear weapons groups demonstrated outside the submarine base in <LOCATION> Groton </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Joanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheehan </PERSON>, of the Norwich-based <ORGANIZATION> War </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resisters </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, described the protest as a `` simple vigil.'' `` It was important for people going to the ceremonies to show them there is opposition to these weapons,'' she said. <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION> is the first submarine and the third <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> ship to bear the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> city's name. The 360-foot submarine displaces 6,900 tons and will carry a crew of 12 officers and 115 enlisted men.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 0024EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PayolaCase     02-12 0274</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Payola Case,0282</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Drops Payola Charges Against Record Promoter</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge has dismissed payola charges against a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco-area </LOCATION> record promoter, saying the counts in the much-publicized <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> investigation were too vague. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Pamela </PERSON> <PERSON> Rymer </PERSON>, in response to a defense motion, on Friday dismissed three misdemeanor payola counts against <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Tashjian </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mateo </LOCATION>, on the grounds the grand jury indictment was n't specific enough to allow the promoter to defend himself. Court documents showed <PERSON> Tashjian </PERSON> was charged with `` making regular undisclosed payments or distributions of cocaine to program directors so the records he was promoting would be added to radio station play lists.'' Prosecutor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Stavin </PERSON>, a special attorney for the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organized </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crime </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strike </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, said the government next week plans to charge <PERSON> Tashjian </PERSON> with 200 individual counts of payola. <PERSON> Stavin </PERSON> attributed the dismissal to a `` weakness in the payola statute'' that addresses only specific incidents and `` does n't contemplate a scheme or ongoing course of action. <PERSON> Tashjian </PERSON> and his wife are set to stand trial later this month on separate felony tax evasion charges stemming from the payola case. Reacting to the judge's ruling, <PERSON> Tashjian </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooklier </PERSON>, said: `` The problem was, the government charged my client with multiple offenses over a long period of time without specifying the dates of those alleged offenses or the records involved.'' The Tashjians, along with another record promoter and a former radio station manager, were indicted in February 1988 after the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> conducted a two-year investigation under the direction of the Organized Crime Strike Force. Charges against the other defendants were pending.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Czechoslovakia 1stLd-Writethru   02-12 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Czechoslovakia, 1st Ld - Writethru,a0626,0505</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jakes Assails Dissidents</HEAD>
<UNK>Eds: ADDS four grafs on editor fired; no pickup</UNK>
<DATELINE>PRAGUE, Czechoslovakia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Milos </PERSON> <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON> warned in a report published Saturday that opposition forces are resorting to `` psychological terror'' against socialists. <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON> and party ideologist <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Fojtik </PERSON>, maintaining a hard line against dissidents, made clear that the <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> leadership is not prepared to listen to the Charter 77 human rights movement or other independent groups. Various groups try to rally `` as an opposition,'' and `` their actions are widely backed and assisted from the West,'' <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON> was quoted Saturday by the <ORGANIZATION> CTK </ORGANIZATION> news agency as saying. He alleged that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government-funded Radio Free Europe and <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> `` and others directly participate in organizing -LRB- anti-socialist forces -RRB-.'' <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON> said foes of the system are moving from covert action to `` attempts at open confrontation, including psychological pressure, intimidation and even psychological terror against people who hold the positions of socialism.'' He apparently referred to 80 anonymous `` terrorist letters and calls'' the party daily Rude Pravo allegedly received, some of them reportedly wishing communist leaders to be hanged on lamp posts. <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON> also expressed the leadership's concern over a petition, signed by more than 1,000 prominent artists and intellectuals, calling for the release of jailed dissident and playwright <PERSON> Vaclav </PERSON> <PERSON> Havel </PERSON>. The party chief's toughly worded remarks contrasted with the official stands on nonconformists in neighboring <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s Parliament last month approved formation of independent political groups and Polish authorities are negotiating with the outlawed Solidarity free trade union on trade union freedom and other reforms. `` We are not calling for dialogue with everybody, only with those who are willing to contribute to the solution of the problems of our society,'' <PERSON> Fojtik </PERSON> was quoted as saying. `` We wo n't have dialogue forced upon us by those who want to judge our problems from the positions of the defeated reaction in Feburary 1948'' when the communists took power. According to <ORGANIZATION> CTK </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON> lashed out at `` activities of illegal religious structures and of some church representatives -LRB- and -RRB- their efforts to misuse the religious feelings of part of the believers against socialism.'' Czechoslovak Catholic Cardinal <PERSON> Frantisek </PERSON> <PERSON> Tomasek </PERSON>, in recent letters to the regime, has sharply criticized police violence in breaking up peaceful demonstrations in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> and called for a conciliatory official stance. Also, <PERSON> Jaroslav </PERSON> <PERSON> Cejka </PERSON>, chief editor of the <ORGANIZATION> Czechoslovak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s cultural weekly <PERSON> Tvorba </PERSON> <PERSON> Cejka </PERSON> has been fired, apparently for criticizing a report on a meeting with cultural figures carried by the party daily Rude Pravo. Reporting on a Politburo session Friday, <ORGANIZATION> CTK </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Cejka </PERSON> was `` relieved of his post'' and `` was entrusted with other duties,'' a customary cliche for being dismissed. The surprising ouster came only two days after <PERSON> Cejka </PERSON> criticized Rude Pravo in <LOCATION> Tvorba </LOCATION> Wednesday for `` not doing a very good job'' covering a discussion between Politburo member <PERSON> Miroslav </PERSON> <PERSON> Stepan </PERSON> and a delegation of cultural figures. The meeting was apparently brought about by the artists' petition.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 0023EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FireDeaths     02-12 0153</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fire Deaths,0158</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eight Die In House Fire; Crack In Chimney Blamed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AUGUSTA, Ark. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fire swept through a farm house from a faulty chimney early Saturday, killing eight family members while they slept, officials said. Two family members escaped the 3 a.m. fire in a rural community seven miles from this eastern <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> town, 75 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION>. `` The fire marshal thinks the chimney had a crack in it,'' said <LOCATION> Woodruff </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Creasey </PERSON> said Saturday night. `` This fire just raced through the house.'' <PERSON> Creasey </PERSON> identified the dead as <PERSON> Bernice </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON>, 46, and six of her children, ages 15 to 30, and a 2-year-old granddaughter. Mrs. <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON>' husband, <PERSON> J.B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON> and their daughter, <PERSON> Angela </PERSON>, escaped Their ages were unavailable. <PERSON> Creasey </PERSON> said a wood stove was attached to the chimney. The sheriff said victim's bodies were found in their beds. `` They never knew what hit them,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-911Disruption     02-12 0322</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-911 Disruption,0329</SECOND>
<HEAD>Emergency 911 System Breaks Down; Hundreds Of Calls Unanswered</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Forrest and Lissa are cq</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of calls to the police and fire departments' 911 emergency number went unanswered Saturday because of a technical problem that knocked out the system for more than four hours. Authorities said they plan to investigate whether the outage, the first in the 911 system's five years of operation, resulted in injury, death or fire damage that could have been avoided had the system been working properly. `` At this point we just do n't know,'' said police Capt. <PERSON> Forrest </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewallen </PERSON>. `` I can say that this is a very serious problem. It is something that quite obviously we'll have to find remedies to ensure that it never happens again.'' The problems began at 1 p.m. when equipment that allows the <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to transfer calls to the <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> stopped working, said <PERSON> Lissa </PERSON> <PERSON> Zanville </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION>, which operates the system. The equipment failure created a backlog that allowed only one in five calls to reach a 911 operator at the central communications center in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, where all 911 calls within city limits are directed, she said. From 3 to 3:40 p.m., the system went down entirely and no calls got through. By 5:14 p.m., <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> technicians had the system working again, Ms. <PERSON> Zanville </PERSON> said. The number of calls that went unanswered was unknown, but the system normally handles 5,000 to 7,000 calls a day, and a four-hour breakdown would easily have left hundreds of calls unanswered, said <PERSON> Lewallen </PERSON>. Not all of those unanswered calls would be emergencies. <PERSON> Lewallen </PERSON> said that about 75 percent of the 4 million calls dialed each year on 911 are emergencies, with the rest usually non-emergency calls or pranks. The Sheriff's <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the county Fire Department, which do n't operate on the city's communications system, were unaffected by the outage, authorities said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Afghanistan 2ndLd-Writethru a0649 02-12 0673</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Afghanistan, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0649,0698</SECOND>
<HEAD>Najib Accuses Pakistan Of Planning Invasion</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 9th graf, ``Afghan Foreign..., to CORRECT spelling of spokesman,
Amani sted Manai. Pick up 10th pvs, ``They're being...</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Afghan Guerrillas, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SHARON HERBAUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> on Saturday accused <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> of massing troops along the border in preparation for an invasion and eventual annexation of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. The government also released 20 imprisoned Iranians to improve relations with its western neighbor, but an Iranian diplomat said his country will not be satisfied until Moslem guerrillas win the civil war. In a speech broadcast on national radio and television, <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> said his government had received information <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> planned first to attack <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION>, about 80 miles east of <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> and 50 miles west of the <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> border. `` Militarist and reactionary parties envisage swallowing our country and turning it into a fifth province of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>,'' the president said in his strongest attack yet on <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s neighbor. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> has allowed Moslem guerrillas fighting <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>'s Soviet-backed government to operate from <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> have supported the guerrillas, who began fighting in 1978 after the communists took power in a coup. In 1979, the Soviets sent troops into <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> to prop up the pro-Marxist government. Under a U.N.-mediated accord, all Soviet troops must be withdrawn by Wednesday. Radio <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> reported Saturday the last motorized army unit was within 125 miles of the Soviet border. The guerrillas are not party to the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> accord and want to overthrow <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>'s government when the Soviets are gone. Afghan <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Nabi </PERSON> <PERSON> Amani </PERSON> said 20 Iranian prisoners were freed to commemorate the 10th anniversary of the Iranian revolution led by <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>. `` They're being released as a goodwill gesture toward the Iranian government,'' he told a news conference. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s highest-ranking diplomat in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, Charge d'Affaires <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> <PERSON> Intizari </PERSON>, welcomed the release but said it will not improve relations. `` We are waiting for a government with the mujahedeen,'' he said. The prisoners appeared to be in good health, but many showed reporters scars and missing teeth and said they had been repeatedly beaten and tortured. The Afghan government had no immediate comment on the allegations. With the withdrawal deadline approaching, <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> exhorted the Afghan people to protect their nation's sovereignty. `` Say in one voice: ` Country or death,''' he said. He also accused the Pakistani military of controlling the guerrillas. In <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, there appeared to be no end to the bitter disputes among guerrilla factions over the composition of a provisional Islamic government they want to form. At issue is how power would be shared by the seven insurgent groups in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and the eight factions based in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. On Friday, 526 guerrillas and other Afghans met as a council to decide the matter but the Iranian-based alliance walked out. <PERSON> Rasul </PERSON> <PERSON> Sayyaf </PERSON>, the spokesman for the meeting, said Saturday the council would meet `` in two or three days.'' He said efforts to persuade the Iranian-based guerrillas not to boycott the council failed. `` We can not expect quick solutions to the problem of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>,'' he said at a news conference. Radio <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> said patrols along the <LOCATION> Salang </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Highway </LOCATION>, the main route between <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> and the Soviet border, were being discontinued. According to the report, the last motorized <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> unit traveled through a mountain pass on the <LOCATION> Salang </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Highway </LOCATION>. It did not say how many troops or what kind of equipment were in the unit. The report also said a `` small group'' of soldiers will remain in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, the Afghan capital, to guard the airport until the Soviets complete a massive food airlift. A Soviet officer, Col. <PERSON> Pavel </PERSON> <PERSON> Vinokunov </PERSON>, said in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> the airlift will continue until Monday and his men will depart then. Col. Gen. <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Moiseyev </PERSON>, the military chief of staff, has said the last Soviet soldier will leave <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> on Tuesday. Soviet officials have said the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> contingent in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> numbered 115,000 before the pullout began May 15 and that half had left by Aug. 15.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Afghanistan-Iran 1stLd-Writethru   02-12 0349</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Afghanistan-Iran, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0650,0358</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Releases 20 Iranian Prisoners</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf, ``Foreign Ministry..., to CORRECT spelling of
spokesman, Amani sted Manai. Pick up 4th pvs, ``They're being...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SHARON HERBAUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> on Saturday released 20 Iranians imprisoned for political crimes, extending an olive branch to the <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> government. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> rebuffed the move and most of the freed prisoners claimed they had been beaten and tortured by the Afghans. <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Nabi </PERSON> <PERSON> Amani </PERSON> said the prisoners were released to commemorate the 10th anniversary of the revolution in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> that brought <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> to power. `` They be being released as goodwill gesture toward the Iranian government,'' <PERSON> Amani </PERSON> told a news conference. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s highest-raking diplomat in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, Charge d'Affairs <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> <PERSON> Intizari </PERSON>, welcomed the release but said it would not help improve relations between <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> supports the efforts of the Moslem guerrillas, or mujahedeen, fighting to overthrow the government of President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>, who has been supported by Soviet troops since December 1979. Soviet forces are in the final days of a withdrawal to be completed by Wednesday under a U.N.-sponsored agreement. `` We have not recognized this government for the past 10 years. How can it improve relations?'' <PERSON> Intizari </PERSON> asked shortly before he greeted the former prisoners at a hotel in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. `` We are waiting for a government with the mujahedeen,'' he said. The 20 men had been imprisoned for 2 to 10 years after they were tried and convicted of various political crimes, including aiding the Moslem rebels. All appeared to be in good health, although many showed reporters scars they said were caused by cigarette brns, missing teeth, and said they had were repeatedly beaten and tortured. The Afghan government had no immediate comment on the allegations. Seventeen of the men were to be flown to <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> on Sunday, <PERSON> Intizari </PERSON> said. One man claimd he was Afghan and will stay in the country. The other two said they did not want to go back to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and were released to the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Cuba     02-12 0238</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cuba,0244</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: U.S. Wants Cuba To Help Fight Drug War</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is looking to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> as an ally in the war against illegal drugs, according to a published report. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> in its Sunday editions quoted unidentified sources as saying that, despite the longtime freeze in relations between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, `` initiatives are being discussed'' through numerous channels with <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, seeking his cooperation in stopping drug shipments from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The newspaper quoted unidentified <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government officials as saying that the contacts are motivated by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' inability to stem the flow of illegal drugs The `` cautious'' contacts with the Communist country grew out of a December meeting in <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION> between <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> and a visiting <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> delegation that included <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Rangel </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Narcotics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>, the News reported. In the past, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has accused <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> of harboring drug traffickers and encouraging them to smuggle illegal drugs to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. After his visit with <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rangel </PERSON> told <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials that `` <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> wants very much to work with both the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> on narcotics control,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> reported Should the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> agree to cooperate in the war on drugs, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government could face an uproar from the Cuban-American community, the News said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 0313EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-JerryBrown 3rd-Writethru a0664 02-12 0706</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jerry Brown, 3rd - Writethru, a0664,0718</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jerry Brown Campaigns For California Party Chair</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 6 grafs to UPDATE with Brown winning post outright.
Picks up 7th graf pvs, `Brown said ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUG WILLIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SACRAMENTO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Gov. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> began what he said could be a political comeback Saturday night by winning the previously obscure <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chair. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> defeated <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Westly </PERSON>, a party official unknown to the general public, 1,554-762, in voting by some 2,300 delegates at the party's annual convention. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s bid to return to the public arena overshadowed other events at the convention, including speeches by most of the major contenders for the Democratic nomination for governor in 1990 and the addresses of 1988 presidential hopefuls <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. The two-time candidate for president picked the race as the vehicle to end the six-year, self-imposed political exile which began after he concluded his two terms as governor with a losing campaign for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, 50, once dubbed `` Gov. Moonbeam'' by his critics, spent part of that exile in seclusion writing in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, part working <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON>'s hospital in <LOCATION> Calcutta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, and part on a CARE hunger project in <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> readily confirmed Friday that if he won the chair's office, he would probably seek higher offices in the future. But if he lost it would be the most embarrassing, and possibly the final, loss of his public career. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said he was confident of victory in Saturday's vote. But his opponent, current vice chair <PERSON> Westly </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Menlo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, said he surveyed more than half of the voting delegates and found <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> leading by only 556 to 525 with 585 undecided. In speeches to the delegates Saturday, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> promised `` to mobilize the millions and millions of non-voters'' to rejoin the political process. `` You will not see my face on the cover of <ORGANIZATION> Time </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Westly </PERSON>, 33, an investment banker and longtime party volunteer, told the delegates. `` But I have a different strength. I get the job done.'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> wrapped up a three-month campaign for the post with endorsements from most of the state's most prominent Democratic politicians, including <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, Assembly Speaker <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> and state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> President Pro Tem <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberti </PERSON>. But at least two dozen <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> officeholders and county chairmen publicly opposed <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, contending that his presence as official head of the party would breathe new life into Republican attacks against the most controversial events of his governship from 1975 through 1982 and be a liability for Democratic candidates in 1990. The bid for the obscure post of party chair by a former governor was unprecedented in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> politics, and it overshadowed all other business of the three-day <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> that started Friday. In an appearance Friday before the <ORGANIZATION> Sacramento </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> described his $ 150,000 campaign as his re-entry into politics and a possible stepping stone back to higher office. But he repeated his pledge that if elected he would n't seek any higher office until his term as chair is completed. `` I'm not running for anything in the next four years,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said, adding that `` obviously, I do n't intend it to be my terminal position -LRB- in politics -RRB-. But where I go next, or where I'm invited to go next, will depend completely on the success of what I've embarked upon here.'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said that as chairman he would devote his full attention to party fund-raising, building local committees and clubs and party registration and get-out-the-the vote drives. He conceded that he often ignored the party while governor, and that the `` nuts-and-bolts'' administrative duties of state chair are exactly the things he tended to neglect as governor. But he said his priorities are different now. `` There has been a lot of discussion about my administrative ability. I've thought a lot about that over the last six years, and it's true ... a good manager -LRB- requires -RRB- doing things in a very structured manner, which is certainly not my natural inclination.'' He said changes in state laws giving the party more influence and the need to reverse declining voter participation trends to revitalize the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> all make the chair's job more important and challenging.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 0506EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-SriLanka-Massacre 1stLd-Writethru   02-12 0374</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Sri Lanka-Massacre, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0665,0380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tamil Rebels Kill 34 In Sleeping Village</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: New thruout to UPDATE with more killings. No pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLOMBO, Sri Lanka (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tamil rebels armed with automatic rifles, machetes and clubs attacked a remote jungle village in central <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> and killed 34 Sinhalese, authorities said Sunday. Elsewhere in the island nation, nine other people were killed as violence escalated with the approach of Wednesday's parliamentary election. One of the victims was an opposition party candidate, the 14th would-be legislator to die since campaigning started five weeks ago. More than 50 rebels crept into the village of <LOCATION> Dutuwewa </LOCATION> late Saturday night and surprised the sleeping residents, said a police officer contacted by telephone in nearby <LOCATION> Horawapatana </LOCATION>. Military officials in <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION> said the victims included 20 children and five women. At least four people in the village survived by fleeing into the thick undergrowth, said the officials, who spoke on condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Dutuwewa </PERSON> is about 60 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>, the capital. The village is in predominantly <LOCATION> Sinhalese </LOCATION> <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Province </LOCATION> but lies just outside <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Province </LOCATION>, a main area of operations by Tamil separatists. A Foreign Ministry official in <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION> blamed the killings on the <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tamil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eelam </ORGANIZATION>, the most powerful of the Tamil guerrilla groups that have been waging a bloody independence campaign since 1983. The <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION> issued a statement denying responsibility for the attack. It was the second massacre of Sinhalese civilians in the region this month. On Feb. 3 at least 11 people were killed in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Province </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Amparai </LOCATION> district about 100 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Duduwewa </LOCATION>. More than 8,500 have died in the ethnic violence as the minority Tamils pressed their attacks on the Sinhalese majority and Sinhalese-dominated government. Tamils form 18 percent of <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>'s 16 million people and live mostly in Northern and Eastern provinces. They claim they are discriminated against by the Sinhalese, who make up 75 percent of the population. In the south, parliamentary candidate <PERSON> Somapala </PERSON> <PERSON> Amarakeerthi </PERSON>, his brother and a supporter were killed Saturday by attackers wearing camouflage uniforms, military officials said. In the eastern town of <LOCATION> Sammanturai </LOCATION>, six supporters of President <PERSON> Ranasinghe </PERSON> <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> were shot and killed by unknown attackers, the officials said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 0826EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Pakistan     02-12 0319</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Pakistan,0334</SECOND>
<HEAD>At Least Five Killed When Protesters Storm U.S. Center</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police opened fire Sunday on Moslem fundamentalists who stormed a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government center in this city. Doctors said at least five people were killed and at least 30 were reported injured. The gunfire broke out when more than 2,000 fundamentalist protesters marched toward the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> to demand banning of a novel, `` The Satanic Verses'' by <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>. Police repeatedly opened fire with rifles and semi-automatic weapons on the charging protesters, who hurled rocks and bricks in fierce fighting in the heart of the capital. Witnesses said the protesters ripped down the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> flag and tore shutters off the building. Protesters who broke into the building, which had been closed, smashed windows and started several small fires. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials had no immediate word on damage. `` American dogs'' and `` God is great,'' the protesters screamed as they hurled rocks at the building and drove away scores of police trying to guard it. `` Hang <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>,'' one protester yelled. Doctors at area hospitals, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said at least five people were killed by police gunfire and many were injured. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s official news agency said 30 people were injured. Police kept the demonstrators at bay for almost an hour before they gathered strength and moved toward the center, which houses a library, a cultural center and the offices of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. An unknown number of police were also injured by rocks, and some were beaten by the crowd. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, and some <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> nations have banned the `` The Satanic Verses,'' which is named after verses the Prophet <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> removed from the Koran _ the <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> holy book _ on grounds they were inspired by the devil. Earlier this month, about 3,000 Moslems demonstrated in the English city of <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION> to protest the book, which they consider blasphemous.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 1128EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--TrainGang     02-12 0135</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Train Gang,0137</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gang Of Youths Rob, Attack Train Passengers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 15 knife-wielding youths robbed passengers on an inter-city train early Sunday and attacked some who resisted, resulting in some injuries, <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> said. `` At least 11 people were robbed of cash, jewelery and other valuables and two people were taken to a hospital with head and neck injuries,'' said a police official, speaking anonymously in keeping with British custom. `` We believe there are other passengers who were robbed and have not yet come forward.'' Police said the youths are thought to have boarded the 1:37 a.m. train to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s King's Cross station at <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Albans </LOCATION>, 19 miles northwest of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. The train was traveling from <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION>, 46 miles north of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. Police could not estimate the value of goods stolen.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 1128EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Sweden-Seals     02-12 0156</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Sweden-Seals,0161</SECOND>
<HEAD>Film About Norwegian Seal Hunting Triggers Storm of Protest</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of angry television viewers called the <ORGANIZATION> Norwegian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>, major newspapers and conservationists to react to a film about Norwegian seal hunting, Swedish media reported Sunday. The documentary ran on Swedish television Saturday night and showed seal puppies being clubbed to death and seals apparently being skinned alive. `` I have never seen anything as disgusting. I am boycotting <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>,'' 23-year-old <PERSON> Freddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Karlsson </PERSON> told the Aftonbladet daily. Some viewers called police to threaten attacks on Norwegian installations, said Swedish radio. The film, `` About Seals and Humans,'' reportedly triggered similar outrage when it ran on Danish and British television last week. It has not been shown in <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>, which is lobbying to end a 1983 <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> ban on importing seal pup skin. Former Norwegian seal inspector <PERSON> Odd </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lindberg </PERSON> filmed the documentary aboard a vessel off <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION> in 1987 and 1988.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 1128EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Korea     02-12 0310</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Korea,0320</SECOND>
<HEAD>North Accuses South of Shooting Across Border</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Communist <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> on Sunday accused South Korean troops of firing across the border at its policemen. The North's official <ORGANIZATION> Korean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said the firing `` gravely threatened the safety of the civilian policemen of our side on routine duty at the post.'' It did not mention any injuries or damage. `` It was entirely due to the patience and self-control of the civilian policemen of our side that this incident did not expand into an arms conflict between the two sides,'' said the agency, monitored in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. It said several <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> soldiers fired `` many bullets'' from automatic rifles Sunday afternoon from the Chosan military police post in the Demilitarized Zone that divides the two Koreas. The post is west of <LOCATION> Munsan </LOCATION>, a city about 25 miles north of <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> and about 10 miles south of the truce village of <LOCATION> Panmunjom </LOCATION> in the DMZ. `` The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> imperialists and the South Korean puppets are committing one military provocation after another on the ground and in the sea while staging the adventurous ` Team Spirit 89' joint military maneuvers,'' the report said. `` This clearly shows how desperately they are making new war provocation moves to invade the northern half of <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, bringing the situation of the <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> peninsula to the extreme pitch of strain,'' it said. Team Spirit is an annual U.S.-South Korean joint military exercise, described as purely defensive. The North, however, says it is a rehearsal for invasion and has demanded it be canceled to improve the atmosphere for North-South talks. The two sides have held a number of contacts in recent months aimed at easing tensions and exploring ways to reunify the peninsula. The North and the South have been divided since 1945. They fought a bloody war in 1950-53 after the North invaded the South.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 1129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--HolyFire     02-12 0172</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Holy Fire,0176</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hindu Holy Fire Burns For 1,128 Years</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Hindu family in southern <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> has been reverently tending a sacred fire for 1,128 years, a news agency reported Sunday. Tradition holds that the fire, although sometimes reduced to glowing embers, has never been extinguished since it was lit. The Press Trust of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> reported that the fire burns in a pit in the home of <LOCATION> Neelakandhan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Namboodiri </LOCATION> at the village of <LOCATION> Cheruvathery </LOCATION>, in the southwest coastal state of <LOCATION> Kerala </LOCATION>. It quoted <PERSON> Namboodiri </PERSON> as saying his family kept the fire burning by sprinkling it three times a day with coconut, butter and a combination of nine grains. The ritual is designed to attain peace and spiritual and material happiness, but <PERSON> Namboodiri </PERSON> said it is also costly. The news agency quoted him as saying it takes about $ 3 a day to keep the fire burning. <PERSON> Namboodiri </PERSON> said copper plates found during excavations in 1949 say the fire was lit in 861 A.D. by <PERSON> Maharishi </PERSON> <PERSON> Vikala </PERSON> <PERSON> Nethreeyacharya </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 1135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--BusAccident     02-12 0092</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Bus Accident,0094</SECOND>
<HEAD>Twenty-Two Injured In French Bus Accident</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROSENHEIM, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bus filled with French tourists ran off a highway and crashed into a wooded area Sunday, injuring 22 people, 18 of them seriously, police said. Police in the Bavarian town of <PERSON> Rosenheim </PERSON> said 46 people were riding in the bus when it veered off the road and overturned. A police spokesman, who declined to be identified, said the accident occurred near the town of <LOCATION> Hofolding </LOCATION> south of <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION>. The cause of the crash was under investigation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 1135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--India-Accident     02-12 0068</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--India-Accident,0070</SECOND>
<HEAD>Truck Overturns, Killing 22 People</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A speeding truck overturned in eastern <LOCATION> Bihar </LOCATION> state, killing 22 people and injuring 15, news reports said Sunday. Television news reports said the victims included 10 children and the driver of the truck. According to the reports, the truck flipped over late Friday near the town of <LOCATION> Gaya </LOCATION>, about 560 miles southeast of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 1138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-AirTerror Bjt   02-12 0783</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Air Terror, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pan Am Bombing Prompts Tight Security, Inquiry, International Effort</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The still unsolved bombing of <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> Flight 103 over <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> has brought more stringent security for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airlines, congressional inquiries and a move to increase international efforts against air terrorism. Although tight airport security has all but eliminated hijackings in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the Dec. 21 bombing of the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 that killed 259 people en route to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and 11 more on the ground raises the spectre of a more deadly kind of air terrorism. It also raises questions about how to respond to the more than 900 threats against <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airlines each year, including when to warn the public. <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> officials told two congressional committees last week that airlines have greatly increased security measures for foreign flights since the bombing of Flight 103. All checked baggage is X-rayed. Passengers are denied any access to baggage after check-in. Passengers are matched with bags to guard against unaccompanied baggage. Additional measures prevent unauthorized access to luggage or planes. And more passengers are subjected to random enhanced screening with suitcases actually opened by inspectors. `` We will not hesitate to tilt the balance toward improved security and away from convenience when that is necessary to protect our citizens,'' <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> told one of two congressional hearings last week. He indicated those measures and others _ which airlines will not discuss _ have brought little complaint. But airline officials and members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> want the increased security imposed on foreign carriers flying into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as well. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which represents <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> carriers, estimates that 50 percent of international travel by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens is on foreign airlines. `` Beefing up security only for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> carriers would be like having policemen patrol only odd numbered streets,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lally </PERSON>, association vice president for security. <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Salazar </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> director for civil aviation security, told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airlines are considered the major target for terrorists and that attempting to impose unilateral restrictions on foreign carriers could start `` an air war.'' But Transportation Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> hopes to reach a consensus on international security measures at this week's special meeting of the 33-member Council of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> called for the meeting to discuss steps to take following the Pan Am bombing. In addition to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> inability to control foreign airlines and airports, authorities trying to combat terrorist attacks against airliners face weapons that X-rays ca n't detect and threats that often come from sources they ca n't identify. At least two devices are under development that can detect plastic explosives such as those investigators believe were planted in luggage aboard Flight 103. One is an explosive vapor detection system that checks people for explosives. <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> officials say preliminary tests were conducted at <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> but it is still in the testing stage. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> has already tested and used two $ 1 million `` thermal neutron analysis'' machines at <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> airports and has ordered six more. Airline officials say the units should be sent right away to high-risk airports in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> has identified 73 airports which it considers the most vulnerable to terrorism. Rep. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Solarz </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, has asked the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> to determine how many machines would be needed for critical airports, how much they will cost and who ought to pay for them. In another congressional inquiry, Rep. <PERSON> Cardiss </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, D-Ill., chairwoman of the Government Operations transportation subcommittee which plans hearings on Flight 103 next month, has asked the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> to provide details of its procedures for warning of threats against aviation In letters last week to the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> asked for documents relating to a telephone threat received by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> against <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> flights from <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> two weeks before Flight 103 was destroyed. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says the threat was a hoax and no public warning was made, but a notice disclosing the threat was posted on the <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> bulletin board eight days before the explosion. <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Bremer </PERSON>, ambassador-at-large for counterterrorism, told <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> the notice should not have been posted and said the government has a policy of not issuing such warning unless they are also made to the general public. He said if warnings were issued for every threat, it could cripple commercial aviation. But survivors of Flight 103 victims, in a statement last week, said passengers should be provided, on request, details of any threat against a flight they plan to take.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 1140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Poll-Israel-PLO Bjt   02-12 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Poll-Israel-PLO, Bjt,0659</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poll Finds Skepticism About PLO But Support for U.S.-PLO Talks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Americans overwhelmingly support <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s overtures to the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> but are deeply suspicious of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> and dubious of its claim to have abandoned terrorism, according to a national poll Only 6 percent of those interviewed in the <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General-Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> survey said they believed the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s recent renunciation of terrorism, while 74 percent said the group just made that claim for political gain. The rest were unsure. Respondents were split on whether the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> would coexist with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> or sought to destroy it, and a strong majority said other groups could represent the Palestinian people. Still, the distrust was tempered by the desire for an end to the <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> conflict. A majority said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> should negotiate with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, although most said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should not force it to do so. The survey also found some frustration with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s support groups in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, with 35 percent saying they had too much influence on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy. Twenty percent said pro-Palestinan groups had too much influence. The poll was conducted among 1,162 adults Jan. 4-12, following <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s statement recognizing <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and renouncing terrorism. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> rejected the move as a ploy, but the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> responded by opening its first talks with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. Sixty-seven percent approved of U.S.-PLO talks, with the rest split between disapproval and no opinion. Support was highest among college-educated Americans, with eight in 10 approving. Respondents, moreover, endorsed a major tenet of the Palestinian cause: Sixty-two percent said the <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> should have their own country. Just 11 percent said no, and 27 percent had no opinion. Roughly a quarter of the respondents had no view on many of the questions posed, reflecting the distance of <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> issues from the daily concerns of many Americans. Significantly more men expressed opinions than did women. The most-educated respondents, those with post-graduate educations, were more likely to favor dealings with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. While 62 percent overall said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> should negotiate with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, for example, that swelled to 79 percent of the most-educated group. Also, 60 percent of the most-educated group said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> should allow the creation of a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state on territory it now occupies in exchange for recognition from the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. Among all respondents, just 44 percent agreed. But the share of respondents who believed the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> has given up terrorism remained low in all groups, peaking at just 11 percent of the most-educated. One-third overall thought the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> wants to destroy <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, about a third believed the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> would coexist with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, and the last third were n't sure. More of the most-educated group, 55 percent, said the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> would co-exist with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. But six in 10 of that group, and five in 10 overall, said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should not recognize the Palestinian state the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> declared in November. The rest were split between support for recognition and no opinion. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has said that it will not negotiate with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> because the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s charter calls for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s destruction, but that it would negotiate with other representatives of the Palestinians. Other Arab nations, however, have declared the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> the only legitimate representative of the Palestinians. In the survey, 63 percent said some group other than the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> could represent the <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> in negotiations with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. And nearly seven respondents in 10 said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should not try to force <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to negotiate with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> by threatening sanctions. The survey had a three-point margin of sampling error. <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a communications company based in <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, publishes the Richmond Times-Dispatch, the Richmond News Leader, the <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Winston-Salem </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal, and operates TV stations <ORGANIZATION> WXFL </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, WCBD in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> WJKS </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 1143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-China-Crash     02-12 0447</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Crash,0462</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tawanese Pilot Says He Planned Flight to China</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The pilot of a Taiwanese fighter jet that crashed in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> said on state-run television Sunday he had planned the flight, and <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> newspapers claimed he carried military secrets to the communists. A local Chinese television station broadcast an interview with Lt. Col. <PERSON> Lin </PERSON> <PERSON> Xianshun </PERSON>, 35, who parachuted to safety Saturday morning 180 miles north of <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION>, capital of southeastern <LOCATION> Guangdong </LOCATION> province. <PERSON> Lin </PERSON> said he flew the F-5E jet fighter to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> of his own free will. He also said none of his family knew about his plans. He did not elaborate. None of the Chinese reports made clear whether <PERSON> Lin </PERSON> requested asylum. In the past, the state media always have given prominent coverage to military defectors from <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s nationally televised news said Sunday night that <PERSON> Lin </PERSON> had been `` warmly welcomed'' by officers from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s air force after his plane crashed into a rice paddy, reportedly after running out of oil. It showed <PERSON> Lin </PERSON>'s mangled jet and of <PERSON> Lin </PERSON> shaking hands with <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> air force officers. It said he was treated in a hospital for slight injuries. Earlier reports from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> said <PERSON> Lin </PERSON> wanted to find his relatives in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. A <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> report said he had asked Chinese authorities to find an uncle, <PERSON> Lin </PERSON> <PERSON> Yuyi </PERSON>. `` But authorities have yet to find the uncle,'' said an official at the state news agency in <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION>, contacted by telephone from <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, a relative of the pilot said he believed <PERSON> Lin </PERSON> defected to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> to see his grandmother. The relative, who spoke to reporters on condition of anonymity, said <PERSON> Lin </PERSON> complained that military officers were banned from visiting <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. In 1987, the Nationalist government eased a ban to allow all Taiwanese, except military and government personnel, to visit <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, the liberal <ORGANIZATION> Independence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Evening </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> quoted unidentified sources as saying <PERSON> Lin </PERSON> took `` several important documents'' about the strength of <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s air force to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. It said he took the documents from his squadron, which trained selected pilots as `` enemy forces'' during mock air battles. The mass-circulation <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Lin </PERSON> might reveal to the Chinese a military blueprint for the defense of eastern <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> from possible <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> attacks. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> officials refused comment on the reports. <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s state broadcasting corporation reported authorities have taken <PERSON> Lin </PERSON>'s wife, daughter and son to Chihhang Air Base for questioning. More than a dozen Taiwanese air force officers have sought asylum in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and 19 Chinese military personnel have defected to <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> since 1949 when the Nationalists lost a civil war to communist forces on the mainland.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 1149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Kemp-Homeless Bjt   02-12 0770</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Kemp-Homeless, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Outspoken Former Congressman Gets His Chance To Attack Homeless Problem</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Writing 10 years ago, <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>'s programs `` are consistently misguided and scandalous.'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, who took over last week as the new secretary of that department, is getting his chance to improve those programs, or what survives of them after a decade of pressure on domestic spending. The former <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> congressman comes to <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> at a time when the problems it deals with have gained heightened visibility. The nation's homeless population is growing and increasingly includes families unable to afford or obtain housing, according to surveys conducted by the nation's big-city mayors. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> and President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> have both acknowledged the problem of homelessness. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, who offered the harsh description of <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> in his 1979 book `` An American Renaissance,'' last month called homelessness `` a national tragedy of appalling proportions.'' He pledged new spending, and last week <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> included increases for emergency shelters in his new budget proposal. But both also have stressed that there are limits to what the federal government will attempt on homelessness and housing, and advocates of urban programs are watching <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> closely for evidence he will back up his enthusiastic talk about innovation and new ideas. `` He's not got a good record, but he has made very positive statements about homelessness lately, and he has recognized homelessness is a major scandal that has to be addressed,'' said <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Foscarinis </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> counsel for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> for the Homeless. `` Now the question is, will he come through?'' she said. After a swearing-in ceremony by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s offices Monday, the new secretary plans to begin visiting inner cities, starting Tuesday with a trip to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. Mayor <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> will lead him on a tour of housing projects and to meetings with public-housing tenants, including one at the Martin Luther King Jr.. Center, said <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, <PERSON> Young </PERSON>'s press secretary The <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> visit is a logical one for <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, who frequently quotes the late civil rights leader the center if named after and actively sought black support as an unsuccessful rival to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> presidential nomination. That outreach to blacks is a goal of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> under <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and, as secretary of <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> is in a position to aid that cause. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> is a conservative Republican who speaks forcefully of empowering the poor by encouraging the creation of more private jobs rather than more federal spending. Urban advocates, some openly saying they want to educate him about the need for more federal spending, have invited him to visit other cities too. `` We're convinced that Mr. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> will change'' after seeing programs firsthand, said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> and Redevelopment Officials. Although there is wide disagreement over just how many people are homeless in the country, urban advocates are convinced the problem is growing. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mayors </ORGANIZATION>, in a survey of 27 major cities, concluded last month that the problem increased in nearly all those cities during 1988 and that in two-thirds of them people were turned away because shelters were full. The mayors also found that one in four homeless people were children. To deal with the emergency cases, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposed $ 144 million in new spending in his fiscal 1990 budget, including full funding of the McKinney Act passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> providing temporary shelter. The budget, however, includes no money for additional units of subsidized permanent housing for low income people, beyond the level of former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s proposal. Spending for housing programs declined some 80 percent during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> years, and a dwindling supply of affordable housing is what mayors cite as the major cause for homelessness. `` Shelters are not the answer,'' <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON> said. `` Permanent affordable housing _ that is the answer.'' Like <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would rely heavily on use of housing vouchers, which are certificates for subsidy that renters use as partial payment of their rents. But critics say those do n't help a family find housing when no affordable units are available, and that <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> under <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> virtually stopped subsidizing the construction of new affordable housing units. `` Vouchers work in some housing markets, but when the units are n't there, vouchers do n't get you anywhere,'' <PERSON> Foscarinis </PERSON> said. Her organization is backing a bill introduced in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> that would provide $ 2 billion to fix up vacant housing units and, backers say, eventually house 1 million people. So far, she says, the group is still waiting to hear from <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 1217EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-US-Sino-Soviet Bjt   02-12 0873</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Sino-Soviet, Bjt,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>``China Card'' Coming Up Aces For U.S. And U.S.S.R. Alike</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The prospect of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> shaking hands at their upcoming summit is causing surprisingly little anxiety in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Several years ago, reports of high-level chumminess between the two communist giants would have caused sleepless nights among <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, wary of a renewed military and political pact between the powerful neighbors. But Asian and Soviet experts in and out of government say the relaxation of tensions between <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, while not totally to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s advantage, could produce some positive steps in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> region. `` Whatever concerns we might have had four years ago, had this come suddenly, have now been gradually reduced,'' said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kreisberg </PERSON>, a specialist in <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> matters with the <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endowment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>. `` No one now expects the Soviets and the Chinese to restart the security alliance they had in the 1950s,'' <PERSON> Kreisberg </PERSON> said, pointing to comments from <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> that his moves toward easing tensions with the Soviets are not designed to damage U.S.-Chinese relations. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is to travel to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> in May for the summit with <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, marking the first top-level meetings between the two countries since <PERSON> Nikita </PERSON> <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON> met with <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Zedong </PERSON> in 1959. The sessions are designed to formally end the 30 years of hostility between the one-time rivals for leadership of the communist world and `` achieve a complete normalization of relations,'' Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> announced last week. `` There may be some Americans who are anxious about this,'' said <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Kallgren </PERSON>, a director of the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Asian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Kallgren </PERSON> points to the rapid growth of the economic relationship between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, arguing that there is little reason for the Chinese to disturb that trend. And the Sino-Soviet relationship `` has a long way to go'' to match it, she said. `` Are we beginning to see the kind of close -LRB- Chinese-Soviet -RRB- relationship that we saw 30 years ago? It seems to me that there are a lot of reasons why that analogy is a very limited value,'' she said. `` There has n't been much of a wringing of hands,'' agreed a senior <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official who follows <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> affairs. `` We've had a chance to get used to this idea ... It's been coming for years.'' The official, who spoke on condition he not be identified by name, said the Soviet move to mend the ties that had been cut in 1960 began under former Soviet leader <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>. The Chinese felt threatened by the Soviet-backed Vietnamese invasion of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> and the Soviet intrusion into <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, and the effort to improve the atmosphere did not revive until <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> came into power. Needing to develop their economies, both nations have strong domestic reasons to alleviate tensions and reduce military forces along their 4,500-mile border. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> is not alarmed by the upcoming summit, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official continued, because the two countries `` are not going to create a combined Sino-Soviet threat _ not a military one, not an economic one, not a political one.'' The Soviets also are meeting Chinese concerns with their withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and support for a Vietnamese withdrawal from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. Another positive result could be a lessening of tension on the <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> peninsula </LOCATION>, where the two powers have vied for influence with <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Il </PERSON> <PERSON> Sung </PERSON>, the experts point out. And by appearing to be less of a military threat in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>, the Soviets are seeking to increase their economic and trade connections with nations enjoying the <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> `` economic miracle,'' such as <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, the Carnegie's <PERSON> Kreisberg </PERSON> said. Former Secretary of State <PERSON> Cyrus </PERSON> <PERSON> Vance </PERSON> wrote recently that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> might see `` more reason for hope than fear'' in the change. `` These two men ... have it in their power not only to end formally a long period of hostility but also to make an enormous contribution to peace,'' <PERSON> Vance </PERSON> wrote in a joint essay published by <ORGANIZATION> Time </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magazine </ORGANIZATION> with <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Holbrooke </PERSON>, who worked with <PERSON> Vance </PERSON> as an assistant secretary for east <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> affairs when President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> established full diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. Although the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> may lose some of the advantage gained by having its own full diplomatic ties with two powers that did not speak formally to one another, they wrote that `` the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should not fear the ending of its monopoly of the Big Three summit dialogue.'' Other experts note that since the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has entered a phase of improved relations with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, it would be expected that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> forge better ties with its own neighbor. `` This brings a balance into the -LRB- three-way -RRB- relationship,'' said another <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official, a specialist in <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> affairs who also asked not to be quoted by name. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s upcoming trip to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> _ and his assertion that he is not deploying `` a <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> card'' by flaunting relations with <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> over <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> _ demonstrates that the level of diplomacy among the three nations has reached a new plane. `` The need for each nation to play off one off another has markedly declined,'' the senior <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 1230EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Afghanistan-Defense Bjt   02-12 0603</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Afghanistan-Defense, Bjt,0621</SECOND>
<HEAD>Afghans Prepare to Defend Link to Outside World</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SHARON HERBAUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As the last Soviet troops prepare to leave <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, a key question remains: Can the Afghan air force keep open <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>'s airport, the capital's vital link to the outside world? Col. <PERSON> Pavel </PERSON> <PERSON> Vinokunov </PERSON>, commander of a small Soviet guard detachment at the airport, has no doubts. `` The Afghan pilots have been trained in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and have continued to study here with us,'' said <PERSON> Vinokunov </PERSON>, who has been in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> more than two years. `` They'll be able to handle it, no worse than we did.'' His words should be put to the test this week, sometime before Wednesday, the deadine for the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> to be out of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, a city of about 2 million, is surrounded by high mountain passes, which are relatively easy for the U.S.-backed rebels to block to cut the flow of goods to the capital. Winter snow and avalanches add to the problem of bringing in supplies. With no obvious end in sight to the 10-year-old civil war, the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> airport will be the key link to the rest of the world. The rebels are armed with sophisticated, heat-seeking missiles. The airport has not come under a rebel rocket attack in more than a month, and no airliner has been shot down over <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. But the threat has scared off all civilian aircraft except <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Ariana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airline </ORGANIZATION> and an occasional <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> plane On Sunday, though, a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> program to bring emergency supplies to the capital was interrupted when an <ORGANIZATION> Ethiopian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jet carrying the goods was ordered by the Ethiopian government not to fly in. Since early January, giant Soviet military transport planes have been airlifting daily hundreds of tons of flour to help ease food shortages in the capital. Helicopters circle the snow-covered mountains, searching for guerrillas and providing a screen of flares to deflect their heat-seeking missiles. `` We would like to give it all up right now and go home,'' said <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Kharenko </PERSON>, 26, of <LOCATION> Byelorussia </LOCATION>. `` But we'll finish the job. We'll help the Afghans. It's winter and things are rough. There's hunger in the city It's no secret.'' <PERSON> Vinokunov </PERSON> invited Western reporters to the airport to watch their operation and then to his quarters for tea, sausage, liver pate and vodka. The mujahedeen, as the Moslem rebels are called, say many in the air force are sympathetic to their cause and will not block the overthrow of President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>. Several Afghan pilots have defected to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, which supports the rebels. Foreign diplomats in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, however, say the air force is an elite ideologically motivated group that is closely watched by the ruling <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Afghanistan </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Rahman </PERSON>, a 27-year-old pilot who studied for three years in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, does not hide his feelings about the mujahedeen. `` They fire their rockets, but they do n't know where they will land. They have no way of being accurate,'' he said, standing with several <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> pilots next to a helicopter gunship. `` I like flying and I like to go out and meet them,'' said <PERSON> Rahman </PERSON>, nicknamed `` Eagle.'' `` I've seen these groups and wiped them out,'' he said as Soviet soldiers laughed and patted him on the back. `` I'm good at shooting them. Come for a ride with me and we'll find some to shoot at.'' The Soviet departure perhaps will have a psychological impact, but in practice, the <LOCATION> Afghan </LOCATION> air force already shepherds Afghan planes arriving in and leaving <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. `` Afraid of them? They are afraid of us,'' said <PERSON> Rahman </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890212-0030 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-12-89 1316EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Brown-Democrats     02-12 0359</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brown-Democrats,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Demo Leader Says Jackson Has ``Tremendous'' Leadership Qualities</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARTON REPPERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
