<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0551EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Boeing     11-18 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Boeing,0434</SECOND>
<HEAD>Talks Resume In Boeing Strike; Union Warns It Wants Movement</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM KLAHN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and Machinists are returning to the bargaining table Saturday, the 46th day of a strike that's idled production lines at the world's biggest commercial airplane builder `` I just felt it is time to get them back to the bargaining table,'' federal mediator <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> said of his call for the meeting. The face-to-face talks, which broke off Nov. 4, were set for 1:30 p.m. at <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON>'s offices. Meanwhile, the union representing engineering workers for <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> agreed Friday to extend its present labor contracts beyond their Dec. 1 expiration dates while negotiations continue. The contracts cover nearly 28,000 workers, who are represented by the <ORGANIZATION> Seattle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Professional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineering </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employees </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Agreement on the engineers' and professional workers' pacts, however, is not expected until there is a settlement in the Machinists' strike. While both <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> and the Machinists welcomed new talks, the union warned `` continued stonewalling by the company would lead to a continuation of the seven-week-old strike.'' The previous talks broke off after union leaders rejected a <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> offer that had a new look but the company conceded included no new money. The union accused <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> of trying to build up workers' hopes, then forcing a membership vote. <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> declined to say whether there was any change in either side's position. `` Our objective all along has been to get the 57,000 <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> employees back to work and the fact the meeting is called is hopefully a sign that we can get them back to work,'' he said. The strike, which began Oct. 4, on Saturday it becomes the second-longest strike in <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION>'s history, surpassing a 1977 work action that lasted 45 days. The longest, in 1948, lasted 140 days. The latest three-year offer from <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> included annual wage increases of 4 percent, 3 percent and 3 percent; annual bonuses of 10 percent of gross pay, 4 percent and 4 percent; a reduction in mandatory overtime from the current 200 hours a quarter to 144 hours by mid-1990, and across-the-board increases in retirement benefits. Machinists represent 57,000 <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> workers, including 43,000 in the <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> area, 12,000 in <LOCATION> Wichita </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, 1,700 in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, and a few hundred others at scattered sites in other states. Work on production lines has been severely curtailed by the strike, though <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> has said it is continuing with help of supervisory personnel and a few thousand machinists who crossed picket lines.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0553EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MovieTurkeys     11-18 0256</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Movie Turkeys,0262</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Inchon' Heads List of Decade's Most Disastrous Movies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` <LOCATION> Inchon </LOCATION>,'' the disastrous war epic produced by the Rev. <PERSON> Sung </PERSON> <PERSON> Myung </PERSON> <PERSON> Moon </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Unification </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, has been selected as the biggest box-office fiasco of the 1980s. In a list released Friday by the entertainment research firm <ORGANIZATION> Baseline </ORGANIZATION>, 1982's `` <LOCATION> Inchon </LOCATION>,'' with <PERSON> Laurence </PERSON> <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON> <PERSON> Bisset </PERSON>, was said to have cost an estimated $ 46 million but made less than $ 2 million at domestic movie theaters. The movie's net loss, $ 44.1 million, placed `` <LOCATION> Inchon </LOCATION>'' on top of Baseline's survey. `` Heaven's Gate,'' widely considered the greatest flop in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> history, landed in fourth place on the top-turkey index. Director <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON>, whose `` E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial'' is the all-time box-office champ, finished in a tie for 10th with `` Empire of the Sun.'' The list does not take into consideration ancillary revenues such as home video and overseas markets. The 10 most spectacular failures, in order: `` <LOCATION> Inchon </LOCATION>'' -LRB- $ 46 million cost, $ 1.9 million box office, $ 44.1 million loss -RRB-; `` The Adventures of Baron Munchausen'' -LRB- $ 52 million, $ 9 million, $ 43 million -RRB-; `` Ishtar'' -LRB- $ 45 million, $ 7.7 million, $ 37.3 million -RRB-; `` Heaven's Gate'' -LRB- $ 36 million, $ 1.5 million, $ 34.5 million -RRB-; `` The <ORGANIZATION> Cotton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>'' -LRB- $ 46 million, $ 15 million, $ 31 million -RRB-. `` Pirates'' -LRB- $ 31 million, $ 700,000, $ 30.3 million -RRB-; `` Rambo III'' -LRB- $ 58 million, $ 28 million, $ 30 million -RRB-; `` Santa Claus'' -LRB- $ 45 million, $ 16 million, $ 29 million -RRB-; `` Lion of the Desert'' -LRB- $ 30 million, $ 1.5 million, $ 28.5 million -RRB-; `` Empire of the Sun'' -LRB- $ 38 million, $ 10.5 million, $ 27.5 million -RRB-; `` Once Upon a Time in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'' -LRB- $ 30 million, $ 2.5 million, $ 27.5 million -RRB-.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0224EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Rats     11-18 0172</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Rats,0176</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rats Devour Precious Grain</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DHAKA, Bangladesh (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rats devour or destroy nearly a half-million tons of grain in <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION> each year, enough to feed at least 3 million people in this impoverished nation, a newspaper said. The destruction begins in farms and continues up to the dining table, the Bengali-language newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Dainik </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bangla </ORGANIZATION> said Friday, quoting agricultural experts. The rats destroy about 100,000 tons of grain in stores alone. More than 480,000 tons of rice and wheat _ 2.5 percent of the country's total grain production _ is lost to the rodents annually, the paper said. <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION>, one of the poorest nations in the world with an annual per capita income of $ 160, produces about 19 million tons of rice and wheat a year. The nation of 110 million people imports 1.6 million tons to 3 million tons of grain to meet yearly shortfalls. The rat population reaches its peak during November and December when winter crops are harvested. During those months, authorities launch an annual rat-killing campaign.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0627EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--TreasureAuction     11-18 0192</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Treasure Auction,0198</SECOND>
<HEAD>Treasure From Sunken Galleon to be Auctioned</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Hariot is cq in 4th graf.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GAINESVILLE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rare silver coins, uncut emeralds and a 70-pound silver bar from a sunken Spanish galleon are among items to be auctioned to raise money for citrus research and 4-H programs. The treasure is just part of the hoard brought up from the <LOCATION> Nuestra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Senora </LOCATION> de Atocha off Key West by treasure hunter <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> in 1985. The items were donated by two couples who got them in return for their investments in <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Treasure </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Salvors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>. Organizers of the auction, scheduled for Dec. 2 in <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION>, wo n't disclose the estimated value of the treasure The donors are <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyon </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> historian specializing in the Spanish colonial period, his wife, <PERSON> Dotie </PERSON>, and by <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Greene </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Hariot </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Lyon </LOCATION> uncovered records in the Archive of the Indies in <LOCATION> Seville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, that provided valuable clues in <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON>'s search for the treasure ship <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> will be the guest of honor at the auction. Proceeds will go to the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> 4-H programs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0603EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Germany-SecretPolice     11-18 0176</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Germany-Secret Police,0179</SECOND>
<HEAD>Secret Police to Answer to Parliament; 5,000 to Lose Jobs</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-East Germany, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EAST BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s dreaded secret police, who attacked pro-democracy protesters last month, will have a new head, will soon answer to <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> and will be reduced by 5,000 employees, officials say. The <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION>, previously under direct control of the General Prosecutor's Office and the ruling Politburo, is in charge of interior security and counter-intelligence. Many East Germans fear its agents, who often have been charged with spying on citizens. The state-run news agency <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> announced the changes late Friday. Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Wolfgang </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwanitz </PERSON>, the new head of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION>, said `` We welcome the control of Parliament ... and will do everything to win its trust.'' `` We're leaving everything behind that in the past was inappropriate or mistaken,'' <PERSON> Schwanitz </PERSON> said in an indirect reference to past excesses, such as the beating of peaceful demonstrators. He said the department would now concentrate on counter-terrorism, investigations of `` imperialist espionage'' and neo-Nazi activities.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0603EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     11-18 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0088</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 18; 21; 27; 34; 39; 43.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 6-5-1-5.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 01; 05; 10; 22; 23; 28.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 07; 10; 26; 32; 36; 39. Bonus: 42332.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday 54 Lotto Game: 09; 18; 23; 26; 33; 43. Supplementary 36.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 9-1-3-0.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 2-7-4; 6-6-1-3; 0-2-6-7-7; 8-7-1-5-6-9.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0556EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-IranArms     11-18 0332</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iran Arms,0341</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jury Finds Swede Guilty of Smuggling Arms to Iran</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CORPUS CHRISTI, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal jury Friday found a Swedish businessman guilty of smuggling military hardware to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in violation of the federal Arms Export Control Act. The jury also found <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Erik </PERSON> <PERSON> Nissen </PERSON>, 62, guilty of conspiracy and money laundering. He and two Canadians were arrested by <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> agents who set up a fake company for the investigation. Jurors found <PERSON> Nissen </PERSON> innocent of three money laundering charges. The jury deliberated all day Thursday and for three hours Friday before reaching a verdict. Prosecutors said he faces up to 27 years in prison and fines of up to $ 1 million when sentenced in January. <PERSON> Nissen </PERSON>, a resident of <LOCATION> Norrkoping </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, was arrested May 25 and indicted in connection with the alleged conspiracy to ship military jet parts to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> without a proper <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> license. <PERSON> Nissen </PERSON>'s alleged co-conspirators, <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Hilton </PERSON> <PERSON> Arab </PERSON>, 52, and <PERSON> Eileen </PERSON> <PERSON> Audrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Arab </PERSON>, 52, both of <LOCATION> Vancouver </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, pleaded guilty to similar charges in October and agreed to testify against <PERSON> Nissen </PERSON>. They will be sentenced next month. The three were caught in an undercover investigation by <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> agents who set up a bogus business at <ORGANIZATION> Corpus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airport </ORGANIZATION>. The government accused <PERSON> Nissen </PERSON> and the Arabs of smuggling 13 air pressure control devices for F-4C Phantom jet fighters. The devices were delivered to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in March, officials said. The government said a separate $ 4.7 million deal was in the works when <PERSON> Nissen </PERSON> and the Arabs were arrested. <PERSON> Nissen </PERSON> maintained that he was a legitimate broker and unaware the transactions were illegal. `` Mr. <PERSON> Nissen </PERSON> is one of those persons who saw <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> after the revolution -LRB- in 1979 -RRB- as a land of opportunity,'' federal prosecutor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Berg </PERSON> said in his closing argument Thursday. `` He got a copy, one way or the other, of an Iranian wish list.'' Defense attorney <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> May </PERSON> argued that <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Arab </PERSON>, not <PERSON> Nissen </PERSON>, was the `` con man'' of the alleged scheme.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Indians Bjt   11-18 0568</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Indians, Bjt,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Panel Recommends Tribal Self-Government</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials say they realize the federal government has mishandled Indian affairs and welcome a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> report that recommends allowing tribes to govern themselves. `` Quite clearly the federal government in the past has not been as efficient, as careful or as caring as it should have been in a number of instances,'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Bracken </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> undersecretary, said Friday. But he said the department already has begun to correct problems identified in a 238-page report released by a special investigating panel of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Indian Affairs. The report summarizes a two-year investigation into government corruption relating to Indians. It recommends that the federal bureaucracy be broken apart to allow tribes interested in self-determination to negotiate for grants from the federal government much the same way as do states and local governments. `` Fraud, mismanagement and corruption pervade virtually all federal Indian programs,'' Sen. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ariz </LOCATION>., chairman of the special committee He said the committee's work showed that many tribes are capable of managing their own affairs. He said federal Indian agencies should continue to exist for tribes that want the services, but in time all tribes would see the benefits of self-government, `` assuring that the billions now wasted on self-perpetuating federal bureaucracies will belong to tribes themselves, to determine their own destiny.'' `` In all, the federal budget for Indian programs equals $ 3.3 billion annually. Yet, surprisingly little of these funds reach the <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> people,'' <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON> said. Under the committee's proposal, the federal government would provide an annual grant to each tribe, equal to the tribe's proportional share of the current federal Indian budget It would be a permanent entitlement, in lieu of federal services from the Bureau of Indian Affairs or other agencies. The tribes would have to be accountable for the funds and tribal officials negotiating the agreements would have to be proven representatives of their tribes. `` I have not yet consulted with <PERSON> Indian </PERSON> tribes about the recommendations contained in this report and will withhold any final comment pending consultation,'' said <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> BIA </ORGANIZATION>. But he said he agreed with the report's finding that `` we must take real actions and not merely offer Band-Aid solutions.'' Rep. <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Nighthorse </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, D-Colo., the only native American in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, joined <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON> and Sens <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>., <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Daschle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.D. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>, in announcing the proposals `` Two hundred years of mistakes in dealing with the American Indian can only lead to more of the same without drastic reform,'' <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> said. The lawmakers said it would take a long time to put the proposals into action, but that they would draw up legislation soon and that <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Indian Affairs, would hold extensive hearings. Rep. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>, D-Ariz., who chairs the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said he had reviewed the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> report and would work with <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON> on legislation The special committee, appointed by <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>, held more than four weeks of hearings last winter and spring. The committee staff visited more than 70 Indian tribes in 16 states, conducted about 2,000 interviews and analyzed more than 1 million documents. The panel examined contracting fraud, gaming operations on reservations, child sexual abuse in federal schools, protection of natural resources belonging to the Indians, housing, the <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and corruption among tribal officials.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0604EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-L'AmourLegacy     11-18 0253</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-L'Amour Legacy,0260</SECOND>
<HEAD>Western Writer Leaves Legacy of Unpublished Work</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Western novelist <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> L'Amour </PERSON> is dead, but he may ride high on the best-seller lists for years thanks to unpublished and out-of-print work. `` We have a couple of full-length novels and we have some -LRB- unpublished -RRB- short story material and we have short story material that was written for the pulps,'' <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> L'Amour </PERSON>, the author's wife of 32 years, said recently. `` So we're in good shape and we'll have a publishing program well into the'90s,'' she said. <PERSON> L'Amour </PERSON>, a favorite of former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, died of cancer in June 1988 at age 80. The unpublished works are from what he called his `` toxic dump'' _ piles of papers stacked haphazardly on the floor and desk of his workroom. `` I took about seven days of randomly walking around and randomly sampling stuff to try and find if there was any order or not,'' said the author's son, <PERSON> Beau </PERSON>, 28. `` After that week I just decided there was n't any order.'' <PERSON> L'Amour </PERSON>'s `` Education of a Wandering Man,'' published a few weeks ago, is on the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> bestseller lists for hardcover nonfiction books. He was proofreading the memoir the day he died. It was his 105th published book, including 86 novels, 16 collections of short stories and three non-fiction books. A hardcover book, `` The <ORGANIZATION> Sackett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Companion </ORGANIZATION>,'' and two paperback collections of short stories, `` Lonigan'' and `` Long Ride Home,'' also have been published since his death.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0600EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AbortionBill Bjt   11-18 0372</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion Bill, Bjt,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Abortion Rights Bill Introduced</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Abortion-rights supporters say they are setting the stage for next year's congressional battle with a bill that would write into law the 1973 <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <ORGANIZATION> Wade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling that legalized abortion. `` This bill is going to be the rallying point,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Claudine </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON>, R-R.I. Bills were introduced in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on Friday that would effectively overcome the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision last summer in the so-called <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> case that gave states greater authority to restrict abortions, supporters said. Just a few lines long, the bill would forbid states from restricting a woman's right to have an abortion before the time her fetus becomes viable for life outside the womb, or at any time when necessary to protect the life of the mother. A leader of the abortion opponents, Rep. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.J. </LOCATION>, said he welcomed the bill because it would bring a full debate on abortion. He said he was confident the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> would defeat it. `` I hope they bring the bill to the floor very quickly,'' he said. `` The question will then be very squarely: ` Will we permit abortion on demand for the whole nine months of pregnancy?''' Although no action was expected until next year, abortion-rights backers said the bill would become the central focus of future congressional and political debate on the abortion issue. The House bill had 88 sponsors, and a version introduced in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> carried 19 sponsors. The bill was aimed at writing into law the landmark 1973 <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> decision establishing a woman's right to an abortion and at reversing the Webster ruling. Abortion-rights supporters contend the <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> decision eroded rights established 16 years earlier and signaled a possible further erosion in future high court decisions. The <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> decision, however, has energized abortion-rights leaders and raised the temperature of the abortion debate in many states. Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON>, R-Ore., an abortion-rights supporter, predicted passage by both the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> but acknowledged backers probably would not be able to override a presidential veto President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is appearing in <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> on Monday at an event for <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON>, despite their differences on abortion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0558EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     11-18 0792</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0826</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> says he's been looking for a new movie script, but he does n't like the parts he's been offered. `` I keep turning scripts down because they're for grouchy grandfathers,'' <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> told fans Thursday at the Tattered Cover Bookstore. `` They do n't have to be grouchy.'' <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, 81, was promoting his book, `` <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> and His Poems,'' a collection of anecdotes and poetry that he recited on `` The Tonight Show.'' He could n't name any writer he considered a great influence on his literary efforts. `` I'm just a newborn poet. I do n't have any,'' <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> signed 300 to 350 books while several hundred fans gathered to get a glimpse of him.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fats </ORGANIZATION> inspired `` The Hustler,'' and now an investor wants to cash in on the current pool craze by naming a sports bar after Fats. `` Pool is getting to be the biggest thing in the world today,'' said Fats, whose real name is <PERSON> Rudolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Wanderone </PERSON> and who is believed to be 76. `` Now they are opening pool rooms as fast as they can. I'm talking multimillion-dollar joints.'' Fats' agent, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Kastle </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Tri-Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, said $ 750,000 is being sought in investment capital for the bar, which would feature many square yards of green felt. <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Gleason </PERSON> portrayed <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fats </ORGANIZATION> in the 1961 movie, `` The Hustler,'' starring <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>. Fats has lived in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> for five years.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ST. CLOUD, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rock musician <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Henley </PERSON>, TV talk show host <PERSON> Geraldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Twins </ORGANIZATION> third baseman <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaetti </PERSON> took part in a radio broadcast to raise money to find <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> <PERSON> Wetterling </PERSON> and other missing children. The marathon 27 -LCB- - hour broadcast on stations KXSS-FM in St Cloud and WLOL-FM in <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> ended Friday morning with more than $ 70,000 pledged for the <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> <PERSON> Wetterling </PERSON> Fund and two missing children's groups, the stations said. <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> <PERSON> Wetterling </PERSON> was seized by a masked gunman the night of Oct. 22 while he was out riding bikes with his brother and a friend. <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> <PERSON> Gigler </PERSON> said coverage of the Wetterling abduction Thursday on the `` <PERSON> Geraldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON>'' show prompted about 75 calls from the public. The show was taped by satellite Nov. 9 at the <ORGANIZATION> Wetterlings </ORGANIZATION>' home. <PERSON> Patty </PERSON> <PERSON> Wetterling </PERSON>, the boy's mother, later said she was upset with the makers of the show because they focused on statistics that showed most abducted children are abused and never seen again.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>KINGSTON, Jamaica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three members of the Atlantis space shuttle crew were scheduled to travel to <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> on Monday to meet Prime Minister <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Manley </PERSON> and talk to schoolchildren about life in space. Tourism Minister <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Pringle </PERSON> said mission commander Capt. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, mission pilot Cmdr. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> McCulley </PERSON> and mission specialist <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> Chang-Diaz </PERSON> accepted his invitation to visit the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> island with their families for a four-day visit.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Rolling Stones `` Steel Wheels'' tour will hit The Boardwalk next month in a multimillion-dollar deal with a gaming hall owned by developer <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>. The show is being billed as `` Rolling Stones and Friends,'' and casino executives hint many celebrities wll accompany the rock' n' roll band on stage Tickets went on sale Friday at $ 38.50 each for performances Dec. 17, 19 and 20 at the city's Convention Center. The Dec. 19 show will be broadcast live on a pay-per-view basis around the country, said <PERSON> Bernie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dillon </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Trumps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sports </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> vice president.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge wo n't rule until next month on a lawsuit brought by former Beatle <PERSON> Ringo </PERSON> <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> against a music producer. <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> won a permanent injunction from <LOCATION> Fulton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Judge <PERSON> Clarence </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> blocking release of an album he did in 1987 and wanted kept off the market because he was drinking heavily during its production. After testimony ended Friday in the non-jury trial, court officials said <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> would n't rule until December on whether <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> owes <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, producer Chips Moman $ 146,239 for studio costs and expenses. <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> said Wednesday there was no formal agreement and that he understood he would not have to pay the studio expenses unless the album were released. <PERSON> Moman </PERSON> contended he and <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> agreed to a three-album deal.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ROCHESTER, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Vice President <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> is joining the <ORGANIZATION> Mayo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trustees </ORGANIZATION>. Mondale, a partner in the <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> law firm of <PERSON> Dorsey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON>, was elected to a four-year term on the 30-member board at a meeting Friday. The board is composed of public representatives and <ORGANIZATION> Mayo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clinic </ORGANIZATION> physicians and administrators. <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> served as vice president in the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> administration after serving 12 years in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Senate. He was the Democratic presidential candidate in 1984.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0557EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Germany-Church     11-18 0738</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Germany-Church,0760</SECOND>
<HEAD>Church Becomes Unwitting Center of Revolution</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-East Germany, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALISON SMALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LEIPZIG, East Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuehrer </PERSON> started regular Monday prayers for peace at his church, Nikolaikirche, back in 1982, he never dreamed they would one day be the kernel of a revolution. Fuehrer, vicar of one of central <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION>'s most historic churches, was one of the thousands of East Germans and millions of West Germans who believed medium-range missiles should not be stationed in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> to counter Soviet SS-20s. The small peace movement in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> then centered largely on its Protestant church, the only institution in the country independent of the Communist authorities. Fuehrer, a quietly determined 46-year-old father of four, started `` peace prayers'' every Monday. Dozens, even hundreds, came. But once <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> missiles were stationed, Fuehrer recalls, disillusioned East Germans stopped coming to the Monday prayers and attendance sank to just ten. Things changed early in 1988, when East German police arrested dozens of youths bold enough to celebrate in their own way at an official ceremony honoring <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON> <PERSON> Luxembourg </PERSON> and <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Liebknecht </PERSON>, heroes of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s failed communist revolution in 1918. `` Many people came, asking to pray for those who were arrested,'' Fuehrer said in an interview. `` And it was there that I first heard from people with problems, who were waiting to leave the country.'' Then, the wait could take two or three years. People who had applied to emigrate West faced obstacles at work, in schools, even at home. They needed counseling, and they found it in Fuehrer's Nikolaikirche, where the motto is that the church is `` offen fuer alle'' -LRB- open for all -RRB- `` Really, we were a substitute for the state,'' Fuehrer said. `` But the state was not ready for, or capable of any dialogue.'' Despite harassment from the authorities, Fuehrer kept counseling the would-be emigres, and providing shelter for small alternative groups such as those concerned with cleaning up <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION>'s heavy polluted environment. `` Now, I've taken down the posters for New Forum,'' <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s largest opposition movement, Fuehrer noted. `` They have a place of their own now. My philosophy is, political parties have no place in church. But if they have no other place to go, then the church will offer them protection.'' By May 7 of this year, <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION>'s authorities had enough of the Monday prayers. Police cordons were thrown up around the church and everyone who attended was registered. In a sign of mounting popular discontent, however, the repression backfired. Curious passers-by stood behind the police cordons, and gradually became interested in the Monday service, forcing Fuehrer to ask other <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION> churches to arrange similar sessions to get people off the street. But the crowds kept growing, irritating the Communist authorities. Under pressure from a mass exodus of tens of thousands of young people through <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, the government started to crack down hard on dissent. On Oct. 7, the nation's 40th anniversary, police in <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION> and other cities beat hundreds of pro-democracy demonstrators in what Fuehrer saw as a `` dress rehearsal'' for a move against his Monday service and spontaneous marches afterwards. Two days later, the attempt was made. After Fuehrer refused to bow to threats of prosecution, the local <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> sent about a thousand of its members to church. The Communists intended to fill most of the 2,000 seats hours before the service began. Again, the tactic backfired. Fuehrer hurriedly asked two other churches to open for prayer, then went ahead and held his own regular session. What Fuehrer calls the next `` miracle'' of that day occurred during the service. A message arrived from three Communist functionaries and <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazur </PERSON>, conductor of <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION>'s famed Gewandhaus orchestra, saying they supported peaceful demostrations. This encouraged the congregation to join a crowd of tens of thousands outside in a peaceful march, despite a strong presence of police and special anti-riot forces. `` You had the impression that a world war, or at the very least a civil war, was on its way,'' Fuehrer said of the security forces. `` But in the end there was no violence,'' and <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s peaceful revolution was born Now, hundreds of thousands of people seeking free elections march through <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION>'s streets every Monday after the `` peace prayers.'' `` Without the church, the demonstrations would not have been possible,'' Fuehrer noted. `` But we did n't organize them. I never imagined, of course, where the peace prayers might lead.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0559EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-EasternEurope Bjt   11-18 0624</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Eastern Europe, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Consults Western Leaders About US-Soviet Summit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, steering clear of the controversial subject of German reunification, is making a concerted show of consulting with Western leaders before his shipboard summit with Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. The White House issued a statement Friday saying <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had called French President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> and Canadian Prime Minister <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> on Friday, and had received a call from West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>. Another statement was issued later to report <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had called <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> and to say they will continue their talks when they meet next Friday at Camp <PERSON> David </PERSON>, the presidential retreat in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Catoctin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>. The leaders talked about the meeting this weekend of European leaders on the fast-moving developments in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s summit with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> Dec. 2 and 3 on ships off the coast of <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>, the White House said. The calls seemed designed to ease European concerns that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was going to meet <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> without the benefit of advice from <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> allies. Preparing for the summit, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was to meet at Camp David today with two groups of academic and think-tank experts on Soviet politics and <LOCATION> East-West </LOCATION> relations. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also held a round of pre-summit talks Friday, meeting at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> with four former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassadors to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>: <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Toon </PERSON>, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Watson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartman </PERSON>. In a radio interview aired today by Mutual and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> brushed aside fears about the possibility of German reunification, saying, `` I do n't think history need repeat itself if there evolves a single German state.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said reunification is `` a matter for the people of the Germanies to determine. And it is a very _ it's a highly sensitive matter as far as the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is concerned. And it's better to leave it right there.'' The opening of the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall has prompted talk about a reunified <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, which has been divided into East and West since the end of World War II. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has said that talk about reunification would mean interference in the affairs of the two Germanies. Moreover, there is nervousness in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> about restoring <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> to full strength, since a militarily strong <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> was at the center of two world wars in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> this century. In another development, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sent a cable to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> expressing hopes for `` a calm and peaceful period of change'' in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, responding to a virtually identical message from <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> a week earlier, indicated his support for the dramatic changes in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and reforms under way in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, said White House Press Secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. A senior administration official said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would not agree at the summit to look the other way in case the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> deems it necessary to crack down against labor unrest and citizens' unhappiness over expected food shortages this winter `` This American president, like his predecessors, will have no understanding for the violent suppression of man's desire for freedom, period,'' the official said, insisting on anonymity. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, welcomed recent political changes in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION>. Department spokeswoman <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> said the formation of a new Cabinet containing 11 non-communist members `` could be a first step'' toward meeting the East German people's demands for democratic reform. She said those demands could not be met fully without free elections. Ms. <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> also applauded the dismissal Thursday of three hardline Politburo members in <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION> and the installation of four officials who are likely to support new <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mladenov </PERSON>. She called it `` an encouraging sign'' that <PERSON> Mladenov </PERSON> has `` the will and the ability to carry out needed reforms.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0600EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CableTV     11-18 0453</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cable TV,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cable TV Has `Unrestricted Monopoly,' Broadcasters Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT GREENE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cable television companies enjoy an `` unrestricted monopoly'' that lets them overcharge customers and seize control of sports programs, broadcast competitors contend. The criticism came Friday from independent and network broadcasters at a hearing of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION>'s communications subcommittee on the regulation of the cable TV industry. The broadcasters say cable television operators pay nothing for 72 percent of the programming viewed by their customers because it is supplied by networks and independent stations. At the same time, the broadcasters contend, the cable industry programmers favorably treat the local cable outlets while charging excessive rates to others. Five companies serve 42 percent of cable households in the country and rates rose 29 percent in the first two years of deregulation starting in 1987, according to the critics. In addition, they say, the same companies that produce cable programs also have the cable systems, giving them control of `` conduit and content.'' `` Cable's unrestricted monopoly operations _ its nearly free use of the compulsory license, and its use of a triple revenue stream of subscription rates, advertising and pay-per-view _ has led to a completely distorted marketplace,'' said <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fritts </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasters </ORGANIZATION>, which represents the networks. The cable industry disputed those contentions, saying rates jumped after being kept artificially low by local regulation. It said rates are now rising at a lower rate than inflation. The industry, through the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, also claims that cable helps networks by extending their reach and improving their signals. The cable industry also says it has increased the amount of sports programming available and blames the team owners for jacking up the bids. <PERSON> Fritts </PERSON>' group supports legislation proposed by Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON>, R-Mo., that would re-regulate the cable industry, which was basically de-regulated by the 1984 Cable Act <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON>'s bill would allow cities to regulate cable rates unless cable companies had effective local competition and would make it easier for cities to revoke the franchises of cable operators who do not serve the community well. <PERSON> Preston </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Padden </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stations </ORGANIZATION>, claimed that cable is monopolizing sports television. He showed the subcommittee a <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> billboard warning, `` No Cable, No <PERSON> Gretzky </PERSON>, No Cable, No Magic,'' a reference to stars <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Gretzky </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kings </ORGANIZATION> hockey team and <PERSON> Magic </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Lakers </ORGANIZATION> basketball team. He also complained that such sports siphoning was occurring in college conference sports. <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> McReynolds </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the cable industry group, acknowledged that there have been `` a few instances'' where sports events have been moved to cable.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0605EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Sandinistas-Contras     11-18 0443</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sandinistas-Contras,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Agreement on Truce Not Close as Talks Recess</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Peace talks between the Nicaraguan government and the Contra rebels resume on Monday with the two sides at an apparent impasse over terms for reviving a cease-fire. During the seventh day of discussions on Friday, the Sandinista government remained adamant in its insistence on a full withdrawal of Contra forces from <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> to base camps in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. For its part, the <LOCATION> Nicaraguan </LOCATION> resistance stood firm in refusing to consider even a partial withdrawal of the estimated 5,000 Contras deployed in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> mediators were spending the weekend drafting a revised working document for presentation to the negotiators when they resume their discussions here on Monday at the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION>. President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> suspended the cease-fire on Nov. 1, citing what he described as Contra terrorist activities. He has said the Feb. 25 national elections will go ahead as planned even if no truce agreement is reached. After a two-hour negotiating session Friday, <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> Vice Foreign Minister <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> warned that a cease-fire in place, as proposed by the Contras, would create in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> a situation similar to that in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> where truces have never taken hold. `` We consider that an effective cease-fire in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> means a separation of forces, and a separation of forces means all the Contras to withdraw with their arms to their camps in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> said. `` Otherwise, there will be no cease-fire.'' Contra spokesman <PERSON> Bosco </PERSON> <PERSON> Matamoros </PERSON> said such a retreat would leave the rebels at a disadvantage. `` Once our forces have withdrawn from certain areas, the government forces have taken advantage to move there in force, deploy huge amounts of weapons, huge amounts of forces, to repress our civilian supporters,'' he said. After two days of talks at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> and five more here, <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION> said there are `` substantial differences'' but noted that both sides are willing to continue the negotiations. <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> also ruled out the possibility of reaching a compromise by allowing the Contras to redeploy in designated enclaves inside <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, subject to international inspection. He said the Nicaraguan terrain does n't lend itself to such a solution because much of the country is heavily wooded and the rebels would have the ability to move in and out of the enclaves undetected. The enclave concept, he said, `` has never functioned in human history.'' <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> mediator <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Zela </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> resorted to understatement in characterizing the status of the talks. He said there are `` some discrepancies'' between the two sides. But, he added, `` the fact that we are continuing signifies progress.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador-Rights     11-18 0575</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador-Rights,0596</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.N. Report Says Torture, Political Repression Rising in El Salvador</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER JAMES SPIELMANN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> report says <PERSON> El </PERSON> <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON>'s government presided over a `` resurgence of torture'' this year that included sexual abuse and beatings of prisoners and summary executions of political opponents The annual report was released Friday, a day after eight people, six of them Jesuit priests, were slain in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Pastor </PERSON> <PERSON> Ridruejo </PERSON>, special representative of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said in the report he `` is again extremely disturbed by the number and seriousness of the human rights violations committed thus far in 1989, particularly by the resurgence of torture. `` Members of the state apparatus, particularly of the armed forces, have carried out politically motivated summary executions whose exact numbers can not be determined but are generally comparable to those for last year.'' Pastor also castigated leftist rebels for kidnappings and assassinations. President <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON>, who took office June 1, said his rightist government was not involved in the Jesuit slayings, which took place amid the biggest rebel offensive in the 10-year-old war. The killings fit a pattern of rising repression, torture and political violence perpetrated by uniformed soldiers, as documented in Pastor's report. The Roman Catholic church's Archdiocesan Legal Protection office said 50 people were killed through August, and the government's <ORGANIZATION> Salvadoran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> said 68 people have been killed However, hundreds of others have been slain by unidentified assassins, or have disappeared. About 250 people were detained for political offenses as of Oct. 14, Pastor said, `` a much higher figure than the previous year.'' Non-governmental organizations that contacted Pastor in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> during his visit Oct. 8-14 `` complained about a marked increase in the torture of political prisoners by their interrogators,'' he said. `` Witnesses belonging to organizations invariably made roughly the same statement: Long periods of interrogation while blindfolded and without being able to sit down or rest, extensive beatings, continuous use of a hood which impedes breathing and causes fainting, electric shocks in water tanks, use of drugs and acids, and on many occasions rape and sexual abuse of both women and men, as well as threat to family members,'' <PERSON> Pastor </PERSON> said. `` Witnesses who did not belong to organizations complained of psychological ill-treatment and sometimes of beatings and death threats to themselves or to members of their families,'' he said. The government told him detainees were blindfolded to prevent them from recognizing their interrogators but denied there was systematic use of torture. Salvadoran authorities said the claims of torture were `` orchestrated'' by the rebels of the <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>. Pastor found that `` thus far in 1989, government action against trade unions and peasant and other organizations has increased. The government claims that some of these organizations answer to <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION>. `` The organizations concerned deny this, although independent Salvadoran sources have indicated ... that in some cases ... the activities of some organizations are not entirely independent of <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. Pastor blamed the rebels for assassinating alleged collaborators with the armed forces, soldiers, officials and ideological opponents. He said individuals have been abducted by the guerrillas, and probably by government-sanctioned death squads, and are still missing. El Salvador only recently emerged from a period of repression during which death squads and rightist elements of the military were accused of killing thousands of people. The Salvadoran right considers church activists and church intellectuals to be subversives.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0608EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CivilRights     11-18 0513</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Civil Rights,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>22-Month Extension of Civil Rights Panel En Route to Bush's Desk</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Legislation extending the life of the troubled <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> for almost two years is headed for President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s desk after winning final approval from the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. `` They're on probation over there for the next 22 months,'' Rep. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, D-Calif., said Friday as the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved the measure, 389-0 The measure, a compromise reached Thursday night between the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, would prevent the commission from going out of business on Nov. 30 when its charter runs out. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration had sought to put the panel out of business for one day only _ allowing <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to dump the members and engage in what Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wis </LOCATION>., called `` a complete housecleaning. The commission then would have been reauthorized for six years. A Democratic version passed by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday would have kept the commission in business for only six more months, buying time for an overhaul by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> designed to end the panel's infighting and other problems The compromise provides for no housecleaning, but <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will have a chance to appoint two new commissioners, including the chairman, and a staff director by the end of the year. <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON> noted, however, that the rest of the panel would remain intact, `` including two commissioners who have been at the center of the personality disputes that have dragged the commission into disrepute.'' He did not specify which commissioners he had in mind, although former Chairman <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, still a member of the panel, has been under fire for delivering before a conservative group a speech titled: `` Blacks? Animals? Homosexuals? What is a Minority?'' <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, who is black, says that he is the only conservative on the commission and that he does not believe `` in coddling people.'' At a recent <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> meeting, <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON> complained that commission member <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Berry </PERSON> has been making `` bizarre'' remarks. In the 1960s, the commission was lauded by civil rights forces for its hearings across the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, its ringing reports on racial injustice and its bold legislative proposals. Over the last six years, however, that atmosphere on the panel has soured, according to lawmakers of both parties. A report from the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> in 1986 found political, financial and other problems on the panel but they `` have never been addressed by the commission,'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. A statement issued Friday by the office of Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, D-Ill., said the commission had been `` mired in controversy for much of the last nine years, leading many in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to question whether it should be kept alive when its charter expires. `` This is a new lease on life for the commission, and I hope it's put to good use,'' <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> said. `` It's a long enough lease to give the president the chance he deserves to steer a new course for the commission, and it's a short enough lease to give <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> a chance to take another look later.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0608EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Satellite'sDemise     11-18 0453</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Satellite's Demise,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Solar Maximum Maxed Out</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Solar Maximum satellite, with most of its instruments shut down, is expected to fall to <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> by the end of the month. The satellite, which has been sending back information about the sun for nearly 10 years, was repaired by a visiting space shuttle crew in 1984. But now it has run out of fuel to power the rockets that have kept it out of the grip of <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>'s atmosphere. `` They are projecting Nov. 29, give or take a few days,'' said <PERSON> Randee </PERSON> <PERSON> Exler </PERSON>, spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s Goddard Space Flight Center. A few weeks ago, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> said three big chunks of the satellite might survive the fiery trip through the atmosphere and crash to <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. But Ms. <PERSON> Exler </PERSON> said there are estimates that as many as 11 pieces might survive. `` There will be debris, but we feel confident that most will be small pieces,'' she said. The satellite's path is 70 percent over water. Solar <PERSON> Max </PERSON> flies over much of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and the southernmost tip of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The only portions of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> under its track are <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, the extreme southern part of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. For weeks, the satellite's altitude has been dropping steadily. On Friday, <PERSON> Solar </PERSON> <PERSON> Max </PERSON>'s orbit was 177 miles high, a 25.7 mile drop since Oct. 31. It fell 2.6 miles since Thursday. Engineers turned off fine-pointing instruments and the spacecraft went into a `` safe hold.'' Scientific operations did n't cease completely; three instruments still were taking and sending data Even at the end, the satellite will perform useful service. Engineers will try to blow off its solar panels, an exercise that would be required if such a satellite were to be put into a space shuttle cargo bay for return to <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. Once the panels are gone, all work will cease. Solar Max cost $ 77 million to build and launch in February 1980, at a time of maximum activity in the sun's 11-year sunspot cycle. Its mission was to study solar flares. But after 10 months of service, three fuses blew in the satellite's attitude control box and it was unable to point itself accurately. That, in turn, caused four onboard instruments to fail. In 1984, the shuttle Challenger pulled alongside Solar <PERSON> Max </PERSON> and astronaut <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> reached out and grabbed it with the ship's robot arm The next day, two astronauts working in the open cargo bay replaced the control system module and an electronics box. The satellite has been working well since then. For a time there were plans to reboost it to a higher orbit but that would have set back other missions and the idea was abandoned.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Walesa 3rdLd-Writethru a0786 11-18 0793</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Walesa, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0786,0813</SECOND>
<HEAD>Walesa Spends Whirlwind Day In New York</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 6th graf, `Walesa was...,' to UPDATE with arrival in Chicago.
^LaserPhotos NY27,30</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICK HAMPSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Polish Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> went through a whirlwind series of meetings Friday with union officials, <PERSON> Jewish </PERSON> leaders, politicians and businessmen, and paused to praise American generosity. He told a group of state union leaders that as he was listening to speeches that preceded his own, he came to appreciate what he termed `` the greatness of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' In <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, he said, `` We fight, we risk, but you are in a different situation. You do n't have to fight, you do n't have to share with us, you do n't have to help us. `` But this is not the way you behave. I thought, ` Would I behave as you do? Would I be seeing this as clearly?''' The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted Tuesday to authorize $ 657 million in economic aid to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> over three years. On Thursday the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> went further, approving a three-year package of $ 846.5 million. After a full day of meetings in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> flew to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> late Friday, arriving at <LOCATION> Midway </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> at 11 p.m. CST. A crowd of about 100 people, many of them Polish-Americans who painted signs of welcome, applauded as he stepped of a plane into blowing snow and ice-cold temperatures. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>'s meeting with <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> state labor leaders began a day that included other sessions with Jewish leaders, newspaper editors and businessmen. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> also met Friday with <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>, who said: `` We hardly know the man. ... But we cheer him for all the wonderful ideas he represents.'' <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> announced plans by <ORGANIZATION> Harper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Row to publish a collection of <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>'s speeches and writings on democracy in Polish and English next year. <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> said he conceived of the `` Lincoln on Democracy Project'' during a meeting in June with teachers from <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> who told him books on <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> were not available in their country. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> thanked <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> for the Lincoln project and alluded to the speed of political change throughout <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>: `` I do n't know if you can keep pace with translations for other languages because the line is already forming.'' <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> met with about 75 Jewish leaders, several of them survivors of the <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> campaign to exterminate Polish Jews. One, <PERSON> Reuben </PERSON> <PERSON> Gruenbaum </PERSON>, told <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> of life at <LOCATION> Auschwitz </LOCATION>, where he was an inmate and where his parents and grandparents were killed. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said he hoped for resolution of a controversy over the location of a Roman Catholic convent on the site of the death camp. He also promised to protect the vestiges of Jewish life in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. Although the nation had a Jewish population of over 3 million in 1939, only a few thousand remain today. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> received numerous gifts, which he accepted with good humor. After he was given a set of knives, he said in mock protest: `` I'm all for nonviolent struggle. I will not use these against anybody.'' Presented with a bust of <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>, he balanced it on his head for photographers. He expressed regret over his inability to meet more people, especially Polish-Americans. `` I would like to reach every American home, to visit every American home,'' <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said. `` I would like to drink a cup of coffee with every American girl, but time is short.'' <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> did manage to spend a quick 40 minutes among Poles during a meeting with the editorial staff of the Polish Daily News, the largest Polish daily newspaper outside <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. He begged for some plain talk, Pole-to-Pole. `` How did you feel in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>?'' a tired-looking <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> was asked. `` Oh, my God,'' he said to a chorus of laughs. `` I have a complex, standing next to all those greats.'' `` But you too are great,'' offered <PERSON> Boleslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Wierzbianski </PERSON>, the paper's publisher. In the evening <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> met more than 100 business executives at the <ORGANIZATION> Forbes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gallery </ORGANIZATION>, repository of publisher <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON>' eclectic collection of artifacts, memorabilia and oddities The former shipyard worker seemed most impressed by the blunt letter President <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> mailed in 1950 to a critic who had unfavorably reviewed his daughter <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON>'s singing. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> chortled as his translator read him <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>'s hand-written note. `` Someday I hope to meet you,'' <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> wrote. `` You'll need a new nose, a lot of beefsteak for black eyes and perhaps a supporter below!'' <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> concluded his visit to the gallery with yet another impassioned plea for investment in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, asking the executives: `` Can we work together in business?'' On Thursday night, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> accepted an award from the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, a non-sectarian, voluntary agency that assists refugees fleeing political, religious or racial persecution. Past recipients included <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON>, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Meany </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hubert </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Elie </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiesel </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0245EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-ElSalvador     11-18 0645</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-El Salvador,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Members of Congress Decry Violence in El Salvador</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic senators are threatening to slash <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> unless President <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> can end violence in the war-torn Central American nation. As an American-trained team of Salvadoran forensic experts began an investigation of the slayings of six Jesuit priests and two others, leftist protesters disrupted a <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> hearing, demanding a halt to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON>'s government. During Friday's rancorous hearing, Sen. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON> declared: `` The time has come for President <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> to evidence his commitment to controlling those officials within his own government and within his own party who are in very large part responsible for the civil conflict.'' `` President <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> is either in control, or he is not ... President <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> either deserves our support, or he does not,'' said <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., chairman of a Foreign Relations subcommittee on the western hemisphere Said Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>, D-Mass.: `` In an era of scarce foreign assistance, we need to be asking what we are achieving for the dollars sent.'' In a statement late Friday, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, D-Wash., and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, called for a return to negotiations and for an investigation of the killings `` This outrage must be investigated thoroughly, those responsible apprehended and promptly brought to justice,'' they said. `` Any other result would be unacceptable to the community of nations, and in particular to the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people.'' <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s senior official for <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> policy, agreed that without improvements, `` the policy wo n't go on.'' But he blamed the current conflict and human rights abuses that have accompanied it on rebel provocations. `` Implicit in our support is a demand that they make real progress in human rights,'' he said. `` Things have to change in <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, which has been fighting <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>'s government in a bloody civil war for the past decade, has undertaken assassinations designed to lure right-wing death squads `` out of the closet,'' <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON> said. `` Their strategy is to polarize'' the country and cripple the new government of <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON>, the rightist president, <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON> said. And he said the purpose of the current <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION> offensive in the capital of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> has been not to strengthen the rebels' negotiating position, as the <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION> contends, but `` to take total power. `` Had they succeeded ... another ally of <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, holding power with Soviet bloc weaponry, would have been firmly entrenched in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON> said. He said the murders early Thursday likely were the work of violent right-wing death squads blamed for most of the 70,000 deaths that have occurred during the country's civil war. But <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON> cautioned against leaping to conclusions before the outcome of the U.S.-supported criminal investigation. `` We want this crime investigated fully, swiftly and those responsible punished with the full force of the law,'' he said. `` Promises will not satisfy the high standards that President <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> proclaimed in his inaugural address, they will not satisfy the Salvadoran people and they will not satisfy the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> noted that <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> had assured <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> that even if members of the Salvadoran armed forces were involved, `` they will feel the full weight of the law.'' `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> expects him to meet that commitment,'' she said. In another development, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> general who drafted a classified military strategy for <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> said the guerrillas can not be defeated on the battlefield, and said the war drags on because of corruption within the U.S.-backed government. Gen. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON>, who until recently headed the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, also said the murder of six Roman Catholic priests most likely was the work of the radical right wing acting without the support or tacit consent of the conservative government.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0248EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GunSales     11-18 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gun Sales,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Recommended Gun-Control Program Hugely Expensive, Sources Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A program of instant background checks for gun-buyers _ intended to prevent sales to convicted felons _ would be so expensive the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is n't expected to recommend immediate implementation, congressional sources say. Such instant background checks could cost up to $ 27 billion to begin, sources said Friday. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> recommendation, due to be released Monday, suggests such a program but does not call for immediate implementation `` because of lack of funds and lack of computerization'' of all the criminal records, one source said. The computerization of complete information, including final dispensation of charges that often are not included in law enforcement computer systems now used, `` will cost tens of millions of dollars and will delay this for several years,'' said that source, who said he was informed of the report by <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials. <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> declined to comment on the report's contents, saying, `` It's still in the process of being reviewed. Until the review's been completed, there's no final decision.'' The report was required by an Anti-Drug Abuse Act amendment that had been approved as an alternative to another measure that would have required a seven-day waiting period _ while authorities conducted background checks if they wished _ before a person could buy a gun. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> was required to provide a report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> by Nov. 18 on its recommendations for preventing sales of guns to felons. Implementation was to begin Dec. 1. Rep. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Feighan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, who introduced the waiting-period measure _ dubbed the `` Brady amendment'' in reference to former presidential press secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> who was wounded by an assailant trying to shoot then-President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> _ said Friday, `` The report is a compelling argument for immediate enactment of the Brady Bill.'' `` The report acknowledges that a point-of-sale check will be enormously expensive and can not be implemented in the relatively near future,'' he said. `` I appreciate the attorney general's effort, but I am bitterly disappointed that we have lost a year's time in saving the lives of Americans Selecting the option of instantaneous checks at the point of sale would be a move toward one of the most expensive undertakings possible at a time when the federal government is strapped for funds, he said. Start-up costs for an immediate, live scan of fingerprints by gun dealers would be $ 9.6 billion to $ 27 billion, according to the report by the <ORGANIZATION> Task </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> on Felon Identification in Firearm Sales published in the Federal Register on Oct. 25. Also being recommended, according to the sources, are point-of-sale telephone checks by gun dealers to authorities with access to computerized information and similar telephone checks to an intermediate computer with the same access to information. Those would have start-up costs of $ 36 million to $ 44 million, according to the task force. <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> said in June that Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> had rejected another option _ the issuance of firearm owner's identification cards following background checks _ that would have had start-up costs of $ 148 million to $ 153 million These costs do not include the original computerization of information, which the task force said will involve `` substantial resources.'' It did not give a precise figure. <PERSON> Gwen </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Handgun </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> criticized the recommendations because they call for no immediate action. `` This removes every obstacle for not passing the <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> as soon as possible,'' <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> said. `` Last September, during the vote on the <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> amendment, and for an entire year, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> did n't have to deal with this because they had the McCollum Amendment -LRB- the one enacted -RRB- to hide behind. They were waiting for this announcement.'' `` It's now clear that nothing is going to happen anytime soon under this directive, which means that convicted felons are still buying guns over the counter in 28 states,'' she said, adding that the rest of the states have some kind of background check or waiting period before an individual can buy a gun. The McCollum Amendment is named for Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> McCollum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Fla </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0249EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--ManReappears 1stLd-Writethru a0419 11-18 0138</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Man Reappears, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0419,0137</SECOND>
<HEAD>Norwegian Phones Home, Disrupts Plans for His Memorial</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS thruout to CORRECT typo in lede, MINOR EDITING</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PORSGRUNN, Norway (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 40-year-old musician interrupted the planning for his own memorial service by calling from <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> to ask if he could come home, a newspaper reported. <PERSON> Morten </PERSON> <PERSON> Berntsen </PERSON> disappeared six months ago and the evidence indicated that he jumped to his death from a bridge, the newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Verdens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gang </ORGANIZATION> said Friday. The jazz musician was unaware that a memorial sevice was being planned for Friday when he called last weekend and asked a shocked friend to come get him in <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>, said the report. The paper said <PERSON> Berntsen </PERSON> apparently had been under a lot of stress due to financial problems and recalled little about the six months he was gone.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0610EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BloodDisorderRecall 1stLd-Writethru a0424 11-18 0378</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Blood Disorder Recall, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0424,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>L-tryptophan Recall Sought</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: INSERTS 1 graf after 4th graf pvs, bgng: ``At least...'' to
add New York ban; picks up 5th graf pvs, bgng: ``Two trade...''</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The federal government is calling for a voluntary nationwide recall of L-tryptophan, a dietary supplement linked to a potentially fatal rare blood disorder. <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> said Friday its offices around the country will start contacting manufacturers on Monday and ask them to recall their products. A week ago, the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> issued a warning telling consumers to stop using the supplement. At least 287 potential cases of the rare disorder, eosinophilia-myalgia syndrome, have been reported in 37 states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. At least one death is believed to have been caused by taking L-tryptophan, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>. The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> state <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> on Friday banned the distribution of L-tryptophan. Department spokeswoman <PERSON> Vicki </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeldin </PERSON> said, `` The ban is effective immediately. All of the products should be off the shelves this weekend.'' Two trade associations earlier this week encouraged manufacturers to pull the product off retail shelves. An <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> statement announcing the recall effort said there is a `` strong, virtually unequivocal link between consumption of L-tryptophan tablets or capsules and the syndrome.'' However, the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> said scientists investigating L-tryptophan do not know why this is happening. Symptoms of the disorder include an abnormally high number of white blood cells, called eosinophils, along with severe muscle pain. The agency said the condition posed a `` moderate to severe and perhaps life-threatening hazard to certain individuals.'' L-tryptophan is used by some people for insomnia, depression, premenstrual syndrome or appetite control. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> said all cases involved people who took tablets, capsules or caplets in which L-tryptophan was the main ingredient. No cases have been reported among people who consumed diet supplements in which it was a minor ingredient. <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Nesbitt </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION>, said the agency decided to take the action because of the `` preponderance of the epidemiological evidence that has been obtained this week.'' <PERSON> Nesbitt </PERSON> said the recall action is voluntary but the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> believes it has the evidence to obtain a court order if needed to remove the product from the shelves.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0106EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Senate-Nominations     11-18 0146</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Senate-Nominations,140</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Approves Nomination of Villalpando As United States Treasurer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> early Saturday approved the nomination of <PERSON> Catalina </PERSON> <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON> <PERSON> Villalpando </PERSON> to serve as treasurer of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. By voice vote, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved the nomination of <PERSON> Villalpando </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> to succeed <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>, who resigned. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> also approved, by voice vote, the nominations of <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schapiro </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> to be a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> for the term of five years expiring June 5, 1994. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Curry </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> was approved as administrator of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Traffic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Admininstration </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Curry </PERSON> replaces <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Steed </PERSON>, who resigned. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Emmett </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> to be a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Interstate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> for a term expiring Dec. 31, 1992. He succeeds <PERSON> Frederic </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Andre </PERSON>, whose term expired.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-IntelligenceBill 1stLd-Writethru a0764 11-18 0578</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Intelligence Bill, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0764,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Passes CIA Inspector General Bill</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: TOP 2 grafs new with Senate passage; picks up 3rd graf pvs,
bgng, `While President.'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> early Saturday gave final congressional approval to legislation that would create an independent inspector general to monitor the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intellingence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, answerable to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> as well as the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> director. The provision was in a compromise bill authorizing the government's intelligence activities for the coming year. Both the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> passed the legislation by voice vote. While President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> director, is said to object to establishing a tighter oversight office within the agency, members of the congressional intelligence committees have said they do not believe he will veto the measure because of the new requirement. In addition to setting up a new inspector general, appointed by the president and confirmed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, the bill would guarantee the congressional oversight committees access in most cases to the IG's audit and investigation reports. <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> has fought the committees over that access in the past, and some Republicans complained that <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> had mishandled the matter. `` <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> recalcitrance was its own undoing,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Livingston </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-La </LOCATION>., during <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor debate on the measure The new oversight provisions grew out of the Iran-Contra scandal, when the nation's intelligence apparatus skirted the law to sell arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and send money to the Nicaraguan Contra rebels despite bans on such activity. But the bill omitted a series of other steps that grew out of the Iran-Contra affair, including codification of requirements that covert operations be brought to the attention of the intelligence committees promptly and in written form, and that any third parties involved be disclosed. Those provisions were dropped because the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> committee wants to try again next year to negotiate stricter controls with the administration, and to write anything into the law now would pre-empt such discussions, said committee chairman Rep. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Beilenson </PERSON>, D-Calif. The new inspector general position would be like other government agency IGs who conduct audits, review the way programs are run and generally try to ferret out abuses, fraud or waste in federal programs. Congressional investigators who probed the Iran-Contra scandal said the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> inspector general lacked independence and did n't have `` the manpower, resources or tenacity'' to uncover arms-for-hostages transactions or the diversion of profits to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s Contra rebels. Currently, the inspector general is appointed by the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> director and reports only to him. Opponents of the change, including the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, had argued that it would create an impression that the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> would be unable to protect sensitive information, particularly about intelligence sources and methods, and valuable information might dry up. Money to carry out the government's intelligence operations is hidden in the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget and is secret, but reports put the overall spending level at upwards of $ 25 billion. Sources said the bill keeps on track a five-year, multibillion-dollar program to upgrade the nation's intelligence collection through so-called `` national technical means,'' or satellites and other electronic spying. Impetus for the buildup began with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ratification of the intermediate-range nuclear arms control treaty with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, which brought new requirements for verification. It has been given additional urgency by developments in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> that enhance the prospects for new strategic and conventional arms control treaties with the Soviets in the coming months.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891118-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-18-89 0256EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Senators-Lincoln     11-18 0542</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Senators-Lincoln,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ethics Committee Hires Attorney to Investigate Senators</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
