<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-06-89 2340EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Shooting-Witnesses     12-06 0663</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Shooting-Witnesses,0689</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Nightmare Come True _ Massacre in a College Classroom</HEAD>
<HEAD>With Canada-Shooting</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MONTREAL (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It was a nightmare come true Wednesday afternoon _ a crowded classroom at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Montreal </ORGANIZATION> engineering building and a rifleman in hunting clothes picking out his victims before firing. By the time the gunman killed himself, he had shot 14 women to death and wounded 12 others. Six women were shot to death in the first classroom he entered and a seventh in another room. Then the man prowled the halls, killing three women in the cafeteria and four more women in the corridor of the third floor, where he then shot himself. Witnesses described the scene in the first classroom, at the beginning of the massacre: `` I was doing a presentation in front of the class and suddenly a guy came in with what I think was a semi-automatic rifle,'' engineering student <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavarie </PERSON> said. `` He told us to stop everything. `` And then when we looked at him we thought it was a joke, but he fired a shot in the air and separated us into two groups, the guys in one corner and the girls in -LRB- another -RRB- corner. `` When that was done, he asked the guys to leave. He left the girls in there. `` We got outside in the hallway and for a couple of minutes he stayed in there and after, when we got out, he leveled his gun at a group of people who were there and he shot three or four shots.'' <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON>, 25, a student in the classroom, said, `` He told the guys to move to one side and the girls to the other. Nobody moved. We thought it was a joke. It was our last hour of the term. We practically laughed. `` I thought it was a blank,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON>, who was close to a classropm wall at which the gunman fired. `` I did n't see anything on the wall. But it made a very loud noise. `` When he came in he was really calm but after the first shot his voice became nervous.'' Professor <PERSON> Yvon </PERSON> <PERSON> Bouchard </PERSON>, who taught the mechanical engineering course, was sitting at his desk listening to the student presentation when the gunman entered. `` I did n't see him walk in. When I saw him, he was two or three feet from the students presenting their project,'' <PERSON> Bouchard </PERSON> said. `` Then he asked all the men to go one one side of the room and the women on the other. `` Nobody moved. We thought it was a joke. `` It does n't make sense.'' Student <PERSON> Luc </PERSON> <PERSON> Gauthier </PERSON>, 24, left the classroom about 5 p.m. The gunman entered, carrying an object that looked like a rifle in a trash bag. `` I went to the bathroom and when I came back, people were running out, screaming, ` There's a crazy guy in there! He's shot people!,' <PERSON> Gauthier </PERSON> said. `` I went to get my things and saw there was blood in front of the photocopy machine. `` Someone told me the first person he shot when he came out of the classroom was a girl in front of the photocopy machine.'' <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Bordeleau </PERSON>, a student who ran from the first to the second floor, said he dragged people by the collar to keep them from going downstairs to see the gunman. Student <PERSON> Vanthona </PERSON> <PERSON> Ouy </PERSON>, 22, tore the sleeve on his coat as he fled the building. `` I saw death up close and I shook. I dropped everything and ran,'' he said. Student <PERSON> Serge </PERSON> <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON> said: `` I was in the stairwell and someone came up the stairs shouting, ` Watch out! Watch out! He's coming!' I thought he was joking.'' <PERSON> Yannick </PERSON> <PERSON> Lacoste </PERSON>, a student who had just left the school library when she heard about five consecutive gunshots in the hallways, said, `` People were yelling, ` Someone is firing!' and students were running through the halls. `` I hurried to the door. I was very nervous. You do n't know if the shots are aimed at you.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-12-06-89 2352EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Colombia 3rdLd-Writethru a0809 12-06 1069</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Colombia, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0809,1096</SECOND>
<HEAD>Truck Bomb at Police Headquarters Kills Dozens</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS graf 3 `Late Wednesday' to CORRECT spelling of Mormon.
Picks up 4th, `Police also ...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos BOG1,3; LaserColor of BOG1; LaserGraphic NY28</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM WELLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOGOTA, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A truck bomb containing a half-ton of dynamite exploded outside secret police headquarters during the morning rush hour Wednesday, killing at least 35 people and wounding hundreds. The bomb, presumably the work of drug gangs, was the most powerful to strike the capital since <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s cocaine traffickers began a wave of terror after the government declared war on them 16 weeks ago. President <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> told Colombians they face an escalation in drug-related violence. Late Wednesday, three bombs exploded in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, the hub of a major cocaine-trafficking cartel, a police spokesman told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> by telephone from the city. He said they went off at an electronics shop, a Morman temple and an evangelical church without injuring anyone. Police also deactivated a car bomb a block from the offices of dozens of judges in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> on Wednesday afternoon, the national police said. <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> said late Wednesday in a nationally televised speech that drug traffickers had begun a new wave of terrorism intended to stop extradition of suspects to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and to destroy Colombian democracy. `` We must not, we will not ever fall before the drug traffickers,'' <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> said in the speech broadcast by radio and television from <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, where he was on a state visit. `` The stable democracy that we have built with great effort and defended for more than a century is in danger.'' The <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> blast, which tore open a crater 20 feet deep and destroyed or heavily damaged a score of buildings, occurred less than 24 hours after government investigators said a bomb caused the crash of a Colombian jetliner last month that killed 107 people. No one claimed responsibility directly for Wednesday's explosion, but Gen. <PERSON> Faruk </PERSON> <PERSON> Yanine </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> police chief, said it was undoubtedly the work of drug traffickers A statement from the so-called Extraditables delivered to newspapers and radio stations in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, said: `` We will stop the war only when the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> understands the people must be our judge.'' The reference was to a bill that would permit a national referendum on extraditing drug trafficking suspects wanted in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The House of Representatives approved it Tuesday night. <PERSON> Barco </PERSON>'s government opposes the measure, contending the drug barons would step up terrorism before a referendum to frighten voters into rejecting extradition. In his comments, <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> blamed traffickers for the bombing of the jetliner last month, for Tuesday's assassination of a judge in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, and for the bombing of the secret police headquarters. He said the three attacks represent `` a vile assault'' by the traffickers. `` These incidents show that what these criminals are capable of as they make sure that the referendum results are in their favor,'' <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> said, who was scheduled to return from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> on Friday. In their statement, the Extraditables said: `` The president should not fear what the congress decides, because the <ORGANIZATION> congress </ORGANIZATION> is the voice of the people, and the voice of the people is the voice of God.'' Minister of Government <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Lemos </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmonds </PERSON> told reporters after the bombing: `` The slaughter that we warned of when the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved extradition in the plebiscite has started.'' He is acting president while <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> is on the state visit. The <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> bomb went off at 7:30 a.m. in an area crowded with people bound for work on foot and in cars. So powerful was the explosion that it broke windows in a building across the street from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy seven miles away. <PERSON> Caracol </PERSON> quoted sources with explosives experts at the scene as saying the truck was packed with 1,100 pounds of dynamite. Reports on the number of dead and wounded varied, and rescuers were pulling bodies from the rubble of buildings hours after the blast. Health Minister <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> said in an interview with <PERSON> Caracol </PERSON> that at least 35 people were killed, 250 seriously wounded and 750 treated for cuts, abrasions, shock and shock. Unconfirmed reports gave higher death tolls. However, the television news program `` 24 Hours'' reported the death toll rose to 40 late Wednesday. Police said they were unable to confirm that report. The explosion blew the facade off the secret police headquarters and destroyed virtually all its walls and windows. Also heavily damaged were an office building for federal judges across the street and the national transit police headquarters a block away. Half a dozen stores across the street from secret police headquarters were reduced to smoking rubble and about 60 cars were destroyed. Visa renewal is one function of the secret police, or Department of Administrative Security. Many foreigners usually are there on any given weekday, but it was not known whether foreigners were among the dead and wounded. This is a busy season because many foreigners go home for Christmas, and can not do so without reports of clean police records. Minutes after the explosion, detectives at secret police headquarters scrambled up ladders and, from the remains of cells, pulled two stunned prisoners awaiting extradition to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The prisoners were taken away in an armored vehicle. <PERSON> Lemos </PERSON> said on Caracol the bombing illustrated the futility of trying to negotiate with the drug gangs. He said the government would not lessen its resolve to crush them. In their statement about the second bomb in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, the national police said the device was hidden in a subcompact <ORGANIZATION> Renault </ORGANIZATION> parked in front of a government building where dozens of judges have their offices. The police did not say how much dynamite was in the car. <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> began the war on traffickers hours after they assassinated a leading presidential candidate, Sen. <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Galan </PERSON>, on Aug. 16 during a campaign speech in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>. He also reinstated extradition of suspects to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which was suspended by <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> rulings in 1987 and 1988. Nine have been sent to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> the past three months. An <ORGANIZATION> Avianca </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> passenger jet exploded in the air Nov. 27 and all 107 people aboard were killed. The government Tuesday said a bomb caused the explosion. Not counting the plane crash victims or the victims of Wednesday's truck bomb, 29 people have been killed and 238 wounded by 201 bombs since <PERSON> Galan </PERSON>'s assassination.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-06-89 0125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens-List     12-06 0709</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens-List,0799</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of Nov. 27-Dec. 3 Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 92.1 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 27.1 rating, 25.0 million homes. 2. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 25.4, 23.4 million homes. 3. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Jillian </PERSON> <PERSON> Preview </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 25.0, 23.0 million homes. 4. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.5, 22.6 million homes. 5. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.4, 19.7 million homes. 6. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.1, 18.5 million homes. 7. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 19.8, 18.2 million homes. 8. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.6, 18.1 million homes. 9. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 19.5, 18.0 million homes. 9. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.5, 18.0 million homes. 11. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` NFL Monday Night Football: 49ers vs <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.1, 17.6 million homes. 12. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.9, 17.4 million homes. 13. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.8, 17.3 million homes. 14. -LRB- 12 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.3, 16.9 million homes. 15. -LRB- 56 -RRB- `` Coach,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.2, 16.8 million homes. 16. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` In the Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.0, 15.7 million homes. 17. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.9, 15.6 million homes. 17. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` Little White Lies'' _ `` NBC Monday Night Movies,'' 16.9, 15.6 million homes. 19. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.6, 15.3 million homes. 20. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.0, 14.7 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. -LRB- 20 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.9. 22. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.7. 22. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Hallmark Hall Of Fame - The <ORGANIZATION> Shell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seekers </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.7. 24. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1. 24. -LRB- 42 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1. 24. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1. 27. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Doogie </PERSON> <PERSON> Howser </PERSON>, M.D.,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.0. 28. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.5. 29. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 14.4. 29. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS, 14.4. 31. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` 20 @ 20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.2. 32. -LRB- 35 -RRB- `` True Blue'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 14.0. 33. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` Family Matters,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.9. 34. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 13.7. 34. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.7. 36. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` Knots Landing,'' CBS, 13.5. 37. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` No Place Like Home'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 13.3. 38. -LRB- 42 -RRB- `` Perfect Strngers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2. 39. -LRB- 47 -RRB- `` Rescue 911,'' CBS, 13.1. 40. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` Major Dad,'' CBS, 13.0. 41. -LRB- 41 -RRB- `` Anything But Love,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.9. 42. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Yesterday, Today Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7. 43. -LRB- 50 -RRB- `` Just The Ten Of Us,'' 12.5. 44. -LRB- 44 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 12.4. 45. -LRB- 44 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.2. 46. -LRB- 52 -RRB- `` My Two Dads - Wednesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.1. 47. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0. 48. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` Quantum Leap,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0. 49. -LRB- 73 -RRB- `` Sister <PERSON> Kate </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.5. 50. -LRB- 59 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.0. 51. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` Mancuso: <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.7. 52. -LRB- 58 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Jillian </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.6. 53. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 10.5. 54. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 10.4. 55. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` Baywatch,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.3. 55. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` Hardball,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.3. 55. -LRB- 63 -RRB- `` Magical World of Disney,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.3. 58. -LRB- 61 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Falcon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 10.2. 58. -LRB- 63 -RRB- `` Police Academy 4'' _ `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' 10.2. 60. -LRB- 80 -RRB- `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.9. 60. -LRB- 61 -RRB- `` Young Riders,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.9. 62. -LRB- 63 -RRB- `` Doctor, Doctor,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 62. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 64. -LRB- 72 -RRB- `` Paradise,'' CBS, 9.7. 65. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Candid Camera Special,'' CBS, 9.6. 65. -LRB- 47 -RRB- `` Famous Teddy Z,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.6. 67. -LRB- 77 -RRB- `` Totally Hidden Video,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 9.2. 68. -LRB- 74 -RRB- `` Life Goes On,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.1. 69. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` Top Of <LOCATION> The </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.7. 70. -LRB- 82 -RRB- `` Kojak'' _ `` ABC Mystery Movie,'' 8.6. 71. -LRB- 75 -RRB- `` Primetime Live,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.0. 72. -LRB- 79 -RRB- `` Snoops,'' CBS, 7.8. 72. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: At Freedoms Gate,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 7.8. 74. -LRB- 86 -RRB- `` Saturday Night With <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Chung </PERSON>,'' CBS, 7.6. 75. -LRB- 91 -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 7.4. 76. -LRB- 90 -RRB- `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 7.3. 77. -LRB- 84 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 7.1. 77. -LRB- 77 -RRB- `` Free Spirit,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.1. 79. -LRB- 76 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.7. 80. -LRB- 85 -RRB- `` Homeroom,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.6. 81. -LRB- 87 -RRB- `` Open House,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.4. 82. -LRB- 94 -RRB- `` Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.1. 83. -LRB- 88 -RRB- `` Living Dolls,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.8. 84. -LRB- 92 -RRB- `` Alien Nation,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.7. 85. -LRB- 92 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Booker </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.2. 86. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Premiere Magazine Presents Christmas Movies'89,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.0. 87. -LRB- 97 -RRB- `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.5.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-06-89 0136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-Summit Bjt   12-06 0630</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Summit, Bjt,0647</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officials Say Military Growth To Continue Despite Global Peace Trend</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY THORSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s defense budget, already judged the third largest in the world, will continue to grow even as the superpowers talk about cutting back on military spending, officials say. In a region so far immune to dramatic improvements in relations like those occurring in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> has at best cool relations with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> as the two countries are deadlocked over an old territorial dispute. And the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is pressing <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> to increase its budgetary support for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces based in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s military budget, always controversial in light of a constitution that bans war, has grown steadily through the 1980s to increase the country's ability to fend off Soviet attack. `` It is separate from -LRB- superpower -RRB- arms reductions from that point of view. So our own efforts for improving our self-defense are not expected to change at the moment,'' <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Taizo </PERSON> <PERSON> Watanabe </PERSON> told a news conference Tuesday. He was asked if the outcome of the superpower summit in <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>, which gave new impetus to arms negotiations between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, would reduce <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s military spending. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is starting to plan for defense cuts, and <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> says the Soviets have reduced military spending. Japanese newspapers reported today that <PERSON> Seiki </PERSON> <PERSON> Nishihiro </PERSON>, vice minister of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, had cautioned the public against thinking that the superpower summit could result in a cutback in this country's defense budget. And an anonymous Foreign Ministry official was quoted in the <ORGANIZATION> Yomiuri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shimbun </ORGANIZATION> daily as saying, `` The Asian situation is completely different from that of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, and still remains unstable. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> needs to develop a minimum defense strength for deterrence.'' Last week, the <ORGANIZATION> Asahi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shimbun </ORGANIZATION> newspaper reported that the defense budget would grow a hefty 6 percent in the fiscal year that begins in April, to about $ 27.8 billion, or roughly 1 percent of gross national product. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> defense budget is more than 10 times as large and consumes 6 percent of gross national product. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s defense spending has grown rapidly in dollar terms due to the yen's almost doubling in value since 1985, and now is judged third-biggest in the world or slightly ahead of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Much of the defense buildup took place in close coordination with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which by treaty is obliged to help defend <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. The two countries' navies and air forces collaborate on defense planning, and the Japanese have been building up potent air and anti-submarine forces. Unlike Central <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, with its fairly clear divide between two superpower camps on the ground, the <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> is a vast area in which control of the sea is a more important factor, and there are more contenders: the Soviets, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, the U.S.-Japan alliance, and powerful smaller countries like <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and the Koreas. The <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> countries, however, have bitter memories of Japanese invasions, and have protested <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>'s increases in military spending. After World War II, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> occupation authorities imposed a constutition that bans the use of military force, and the armed forces have an ambiguous status. Their existence is justified as strictly for self-defense, and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> has not acquired hardware that would enable distant military adventures, such as long-range bombers or aircraft carriers. But some Americans have called for <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to increase defense efforts even more to relieve the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military outlay. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> recently signed a bill calling on <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to pay all the costs of the roughly 50,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops stationed in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> now pays about 45 percent of the support, or about $ 2.8 billion a year. The Japanese government has not yet commented on the new call from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-06-89 0136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Nobel-Cela     12-06 0300</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nobel-Cela,0309</SECOND>
<HEAD>Literature Laureate Says He'll Be Happy When It's Over</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KARIN STRAND</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Spanish author <PERSON> Camilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Cela </PERSON>, in town to collect his Nobel Prize for literature, says he'll be glad when all the fuss is over and he can start working again. `` Since the announcement of the prize I have n't led any life at all. I've just been answering questions all the time,'' he told a news conference Tuesday. <PERSON> Cela </PERSON>, 73, has published 70 novels, travelogues, essays and books of poetry. His 1942 book `` The Family of Pascual Duarte'' was the most popular work of Spanish fiction since <PERSON> Cervantes </PERSON>' <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Quixote </PERSON>. Though claiming to be disturbed by the unceasing attention since the prize was announced Oct. 18, <PERSON> Cela </PERSON> said he was coming to receive the Nobel `` with gratitude and emotion.'' `` But I'm looking forward to being able to sit at my desk and start working again,'' he said. <PERSON> Cela </PERSON> will be given his award by <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s King <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> XVI </PERSON> <PERSON> Gustaf </PERSON> on Sunday, and a check for the equivalent of $ 469,000. The writer dismissed the idea he would now `` rest on his laurels'' after receiving one of the world's most coveted literary awards. `` I ca n't imagine a retrospective future,'' he said. Asked who inspired him the most, <PERSON> Cela </PERSON> said, `` I was inspired by all Spanish authors before me. Literature is part of a culture.'' He said he best enjoyed reading medieval <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> poets. He also mentioned the late <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Hemingway </PERSON> as an influence. `` <PERSON> Hemingway </PERSON> was my friend. We went to a lot of bullfights together. He was a great author and a great friend,'' <PERSON> Cela </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Cela </PERSON> drew on his experiences in the Spanish Civil War for many of his stories, which often showed the violent and gruesome side of life.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-06-89 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Ethiopia-Famine     12-06 0235</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ethiopia-Famine,0241</SECOND>
<HEAD>Up To Four Million of Ethiopians Said To Face Possible Starvation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Crop failure in civil war-plagued <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> threatens up to four million people with a famine worse than the mass starvation of five years ago, the 24-nation <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> says. `` The situation in the coming months risks being more serious than in 1984-85,'' when 1 million Ethiopians starved to death, said <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Wheeler </PERSON>, president of the Paris-based organization's Committee for Aid and Development. Food shortages stemming from crop failure are aggravated by difficulties in distributing emergency aid across combat zones in northern <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Wheeler </PERSON> said Tuesday after the committee's annual meeting on world development aid The committee called on the world community to help get aid through to hard-to-reach regions. <PERSON> Wheeler </PERSON> said several regions controlled by forces opposed to <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>'s government are no longer producing enough food to feed their populations. The Marxist government must overcome its traditional reluctance to open up contact to rebel-held areas if the civilian population is to have any chance of surviving 1990, <PERSON> Wheeler </PERSON> said. `` It's often possible to persuade governments to permit certain actions for humanitarian reasons,'' he said. `` It's essential to get food across the lines.'' <PERSON> Wheeler </PERSON> said similar problems had been overcome in neighboring <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>'s members include all <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> nations, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, and neutral countries such as <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-06-89 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Education Bjt   12-06 0613</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Education, Bjt,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>NEA, Urban Schools Seek Input Into National Education Goals</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TAMARA HENRY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As the nation's governors try to meet a self-imposed deadline for developing national education goals, leaders of education groups are moving to have some impact on the finished product. <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Geiger </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, proposed Tuesday that federally financed preschool programs for poor youngsters integrate nutrition, prenatal care and health screening. Early childhood education should be the primary focus of the nation, <PERSON> Geiger </PERSON> said in an interview two days before Thursday's meeting of the Education Task Force of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governors </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, And while preschool was included in its recommendations, a second education group, the <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Great </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Schools </ORGANIZATION>, said the first priority should be to improve urban The council said 30.4 percent of all poor children in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are enrolled in only 50 urban school systems and the teacher shortage in urban schools is 2 -LCB- times greater than the national average. <PERSON> Geiger </PERSON> and council leaders _ President <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Zenke </PERSON> and Director <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Husk </PERSON> _ will present their ideas on national performance goals for education at the task force meeting. The governors' group has been working since the idea was approved in September at the education summit between governors and President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. All 50 governors will convene in late February to put on the finishing touches. In a Dec. 1 letter to the task force co-chairmen, <PERSON> Geiger </PERSON> suggested the goals `` be both ambitious and specific: ambitious enough to demonstrate that <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s leaders understand the depth of the problems schools face, specific enough to enable Americans to hold government accountable.'' <PERSON> Husk </PERSON> said the council's board of directors decided in early November to strongly recommend that national goals contain specific targets, outcomes and measures from each area; interim goals to be met along the way; program and funding strategies at all levels and plans for incentives and accountability. The Council of the <ORGANIZATION> Great </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Schools </ORGANIZATION> is an organization of 45 urban school districts that concentrates on the concerns of city schools. `` Urban educators have proven their ability to improve our schools with limited resources, however, the time has come for governments, businesses and our communities to provide the monetary resources to support efforts to fulfill our commitment to quality education for all children,'' <PERSON> Husk </PERSON> said. `` No child should be allowed to fall through the cracks,'' <PERSON> Geiger </PERSON> said. `` Every child should arrive at school physically, intellectually, emotionally and socially able to learn.'' Head Start has been touted as the most successful preschool program financed by the federal government. About 1,300 Head Start programs operate around the country, providing education and health and nutrition services to about 20 percent of the impoverished preschoolers who are eligible. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> recently signed a law to increase spending for the Head Start program this fiscal year by $ 147 million to $ 1.6 billion. But the <ORGANIZATION> NEA </ORGANIZATION> estimated about $ 6.3 billion is needed to serve all eligible children ages 3 through 5. Both the <ORGANIZATION> NEA </ORGANIZATION> and council offered similar proposals they want incorporated into the national performance goals. For example, both called for safe, disciplined and drug-free schools. The council also suggested there should be specific steps to be taken by distillers, tobacco and firearms manufacturers to reduce youth access to their products. The groups also called for a reduction in the dropout rate. The <ORGANIZATION> NEA </ORGANIZATION> proposed providing a fully qualified teacher for every classroom, with salaries and benefits competitive with other fields that require comparable skills, preparation and responsibility. The council suggested the goals target specific number or percentages of teachers needed by 2000 to better reflect the racial characteristics of students.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-06-89 0222EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Batbikes     12-06 0105</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Batbikes,0108</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nearly 2,000 `Batman' Bikes Stolen</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CARSON, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Detectives are trying to track down the joker who stole 1,980 `` Batman'' bicycles. The bandits took the bikes, worth $ 90,000, from the <ORGANIZATION> Schaefer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Distribution </ORGANIZATION> trucking company last weekend, said Detective <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff's Department. `` The only thing we know for sure is they cut the locks off the chain-link gates and went in there with some tractors and stole the bikes,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` We have very little to work with right now.'' Investigators believe the thieves first stole two big-rig trailers to haul away the bicycles.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-06-89 0121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     12-06 0797</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Analysts: Farmers Will Be in the Market for New Machinery</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A relatively high level of cash income is expected to put more farmers in the 1990 market for new machinery and other capital improvements, <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> analysts say. Net cash income is expected to be in the range of $ 52 billion to $ 54 billion this year, down from a record $ 59.9 billion in 1988 because of higher production expenses and lower government payments. In 1990, according to projections announced at the department's recent outlook conference, net cash income _ the difference between cash gross income and cash expenses _ may be in the range of $ 52 billion to $ 57 billion <PERSON> Stan </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daberkow </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said that with 1990 net cash income looking brighter and interest rates to remain near current levels, capital spending next year could rise 4 percent to 5 percent. `` Prospects for increased planted acreage and an aging farm machinery stock may also positively influence capital spending by farmers,'' he said. A seven-year slump for the farm machinery industry ended in 1986. `` Unit sales of new farm tractors and other large pieces of farm equipment increased in 1987 and 1988 and are likely to show further gains in 1989 and 1990,'' <PERSON> Daberkow </PERSON> said. `` Sales of new over-40-horsepower tractors may reach 64,000 units, up from an estimated 62,000 in 1989.'' <PERSON> Daberkow </PERSON> said combines did not substantially rebound until this year because some farmers had to postpone capital spending because of the 1988 drought. Even so, self-propelled combine sales, which are closely related to harvest prospects, `` began to rise significantly'' from 1988 levels by April of this year. The retooling of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agriculture is long overdue. Between 1980 and 1986, he said, capital expenditures dropped by nearly 60 percent. `` Rising real interest rates, declining commodity prices, curtailed agricultural exports, reluctance to take on additional debt, falling land values, reduced planted cropland and a binge of capital spending in the 1970s led to very conservative levels of capital spending in the 1980s,'' <PERSON> Daberkow </PERSON> said. Tractors and other farm machinery usually make up about 60 percent of all capital expenditures, with buildings and land improvements accounting for 25 percent to 30 percent, and cars and trucks the remainder. Sales of large new tractors were one of the hardest hit categories during the early and mid-1980s, with the number of units sold plummeting 75 percent. <PERSON> Daberkow </PERSON> said farmers may spend between $ 118 billion and $ 121 billion next year on total agricultural supplies, or inputs, which would be down 1 percent to 2 percent from this year. That would be due in part to lower feed costs.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has been authorized to buy an additional 1 million metric tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat at subsidized prices. Acting Undersecretary <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> said Tuesday that the wheat will be available to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> under the department's Export Enhancement Program, or EEP. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 36.7 bushels of wheat. Under EEP arrangements, private exporters can sell <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commodities at reduced prices to meet foreign competition in selected overseas markets and then collect free government surpluses of grain or other commodities as bonuses, or subsidies. The subsidies have averaged from around $ 10 per ton, to more than $ 40 per ton of wheat, or in the range of 27 cents to about $ 1.10 per bushel. <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> said 10,000 tons remained in the previous <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION> allocation for <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> announced Feb. 27. That allocation was for 2 million tons. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> was the largest foreign buyer of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat in the 1988-89 wheat marketing year that ended May 31 with orders for nearly 8.1 million tons, all of it under the <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION> program. Sales for 1989-90 total about 4.7 million tons, most of it without subsidies. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is also the world's largest wheat producer this year with an output estimated at 91 million tons. That compares with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s harvest of 89 million tons this year and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production of about 56 million tons.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Imports of lambs and sheep rose sharply this year and are expected to continue rising in 1990, according to <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> livestock analysts. Imports during the first eight months of 1989 totaled 106,676 head, up from only 24,775 in the same period last year, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. Traditionally, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> supplies most of the lamb imports, but this year large shipments have been received from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> feedlots. `` With the investment in the facilities and the initial outlook for lamb prices to be marginally above present levels, lambs should continue to be imported next year,'' the agency said in an outlook report.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-06-89 0140EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Forum-Keating     12-06 0681</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Forum-Keating,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>S&amp;L Scandal Hits Donations to Voter Registration Groups</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two liberal voter registration groups that took money from <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>, a central figure in the savings and loan scandal, have seen contributions dry up, officials of the organizations say. Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, D-Calif., one of five senators under investigation by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee, played a role in soliciting money from <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> for both groups, said <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> <PERSON> Flander </PERSON>, his spokesman One group, The <ORGANIZATION> Forum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, will suspend operations Jan. 1 because the links to <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> have prompted so much turmoil, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeffress </PERSON>, the group's lawyer, said Tuesday. `` Given all the proceedings, given the involvement of <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>, the board thinks it's best they suspend operations on Jan. 1,'' <PERSON> Jeffress </PERSON> said. The other group, the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Participation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION>, based in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, is not `` actively soliciting resources,'' according to <PERSON> Cruz </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynoso </PERSON>, chairman of the board. The center's future will be discussed at the next board meeting, <PERSON> Reynoso </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reynoso </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> justice and also a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Forum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>'s board, said the bad publicity surrounding <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> has `` made it very difficult to raise money.'' Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported today that federal law enforcement authorities are investigating whether both groups violated their tax-exempt status by instructing employees to register more Democrats than Republicans. <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON> denied that in an interview with the Times, saying voter registration drives were `` carefully done in accordance with legal requirements.'' <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> millionaire who headed the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and its subsidiary, the <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, contributed $ 325,000 over two years to the institute, <PERSON> Jeffress </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> also gave $ 400,000 to the center, a group set up by <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>'s son, <PERSON> Kim </PERSON>, with his father's help, to register new voters in Western states. The Lincoln failure, the subject of numerous federal and state investigations, is expected to cost taxpayers $ 2.5 billion, the largest single thrift collapse. The Forum Institute was created in 1981 by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stein </PERSON>, a philanthropist and paid consultant to the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> until October. <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON> and <PERSON> Stein </PERSON> frequently worked in tandem to raise money for voter registration, an issue in which both men were interested, <PERSON> Flander </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Flander </PERSON> said <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, who has a personal passion for registering new voters, traveled around the country raising money for his cause, including money from <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>. `` As far as <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> is concerned, this is a good cause,'' <PERSON> Flander </PERSON> said, adding that <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON> first met <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> either in 1985 or 1986. <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON> sought money from <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> for the <ORGANIZATION> Forum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Participation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION> and USA Votes, a project of <PERSON> Stein </PERSON>'s company, <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dimension </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Flander </PERSON> said. New Dimension paid for more than a dozen trips for <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON> to travel around the country raising money for voter registration drives in 1988, according to <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>'s financial disclosure forms. <PERSON> Stein </PERSON> refused in two telephone conversations to answer any questions about his involvement with <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON> or <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>. He said he wanted the controversy to subside before he talked about his projects. The non-profit, tax-exempt <ORGANIZATION> Forum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> is an organization that `` gives grants to groups that encourage voter participation and public education,'' according to records filed by with the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Forum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> raised $ 2.1 million in 1988, about $ 300,000 more than the previous year, the group's <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> records show. Among the grants the institute handed out were a total of roughly $ 305,000 in 1987 and 1988 to the Center for Participation in Democracy. The <ORGANIZATION> Forum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> also gave about $ 800,000 to the <ORGANIZATION> Organizing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grove </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, a group that trained registrars for the center. Other forum grants went for a variety of projects, ranging from clear air to youth activities. <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, along with <PERSON> Sens </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ariz </LOCATION>., <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>, D-Mich., <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>., are under investigation by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee for accepting campaign contributions from <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> while at the same time intervening with federal regulators seeking to curb <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> The senators have denied they did anything illegal.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-06-89 0140EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BarbaraBush     12-06 0384</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Barbara Bush,390</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mrs. Bush Plugs Salvation Army Bell Ringers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, giving a plug for the <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> as several local shopping malls shut it out this holiday season, said all shopping centers should welcome the annual bell ringers. `` It just would n't be Christmas without that bell ringing,'' the first lady said Tuesday as she dropped $ 10 into the <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> kettle inside the entrance to the upscale <PERSON> Mazza </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallerie </PERSON> mall. She decided to lend her support when she read a newspaper story about a large number of local shopping malls that are excluding the annual solicitation on the grounds that they bar all groups from soliciting. `` I am a great fan of the <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, so I wanted to come out and tell you what great work I think you do,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> volunteer <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> and Col. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Waters </PERSON>, commander of the regional <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> division. Waters said about a third of the shopping malls in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> metropolitan area bar the annual holiday solicitation by the bell ringers _ about double the rate of refusals in other parts of the country. He said more than 125,000 people came to the local <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> for assistance last year, and this year already has seen more requests. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said all shopping malls should allow the <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> to set up its kettles during the Christmas season. Asked what message she would give to those who refuse, she said she had none but wanted only to praise the ones that do cooperate. `` I'm saying this mall is a great mall,'' she told reporters. `` I ca n't possibly think of Christmas without the <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. I ca n't think of disasters without the <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>,'' she said referring to the organization's work for victims of natural disasters. `` I ca n't think of the needy without the <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>.'' The organization said that last year it raised $ 600,000 in its kettles throughout the capital region, and about $ 100,00 of that will be lost due to malls that are barring the kettles this year. After stopping at the <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> kettle, Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did some Christmas shopping in <ORGANIZATION> Neiman-Marcus </ORGANIZATION> department store. She bought toys and clothes for her grandchildren, said her press secretary, <PERSON> Anna </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-06-89 0141EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Summit-Afghanistan     12-06 0663</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Afghanistan,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Support for Najibullah Blocked Political Headway at Malta
Summit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> will continue supporting the pro-Moscow leader of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> despite President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s insistence at the <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> summit that President <PERSON> Najibullah </PERSON>'s ouster would hasten settlement of the war in that country, according to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> described <PERSON> Najibullah </PERSON> as `` unacceptable'' to U.S.-backed Moslem guerrillas, but Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said he was a national figure who was gaining popularity in the country, the officials said Tuesday. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> were unable to break new ground at their superpower summit to end the conflict between government and Moslem forces in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> even though the last Soviet troops departed in February. The dispute, which surfaced in an exchange between <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> on the Soviet cruise ship Maxim Gorky on Sunday, stood in sharp contrast to the mostly positive results of the shipboard meeting. A parallel disagreement over <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> was disclosed by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> at a windup news conference Sunday. `` I ca n't say there are no differences between us,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told reporters without making any direct reference to the war in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. He stressed their differences over Soviet arms supplies to leftist rebels in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> insists anti-aircraft missiles and other weapons were being delivered by <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, but <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said he did not know how the arms got to the <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> that is at war with the Salvadoran government, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> at the summit meeting. Regional conflicts have proved to be the most resistant to U.S.-Soviet reconciliation. By contrast, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> set as targets arms control accords to limit nuclear, conventional and chemical weapons. <PERSON> Sibghatullah </PERSON> <PERSON> Mojaddedi </PERSON>, the head of the U.S.-backed Afghan resistance, met with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> at the White House before the <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> summit and said he wanted high-altitude anti-aircraft weapons to use against Soviet bombers. He also expressed hope that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would tell <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to drop Soviet support for the `` puppet regime and the communist government'' in the Afghan capital of <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. `` Unfortunately, the free world thinks that the Russians have withdrawn completely from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Mojaddedi </PERSON> said. `` Still, the Russians are bombing our people, the mujahedeen, from their own territory.'' The Soviet <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> rolled into <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in December 1979 to back a Marxist government against Moslem guerrillas in a war that had broken out a year earlier. The last of the Soviet troops were withdrawn in February, but <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence sources claim <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> has increased <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to <PERSON> Najibullah </PERSON>'s government to $ 300 million to $ 400 million a month. Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, at his meeting in <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hole </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, in September with Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>, complained about the arms shipments. The Soviets responded that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, by sending the guerrillas a reported $ 500 million in arms annually via <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, was violating the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> accords signed last year that secured the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> humanitarian aid to the rebels and refugees in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> amounts to $ 130 million a year. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials decline to acknowledge on the record that any <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> arms are being sent to the insurgents. At the summit, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> the Marxist president must relinquish power before there could be a political settlement of the war. The president told <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> that <PERSON> Najibullah </PERSON> `` has to go,'' said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, who spoke on condition of anonymity. In another troubled area, the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, the summit talks produced no apparent discord. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> appealed for a warmer <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> stance toward <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>, the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, and said he had `` gone out on a limb'' to seek peace with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> urged <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to understand <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s concerns over the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. Although the two leaders reached no agreement, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> concluded the Soviets were making a `` positive contribution'' to efforts to resolve the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> dispute and the war in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-06-89 0200EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SoftMoney     12-06 0696</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soft Money,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Group Says Parties Abused Legal Loophole in Campaign Spending</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 National and state officials of both major political parties deny a study group's charge that they pumped money exempt from federal regulation into last year's presidential campaign. In a report issued Tuesday, the Center for <ORGANIZATION> Responsive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Politics </ORGANIZATION> said <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> and Democratic parties in nine battleground states received $ 28.5 million in so-called `` soft money'' donations not covered by federal limits. Included in the total were contributions of more than $ 7.5 million from the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and more than $ 2 million from the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` Anyone can see there was wholesale erosion of our campaign finance laws during last year's presidential campaign,'' said <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, executive director of the center, a bipartisan group that studies campaign finance. But the parties say the center is taking a one-sided view of campaign spending. <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said the report `` really ignores the fact that ... we operate on two levels, under federal laws and under state laws.'' <PERSON> Ginny </PERSON> <PERSON> Terzano </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said: `` They sort of want to federalize the process, which is not going to be realistic. When you put money into state parties, that's a state issue and the state has to deal with that, and they do n't want federal involvement.'' <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Democratic Chairman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Slagle </PERSON>, contacted in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, said, `` Those folks in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, are looking through the wrong end of the telescope, and I do n't know if a microscope would help.'' <PERSON> Slagle </PERSON> said the Democratic party in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, which has not been carried by a Democratic presidential candidate since 1976, is more interested in protecting its state and local candidates from a <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> sweep than in promoting a presidential candidate. <PERSON> Slagle </PERSON>'s Republican counterpart, <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Meyer </PERSON>, said his party uses contributions that are exempt from federal limits for research, recruitment and training of candidates and for administrative functions. But Ms. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said the group found `` obvious patterns of questionable soft money giving. No wonder voters have so little confidence in our politicians when they are sabotaging our laws like this.'' Ms. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said the group concluded soft money was used toward the presidential race because 11 individuals and eight businesses each contributed more than $ 100,000 in the nine states and 42 percent of the money came from out-of-state sources including the two national political parties. Also, much of the money was given in key presidential states and about a third of the money was given in the last four weeks. Although corporations and labor unions are barred from contributing directly to campaigns for federal office, and individual contributions are limited, they may make unlimited contributions in most states for state and local campaigns, party building and voter drives. This is called `` soft money'' and is not supposed to be used in campaigns for federal office. The center wants such contributions brought under federal control. The study covered 7,098 contributions by individuals, corporations, unincorporated businesses, trade associations and the Democratic and Republican national committees to state parties in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Individuals gave $ 9.2 million to <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> state parties and $ 1.8 million to Democratic state parties. Corporations gave nearly $ 6.5 million, almost of a third of it to the Republican parties. Soft money contributions to Republican parties from all sources came to $ 16.7 million and to $ 11.8 million for Democratic parties, according to the study. Republicans received more than Democrats in all states except <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> had the largest infusion of soft money, $ 5.8 million to the Republican party and $ 4.4 million to the Democrats. Other state totals were: <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, $ 4.7 million; <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, $ 4.4 million; <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, $ 3.2 million; <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, $ 2.1 million; <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, $ 1.5 million; <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> just under $ 1 million; <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> $ 883,000 and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> $ 345,286. `` The bottom line is we do not go above the law or <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> regulations when we are putting money into states for various races,'' Ms. <PERSON> Terzano </PERSON> said. `` We put our money into the state, and we use it and the money is directed according to <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> regulations.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-06-89 0201EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-RiskyPrograms     12-06 0606</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Risky Programs,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>OMB Details Where Hundreds of Billions of Tax Dollars in Jeopardy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHERINE RIZZO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Top managers of federal agencies believe tens of billions of tax dollars are jeopardized by waste, fraud and shoddy practices, according to an inventory of `` high-risk programs'' compiled by the Office of Management and Budget. The list is a department-by-department blueprint of costly flaws in the way the federal government conducts the people's business. It was made public Tuesday by Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. He noted that warnings about the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> went unheeded until flaws grew into an estimated $ 6 billion crisis and praised budget director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> for trying to identify `` programs which could become our next HUDs.'' `` He's really bringing some of these things to light ... so that we'll know if there are any more of those <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> situations out there,'' <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> confirmed it gave the list to <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>. Spokeswoman <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> said the administration plans to work closely with <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> to develop `` management systems and internal controls sufficient to deal with the high risks identified on the list.'' The list detailed problems with more than 70 programs. Among them: _ The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> pays for goods it does n't receive and ca n't account for, or adequately trace, $ 56.5 billion worth of government property that's in the hands of government contractors _ There's a $ 58.5 billion difference between the amount of money the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> records say has been received from workers and the amount indicated by <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> records _ At the <ORGANIZATION> Patent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trademark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, 1.89 million documents are missing or misfiled <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> has been holding a series of hearings on government efficiency. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' investigative arm, told <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>'s committee last month that `` inadequate financial controls'' resulted in the loss of $ 4 billion at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>, more than $ 10 billion in military sales and loans to foreign governments and $ 12 billion dollars at the <ORGANIZATION> Commodity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Credit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> `` All of the major agencies have serious problems,'' Comptroller General <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> told the committee. `` Unfortunately, time and time again we find situations where agencies and auditors have identified problems, yet the corrective actions taken, if any, are ineffective and the problems remain uncorrected for years.'' In October, <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> told the committee the list of risky areas was being put together with the intention of devoting `` significant attention to correcting these vulnerabilities over time.'' `` I have instructed <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> budget staff to give priority to providing resources to needed corrections,'' <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> testified. He also said the problems encountered at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> `` are not unique.'' <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> said he asked federal managers to report weaknesses that might lead to waste and fraud, and their reports showed `` <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> was n't the worst. It was in the middle of the pack, which leads one to worry about any number of other big problems out there.'' The 27-page list covers the well-publicized problems at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> and at the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s nuclear plants and highlights numerous others. The list criticizes the financial controls set up for the Superfund environmental cleanup program. The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> does n't log some `` accounts receivable'' until payments come in, and the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s inspector general found $ 8 million of such accounts in one regional office, the report said. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> reported the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> has failed to collect more than $ 63 billion worth of delinquent taxes. The list also noted <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> compensation and pension programs have made $ 53 million in overpayments. Benefit decisions `` have not always been appropriate or correct,'' the document said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-06-89 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;LRegulator     12-06 0792</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;L Regulator,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hearings `Just the Beginning' of S&amp;L Probe: Gonzalez</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> says hearings that led to the resignation of savings and loan regulator <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Wall </PERSON> are `` just the beginning'' of his investigation of the <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L crisis. Wall resigned just two weeks after the committee completed 50 hours of hearings focusing on the regulator's handling of <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Irvine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> is expected to become the nation's biggest S & amp; L failure, expected to cost taxpayers more than $ 2 billion `` This is just the beginning,'' Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, said in a telephone interview Tuesday from his home in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>. `` We started with <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> because it's the prototype ... of everything that went wrong.'' <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> said he may conduct more hearings on <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> and the panel later would explore other S & amp; L failures, including <ORGANIZATION> Silverado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Colo </PERSON>. The Silverado case is politically sensitive because President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s son, <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, served on <PERSON> Silverado </PERSON>'s board of directors. <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> said the committee will concentrate on the constitutional question of how in 1988 Wall's agency, without specific congressional authorization, was able to commit the government to spending $ 40 billion on <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L rescues. The panel also will explore whether the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> should have more vigorously pursued shady S & amp; L executives. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> avoided questions about whether the president or his top aides wanted Wall to quit. `` He resigned and it will be accepted,'' he said. Under legislation enacted in August, the director of the thrift office serves a five-year term and must be confirmed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, which returns from holiday recess next month. According to an industry source, who spoke on condition of anonymity, <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> officials who oversee Wall's agency favor appointing an experienced regulator to succeed Wall. Early speculation is centered on several officials who have worked for either the Federal Reserve System or the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deposit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. Neither Wall nor his immediate predecessor, <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, had regulatory experience. Wall had served as staff director of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> under Sen. <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> <PERSON> Garn </PERSON>, R-Utah. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> was a former public relations executive and press secretary to <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s 1980 campaign. Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said the new thrift regulator `` has to be able to stand up to powerful interests within the industry, on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> and, frankly, within the administration. ... He's got to be able to inspire public confidence.'' `` You need someone who does not come out of the political environment as Wall did. Rather, you need a tough, experienced regulator who has a long history in banking regulation and knows the ins and outs of the industry,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, also a banking panel member. Wall, in a news conference announcing his resignation Monday, defended his record and said <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> resorted to `` corruption of the truth and abandonment of our historical devotion to fair play.'' <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> dismissed Wall's complaint Tuesday. `` Down here in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> ... we know that when a skunk is frightened and retreating _ that is when he is spraying the hardest.'' The committee chairman also rejected complaints his intense criticism of Wall had made it all but impossible for the administration to find someone else willing step into the cross fire. `` Watergate did n't deter people from running for the presidency,'' he said. Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Sporkin </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> was preparing to hear arguments Thursday in a lawsuit challenging the federal takeover of <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>. Among the witnesses subpoenaed are <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>'s parent company. <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bickwit </PERSON>, an attorney for <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION>, declined Tuesday to indicate whether <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> would testify or assert his Fifth Amendment right against self-incrimination. <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> is the subject of a federal grand jury probe in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and the target of a $ 1.1 billion federal fraud and racketeering suit. Among the 11 individual defendants in the fraud suit is <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>'s brother, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>, a former two-term <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> who is chief executive officer of the <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> and chairman of the board of directors of The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> is not accused of fraud or racketeering, but is named in three of 15 counts and is accused of negligence and breach of fiduciary duty. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>, who served on the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> board, has said he attended only two board meetings. His lawyer, <PERSON> Chester </PERSON> <PERSON> Kamin </PERSON>, has said he was seeking to have <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>'s name removed from the government's suit. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> on Tuesday declined to comment on the suit, saying, `` As long as this matter is in litigation, I'm not really able to discuss that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-06-89 0134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     12-06 0782</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0814</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s attorney general has decided against prosecuting a magazine for defamation after it quoted the wife of former Swedish tennis great <PERSON> Bjorn </PERSON> <PERSON> Borg </PERSON> as saying, `` Swedes are stupid nobodies.'' The remark attributed to <PERSON> Loredana </PERSON> <PERSON> Borg </PERSON>, a former Italian rock singer who married <PERSON> Borg </PERSON> in September, appeared on the advertising billboard of the celebrity and gossip weekly <PERSON> Svensk </PERSON> <PERSON> Damtidning </PERSON>. Attorney General <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Stark </PERSON> received a complaint from an unidentified person who said that the headline violated the law forbidding `` agitation against an ethnic group.'' Stark told the TT news agency on Tuesday he was dismissing the complaint.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version moving on financial wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>TAMPA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Industrialist <PERSON> Armand </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammer </PERSON> is receiving an honorary degree Thursday from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION>, which is sending a delegation thousands of miles to hand him the award. The group headed to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> on Tuesday to award Hammer a doctorate of humane letters. `` This is the first time an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> citizen has received a degree from an American university in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Clodius </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colleges </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Borkowski </PERSON> said the award recognizes Hammer's humanitarian, cultural and philanthropic contributions. `` Armand Hammer has been perhaps the single most influential American in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Borkowski </PERSON> said. `` He has contributed to glasnost and perestroika. That's why we are giving him the degree in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.'' Hammer, the 91-year-old chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, has been an unofficial business envoy to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> since 1921. He has used his influence to allow <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> doctors and rescue teams to travel to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to aid in the <LOCATION> Chernobyl </LOCATION> nuclear accident and the Armenian earthquake.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NORTH CHARLESTON, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' oldest member offered the secret of a long life as he marked his birthday: a good diet and exercise. `` If a person follows that, then they will have a chance to live a happier life and help humanity,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Strom </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>, <PERSON> R-S.C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>, who turned 87 Tuesday, said he watches his diet and exercises 50 minutes each morning, doing calisthenics, lifting weights and riding a stationary cycle. He said he also tries to keep an optimistic outlook on life. He came to this city just northwest of <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Transportation Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> to announce a $ 32 million emergency grant for repairs to highways damaged by Hurricane Hugo.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Wu'er <PERSON> Kaixi </PERSON> and <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Lu </PERSON>, exiled Chinese student leaders, accepted a $ 30,000 human rights award but lamented that two of their allies in the spring uprising at <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> were still in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. Rock star Sting presented the 1989 <ORGANIZATION> Reebok </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Award </ORGANIZATION> to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s crushed student democracy movement, represented by Wu'er and <PERSON> Li </PERSON> during a ceremony Tuesday. `` It is very frightening to me that I live and my children live in a world where governments routinely discard basic human decency and violate human rights,'' Sting said at the presentation. Wu'er sent a message to friends still in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, saying, `` Take care of yourselves when the cold of midnight hits you.'' A videotape interview with another student leader, <PERSON> Chai </PERSON> <PERSON> Ling </PERSON>, was flashed on a screen. `` She was my best friend in <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Li </PERSON> said. `` <PERSON> Chai </PERSON> <PERSON> Ling </PERSON> was the heart of the democracy movement.'' Organizers placed two empty chairs on the stage for <PERSON> Chai </PERSON>, whose name is on a wanted list and <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Dan </PERSON>, a student leader now in jail.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorean </PERSON> is back in the car business. Nationwide, 404 Toys `` R'' Us stores are selling a pint-size version of the <ORGANIZATION> De </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lorean </ORGANIZATION> car featured in the movie `` Back to the Future Part II'' under a licensing agreement between <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> and the former <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> automaker. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorean </PERSON> said he would get about 5 percent of the toy car's sales. `` By the time I give up on them, it will be ` Back to the Future Part 71,''' <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorean </PERSON> said Tuesday in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. In the original movie and the sequel, stars <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> use a modified <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorean </PERSON> to travel through time. The original <ORGANIZATION> De </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lorean </ORGANIZATION> _ a gull-winged door, stainless-steel body sports car _ was produced in <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, from 1981 until October 1982, when the British government shut down the plant after 9,000 cars were made. That month, <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorean </PERSON> was arrested on a drug trafficking charge in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, for which he was acquitted. He has been in and out of court since then in divorce and bankruptcy proceedings.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-06-89 0134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     12-06 0285</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0296</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cosby Helps NBC Win Sweeps</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY BUCK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON> and the rest of <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s Thursday night lineup helped the network win the ratings sweeps for November. November is one of four months in which the size of a network's audience is used to determine an affiliate's advertising rates <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> placed six shows, its Thursday programs plus `` The Golden Girls'' from Saturday, in last week's top 10, according to the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s average prime-time rating for the week was 15.4 <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s was 13.2 and CBS' 11.6. Each rating point represents the percentage of the nation's 92.1 million households tuned to a show. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> leads for the season with 15.0 to <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s 13.4 and CBS' 12.3. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Cosby Show'' was first, followed by <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Cheers'' and a Thursday night preview of its comedy series `` <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Jillian </PERSON>,'' which is slated for Sunday nights. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne'' was fourth. Others in top 10: <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Golden Girls,'' CBS' `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` L.A. Law,'' CBS' `` 60 Minutes'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Wonder Years,'' tied. The <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday night movie, `` Little White Lies,'' starring <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Jillian </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Matheson </PERSON>, was 17th for the week. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Hallmark Hall of Fame'' presentation of `` The <ORGANIZATION> Shell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seekers </ORGANIZATION>,'' starring <PERSON> Angela </PERSON> <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON>, tied for 22nd with <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Night Court.'' The lowest-rated network show was <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Living Dolls.'' Among the evening news shows, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` World News Tonight'' was first for the ninth straight week, including two ties with <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>. Its lead over the second place news show is the largest since the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> news show began in 1952. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> was first last week with 11.5, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> had 10.3 and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 10.2.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-06-89 0107EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DetroitNewspapers 1stLd-Writethru a0786 12-06 0326</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Detroit Newspapers, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0786,0328</SECOND>
<HEAD>Price Increases Announced for The Detroit News, Free Press</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 4th graf, `The Free ...' to CLARIFY News' editions; SUBS
7th graf, `William J. ...' to restore first reference to Detroit Newspaper
Agency; A version moved on financial wire.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> will increase the price of their daily papers to 25 cents from 15 cents and 20 cents, respectively, the newspapers announced Tuesday. The increases had been anticipated since the newspapers began a partial merger Nov. 27. Advertisers also will begin paying higher rates Sunday because of the joint operating agreement. The newspapers are merging business, advertising, production and circulation operations to cut costs while keeping separate news and editorial departments. The Free Press remains a morning newspaper weekdays. The News will have one morning edition available for street sales only and three editions for afternoon home delivery. There will be joint weekend editions under the masthead of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> and Free Press. The price for the Sunday edition will go up to $ 1 from 75 cents this Sunday. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. Hall, publisher and chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, said he hopes the newspapers, the ninth - and 10th-largest in the country, will maintain their circulation Home subscription rates will remain unchanged at least through December, said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>, president and chief executive officer of the <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, which handles business and publishing matters for the newspapers. Wednesday's edition of the Free Press said the DNA had begun telling advertisers of its new rates, but company officials declined to disclose the size of the increase. The <ORGANIZATION> JOA </ORGANIZATION>, first requested in 1986, was approved by then-Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> in 1988 but stalled by court challenges from a coalition of readers and advertisers. Legal delays ended Nov. 13, when the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s 4-4 tie on an appeal let stand lower court rulings upholding the agreement.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891206-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-06-89 0209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AZT-Tumors 1stLd-Writethru a0419 12-06 0509</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AZT-Tumors, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0419,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Health Officials See Little Cause for Cancer Concern for AZT Users</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: Recasts lede; SUBS 12th graf, `Of the ...' to insert dropped
word; picks up 13th graf, `The company ...' ^By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
