<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 2338EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TimesSued     01-13 0265</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Times Sued,0271</SECOND>
<HEAD>NAACP Drops Out of NY Times Suit</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> said Friday it had pulled out of a suit against <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> that charged the newspaper's real estate advertisements promote racial discrimination by featuring white models. Director Dr. <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hooks </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> `` suspended its participation'' because the organization had not held direct negotiations with the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> prior to filing the suit, contrary to longstanding policy. The suit was filed Thursday in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disrict </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> by the New York Open Housing Center and four individuals, along with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Colored People. `` While other members of the coalition met with representatives of the Times, the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> was not represented and hence the Times' publisher, <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochs </PERSON> <PERSON> Sulzberger </PERSON>, was correct when he complained that the lawsuit was filed without any discussion with the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Hooks </PERSON> said in a news release Hooks said the failure to hold direct talks occurred `` through an adminstrative oversight.'' Hooks said the suit had not been dropped and a meeting with <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> officials would be sought. `` We regret any confusion that might have arisen over this matter and have taken steps internally to see that such an oversight does not occur again,'' <PERSON> Hooks </PERSON> said. On Thursday, the Times issued a statement maintaining that its advertising conforms with anti-discrimination laws and saying the complaint appeared at first reading to be `` without merit.'' The plaintiffs said photos and drawings that accompany real estate ads in the Times `` depict whites almost exclusively as potential residents, thus indicating a preference based on race.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 2340EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-GayBashing     01-13 0203</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gay Bashing,0207</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Skinhead' Neo-Nazis Sentenced to Prison in Gay Bashing Case</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTA ANA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three `` skinhead'' members of a neo-Nazi youth gang were sentenced Friday to prison terms ranging from three to seven years for attacking a homosexual man in a <LOCATION> Laguna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> park. `` It's not your politics being punished here but your behavior,'' Superior Court Judge <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brickner </PERSON> told the men during sentencing in the highly publicized gay-bashing case. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Walther </PERSON>, 18, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 23, and <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> <PERSON> Fredrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Compean </PERSON>, 19, all of <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, were acquitted of attempted murder charges on Dec. 1 but were convicted of assault with a deadly weapon. <PERSON> Walther </PERSON> was sentenced to four years in prison, <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> to four years and eight months, and <PERSON> Compean </PERSON> to seven years for the July 14, 1988, attack on <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> at the city's <LOCATION> Heisler </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON>, 48, suffered serious injuries at the hands of the attackers. <PERSON> Compean </PERSON>'s use of a lead pipe was the reason for the lengthier sentence. The three had been roaming the <LOCATION> Laguna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> park in search of gay men to attack when they confronted <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON>, said <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Deputy District Attorney <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Avdeef </PERSON>, who won imposition of maximum sentences.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 2343EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Bush-Bowl     01-13 0571</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Bowl,0588</SECOND>
<HEAD>Immigrant's Dream Realized in Inaugural Crystal</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto PG5 of Jan. 13</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EARL BOHN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewczenko </PERSON> has n't mastered English yet, but he reached a pinnacle in the dwindling art of deep-cut crystal glassmaking when he cut the bowl <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will give <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Inauguration Day. `` It was like a dream come true,'' the shy Polish immigrant said from his job at the <ORGANIZATION> Lenox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crystal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> plant in <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pleasant </LOCATION>, 40 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Lewczenko </PERSON>, 39, is one of fewer than 25 master deep cutters in the country and of four on the <LOCATION> Lenox </LOCATION> staff. His experience cutting difficult designs nominated him for the bowls ordered by the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on the Inauguration, plant superintendent <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Eshland </PERSON> said Friday. <PERSON> Lewczenko </PERSON>, pronounced Lev-chenko, is not known as a talkative man. He did little more in a telephone interview than express his pride in the assignment and the finished piece. `` He's excited and bashful about all the publicity going on around him. He's not comfortable about it. He's -LRB- a -RRB- rather quiet man,'' his wife, <PERSON> Krystyna </PERSON>, 33, said from their home in Mount Pleasant. `` This is like <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> dream come true, especially ... coming to this country with 3-year-old kid, without language and $ 100 on hand,'' she said. <PERSON> Lewczenko </PERSON>'s pride was infectious, said <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Handyside </PERSON>, the 33-year-old <PERSON> Lenox </PERSON> designer who interpreted the congressional committee's ideas and worked side-by-side with <PERSON> Lewczenko </PERSON>. `` The enthusiasm was just overwhelming. That was part of the excitement in working with him,'' Miss <PERSON> Handyside </PERSON> said from <LOCATION> Lenox </LOCATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> Lawrenceville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J </LOCATION>. The first gift <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> receives Jan. 20 and the only one he's scheduled to get at the inaugural luncheon will be <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>'s crystal bowl of nearly 20 pounds and nearly 9 inches in diameter, according to Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> will receive a smaller version of the bowl, which <PERSON> Lwwczenko </PERSON> also cut. <PERSON> Lenox </PERSON> declined to reveal the price of the bowls. Blossoming cherry trees engraved on the front of each bowl frame a transparent area through which the west face of the Capitol is visible engraved on the far side of the bowl. The president's bowl rests on a 14-pound, beveled, lead glass plinth, or flat base. It is inscribed with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s name and the words `` Bicentennial Inauguration, Jan. 20, 1989.'' Rendering an architectural scene on a curved surface complicated the cutting, which was accomplished by holding the hefty piece against diamond-and carborundum-tipped cutting tools. `` It makes it even more difficult seeing through the glass to cut,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Potts </PERSON>, vice president of manufacturing for <ORGANIZATION> Lenox </ORGANIZATION>. `` The skill is to make sophisticated and accurate cuts when your're holding a heavy piece such as this. `` To hand hold this thing absolutely steady through the hours that it takes to polish this thing is absolutely unimaginable,'' Miss <PERSON> Handyside </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Lewczenko </PERSON> showed an aptitude for skilled work while sculpting clay as a child, his wife said. He studied at a glass-cutting school in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> then spent 20 years cutting glass there. He and his wife and son, <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON>, now 10, immigrated to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in April 1983, two weeks before huge antigovernment protests at the Lenin shipyards. <PERSON> Lewczenko </PERSON> worked as an maintenance man while building a glass-cutting machine at home to create pieces to prove himself as a cutter. A one-year stint at a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> glass studio led to his job at <LOCATION> Lenox </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 2343EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Goetz-Chronology     01-13 0369</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Goetz-Chronology,0390</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Chronology Of The Goetz Case</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in the Saturday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Goetz Sentencing, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a chronology of events in the <PERSON> Bernhard </PERSON> <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> case:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>1984</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 DEC. 22 _ Gunman shoots four young <PERSON> black </PERSON> men on subway train and escapes. DEC. 31 _ <PERSON> Bernhard </PERSON> <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON>, 37, of <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, surrenders to state police in <LOCATION> Concord </LOCATION>, N.H.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>1985</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 JAN. 3 _ <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> returns to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and is arraigned on charges of attempted murder and illegal weapons possession. JAN. 25 _ Grand jury indicts <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> for illegal weapons possession, rejecting charges of attempted murder. MARCH 27 _ Second grand jury hears new witnesses, including two of those wounded who had refused to testify to previous grand jury without grants of immunity. <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> indicted on four counts of attempted murder, one count of reckless endangerment, four counts of assault and illegal weapons charges. JAN. 16 _ Acting state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Crane </PERSON> drops attempted murder charges because he says grand jury was not properly instructed on laws of justification. JULY 8 _ The state's highest court, the <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>, reinstates attempted murder charges. DEC. 12 _ Jury selection begins.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>1987</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 APRIL 7 _ Jury selection completed, with half of those seated crime victims. APRIL 27 _ Trial opens with prosecutor calling <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> `` vicious, even sadistic'' in shooting the young men, while defense claims <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> `` gave the victims _ thugs _ what the law allows.'' JUNE 16 _ Jury acquits <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> of attempted murder but convicts him on one count of illegal gun possession. OCT. 19 _ <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> sentenced to six months in prison and five years' probation
</TEXT>
<NOTE>1988</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 JUNE 29 _ Appellate Division rules that six-month sentence for weapon possession is illegal because law mandates either one-year term or indeterminate sentence. Because of legal peculiarity, <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> would be eligible for release after serving two months of one-year term, but must complete four months of six-month term. NOV. 22 _ <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> upholds <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON>'s conviction for gun possession and agrees that six-month sentence was wrong.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>1989</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 JAN. 13 _ <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> resentenced to one year in jail and fined $ 5,000. He will be eligible for parole in 51 days.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 2352EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GoetzVictims     01-13 0576</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Goetz Victims,0603</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brief Sketches of Bernhard Goetz's Four Shooting Victims</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Goetz Sentencing, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are brief sketches of <PERSON> Bernhard </PERSON> <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON>'s four shooting victims, all of whom were 19 when <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> shot them on Dec. 22, 1984, with an unlicensed .38 - caliber <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON>, who was resentenced Friday to one year in jail for possessing the gun used in the shootings, has said he thought he was about to be mugged by the four as he rode the subway. The victims say they were only panhandling. Three of the victims, <PERSON> Darrell </PERSON> <PERSON> Cabey </PERSON>, <PERSON> Troy </PERSON> <PERSON> Canty </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramseur </PERSON>, filed lawsuits totaling $ 63.5 million against <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> that were consolidated in state court in October. The lawsuit could not proceed unless <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> was sentenced, ending his criminal trial, according to <PERSON> Cabey </PERSON> attorney <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Kunstler </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ <PERSON> Darrell </PERSON> <PERSON> Cabey </PERSON> was the most seriously injured of <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON>'s victims; he was paralyzed from the waist down and suffered brain damage During <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON>'s 1987 trial, a neurologist, <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Macaluso </PERSON>, testified that <PERSON> Cabey </PERSON> fell into a coma and `` a persistent vegetative state'' that lasted six weeks while hospitalized. `` He sits and watches TV. His mother struggles to make a life for him,'' <PERSON> Kunstler </PERSON> said Friday. <PERSON> Kunstler </PERSON> initially opposed the consolidation of the three lawsuits filed against <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> because he said the other two plaintiffs are notorious felons and <PERSON> Cabey </PERSON> would be prejudiced by association with them.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramseur </PERSON> was wounded in his left arm and chest He is serving an eight-year sentence at Coxsackie Correctional facility for raping and robbing a woman. During the trial, he said <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> attorney <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Slotnick </PERSON> tried to `` kill my credibility'' during courtroom questioning. `` I'm not the defendant. I was the victim of that crime,'' <PERSON> Ramseur </PERSON> said. After he refused to testify, he was taken from the court, held in contempt and his testimony was stricken from the record. `` I do n't feel that if I testified it would have made any difference,'' <PERSON> Ramseur </PERSON> said after the trial. <PERSON> Ramseur </PERSON> has said all along that he and <PERSON> Cabey </PERSON> were sitting when <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> started shooting. He said he thought the jury should have found <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> guilty of attempted murder and assault.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> claimed his Fifth Amendment right against self-incrimination 21 times after being sworn in during <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON>'s He was threatened with contempt. He was denied immunity from prosecution if he testified. He served time at <LOCATION> Rikers </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> city jail for violating parole for a necklace snatching. The state <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Friday that <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> was paroled in October.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ <PERSON> Troy </PERSON> <PERSON> Canty </PERSON> is a self-described former drug addict and ninth-grade dropout who calmly handled tough questioning by <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> attorney <PERSON> Slotnick </PERSON> On the stand, <PERSON> Canty </PERSON> wore a suit and tie and was well groomed. <PERSON> Slotnick </PERSON> placed a large photograph near Canty of him in sneakers and a jacket glaring at a photographer. <PERSON> Canty </PERSON> acknowledged his past: often in trouble in school, attacking a teacher, being sent to a psychiatric day school for `` hostile and assaultive'' behavior.'' He said he learned how to break into video machines when he was 14 or 15 and shoplifted in department stores. He started smoking marijuana at 13 or 14. By the time he met <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> on the subway, he said, he was using crack twice a day and had been arrested and convicted on theft charges. He testified he was no longer a drug addict and hoped to enter a cook training course.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 2357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-East-West-Accord     01-13 0233</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-East-West-Accord,0244</SECOND>
<HEAD>Key Provisions of Accord</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-East-West, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Key provisions of the human rights accord tentatively approved Friday by 35 nations at the <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> review conference:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ To give prisoners humane treatment, and stop the abuse of psychiatry against political prisoners; _ To decide outstanding emigration applications within six months, applications for <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc citizens to join Western spouses within three months, for family reunions within one month, and for urgent medical travel or funeral attendance within three days; _ To allow religious education, the dissemination of religious literature and church charity; _ To encourage tourism, particularly by allowing Western tourists to stay in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc homes; _ To allow freer spread of information, halting <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc jamming of Western radio stations; _ To stop expelling journalists or taking other measures against them over the content of their reports; _ To allow independent groups to monitor their governments' human rights behavior and action on the environment; _ To exchange much more economic data to facilitate Western business with the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>; _ To publish widely the text of the <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> Final Act, the <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> document and conditions for emigration or travel abroad; and _ To hold annual conferences on human rights, and to allow any <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> signatory to raise human rights affairs on a bilateral level with any other signatory state.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     01-13 0039</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0044</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Thursday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 6-5-1-4.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 03; 13; 23; 25; 29; 37. Bonus: 46677.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 0-5-8-3.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ScienceFront     01-13 0699</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Science Front,0722</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Science Front</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Similar version in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Among developments on the science front:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MEDICINE-BLACKS</NOTE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 New research indicates blacks have less access to medical care than whites. According to a 1986 nationwide telephone survey, one in 11 blacks reported not seeing a doctor for economic reasons, compared with one in 20 whites. And blacks who did go to a doctor may not have been treated as well as whites, the study said. The report, which appears in today's Journal of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, also said blacks were less likely to have health insurance. Another study in the Journal reviewed 50 medical studies of trials of new drugs published from 1984-1986 and found that blacks were included in less than two-thirds of them. A third study looked at racial inequities in use of medical procedures for heart-disease patients in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, and found that whites were 1.38 times more likely to undergo angiography, a technique for taking X-rays of the heart, and 2.26 times more likely to undergo bypass operations.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>OSTEOPOROSIS</NOTE>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Scientists say a new treatment for osteoporosis has proved successful in reversing the bone loss that afflicts an estimated 5 million Americans. A five-year clinical test reveals that use of a new slow-release form of sodium fluoride _ long used by dentists to strengthen teeth _ when given with calcium citrate can reverse the effects of osteoporosis by increasing bone mass, researchers at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> reported Thursday. Spinal osteoporosis, a gradual loss of a kind of bone found primarily in the spine, commonly affects elderly, postmenopausal women and results in shortened stature, curvature of the back and a protruding abdomen that can cause back pain and discomfort in the digestive system.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>ULCERS</NOTE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MEASLES</NOTE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> recommends two significant changes in the routine for measles vaccinations. _ Infants under 15 months old, in areas where recurrent measles is a problem, should get two measles shots instead of one _ a shot of measles vaccine alone at 9 months, and a second dose at 15 months of the commonly used measless-mumps-rubella vaccine. _ In schools with measles outbreaks _ and in nearby schools where the disease might spread _ all students whose measles shots came before 1980 should be re-vaccinated, along with their siblings. Measles specialists have discovered two major outbreak patterns in recent years: outbreaks among infants under the 15-month vaccination age and outbreaks among school-age children who have been vaccinated but still got measles anyway. As much as 10 percent of all vaccinations do n't provide the intended protection.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>HERPES</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Studies show that acyclovir, an antiviral drug, can reduce or eliminate recurrent outbreaks of genital herpes even when taken for more than a year, a researcher reported. Dr. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, a specialist in obstetrics and gynecology, said Thursday that a study involving 261 patients with active herpes infections showed that outbreaks of the disease were virtually eliminated for about half of those taking acyclovir twice daily. The others who took the drug experienced milder, shorter outbreaks. Although earlier studies showed that acyclovir was effective temporarily against herpes, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said the trial was the first to demonstrate that the antiviral drug is effective over many months. A report on the study was published this month in the journal Obstetrics and Gynecology.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 0058EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BelgianSoldier     01-13 0284</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Belgian Soldier,0291</SECOND>
<HEAD>Belgian Soldier Tells Police Killings Were Acts Of Revenge</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Belgian soldier assigned to his country's <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> embassy surrendered to police Thursday, saying he had killed two people here as revenge after breaking up with his male lover, authorities said. <PERSON> Rudy </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Den </PERSON> <PERSON> Borre </PERSON>, 25, surrendered after making several calls to police, challenging them to `` come and find me.'' He was booked into Broward County Jail without bond on two counts of first-degree murder. He told the officer who arrested him early Thursday that he'd killed two people and was planning another murder as revenge against the lover he'd just broken up with, the <LOCATION> Broward </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff's office said in a `` He had a lover's quarrel with his boyfriend up -LRB- in -RRB- the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> area,'' sheriff's Sgt. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Carney </PERSON> told reporters. `` He came down here, he was emotionally upset about that.'' Police statements said <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Den </PERSON> <PERSON> Borre </PERSON> arrived in south <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> Jan. 4 and wandered around the <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> beach area visiting gay hangouts. `` And he meets these people at local clubs, goes down on the beach with them and at some point decides that he's going to shoot and kill them,'' <PERSON> Carney </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Egan </PERSON>, a 36-year-old airline reservation clerk from <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION>, was found shot in the head Jan. 8. Less than 24 hours later, the body of <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> cab driver <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Simons </PERSON>, 52, was found, similarly killed. <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> police said both victims were homosexuals. Because <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Den </PERSON> <PERSON> Borre </PERSON> is a diplomatic employee, there is some question about his status before the law. Officials said the <ORGANIZATION> Belgian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> had been told of the charges against him and was cooperating in the investigation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BerettavsBeretta     01-13 0329</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Beretta vs Beretta,0339</SECOND>
<HEAD>Auto Buff Magazine Compares Pistol, Sedan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An automobile magazine that could n't resist the trademark battle between <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and an Italian gun maker did a `` road test'' comparison of <LOCATION> Beretta </LOCATION>, the pistol, and Beretta, the <LOCATION> Chevy </LOCATION>. Car and Driver, its editorial tongue planted firmly in its cheek, has a story in its current issue with the headline: `` We've shot from the hip before, but never like this.'' <PERSON> Fabbrica </PERSON> <PERSON> d'Armi </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Beretta </PERSON> SpA, the gun company, sued <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> for $ 250 million in federal court in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> last July, claiming that the car infringes on the pistol's trademark. The case is pending. The Car and Driver comparison was thought up by Editor <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeanes </PERSON>, and was written by <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Contributing Editor <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> McCall </PERSON>. `` For our test, we chose a 1989 Beretta V-6 GTU two-door notchback coupe and a 1989 Beretta 16-round Model 92F 9mm Parabellum, the spiffiest models in their respective lineups,'' <PERSON> McCall </PERSON> wrote. The magazine listed these details: Curb weight: Beretta, the pistol, 2.5 pounds; Beretta, the Chevy, 2,847 pounds. Top speed: Beretta, the gun, 878 mph -LRB- at the barrel end -RRB-; <LOCATION> Beretta </LOCATION>, the sedan, 114 mph. Price, as tested: Beretta, the semiautomatic, $ 596; Beretta, the car with an automatic transmission, $ 15,428. Along with the facts and figures, there are some performance opinions in the article: _ `` The Beretta 92F -LRB- the pistol -RRB- ... hates corners more than any device C-D has tested since the 1964 <ORGANIZATION> AMC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marlin </ORGANIZATION>.'' _ `` We liked the solid heft and natural feel of the Italian lightweight. It falls easily to hand. ... No such provision is designed into the five-speed Getrag shifter fitted to our <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> test sample, perhaps because while the Italian aims to be on the hip of everybody in uniform, the American aims only to be uniform among everybody hip.'' _ `` You can field-strip the Italian in minutes without tools, while the same task performed on the Chevy would require countless hours and untold broken fingernails.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 0106EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-NewVietnam     01-13 1045</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-New Vietnam,1076</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Leadership Changes Direction, Courts Capitalism</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE ESPER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HO CHI MINH CITY, Vietnam (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A generation ago, when this was <LOCATION> Saigon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> officers lived and played in the Rex Hotel, a sandbagged fortress frequently silhouetted against the night sky by flares and tracer bullets. Today, sedans instead of jeeps drive up to its doors, and uniformed doormen rather than military guards greet them. The <PERSON> Rex </PERSON> now beckons foreign businessmen and tourists, not soldiers. This is the new <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, leaving its course of economic self-destruction, opening its doors, courting capitalism. Its young are attuned more to American jeans, pop music and the good life than to a war with <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> they never really knew. `` In 1975, at that time, I was just seven; I do n't know anything,'' said Thu An, a 20-year-old classical violinist studying at the Ho Chi Minh Conservatory of Music. It was in April of 1975 that the long war ended. In the fifth floor restaurant of the <PERSON> Rex </PERSON>, beneath the chandeliers, Thu An entertains <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> tourists with such ballads as `` I Left My Heart In <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>'' and `` The Shadow of Your Smile'' as they dine on lobster and Chateaubriand. There even was a `` Happy Birthday'' salute _ that venerable bit of Americana _ for <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Gershen </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> travel agent who turned 47. Black-tied waiters brought a birthday cake decked with lighted candles. For the masses, things remain the same, at least for the moment. They struggle to survive along with their proud and stubborn country, which exiled itself and waited in vain for what it considered its due from the world for standing up to the Giant of the West. Throngs of unemployed wander the streets of <LOCATION> Ho </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Minh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, once the boisterous capital of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s unemployment rate is about 25 percent and the cost of living increased in 1988 by 7 percent to 11 percent a month. Like the violinist Thu An, many young Vietnamese have no emotional attachment to the war, in which the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> took part from 1961 to 1975. They are restless, impatient, looking to personal futures of education, jobs and travel abroad. They envy affluent <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> neighbors and countrymen who went to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> as refugees and prospered. Some older southerners live in the past, the good old days when millions of American dollars propped up the economy and brought <PERSON> Saigonese </PERSON> the luxuries they no longer can afford. More workers and government officials are speaking out about the hardships. <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Thuong </PERSON>, maitre d'hotel at the Ramuncho Restuarant favored by Americans in the war years, is unhappy with the measly $ 50 a month he is paid for the same job at the Rex. `` I do not have enough food for my family,'' said <PERSON> Thuong </PERSON>, who is 53 and has six children. `` I work much but I receive nothing. At Ramuncho, I was happy.'' He looked around the room and added: `` There are government officials everywhere, but we do n't scare because our life go down.'' Some officials agree with him. One is <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> <PERSON> Xuan </PERSON> <PERSON> Oanh </PERSON>, a Harvard-educated economist for the old <LOCATION> Saigon </LOCATION> regime who advises the communist government in <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> and serves in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. `` It has deteriorated,'' he said. `` We try very hard to keep some of the hotels in a decent state so the foreign investors can come in. We need capital. We need more industrial ventures. We need technology. We have plenty of labor.'' The Vietnamese look to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for these necessities of transition from failed central planning to a market-oriented economy that allows free enterprise, competition and foreign investment. <PERSON> Oanh </PERSON> said it does not mean the end of communism, or socialism as it is called here. He explained: `` Socialism is not an end in itself. There are so many variations of the same thing. We try very hard to keep away from ideology. `` Whatever the Americans, the Europeans have done, this is the result of thousands of years of experience. Let's just take that. Do n't say this belongs to capitalism or what. Take the best of both worlds and build the economy of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>.'' In keeping with the new approach, <PERSON> Oanh </PERSON> was blunt in evaluating the economy: `` We have had a lot of state enterprise, but these guys are no good because they just wait for the government. ... They do n't care whether -LRB- what they make -RRB- can be sold or not. `` Now it's different. We now allow the private businessman to really worry about production so they have to watch their step. They have to worry about marketing, everything, just like any other businessman.'' <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> now imports three times more than it exports, but officials hope the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will help by providing financial aid and lifting its trade embargo once diplomatic relations are established. They say that should happen within a few years. A major sticking point is the Vietnamese occupation of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, which began with an invasion in December 1978. Occupation troops and the government <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> installed are fighting a civil war with Cambodian guerrillas. `` If there is a political solution, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> will withdraw all its troops at the latest by next September,'' said Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Tran </PERSON> <PERSON> Cong </PERSON> <PERSON> Man </PERSON>, editor of the army newspaper. `` If there is no political solution now, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> will withdraw all its troops in 1990. There will be nothing to settle and to debate. Then the Americans will have no reason not to establish diplomatic relations.'' Half a million southerners, many of whom worked for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government, have applied for exit visas to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, to join relatives or in hopes of jobs and business opportunities. Tens of thousands have spent years trying to get out and their struggle has an ironic counterpoint: Members of the first emigrant wave, many of them now American citizens, return by the thousands for short visits with relatives and pour badly needed dollars into the economy. Gen. <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> <PERSON> Vinh </PERSON> <PERSON> Nghi </PERSON>, 58, who was captured by North Vietnamese troops shortly before the fall of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> on April 30, 1975, hopes to take his wife and three children to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He was released from prison camp a year ago and says: `` I have nothing to do here.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ArtScandal     01-13 0853</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Art Scandal,0881</SECOND>
<HEAD>Art Swindles Tarnish French Museums</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARILYN AUGUST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 75-year-old widow in need of money said officials tricked her out of a masterpiece for a pittance. A court agreed, giving the first round to her in one of three swindles that have shaken the French museum world. Last month, the court convicted the city of <LOCATION> Strasbourg </LOCATION> and its <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Decorative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> fraud </ORGANIZATION> in the purchase from <PERSON> Marie-Madeleine </PERSON> <PERSON> Falbisaner </PERSON> of an unsigned painting attributed to <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Vouet </PERSON>, court painter of King Louis XIII. When the museum did not return the painting as ordered, a magistrate charged chief curator <PERSON> Jean-Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ludmann </PERSON>, 51, with `` breach of trust,'' for failing to do so. `` My family has lived for generations in <LOCATION> Strasbourg </LOCATION> and I wanted the family heirloom to remain here,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Falbisaner </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. `` This is what I get for being sentimental. I was gypped.'' <PERSON> Ludmann </PERSON>, the museum and <LOCATION> Strasbourg </LOCATION> have appealed. A decision is expected within two years and Mrs. <PERSON> Falbisaner </PERSON> hopes to recover the painting, now in storage at the museum. `` Knock wood, I wo n't die before then,'' she said. Also in December, charges were brought against <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenberg </PERSON>, chief curator of paintings at the <LOCATION> Louvre </LOCATION>, for involvement in the purchase of a work by 17th century portraitist <PERSON> Bartolome </PERSON> <PERSON> Esteban </PERSON> <PERSON> Murillo </PERSON> for half its estimated worth. <PERSON> Rosenberg </PERSON>, a scholar with an international reputation, was accused of either knowing or purposely ignoring the fact that the painting, `` The Gentleman of <LOCATION> Seville </LOCATION>,'' might have been stolen from its owner, an elderly, eccentric heiress who died under suspicious circumstances in 1986. Another elderly widow saw justice done in December when an unsigned painting by <PERSON> Nicolas </PERSON> <PERSON> Poussin </PERSON> was returned to her and she sold it for $ 1.4 million. Twenty years ago, her husband sold it for the equivalent of $ 366 to the <LOCATION> Louvre </LOCATION>, whose experts had noticed the mislabeled painting in a sale catalogue. After the museum displayed it as a <LOCATION> Poussin </LOCATION>, the family sued. The court ruled that the <LOCATION> Louvre </LOCATION> did not have the right to use its vast resources and expertise to cheat ordinary citizens. French museums have been an elite preserve, some say above the law, so newspapers recounted the unfolding dramas like installments in a seamy soap opera. `` Is there something rotten in the kingdom of museums?'' art critic <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON> <PERSON> Foucart </PERSON> asked in <ORGANIZATION> Beaux </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION>, recalling <PERSON> Hamlet </PERSON>'s moral dilemma. `` Curator Tripped Up By Canvas,'' one headline sniffed. An editorial by <PERSON> Gerard </PERSON> <PERSON> Dupuy </PERSON> in the newspaper Liberation was called `` The Scholar Gone Astray.'' The latest episode is known as the Vouet Affair for the 17th century portraitist who experts say is the likely creator of Mrs. <PERSON> Falbisaner </PERSON>'s unsigned `` Allegory of Force.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Falbisaner </PERSON>'s story began in 1986 when she decided to supplement her monthly pension of about $ 450 by selling `` Allegory'' to the city of <LOCATION> Strasbourg </LOCATION> for about $ 55,000. It had been in the family for more than 250 years and was believed to be the work of <PERSON> Vouet </PERSON>, who introduced the Italian Baroque School to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. Experts examined the painting before the sale, however, and to Mrs. <PERSON> Falbisaner </PERSON>'s chagrin, concluded it was a high-quality example of the Vouet school but not by the master himself. The museum still was interested, however, and curator <PERSON> Ludmann </PERSON> borrowed the work to examine its condition, a standard procedure. Without telling Mrs. <PERSON> Falbisaner </PERSON>, he took the painting to the <LOCATION> Louvre </LOCATION> for laboratory examinations, including X-rays. Tests indicated the work was by <PERSON> Vouet </PERSON>, or at the very least attributable to him. That information was not passed on to Mrs. <PERSON> Falbisaner </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ludmann </PERSON> sent an enthusiastic letter to city officials urging them to approve the sale. The tests, he wrote, `` reveal the existence of several retouchings by the artist himself.'' He said the price was `` more than reasonable, and assuredly advantageous, given <PERSON> Vouet </PERSON>'s fame and his value on today's market.'' Both the <LOCATION> Louvre </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Strasbourg </LOCATION> officials have denied formally authenticating the work as a <ORGANIZATION> Vouet </ORGANIZATION>. `` I'm convinced the essentials of the painting _ its composition, idea and colors _ are <PERSON> Vouet </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Ludmann </PERSON> told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, but added that he can not be certain because the work is unsigned. Big money is at stake. In today's art market, a Vouet is estimated to be worth up to $ 500,000, nearly 10 times what the museum agreed to pay Mrs. <PERSON> Falbisaner </PERSON>. Many in the art world say privately they are delighted to see museums get a comeuppance, but have closed ranks publicly, dismissing the scandals as the price of becoming fashionable. `` Ten years ago, no one outside the museum world would have noticed,'' one said privately. `` Today, a curator is a superstar who appears on television and dines with the mayor.'' <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Cremin </PERSON>, a respected art critic, said: `` The museums, because of their limited acquisitions budgets, have to be on the lookout for bargains. `` These kinds of affairs have probably happened countless times in the past. The difference is the money involved. The ordinary person today hires a good lawyer to get the property back, and the story makes the papers.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Grammy-Chapman     01-13 0589</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Grammy-Chapman,0614</SECOND>
<HEAD>Recording Industry's Newest Star Revives Singer-Songwriter Tradition</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>^With PM-Grammys, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOLORES BARCLAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Arts Editor</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON> seems of another time, a time when <PERSON> Dylan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Odetta </PERSON>, <PERSON> Seeger </PERSON> and <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON> celebrated freedom and the spirit of man, and defied brutality and repression with their songs and anthems. <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, whose self-titled debut album has been nominated for six Grammys, is of this age and her songs take a hard, cold look at poverty, racism, inequality and human relations. She is uncompromising, tough and compassionate. `` I think people look at the world in many different ways and choose to see what they like,'' she said in an interview last year with <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. `` I think lots of people ignore some of the harder issues, the more unpleasant things. I do n't think I harp on them.'' Her LP opens with `` Talkin' Bout a Revolution,'' a song that tells of `` standing in the welfare lines Crying at the doorsteps of those armies of salvation Wasting time in the unemployment lines Sitting around waiting for a promotion Poor people gon na rise up And get their share Poor people gon na rise up And take what's theirs.'' Until `` <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>'' hit record stores last April, the 24-year-old poet-singer-songwriter-folksinger was one of the <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> area's best kept secrets. As an anthrolopolgy major at <ORGANIZATION> Tufts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Medford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, she performed in coffee houses and clubs, and was a local hit. The LP, with its range from folk to pop ballad to reggae, enchanted millions more. It has sold over 4 million copies and has been nominated for album of the year and best contemporary folk recording. The single, `` Fast Car,'' has been nominated for best song and record of the year, and <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON> herself is up for best new artist and best female pop vocalist. `` Fast Car'' was a No. 1 hit and tells of a high school dropout who works to supports her alcoholic father and who wants to escape it all with her unemployed boyfriend: `` You got a fast car And I got a plan to get us out of here I been working at the convenience store Managed to save just a little bit of money We wo n't have to drive too far Just ` cross the border and into the city You and I can both get jobs And finally see what it means to be living. <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>'s rich contralto with its melancholic underpinnings is an instrument by itself and highly effective on `` Behind the Wall,'' a song about a battered woman. She sings a capella of the harsh realties of the domestic fight: `` Last night I heard the screaming - Then a silence that chilled my soul'' _ and slams the police for doing nothing. She grew up in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> and has been singing since she was a child. She was in a <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> boarding school when singer-songwriters had been put out to pasture by synthesizer philistines. <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON> did n't turn on her radio, but many of her classmates listened to folk music and played guitar. In college, one of her classmates was <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Koppelman </PERSON>, whose father, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, is a leader in the music publishing business. This gave her the wedge she needed to gain entry to the recording world. <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, whose musical roots can be traced to <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Armatrading </PERSON>, <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> and <PERSON> Joni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, was part of a new wave of singer-songwriters in the late 1980s, especially women such as <PERSON> Toni </PERSON> <PERSON> Childs </PERSON>, <PERSON> Marti </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON> <PERSON> Etheridge </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Shocked </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HomelessSchools 2ndLd-Writethru a0781 01-13 0661</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Homeless Schools, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0781,0677</SECOND>
<HEAD>Signs of Homeless Students Prompt School-Based Shelters</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 7 grafs to UPDATE with eight seeking refuge; picks
up 8th graf: `Houston is ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF AWALT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOUSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Public school officials, concerned that students may be living on the streets, opened homeless shelters in two <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> schools Thursday so needy pupils can get beds, showers and a meal. A 12-year-old girl who had been sleeping under an abandoned house was the first of eight people to enter the shelters, officials said. `` We did n't discuss anything with the child when she came in,'' said school board President <PERSON> Melody </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON>. `` Right now she's playing checkers with one of the administrators. We just tried to give her encouragement and let her play.'' The shelters will remain open nightly until at least Jan. 20, when the superintendent the <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> will recommend to the school board that the program be continued or modified. Within an hour of opening, six children arrived at the shelters, and Ms. <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> said four other young boys who showed up at one of the campuses left before entering, apparently because of television cameras nearby. `` It is drizzling outside and it is extremely cold, and I would really like for these children to come in,'' Ms. <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> said when asking reporters to leave the area. Temperatures were in the low 40s Thursday night. By late evening eight youths and one parent were in the two shelters, including a homeless woman with five children, all enrolled in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> schools, and a 14-year-old dropout. <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> is estimated to have 20,000 to 25,000 people who live on the streets or in shelters, but it's uncertain how many of those are children. The school shelters are not intended for children whose families are staying in city shelters, but rather for those pupils who seem to live alone on the streets. `` We've had teachers discovering students sleeping in areas around schools, storing clothes under houses in the neighborhood and some who are asking for help,'' school district spokesman <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Yawn </PERSON> said. It's not certain why those pupils are on the streets, however. <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hay </PERSON>, of <ORGANIZATION> Harris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protective </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, said use of the term `` homeless'' for the school program may be a misnomer. `` I know there's children out there,'' she said. `` But I certainly did n't think they were in school. These children have a home somewhere, but they either are abused or choose not to be at home.'' Ms. <PERSON> Hay </PERSON> said programs already exist for `` truly homeless'' children, whose parents, for example, may be living out of their cars. Other social service programs also exist for children who need a `` cooling-off'' time away from their parents, she said. `` There are vacancies in shelters right now,'' Ms. <PERSON> Hay </PERSON> said. `` It's going to be interesting to find out what these principals have been seeing.'' Under the Schoolhouse Shelters program, approved this week and announced Wednesday, volunteers from the school system and other social agencies will staff the shelters, which officials hope may lead to more permanent assistance for homeless youths seeking help in a familiar place. One school is set up to handle children from kindergarten through eighth grade. The other is intended for high school students. The <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> has donated 75 beds and blankets. Existing showers and dressing rooms in gymnasiums of the schools will be used, officials said. The cost to the school district, while not yet determined, should be minimal, officials said. The district is providing food _ soup and sandwiches _ and security guards. The program will serve only students enrolled in the <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION>, among the nation's 10-largest districts with about 190,000 students. Security officers will guard against drugs and weapons, and <PERSON> Yawn </PERSON> said hand-held metal detectors will be used at the school entrance. Students entering the shelters, operated from 5:30 p.m. until 7 a.m., will have to prove they are enrolled before entering.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Grammys-List 4Takes   01-13 0633</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Grammys-List, 4 Takes,0653</SECOND>
<HEAD>A List of 31st Annual Grammy Nominees</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Grammys Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Complete list of nominees for the 31st annual Grammy Awards: 1. RECORD OF THE YEAR: `` Do n't Worry, Be Happy,'' <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> McFerrin </PERSON>; `` Fast Car,'' <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>; `` Giving You the Best that I Got,'' <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>; `` Man in the Mirror,'' <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>; `` Roll With It,'' <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Winwood </PERSON>. 2. ALBUM OF THE YEAR: `` Faith,'' <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>; `` ... Nothing Like the Sun,'' Sting; `` Roll With It,'' <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Winwood </PERSON>; `` Simple Pleasures,'' <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> McFerrin </PERSON>; `` <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>. 3. SONG OF THE YEAR: `` Be Still My Beating Heart,'' Sting; `` Do n't Worry, Be Happy,'' <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> McFerrin </PERSON>; `` Fast Car,'' <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>; `` Giving You the Best that I Got,'' <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>; `` Piano in the Dark,'' <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>. 4. NEW ARTIST: <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Astley </PERSON>, <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Toni </PERSON> <PERSON> Childs </PERSON>, Take 6, <PERSON> Vanessa </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. 5. POP VOCAL, FEMALE: `` Chalk Mark in a Rain Storm,'' <PERSON> Joni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>; `` Fast Car,'' <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>; `` Get Here,'' <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>; `` One Moment in Time,'' <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> <PERSON> Houston </PERSON>; `` Tell It to My Heart -LRB- Album -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> <PERSON> Dayne </PERSON>. 6. POP VOCAL, MALE: `` Be Still My Beating Heart,'' Sting; `` Do n't Worry, Be Happy,'' <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> McFerrin </PERSON>; `` Father Figure,'' <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>; `` A Groovy Kind of Love,'' <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>; `` Roll With It,'' <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Winwood </PERSON> 7. POP VOCAL, DUO OR GROUP: `` Anything for You -LRB- Spanish Version -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Gloria </PERSON> <PERSON> Estefan </PERSON> and The <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Sound Machine; `` Brasil,'' <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> Transfer; `` <LOCATION> Kokomo </LOCATION>,'' Beach Boys; `` Piano in the Dark,'' <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Esposito </PERSON>; `` Wild, <ORGANIZATION> Wild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Escape </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>. 8. POP INSTRUMENTAL: `` Always With Me, Always With You,'' <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Satriani </PERSON>; `` Close Up,'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanborn </PERSON>; `` Music From <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Otherwise,'' <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Post </PERSON>; `` Pump Up The Volume,'' M-A-R-R-S; `` Silhouette,'' <PERSON> Kenny </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> 9. ROCK VOCAL, FEMALE: `` All Fired Up,'' <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Benatar </PERSON>; `` Bring Me Some Water,'' <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON> <PERSON> Etheridge </PERSON>; `` Do n't Walk Away,'' <PERSON> Toni </PERSON> <PERSON> Childs </PERSON>; `` The Lion and the Cobra,'' <PERSON> Sinead </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>; `` <PERSON> Tina </PERSON> <PERSON> Live </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Tina </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>. 10. ROCK VOCAL, MALE: `` After Midnight,'' <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Clapton </PERSON>; `` Forever Young,'' <PERSON> Rod </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>; `` <PERSON> Robbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Robbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>; `` Simply Irresistible,'' <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON>; `` Unchain My Heart,'' <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Cocker </PERSON>. 11. `` ROCK VOCAL, DUO OR GROUP: `` Beds Are Burning,'' Midnight Oil; `` Desire,'' U2; `` I Hate Myself for Loving You,'' <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jett </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Blackhearts </ORGANIZATION>; `` Kick -LRB- Album -RRB-,'' <ORGANIZATION> INXS </ORGANIZATION>; `` Let It Roll,'' Little Feat 12. ROCK INSTRUMENTAL: `` Blues for <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Santana </PERSON>; `` Guitar,'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Zappa </PERSON>; `` Hideaway,'' The <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Healey </PERSON> <PERSON> Band </PERSON>; `` Surfing with the Alien,'' <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Satriani </PERSON>; `` Writes of Winter,'' <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Page </PERSON>. 13. HARD ROCK-METAL VOCAL OR INSTRUMENTAL: `` ... And Justice for All,'' <PERSON> Metallica </PERSON>; `` Blow Up Your Video,'' <ORGANIZATION> AC </ORGANIZATION> @ <ORGANIZATION> DC </ORGANIZATION>; `` Cold Metal,'' Iggy Pop; `` Crest of a Knave,'' <PERSON> Jethro </PERSON> <PERSON> Tull </PERSON>; `` Nothing's Shocking,'' <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>'s Addiction. 14. RHYTHM & amp; BLUES VOCAL, FEMALE: `` Girlfiend,'' Pebbles; `` Giving You the Best that I Got,'' <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>; `` I'll Always Love You,'' <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> <PERSON> Dayne </PERSON>; `` The Right Stuff -LRB- Single -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Vanessa </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>; `` The Way You Love Me,'' <PERSON> Karyn </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>. 15. RHYTHM & amp; BLUES VOCAL, MALE: `` Any Love,'' <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> Vandross </PERSON>; `` Characters,'' <PERSON> Stevie </PERSON> <PERSON> Wonder </PERSON>; `` Introducing The Hardline According to <PERSON> Terence </PERSON> <PERSON> Trent </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Arby </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Terence </PERSON> <PERSON> Trent </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Arby </PERSON>; `` Joy,'' <PERSON> Teddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Pendergrass </PERSON>; `` Nite and Day,'' Al B. Sure!. 16. RHYTHM & amp; BLUES VOCAL, DUO OR GROUP: `` Acting This Way,'' The <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Cray </PERSON> <PERSON> Band </PERSON>; `` Da' Butt,'' E.U.; `` If it is n't Love,'' New Edition; `` Love Overboard,'' <ORGANIZATION> Gladys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Knight </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; the Pips; `` Rocket 2 U,'' The Jets. 17. RHYTHM & amp; BLUES INSTRUMENTAL: `` Coast to Coast,'' <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dupree </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Who It Is; `` I Came to Play,'' <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, Jr.; `` Light Years,'' <LOCATION> Chick </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Corea </LOCATION>; `` Reflections,'' <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>; `` So Amazing,'' <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Albright </PERSON>; `` What's Going On,'' <PERSON> Doc </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>. 18. RHYTHM & amp; BLUES SONG: `` Any Love,'' <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> Vandross </PERSON>; `` Do n't Be Cruel,'' <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>; `` Giving You the Best that I Got,'' <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>; `` I'll Always Love You,'' <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> <PERSON> Dayne </PERSON>; `` Just Got Paid,'' <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> 19. RAP: `` Going Back to <LOCATION> Cali </LOCATION>,'' L.L. Cool J; `` Parents Just Do n't Understand,'' D.J. <ORGANIZATION> Jazzy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jeff </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; The Fresh Prince; `` Push It,'' <PERSON> Salt-N-Pepa </PERSON>; `` Supersonic,'' <PERSON> J.J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fad </PERSON>; `` Wild Wild West,'' <PERSON> Kool </PERSON> <PERSON> Moe </PERSON> <PERSON> Dee </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 0131EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BushBuddies Bjt   01-13 0680</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush Buddies, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Known as `Ellie the Elephant' After Wartime Rescue</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Surviving crew members of the World War II submarine Finback are looking forward to a nostalgic reunion with <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the young <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> pilot they dubbed `` Ellie the Elephant'' after rescuing him from the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> more than 44 years ago. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohler </PERSON>, 64, of <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Ark. </LOCATION>, the torpedoman who helped pull a grateful <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to safety from his orange life raft onto the Finback's deck, remembers offering a smile and a hearty `` welcome aboard,'' but recalls little else about the incident `` At that time, he was just another downed pilot,'' said <PERSON> Kohler </PERSON>, a retired <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> businessman. `` Nobody back then knew he'd become president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' Rescued after his plane was shot down by Japanese fire, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> eagerly took his turn at night lookout watches and other seagoing duties, watched <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Grable </PERSON> movies in the wardroom and donned earphones to listen in awe as the submarine's torpedoes sank two enemy ships. Former Finback officers remember the 20-year-old <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as a gregarious jokester who earned the nickname `` Ellie'' for his comic wardroom imitation of a trumpeting elephant, they said in recent telephone interviews. `` I remember he was very lively, obviously intelligent and very personable,'' said retired Rear Adm. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Heyworth </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, who was the Finback's torpedo and gunnery officer when <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was hauled aboard on Sept. 2, 1944. Said <PERSON> Heyworth </PERSON>: `` All three pilots we rescued were bright, bright-eyed young men, but <PERSON> George </PERSON> seemed the most outgoing and had the most ebullient personality. He was the most entertaining, and he made us laugh a lot. `` We called him <PERSON> Ellie </PERSON> because of his outstanding imitation of an elephant trumpeting. <PERSON> Ellie </PERSON> the Elephant. It was n't because we all sat around thinking we were Republicans. We must have seen one in a Tarzan movie. We just thought elephants were funny. We kept asking <PERSON> George </PERSON> to do it over and over again.'' `` He had a tremendous sense of humor,'' recalled W.E. `` Bill'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, an insurance agent and retired <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> commander. As a bearded ensign aboard the Finback, <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> filmed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s rescue with an 8mm Kodak movie camera. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said that at last count, nearly 30 surviving officers and enlisted crewmen of the Finback were planning to attend <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s swearing-in at noontime Jan. 20 at the Capitol They and a few of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s former flying buddies plan to sit together in prime bleacher seats on <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION> for the inaugural parade after <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> takes the presidential oath of office. Inaugural officials reportedly were trying to arrange a reunion for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his old submarine buddies at <ORGANIZATION> Blair </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the presidential guest quarters across the street from the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, possibly next Wednesday. <PERSON> Heyworth </PERSON> and <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> have stayed in touch with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> over the years. But most of the Finback veterans have n't seen or spoken to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> since he left the submarine at <LOCATION> Midway </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> after a month-long combat patrol. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> won the Distinguished Flying Cross for completing his bombing run against a <ORGANIZATION> Japanese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> center </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> Bonin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, about 600 miles south of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, after his Grumman Avenger torpedo bomber was struck by enemy fire and engulfed in flames. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> bailed out over the water but his two crew members were lost. According to his autobiography, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s only injuries were a gash on the forehead and a painful sting from a Portuguese man-of-war. He was picked up by the Finback less than two hours after his parachute hit the ocean. `` I'm proud of what I was able to do to help Mr. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on board our boat,'' said <PERSON> Kohler </PERSON>. But <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Moody </PERSON>, 71, a Finback veteran and retired radiation laboratory technician living in <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, gave little thought to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> at the time. `` We brought him aboard, dried him out and gave him hot coffee,'' he said, and then forgot him. `` I was 26 years old and a first class torpedoman,'' <ORGANIZATION> Moody </ORGANIZATION> said. `` Who'd pay any attention to a 20-year-old kid?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Grammys-List-1stAdd     01-13 0706</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Grammys-List - 1st Add,0724</SECOND>
<HEAD>BEVERLY HILLS, Moe Dee.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 20. NEW AGE: `` Castalia,'' <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Isham </PERSON>; `` Down in <LOCATION> Belgorod </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Winter </PERSON>; `` Folksongs for a Nuclear Village,'' <PERSON> Shadowfax </PERSON>; `` Local Color,'' <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Mounsey </PERSON>; `` Neverland,'' <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Ciani </PERSON>. 21. JAZZ FUSION: `` Amaretto,'' <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>; `` Every Step of the Way,'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Benoit </PERSON>; `` <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Patitucci </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Patitucci </PERSON>; `` Street Dreams,'' <PERSON> Lyle </PERSON> <PERSON> Mays </PERSON>. 22. JAZZ FIELD, FEMALE: `` Autumn Leaves,'' <PERSON> Rickie </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>; `` Fine and Mellow,'' <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> <PERSON> McRae </PERSON>; `` Look What I Got!'' <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>; `` The Men in My Life,'' <PERSON> Lena </PERSON> <PERSON> Horne </PERSON>; `` Miss <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> Sings the Blues,'' <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>. 23. JAZZ FIELD, MALE: `` Brother,'' <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> McFerrin </PERSON>; `` Ever Since the World Ended,'' <PERSON> Mose </PERSON> <PERSON> Allison </PERSON>; `` Live in <LOCATION> Montreux </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Joao </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilberto </PERSON>; `` September Ballads,'' <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>; `` A Vintage Year,'' <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Torme </PERSON>. 24. JAZZ VOCAL PERFORMANCE, DUO OR GROUP: `` The <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> <PERSON> McRae </PERSON> - <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> <PERSON> Duets </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> <PERSON> McRae </PERSON> and <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>; `` I Wo n't Leave You Again,'' <PERSON> Lena </PERSON> <PERSON> Horne </PERSON> and <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>; `` One More Rose,'' <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Cain </PERSON> and <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kral </PERSON>; `` Spread Love,'' Take 6; `` Stings' n' Swing ` I Remember Bird,''' 25. JAZZ INSTRUMENTAL, SOLOIST: `` Do n't Try this at Home,'' <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Brecker </PERSON>; `` Duets,'' <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Wasserman </PERSON>; `` Music from Siesta,'' <PERSON> Miles </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>; `` Random Abstract,'' <LOCATION> Branford </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Marsalis </LOCATION>; `` The <LOCATION> Winton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Marsalis </LOCATION> Quartet Live at <LOCATION> Blues </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alley </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Wynton </PERSON> <PERSON> Marsalis </PERSON>. 26. JAZZ INSTRUMENTAL, GROUP: `` Amnesia,'' <ORGANIZATION> Chick </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION>; `` Blues for <PERSON> Coltrane </PERSON>; A Tribute to <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Coltrane </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyner </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pharoah </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON>, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cecil </PERSON> <PERSON> McBee </PERSON> and <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>; `` Random Abstract,'' <ORGANIZATION> Branford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marsalis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Quartet </ORGANIZATION>; `` Still Live,'' <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarrett </PERSON> Trio; `` The Wynton Marsalis Quartet Live at <LOCATION> Blues </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alley </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Winton </PERSON> <PERSON> Marsalis </PERSON> <PERSON> Quartet </PERSON>. 27. JAZZ INSTRUMENTAL, BIG BAND: `` <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Holman </PERSON> <PERSON> Band </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Holman </PERSON> <PERSON> Band </PERSON>; `` Bud & amp; Bird,'' <PERSON> Gil </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> and The Monday Night Orchestra; `` Ebony,'' <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> <PERSON> Herman </PERSON>'s Thundering Herd; `` <PERSON> Jacquet </PERSON>'s Got It!,'' <PERSON> Illinois </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacquet </PERSON> And His Big Band; `` Tribute to Count Basie,'' The <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> All-Star Big Band 28. COUNTRY VOCAL, FEMALE: `` Back in Baby's Arms,'' <PERSON> Emmylou </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>; `` Hold Me,'' K.T. <PERSON> Oslin </PERSON>; `` I'm Down to My Last Cigarette,'' k.d. lang; `` Reba,'' <PERSON> Reba </PERSON> <PERSON> McEntire </PERSON>; `` Strong Enough to Bend,'' <PERSON> Tanya </PERSON> <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>. 29. COUNTRY VOCAL, MALE: `` Addicted,'' <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Seals </PERSON>; `` <ORGANIZATION> Buenas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Noches </ORGANIZATION> from a Lonely Room,'' <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Yoakam </PERSON>; `` Diamonds & amp; Dirt,'' <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Crowell </PERSON>; `` Old 8 X 10,'' <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Travis </PERSON>; `` <LOCATION> Pontiac </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Lyle </PERSON> <PERSON> Lovett </PERSON>. 30. COUNTRY VOCAL, DUO OR GROUP: `` Big Dreams in a Small Town,'' Restless Heart; `` Give a Little Love,'' The <ORGANIZATION> Judds </ORGANIZATION>; `` Gon na Take a Lot of River,'' The Oak Ridge Boys; `` Highway 101 - 2,'' Highway 101; `` Sincerely,'' The Forester Sisters. 31. COUNTRY VOCAL COLLABORATION: `` Crying,'' <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Orbison </PERSON> and k.d. lang; `` <ORGANIZATION> Honky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tonk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angels </ORGANIZATION>' Medley,'' k.d. lang, <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, <PERSON> Loretta </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON> <PERSON> Wells </PERSON>; `` It's Such a Small World,'' <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Crowell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rosanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Cash </PERSON>; `` Streets of <LOCATION> Bakersfield </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Yoakim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Buck </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>; `` We Believe in Happy Endings,'' Early <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Conley </PERSON> and <PERSON> Emmylou </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>. 32. COUNTRY INSTRUMENTAL, ORCHESTRA, GROUP OR SOLOIST: `` Busy Signal,'' <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> Kottke </PERSON>; `` Country Idyll,'' <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> and Mannheim Steamroller; `` The Great Train Song Medley,'' <PERSON> Carlton </PERSON> <PERSON> Moody </PERSON> and The <ORGANIZATION> Moody </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION>; `` Still Fiddlin' Around,'' <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Gimble </PERSON>; `` Sugarfoot Rag,'' Asleep at the Wheel. 33. BLUGRASS RECORDING, VOCAL OR INSTRUMENTAL: `` Drive,'' <PERSON> Bela </PERSON> <PERSON> Fleck </PERSON>; `` Fifteenth Anniversary Celebration, Live at the Kennedy Center,'' The Seldom Scene and their Very Special Guest; `` Home is Where the Heart Is,'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Grisman </PERSON>; `` New Moon Rising,'' <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Nashville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bluegrass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION>; `` Southern Flavor,'' <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON>. 34. COUNTRY SONG: `` Chiseled in Stone'' <PERSON> Vera </PERSON> <PERSON> Gosdin </PERSON>; `` Hold Me,'' K.T. <PERSON> Oslin </PERSON>; `` I Could n't Leave You if I Tried,'' <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Crowell </PERSON>; `` She's No Lady,'' <PERSON> Lyle </PERSON> <PERSON> Lovett </PERSON>; `` Streets of <LOCATION> Bakersfield </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Yoakam </PERSON> and <PERSON> Buck </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>. 35. GOSPEL, FEMALE: `` Almighty God,'' <PERSON> Sandi </PERSON> <PERSON> Patti </PERSON>; `` Do You Hear What I Hear?'' <PERSON> Deniece </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>; `` Lead Me On,'' <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>; `` Precious is the Name,'' <PERSON> Delores </PERSON> <PERSON> Winans </PERSON>; `` The Reckoning,'' <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Becker </PERSON>. 36. GOSPEL, MALE: `` Christmas,'' <PERSON> Larnelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>; `` Find Us Faithful,'' <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON>; `` I 2 -LRB- Eye -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>; `` Real Life Christmas,'' <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>; `` <PERSON> Russ </PERSON> <PERSON> Taff </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Russ </PERSON> <PERSON> Taff </PERSON>. 37. GOSPEL, DUO, GROUP, CHOIR OR CHORUS: `` An Evening in December, Vol. II,'' First Call; `` D & amp; K,'' <PERSON> DeGarmo </PERSON> & Key; `` Doing It by the Book,'' The Whites; `` Silent Night, Holy Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> BeBe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> CeCe </PERSON> <PERSON> Winans </PERSON>; `` The Winans Live at Carnegie Hall,'' The Winans. 38. SOUL GOSPEL, FEMALE: `` I Have a Father,'' <PERSON> CeCe </PERSON> <PERSON> Winans </PERSON>; `` The Joy That Floods My Soul,'' <PERSON> Tramaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>; `` Live ... in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON>; `` One Lord, One Faith, One Baptism,'' <PERSON> Aretha </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON>; `` Pressing On,'' <PERSON> Vanessa </PERSON> <PERSON> Bell </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Grammys-List-2ndAdd     01-13 0677</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Grammys-List - 2nd Add,0695</SECOND>
<HEAD>BEVERLY HILLS, Bell Armstrong.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 39. SOUL GOSPEL, MALE: `` Abundant Life,'' <PERSON> BeBe </PERSON> <PERSON> Winans </PERSON>; `` Back to the Cross,'' <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>; `` Dancin in the Spirit,'' <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Winans </PERSON>; `` Special Gift,'' <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>; `` You Did it All,'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Smallwood </PERSON>. 40. SOUL GOSPEL, DUO OR GROUP: `` Conqueror,'' The Clark Sisters; `` Hold Up the Light,'' The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Choir </LOCATION>; `` Oh Happy Day,'' <PERSON> Aretha </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mavis </PERSON> <PERSON> Staples </PERSON>; `` <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Winans </PERSON> Family & amp; Friends Choir,'' <ORGANIZATION> Ronald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Winans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Friends Choir; `` Take Six,'' Take 6; `` That Name,'' <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>. 41. LATIN POP: `` Cae La Noche,'' Dyango; `` Las Apariencias Enganan,'' <PERSON> Raphael </PERSON>; `` <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON>; `` Soy Asi,'' <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Jose </PERSON>; `` <LOCATION> Sueno </LOCATION> <LOCATION> De </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Libertad </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Perales </PERSON>. 42. TROPICAL LATIN: `` Antecedente,'' <PERSON> Ruben </PERSON> <PERSON> Blades </PERSON> <PERSON> Y </PERSON> <PERSON> Son </PERSON> <PERSON> Del </PERSON> <PERSON> Solar </PERSON>; `` La Salsa Soy Yo,'' <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Leon </PERSON>; `` Mister E,'' <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Escovedo </PERSON>; `` Salsobita,'' <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Pacheco </PERSON> & amp; <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> `` El Conde'' <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>; `` <PERSON> Sigo </PERSON> <PERSON> Atrevido </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Santiago </PERSON>. 43. MEXICAN @ AMERICAN: `` <LOCATION> Canciones </LOCATION> <LOCATION> De </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Padre </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Ronstadt </PERSON>; `` <PERSON> Flaco </PERSON>'s Amigos,'' <PERSON> Flaco </PERSON> <PERSON> Jimenez </PERSON>; `` Idolos Del Pueblo,'' <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tigres </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Del </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Norte </ORGANIZATION>; `` No Me Olvidaras,'' <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Solis </PERSON>; `` Petalo Y Espinas,'' <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yonics </LOCATION>; `` <PERSON> Quiero </PERSON> <PERSON> Verte </PERSON> <PERSON> Otra </PERSON> <PERSON> Vez </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> Pio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trevino </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Majic; `` Si Me Recuerdas,'' <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bukis </LOCATION>; `` Vida Nueva,'' <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Freddy </LOCATION>'s. 44. TRADITIONAL BLUES: `` Ai n't Nothin' But a Party,'' <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Copeland </PERSON>; `` Hidden Charms,'' <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>; `` Live at <PERSON> Antone </PERSON>'s Nightclub,'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Cotton </PERSON>; `` Saturday Night Zydeco,'' <PERSON> Rockin </PERSON><PERSON> ' </PERSON> <PERSON> Dopsie </PERSON>; `` The Story of My Life,'' Guitar Slim, Jr. CONTEMPORARY BLUES: `` Blues You Can Use,'' <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Bland </PERSON>; `` Do n't Be Afraid of the Dark,'' The <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Cray </PERSON> <PERSON> Band </PERSON>; `` Low-Commotion,'' Ry Cooder; `` Seven Year Itch,'' <PERSON> Etta </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON>; `` Talk to Your Daughter,'' <ORGANIZATION> Robben </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>. 46. TRADITIONAL FOLK: `` Folkways: A Vision Shared _ A Tribute to <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON> and <PERSON> Leadbelly </PERSON>,'' Various Artists; `` Irish Heartbeat,'' <ORGANIZATION> Van </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morrison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; the Chieftans; `` Journey of Dreams,'' <PERSON> Ladysmith </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON> <PERSON> Mambazo </PERSON>; `` Le <LOCATION> Mytere </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Voix </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bulgares </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> Bulgarian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Female </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vocal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Choir </ORGANIZATION>; `` Pretty Boy <PERSON> Floyd </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dylan </PERSON>. 47. CONTEMPORARY FOLK: `` Emergency,'' Sweet Honey in the Rock; `` Homeland _ A <ORGANIZATION> Collection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> African Music,'' various artists; `` <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Prine </PERSON> <PERSON> Live </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Prine </PERSON>; `` Short Sharp Shocked,'' <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Shocked </PERSON>; `` <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>. 48. POLKA: `` All Aboard it's Polka Time,'' <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Ostanek </PERSON> and His Band; `` Born to <LOCATION> Polka </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Sturr </PERSON> & amp; his Orchestra; `` Join the Polka Generation,'' <PERSON> Lenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Gomulka </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Push; `` Let's Have a Party,'' <PERSON> Stas </PERSON> <PERSON> Bulanda </PERSON>'s Average Polka Band; `` Sounds from a <ORGANIZATION> Polka </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> Jimmy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; The Sounds. 49. REGGAE: `` Breakfast in Bed,'' UB40 and <PERSON> Chrissie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hynde </PERSON>; `` Conscious Party -LRB- Album -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Ziggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Marley </PERSON> and The Melody Makers; `` Hanging Fire,'' <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Cliff </PERSON>; `` Toots in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Toots </PERSON>; `` UB40,'' UB40. 50. RECORDING FOR CHILDREN: `` The Bible: The Amazing Book,'' Candle; `` The Legend of Sleepy Hollow,'' <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Close </PERSON>, narrator; `` Pecos Bill,'' <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, narrator; `` <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> and the Wolf _ Carnival of the Animals -LRB- Part II -RRB-,'' `` Weird Al'' <PERSON> Yankovic </PERSON>, narrator; `` The Tailor of <LOCATION> Gloucester </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Meryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Streep </PERSON>, narrator; `` The Tale of Peter Rabbit ...,'' Meryl Streep, narrator. 51. COMEDY: `` Even Worse,'' `` Weird Al'' <PERSON> Yankovic </PERSON>; `` Fontaine: Why am I Straight?,'' <PERSON> Whoppi </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>; `` Good Morning, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>; `` Jonathan Winters Finally Captured,'' <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Winters </PERSON>; `` What am I Doing in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>?,'' <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlin </PERSON>. 52. SPOKEN WORD OR NON-MUSICAL: `` A Christmas <PERSON> Carol </PERSON>,'' Sir <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Gielgud </PERSON>; `` A Prairie Home Companion: The 2nd Annual Farewell Performance,'' <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON> <PERSON> Keillor </PERSON>; `` The Screwtape Letters,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Cleese </PERSON>; `` Speech by Rev. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>,'' Rev. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>; `` Winter's Tales,'' <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Winters </PERSON>. 53. MUSICAL CAST SHOW ALBUM: `` Anything Goes,'' `` Chess,'' `` Of Thee I Sing _ Let'Em Eat Cake,'' `` Into The <PERSON> Woods </PERSON>,'' `` Showboat.'' 54. INSTRUMENTAL COMPOSITION: `` Central City Sketches,'' `` Eternal Child,'' `` Olympic Spirit,'' `` The Theme from <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' `` Winter Games.'' 55. ORIGINAL INSTRUMENTAL BACKGROUND SCORE WRITTEN FOR A MOTION PICTURE OR TELEVISION: `` Empire of the Sun,'' `` Fatal Attraction,'' `` The Last Emperor,'' `` Tucker: The Man and His Dream,'' `` Who Framed <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabbit </PERSON>.'' 56. SONG WRITTEN SPECIFICALLY FOR A MOTION PICTURE OR TELEVISION: `` Century's End,'' `` Bright Lights, <LOCATION> Big </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>''; `` Cry Freedom,'' `` Cry Freedom''; `` <LOCATION> Kokomo </LOCATION>,'' `` Cocktail''; `` One Moment in Time,'' `` The 1988 Summer Olympics Album''; `` Two Hearts,'' `` Buster.'' 57. MUSIC VIDEO: `` Check It Out,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Cougar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mellencamp </PERSON>; `` Glass Spider,'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowie </PERSON>; `` <PERSON> Stevie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicks </PERSON>: Live at <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rocks </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Stevie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicks </PERSON>; `` The Symphony Sessions,'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON>; `` Where the Streets Have No Name,'' U2.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 0137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WhatAwaitsWatkins Bjt   01-13 0747</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-What Awaits Watkins, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Designated Energy Chief Faces Uphill Struggle On Nuclear Problems</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Retired Adm. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> is scrambling back to his battle station three years after ending a sparkling 41-year <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> career. But this time the threat is a homegrown crisis instead of a foreign power. He was nominated Thursday by President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to head the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, which has been rocked by a partial shutdown of the nuclear plants that produce the nation's atomic warheads and by the prospect of devoting tens of billions of dollars to rebuilding and cleaning up the aging nuclear complex. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, 61, has no background in the commercial energy field, but he has been associated with the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s nuclear operations since early in his career, which was capped by a four-year stint as chief of naval operations, the top <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officer. In 1958, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> studied nuclear engineering at <LOCATION> Oak </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION>, one of the links in the nationwide nuclear bomb-making network. He later taught at <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> nuclear training centers and worked in the Naval Reactors Division of the <ORGANIZATION> Atomic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, a forerunner of the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. At a news conference following the announcement of his nomination as energy secretary, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said grappling with the nuclear weapons plants problem would be his `` first order of business'' before his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation hearings start. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>' selection came just hours after President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> formally endorsed an <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report recommending that $ 81 billion be spent over the next two decades to modernize the nuclear bomb factories. It acknowledged that budget constraints would make it difficult to carry out the plan. One of the most immediate threats posed by the nuclear weapons plant problem is the possibility that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> could run low on tritium, a short-lived radioactive gas that <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> reactors produce for atomic warheads. Last year, the last of the tritium-producing reactors was shut down for safety reasons, leaving the country at least temporarily without fresh supplies of the gas. The Pentagon has said the reactors must be restarted soon in order to avoid jeopardizing the nation's nuclear arsenal, but officials have not said just when the problem would become critical. No date has been set for restarting the tritium-producing reactors, although <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s report said it was unlikely before late 1989. Even once the key reactors are made safe and put back into operation, the new energy secretary will face great uncertainty over whether and when to build a new generation of tritium-producing plants. The existing ones are more than 30 years old. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s report called them obsolete and in need of replacement A related, and perhaps more long-lasting, problem is finding the technology _ and the money _ to clean up the widespread environmental damage caused by four decades of bomb-making. Energy industry officials welcomed the selection of <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, although his name was not among the many that had churned through <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> rumor mills in recent weeks. `` Adm. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> has demonstrated his ability as a leader and administrator,'' said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> DiBona </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, representing major oil companies. Other officials urged <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> to tackle the military reactors problem immediately. `` It is especially important that this national security issue be handled skillfully ... so it does not become an abiding distraction to other energy issues,'' said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, a trade group. Although the nuclear problem is likely to give <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> his most immediate headaches, the new energy secretary will face challenges on other fronts. Among them are: _ An emerging battle in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> over whether to raise the federal gasoline tax as a way of curbing gasoline consumption and cutting the federal budget deficit Debate over a possible tax on oil imports also is likely to heighten this year. _ A growing wave of oil imports that has increased concern about <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dependence on <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> Some economists and members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> have said the government should act now to insulate the nation better against a supply disruption _ particularly in the volatile <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> _ that could force up oil prices. _ Calls by the natural gas industry for ending all controls on gas prices Consumer groups are opposed. _ Deciding whether to open up more federal lands in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and elsewhere for oil and gas exploration Conservations are strongly opposed; the oil companies say such additional exploration is vital to halting a recent slide in domestic oil production.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890113-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-13-89 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Grammys-List-3rdadd     01-13 0959</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Grammys-List - 3rd add,0976</SECOND>
<HEAD>BEVERLY HILLS, U2.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
