<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 2327EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HurricaneGabrielle 2ndLd-Writethru a0752 09-07 0410</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hurricane Gabrielle, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0752,0416</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bermuda Prepares For Hurricane Gabrielle</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf, `The hurricane's ..., to UPDATE wind force; SUBS
grafs 9-12, `At 6 p.m. ..., with 4 grafs to UPDATE with 10:30 p.m. EDT
positions.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KIM S. MARTIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tropical storm-force winds swept the island of <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION> on Thursday, forcing boats to stay in port as a weakened Hurricane <PERSON> Gabrielle </PERSON> approached. Hurricane Felix, meanwhile, dwindled into a tropical storm. <PERSON> Gabrielle </PERSON> was heading due north, with its center passing about 300 miles east of <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION> late Thursday, forecasters said. The hurricane's winds weakened earlier in the day from 135 mph to 105 mph, but then rose by 10:30 p.m. EDT to 110 mph. Little change in strength was expected for <PERSON> Gabrielle </PERSON> as it headed towards Tropical Storm Felix. `` The winds wo n't change much until it reaches cooler waters,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheets </PERSON>, director of the National Hurricane Center. Swells in <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION>'s harbors were reported at 10 feet, and the island's eastern tip reported swells of 15 to 20 feet. The high seas, combined with winds of 30 to 35 mph, prevented any seagoing traffic around the island. Otherwise, <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION>'s residents were making few preparations for the storm, Sheets said. Strong winds stretched as far as 1,000 miles from <PERSON> Gabrielle </PERSON>'s center, reaching the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> `` A ship 60 miles off the coast of <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> reported seeing 12 - to 15-foot seas,'' Sheets said High seas were also reported off the coast of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. At 10:30 p.m. EDT Thursday, Hurricane <PERSON> Gabrielle </PERSON> was centered near 32.6 degrees north latitude and 59.6 degrees west longitude, or 310 miles east of <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION>. It was traveling north at nearly 17 mph. <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> was downgraded from a hurricane to a tropical storm earlier Thursday as it continued to weaken. The tropical storm posed no threat to land on its northward trek. Forecasters expect <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> to turn toward the northwest and become engulfed in the larger <PERSON> Gabrielle </PERSON> system. <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> is traveling northward at 7 mph with winds of 60 mph. At 10:30 p.m. EDT Thursday, <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> was located near 41.0 degrees north latitude and 48.5 degrees west longitude, or about 450 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Race </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Newfoundland </LOCATION>, in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> was the sixth and <PERSON> Gabrielle </PERSON> the seventh named storms of the 1989 Atlantic hurricane season. Storms are named when their winds reach 39 mph, and are classified as hurricanes when they grow to 74 mph.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 2330EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Poland-CabinetList     09-07 0269</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Poland-Cabinet List,0293</SECOND>
<HEAD>Unofficial List of Nominees for 1st Non-Communist-Led Government</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Poland</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is an unofficial list of nominees offered by Prime Minister <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> to fill the ministries in the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc's first non-communist-led government in more than 40 years. The list was provided by Solidarity parliamentary deputies who said late changes could be made before the prime minister's official announcement Tuesday. Solidarity or independent: Deputy Prime Minister-Finance Minister -LRB- combined post -RRB- _ <PERSON> Leszek </PERSON> <PERSON> Balcerowicz </PERSON>, economist; Foreign Affairs _ <PERSON> Krysztof </PERSON> <PERSON> Skubiszewski </PERSON>, church adviser, international lawyer; Education _ <PERSON> Henryk </PERSON> <PERSON> Samsonowicz </PERSON>, former <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> rector; Building _ <PERSON> Aleksander </PERSON> <PERSON> Paszynski </PERSON>, journalist-builder; Local Government _ <PERSON> Jerzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Regulski </PERSON>, engineer-economist; Culture _ <PERSON> Izabela </PERSON> <PERSON> Cywinska </PERSON>, theater director; <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Jacek </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuron </PERSON>, veteran opposition activist; Industry _ <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Syryjczyk </PERSON>, private enterprise activist; <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> Deputy Prime Minister-Interior Minister -LRB- combined post -RRB- _ Gen. <PERSON> Czeslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiszczak </PERSON>, incumbent; <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> _ Gen. <PERSON> Florian </PERSON> <PERSON> Siwicki </PERSON>, incumbent; <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Wieladek </PERSON>; <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> _ undecided; <ORGANIZATION> Peasant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> Deputy Prime Minister-Agriculture Minister -LRB- combined post -RRB- _ <PERSON> Czeslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Janicki </PERSON>, agriculture professor; Health _ <PERSON> Andrzej </PERSON> <PERSON> Kosiniak </PERSON>; Environment _ <PERSON> Bronislaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaminski </PERSON>; <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Aleksander </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentkowski </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Peasant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> parliament leader; <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prime </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minister-Head </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- combined post -RRB- _ <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Janowski </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> parliament leader; Domestic Trade _ <PERSON> Aleksander </PERSON> <PERSON> Mackiewicz </PERSON>. In addition, <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> nominated communist Politburo member <PERSON> Wladyslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Baka </PERSON> to head the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Planning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, Solidarity Senator <PERSON> Witold </PERSON> <PERSON> Trzeciakowski </PERSON> to chair his council of economic advisers, and Solidarity activist <PERSON> Aleksander </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> to serve as his liaison with political parties. The chairmanship of the committee that oversees state radio and television was to go to Solidarity, but no individual was nominated.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-RivieraFire 2ndLd-Writethru a0785 09-07 0505</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Riviera Fire, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0785,0513</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Forces Evacuation of Las Vegas Resort</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 6th, ``Everything worked ..., to UPDATE
with casino reopening, Anka performance, buffet for guests.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM DAHLBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A smoky fire touched off by a welder's torch raced through a new casino under construction Thursday at the <LOCATION> Riviera </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hotel </LOCATION> and Casino, forcing the evacuation of at least 3,000 gamblers and guests. Only two minor injuries were reported in the 10:20 a.m. blaze, which burned curtains and broke windows in up to 75 rooms in the hotel before being stopped by automatic sprinklers. Damage was estimated at about $ 3.5 million. Gamblers and guests were evacuated without incident when smoke began filling the inside of the resort. The hotel patrons joined several thousand spectators on the Strip watching the fire, which was put out in about two hours. `` The first thing we did was secure all of the money -LRB- in the casino -RRB- and evacuate all the people,'' hotel President <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Sterbens </PERSON> said. `` To my knowledge it's the first time we've ever shut down gambling at the <LOCATION> Riviera </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Waltzman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Riviera </LOCATION> chairman, said he went floor to floor with security officers, knocking on doors to alert hotel guests as corridors filled with smoke. `` Everything worked the way it was supposed to work,'' <PERSON> Waltzman </PERSON> said of the hotel's sprinkler and fire alarm systems. The casino, which suffered water damage, reopened about 9 p.m. Thursday, and a performance by <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Anka </PERSON> was delayed until 10 p.m. Hotel officials invited all guests to a free prime rib buffet and offered them free tickets to <PERSON> Anka </PERSON>'s performance. The fire blackened the exterior of a section of the original hotel's nine-story structure built in 1953. The fire reached inside 50 to 75 rooms in the building, fire officials said, before being stopped by automatic sprinklers. The fire began in wooden forms being used to build a new 125,000 square-foot two-story casino touted as the world's largest. The blaze also spread to the eaves of an existing casino area and burned part of an outdoor sign on the casino. Embers fanned by 25 mph winds also crossed the street and briefly set the roof of a motel on fire. Two other high-rises at the <LOCATION> Riviera </LOCATION>, where most of the hotel's rooms are located, were not affected by the fire but were evacuated anyway <ORGANIZATION> Clark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Leinbach </PERSON> said the blaze was touched off by welders who were building a swimming pool on top of the new casino. <PERSON> Leinbach </PERSON> said firefighters later found two empty fire extinguishers nearby. <PERSON> Sterbens </PERSON> said the hotel's 2,200 rooms were sold out. The hotel is hosting a convention of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Spinal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cord </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Injury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nurses </ORGANIZATION> and Psychologists. <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> enacted some of the most stringent fire safety codes in the nation after a fire at the former MGM Grand Hotel in November of 1980 killed 87 people and a blaze at the Las Vegas Hilton three months later killed eight people.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PRI--RecruitingRetirees 1stLd-Writethru forlimitedblackparticipationver-HairedAmbassadorsRecruitOtherRetirees
09-07 0758</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-PRI--Recruiting Retirees, 1st Ld - Writethru,b2058,0770</SECOND>
<HEAD>In Hot Springs, Silver-Haired Ambassadors Recruit Other Retirees</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf of b2058, moved Sept. 4 for use today, to reflect
that chamber of commerce has taken over recruitment office.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SCOTT CHARTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOT SPRINGS, Ark. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hot Springs has an army of silver-haired ambassadors who love to brag about mineral springs, pure air and cheap living in the <LOCATION> Ouachita </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>. When a prospective senior settler calls the <ORGANIZATION> Greater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Springs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce-run </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retiree </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recruitment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, coordinator <PERSON> Gail </PERSON> <PERSON> Ezelle </PERSON> unleashes the 150-strong force of volunteers whose enthusiasm bubbles like this resort's hot spring water. Dapper in matching blue blazers, breast pockets adorned with their names and the city logo, the volunteers court potential new neighbors with answers about health care, expenses, and recreation. They escort guests up the 216-foot Hot Springs Mountain Tower for a panoramic view, then head downtown for a look at restored Bathhouse Row. The leisurely tour may end with a meal, or maybe a sunset cruise aboard a <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hamilton </LOCATION> party barge. The personal pitches have been potent. The office has fielded more than 6,500 inquiries since it started advertising nationally last summer; it takes credit for 75 moves. Part of its success comes from a 1987 Rand-McNally study listing Hot Sprngs as the nation's third most desirable retirement spot, after the <LOCATION> Murray-Kentucky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Clayton-Clarksville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, areas To Mrs. <PERSON> Ezelle </PERSON>, 55, who moved from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, recruiting retirees is just like recruiting an industry. `` They have such a tremendous economic impact on the community, and they give us expertise and enthusiasm.'' But retirees do n't bring some of industry's bothersome baggage: pollution, clogged highways and fluctuating workforces. They arrive with average assets of $ 215,000 and average annual incomes of $ 33,000, along with taxes and spare time to devote to community activities. That equates to an annual economic impact of more than $ 9 million, the office estimates. Mrs. <PERSON> Ezelle </PERSON> praises her volunteer corps, who buy their own jackets, pay for their own gas and provide any extras, such as lake cruises or meals. She offers a toll-free telephone line and complimentary passes to the mountain tower. Aggressive retiree recruitment is nothing new. But Hot Springs is innovating by applying the concept to an existing city instead of a carefully planned senior citizens development, said aging expert <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Longino </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> `` <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> has been a nice place for people to retire for a long time, so they have a tradition up there,'' said <PERSON> Longino </PERSON>, associate director of the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Adult </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> and Aging at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION>. `` But the difference with <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> is they are really going after the retirees, instead of letting the retirees come to them. States have to kind of compete for retirees. They bring expendable income and lots of advantages. And older people rarely move someplace where they do n't know anybody.'' That's why volunteers like <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> and <PERSON> Marge </PERSON> <PERSON> Bingham </PERSON> are valuable _ they know what it's like to downshift from a fast-paced working lifestyle. The <ORGANIZATION> Binghams </ORGANIZATION> moved to <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> in 1987 from <LOCATION> Covina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, their home for more than three decades. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON>, 57, knew it was time to get out when his 28-minute commute to a securities office turned into a 1 -LCB- - hour headache They were familiar with <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> because their daughter and grandchildren live in <LOCATION> Mena </LOCATION>, on the state's western edge. A deal on a lake house clinched the decision. And once <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> unwound after three months of relaxation, he decided to tell others about <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Marge </PERSON>, 53, says she was floored by friendliness. `` Out in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, it was so huge and impersonal. We maybe knew our neighbors across the street and on either side of us. But here, we've already got 50 to 100 close friends, and 500 speaking acquaintances. I love it.'' <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Bingham </PERSON> likes to end a recruiting session by inviting guests onto his party barge, docked a few yards behind his home on <PERSON> Lake </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>. He doffs the blazer, kicks back and steers the vessel toward the setting sun. <PERSON> Marge </PERSON> waves to a passing dinner cruise boat; two dozen strangers wave back. `` See what I mean? Everybody's friendly. Heck, in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, if a guy raises his hand like that, he may have a gun in it.'' The office generally refrains from bashing other states, but proudly displayed is a map showing states generating the most inquiries this year shaded in blue. In descending order, they are <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> -LRB- 400 calls -RRB-; <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> -LRB- 314 -RRB-; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> -LRB- 291 -RRB-; <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -LRB- 265 -RRB-; and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> -LRB- 221 -RRB-.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0058EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ImperialBachelor     09-07 0739</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Imperial Bachelor,0759</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japan's Most Eligible Bachelor Still Searching for a Bride</HEAD>
<NOTE>^Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<NOTE>An AP Extra</NOTE>
<NOTE>By ERIC TALMADGE</NOTE>
<NOTE>Associated Press Writer</NOTE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s most eligible bachelor, Crown Prince <PERSON> Naruhito </PERSON>, is looking for a bride, but the heir to the Chrysanthemum Throne has discovered it's not easy finding a woman both willing and suited to marry into the world's oldest royal family. Four years ago, upon his return from postgraduate history studies at <ORGANIZATION> Oxford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Merton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, the prince said he would like to marry by age 30, a milestone he reaches in February. But few palace watchers expect the prince to achieve that goal, despite his obvious assets _ he's the eldest son of Emperor <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON>, has an excellent education, and enjoys foreign travel. Women who appreciate culture might be interested in knowing he plays the viola. For sporty types, the prince is an avid mountain climber and enjoys tennis. `` We are trying to realize -LRB- his marriage -RRB- as soon as possible, but have not yet reached the point where we can speak of any particulars,'' <PERSON> Iwao </PERSON> <PERSON> Miyao </PERSON>, deputy head of the <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, told a parliamentary committee Aug. 29. <PERSON> Miyao </PERSON>'s comment on <PERSON> Naruhito </PERSON>'s nuptial difficulties was prompted by news a few days earlier that <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Aya </PERSON>, <PERSON> Naruhito </PERSON>'s younger brother, was engaged and likely to marry first. The idea of 23-year-old Aya, second in line to the throne, marrying before his elder brother was met with considerable opposition from palace conservatives, one palace source said. `` But the crown prince seems to be in no hurry, and has n't found the right woman yet,'' the source said, requesting anonymity. A formal palace announcement on <PERSON> Aya </PERSON>'s engagement will be made after it is approved by the 10-member <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, headed by Prime Minister <PERSON> Toshiki </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON>. It is scheduled to meet Sept. 12. Qualifications for women marrying into the imperial family have eased in recent years, but candidates still can expect their family histories and personal backgrounds to be thoroughly checked by both the palace and the media. Newspapers dug up high school album photographs of <PERSON> Kiko </PERSON> <PERSON> Kawashima </PERSON> and even published diagrams of her family tree, complete with detailed profiles going back four generations when it was discovered she will marry Aya. Miss <PERSON> Kawashima </PERSON> comes from a good, but common, family, they said. Her father is a professor of economics at <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Gakushuin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, the alma mater of much of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s royalty. She has lived in <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Because <PERSON> Naruhito </PERSON>'s wife will become empress, his choice will be subject to much closer scrutiny. Descendants of prewar nobility or daughters of leading industrialists are preferred in prospective princesses, though these qualifications are not ironclad. A clean bill of health, however, is a must, as is Japanese citizenship. Some experience living abroad, or ability in a foreign language, is also seen as a plus, since members of the imperial household often are hosts to foreign dignitaries. Attention has focused on three women singled out by the media as possible mates for <PERSON> Naruhito </PERSON>: <PERSON> Mari </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatano </PERSON>, 23, fluent in French and English, and a student in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, where she lives with her parents; <PERSON> Masako </PERSON> <PERSON> Owada </PERSON>, the 25-year-old daughter of a diplomat and a student in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>; and <PERSON> Teruko </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuni </PERSON>, 25, a cousin of the prince. But many palace watchers suspect the prince's final choice will come as a surprise. `` The crown prince has a very clear idea of the kind of woman he wants to marry, and he is too stubborn to just accept whomever the palace chooses, which was how things used to be done,'' said <PERSON> Toshiaki </PERSON> <PERSON> Kawahara </PERSON>, a journalist who has written several books on <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s imperial family. <PERSON> Kawahara </PERSON> said the tradition-minded, strictly regimented life of the <LOCATION> Japanese </LOCATION> royal family has frightened away women reared in the relatively open atmosphere of modern <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. `` Before Empress <PERSON> Michiko </PERSON> married the emperor, she had to go through hours of ` princess studies' every day for three months,'' he said. `` And because she was not of noble heritage, she had to endure a good deal of bullying from the old nobility. Her precedent may scare off other women who could marry into the imperial household.'' <PERSON> Michiko </PERSON>, the daughter of a wealthy businessman, is the first commoner to become empress of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. She wed <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> in 1959, when he was crown prince, and is credited with shrinking the gap known as the Chrysanthemum Curtain between the public and palace.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0524EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Abortion-Arson     09-07 0132</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Abortion-Arson,0138</SECOND>
<HEAD>Clinic's New Home Burns</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An arson fire caused $ 5,000 damage to an abortion clinic that had moved in the hope of escaping further attention of abortion protesters, authorities said. Flammable liquid was thrown against the <ORGANIZATION> Allegheny </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reproductive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> entrance early Wednesday, then was ignited, said Deputy Fire Chief <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Harper </PERSON>. The fire damaged the door, a staircase and an awning, <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> said. No arrests were made. The building was unoccupied when the fire broke out, said executive director <PERSON> Claire </PERSON> <PERSON> Keyes </PERSON>. `` We're very thankful that there were no injuries when this terroristic act occurred,'' she said. `` We want to assure our patients that services will be continuing uninterrupted.'' During the weekend, the clinic moved from a building across the street, where several protests had been staged.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SatanismTreatment     09-07 0539</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Satanism Treatment,0552</SECOND>
<HEAD>Psychiatric Hospital Sets Up Unit To Treat Satanism</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHARLES J. GANS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Psychiatrists and psychologists at <LOCATION> Hartgrove </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> bristle at being called modern-day exorcists, but they're creating one of the nation's first treatment programs to wean teen-agers from Satanism `` In no way are we comparable to the old exorcists,'' says <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON>, an adolescent psychologist at the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Side </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> hospital </ORGANIZATION>, which plans to begin offering the program this month. `` The kids who will be admitted will be here primarily because of their behavioral and emotional problems. No one will be hospitalized for strange beliefs or unusual values that we would disagree with,'' <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> said Wednesday. `` I do n't think there is any doubt Satanism is a growing problem,'' said social worker <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Trahan </PERSON>, who has been researching satanic beliefs for three years and was contracted to organize the program for <PERSON> Hartgrove </PERSON>'s new Center for the Treatment of Ritualistic Deviance. `` We do n't know the percentages because so much is secretive, but we do know ... it is beginning to show up throughout the country,'' <PERSON> Trahan </PERSON> said. More such programs will be needed as police, teachers and parents learn to recognize involvement, said <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Simandl </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> police youth officer and expert on satanic cults, who has helped train Hartgrove staff. `` That's been the problem. There are n't places to take the kids,'' <PERSON> Simandl </PERSON> said. In the program, teen-agers will spend four to eight weeks as in-patients and undergo individual and group counseling. Most of the youths will be admitted voluntarily. <PERSON> Hartgrove </PERSON>'s facility _ to be staffed by specially trained psychiatrists, psychologists, social workers and nurses _ should receive its first patients in two to four weeks, and initially will take as many as six patients at a time, <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> said. A similar program exists at <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION> PsychHealth. The new program will seek to undermine Satanism's underlying belief system, which hampers conventional treatment. Satanism `` gives them the promise of power and privilege beyond anything they ever imagined. Not only can they have everything they want ... but can do so while totally indulging themselves in drugs, sex or any momentary pleasure,'' <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> said. `` We try to help them see how unrealistic the promises are. Our ultimate goal is to make them able to function in the world so they can have a reasonable and successful life for themselves and not harm anyone else.'' Youngsters involved in Satanism often exhibit unusual behavior, which can include suicide attempts, violent rages, rejection of family, drug use, sexual promiscuity, a drastic drop in grades, intensified rebellion, a strong interest in heavy-metal music, role-playing games or horror films, and the use of occult symbols such as `` 666'' or upside-down crosses, <PERSON> Trahan </PERSON> said. `` They usually are intelligent, creative and bored with traditional pursuits. They generally have a feeling of being different and not belonging, are often underachievers and generally have a feeling of being powerless,'' he said. `` One of the problems is helping people see and diagnose the problem,'' <PERSON> Trahan </PERSON> said. `` Often people with a little bit of knowledge think they see it everywhere and think if a kid is into heavy-metal music he must be a Satanist, but that's not true.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0022EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TeacherStabbed     09-07 0290</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Teacher Stabbed,0301</SECOND>
<HEAD>12-Year-Old Arrested in Teacher's Slaying</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT WORTH, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 12-year-old boy was arrested in connection with the fatal stabbing of an elementary school teacher, police said Wednesday. The boy, whose name was not released because of his age, was being held at <ORGANIZATION> Tarrant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Juvenile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, police said, but it was not known when he would be formally charged. The body of <PERSON> Jana </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>, 24, was found on stairs outside her classroom at <ORGANIZATION> Glen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> on Aug. 28. She had been stabbed several times in the chest, neck and head. Her purse was untouched and she did not appear to have been sexually assaulted. Police said the boy has admitted he was prowling around the schoolgrounds when Ms. <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> was killed and he has given other details about the crime. Police spokesman <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Clarke </PERSON> on Wednesday night stopped short of calling the boy's statement a confession. `` We feel real confident that we'll have a good case on it,'' <PERSON> Clarke </PERSON> said. `` We really do n't have a motive. We feel like she was just in the wrong place at the wrong time.'' Immediately after the slaying, police said they were looking for a teen-ager who was seen in the area. Ms. <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>'s brother, <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>, said he and his family learned there had been an arrest in the case as they were gathering Ms. <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>'s belongings at her <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> residence. `` We feel a lot better that it was n't someone who knew <PERSON> Jana </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>. Fort Worth schools opened Tuesday. A plainclothes police officer walked the <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> <PERSON> Park </PERSON> campus and teachers were encouraged to discuss the killing with pupils. Ms. <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> was new to the school, and was to have taught third-and fourth-graders.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0058EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Mexico-Labor     09-07 0648</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico-Labor,0669</SECOND>
<HEAD>Strike Accord Seen as Blow to Union Corruption in Mexico</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAM ROSSIE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MONTERREY, Mexico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assembly plants, back in operation after winning a three-week labor dispute, have blazed the trail for other companies to fight the extraordinary power labor unions hold in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, industry spokesmen say. A union power struggle that shut down 15 American plants known as maquiladoras in the border city of <LOCATION> Reynosa </LOCATION> ended with labor and government officials agreeing Aug. 18 to let the workers form a union independent of the nationally powerful <ORGANIZATION> Mexican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> whose local representative forced the workers to strike. `` It definitely means that companies can take a stand against illegal activities and corruption and be successsul,'' said <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, manager for <ORGANIZATION> Reynosa </ORGANIZATION>'s West Bend plant. `` We blazed a new trail.'' The strike was settled after intervention of President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON>'s government in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> has made clear he will not let unions stand in the way of his goal of modernizing the Mexican economy and attracting more foreign investors. `` The <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> government has acted in a certain direction to remove as much of the corruption as it possibly can,'' said <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Kezsbom </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York-based </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> whose <LOCATION> Reynosa </LOCATION> plant was closed in the strike. `` He does n't want to have the negative publicity that occurred out of this permeate throughout the world. The issue was the expansion of the maquiladora industry in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>.'' Maquiladoras, in which foreign-owned companies take advantage of cheap Mexican labor to produce goods for sale in their own countries or elsewhere, have become a top foreign income earner for <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. The industry, which generated $ 2.3 billion in foreign currency last year, has grown by more than 70 percent since 1985 and employs about 392,000 people, mainly along the U.S.-Mexican border. The strike cost an estimated $ 500,000 a day in lost production, but plant managers said it was worth it because the outcome was favorable to them. Although the plant workers indicated no great sympathy for a walkout, they went on strike July 25 on the orders of <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Morales </PERSON>, a local leader of the powerful <ORGANIZATION> Mexican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION>. Strike flags were hoisted. Traditionally in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, workers who violate strike flags face severe consequences, including possible physical harm, immediately or later. The plants, nevertheless, continued to pay the workers their wages and benefits, averaging about $ 1.20 a hour, during the strike. <PERSON> Kezsbom </PERSON> said the American managers resisted <PERSON> Morales </PERSON>, who controls most of the labor contracts at <LOCATION> Reynosa </LOCATION>'s 27 other maquiladoras, because they considered him corrupt. <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> forced companies to give him control of trucking contracts, waste disposal and scrap resale, and to issue food coupons good only at stores he controls. The coupons are part of the employee benefit packages. The nearly 2,000 workers at the plants <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> shut down waited for two weeks while plant managers and business leaders pleaded with the federal government in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> to step in. Then, frustrated by government inaction, about 900 workers ripped down the strike flags, stormed back into their plants and went to work. That same day <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Fernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Gutierrez </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrios </PERSON> met with industry leaders in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and promised the government would intervene. Gov. <PERSON> Americo </PERSON> <PERSON> Villarreal </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tamaulipas </LOCATION> summoned the managers to a meeting in the state capital, <LOCATION> Ciudad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Victoria </LOCATION>, the next day to work out an accord giving the plant workers the right to form an independent union. The agreement surprised those familiar with the strength of the <ORGANIZATION> Mexican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION>, the nation's largest labor organization and a powerful sector of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Institutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Although the agreement stipulates that only workers from the affected 15 plants can join the independent union, industry spokesmen say it may open a new era of labor relations in <LOCATION> Tamaulipas </LOCATION> and other Mexican states with maquiladora plants.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0023EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     09-07 0521</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0540</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JOPLIN, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 From the green hills of <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> to the granite faces of <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rushmore </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Brutus </PERSON> the traveling dog has seen it all _ from the back of a motorcycle. <PERSON> Brutus </PERSON>, a 70-pound mix of boxer and <LOCATION> Labrador </LOCATION> retriever, has traveled 25,000 miles during the past year standing on the trailer of a motorcycle driven by <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Wassenberg </PERSON>. <PERSON> Wassenberg </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Marysville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, said the former stray dog hopped on his bike about two years ago. `` I do n't tell him to get on. I just hook up the trailer and he knows it's time to go and gets up there,'' <PERSON> Wassenberg </PERSON> said. `` He stands up the whole time. Sometimes he takes a break and sits when I stop at a stoplight or get gas.'' <PERSON> Brutus </PERSON> wears goggles to protect his eyes and a hooded sweatshirt when the temperature drops below 30 degrees. A harness keeps him hitched to the trailer. `` He actually prefers to ride on the gas tank, but many states are against that because he could obscure my vision,'' <PERSON> Wassenberg </PERSON> said during a recent stop in <PERSON> Joplin </PERSON> en route to <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> on a sightseeing trip. <PERSON> Brutus </PERSON> has made two trips with <PERSON> Wassenberg </PERSON> to motorcycle rallies at <LOCATION> Sturgis </LOCATION>, S.D. They make weekend jaunts of several hundred miles through <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version moved on the financial wire</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Anyone who has seen `` Nightmare on Elm Street'' horror movies knows fiendish <PERSON> Freddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Krueger </PERSON> is no doll. But a toy company has sweet dreams about sales of a new talking doll version of the popular movie villain. Matchbox Toys -LRB- USA -RRB- Ltd.. Wednesday announced creation of a 17-inch-tall, bendable doll based on the <PERSON> Freddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Krueger </PERSON> character with a repertoire of six ghoulish sayings Pull a string and the <PERSON> Freddy </PERSON> doll spouts phrases such as `` Pleasant dreams,'' `` Watch Out, <PERSON> Freddy </PERSON>'s back'' or the character's trademark diabolical laugh The doll, which will sell for about $ 25, will be available in stores for Halloween sales. `` <PERSON> Freddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Krueger </PERSON> has translated nightmares into a dream business,'' said <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Morra </PERSON>, senior director of marketing at <ORGANIZATION> Matchbox </ORGANIZATION>. `` We've known the talking doll business and we hope to do well with <PERSON> Freddy </PERSON> because we know when <PERSON> Freddy </PERSON> talks, people listen,'' <PERSON> Morra </PERSON> said in a news release.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>RENO, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, home of easy divorce, legalized gambling and prostitution, is n't a blot on the nation and should be proud of its unique heritage, says the producer of a video history of the state. The video will be the cornerstone of a year-long celebration of the Silver State's 125th birthday, and is being paid for by a $ 50,000 grant the <ORGANIZATION> Nevada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> telephone company presented Wednesday to Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>. `` Actually, we're treating this anniversary celebration as a sophisticated educational campaign,'' producer <PERSON> Norm </PERSON> <PERSON> Neilson </PERSON> said. `` Some writers have referred to <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> as a blot on the nation,'' <PERSON> Neilson </PERSON> said. He said the video would dispel those impressions and show `` it was just frontier values'' that paved the way for legalized prostitution, gambling and quickie divorces. On Oct. 31, 1864, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> became the 36th state in the union.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SpokesmanQuits     09-07 0509</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Spokesman Quits,0525</SECOND>
<HEAD>Marcos Spokesman Quits, Returns To Philippines</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTINE DONNELLY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A spokesman for former Philippine President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> quit his job and returned to <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> on Wednesday, giving up his appeal for political asylum in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> `` Gemmo'' <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION>, 45, was media spokesman since shortly after <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> was exiled here in February 1986. <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> left <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> early Wednesday, after visiting his parents and son in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> entered the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in March 1986 on a tourist visa. After the Immigration and <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> began deportation proceedings against him last January for overstaying the visa, <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> applied for political asylum, claiming his life would be in danger in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> now that <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> foe <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> is president. A hearing on the appeal was scheduled for later this month. Although he still fears persecution, <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> said personal problems, including a recent divorce, prompted his decision to go home. `` I believe the emotional problems caused by the divorce have caused me to be less effective as spokesman,'' he said. `` I'm still a bit apprehensive about what will greet me, but if I get arrested, it will help my colleagues.'' Several other <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> aides seek political asylum here. <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> was married in 1978 and divorced last January. His ex-wife, <PERSON> Norma </PERSON>, will remain in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, as will their 8 -LCB- - year-old son, <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynaldo </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> said <PERSON> Tomas </PERSON> `` Buddy'' <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> consul general here, called <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION>'s fears of persecution `` preposterous'' and said many <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> allies prosper in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> said he would work for an export company in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, as well as write a twice-monthly column for a Filipino newspaper in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. He's also working on a book detailing his years with the Marcoses. Near the end of <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' 20-year rule, <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> was a regional director in the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Settlements </ORGANIZATION>, then headed by <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' wife, <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON>. The Marcoses are under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> indictment for allegedly stealing nearly $ 200 million from their homeland and stashing it in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government has filed a companion civil lawsuit, so that claims against them can continue if the 71-year-old <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> dies. He has been hospitalized here for the past eight months and remained in critical condition Wednesday. Although Mrs. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> has said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> governments' freeze on many of the couple's vast assets made it difficult to pay bills, <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> said he got a regular `` allowance'' and money played no part in his decision. Mrs. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> downplayed reports that <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> left because of increasing tension between him and other members of the <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> entourage, including <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> `` Gemmo is a good guy,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. `` He can always come back and he still has my trust.'' His attorney, <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Oldenburg </PERSON>, said <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> withdrew the application for political asylum Tuesday and the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> granted him a voluntary departure order, meaning the deportation proceedings would be suspended. The <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> said <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> could apply for a new visa if he wants to return to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0122EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Drugs-Honduran     09-07 0463</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drugs-Honduran,0479</SECOND>
<HEAD>Honduran Drug Kingpin Convicted of Cocaine Trafficking</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-US-Columbia, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDA DEUTSCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The conviction of a billionaire drug kingpin whose arrest in his native <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> sparked a week of riots there is a big victory in the war on drugs, federal prosecutors said. Jurors on Wednesday found <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Matta </PERSON> <PERSON> Ballesteros </PERSON> guilty of masterminding a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> drug ring linked to a Colombian cocaine cartel. After the conviction, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Feess </PERSON> described the 45-year-old <PERSON> Matta </PERSON> as `` one of the most significant narcotics traffickers in the world today.'' Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Gurule </PERSON> said the federal court jury's decision was a message to the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> government `` that if they extradite drug kingpins we will prosecute them to the full extent of the law.'' <PERSON> Matta </PERSON> could be sentenced to life imprisonment without possibility of parole, <PERSON> Feess </PERSON> said. Sentencing is scheduled for Oct. 5. <PERSON> Matta </PERSON> led a powerful cocaine cartel based in <LOCATION> Cali </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, that funneled thousands of pounds of the drug to <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> through <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Feess </PERSON> said. He compared <PERSON> Matta </PERSON>'s power to that of <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivas </PERSON>, the Colombian drug lord convicted earlier this year in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. `` The conviction of <LOCATION> Ballesteros </LOCATION> is a major blow to the gangsters who run the international drug rings,'' Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said in a statement from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The jury convicted <PERSON> Matta </PERSON> on one count each of conspiracy, running a continuing criminal enterprise and possession with intent to distribute cocaine and four counts of distribution of cocaine. <PERSON> Matta </PERSON>'s lawyer, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Stolar </PERSON>, said he will file motions to have the verdict overturned and, failing that, will appeal. He insisted that the case was prejudiced by publicity surrounding the U.S.-Colombian anti-drug campaign and President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s speech Tuesday night. <PERSON> Stolar </PERSON> said he asked <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to delay his address but received no response. He maintained that <PERSON> Matta </PERSON> was a legitimate businessman and <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>' largest single employer. He said <PERSON> Matta </PERSON>'s fortune came from cattle ranching, construction and the tobacco, coffee and spice trade. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, however, said <PERSON> Matta </PERSON> controlled a narcotics empire worth up to $ 2 billion. He was accused of overseeing a network that distributed $ 72 million worth of cocaine in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. The case against <PERSON> Matta </PERSON> stemmed from a September 1981 raid on a Van Nuys apartment complex, where $ 1.9 million in cash and 114 pounds of cocaine were sezied. At that time, that was the largest seizure of cocaine in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> history. <PERSON> Matta </PERSON> became a folk hero to his impoverished neighbors in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> where he granted loans, bought desks for school children and employed about 800 people on his tobacco and dairy farms. His extradition triggered outrage in <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION> where 2,000 demonstrators burned the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy annex. Five Hondurans died in the week-long violence.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0122EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ActressStalker     09-07 0384</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Actress Stalker,0397</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Trails Actress, Threatens Suicide Outside Theater</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BERKELEY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man who had been following actress <PERSON> Justine </PERSON> <PERSON> Bateman </PERSON>, former star of the television series `` Family Ties,'' was arrested Wednesday after threatening suicide at a theater where she was appearing, police said. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Smetek </PERSON>, 39, was taken into custody about three hours after he appeared outside the <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION> Repertory Theater holding a loaded revolver to his abdomen, said police Lt. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bateman </PERSON>, 23, best known for her television role as <PERSON> Mallory </PERSON> <PERSON> Keaton </PERSON>, appeared in the title role of the theater's production of `` Lulu'' at its premiere Wednesday night. <PERSON> Smetek </PERSON>, who will undergo a psychiatric evaluation at <LOCATION> Highland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, had been trailing <PERSON> Bateman </PERSON> for months and maintained that the two shared an intimate relationship, <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> said. `` He just wants to talk with her and indicate his love-fixation with her,'' <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> said. Theater workers first noticed Smetek about 10 a.m. sitting on a bench in the theater's courtyard. He was holding a .22 - caliber Magnum revolver to his chest, said <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION> Rep spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> Another theater worker told police <PERSON> Smetek </PERSON> threatened to kill himself. A team of about 10 police officers and mental health officials negotiating with <PERSON> Smetek </PERSON> persuaded to take the cocked gun away from his abdomen and tuck it in his waistband, said <PERSON> Peters </PERSON>. At about 12:30 p.m., <PERSON> Smetek </PERSON> surrendered to authorities without incident, <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Smetek </PERSON> was taken to the <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>, where investigators arrested him for investigation of possession of a loaded firearm within city limits and two felony counts of displaying a firearm. They were reviewing <PERSON> Smetek </PERSON>'s criminal record and also considering a possible harassment charge, <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bateman </PERSON>'s concern about <PERSON> Smetek </PERSON> was raised following two incidents, which were not described, on the `` Family Ties'' set at <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> earlier this year, said the actress' publicist, <PERSON> Cindy </PERSON> <PERSON> Guagenti </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Justine </PERSON> was aware that he was pursuing her and took the situation seriously,'' said <PERSON> Guagenti </PERSON>. `` She contacted the police in <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION> when she found out he was up there. And she hired a private security firm.'' <PERSON> Bateman </PERSON> and theater officials said a temporary restraining order against <PERSON> Smetek </PERSON> is scheduled to take effect Thursday. The slaying of actress <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaeffer </PERSON> on July 18, allegedly by an obsessed fan, has heightened celebrities' uneasiness about mentally unstable fans.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--PollardParole     09-07 0184</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Pollard Parole,0187</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anne Pollard Denied Early Parole</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON>, the wife of convicted spy <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON>, has been denied early parole on her conviction as his accessory, but will probably be released in 1990, a federal official said Wednesday. In denying Mrs. <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON>'s request, <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>, regional parole commissioner, accepted a recommendation made last month by a board of examiners. Mrs. <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON> was sentenced March 4, 1987, to five years in prison as an accessory after the fact in her husbad's case. Her husband is serving a life sentence at the federal prison at <LOCATION> Marion </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, for selling secrets to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> while he worked as an intelligence analyst with the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON> has been earning a 10-day-per-month reduction in her sentence for good behavior and probably will be released at the end of March 1990, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Kravisky </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parole </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said Wednesday. Mrs. <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON> is at the federal penitentiary in <LOCATION> Danbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, which is part of the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> region of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parole </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. Her first appeal for parole was denied last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-SouthAfrica 8thLd-Writethru a0418 09-07 0794</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-South Africa, 8th Ld-Writethru, a0418,0813</SECOND>
<HEAD>Governing Party Suffers Worst Setback; Police Disperse Protesters</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos JOH3,CPN3</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 7 grafs to ADD comment from de Klerk, turnout figure.
Picks up 8th pvs, `The Conservatives ...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID CRARY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The governing party suffered its worst election setback in 41 years of power on Wednesday, losing nearly a quarter of its parliamentary seats to far-right and anti-apartheid rivals. Riot squads with whips, tear gas and shotguns dispersed blacks protesting their exclusion from the balloting, and police said more than 50 people were arrested. Anti-apartheid leaders, who called a general strike, said 3 million people stayed away from jobs and classes. It appeared, with just four of 166 districts undecided, that the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> would retain 93 or 94 of its previous 123 seats. The far-right <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> improved from 22 to 39 seats and the liberal <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> moved from 20 to 33 seats, the most ever for an anti-apartheid faction. With his party narrowly retaining its majority in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader and acting President F.W. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> is expected to be chosen by an electoral college next week to serve a five-year term as president. He described the results as `` a clear mandate'' for his party's plans for gradual political reform and contended that both opposition parties had little chance for further growth Independent commentators said it was the first time since 1953 that the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> failed to get a majority of the popular vote. The Nationalists won about 48 percent of the vote, to 31 percent for the Conservatives and 21 percent for the Democrats. About 69 percent of the 3,160,667 registered white voters turned out for the election. The Conservatives, who favor stricter racial segregation, lost by just five votes in <LOCATION> Vereeniging </LOCATION>, former district of <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>, who was not a parliamentary candidate. Foreign Minister <PERSON> Pik </PERSON> <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> and Defense Minister <PERSON> Magnus </PERSON> <PERSON> Malan </PERSON> were re-elected by margins sharply lower than in the white election of 1987. The Conservatives won their first-ever seats in <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION>, the capital, and in <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Province </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Orange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>. The election was widely viewed as among the most important in history for the whites who control <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. It gave white voters the choice of stating that they want to strengthen apartheid, eliminate it or take a middle course. The amount of support for the other parties was expected to influence the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in deciding whether to speed up or slow down its program of limited political reform. Voting stations around the country were heavily guarded. Armored vehicles patrolled some mixed-race townships, which were enveloped in smoke from burning street barricades. Also at stake were seats in mixed-race and Indian chambers, which were established in 1984 and have little power. Blacks, who outnumber whites more than 5-1, have no voice in national affairs. Anti-apartheid activists called for a boycott of the non-white elections. Of the nation's 37 million people, 5 million are white, 28 million black, about 3 million of mixed race and nearly 1 million of Indian descent. The campaign platform of de Klerk called for limited black participation at the national level within five years. He is depicted as more flexible than his predecessor, President P.W. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, but supports segregation of schools and neighborhoods and rejects a one-person, one-vote system leading to black majority rule. The <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> opposes political concessions to blacks and favors comprehensive racial segregation. The <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> wants an immediate end to segregation and a vote of equal weight for every South African. In the five weeks before the election, anti-apartheid groups mounted an unprecedented defiance campaign, in many cases provoking violent response by police. Riot squads have used shotguns, water cannons, tear gas, clubs and dogs against anti-election marches, campus rallies and church meetings. More than 2,000 people have been arrested for disobeying laws that segregate hospitals, beaches and buses, and for defying restrictions on speech and political activity. <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON>, the black Anglican archbishop and anti-apartheid leader, said of the election: `` I'm not paying a great deal of attention. I'm more interested in how many people stay away. `` I would hope that white South Africans would be aware that the bulk of the people in this country are not voting, and they should join us in getting rid of the system.'' Black worker absenteeism ranged from about 70 percent in the industrial heartland around <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> to virtually 100 percent in the eastern <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> province cities of <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Elizabeth </LOCATION> and Uitenhage, labor experts at <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Witwatersrand </ORGANIZATION> reported. Most mines operated normally, but all motor vehicle plants were shut down. Officials said registered voters included 665,870 Indians and 1.77 million people of mixed race.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CocaineAddiction Bjt   09-07 0684</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cocaine Addiction, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scientists Still Looking for Ways to Control Cocaine Addiction</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Special Report</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The addict slips the needle into his scarred arm and drives down the plunger, or flares a crack-filled pipe and inhales the heated vapor. In both cases, the cocaine hits the brain within seconds, giving the user sensations of pleasure that some have said is like no other high. But the pleasure lasts only 10 to 20 minutes, followed quickly by a `` crash'' and a relentless, ignore-all-else craving to get high again. It's that cycle of ecstasy, depression and renewed craving for euphoria that makes cocaine and crack among the most habit-forming drugs. And, experts say, medical science has not found a treatment that can be applied universally to break the cycle of dependency. `` Cocaine is clearly a very addictive drug because it is the most reinforcing and pleasurable of the abused drugs,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON>, chief of the treatment branch at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abuse </ORGANIZATION>. `` As yet, we do n't have any good, solid research on successful crack or cocaine treatment.'' Both cocaine and crack, a crystallized form of cocaine that is smoked, work directly on the brain. It's believed the drug causes protein molecules called neuroreceptors to ignite sensations of pleasure and send pulses of euphoria along nerve pathways time after time after time. Eventually, the molecules are absorbed and the effects diminish. For the user, there's a letdown and then, quickly, a desire for more of the drug. That, <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON> said, is a cycle of reinforcement that makes cocaine so dangerous. By some estimates, almost half of all cocaine users quickly slip from casual use into an uncontrolled craving. And an even higher percentage of crack users quickly become addicts. `` Crack may be the most euphoric of all the drugs,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kleber </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> researcher who is with the National Drug Control Policy office. `` It is intensely pleasurable. It wears off very quickly and puts the user back to not feeling good. And the body has no barrier to its use.'' Those who inhale powdered cocaine are limited by the amount the nose will absorb, <PERSON> Kleber </PERSON> said, and those who inject the drug eventually run out of veins. But the lungs have a virtually unlimited ability to absorb crack smoke, he said. Success in treating addiction, he said, depends to a large degree on who is being treated. `` Some need only rehabilitation,'' he said. `` Give me an employed -LRB- professional -RRB- and I will have 60 to 70 percent success. In a year, he'll be off the drug.'' But for addicts living in poverty, particularly in the inner city, there are few positive elements to provide an incentive to stay away from cocaine. Drugs in such neighborhoods often are viewed as an industry and an economic opportunity for the young to gain wealth quickly. `` For those in the inner city, you have to address not just the drug, but the whole lifestyle,'' <PERSON> Kleber </PERSON> said. `` First they have to be off the drug. Then they have to get the skills to stay off it.'' That must include medical care, housing, education and vocational training. And `` when they go back into the community there's got to be a strong support system, a drug-free network'' to reinforce the new way of life, he said. Meanwhile, scientists are searching for a medication to help wean addicts from cocaine. `` This is not an area yet where we have good clinical science,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jasinski </PERSON>, chief of a chemical dependency clinic at <ORGANIZATION> Francis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scott </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Key </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, which is affiliated with <ORGANIZATION> Johns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hopkins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>. Finding a cocaine substitute, he said, `` is going to be very important'' in finding the best way to control cocaine. `` Within two or three years, we should have a major medication to help us,'' <PERSON> Kleber </PERSON> said. `` But I ca n't see any of these being a magic bullet'' that will automatically stop the craving or provide an effortless cure. `` It's not going to be that easy,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FungicideWithdrawn Bjt   09-07 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fungicide Withdrawn, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fungicide Voluntarily Withdrawn Due to Possible Cancer Risk</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A widely used class of fungicides is being taken off the market voluntarily for dozens of crops _ from apples to cucumbers _ because government tests indicate a higher risk of cancer than may be acceptable. The three manufacturers of the fungicide <ORGANIZATION> EBDC </ORGANIZATION> announced Wednesday they are curtailing the use of the chemical `` to maintain public confidence'' in the food products involved. However, they maintained the chemical is safe for consumers if used properly. EBDC, or ethylene bisdithiocarbamate, has been under a special review by the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> since 1987 because a breakdown product from the chemical has been shown to cause cancer in test animals. The agency recently informed the companies of preliminary cancer risk estimates that likely would require curbs on the use of EBDC on some food products, according to agency documents obtained by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The fungicide has been used for nearly 40 years to combat mildew and mold on more than 70 different food crops including apples, potatoes, tomatoes, sweet corn, onions, mushrooms, carrots, grapes, lettuce and citrus fruits, among others. In a joint announcement the three manufacturers _ the <ORGANIZATION> Du </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Pennwalt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Rohm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Haas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> _ said Wednesday they will discontinue sales of the chemical for use on all but 13 food products. The manufacturers maintained that use of the chemical _ if applied properly _ poses no health concerns, but said `` the theoretical risks'' that are being reviewed by the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> in connection with use on some products `` unnecessarily raises questions about the safety of this entire class of fungicides.'' Such concerns have been heightened since the uproar earlier this year over the pesticide Alar. While the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> did not formally order Alar off the market, its link to cancer and the widespread publicity over its use on apples earlier this year caused the sale of apple products to plummet, costing the apple industry tens of millions of dollars. The manufacturer of Alar subsequently stopped selling the pesticide in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to calm consumer fears. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasper </PERSON> confirmed that the agency is preparing to announce some curbs on the use of EBDC because of the latest cancer risk data on some food crops. `` We've got some risk estimates that we're concerned about,'' said <PERSON> Kasper </PERSON>. He said the agency will review the voluntary withdrawal of the chemical for some foods and determine whether that is adequate. But, according to <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> documents, agency tests show that the cancer risks posed by <ORGANIZATION> EBDC </ORGANIZATION> residues on some foods were many times the one in 1 million level the agency uses to indicate negligible risk. In the case of tomatoes the risk was found to be 63 times the one-in-a-million risk level which the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> considers negligible. For apples it was 150 times that benchmark, according to the documents. By comparison, the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> estimated risk estimate for Alar on applies earlier this yeas was 45 times the one-in-a-million benchmark. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Heier </PERSON> emphasized that the risk figures EBDC were preliminary and assumed crop residues at the maximum level of application according to manufacturers' instructions. The companies are conducting marketbasket studies to determine actual exposure to consumers since the chemical is known to decay with time and residues likely will be reduced through handling, processing and washing. Although the manufacturers' announcement named no food products, an environmental group, the <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, said the 13 crops for which <ORGANIZATION> EBDC </ORGANIZATION> will continue to be used include potatoes, sugar beets, sweet corn, tomatoes and wheat and almonds. <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Hathaway </PERSON>, an attorney for the environmental group, called the voluntary withdrawal of the chemical from many food crops `` an unprecedented and responsible step'' in that it comes even before the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> has proposed curbs on the fungicide's uses. But Ms. <PERSON> Hathaway </PERSON> maintained that the chemical continues to pose significant health risks in some of the foods for which it has not been withdrawn `` particularly foods like bananas, grapes and potatoes which are consumed in large quantities by children.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0211EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lebanon-US Bjt   09-07 0976</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon-US, Bjt,1009</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pullout of U.S. Diplomats Marks Milestone in Relations</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FAROUK NASSAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The evacuation of the last <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomats from <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> marks a milestone in 30 years of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> involvement in turbulent <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s envoys had clung tenaciously to the war-battered capital despite the assassination of one <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambasador, the suicide car bombings of two embassy buildings, the abductions of Americans and murderous artillery barrages. But on Wednesday, Ambassador <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> and his 29 remaining American staff members slipped out of the country aboard three <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> helicopters amid mounting criticism from militant pro-Western Christians. The Christian standard-bearer, army commander Gen. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>, had charged that <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> has `` sold <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'' out of fear for the lives of eight Americans held hostage by pro-Iranian zealots. But <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> Spokeswoman <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> angrily blamed the evacuation on <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>, saying he had threatened to expose <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> and his staff to a `` good dose of Christian terrorism.'' She said that before the evacuation, an unidentified telephone caller had threatened to shoot down a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> helicopter that brought supplies to the hilltop embassy compound in east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s Christian suburb of <LOCATION> Aukar </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s supporters besieged the embassy on Tuesday and Ms. <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> said an unidentified leader of the protest had warned that embassy employees moved in and out of the premises `` at their own risk.'' The protesters called off the siege hours after the evacuation. It is the first time that an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> ambassador has been pulled from <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> since <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s civil war between Moslems and Christians began in 1975. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials were at pains to point out that <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> diplomats would return to the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> country as soon as conditions permit, but there was no sign that this would be any time soon. Observers in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> said the American pullout would escalate the nearly 6-month-old confrontation between <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s 20,000 mainly Christian troops and 40,000 Syrian soldiers based in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s Moslem areas The fear is that the Syrians could be encouraged by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> withdrawal to step up their military pressure on <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s forces in the besieged Christian enclave north of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s troops have been locked in savage artillery duels with the Syrians and their Druse Moslem allies since March 8. The battles have killed 828 people, wounded 2,455 and forced many of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s 1.5 million residents to flee the city <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> intervened in 1976 under an Arab League mandate to stop the civil war. But <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>, who heads a <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> military Cabinet in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s splintered government, contends the Syrians betrayed their mission by supporting the Moslems. <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> declared a `` war of liberation'' March 14 to drive the Syrians out. They retaliated by blockading and ruthlessly shelling the Christian enclave. <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, whose mansion in suburban <LOCATION> Yarze </LOCATION> was frequently hit by <LOCATION> Syrian </LOCATION> shellfire, has been outspokenly critical of <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s actions and repeatedly urged <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION> to begin a dialogue with <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>. But the 54-year-old Maronite Catholic general said <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>'s behests were merely `` lip service'' and demanded full <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> recognition of him as the legitimate prime minister of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> came to <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> late in September 1988. But he did not present his credentials pending the election of a new head of state to succeed former President <PERSON> Amin </PERSON> <PERSON> Gemayel </PERSON>, whose six-year term expired that month. <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>'s move was designed to avoid recognizing either <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s Cabinet, which was formed by <PERSON> Gemayel </PERSON> minutes before he bowed out, or that of acting Prime Minister <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoss </PERSON>, a Sunni Moslem The power struggle between the two Cabinets has deepened the de facto partition of the country into sectarian mini-states. The evacuation of <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> and his staff was carried out with surgical precision. Two helicopters landed at the embassy compound at first light and took off with all 30 people within five minutes. A third gunship flew cover, witnesses reported. Nearly 540 Lebanese guards and administrative employees were left in control of the embassy and of the ambassador's residence in <LOCATION> Yarze </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> involvement in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> began July 15, 1958, when President <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> sent <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION> to <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> at the request of Christian President <PERSON> Camille </PERSON> <PERSON> Chamoun </PERSON> to quell an uprising by <PERSON> Chamoun </PERSON>'s Moslem rivals. Civil war broke out in 1975 and the following year Moslem radicals kidnapped and murdered <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Melloy </PERSON> along with his economic counselor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Waring </PERSON>. With the war, <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> became the dominant force in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s Moslem areas. That lasted until <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> invaded in June 1982. In August of that year, 800 <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION>, part of a 5,400-man peacekeeping force with British, French and Italian units, went ashore to oversee the evacuation of Israeli, Syrian and <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> forces from <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> force was later increased to 1,800 men. In April 1983, a Shiite Moslem suicide bomber rammed an explosives-packed van into the seaside <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy in west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, killing 63 people, including 17 Americans. The worst was yet to come. On Oct. 23, 1983, another Shiite suicide bomber attacked the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Marine base near <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> airport, killing 241 men, and a second bomber attacked a <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> paratroopers' base, killing 58 men. In December, American reconnaisance planes were fired on and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> responded with a <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> fighter-bomber attack that inflicted `` significant damage'' on Syrian missile and artillery batteries in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. A few days later, the battleship USS <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> bombarded Moslem positions with 250 shells from its 16-inch guns. But in February 1984, as the civil war erupted anew, the Marines were pulled back to warships off <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, a move that marked the beginning of their final withdrawal after a 22-month peacekeeping operation in which 264 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> servicemen were killed. In September 1984 a suicide bomber hit the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassy annex in <LOCATION> Christian </LOCATION> east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, killing 12 people and wounding 96, including the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador. It was this compound that was evacuated Wednesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0226EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r e BC-Kabuki     09-07 0466</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Kabuki,0488</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kabuki Troupe Opens in Met Opera House</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Stands for PMs.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Americans who only occasionally see Japanese kabuki theater may not find <PERSON> Ennosuke </PERSON>'s Kabuki as controversial as publicity before its appearances here and in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> has led them to expect. Except for some acrobatics, quick costume changes and one exit on wires through the sky, at Wednesday's first of eight performances at the Metropolitan Opera, <PERSON> Ennosuke </PERSON>'s Kabuki seemed largely to follow kabuki's traditions such as stylized fights and poses held a moment to increase tension. The troupe later will perform at Kennedy Center. The most remarkable aspect of <PERSON> Ennosuke </PERSON>'s Kabuki is its leading actor, <PERSON> Ichikawa </PERSON> <PERSON> Ennosuke </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, who has organized this company of 36 actors and 24 musicians. Two pieces are done at each performance, which lasts three and a half hours, longer than many Americans wish an evening of theater to last. The first is three acts from `` Yoshitsune Senbonzakura,'' an eight-hour, six-act play which was first done in 1747 with puppets and adapted to kabuki the following year. In it, <PERSON> Ennosuke </PERSON> plays two parts, <PERSON> Tadanobu </PERSON>, a warrior faithful to a hero and a fox who has transformed himself to look like the warrior. The fox did it, the audience learns, to be near <PERSON> Tadanobu </PERSON>'s lover who has a drum made of the skin of his parents. This illustrates fillial piety. <PERSON> Ennosuke </PERSON>, who is 49, is young enough to jump up a flight of steps two at a time, vault off the back of a porch and crawl under it, emerging at the front in white fox fur. But more remarkable than that is the difference in stance the actor has for <PERSON> Tadanobu </PERSON> and for the fox as <PERSON> Tadanobu </PERSON>, when his hands subtly become paws and his head is held less militarily. Some kabuki companies' strongest actors play young women. However, the actor playing <PERSON> Tadanobu </PERSON>'s lover was simpering and whiney. In the second play, `` Kurozuka,'' <PERSON> Ennosuke </PERSON> played an old woman, actually a demon, whose soul is soothed by a <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> priest who says that even demons can find enlightenment. <PERSON> Ennosuke </PERSON> does a gentle dance in what looks like a corn field, including deep breaths of relief. Then a comic character, played by <PERSON> Ennosuke </PERSON>'s younger brother, blunders and <PERSON> Ennosuke </PERSON> becomes a demon with red tongue and deep, angry voice. In other kabuki troupes visiting here, older actors have made characters like the old woman more poignant. But <PERSON> Ennosuke </PERSON>'s old woman is n't superficial. One would like to see his troupe again and him again, as he deepens farther in conveying human emotion. Viewers could rent an apparatus to place in one ear, for English summary and commentary, while allowing the rise and fall of the Japanese voices to be heard with the other ear.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0226EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     09-07 0344</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0355</SECOND>
<HEAD>NBC News Special `Bad Girls' Makes TV Top 10</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY BUCK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Bad Girls,'' a news special on juvenile delinquents, helped <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> extend its prime-time <PERSON> Nielsen </PERSON> ratings streak to 63 weeks in a week dominated by sitcoms. `` Bad Girls,'' reported by <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> correspondent <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Norville </PERSON>, tied for seventh place with <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Who's the Boss?'' It was the only original show in last week's top 10 during this summer rerun period. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne'' was first again in the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> survey, followed by <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Cheers.'' <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'s highest-rated show, `` Married ... With Children,'' dropped from 17th to 41st place. Still, most of the <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> shows were able to hold their newfound positions in the middle of the ratings. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> extended its record streak at the top with an average prime-time rating of 10.6. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s average was 9.7 and CBS' was 9.0. The rating point is the percentage of the nation's estimated 90.4 million homes with televisions. The first of the new fall shows for the three networks will make its appearance this week. CBS' `` Rescue: 911'' had its premiere on Tuesday. Next week, five more shows will make their debut, and the fall season begins Sept. 18. <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> has gotten an early start with some of its shows. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> last week had seven of the top 10 shows. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> once again failed to make the top 10. Its highest-rated show was `` Designing Women'' in 13th place. Here are the top 10: <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Cheers,'' `` The Cosby Show,'' `` A Different World'' and `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Wonder Years,'' NBC News special `` Bad Girls'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Who's the Boss?'' tied, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Golden Girls'' and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Empty Nest'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Anything But Love,'' tied. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> was first among the evening news shows with a rating of 9.1. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> had a 9.0 and NBC 8.6. `` The Joan Rivers Show,'' a new syndicated daytime talk show, made its premier Tuesday with good ratings in the Nielsen overnights. It was first in six of 13 cities, according to <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0228EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     09-07 0719</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0804</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of Aug. 28-Sept. 3 Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.4 rating, 17.5 million homes. 2. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.6, 15.9 million homes. 3. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.5, 14.9 million homes. 4. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.1, 14.6 million homes. 5. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.8, 14.3 million homes. 6. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.7, 14.2 million homes. 7. -LRB- X -RRB- `` News Special: Bad Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3, 13.8 million homes. 7. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3, 13.8 million homes. 9. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.2, 13.7 million homes. 10. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1, 13.6 million homes. 10. -LRB- 12 -RRB- `` Anything But Love,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1, 13.6 million homes. 12. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.5, 13.1 million homes. 13. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 14.4, 13.0 million homes. 14. -LRB- 32 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 14.0, 12.6 million homes. 15. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 13.7, 12.4 million homes. 16. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.5, 12.2 million homes. 17. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.0, 11.7 million homes. 18. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 12.9, 11.6 million homes. 19. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.6, 11.4 million homes. 19. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.6, 11.4 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5. 22. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.2. 23. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.1. 24. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 12.0. 24. -LRB- 47 -RRB- `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0. 24. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> Pre-Season Football,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0. 27. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` FM,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.9. 28. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' CBS, 11.8. 28. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 11.8. 28. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Designing Women Special,'' CBS, 11.8. 31. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.7. 32. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.5. 32. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` Midnight Caller,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.5. 34. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` In the Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.4. 35. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Valvoline National Driving Test,'' CBS, 11.3. 35. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 35. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 38. -LRB- 61 -RRB- `` Police Academy 3: Back In Training,'' _ `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' 10.9. 38. -LRB- 73 -RRB- `` Primetime Live,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.9. 40. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Saved By The Bell Preview,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.7. 41. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 10.4. 42. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.6. 43. -LRB- 77 -RRB- `` 13 East,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.1. 44. -LRB- 89 -RRB- `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.0. 44. -LRB- X -RRB- `` ABC News Special: Black In <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.0. 46. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` Final Jeopardy,'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 8.9. 47. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.5. 48. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 48. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> Pre-Season Football,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 48. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Totally Hidden Video,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 48. -LRB- 76 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: No Place Like Home,'' CBS, 8.3. 48. -LRB- 60 -RRB- `` Coach,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 53. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` Hooperman,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.1. 54. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` My Two Loves,'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 8.0. 55. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` Deep Cover,'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 7.9. 55. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 7.9. 57. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Queen of the Beasts,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 7.7. 58. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Open House,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 7.4. 58. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Mannequin,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 7.4. 58. -LRB- 92 -RRB- `` Quiet Victory,'' _ `` CBS Friday Movie,'' 7.4. 61. -LRB- 72 -RRB- `` The Equalizer,'' CBS, 7.3. 62. -LRB- 63 -RRB- `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 7.2. 63. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.0.. 64 -LRB- X -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> Pre-Season Football,'' CBS, 6.9. 65. -LRB- 46 -RRB- `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.7. 65. -LRB- 105 -RRB- `` Knots Landing,'' CBS, 6.7. 67. -LRB- 99 -RRB- `` A Man Called Hawk,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.5. 68. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Short Summer-Charlie <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS, 6.4. 69. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` Bring Me The Head-Dobie G,'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 6.0. 70. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Gideon </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON>,'' _ `` ABC Mystery Movie,'' 5.9. 71. -LRB- 83 -RRB- `` Paradise,'' CBS, 5.8. 71. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.8. 73. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Bugs Bunny's Mad World,'' CBS, 5.6. 73. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Great Circuses of the World,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.6. 75. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.1. 76. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.0. 76. -LRB- 107 -RRB- `` Incredible Sunday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.0. 78. -LRB- 83 -RRB- `` The Barefoot Executive,'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> Magical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 4.5. 79. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Hound Town Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 4.4. 80. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.2. 81. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` The Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.1. 82. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Only Temporary Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 3.8. 82. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.8. 83. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.7.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0229EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     09-07 0048</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0052</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Wednesday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 05; 07; 11; 13; 30; 33.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto Game: 20; 25; 28; 29; 35; 42. Supplementary 22.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 3-3-7; 1-7-8-8; 5-0-6-1-6; 2-5-5-6-2-9.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890907-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-07-89 0121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MTVAwards 4thLd-Writethru a0402 09-07 0871</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-MTV Awards, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0402,0897</SECOND>
<HEAD>Michael Jackson Leads Video Nominees</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 25 grafs to UPDATE with final awards; picks up 15th
graf, `Jackson was ...</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto LA8,9</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN ANTCZAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNIVERSAL CITY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
