<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0031EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Frank     12-09 0328</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Frank,0337</SECOND>
<HEAD>Publisher Frank Dead at 77</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Publisher <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, chairman emeritus of the Sunday newspaper supplement USA Weekend, died of complications following heart surgery in <LOCATION> Bridgeport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, his son said Friday. He was 77. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> died late Thursday at <LOCATION> Bridgeport </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, said his son, <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodds </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, a correspondent with ABC News in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. For 14 years, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> was in charge of Family Weekly, now called USA Weekend. During his tenure, circulation grew from about 3 million in fewer than 100 newspapers to more than 13 million in more than 360 newspapers. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> arranged the sale of the publication in 1976; it is now owned by <ORGANIZATION> Gannett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. Inc.. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> also was on the board of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nursing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishing </ORGANIZATION> and of <ORGANIZATION> Horizon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, publishers of <ORGANIZATION> Vista </ORGANIZATION>, a national newspaper supplement targeted at A native of <LOCATION> Pitcairn </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> earned gradyated from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> in 1933. He received a law degree from <ORGANIZATION> Alfred </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1979. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> started his career as an advertising manager for the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Braddock </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, and a year later was named editor of the <ORGANIZATION> Braddock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. He next worked for the <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> for six years, as an advertising salesman, entertainment writer and manager of rotogravure. During World War II, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> was an intelligence officer and gunnery officer before becoming executive officer of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Fleet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Town </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> In 1946, he worked for the <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> before moving to <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, with his first wife, <PERSON> Agnes </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodds </PERSON>. There they owned, edited and published weekly newspapers including the <ORGANIZATION> Canton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economist </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Stark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. Divorced in 1958, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> married <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Pope </PERSON>, a magazine editor, in 1963. The couple lived in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Easton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> is survived by his wife; his son <PERSON> Allan </PERSON>; another son, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, an independent record producer in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, and a daughter, <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, an actress in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     12-09 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0025</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 10; 19; 21; 23; 40; 41.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     12-09 0082</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0087</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 10; 19; 21; 23; 40; 41.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 8-2-2-8.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 05; 19; 24; 25; 30; 35.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 03; 07; 13; 16; 20; 37. Bonus: 3-1-4-7-7.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto Game: 07; 21; 24; 36; 41; 48. Supplementary 25.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 7-1-9-2.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 8-3-5; 3-2-5-6; 8-6-3-4-9; 3-3-4-1-7-1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0426EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--HomelessCarol     12-09 0163</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Homeless Carol,0174</SECOND>
<HEAD>Doctors to Sing Carol For Homeless Vets at White House</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WEST HAVEN, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will get a musical reminder about the plight of homeless veterans when a group of doctors performs at the White House next week. Dr. <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, chief of rehabilitative medicine at the <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Haven </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, said he will sing `` A Soldier's <PERSON> Carol </PERSON>,'' when the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> sings Christmas carols for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his family on Wednesday. The group was formed seven years ago to sing for patients. The song tells of a soldier serving in a foreign land. Crouching in a foxhole, he sees a bright star and thinks about Christmas and his home. It continues: `` Now I'm home for Christmas `` My home is on the ground. `` Family all have left me, `` And strangers all around. `` It is n't what I fought for `` But what is there to say. `` I fought for flag and country. `` Please God, help me this day.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-FamilyReunited     12-09 0520</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Family Reunited,0533</SECOND>
<HEAD>Plaintiff in Prominent Abortion Case Reunited with Last Missing Child</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY L. CARTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman who was the anonymous plaintiff in one of two landmark <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decisions legalizing abortion said Friday she will be reunited with the last of the children taken from her 20 years ago. <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Cano </PERSON>, who was identified as <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> in <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Bolton </PERSON>, said her 22-year-old daughter April will fly to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> on Saturday. It will be their first meeting in more than 17 years. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s decision in Doe vs. <PERSON> Bolton </PERSON>, which struck down <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>'s abortion law, was issued Jan. 22, 1973, the same day the court struck down <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>' abortion law in the more famous case labeled <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON>. Earlier this year <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Cano </PERSON> was reunited with the daughter involved in that case. Mrs. <PERSON> Cano </PERSON> said she gave that child, <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON>, up for adoption in 1970 after deciding not to go through with the abortion. Mrs. <PERSON> Cano </PERSON>, of suburban <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, noted that two older children, a son <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> and a daughter April, had been taken from her a year before that. She said she lost custody of the children after a dispute with a sitter and `` because of me being young and naive.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Cano </PERSON>, whose name was <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Bensing </PERSON> at the time, said she tried to regain custody of the children from the family they had been placed with and finally got the boy 12 years ago, when he was 11. She has not seen the girl, however, since 1972. Child welfare officials thought it best that the family not be reunited. `` Family and Children Services just kept telling me she was happily adopted and to let her alone,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Cano </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. She said she managed to track the adoptive parents to <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION> and then <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, but hit a dead end eight years ago. In November, a week after Thanksgiving, April called. Mrs. <PERSON> Cano </PERSON> said her daughter told her she had been trying to find her mother since being abandoned by her adoptive family and placed in a mental hospital at age 14. She said her adoptive father, who refused to have anything to do with her, was the one who finally told her to contact <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> social services, leading her to her birth mother. Now that she has her family back, Mrs. <PERSON> Cano </PERSON> said, she plans to increase her involvement in the pro-life movement. Because of her connection to the court case and her present stand against abortion, she has been invited to represent the anti-abortion position on talk shows and at meetings. After she identified herself as the case's <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> in February, she said, her car was shot at, two trucks were stolen and graffiti was scrawled on another vehicle. She and her husband moved out of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> to a suburb, she said, declining to identify their hometown. `` I'm going to start coming out, start speaking out and being more active now, because we've got the children back,'' she said. `` Not many people get that second chance.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0426EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--ArmyMule     12-09 0136</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Army Mule,0140</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cancer Claims One Of Army's Mule Mascots</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WEST POINT, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Army Cadets were minus one of their veterans in today's college football game against <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Black </PERSON> <PERSON> Jack </PERSON>, one of three mules used as mascots at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>, died of stomach cancer on Thursday. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> officials said Friday there was nothing suspicious about the death. `` The timing was curious but there was no foul play,'' <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> spokesman Col. <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawthorne </PERSON> said. He said the other two mules, 21-year-old Spartacus and 16-year-old Ranger, were to be at today's game at Giants Stadium in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rutherford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> Mules became the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> mascot in 1899, when <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s football team showed up with a goat at the game. <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> fans retaliated by borrowing a mule from an ice wagon.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ElectricChair     12-09 0254</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Electric Chair,0260</SECOND>
<HEAD>Christmas Display Features Electric Chair</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NYACK, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 You've seen flashing lights, glowing Santas and red-nosed <ORGANIZATION> Rudolphs </ORGANIZATION> plugged in to mark the Christmas season. <PERSON> Arlene </PERSON> <PERSON> Lederman </PERSON> opted for something different this year: an electric chair. The antiques shop owner is sending shock waves along Main Street in <LOCATION> Nyack </LOCATION> with the oak chair, the centerpiece of her store's holiday window display. <PERSON> Lederman </PERSON>, a member of <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, said the display symbolizes her opposition to the death penalty. `` It's a good time to make people look,'' <PERSON> Lederman </PERSON> said. `` There are certain times people look at windows and Christmas is one time people do a lot of Christmas window shopping.'' The chair, decked with holiday lights, is surrounded by polyester snow and an art deco sled. Inside the store, <PERSON> Lederman </PERSON> provides her customers with anti-death penalty literature. <PERSON> Lederman </PERSON> found the chair at a renovation site in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J </LOCATION>. Since the display went up on Wednesday, <PERSON> Lederman </PERSON> has heard plenty about it in the town 25 miles north of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. `` Some people do n't like it. They do n't think it's in the Christmas spirit. I could have put up little Santas and toys, but I decided to see what happened when I did this.'' There have been a few nasty phone calls and sarcastic remarks such as, `` Why do n't you put <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION> in there and burn him?'' she said. Other callers have offered support. `` We've made mistakes with capital punishment and there's nothing you can do There's no reprieve,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;Ls-CenTrust Bjt   12-09 0851</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;Ls-CenTrust, Bjt,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Reins In Florida's Largest S&amp;L</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal regulators are reining in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s largest savings and loan, <ORGANIZATION> CenTrust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION>, which lavished millions of dollars on expensive art, yachts, corporate jets and limousines <ORGANIZATION> CenTrust </ORGANIZATION> called the action unnecessary, saying the thrift was in its best financial condition in five years. In a legal order issued Friday, the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thrift </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supervision </ORGANIZATION> told the institution to sell what's left of its $ 29 million art collection, some of which had been kept at the home of <ORGANIZATION> CenTrust </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>. It forbid <ORGANIZATION> CenTrust </ORGANIZATION> from increasing its executives' salaries or paying dividends to stockholders, told it to sell its limousines, jet and a $ 233,000 sailboat known as `` Bodacious.'' Within 90 days, the institution must stop paying the crew and other expenses for the yacht owned by <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, `` Grand Cru.'' The thrift office said in a statement that it issued the order to `` curb serious dissipation of the institution's assets'' after determining that <ORGANIZATION> CenTrust </ORGANIZATION> had `` engaged in regulatory violations and unsafe or unsound practices.'' <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, in a statement issued in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, criticized the OTS action. `` The OTS is clearly trying to use <ORGANIZATION> CenTrust </ORGANIZATION> as a test case to impose its views on the thrift industry after it failed to get its views adopted by the accounting profession,'' <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> said. `` Our financial statements ... have been reviewed by a leading accounting firm and found to be in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles. `` We intend to vigorously contest this unilateral and misguided OTS action.'' S & amp; L bailout legislation enacted in August `` gave us the enforcement power to move quickly, and we are taking full advantage of this authority,'' said thrift office director <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Wall </PERSON>. However, a private analyst said <ORGANIZATION> CenTrust </ORGANIZATION> will almost certainly fail and that the `` cease and desist'' order came too late to save taxpayers much money. `` Centrust is a gone institution. I think the order in and of itself is n't going to do anything. The damage has been done,'' said <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Ely </PERSON>, a financial institutions analyst in <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. At the end of June, <ORGANIZATION> CenTrust </ORGANIZATION> was reporting assets of $ 9.7 billion, making it the nation's 22nd largest S & amp; L and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s It was $ 43.3 million in the red, as measured by tangible capital, having slipped over the previous year from being in the black by $ 12.89 million. The S & amp; L and its 71 branch offices remain open during normal business hours, with all deposit accounts federally insured to $ 100,000. <ORGANIZATION> CenTrust </ORGANIZATION> has been seeking federal approval to sell 63 of its branches and deposit accounts assigned to those offices to <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, the nation's second-largest <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ely </PERSON> speculated that the thrift office's order was issued to buy time until the branch sales can go through One provision of the order forbids <ORGANIZATION> CenTrust </ORGANIZATION> from further sale of its uninsured debt to its retail customers. Such sales have drawn the close scrutiny of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> since the spring when 22,000 customers lost an estimated $ 250 million by purchasing the debt of <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Irvine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> member who is sponsoring legislation banning S & amp; Ls from selling debt through their branch offices, said <ORGANIZATION> CenTrust </ORGANIZATION>'s debt also was `` potentially worthless. Earlier, it received permission from the thrift office to sell $ 50 million in debt in minimum denominations of $ 2,000. <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON> said thrift office records show that shaky S & amp; Ls are more likely to issue their debt in small denominations, which attracts unsophisticated investors who can be misled into thinking they are buying insured certificates of deposit. <ORGANIZATION> CenTrust </ORGANIZATION>, under orders from state regulators, has already sold much of its 22-painting collection, bought for $ 29 million, including `` Portrait of a Man as Mars'' by Flemish master <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubens </PERSON>. According to the thrift office, <ORGANIZATION> CenTrust </ORGANIZATION> also spent $ 329,000 on four sculptures, $ 208,000 for four oriental rugs and $ 84,000 for crystal stemware. Maintenance and hangar fees for its corporate jet exceeded $ 1 million a year. It spent $ 26,000 a year to lease a <ORGANIZATION> Mercedes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Benz </ORGANIZATION> limousine in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and $ 40,000 to buy a <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> limousine maintained in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Despite <ORGANIZATION> CenTrust </ORGANIZATION>'s deteriorating condition, its chairman's compensation increased from $ 550,000 a year in 1988 to $ 950,000 a year currently Over the period, he also received bonuses, stock dividends and insurance benefits worth nearly $ 4 million. Additionally, the thrift paid $ 308,000 from January 1987 through July 1989 for guard services at his home and spent $ 45,000 in 1988 to put the chairman up for 35 nights at the Stanhope Hotel in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. As part of the order, <ORGANIZATION> CenTrust </ORGANIZATION> was required to make its books and records immediately available to federal regulators, who began examining the institution May 31 and complained that they were denied access to records. <ORGANIZATION> CenTrust </ORGANIZATION>'s books `` are so incomplete'' that examiners can not determine its true financial condition, the thrift office said. <ORGANIZATION> CenTrust </ORGANIZATION> stock, which had been selling on the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> for as much as $ 6.87 -LCB- within the past year, on Friday fell from $ 1.37 -LCB- to $ 1 at the close of trading.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TechnologyExports Bjt   12-09 0574</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Technology Exports, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration May Relax Ban on High-Tech Exports</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, in the wake of the <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> summit and the dramatic changes occurring in the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> bloc, is reviewing whether to relax the ban on sale of high-technology exports to Communist countries. Commerce Secretary <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> said in an interview Friday that he expected the administration would reach a decision by April, predicting that <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> could be early beneficiaries of a more liberalized policy. The dispute involves a 40-year-old prohibition intended to keep high technology products with military applications from falling into Communist hands. The administration is under growing pressure to ease the controls as a way of boosting the economic and political reforms sweeping through <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Western allies argue that with Cold War frictions easing, it is important for the West to supply the technology needed for Communist countries to boost living standards. Controls on high-technology exports are administered by the <ORGANIZATION> Coordinating </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Multinational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Export </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Controls </ORGANIZATION>, known as <ORGANIZATION> COCOM </ORGANIZATION>. It consists of the 15 <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> nations along with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> said the administration hoped to reach a decision on easing controls in time to present the proposals at the next meeting of <ORGANIZATION> COCOM </ORGANIZATION>, scheduled for early April in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> said that <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> are already discussing with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials how to prevent the transfer of militarily strategic items to neighboring Communist bloc countries. He said that such assurances would allow the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to look favorably on giving those two countries access to more sophisticated technology. `` Everybody is discussing what we should be doing about <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, whether it is politically, economically or technologically,'' <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> said in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is considering `` a shortening of the list -LRB- of restricted items -RRB- to those things which are truly important and essential,'' <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> said in a separate interview taped for public television's American Interests program. `` The shortening will be substantial ... that would be our recommendation,'' he said. The administration has been split between hardliners such as <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>, who oppose the easing for national security reasons, and others such as <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON>, who argue that liberalization is needed in light of the changes. <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> was the third administration official in recent days to discuss the possibility of lowering export controls. Similar comments about possible changes have also been made by <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Undersecretary <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulford </PERSON> and Deputy Secretary of State <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON>. <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> planned to eliminate the case-by-case approval required to export `` dual use'' high-technology items to other <ORGANIZATION> COCOM </ORGANIZATION> members. `` Dual use'' refers to technology that has both commercial and military applications. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has repeatedly clashed with its allies, especially <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, over what it argues are violations of <ORGANIZATION> COCOM </ORGANIZATION> rules regarding dual use technology. In the latest such case, the administration accused the Italian computer manufacturer <ORGANIZATION> Olivetti </ORGANIZATION> of selling the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> computerized machine tools that the Soviets used to make jet fighter engines. In a speech last week, <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> said the requirement for individual licenses will be lifted within six months. Referring to the question of easing restrictions on exports to <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> said the `` nature of the military threat faced by the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> is changing'' and the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> needed to `` signal our clear willingness to respond constructively to the democratization under way in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AutoSafety-Curry     12-09 0345</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Auto Safety-Curry,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Traffic Safety Head Opposes On-Board Vapor Units</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government's top highway safety official says devices inside cars to capture gas vapors when a tank is being filled would pose safety risks. `` It appears to be an idea whose time has not come,'' <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Curry </PERSON> said Friday in his first speech since being sworn in last week as administrator of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Traffic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Curry </PERSON> said the agency will join safety groups in opposing legislation that would require the units on all new cars. A bill supported by environmental groups and the oil industry is pending in the House. <PERSON> Curry </PERSON> said his agency's first priority in dealing with auto and truck issues would continue to be highway safety, followed by better gas mileage and clean air. The former <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> major general said <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION>'s technical evaluations show that some important safety concerns remain with the systems to capture gas vapor and return it to a car's engine through a special holding unit containing charcoal. <PERSON> Curry </PERSON> said there have been problems even with some of the simple systems cars have had since 1971 for returning some vapor to the gas tank, which have resulted in fires, injuries and vehicle recalls. Several areas of the country require gasoline stations to equip their hoses with units that suck vapors back into the station's tank The requirements often are part of state and city efforts to meet <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> air quality standards. <PERSON> Curry </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> supports the idea of a vapor recovery system and will continue to work with the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> to test proposals for effectiveness and safety. On other issues, <PERSON> Curry </PERSON> said he: _ Supported laws requiring motorcyclists to wear helmets, saying he would wage a campaign of letters and support legislation to require them _ Would base future recommendations for auto mileage standards, or Corporate Average Fuel Economy -LRB- CAFE -RRB- standards, `` on facts, not on theology. Environmentalists are pushing for tighter standards, but auto manufacturers say that would prevent them from building many larger cars and could decrease overall auto safety.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CoalfieldChristmas Bjt   12-09 0650</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Coalfield Christmas, Bjt,0671</SECOND>
<HEAD>Christmas in Strike-Torn Coal Fields</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID REED</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROANOKE, Va, (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This Christmas season is bittersweet for striking coal miners, who've been living off meager union payments for eight months but enjoying a groundswell of support from workers around the country and the world. Other unions are shipping tons of donated food, clothing and toys to the <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> coal fields, where the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> are locked in a strike that began just after Easter. Members of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commercial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> today are bringing toys, treats and clothes to the <LOCATION> Russell </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fairgrounds </LOCATION>, where they'll sing Christmas carols for miners' During Thanksgiving week, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> had a 15 - to 20-pound turkey delivered to each striking miner's family `` This is going to be a terrific Christmas for the strikers' kids because of the support that we've got from other unions around the world,'' said <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, a striker who supports a wife and two daughters `` This may be one of the best Christmases they've ever had. The strike has become a symbolic line in the sand for members of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> labor movement who want to stop the erosion of collective bargaining. They portray <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> as the prime example of a union-busting company. <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> officials say they are offering a fair contract and are being unfairly targeted by the union's national leadership. The strike started after <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> bolted from a contract between the <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Bituminous </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operators </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, saying health benefits offered by the owners' group were too generous. Labor solidarity with the miners was bolstered in October when <ORGANIZATION> UMW </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Trumka </PERSON> brought the union, which had been independent for 40 years, back into the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>. Strikers say Labor Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s interest in resolving the strike only increased after an official of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s Solidarity movement visited the coal fields in November and criticized treatment of the miners in a meeting with Mrs. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> About $ 300,000 has been donated to a Christmas fund set up for the miners on Nov. 10. The money will be distributed next week to families of the 2,100 striking and laid-off miners in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>. `` We've had people calling from all around the contry wanting to send money or donate food or clothing,'' said <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON>, a striking miner and the Christmas fund trustee. `` It seems like people are getting into the Christmas feeling that giving is better than receiving.'' `` They see the hardships we're going through,'' said <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, 35. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 42, an electrician, said he would use his share of the Christmas fund to buy winter coats for his two children. But what his family really needs, he said, is for him to get back to work. `` It wo n't be the happiest Christmas,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. `` With all this support it's not going to be all that grim. But we still do n't know what tomorrow is going to bring. Union and company negotiators are planning to meet Monday in northern <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> for another round of contract talks mediated by former <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Usery </PERSON>. <PERSON> Usery </PERSON> is optimistic that the negotiations will lead to a settlement, but striking miners are skeptical. `` Nobody thinks it will be settled by Christmas,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. The miners are preparing for the strike to last through winter and on Thursday opened an indoor rally site, Camp Solidarity II, near <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, to demonstrate their resolve The miners, used to earning as much as $ 635 a week, have been receiving $ 225 a week in strike wages, and that pays only for necessities, <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> said. In many cases, wives who did not work before the strike have taken jobs. `` Things have gotten tight,'' <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> said. `` You just hold off on the luxuries of life when you're on strike and not working.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TitanLaunch     12-09 0153</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Titan Launch,0156</SECOND>
<HEAD>Storm Scrubs Satellite Launch</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Stormy weather forced <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Marietta </PERSON> to delay the first commercial launch of its Titan 3 rocket carrying British and Japanese communications satellites. The attempt was called off Friday about two hours before the planned liftoff when a storm dumped heavy rain on the launch area. The delay will last at least until next week because a <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> rocket scheduled for Sunday carries a military navigation satellite for the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and has priority. Officials said the Titan could be delayed until later in December because it also has lower priority than both the Titan II missile launch scheduled next week and the flight of the Space Shuttle Columbia planned for Dec. 18. The flight was to have marked <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Marietta </PERSON>'s entry into the highly competitive commercial launch business. Liftoff had been postponed on Thursday night by a computer software problem.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PersianGulf-Battleship     12-09 0294</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Persian Gulf-Battleship,290</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Sends Battleship New Jersey Into Persian Gulf</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials say the battleship <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> has entered the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> _ the first time such a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warship has sailed the sensitive waterway in modern times. <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman Army Col. <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> said Friday that the 58,000-ton vessel entered the gulf Thursday night on a `` routine operation to demonstrate a continuing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commitment to the region.'' The oil-rich gulf was the scene for much of the decade of hostilities between <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, marked by fighting that sank or damaged more than 500 commercial ships and killed 300 people. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> sharply expanded its naval force in the region in 1987, using it to protect merchant ships flying <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> flags. After the August 1988 truce between the two nations, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> reduced its naval presence. One Pentagon official, commenting on condition he not be identified by name, said port calls in <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Emirates </LOCATION> are scheduled for the warship, but that a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> offer to have the ship visit a port in <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> was turned down. <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> said he could not disclose the ship's schedule nor the ports it planned to visit. He did say the battleship was not being accompanied by a battle group of support vessels. While <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> battleships have entered the <ORGANIZATION> Straits </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hormuz </ORGANIZATION>, which links the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> to the northern <LOCATION> Arabian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>, none has ever sailed deep into the waterway that divides <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> from the <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabian </LOCATION> peninsula, other sources said. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Quigley </PERSON>, who said he could not confirm the movement of the battleship, said the service `` does n't have a record that indicates a battleship has been in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> in modern times.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Yugoslavia-Crisis Bjt   12-09 0670</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Yugoslavia-Crisis, Bjt,0692</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yugoslovia Consumed by Crisis</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DUSAN STOJANOVIC</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BELGRADE, Yugoslavia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 While most European Communist nations surge toward democracy, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>, once a socialist showcase, is sinking ever deeper into its apparently unending political crisis. Faced with ethnic and social tensions, rapidly growing inflation and labor unrest, the country is now split into what looks like an unbridgeable rift between two of its six republics _ <LOCATION> Slovenia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION>. Some lawmakers, newspapers and organizations even raise the issue of civil war. In an unprecedented move, <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION> on Nov. 29 severed all political and business ties with the northern region of <LOCATION> Slovenia </LOCATION> after authorities there banned a rally planned by Serbs seeking to topple <LOCATION> Slovenia </LOCATION>'s liberal leadership. Except for a desperate warning that the country's unity is `` seriously'' threatened by the clash, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>'s divided leadership has done nothing to ease tensions. <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> has for years been a socialist showcase despite its one-party system, with a relatively free press and no travel restrictions. But its political, economic and social problems have mushroomed since the death in 1980 of President <PERSON> Josip </PERSON> <PERSON> Broz </PERSON> <PERSON> Tito </PERSON>, whose charisma was seen as a major force in keeping <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> together and submerging regional tensions. The man in the center of <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>'s current turmoil is <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION>'s president, <PERSON> Slobodan </PERSON> <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>, described in <LOCATION> Slovenia </LOCATION> and some other republics as `` a Stalinist, dogmatist and totalitarian leader.'' In his speech to the Serbian Parliament Tuesday, <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON> denounced the Slovenian leadership for not allowing an anti-Slovenian rally by Serbs planned in the Slovenian city of <LOCATION> Ljubljana </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON> vowed that <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION> will not re-establish ties with <LOCATION> Slovenia </LOCATION> `` until the conservative, aggressive and brutal'' Slovenian leaders step down. Commenting on <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>'s speech, the Croatian Vjesnik daily said Thursday that the Serbian leader's `` stubborn ultimatum'' is aimed at imposing his hard-line brand of Communist orthodoxy on the rest of the country. The newspaper described as `` grotesque'' <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>'s accusations against <LOCATION> Slovenia </LOCATION> and appealed to the country's leadership to stop the <LOCATION> Serbian </LOCATION> president and prevent him from `` leading the country to civil war.'' Similarly, <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zagreb </ORGANIZATION> last week said, `` <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> is on the verge of war with itself.'' <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON> has purged thousands of opponents in <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION>, and several independent political and human rights groups, which are growing elswhere in the country, have been banned in the southern republic. On Thursday, a prominent Serbian journalist appeared in court to answer charges of leading an unofficial gathering that described <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>'s recent re-election as <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION>'s president as `` undemocratic.'' In <LOCATION> Slovenia </LOCATION>, its liberal-minded leadership advocates regional autonomy and has already legalized several opposition parties that are to contest the first-ever free, multiparty elections in postwar <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>, scheduled in <LOCATION> Slovenia </LOCATION> for March. `` <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION>'s move against <LOCATION> Slovenia </LOCATION> represents an attack by a totalitarian concept of -LRB- Communist -RRB- party monopoly against all who strive for democratic reforms and whose oppinions differ from those of Serbian political leaders,'' said a statement released by Slovenian <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. Slovenian leaders believe <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON> wants to provoke a showdown with their republic in order to turn public attention away from his economic and political failures. An announced $ 1 billion public loan, described as a centerpiece of <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>'s economic policies in <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION>, has all but collapsed when government officials were able to secure only about 3 percent of the planned sum. Despite <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>'s promises to halt ethnic Albanian unrest in the southern <LOCATION> Serbian </LOCATION> province of <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>, disturbances there have continued unabated. <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>'s parliament is to meet next week for an urgent session to discuss the country's crisis. `` Comrades, our country is falling appart,'' said a parliamentary deputy Thursday. Western diplomats in <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION> point out that the split within <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> could not have come at a worse time for the reformist government of Premier Ante <PERSON> Markovic </PERSON>, which is currently negotiating with the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monetary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> on obtaining crucial new loans designed to repay the country's $ 17 billion foreign debt. The diplomats say <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>'s `` irrational moves'' could collapse the delicate negotiations that began Thursday, thereby threatening radical market-oriented reforms <PERSON> Markovic </PERSON> is trying to implement in <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names Sub a0418 12-09 0233</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names, Sub, a0418,0238</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS NEW YORK-dated 1st item to CORRECT in 2nd graf, `Mason
met ...' `Spector' to `Specter.'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A politician has unleashed comedian <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> again, despite the fallout <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> caused during the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> mayoral race. <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> met with Sen. <PERSON> Arlen </PERSON> <PERSON> Specter </PERSON>, R-Pa., in a very public lunch Friday that <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> said was aimed at creating a higher profile for <PERSON> Specter </PERSON>, though his re-election campaign is n't until 1992 <PERSON> Specter </PERSON> said he and <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> had met last year in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for lunch _ `` I still have the receipt in my pocket,'' the senator cracked _ and they have stayed in touch since then. `` All my life I heard there was no such thing as a free lunch. But whenever I see a senator eating, he's eating for free,'' <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> said. The two men posed for photographs after lunch at <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON>'s and <PERSON> Specter </PERSON> said he was unworried about any fallout. <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> created problems for <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> mayoral hopeful <PERSON> Rudolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON> earlier in the year with a perceived slur against blacks. `` <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON>'s speaking for himself. I'll deny everything <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> says,'' <PERSON> Specter </PERSON> joked. Though <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> was apologetic after his remarks during the campaign, he was back to his nose-thumbing self on Friday. `` It's the same jokes I told on Broadway for two years. I got a Tony Award for those jokes,'' said <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Quayle-StarWars     12-09 0430</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle-Star Wars,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayle Tells Soviets They May Like Star Wars After All</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> says the Soviets may find they like Star Wars after all. `` I have a hunch, over a longer period of time, the more the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> thinks about the SDI, there may be a change of heart, because this is defending against ballistic missiles, not just a threat from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>, but a threat from other countries,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said in an interview published Friday in the Soviet daily newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION>. The Strategic Defense Initiative `` makes sense for both sides,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said in the interview conducted Thursday in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. SDI calls for a space-based high technology network that would shoot down incoming enemy missiles. U.S.-Soviet disagreement over the plan, long a bone of contention between the two superpowers, wrecked the 1986 summit in <LOCATION> Reykjavik </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iceland </LOCATION>. `` As we look at this world in the future, becoming less dependent on offensive weapons for deterrence, reducing -LRB- but not eliminating -RRB- offensive strategic weapons, we'll see other countries gaining ballistic missile technology,'' the vice president said. `` Instead of having only the ability of going in and attacking after an attack, you might want the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to have a more effective defense than it has today _ against Third World threats. `` The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has always thought in terms of defense _ strategic and conventional _ so SDI, which was a sticking point in the past, perhaps will not be in the future.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said he regarded the <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> summit between President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> as `` very positive'' meeting that could lead to conclusion of an agreement on strategic nuclear arms by the next summit next summer. `` Neither side is going to do anything to jeopardize its security by rushing,'' he said. `` But we'd like to meet that timetable. By making that statement, we're making a significant step forward. `` So, we're very hopeful for improved relationship, for new opportunities for reduction of tensions. But as we are hopeful, we must also maintain our preparedness, and that we will do. `` As you see those reforms take place in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, there will continue to be improvement and perhaps you can say, then, that indeed the Cold War is over. But it depends on whether the democratic values that President <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> talks about can actually be implemented.'' Regarding <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said that `` the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> people need to ask the question: Why are we spending $ 7 billion on <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> when we could be spending it on meat and food and assistance back home?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Pentagon-Drugs     12-09 0318</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pentagon-Drugs,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cheney Approves Plans for National Guard</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> has approved plans to increase <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> support in the war against illicit drugs, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> says. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> authorized $ 450 million for <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> anti-drug programs in fiscal 1990, with some $ 70 million used to fund specific state and territorial anti-drug plans, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement Friday. The largest allotments went to border states, such as <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> with $ 10,936,000; <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> $ 7,991,000; <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> $ 6,037,000; and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> $ 4,912,000. The decisions on the allotments were made by the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> `` in coordination with the federal law enforcement agencies,'' the statement said. While the Guard may not take part in such law enforcement activities as arrests and seizures, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said the activities outlined in some of the plans include: radar surveillance; detection and monitoring of drug smuggling through air surveillance; aerial photography; assistance in searching containers; transportation of law enforcement personnel, equipment and seized substances; expanded training of law enforcement personnel; and increased loans of military equipment. Here are the approved plans and amounts culled from plans submitted from the governors of 53 states and territories. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hamsphire </LOCATION> did not submit a plan. <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>: $ 1,551,000 <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>: $ 835,000 <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>: $ 2,364,000 <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>: $ 992,000 <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>: $ 7,991,000 <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>: $ 244,000 <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>: $ 62,000 <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>: $ 134,000 D.C.: $ 2,349,000 <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>: $ 6,037,000 <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>: $ 2,429,000 Guam: $ 279,000 <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>: $ 708,000 <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>: $ 235,000 <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>: $ 222,000 <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>: $ 333,000 <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>: $ 326,000 <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>: $ 349,000 <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>: $ 2,751,000 <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>: $ 1,829,000 <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>: $ 488,000 <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>: $ 906,000 <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>: $ 1,036,000 <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>: $ 474,000 <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>: $ 555,000 <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>: $ 1,104,000 <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>: $ 507,000 <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>: $ 296,000 <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>: $ 756,000 <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>: $ 191,000 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>: $ 1,562,000 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>: $ 654,000 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>: $ 4,912,000 <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>: $ 2,144,000 <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>: $ 88,000 <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>: $ 378,000 <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>: $ 532,000 <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>: $ 1,216,000 <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>: $ 1,019,000 Puerto Rico: $ 691,000 <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>: $ 143,000 <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>: $ 1,904,000 <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>: $ 129,000 <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>: $ 668,000 <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>: $ 10,936,000 <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>: $ 509,000 <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>: $ 62,000 <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>: $ 931,000 <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>: $ 130,000 <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>: $ 316,000 <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>: $ 120,000 <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>: $ 286,000 <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>: $ 25,000
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0203EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtonInBrief     12-09 0469</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington In Brief,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>VA to Close Several Regional Offices Nationwide</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Veterans Affairs Department will close centers in five cities and create new headquarters in <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> in an attempt to consolidate its seven regional medical offices into four. <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said Friday that regional medical offices would be closed in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Durham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>; and <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Arbor </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> would keep their medical center headquarters, with <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Arbor </PERSON> serving the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> the West, while new centers would be established in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> to serve the <LOCATION> Northeast </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> to serve the Sun Belt, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said Veterans Secretary <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> hopes to have the plan in place by May 1990. <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> also wants to close the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION>'s 27 district medical offices around in the country.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Navy Charges Two With Conspiracy to Commit Espionage</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two sailors from the USS <LOCATION> Fairfax </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> are facing charges they conspired to pass secret information to a foreign agent, the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investigative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> says. The agency said Friday that it did not believe the sailors had actually passed any classified information but that the case was under review. The sailors, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Schoof </PERSON>, 20, and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Haeger </PERSON>, 19, both petty officers third class, were arrested Dec. 1 while the ship was at <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said. Their hometowns were not available. The two, operations specialists with access to classified information, were charged with conspiracy to commit espionage. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> declined to identify the foreign nation whose agent was alleged to be involved. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officials also declined to describe the material the sailors were accused of conspiring to disclose beyond saying it was classified secret. The two sailors are in pre-trial detention awaiting court-martial by the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> was leaving today for a six-day European trip to meet with law enforcement officials in four nations to discuss drugs and terrorism. `` One of my primary goals will be to urge our <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> partners to take swift action to ratify the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Against </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illicit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Traffic </ORGANIZATION> in Narcotics Drugs,'' <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said in a statement Friday. `` With the threat of increased drug problems in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, it is important that the European community move swiftly to join us in carrying the provisions forward to implementation.'' <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> will also discuss international efforts to combat terrorism. The attorney general, accompanied by <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sessions </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawn </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, will attend a conference of European law enforcement officials in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> will meet with officials in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Luxembourg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. He also is scheduled to meet with officials of <LOCATION> TREVI </LOCATION>, the European community's organization of law enforcement agencies.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0212EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush Bjt   12-09 0704</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Hits the Campaign Trail for GOP Candidates</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is back in the snowy capital today after spending two days on the campaign trail in a three-state swing to drum up support for Republican <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> candidates and reverse <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> political fortunes. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> stumped Friday for Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moines </LOCATION>, the last stop in two days of appearances that included fund-raising events for <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> candidates <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Iowa Republicans hoped <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s appearance would give <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON> an early boost in his underdog bid to unseat first-term Democratic Sen. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> canceled plans to spend the weekend at the Camp David presidential retreat in the <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> countryside when a snowstorm swept the region Friday. He opted to stay at the White House instead. The president arrived in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> on a day when the <ORGANIZATION> Des </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Moines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Register </ORGANIZATION> published a poll showing his approval rating at 74 percent statewide. But Republicans acknowledged a tough road ahead for <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON>. Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Lightfoot </PERSON> said Friday night that the party faces `` one of the toughest most difficult years that any of us have gone through'' before the November 1990 election. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> helped raise $ 250,000 for <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON> in what <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON> aides said was the biggest single political fund-raiser in the state's history. `` His values reflect the greatness of <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, praising <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> record. Earlier Friday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> at a luncheon for Rep. <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> congressman who hopes to succeed retiring Republican Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>. Republicans have pinned their hopes on <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> to retain the seat for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> and would consider it a crushing blow to lose the seat, one top <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> adviser said. The night before, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> helped <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON> raise $ 2.4 million in a <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> Astrodome dinner. <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, who accompanied <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on the two-day trip, said that was the most lucrative single political event in the nation's history. However, <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>, a one-time Democrat who enjoys solid backing in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, is not considered to be in any danger for re-election. Speculation persists that he has presidential ambitions. Sending <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on the political trail is part of the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> strategy as the party tries to reverse its dismal 1989 election record that followed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s resounding victory in the 1988 presidential race. In November, the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> lost gubernatorial races in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and the mayor's race in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, all campaigns in which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> personally campaigned. Last week, a Republican stronghold district in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, elected Democrat <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON> <PERSON> Killea </PERSON> to the State Senate. The election followed a campaign rocked by a Catholic bishop's public censure of <PERSON> Killea </PERSON> for her pro-choice position on abortion. <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, acknowledging the party's losses, remarked to reporters that he had a far happier year in 1988, but insisted the party's fortunes will turn around in 1990 The <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> hopes to get a solid footing early by sending the president to big-ticket fund-raising events. In <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Finch </PERSON> said the party wanted <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the state early to raise money because <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON> will be able to collect a sizable war chest. <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> hierarchy turned out for the dinner _ Gov. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Branstad </PERSON>, Sen. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Grassley </PERSON>, and the state's three other <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members, <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lightfoot </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Grandy </PERSON>. Before the dinner at the <ORGANIZATION> Des </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Moines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> joined <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON> on a call-in radio show for 15 minutes at station WHO. In <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> talked about the environment, holding down taxes, farm policy and international relations as he plugged <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s candidacy. `` <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> is what you need and is what this administration needs _ a senator to make <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> strong, to make this nation proud, and a leader in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> that I can work with as president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' Also Friday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, with drug policy director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> at his side, delivered an anti-drug speech to an enthusiastic auditorium of students at <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> F. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told the young people that if they have ideas on how to solve the drug problem they should let their schools and their government know about them.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ColoradoSymphony Bjt   12-09 0663</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Colorado Symphony, Bjt,0682</SECOND>
<HEAD>Musicians' Symphony, With Rock Promoter, Says Success is Near</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB UNRUH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphony </ORGANIZATION> musicians dumped their board of directors and rechristened themselves the <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Symphony </LOCATION>, in partnership with a local rock impressario, skeptics predicted disaster. It has n't happened. While things are far from rosy for the 53 musicians, they have arranged a concert season with guest conductors and soloists and launched a catchy advertising campaign that seems to be attracting larger audiences. The money is n't great _ but who joins an orchestra to get rich? And what's most important, said violinist <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Goble </PERSON>, `` We are still a very good orchestra.'' `` I think we know we still have hurdles. Sure, it's still going to be lean for the orchestra,'' said violist <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeingst </PERSON>, a member of the new musician-run orchestra's board. `` -LRB- But -RRB- we really now have got our feet under us.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION> arose from the ashes of the <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION>, which had accumulated debts of $ 2.5 million and owed $ 700,000 in unpaid rent to the city of <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> symphony's troubles are far from unique _ orchestras in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>; and <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, to name a few, have suffered financial worries recently. In the last two years, the <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> musicians' pay was cut, the concert season scaled back. But this fall, when the board proposed a 1989-1990 season of just 11 weeks paying $ 530 a week _ down from $ 670 a week for 41 weeks the year before _ musicians decided to begin their own orchestra. `` It's unique,'' said <PERSON> Yeingst </PERSON>. `` You do n't find an orchestra where the musicians accept the responsibility not only for the music-making but the actual operation.'' <PERSON> Yeingst </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> CSO </ORGANIZATION> is paying musicians a base salary of $ 22,000 for a 26-week season. `` If the gate is larger, they'll make more; if it's smaller, they'll make less,'' he said. `` Nothing is guaranteed, just like real life.'' Rock promoter <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Fey </PERSON>, who is helping to produce and bankroll the new orchestra, is more accustomed to booking acts such as the Rolling Stones. He admitted in September that he had never attended a symphony. <PERSON> Fey </PERSON> wants the orchestra off the society pages and onto entertainment pages. `` There will be some highs and some lows along the road, but at the end of the year, we'll be fine,'' <PERSON> Fey </PERSON> said. But <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Maxwell </PERSON>, an administrator for the <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Symphony </LOCATION>, which is going through bankruptcy reorganization, said he sees many empty seats when he attends <ORGANIZATION> CSO </ORGANIZATION> concerts. `` Naturally we are concerned and disturbed -LRB- by the -RRB- very low level of community support for those concerts,'' he said. `` Patronage has been very low. It can not be economical for the musicians.'' <PERSON> Yeingst </PERSON> said musicians did not expect sold-out houses and improved paychecks right away. But `` we have been more than meeting expenses, and with any successful fund-raising, any kind of support, we'll be fine,'' he said. Community support, however, is a problem. <PERSON> Yeingst </PERSON> said patrons have grown resentful over the years with having to support an organization in perpetual financial crisis. `` People now are simply not willing to write a check and let it go at that. Those who are coming forward are interested to know exactly where the money is going,'' he said. `` They want to know about costs, budget.'' The symphony's new fund-raising drive is aimed at the general population, from whom it is soliciting donations of $ 18.12, after <PERSON> Tchaikovsky </PERSON>'s `` 1812 Overture.'' The season opened in November with a `` Symphony Sampler'' concert in <ORGANIZATION> McNichols </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sports </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arena </ORGANIZATION> that attracted nearly 12,000 people. But a few days later, when the classical series began at <PERSON> Boettcher </PERSON> concert hall, only a few hundred showed up. `` But after finishing our fourth week things look a lot better,'' <PERSON> Yeingst </PERSON> said. `` We're getting decent houses, and they will improve. And we've had very favorable talks with the governor and the mayor'' about support for the new orchestra.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ThriftFails     12-09 0715</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Thrift Fails,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Regulators Take Over New Jersey's Largest Thrift</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-S&amp;Ls-CenTrust, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JANE E. ALLEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There was little surprise when federal regulators took over <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jersey </ORGANIZATION>'s largest savings and loan, removing its chief executive officer and directors. <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bedminster </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, had been recording increasingly large losses from real estate ventures in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Its third quarter results showed bad loans outweighing equity by about nine times. Furthermore, the savings bank said last month that it would be unable to meet new capital requirements that became effective Thursday under the thrift bailout law signed last summer. `` It's not surprising,'' <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> McCrystal </PERSON>, an analyst with <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Beck </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, who has been following the institution's faltering performance, said Friday. `` They had an extremely large amount of non-performing assets in excess of their equity.'' As of Sept. 30, <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> had $ 747 million in non-performing assets _ past-due loans and loans that do n't pay interest _ and only $ 89 million in equity, compared with $ 326.2 million at the end of 1988. `` Under normal conditions, non-performing assets are no more than 25 percent of equity,'' <PERSON> McCrystal </PERSON> said. `` With $ 89 million in equity, their losses probably would have wiped out equity had the feds not stepped in.'' The thrift's dire straits prompted the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thrift </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supervision </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to transfer control to the <ORGANIZATION> Resolution </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a federal agency created in August to dispose of failed S & amp; Ls. `` City Federal was below all its capital requirements. It does n't look to us like they could recapitalize this institution without federal assistance,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Albanese </PERSON>, senior deputy director of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thrift </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supervision </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. `` And the institution is continuing to experience operations losses and loan losses,'' <PERSON> Albanese </PERSON> said. Bad commercial real estate and construction loans lie at the heart of the thrift's troubles. Only recently, City Federal sold a mortgage banking operation in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <PERSON> McCrystal </PERSON> said. City Federal was the lead lender in <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberte </ORGANIZATION>, a $ 750 million luxury project planned for <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> McCrystal </PERSON> said. `` They got very aggressive in the real estate market, but it began to soften,'' he said. The thrift also was hurt by new rules that phase out by 1995 an accounting break known as goodwill. City Federal was among several institutions in the early and mid-1980s that bought ailing thrifts when regulators had no money to deal with savings banks and were able to persuade institutions such as City Federal to take over the thrifts in exchange for goodwill. According to <PERSON> McCrystal </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> had $ 213 million in goodwill on its books as of Sept. 30. <PERSON> Albanese </PERSON> said representatives of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thrift </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supervision </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Resolution </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deposit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> gathered at the savings bank's <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> offices Friday. They replaced Chief Executive Officer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Atherton </PERSON>, other top City Federal officers and the thrift's board of directors with a government-selected managing agent and oversight team, but retained some employees, <PERSON> Albanese </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> officials did not return repeated phone calls. According to <ORGANIZATION> RTC </ORGANIZATION>, which has taken control of 280 thrifts and disposed of more than 30 nationwide, <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> had $ 9.8 billion in assets and $ 7.3 billion in 858,348 deposit accounts. <ORGANIZATION> RTC </ORGANIZATION> will help find a buyer for the institution, which maintained 105 retail branches in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> that are considered a valuable network. It also could decide to liquidate the thrift. `` For right now, it's business as usual,'' <PERSON> Albanese </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> RTC </ORGANIZATION> will oversee a newly created federal mutual association, known as <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, which will continue handling depositors' funds during normal business hours as a permanent solution is negotiated. <PERSON> McCrystal </PERSON> said the corporation's stock had become worthless, trading at just one-eighth Friday, but noted `` the significant loss has been over the last year or two. This is n't going to wipe out anybody.'' Four other <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> thrifts already have been taken over by federal regulators. <PERSON> McCrystal </PERSON> said the federal action was an indicator of things to come now that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has clamped down on the floundering savings industry. `` This says the government is going to follow through on the legislation passed to do something about these large, troubled thrifts.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     12-09 0525</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0544</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONG BEACH, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Mouse </PERSON> used to whistle while he worked back when he was <PERSON> Steamboat </PERSON> <PERSON> Willie </PERSON>, but he's got a more strident tone as captain of the Queen <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Walt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which owns the leaseholds on the permanently docked ocean liner and the adjacent Spruce Goose exhibit in <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>, told all hands this week to conform to <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>'s 35-year-old dress code. The code deep-sixes beards, mustaches and long hair on men and lowers the boom on bright eyeshadow, red fingernails or `` inappropriate'' makeup on women. The rules apply to 30,000 employees in Disney parks and resorts. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Magness </PERSON>, first officer on the Queen <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>, would sooner ship out than shave off the mustache he grew 42 years ago and wore in the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> during the Korean War, aboard ships worldwide and skippering motor yachts off <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. `` No,'' <PERSON> Magness </PERSON> said of removing the mustache, even if that means he has to give up the ship, on which he has worked for 7 -LCB- years. `` They said a mustache ` does n't give a clean, fresh, wholesome look,''' he said. Although <PERSON> Walt </PERSON> <PERSON> Disney </PERSON> himself sported a mustache, <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> apparently thinks hairy lips could sink its ship. `` The grooming standards were designed to fit into the entire guest experience. We do n't want to do anything that tends to detract in any way from that experience,'' said <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerlin </PERSON>. The company bought the rights to the tourist attractions nearly two years ago but only decided to put the code into effect in preparation for an upcoming promotion.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>OLYMPIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state has an <LOCATION> Elwha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, an <LOCATION> Elwha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION> and now, thanks to the ferry <LOCATION> Elwha </LOCATION>, an <LOCATION> Elwha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Geographic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Names </ORGANIZATION> on Friday officially named the reef in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> for the ferry, which rammed it Oct. 2, 1983. Ferry Capt. <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Fittro </PERSON> unwittingly romanced the stone when he made an unauthorized detour into <LOCATION> Grindstone </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> Orcas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> while giving a local resident a waterside view of her home from the Elwha's pilothouse. The ferry was damaged to the tune of $ 250,000, and local wits came up with a tune of their own, `` Elwha on the Rocks.'' T-shirts also carried Elwha slogans, and an island bar named a rum drink after the incident. <PERSON> Fittro </PERSON> resigned and his boss, Capt. <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON>, was fired after he tried to run cover for Fittro. Islanders have for years called the reef <LOCATION> Elwha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Seattlite </PERSON> <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Lange </PERSON> proposed to the board that it be named for the boat that struck it. That's the way many rocks have gotten their names, he said. Land Commissioner <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyle </PERSON>, who heads the board, spoke in favor of the name. `` There is a sense of whimsy attached to the name, but it will serve as a significant warning to other people who travel in these waters _ a stark reminder of what happened,'' <PERSON> Boyle </PERSON> said. The vote was 5 to 1, with dissenter <PERSON> Emmett </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> grousing, `` I do n't understand how people could suggest to name something after an incident that endangered people's lives.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-Quake     12-09 0172</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Quake,0176</SECOND>
<HEAD>Strong Earthquake Hits Northern Japan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A strong earthquake rocked eastern <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> early today, but police said there had been no damage or casualties reported. The quake, with a magnitude estimated at 5.4 on the Richter scale, shook cities on the northeastern coast of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Meteorological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported. The agency said there was no danger of tsunami, or tidal waves. The agency said the quake's epicenter was located 25 miles below the sea 47 miles northeast off Mito, 60 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. Also today, an earthquake measuring 5.9 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale was reported about 470 miles east-southeast of the Philippine capital of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Hong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observatory </ORGANIZATION> said the quake struck Friday evening. No further details were reported. The <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale is a measure of ground motion as recorded on seismographs. Every increase of one number means a tenfold increase in magnitude. A quake measuring 5 on the scale can cause considerable damage, and a quake of magnitude 6 can cause severe damage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0247EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Brazil     12-09 0606</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Brazil,0626</SECOND>
<HEAD>Socialist-Conservative Battle for President Widens Brazilian Rift</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By TODD LEWAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The battle for the presidency between a socialist labor leader and a conservative reformer has widened divisions in a country already threatened with social and economic chaos. Former Gov. <PERSON> Fernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Collor </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Mello </PERSON> and socialist <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Inacio </PERSON> <PERSON> Lula </PERSON> <PERSON> da </PERSON> <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> are in the Dec. 17 runoff to become <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s first directly elected president in 29 years. Neither won a majority in the 21-candiate election on Nov. 15, when about 82 million Brazilian cast their ballots. President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON>, barred by law from seeking re-election, won a 1985 electoral college vote controlled by the military that ruled <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> from 1964-1985. Four economic plans introduced by <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON>'s government failed to halt inflation, which is at an annual rate of 1,460 percent. Political anaylysts have expressed fear that the runoff election will be a showdown between rich and poor. They say civilian rule, reeling under an economic slump, the social impact of rapid urbanization and a $ 110 billion foreign debt, may not be ready for such a harsh test. `` This radical polarization is dangerous for <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, which now must choose between two extremes that do not represent all political options,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Fabio </PERSON> <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> of the center-left <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Industrialists say a da <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> victory would accelerate the flight of capital from the country. Labor leaders counter that if <PERSON> Collor </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Mello </PERSON> leaves social reforms to free-market forces the unrest could boil over. The prospect of a socialist victory disturbs <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s right-wing military chiefs. `` We are now facing the dilemma of choosing between one man's savior and another man's devil,'' said <PERSON> Jair </PERSON> <PERSON> Meneguelli </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, a labor umbrella group <PERSON> Collor </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Mello </PERSON>, 40, a former governor of <LOCATION> Alagoas </LOCATION> state, founded his <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reconstruction </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> last February on a platform of moral cleanup. He vowed to root out corruption and cronyism and blamed <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> so sharply for <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s economic ills the president ordered the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> to file suit for slander. <PERSON> Collor </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Mello </PERSON> has publicly refused the support of ultraright groups but they back him. <PERSON> Da </PERSON> <PERSON> Silva </PERSON>, a 44-year-old former lathe operator, calls for a redistribution of land and wealth, increased worker control of state monopolies and a moratorium on foreign debt payments. He is the leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and is backed by Marxist groups, labor unionists and the liberal wing of <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Da </PERSON> <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> built his power base in the industrial belt around <LOCATION> Sao </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paulo </LOCATION> and has broad support in the drought-ridden northeast. Polls taken in early December gave <PERSON> Collor </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Mello </PERSON> a 10-point lead. Both candidates are trying to soften their images as they campaign to win centrist support. The main targets are the centrist <ORGANIZATION> Brazilian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which has the largest number of legislators in both houses of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Both candidates must form alliances. Together their parties have less than 6 percent of the seats in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and the winner will have to put together a broad congressional coalition to govern. <PERSON> Da </PERSON> <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> has been more successful than Collor de Mello in wooing support. He has won limited endorsements from the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and from <PERSON> Leonel </PERSON> <PERSON> Brizola </PERSON> of the leftist <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> who came in a close third behind da <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> in the November balloting. Rigidity in the Workers' Party could jeopardize a broader leftist front, accoarding to some analysts. `` The Workers' Party is a one-class party. It will have to open up more and become multi-class,'' wrote political scientist <PERSON> Helio </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaguaribe </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0248EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RiotTrial Bjt   12-09 0550</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Riot Trial, Bjt,0566</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lozano Says He Was Scapegoat, Hispanics Organize Fund Drive</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD COLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Hispanic community rallied around a Colombian-born policeman convicted of killing two black men, but in black neighborhoods where riots have followed racially tinged trials in the past, all was calm. Two radio stations that cater to Colombians have scheduled rallies today for <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> officer <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>, convicted Thursday on two counts of manslaughter in the January deaths of <ORGANIZATION> Clement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lloyd </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON>. <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>, who remains suspended from the force with full pay pending a police department hearing, echoed feelings among <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>'s Hispanics that he was convicted in order to avoid further rioting by <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>'s blacks `` I do n't think it was fair,'' said <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>, 31. You have to realize -LRB- there have been -RRB- a lot of problems in the community in the past. I was just being used as a scapegoat for this.'' <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON> also said he knew the verdict would be guilty as soon as the six-member jury entered the courtroom Thursday. `` Because when the jurors came out, everyone, every single person from the jurors, they were looking down,'' he said. `` They were sad, and you can read in their eyes that nobody wanted it. And I knew, right there and then.'' Three days of racial disturbances ensued in the Liberty City and <LOCATION> Overtown </LOCATION> neighborhoods after the shooting of <LOCATION> Lloyd </LOCATION>, 23. <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON>, 24, suffered fatal injuries in the crash of the motorcycle that <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> was driving. The two were fleeing another group of police. Rioting also followed trials in the past where white officers were acquitted in the slayings of blacks. But all was quiet Friday in the black neighborhoods. Leaders of the black community praised <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>'s guilty verdict as a victory for justice, but many Hispanics, including the 200,000-strong Colombian community, have said the officer was shortchanged by racial politics. `` We are deeply hurt,'' <PERSON> Hernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, executive secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Colombian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Political </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said Friday. `` We are convinced that officer <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON> was doing his duty defending the community.'' The two radio stations organizing the rally, WOCN-AM and WKAT-AM, said they would seek money for <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>'s expected appeal and signatures for a petition asking Dade Circuit Judge <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Farina </PERSON> to show leniency in <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>'s Jan. 24 sentencing. On Friday, Jewish, <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> and lay religious leaders held a joint news conference and declared a weekend of prayer for the shooting victims's families and for <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>'s family. `` Our prayers should be directed at preserving the unity of our community within which the opinions are as diverse as our population,'' said Rabbi <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON> <PERSON> Schiff </PERSON>, chairman of <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>'s Community Relations Board `` I think the worst thing we can do as a community is to sit back smugly and say we came through this time without fires and riots.'' <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>'s family issued radio appeals earlier in the day for more legal funds. `` We need money urgently,'' <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>'s brother <PERSON> Jairo </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> police officer, told listeners on WKAT. `` I could n't sleep all night worrying about it.'' `` It seems like things are better off here for a drug trafficker than for a police officer _ maybe it would have been better for us that way,'' he said. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON>'s brother, <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION>, and his wife, <PERSON> Ana </PERSON>, also are <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> police officers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891209-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-89 0251EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WoodShooting     12-09 0368</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wood Shooting,0378</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hunter Indicted for Manslaughter in Woman's Death</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGOR, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
