<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-D'Amato-Audit     06-08 0381</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-D'Amato-Audit,0395</SECOND>
<HEAD>HUD Audit: Island Park Officials Excluded Blacks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Officials of <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, home village of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, rigged the distribution of federally subsidized homes in the early 1980s to keep out blacks, according to a published report. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> in its Thursday editions reported that an audit by the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> indicates that one person who received preferential treatment was <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>'s cousin, <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Ciccimarro </PERSON> At the time, <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON> was supervisor of the Town of <LOCATION> Hempstead </LOCATION>, of which Island Park is an incorporated subdivision. He was elected to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> shortly after that, the newspaper said. <PERSON> Ciccimarro </PERSON> was selected to buy a $ 40,000 <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> house, the Times said. Also receiving preferential treatment was <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> McGann </PERSON>, a village board member and a high-ranking <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> administrator whose son received a $ 44,500 house, it said. In the 1980s, <LOCATION> Nassau </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> got enough money to build 285 houses for lower-income families. Island Park, which is 97 percent white, got enough money to build 44 homes ranging from $ 40,000 to $ 64,000. The audit does not say if the people selected for the <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> houses actually were eligible to buy them. Buyers included the niece of the village clerk, the niece of a village trustee, two village supervisors, a lawyer who soon will become a village justice and the daughter of a village employee, the newspaper said. None of them are black. The <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> houses were supposed to be advertised in local newspapers so lower-income residents, especially minorities, would have a chance to buy a home. Instead, some selected residents were told in advance when the ads would appear and they slipped their applications under the Village Hall door before dawn, the Times reported. The 1984 audit recommended disciplinary action against Mrs. <PERSON> McGann </PERSON> and the village but no penalties. Mrs. <PERSON> McGann </PERSON> last year was promoted to regional <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> administrator after her friend, <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, lobbied <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the White House on her behalf, the newspaper said. When the Times requested a copy of the audit, Mrs. <PERSON> McGann </PERSON> deleted the names of eight villagers, including her son. `` This program was a mockery,'' said <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Pless </PERSON>, who did the audit. `` It took everyone's tax money and gave it to the people who did n't need it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-China-Flights 1stLd-Writethru a0757 06-08 0366</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Flights, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0757,0375</SECOND>
<HEAD>United Adds At Least One Beijing Flight</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 7 grafs to UPDATE with 2nd flight offered; picks
up 6th graf pvs: `Earlier Wednesday ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, the only <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> carrier serving <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, announced Wednesday it was adding at least two extra flights to the three scheduled weekly to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s capital, and <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> said it will join the evacuation with charter flights. `` <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> stands ready to assist Americans who desire safe and efficient transportation out of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>,'' Chairman <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON> said. The first of the additional flights from <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> arrived in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> on Wednesday, said spokesman <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Doughty </PERSON>. It was scheduled to to <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> before returning to <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, but <PERSON> Doughty </PERSON> could n't say how many of the 400 seats were occupied. United has agreed to provide the planes and crews and the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> will determine who boards the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747s, <PERSON> Doughty </PERSON> said. The second charter flight, a round-trip flight between <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> only, received approval from both governments late Wednesday and is scheduled to arrive Thursday, <PERSON> Doughty </PERSON> said. Two <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> commercial flights which had already made round trips between <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> earlier this week were not fully booked out of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, he noted. There were 307 passengers on one and 335 on the other, he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747-100s used on the route can carry more than 400 passengers. Earlier Wednesday, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration urged all Americans to leave <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> after rifle fire broke windows at apartment buildings occupied by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government workers. While the administration noted there had been no direct threats against foreigners, it cited an increasingly chaotic situation. On Tuesday, the government's advice had focused solely on <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. United personnel reported no problems at or en route to the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> airport, <PERSON> Doughty </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> announced in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> that it would provide a DC-10 for U.S.-chartered shuttle flights between <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, perhaps through the weekend. The aircraft, with a capacity for 284 passengers, will operate two daily shuttle flights on Friday, airline spokesman <PERSON> Ned </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> said. There was no immediate word from <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> about whether it would supplement it twice-weekly flight to <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bush-Networks     06-08 0038</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Networks,0038</SECOND>
<HEAD>TV Coverage of Bush Press Conference Tonight</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> plan live coverage tonight of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s first formal prime-time press conference. The coverage begins at 8 p.m. EDT.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SpottedOwl-BLM     06-08 0257</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Spotted Owl-BLM,0263</SECOND>
<HEAD>Appeals Court Restores Timber Injunction</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal appeals court Wednesday restored the injunction prohibiting the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> from selling old-growth timber around northern spotted owl nests in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>. Acting on an appeal brought by the <ORGANIZATION> Portland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> and other environmental groups, the 9th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> without comment restored the year-old injunction lifted last month by a federal judge. The action was praised by environmentalists, who contend the spotted owl will become extinct unless the ancient forests where it lives and hunts are preserved. The timber industry contends that thousands of jobs will be lost unless logging of old growth timber on federal lands is allowed to continue. The action means as much as 400 million board feet of timber, a third of the agency's annual harvest in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, wo n't be offered for sale, said <ORGANIZATION> BLM </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Smurthwaite </PERSON>. Five timber sales on the <LOCATION> Medford </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Coos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> BLM </ORGANIZATION> districts which were sold during the course of the legal wrangling were n't included in the injunction. The action was separate from a lawsuit filed by environmentalists against the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> pending in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> that stopped harvest of 1 billion board feet of timber on national forests in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. In lifting the injunction, Judge <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Frye </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> BLM </ORGANIZATION> failed to consider new information in preparing its managment plans for spotted owls, which the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Fish & amp; <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> has proposed for listing as a threatened species.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APAppointment     06-08 0179</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Appointment,0182</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Seattle Bureau Chief Named</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON>, director of <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> operations in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> since 1985, has been appointed bureau chief in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boccardi </PERSON>, president and general manager of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, announced the appointment Wednesday. Day, 32, will take over the news cooperative's operations in four <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> offices _ <LOCATION> Olympia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yakima </LOCATION> and the control bureau in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. He succeeds <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Slaughter </PERSON>, who has been promoted to general executive at <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> headquarters. A <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> native, Day graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Holy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Worcester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, and received a master's degree in journalism from <ORGANIZATION> Marquette </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>. He worked for the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, before joining the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION> in 1981. In 1982, Day was appointed <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> broadcast editor and in 1983 was promoted to news editor in <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb </LOCATION>. Two years later, he was elevated to correspondent in charge of <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>. In 1988, <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION> was upgraded from an office reporting to <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, to an independent bureau and Day became bureau chief.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SlainEcologist     06-08 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Slain Ecologist,0512</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brazilian Firms Gets Film Rights of Ecologist's Life Story</HEAD>
<UNK>By TODD LEWAN ^Associated Press Writer</UNK>
<DATELINE>RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Brazilian film company beat out <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> filmmakers and purchased the rights to film the life story of the assassinated <LOCATION> Brazilian </LOCATION> ecologist <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> `` Chico'' <PERSON> Mendes </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> JN </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Filmes </ORGANIZATION> signed a $ 1.76 million contract with the <ORGANIZATION> Chico </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mendes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> to lease the exclusive rights to an English-Portuguese film, TV series, autobiographical book and videocassette on <PERSON> Mendes </PERSON>' life, producer <PERSON> Jofre </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodrigues </PERSON> told a news conference The announcement Wednesday ended a two-month contest among international movie companies _ including <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Artists </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Redford </PERSON>, representing 20th <ORGANIZATION> Century </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> _ for the rights to shoot a movie about the life and death of <PERSON> Mendes </PERSON> <PERSON> Mendes </PERSON>, 44, was the leader of a rubber tappers union who fought to save the <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> jungle from deforestation. In December, he became to many the world's first ecological martyr when he was shot to death outside his modest wooden house in the Acre state jungle town of <LOCATION> Xapuri </LOCATION>, 2,700 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION>. Authorities arrested the son of a cattle rancher in the shooting. <PERSON> Mendes </PERSON> had won a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> award for his struggle against ranchers eager to clear the rain forest for grazing. His death struck a chord worldwide. Hollywood producers rushed to the <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> with offers to buy film rights. But a four-member panel from the <ORGANIZATION> Chico </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mendes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, an organization made up of ecologists, rubber tappers and family members, chose <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> JN </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Filmes </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday night. `` We are not trying solely to make money on this project,'' <PERSON> Chico </PERSON>'s widow, Ilzamar, told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. `` We want to get news out throughout the world of who <PERSON> Chico </PERSON> was, what he stood for and the forces who tried to stop him.'' Panel member <PERSON> Gilson </PERSON> <PERSON> Pescador </PERSON> said JN was chosen because its offer included making a TV series, a video and a book based on <PERSON> Mendes </PERSON>' life <PERSON> Pescador </PERSON> called some of the Hollywood proposals `` illusory,'' but also noted, `` We thought a Brazilian film company would best show the destruction that's going on and the reality of the people of the region.'' He declined to confirm a reported $ 1.2 million offer made this week by <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION> for rights to the movie alone. The movie script, to be written by Brazilian author <PERSON> Marcio </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Souza </PERSON>, will be in English and <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> and foreign distributors will be contacted to help sell the film abroad, <PERSON> Pescador </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Claudio </PERSON> <PERSON> Padilha </PERSON>, the designated director, said filming for the estimated $ 10 million project would begin in May 1990 on location in <LOCATION> Xapuri </LOCATION>. Plans also include filming in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Pescador </PERSON> said nearly $ 400,000 from the rights would go to family members, with $ 400,000 going to public education and health projects for Indians and rubber tappers throughout the region. He said <PERSON> Ilzamar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mendes </PERSON> would donate the remainder to the rubber tappers union and other such organizations in the state of Acre, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     06-08 0049</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0051</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Wednesday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 02; 03; 07; 11; 22; 24.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 24; 26; 38; 39; 41; 54. Supplementary 02.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 7-6-3; 3-0-0-6; 2-4-8-6-7; 5-1-3-3-6-8.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TielessTeacher     06-08 0470</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tieless Teacher,0488</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tieless Teacher Wins Court Victory</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KELLY P. KISSEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A teacher was illegally suspended by a school board for refusing to wear a tie in his classroom, a circuit judge ruled Wednesday. The ruling does n't ensure that <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>, 46, will return to his <ORGANIZATION> Point </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pleasant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> classroom, but it undermines the <ORGANIZATION> Mason </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>'s main charges in the math teacher's firing `` If they could n't suspend him, they sure as hell could n't fire him,'' the teacher's wife, <PERSON> Julie </PERSON>, said in a telephone from the couple's <LOCATION> Gallipolis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, home. Her husband was en route to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> to appear on `` The Oprah Winfrey Show,'' which planned a program Thursday on people fired because of the way they dress. The <ORGANIZATION> Mason </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> board suspended <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> three times last fall, accusing him of insubordination for violating a dress code requiring male teachers to wear dress pants and ties. <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>, whose standard classroom wardrobe consisted of blue jeans and cotton shirts, openly challenged Superintendent <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON>' order, drawing suspensions lasting 4, 11 and 30 days before being fired Dec. 19. Kanawha Circuit Judge <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>'s ruling set aside the 11-day suspension, meaning <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> will be paid for that time, said the teacher's attorney, <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kopleman </PERSON>. A hearing on the firing and the 30-day suspension is pending, <PERSON> Kopleman </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> did n't challenge the four-day suspension because he was paid. King said the dress code was improperly established and that <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> had the right to disobey rules he believed were illegal. `` If you challenge a rule that is in effect unlawful, it's not insubordination,'' said <PERSON> Kopleman </PERSON>. The board claimed <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> should have worn a tie while challenging Chambers' order. `` The superintendent did n't have the authority to unilaterally issue a dress code,'' said <PERSON> Kopleman </PERSON>. `` Only the board has the authority. That was one of our premier arguments.'' Board member <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Siders </PERSON>, who introduced a proposal to fine <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>, said Wednesday night he was n't aware of King's decision and that the board had not talked about what to do if <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>'s appeals were successful. Board president <PERSON> Emma </PERSON> <PERSON> Kearns </PERSON> could not be reached. Chambers and board attorney <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> have unlisted numbers. The next board meeting is scheduled for June 19. The controversy began in August 1988, when the board said male instructors would have to wear ties, a change from contracts teachers signed last spring. <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>, who has worked for the <LOCATION> Mason </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> school system for 19 years and is also a farmer, has spent his spare time working around the house and at a body shop he runs. Mrs. <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> said her husband will be wearing denim from top to bottom on the <PERSON> Oprah </PERSON> <PERSON> Winfrey </PERSON> program Thursday. `` I pressed them before he left,'' she said. `` I seldom press them, but this is big time.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Foley-GOP 3rdLd-Writethru a0741 06-08 0757</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Foley-GOP, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0741,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>GOP Official Resigns in Uproar Over Foley Memo</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS grafs 6-7: ``The president,'' with Sununu interview</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A national <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> official resigned Wednesday in the uproar over a memo he wrote comparing <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>'s voting record with that of a homosexual congressman. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as described as `` disgusted by this entire incident'' and as considering it closed. However, <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said the resignation of `` one staffer'' was n't good enough and suggested his <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> counterpart, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s former campaign manager <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, should be fired by the president. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodin </PERSON>, a press assistant in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s 1988 presidential campaign, wrote the memo and had it distributed as communications director of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. The memo, which <PERSON> Goodin </PERSON> said was sent out without his boss <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>'s knowledge, compared <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>'s voting record to that of liberal Rep. <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, D-Mass. The memo was titled: `` <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>: Out of the Liberal Closet.'' `` The president was very upset,'' said White House chief of staff <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> in an interview reported in Thursday editions of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. `` I was upset. It went too far. It was wrong. The innuendo was wrong. It's wrong not because it damages our relationship with the Democrats. It's wrong because it's wrong. `` It's a terrible thing to happen at this time. It was not appropriate or fair,'' said <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON>, who said both he and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had rebuked <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> called <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, his 1988 campaign manager, Wednesday morning, shortly before the resignation was announced. <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> had telephoned <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> to apologize Tuesday night. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s spokesman said, `` He was disgusted by this entire incident.'' `` We consider the matter closed,'' he added. <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, likewise, commenting after a previously scheduled meeting with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> at the White House, said, `` The issue is closed.'' He said there was no mention of it during the meeting. Earlier at the Capitol, <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> said that on the telephone <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> had been `` deeply apologetic for any inferences of personal character.'' `` He repudiated the statement and apologized ... I accepted that,'' said <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, adding that <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> promised there would be no more such attacks. <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, in his first full day as <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> speaker, said any suggestion that he is homosexual is `` entirely untrue of course.'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commitee </ORGANIZATION>, said of <PERSON> Goodin </PERSON>'s resignation, `` One staffer ca n't take the fall for an entire <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> political operation that's up to its knees in sewer-style politics. I think it's fair to ask President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> if he'll also have his hand-picked party chairman, <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, to resign. `` The president himself has to be accountable for the activities of his henchman,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said in a statement. <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> leaders also decried the memo and the strategy it seemed to represent. Senate Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor, `` I would guess this is a rather deliberate effort on the part of some to smear <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> ... on his first day as speaker. ... I would say this is not politics. This is garbage. We're disgusted by it.'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> declared, `` To those who have now departed the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, I say, ` Good riddance!''' House Minority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ill </LOCATION>., expressed dismay over the memo Tuesday and called both <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, aides said <PERSON> Michel </PERSON>, at the White House for the meeting with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, told reporters, `` It was a mistake obviously from the national committee's point of view.'' He said he did not know if <PERSON> Goodin </PERSON> had been asked to resign but said he had told <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, `` There's got to be some remedy for what took place, and <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, it's your shot. Do whatever you think is appropriate.'' <PERSON> Goodin </PERSON> said in his resignation letter to <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, `` At no time did I ever intend to damage anyone's reputation. Nonetheless, the purpose of the memorandum has been misconstrued. And in that regard, I have no one to blame but myself.'' Rep. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, the second-ranking <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democrat, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> needed to take more responsibility. `` They're playing good cop, bad cop,'' <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> said before the resignation was announced. `` Here's a guy sent in by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to do the dirty deeds, and he calls and apologizes after the fact. If they're really upset about these tactics, all they have to do is fire somebody. Rep. <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Okla </LOCATION>., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` I think we're going to be moving rather strongly to make sure it stops.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Bounty     06-08 0325</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bounty,0335</SECOND>
<HEAD>Price Put on Head of Boulder Man Acquitted of Rape</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOULDER, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Muslim couple has put a price on the head of man acquitted of raping their daughter in her University of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> dormitory room, the district attorney has told the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>. The woman's parents `` are prominent Islamics residing in <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>'' who apparently believe it appropriate to pay someone to kill 18-year-old <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, lawyer <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Caplis </PERSON> said in a court document released Wednesday. <PERSON> Caplis </PERSON> told District Attorney <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> that he compared <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>'s plight to that of author <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> _ who was sentenced to death by the late <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> for writing `` The Satanic Verses.'' <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> has asked the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> to complain through diplomatic channels. `` There's very little that agencies in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> can do,'' said Assistant Boulder District Attorney <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON>. `` It's very difficult for any law enforcement agency to do anything other than keep a closer eye on Mr <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> has gone into hiding, moving three times in the past month, <PERSON> Caplis </PERSON> said. `` He's terrified, basically, out of his mind. He just firmly believes that they will try to kill him,'' the lawyer said. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> was accused of raping the woman in her dormitory room last October. He claimed she consented to have sex with him. Prosecutors dismissed the case without filing charges. The woman returned to <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION> earlier this year. When <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> said he would sue the woman unless she apologized publicly, she beat him to the punch with a lawsuit of her own. <PERSON> Caplis </PERSON> first got wind of a possible threat against his client's life while taking a deposition for the civil case from one of the woman's friends A second friend confirmed the story, <PERSON> Caplis </PERSON> said. The alleged murder plot came to light after <PERSON> Caplis </PERSON> petitioned a <ORGANIZATION> Boulder </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> judge to lift a gag order in the case. He argued that the public spotlight might help protect <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-OnionField     06-08 0450</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Onion Field,0464</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Onion Field' Killer Pleads Guilty to Drug Charge</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WEST COVINA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Convicted `` Onion Field'' killer <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> was sentenced to a 90-day jail term on a drug charge Wednesday, but prosecutors dropped assault and attempted rape charges for lack of evidence, officials said. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 58, pleaded guilty to a misdemeanor charge of being under the influence of a banned narcotic substance, said <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Stuedgen </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Citris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Municipal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> clerk. Police said the drug was heroin. Commissioner <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lutz </PERSON> sentenced <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> to a 90-day term, to be served concurrent with any other terms stemming from a possible parole violation, Ms. <PERSON> Stuedgen </PERSON> said. Prosecutors rejected police charges of suspicion of attempted rape, false imprisonment and heroin possession for lack of evidence, said <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalvey </PERSON>, a secretary at the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Covina </LOCATION> disrict attorney's office Police arrested <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> late Monday after a 36-year-old woman alleged that he held her captive over the weekend. The woman escaped and called police Monday, officials said. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> still could be sent back to state prison because his arrest on Monday violated terms of his parole in the `` Onion Field'' police killing, officials said. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> could serve up to a year even without a new conviction, said <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, deputy regional administrator for the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parole </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> Division. The state Board of Prison Terms can revoke parole upon a finding of `` just cause,'' said <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>'s parole agent. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> abducted <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officers <PERSON> Ian </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Hettinger </PERSON> in March 1963 and drove them to an onion field south of <LOCATION> Bakersfield </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> killed <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> and shot at <PERSON> Hettinger </PERSON>, who escaped on foot in the darkness. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> were twice sentenced to death for the killing. The sentences were overturned. The crime and ensuing trial were recounted in <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Wambaugh </PERSON>'s best-selling 1973 novel, `` The Onion Field,'' which was made into a movie <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> is serving a life term. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> was paroled in February 1982 after serving 19 years at Soledad Correctional Facility. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> was ordered back to prison in 1982 for six months after failing a drug test and neglecting to tell his parole officer he was leaving the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area. In July 1984, he was convicted of selling heroin while on parole and sentenced to five years. He was paroled in November 1986. His parole was revoked twice after that. <PERSON> Hettinger </PERSON>, now a supervisor on the <ORGANIZATION> Kern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supervisors </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>'s death sentence should have stood. `` Both of them should have been executed,'' he said. `` This is typical of a continuing pattern of violence from <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. I know what he did to me and my partner.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MassExtinction     06-08 0550</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mass Extinction,0564</SECOND>
<HEAD>Findings Support Ancient Celestial Collision Linked to Mass Extinction</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: `Stevns' is cq.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Scientists said today they have discovered two highly unusual substances in old soils, supporting the idea that an ancient comet or asteroid struck the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> and maybe killed off the dinosaurs. Two amino acids that are very rare on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> but abundant in some meteorites appear in sediments that formed around 65 million years ago, the time of a mass extinction involving organisms from dinosaurs to marine plankton. The finding is `` a very compelling piece of evidence'' that an extraterrestrial object struck the Earth around that time, said study co-author <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Bada </PERSON>. But in a recent telephone interview, he said he took no stand on whether the impact caused the extinction. <PERSON> Bada </PERSON> and <PERSON> Meixun </PERSON> <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Scripps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanography </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, present their work in today's issue of the British journal Nature. An editorial accompanying the report called the findings intriguing but cited `` troubling'' questions about the researchers' interpretation The work follows on a hypothesis proposed in 1980, that mass extinction occurred some 65 million years ago because a mountain-sized object struck the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, kicking up large quantities of dust and igniting huge fires. The dust and smoke blocked the sun's rays, and many species froze or starved as their food supply disappeared, the hypothesis suggests. Supporters of the idea note that sediments that formed at the time of the mass extinction contain unusually high concentrations of iridium, a substance rare in the Earth's crust but found in meteorites. Skeptics counter that the iridium may have been produced by extensive volcanic activity. The new study found amino acids called alpha-aminoisobutyric acid and racemic isovaline in sediments that lie close to the main iridium-bearing layer in <LOCATION> Stevns </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Klint </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>. These amino acids are extremely rare on Earth and not likely to come from volcanoes, the reseachers said. In addition, the ratio of the amounts of the two substances was comparable to that previously measured in a meteorite. Surprisingly, the substances were not found in the same layer as the bulk of the iridium, but only in nearby strata, the researchers said. Perhaps the amino acids leaked away from the iridium-bearing clay, they said. But that does not explain how the amino acids could vacate the clay completely, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronin </PERSON> of the chemistry department at <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> wrote in the editorial. The researchers also said they found greater amounts of the amino acids than one would expect to survive from the impact of a meteoritelike body. They suggested that the celestial body may have carried unusually high amounts of the substances, at least in comparison to its iridium content. A comet might have done that, they said. <PERSON> Cronin </PERSON>, in a telephone interview, said no celestial object has been found to meet that requirement. Too little is known about comets to know whether they could be the explanation, he said. To follow up on the new findings, scientists could study different locales and search 65-million-year-old sediments for other amino acids that occur in meteorites but apparently not on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, he said. More than 50 amino acids with no known terrestrial source have been found in meteorites, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0155EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--EvictedCount     06-08 0155</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Evicted Count,0160</SECOND>
<HEAD>Penniless Count Chased From His Dilapidated Chateau</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AVRILLE, France (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Count <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Saint-Pol </PERSON>, losing his last battle with officialdom, has been banished from his ancestral chateau, which is being turned into a local attraction replete with golf course. `` I wanted so much to die at La Perriere,'' the penniless 73-year-old count was quoted by the French news agency Agence France-Presse as saying. The count was expelled Monday from the crumbling edifice where his ancestors lived for 300 years in this town 255 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. For temporary housing, a monks' abbey lent him a farmhouse with neither electricity nor running water. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Saint-Pol </PERSON> was given an indemnity of $ 300,000 in lieu of the chateau _ money which he has not yet touched. The bearded count, without financial means, has been fighting since 1981 to keep his chateau, a dilapidated but historic monument which the municipality wanted to restore.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ChildShot     06-08 0164</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Child Shot,0169</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Children Dead In Separate Accidental Shootings</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIRAMAR, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 10-year-old boy dialed 911 and frantically pleaded with operators to save his little sister, an 8-year-old girl he shot with the pistol he found in his father's dresser drawer. `` I shot her. I did n't mean to,'' <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> pleaded as his sister <PERSON> Erin </PERSON> was dying. `` Please do n't die. Please God, please, do n't be dead. The 911 operator kept him talking until police showed up. But the girl, a second-grader, died within minutes of the shooting Monday. <PERSON> Erin </PERSON>'s parents have arranged a private memorial service Friday at <ORGANIZATION> Miramar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. Her ashes will be spread at a <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> campground where the family spent Memorial Day weekend. In <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION>, a teen-ager playing with a .357 - caliber Magnum handgun taken from his father's briefcase accidentally shot a 10-year-old friend in the Fourth-grader <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Feltner </PERSON> died at <ORGANIZATION> Orlando </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday. No charges were filed in either case.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0542EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM--BRF-Bus-Landslide     06-08 0133</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM--BRF-Bus-Landslide,0135</SECOND>
<HEAD>Landslide Throws Crowded Bus off Hill Road</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JAMMU, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At least 50 people were killed when a landslide hurled the crowded bus they were riding in into a ravine in the northern state of <LOCATION> Jammu-Kashmir </LOCATION>, officials and news reports said. The bodies of ten passengers were recovered from site of Wednesday's accident near <LOCATION> Srinagar </LOCATION> and at least 20 people were hospitalized with injuries, said M.S. <PERSON> Pandit </PERSON>, the top civilian administrator for the <LOCATION> Srinigar </LOCATION> region. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> news agency quoted an unnamed government spokesman as saying 50 people were killed. <PERSON> Pandit </PERSON> said the bus was traveling from the western town of <PERSON> Uri </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Srinagar </LOCATION> on a remote hill road when was caught under the landslide. The vehicle toppled hundreds of feet into a ravine, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Foley Bjt   06-08 0738</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Foley, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Doesn't Want to Be a `Czar,' But Pledges to Push Education</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> says he has no appetite for becoming an all-powerful `` czar speaker'' but wants to use his new power as leader of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to bolster the nation's education system and arrest the growth of an underclass in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. At the same time, he concedes that under predecessor <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> the Democrats sometimes used their majority status to muscle aside the Republicans. He vows that wo n't happen under a Speaker <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>. And he says he has given no thought to his new situation as second in the line of succession to the presidency _ even though his mother `` is enjoying that fact.'' `` But the speaker of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> has never succeeded to the presidency and we all pray that the president has a healthy and long and successful administration at least for the next 3 -LCB- years,'' he said, adding that any American who does not wish President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> well `` is no friend of the republic.'' Relaxed, sipping a diet cola and back from reminiscing during a 90-minute Oval Office lunch with onetime freshman congressman <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> demonstrated in an interview Wednesday the style that propelled him into the speakership with the good will of many Republicans. `` The days of the czar speakers have long been over,'' <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> said, recalling the tale that 19th century speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON>, when asked by a constituent for a copy of the rules that govern the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, `` sent by return mail an autographed photograph of himself.'' <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> rejected the view that the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> is `` a moral swamp,'' but said some politicians come to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> out of a love for political warfare and their every act is aimed at the next election while others come to govern. He put himself among the latter and, ticking off the issues that are dear to his heart, listed education high. `` I'm worried about the growth of the so-called underclass,'' he said, `` millions of young adults and children who are not, for one reason or another, performing in school, or looking forward to an ability to compete in the job market.'' He noted that South Korean children have pulled ahead of Japanese children and far ahead of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> kids in educational achievements. He said Korean youngsters go to school for 240 days a year and carry two lunches _ one for noon, one for late in the day _ because their school day is so long. By contrast, <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> children typically attend school only 180 days. `` I think the quality of elementary and secondary education is going to determine more our ability to successfully compete in an international economy than probably anything else,'' he said. He said he worries about the `` enormous strains'' imposed on middle-class families, especially those with a few children in college at the same time. He has no agenda of legislation to shove through <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, but he cited civil rights and civil liberties as important to him, along with education and the enactment this year of congressional ethics legislation. There is no `` <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> plan,'' he said, but one idea worth examining `` might be linking some extinguishment of honoraria with some staged increase in salary'' for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. House members are allowed to keep $ 30,000 a year in fees for giving speeches or writing. Most of the money comes from special-interest groups, and some reform suggestions propose eliminating such honoraria and raising congressional salaries. But <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> suggested he will be in no rush to propose a pay increase in view of the uproar that cause the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to kill a Bush-backed 50 percent raise in January. <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> conceded a point to Republicans, saying that under <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, `` I think we've pushed it sometimes to the point where, while we were still within the rules, we were making maximum use of the power of the majority. ... I do n't think we should do that.'' Rep. <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said if <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> is `` serious about a new beginning,'' he should support a package of rules changes proposed by the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> last January. Democrats ignored the proposals under <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s leadership, he said. `` There is a new leader and <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> has a different style,'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said, adding that <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> `` systematically excluded the views, opinion, debate, amendments of people who disagreed with the leadership, whether Democrats or Republicans.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-JapanFighter Bjt   06-08 0666</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan Fighter, Bjt,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Vote on FSX Bill Falls Short of Margin to Beat Veto</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARTON REPPERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House opponents of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's planned $ 6 billion FSX fighter deal with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> are far short of the votes needed to override an expected presidential veto A measure to restrict the deal passed the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday but only on a 262-155 vote, far less than the two-thirds margin of 290 needed to override a veto in the 435-member chamber. The administration already has agreed to develop the fighter jointly with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. The measure passed Wednesday seeks to stipulate the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> negotiating position in future talks on how the FSX, an advanced version of the F-16 jet fighter, actually will be produced. An identical <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> resolution passed 72-27 on May 16. Opponents of the deal say it amounts to a giveaway of critical <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> defense technology, but the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration says the restrictive legislation would tie its hands in the talks. Before the measure was approved, Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, warned that `` in case there's any doubt, the White House will veto this amendment if it is passed.'' The legislation would prohibit transfer to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> of critical American jet engine technology and bar <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> from selling to third countries the FSX or any of the plane's major subcomponents. It also states that any agreement on coproduction of the FSX should guarantee that at least 40 percent of the work _ including provision of spare parts _ will be handled by American companies. Opponents declared that the legislation, sponsored by Rep. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON>, D-Ill., might require renegotiation of a memorandum of understanding already reached with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Solarz </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> affairs, said the legislation `` could arguably require a renegotiation of the FSX agreement.'' But a leading FSX opponent, Rep. <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON>, D-Calif., said the restrictions embodied in the measure are needed to `` hold the administration's feet to the fire'' in negotiations Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Mo </LOCATION>., said afterward that `` the margin by which both houses passed this legislation sends a message to the president that we are serious about safeguarding <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s trading rights, protecting American jobs and preserving <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s clear advantage in aerospace technology and production. Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, who sponsored the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> version of the FSX legislation, said it `` increases the leverage of executive branch negotiators'' in dealing with future coproduction of the `` I sincerely hope the president will not veto improvements in this project, or veto increased leverage for his negotiators,'' <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said following the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote. The measure was adopted after the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted 320-98 to pass a nonbinding sense-of-Congress resolution expressing disapproval of the FSX deal in general, but that vote carries no legal weight. Under the FSX deal, <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dynamics </ORGANIZATION> is to join with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heavy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> in jointly developing and producing the warplane, for deployment by <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> in the late 1990s Most of the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dynamics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> FSX </ORGANIZATION> work would be done at its F-16 plant in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. During more than five hours of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor debate Wednesday, opponents contended that the deal amounts to a loss of advanced American technology that will be used by <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to help propel its own aircraft industry into head-to-head competition with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in the world market. `` The sale of this technology represents an enormous threat to the health of our domestic aircraft industry,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON>, D-Kan. FSX foes also said that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> instead should have purchased `` off the shelf'' American-made F-16s to help offset the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade deficit with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> of more than $ 50 billion Supporters of the <ORGANIZATION> FSX </ORGANIZATION> said implementing the deal was important to maintaining U.S.-Japan defense ties and would provide about $ 2.5 billion worth of work for American companies. <PERSON> Solarz </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> that he believes the agreement is `` very much in the commercial, political and strategic interests of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     06-08 0864</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,860</SECOND>
<HEAD>Decision Expected Soon on Oil, Butter Sales to Soviets</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A decision may be announced soon by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> on whether to sell the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> some vegetable oil and butter at cut-rate prices. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration has been under pressure to add soybean oil to the list of commodities eligible for the Export Enhancement Program, or <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION>, so that <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> can buy the oil at subsidized prices. Corn oil and butter are also being sought for the <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION> arrangement with the Soviets. Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> has the proposal under advisement, although there has been some resistance to expand the subsidy program. A consumer advocate, <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nutrition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, told <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> in a May 26 letter the soybean industry's proposal for subsidizing oil exports would be `` patently unfair'' for several reasons. Soybeans are in short supply in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and a bumper harvest this fall will not change the situation. Food price inflation will remain `` a constant threat to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> consumers until more normal food reserves are in place,'' he said. The global supply of soybean oil also is reported to be tighter than normal, <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> said. `` Soybean processors argue that domestic soybean oil supplies are slightly at a surplus, a condition they say could be eliminated by the Soviet sale,'' he said. `` However, domestic market conditions appear to be tight enough so that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> would likely need to import 60,000 to 70,000 metric tons of food oil for every 100,000 tons of soybean oil sold to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> contended that export subsidy programs for farm products `` are of doubtful value, even during periods when domestic supplies are large.'' But Sen. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Iowa </LOCATION>, and others in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> contend that soybean oil should be made available to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> under <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION>, a program set up in 1985 to counter foreign subsidies. <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON> said last month that the Soviets want to buy 200,000 to 500,000 tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soybean oil, and urged President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to approve the sale under the subsidy program. He also asked that corn oil be included. Of immediate concern, <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON> said, are <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>'s tax laws that allow its processors to undercut <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soybean oil prices on the world market by more than $ 160 per ton. `` The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is a potential market for the equivalent of 1 billion bushels of soybeans a year,'' <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON> said. `` We need to move vigorously to develop that market and secure a fair share of it for our soybean industry.'' <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON> noted that current <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> inventories of soybean oil are at record level of 1.76 million tons and that stocks of corn oil and other vegetable oils also are large.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says there are more jobs waiting for the Class of 1989 at major agricultural colleges than there are graduates to fill them. <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, administrator of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Cooperative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said Wednesday a recent informal survey showed another decrease in the number of agricultural graduates. At the same time, more companies are recruiting on campuses. The telephone survey was done by <ORGANIZATION> Purdue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION>, Ind. Although the number of graduates is down, the survey found an increase in the number of freshmen enrolled in agricultural courses. <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Goecker </PERSON>, assistant dean of agriculture at <ORGANIZATION> Purdue </ORGANIZATION>, said the job market has been more competitive and that both employers and students are making earlier commitments. Half of the 1,721 undergraduates in <ORGANIZATION> Purdue </ORGANIZATION>'s school of agriculture are enrolled in three departments _ agricultural economics, horticulture, and forestry and natural resources. The school expects to graduate 365 seniors this year, up from 355 in 1988, <PERSON> Goecker </PERSON> said. Starting salaries for <ORGANIZATION> Purdue </ORGANIZATION> graduates range from $ 18,000 to $ 30,000 a year, with the average just over $ 20,000, he said. <PERSON> Goecker </PERSON> is a member of a <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> committee that has forecast an annual shortage of 4,000 food and agricultural science graduates in the 1990s. Other schools surveyed included: <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tech </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Mississippi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A senior <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official says <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s food inflation may be contributing to much of the bloody turmoil that has centered on <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mayer </PERSON>, acting assistant secretary for economics, said the big purchase of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat announced on Monday _ a total of 1.85 million metric tons _ helped reflect `` a sensitivity within <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> to this issue -LRB- of access to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat -RRB- and the need for food.'' <PERSON> Mayer </PERSON>, in an interview aired today by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> radio, said the big wheat purchase at <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> market prices _ even when <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> still qualified for grain under the department's price subsidy program _ was `` some indication of their need for additional grain'' during the current turmoil. `` Internally, they've had substantial increases in food prices,'' <PERSON> Mayer </PERSON> said. `` I have had one Chinese specialist tell me that food prices have gone up 30 to 40 percent in the major cities over the last 18 months.'' <PERSON> Mayer </PERSON> speculated that this rise in food prices has helped fan popular support of the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> protesters.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0542EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Alcohol-Strokes     06-08 0331</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Alcohol-Strokes,0341</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Research Links ``Bottoms Up'' Drinking With Strokes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Young adults have been the victims of strokes in recent years after traumatizing one of four main arteries supplying blood to the brain while performing such simple tasks as brushing teeth or tossing back a drink. A 32-year-old woman recently suffered a stroke after playing a drinking game in which she tossed back several shots of whiskey, according to a letter published in today's New England Journal of Medicine. `` It was not only the alcohol but the manner in which she consumed it,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Trosch </PERSON>, a neurology resident at the <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> and a co-author of the article. Knocking back a shot of whiskey should be included among a list of potential stroke-causing `` trivial traumas,'' including old whiplash injuries, childbirth, heavy lifting and diving into water, <PERSON> Trosch </PERSON> and his colleagues reported. `` We believe that ` bottoms up' drinking, as a form of trivial trauma, caused this young woman's dissection and subsequent stroke,'' wrote <PERSON> Trosch </PERSON> and his <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> co-authors, Drs. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brass </PERSON> and <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Hasbani </PERSON>. `` Although alcoholic intoxication has been reported as a risk factor for stroke, the manner in which one chooses to become intoxicated has not.'' <PERSON> Trosch </PERSON> said young adults were particularly prone to damaging the extracranial carotid artery, a major vein through which blood is pumped from the heart to the brain. `` The young are particularly predisposed not only because they more often play drinking games, but also because their arteries are a little more taut than older people's and do not stretch,'' <PERSON> Trosch </PERSON> said in an interview. Known risk factors for dissection of the extracranial carotid artery include fibromuscular dysplasia, hypertension and <PERSON> Erdheim </PERSON>'s cystic medical necrosis The Yale Stroke Program researchers' article suggests many strokes might also have been caused by `` trivial traumas'' that frequently go undetected. `` Patients may consider such movements insignificant and thus not recall them, or be too embarrassed to recount them,'' the authors wrote.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0542EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;LWithdrawals     06-08 0378</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;L Withdrawals,370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Savings Withdrawal Rate Expected To Continue Falling</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Net withdrawals from the nation's savings institutions should continue to ease from record high levels as interest rates decline, economists say. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday that <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L customers withdrew $ 5.4 billion more than they deposited in April, down from the records set earlier this year but still high in historic terms. Net withdrawals totaled $ 8.3 billion in March, $ 9.2 billion in February and a record $ 10.8 billion in January for a total of $ 33.7 billion so far this year. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Barth </PERSON>, the bank board's chief economist, attributed much of the recent outflow to thrift institutions' failure to keep pace with rising interest rates offered by competitors such as mutual funds. S & amp; L analyst <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Ely </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L reports will show slower withdrawals or perhaps even a modest gain in deposits in May and June. Interest rates offered by thrifts historically lag behind money market funds both on the way up and on the way down. `` We have reached the most recent peak in interest rates and now of course they are trending down. We're seeing a lessening of the rate-driven shrinkage of deposits,'' <PERSON> Ely </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Barth </PERSON> also attributed the shrinkage in April to pressure from regulators on overextended thrift institutions to shrink. About half of the decline can be traced to 10 institutions, four of them insolvent, he said. Other analysts, however, say a loss of public confidence in S & amp; Ls has also played a role. <PERSON> Barth </PERSON> said the April figure is better than it at first appears because withdrawals normally increase in that month because people pay federal taxes. He said outflow was $ 1.6 billion on a seasonally adjusted basis, down sharply from $ 6.7 billion in March and the smallest outflow since last September. Economist <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Getman </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wefa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, a consulting firm in <PERSON> Bala </PERSON> <PERSON> Cynwyd </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, said $ 5.4 billion is `` still not a great number.'' He noted that Americans are saving more this year _ 5.8 percent of their income compared with 4.2 percent last year. `` So, you've got people saving more but still taking money out of thrift institutions. That's not a vote of confidence at all,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0543EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DroughtRelief     06-08 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought Relief,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drought Relief Decision May Not Come Til Fall</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If winter wheat farmers are to get any drought relief aid, it may not be decided until the end of the fiscal year, Sept. 30. During an informal meeting Wednesday with <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt., said he did n't want to pass legislation that would have to be revised later `` It seems too early to cover spring planted crops,'' said <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON> during the meeting which attracted 20 other senators. `` We do n't known whether such crops are going to be weather damaged. To act now on spring-planted crops shifts the risk of production almost totally to the federal government _ I do n't think that is a good idea.'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> was critical of a bill passed last month by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, calling it a `` Christmas tree'' because it promises relief to many crops other than winter wheat, just in case weather later in the year damages them. `` If we do develop legislative response, it ought to be very narrowly defined and circumscribed to the people who have been hurt,'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> pointed out that rain has been falling steadily in the past few weeks, even to the point of causing planting delays in some parts of the country. <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>'s committee has not yet acted on any legislation, though a bill authored by Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan. and one sponsored by <PERSON> Sens </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON>, D-Neb have been introduced. Those measures would extend assistance provided under the 1988 drought relief act to crops planted in 1988 for harvest in 1989 _ mostly winter wheat. But <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON> said, `` If you have a winter wheat bill, it becomes the vehicle for the year,'' and he does n't want a measure the country ca n't afford. He said cost estimates for any bill are suspect at this early date, though damage to winter wheat has been estimated to be about $ 1 billion. He said he did n't want to give farmers assistance in a bill that would have to be taken away because of budget restraints. But <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said he did n't see any reason to wait. `` I hope we do n't have to hold the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> hostage until we see if there are problems in other states,'' he said. He said his bill is budget neutral, in that it would use deficiency payments being saved because of higher wheat prices to pay the farmers who are facing losses.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0543EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Deland-Environment     06-08 0574</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Deland-Environment,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Environmentals Hope Deland Can Boost Role of Presidential Council</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Environmentalists say they hope the selection of <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Deland </PERSON> to the president's <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Quality </ORGANIZATION> will signal a revival for the advisory panel, which was largely ignored in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> announced Wednesday he plans to nominate <LOCATION> Deland </LOCATION>, regional administrator in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> for the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, to the three-member council and then make him its chairman. The selection of <LOCATION> Deland </LOCATION> brought praise from several environmental groups. He has gained a reputation as a strong enforcer of environmental laws as the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s chief in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. The council advises the president on environmental matters, but the panel languished with little money, staff or power during the eight years of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> largely ignored its members. `` <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Deland </PERSON> is a first rate environmentalist and I think he's an outstanding choice,'' said <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Hair </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> `` The bigger question is whether or not the president will give him both the resources and the respect in order to revitalize, rebuild and redirect the <ORGANIZATION> CEQ </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardiner </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Sierra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> said <LOCATION> Deland </LOCATION> was `` a very strong environmentalist'' and called his selection `` very much a positive step'' and that he assumed that <LOCATION> Deland </LOCATION> `` would not have taken the job if he had not had some assurances of what the <ORGANIZATION> CEQ </ORGANIZATION>'s authority would be'' in the White House. The council's influence largely will be `` a question of staffing and money,'' said <PERSON> Gardiner </PERSON>. In the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> administration the <ORGANIZATION> CEQ </ORGANIZATION> was provided with professional staff that could research issues and brief council members who, in turn, had strong influence on the president. `` Under the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration they -LRB- the staff -RRB- vanished,'' said <PERSON> Gardiner </PERSON>. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had at one time sought to abolish the council. <LOCATION> Deland </LOCATION>, who has been mentioned as a possible Republican gubernatorial candidate in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, has been director of the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s regional office in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> since 1983 where he gained a reputation for aggressively pursuing polluters. He sometimes was at odds with the agency's <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> headquarters. Earlier this year he was mentioned widely as a top prospect to become head of the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> in the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON> was selected instead. During last year's presidential race, <LOCATION> Deland </LOCATION> added fuel to the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign's attack on Democratic opponent <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for failing as <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor to clean up <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>. But while <LOCATION> Deland </LOCATION> criticized <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for delaying the cleanup, he acknowleged that the federal EPA under the Republican administration also shared blame. When <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> took reporters on a boatride through the polluted harbor, <LOCATION> Deland </LOCATION> refused to go along. <ORGANIZATION> Deland </ORGANIZATION> 47, whose back problems force him usually to rely on a wheelchair, had occasional clashes with his superiors in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> years as well as with then-New Hampshire Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON>, now White House chief of staff. He stood his ground against opposition from <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> headquarters and blocked the development of a shopping mall in <LOCATION> Attleboro </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, arguing the complex would destroy environmentally important wetlands. He clashed with <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> over a proposed development in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Loon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> and endorsed a moratorium on development on <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cod </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Deland </LOCATION> is a graduate of <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. He worked for the president of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION>, on the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s legal staff and as a private consultant before taking the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> job in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Gingrich-Lukens     06-08 0533</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gingrich-Lukens,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gingrich Won't Challenge Convicted Republican's Right To Vote In
House</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID PACE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Newt </PERSON> <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, who rose to prominence in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> with his ethics crusades against Democrats, says he wo n't challenge a fellow <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION>'s right to vote in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> while appealing his conviction for having sex with a teen-age girl. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> whip, said in an interview Wednesday that Rep. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> `` Buz'' <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> R-Ohio </LOCATION>, should not have to give up his right to vote because his conviction involved a misdemeanor, not a felony. He said the conviction for contributing to the delinquency and unruliness of a minor is `` a serious offense, but it's a serious misdemeanor'' which will not cause <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION> to lose any citizenship rights. <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION> faces up to six months in prison and a $ 1,000 fine for his conviction. `` I think the Lukens case will go to the ethics committee and I think the Republican Conference will insist on it,'' <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> said. `` But I think it is inappropriate for us to impose our judgment on the courts of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>'' and bar <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION> from voting while his conviction is on appeal. <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION>' chief of staff, <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarrell </PERSON>, said the congressman would have no response to <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>'s comments. `` Congressman Lukens is not going to take out time and react to every statement that comes down the pike,'' he said. `` He's taking care of business here on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> has insisted since his freshman term in 1980 that any congressman convicted of a felony should not be permitted to vote in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> while appealing his conviction. He moved to expel then-Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Diggs </PERSON>, D-Mich., in 1980 after he continued to vote following his fraud conviction, and he threatened similar action against then-Rep. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, after his 1987 conviction for accepting <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON> stopped voting after the threat. `` The principle in regard to the felony convictions of <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON> and <PERSON> Diggs </PERSON> was that if you're convicted of a felony, you lose certain of your political rights, including the right to vote,'' <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> said his decision not to challenge <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION>' right to vote was not influenced by his frienship with the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> congressman, who was one of the conservative Republicans who joined with <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> to form the <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opportunity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> in the early 1980s. He compared <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION>' case to that of Rep. <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Studds </PERSON>, D-Mass., who along with then-Rep. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Crane </PERSON>, R-Ill., was censured by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> in 1983 for sexual misconduct with <PERSON> Studds </PERSON> has remained in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and is now chairman of a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> predicted that <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION> eventually will be punished by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, and he suggested that a resolution of censure, such as that imposed on <PERSON> Studds </PERSON> and <PERSON> Crane </PERSON>, might be appropriate. During the 1983 <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> debate over punishment for <PERSON> Studds </PERSON> and <PERSON> Crane </PERSON>, however, <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> argued that they should be expelled from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` There is no high school or college in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> where exploiting, seducing or sleeping with students, boy or girl, would be punished with a reprimand,'' he said in the 1983 debate. `` The teacher would be fired. Similarly, the two congressmen, like a teacher, must be fired.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0214EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MedicareSurcharge     06-08 0682</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Medicare Surcharge,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Panel to Review Medicare's Catastrophic Health Provisions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, after narrowly rejecting an attempt to postpone major parts of the new catastrophic health provisions of <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION>, has ordered a committee review of the program. The aim of the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> review is to consider reducing the income tax surcharge on the elderly that pays for the new benefits. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, R-Ariz., fell two votes short Wednesday evening of attaching an amendment to separate legislation that would have forced a delay of at least one year in the so-called `` supplemental premium'' imposed this year on Medicare-eligible individuals to pay for a package of benefits that start taking effect next January However, <PERSON> McCain </PERSON> also would have pushed back those benefits yet another year, and opponents argued that his proposal effectively would have killed major parts of the program approved overwhelming by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last summer. It is the first major expansion of Medicare since its creation two decades ago. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, seeking to head off the <PERSON> McCain </PERSON> attempt, introduced a substitute amendment that put the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on record as instructing the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> to look into reducing the surtax if it is shown that more money is being collected than will be needed. <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, first raised that possibility several weeks ago but the administration, as well as influential <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leaders, are on record against any tax rollback. In debate on <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>'s proposal, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> also pledged to look closely at ways to exempt from the catastrophic surtax those retired Americans who have equal coverage under `` Medigap'' policies that are paid in full or part by their former employers. And he said he would renew efforts to attach the catastrophic coverage to Part B of Medicare, thus making it voluntary. Part B of Medicare, the section that pays doctor bills, is voluntarily taken by more than 95 percent of those eligible _ in large part because the federal government foots the bill for 75 percent of the costs. Although members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> have been hit by thousands of letters protesting the new catastrophic program, opponents of the <PERSON> McCain </PERSON> proposal argued that opponents still represent a tiny minority of the 32 million people covered by <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION>. The idea behind the financing mechanism adopted last year was that _ with huge budget deficits making it impossible to provide new government benefits without additional revenue to pay for them _ it was reasonable to expect that those being offered additional benefits be required to pay for them. Moreover, framers of the program maintained, it was fair for middle - and upper-income retired Americans to pay a proportionately larger share of the cost just as the federal tax system in general is pegged to a percentage of income The catastrophic 15 percent tax surcharge follows that principle, except the maximum imposed on any individual this year is $ 800, regardless of income. Opponents of the <PERSON> McCain </PERSON> attempt argued that an estimated 59 percent of the 32 million Medicare beneficaries do not have enough income to qualify for income tax and would pay only $ 4 a month for the additional coverage. They cited <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> estimates that 70 percent of those eligible for <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> would pay $ 100 or less a year in additional surtaxes and that only 5.6 percent in upper income levels would pay the maximum $ 800 tax. The catastrophic coverage started taking effect Jan. 1 with unlimited hospitalization coverage after a once-a-year $ 560 deductible. However, a $ 1,370 cap on out-of-pocket doctor bills does not kick in until next year and a new prescription drug benefit begins a three-year phase-in period in 1991. It was those benefits beginning next January that <PERSON> McCain </PERSON> wanted to delay, along with the surtax imposed to finance them. Prior to Jan. 1, <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> provided full hospital coverage for only 59 days a year. <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> pays 80 percent of physician bills after a $ 75 annual deductible, but until the new catastrophic provisions on doctor fees take effect there is no cap on the patient's share.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0214EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SpendingBill     06-08 0586</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spending Bill,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>House, Senate Face Deep Differences Over Domestic Spending Bill</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> face pressure to resolve their differences speedily over a long-delayed spending bill, but the widest gulf is over one of the hottest political issues: illegal drugs. A bipartisan <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voiced approval Wednesday for legislation pouring an extra $ 3.3 billion this year into veterans, student loan and other programs. The vote capping lawmakers' fourth day of debate came more than two months after President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> asked <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for a $ 2.2 billion version of the bill. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> passed its own $ 3.7 billion measure on May 24 on a contentious party-line vote. As is usual with spending legislation, each chamber sprinkled its own bill with provisions boosting individual lawmakers' favorite projects. The biggest difference between the two bills is $ 822 million the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> included for a host of anti-drug programs. Majority Democrats there inserted the money into the bill, over veto threats from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration officials arguing that the spending would further inflate the deficit. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> version contains no drug monies. Despite public opinion polls indicating that illegal drugs is the pre-eminent domestic problem, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> heeded <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s warnings and joined Republicans in preventing some legislators from putting drug spending into the bill. <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Silvio </PERSON> <PERSON> Conte </PERSON>, ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said he did not believe it would be difficult for the two houses to work out their differences over financing new anti-drug efforts. `` I think I can get the White House to compromise on something,'' he told a reporter. But one administration official, speaking on condition of anonymity, insisted Wednesday there was still `` no way'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would sign the final bill if any drug spending was included. That was also the conventional wisdom among lawmakers and congressional aides. Legislators will be pressed to bargain quickly by many groups hoping to garner money from the bill, but foremost among them will be the nation's veterans. In each house's measure, there is $ 1.2 billion for health care, compensation increases and other programs for the nation's 27 million veterans. There is no disagreement that the coffers of the Department of Veterans Affairs are running low. The agency has already begun curtailing medical services, purchases of new equipment and other efforts. The two bills also contain money for the Guaranteed Student Loan program, forest fire fighting, foster care, refugee assistance, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> peacekeeping and other initiatives. Before they can send a compromise bill to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for his signature, lawmakers will have to make trade-offs over whose pet projects remain in the measure. There are many. The House bill has provisions directing the <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> to build a road at <LOCATION> Saylorville </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>; allowing extra money to be spent on an agriculture research center in <LOCATION> Lane </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>; and temporarily blocking development of a laser device in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> as an anti-satellite weapon. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> measure provides $ 75 million to replace a broken 300-foot radio telescope in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>; supplies $ 7.3 million for the cleanup of the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> oil spill; and urges the government to buy more apples for the school lunch program. On Wednesday, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rejected 51-49 an effort by Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>., to amend the bill with a provision delaying much of <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION>'s new catastrophic care program for a year Instead, senators agreed to non-binding language promising a future look at altering the program, which imposes a surtax on the elderly that some have complained costs them too much.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0300EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CocaineProduction     06-08 0360</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cocaine Production,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>No Progress in Sight Against Cocaine Production</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A top <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drug-control official says efforts to stem the cocaine trade by eradicating crops in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> will not produce substantial results for years. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Westrate </PERSON>, the Drug Enforcement Administration's assistant administrator for operations, offered that assessment Wednesday in testimony before the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> narcotics committee. `` Escalating coca cultivation and cocaine production in the Andes has at no time been more critical nor posed as profound a threat to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and its allies,'' <PERSON> Westrate </PERSON> said. But while progress is being made in eradication, `` We will not see substantial effects for years against coca,'' he said. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Skol </PERSON>, deputy assistant secretary of state for inter-American affairs, said the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is considering `` new directions'' in the eradication effort. He did not spell them out, but suggested they will be expensive. `` Money is a crucial part of the narcotics trade, and unfortunately in this time of tight budgets, money may be one of the most effective weapons we can muster for our anti-narcotics programming,'' he said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy, he said, must consider `` what happens if and when we are successful'' in eradicating cocaine production: what will happen to the peasant farmers earning their livings growing coca, to the economies of those countries and to the governments that, by wiping out the cocaine business, will be confronted by an angry populace. He said increased economic and military aid will be required. <PERSON> Skol </PERSON> said the governments of <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> need additional military assistance because anti-drug officials there are battling both guerrilla groups and well-armed drug traffickers _ who occasionally support each other for either economic or geographic reasons. In <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Skol </PERSON> said, the Sendero Luminoso, or `` Shining Path,'' guerrillas have virtually taken control of the <LOCATION> Upper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huallaga </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, a primary source for the world's supply of coca leaf. When the Peruvian government tries to eradicate the crops there, it winds up fighting the guerrillas as well, he said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military assistance this year to <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> is $ 6 million, and the department has requested $ 20 million for next year, <PERSON> Skol </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890608-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-08-89 0301EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Panama     06-08 0503</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Panama,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nicaragua Was Ready To Send Troops To Panama, Officials Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
