<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0106EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PacificSearch     05-05 0185</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pacific Search,0189</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ships And Plane Search For 22 Crewmen After Trawler Sinks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ships and an airplane searched the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> 1,150 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Midway </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> on Thursday for 22 crewmen of a Taiwanese fishing vessel that sank after colliding with a sister ship, officials said. Four Taiwanese fishing vessels, two commercial vessels and a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> patrol plane were taking part in the search for the crew of the Hun-Kuoa No. 2, which sank after the collision Wednesday, said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Goff </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. So far the searchers have found no sign of the missing men. The Hun-Kuoa No. 1, which was involved in the collision, lost power and was unable to pick up the crewmen who jumped into the water in lifejackets when their vessel began sinking, <PERSON> Goff </PERSON> said. The Hun-Kuoa No. 1 later got its power back and joined the search for the missing seamen, he said. A <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> P-3 Orion patrol plane from Adak, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, reached the area at midday Thursday and was ready to drop rescue gear to any survivors spotted in the water, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PornDismissal     05-05 0298</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Porn Dismissal,0306</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Says LA Too Diverse to Consider Porn Films as Obscene</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge has ruled that certain X-rated, sexually explicit videotapes might violate community standards in some small town elsewhere _ but not in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. `` There is stuff out there which is apparently accepted by the community which is far more morbid and shocking,'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Kenyon </PERSON> said Wednesday in acquitting a video salesman of racketeering charges. Federal prosecutors tried to prove that tapes such as `` Prisoner of Pleasure'' and `` Kneel Before Me'' could by judged by <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> standards as patently offensive. The judge said that in a small community, perhaps, the videos could be deemed obscene. But he added that `` the court ca n't say it in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> in this day and age.'' Attorneys on both sides said the ruling may change the government's courtroom tactics, allowing films to stand on their own as evidence rather than calling in expert witnesses to testify about community standards. `` It's an important case and in any future case tried in federal court, it will be cited,'' said defense attorney <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Fleishman </PERSON>. The case centered on interpretations of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s 1973 decision that found that to be obscene, material must appeal to the prurient interest, depict sexual conduct in a manner that would be patently offensive judged by the community's standards, and lack serious literary, artistic, political or scientific value <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> <PERSON> Gottesman </PERSON>, 56, owner of <ORGANIZATION> X-Citement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Video </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> and R.G. Sales Co., still faces two charges of interstate transportation of child pornography and one charge of conspiracy for selling films starring porn star <PERSON> Traci </PERSON> <PERSON> Lords </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gottesman </PERSON> testified that he did not know Miss Lords was under 18 years old when she made most of her films.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-APAppointment     05-05 0138</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Appointment,0140</SECOND>
<HEAD>AP Names Assistant Bureau Chief in Washington</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, a news editor in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> bureau of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has been promoted to assistant chief of bureau. The appointment was announced Thursday by <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Chief of Bureau <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolman </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, who joins <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Espo </PERSON> as one of two assistant chiefs in the bureau, has been an editor in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> since 1983. She directed <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s coverage of the 1986 and 1988 political campaigns, as well as the 1988 political conventions, and was named news editor in January. Ms. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, 33, is a native of Revillo, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, and a graduate of <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dakota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. She began her AP career in <LOCATION> Bismarck </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION>, in 1978. She also worked in <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON>, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, and was correspondent in <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> before transferring to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0233EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     05-05 0074</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0078</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 4-3-6-0.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 16; 19; 20; 25; 34; 36.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 13; 15; 22; 28; 34; 38. Bonus 59083.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 18; 21; 35; 36; 45; 52. Supplementary 46.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 8-3-4-3.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 7-6-0; 3-7-2-0; 9-3-2-6-2; 6-9-0-3-1-3.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BolivianElection     05-05 0756</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bolivian Election,0781</SECOND>
<HEAD>Memories of Better Days Give Former Dictator Edge in Campaign</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN NOBLET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LA PAZ, Bolivia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former dictator <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> <PERSON> Banzer </PERSON> has demonstrated a lasting, broadly based popularity in his campaign to win election Sunday to the presidency he once took by force. The 62-year-old retired army general is playing to enthusiastic audiences from all social levels of this poor, largely Indian nation of 6 million. His popularity is a curious phenomenon at a time when dictatorsip is on the decline in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and democracy on the rise. He explained it this way in a speech: `` The people have an instinct that the political hacks have yet to discover. The people remember the good things as well as the bad.'' When <PERSON> Banzer </PERSON> was in power from 1971 to 1978, prices for tin, oil and other exports were high, <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION> enjoyed economic growth and its people were working. After his departure came slumping prices, rising debt, unemployment and rampant inflation. During a tour of slums at <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION>, a tropical city that is <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION>'s second largest, packs of ragged youngsters shouting `` Viva Banzer!'' chased his open car through the unpaved streets. He was dressed casually in a sport shirt and waved to cheering crowds. Mothers held up babies to be kissed. The evening before, he attended a crowded fund-raising dinner in a La Paz luxury hotel, where an organization of doctors, lawyers and other professionals gave the former general a gold medal designating him `` Leader of Bolivian Democracy.'' Nearly every poll shows him leading the field of 10 candidates. <PERSON> Banzer </PERSON> finished first four years ago with 28.6 percent of the vote, but lack of a majority left the decision to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. It chose <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> <PERSON> Estenssoro </PERSON>, who was second with 26.4 percent. No candidate is expected to get a majority this time either, but <PERSON> Banzer </PERSON> hopes to build a large enough plurality to make him the only possible choice for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` A great economic and social development'' occurred under his military government, <PERSON> Banzer </PERSON> says. After he was forced out of office by popular pressure for a return to democracy, an economic crisis descended on <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and the good times ended. Inflation eventually soared to 20,000 percent a year. <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> <PERSON> Estenssoro </PERSON> had to adopt drastic austerity measures, including the dismissal of 22,000 employees of state-owned tin mines. Authorities say the austerity program is working, restoring stability and allowing some real economic growth, but it also has meant painfully hard times for many working-class Bolivians. Nationalist Democratic Action, <PERSON> Banzer </PERSON>'s party, promises in its slogan a return to `` Order, Peace and Work.'' Opponents and some human rights groups dwell on the former dictator's tactics while in power. The <ORGANIZATION> Bolivian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Permanent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> says at least 33 people disappeared and hundreds were arrested, tortured or forced into exile in a crackdown on leftists, labor and dissident journalists. `` <PERSON> Banzer </PERSON> kept the people subjected, violating the most basic human and civil rights,'' <PERSON> Rolando </PERSON> <PERSON> Villena </PERSON>, a Roman Catholic bishop and president of the assembly's executive committee, said in an interview. `` The people are losing their historical memory,'' <PERSON> Villena </PERSON> said of the public support. The <PERSON> Banzer </PERSON> slogan, he said, `` means order imposed from above on those below.'' In campaign speeches, <PERSON> Banzer </PERSON> points out that he did not seize power from an elected government. His coup in 1971 ousted a leftist military government that had installed a People's Assembly and planned other communist-style changes. Many civilians, including <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> <PERSON> Estenssoro </PERSON>, supported the coup. <PERSON> Villena </PERSON> said <PERSON> Banzer </PERSON> relinquished power only when forced to do so by popular resistance, hunger strikes and labor actions. `` Democracy is n't a gift of this dictator,'' he said. `` It was won by the people against his wishes.'' To such arguments, <PERSON> Banzer </PERSON> responds: `` We are n't trying to convince our adversaries of today, who only want to listen to themselves, that we are democrats. ... We know that would be like plowing the sea.'' <PERSON> Banzer </PERSON> claims democratic credentials on the basis of peaceful participation in the process since forming his party a decade ago and his acceptance of the decision by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to deny him the presidency in 1985. His main opponents this time are <PERSON> Gonzalo </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Losada </PERSON> of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Jaime </PERSON> <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> <PERSON> Zamora </PERSON> of the Movement of the Revolutionary Left. He challenged both to pledge their support to the top vote-getter, whoever that is. They refused, saying <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> must retain its constitutional authority. A new <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> also is to be elected Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0867 05-05 0591</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0867,0610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: ADDS Fleisher; AMs separates moved as a0753 on Watson and a0801
on Younger. Fleisher also moved on the sports wire.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Douglass Watson</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Douglass </PERSON> <PERSON> Watson </PERSON>, a actor who played <PERSON> Mackenzie </PERSON> <PERSON> Cory </PERSON> on the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> soap opera `` Another World,'' died Monday in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> of a heart attack. He was 67. The role, which he played for nearly 15 years, earned him Emmy Awards in 1980 and 1981. <PERSON> Watson </PERSON> won the Distinguished Flying Cross and two Purple Hearts for his service in the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> in World War II. He appeared in more than 30 Broadway plays, including the title role in `` Confidential Clerk.'' Other theater credits included `` Over Here,'' ` <ORGANIZATION> Wisteria </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trees </ORGANIZATION>,'' `` <PERSON> Romeo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Juliet </PERSON>'' and `` Glass Clock.'' <PERSON> Watson </PERSON> was awarded a New York Drama Desk award in 1974 for his portrayal of <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Pedro </PERSON> in <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>'s `` Much Ado About Nothing.'' He was also seen in the films `` Sayonara,'' `` <PERSON> Julius </PERSON> <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON>,'' `` Ulzana's Raid'' and `` The Money Pit.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Evelle Younger</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Evelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Younger </PERSON>, a former district attorney who oversaw the prosecution of <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Manson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON>, died Thursday of arteriosclerotic cardiovascular disease. He was 70. Younger served eight years as state attorney general and won the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> nomination for governor in 1978 after careers as an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent, deputy city attorney, city prosecutor, municipal and superior court judge, and district attorney. During his six-year tenure as <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> district attorney, <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON> was tried and convicted for the 1968 assassination of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. Younger's office also brought the first indictments against <PERSON> Manson </PERSON> and his followers for the 1969 Tate-LaBianca slayings. In 1968, he headed President-elect <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s Crime and <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Task </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>. Younger was also chief of President <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Task </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> on Administration of Justice. After losting the governor's race to Democratic incumbent Gov. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> in 1979, <PERSON> Younger </PERSON> became a senior partner in the law firm of <LOCATION> Buchalter </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Nemer </PERSON>, Fields and <PERSON> Chrystie </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Herschel Loveless</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DES MOINES, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Herschel </PERSON> <PERSON> Loveless </PERSON>, a former governor of <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, died Wednesday in <LOCATION> Winchester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, at the age of 77. Loveless, who served as governor from 1957 to 1961, was the first Democratic governor in 18 years when he succeeded Republican <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoegh </PERSON> in the governor's mansion. He left office in 1961 after losing the 1960 <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> race to Republican <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Larry Fleisher</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Fleisher </PERSON>, who founded the <ORGANIZATION> NBA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Players </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and as an agent represented some of the biggest names in the sport, collapsed and died Thursday following a squash game. He was 58. A <ORGANIZATION> Roosevelt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said it was policy not to release the cause of death. Under <PERSON> Fleisher </PERSON>'s leadership of 26 years, <ORGANIZATION> NBA </ORGANIZATION> players became some of the highest paid in sports and gained one of the best free-agent systems. <PERSON> Fleisher </PERSON> also worked with the league in developing a model drug-abuse program in which the union participated. When <PERSON> Fleisher </PERSON> started the association in 1961, the average player's salary was $ 10,000. Under the six-year collective bargaining agreement he negotiated in 1988, the average salary will increase to $ 900,000 by 1993. It is now about $ 600,000. <PERSON> Fleisher </PERSON> operated the union under the title of general counsel. He resigned last September, and a month later joined <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> as head of its sports division. In addition to his union activities, <PERSON> Fleisher </PERSON> represented such leading players as <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> West </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Havlicek </PERSON>, <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Lanier </PERSON> and <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> English.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CDC--Flu     05-05 0356</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CDC--Flu,0366</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Health Officials Tinkering With Flu Vaccine</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BYRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's flu vaccine will have a new formula, designed to better attack the flu strains expected to hit the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> next winter. Two of the three virus strains in the 1989-90 flu vaccine will be different from last year's flu shot, guarding against new strains of flu, the national <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday. The third ingredient remains the same. The reason: the three major types of flu virus show what researchers call `` drift'' from time to time, changing into different forms that prompt the development of slightly different vaccines to maintain the effectiveness of the flu shot. Last year's vaccine targeted the Type A-H3N2 strain known as the <LOCATION> Sichuan </LOCATION> flu and the Type B strain called the <LOCATION> Victoria </LOCATION> flu; next winter's shot will go after two new variations: the <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> flu an the <LOCATION> Yamagata </LOCATION> flu. The third ingredient, designed to stop the Type B strain called the <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> flu, remains unchanged. `` The prediction is that these -LRB- strains -RRB- look like the likely ones to circulate next year,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tipple </PERSON>, a CDC flu specialist. Flu vaccine is especially recommended for people who are at high risk of serious problems if they get the flu, including heart and lung patients and elderly people. The <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Immunization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Practices </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> also recommends flu shots for nursing home residents, people with chronic diabetes or kidney disease, people with suppressed immune systems and young people on aspirin therapy, who might develop <PERSON> Reye </PERSON>'s syndrome after a flu infection. The <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> further recommends flu shots for anyone who simply wants to lessen the chance of getting influenza. Flu season traditionally strikes during the cold weather months. The strains being recommended for the 1989-90 vaccine started to appear in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> late last winter, and some are now being seen in the <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION>, where the seasons are reversed. `` Those are actually strains that just started to pop up at the end of the -LRB- <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> -RRB- flu season and are circulating now in other parts of the world,'' Tipple said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--MillionaireBaby     05-05 0119</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Millionaire Baby,0121</SECOND>
<HEAD>Michigan Boy a `Million Dollar Baby'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SOUTHFIELD, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 21-month-old boy has won a national `` Million Dollar Baby'' search, earning a municipal bond that will be worth $ 1 million when it and the winner mature. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Markowitz </PERSON> on Thursday received the bond, which will reach full value when he is 21, according to the cable network Video Hits 1. The 10-week contest, in which viewers were invited to send in pictures of children 4 months to 2 years old, was sponsored by the network, Downy Fabric Softener and <ORGANIZATION> Gerber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>. The name of the baby from suburban <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> was drawn at random from among about 200,000 entries, VH-1 spokeswoman <PERSON> Kristy </PERSON> <PERSON> Loveman </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Wright-Loan     05-05 0299</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wright-Loan,0306</SECOND>
<HEAD>Speaker Borrowed, Lost $100,000 in Investment</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> borrowed $ 100,000 to invest in a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> nursing home company in 1983, and lost the money when the company was liquidated in bankruptcy proceedings two years later, according to pubished reports. Before the company failed, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> received dividends on his investment in <ORGANIZATION> Jewell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, although other investors received none, according to reports in The <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s financial disclosure statements list `` investment income'' from <ORGANIZATION> Jewell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION> of between $ 5,001 and $ 15,000 in 1983. But <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Oldaker </PERSON>, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s attorney, said <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> also received $ 17,000 around the beginning of 1985, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said in its Friday editions. Only one other investor, a friend of <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s who recommended the investment to him, received payments from the company, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said, citing interviews with 20 of the 27 other investors. The <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> reported on Tuesday that <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> borrowed all the money for his purchase of $ 100,000 worth of stock in <ORGANIZATION> Jewell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION> and used the stock as collateral for the loan. T.R. <PERSON> Jewell </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Jewell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION>, was also a director at the bank that lent <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> the money, The <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Jewell </PERSON>'s bankruptcy made the stock worthless, but the loan still had to be repaid. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> also had to repay $ 13,500 of the dividends he had received, the reports said. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> finished paying off the loan last June, using some of his $ 340,000 profit from a later gas well deal, The <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> reported. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee is looking into the circumstances of the well venture. The speaker is currently defending himself against charges he broke <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> rules 69 times over the past decade. The ethics panel is expected to hold a hearing on the charges later this month.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0250EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Economy     05-05 0889</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Economy,0907</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sugar, Salt &amp; Soap: Shortages Worsen Under Perestroika</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN-THOR DAHLBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the town of <LOCATION> Kimry </LOCATION>, soap rationing began in April, limiting each man and woman to one bar of household soap and 1 -RCB- pounds of bath soap in local shops. Not each week or month, but each year. The residents of <LOCATION> Ufa </LOCATION>, a city of 1 million people in the Urals, are loading up on salt and matches due to rumors of pending shortages. Sugar rationing went into effect in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> on May 1 for the first time since World War II, and even the Soviet minister of trade, <PERSON> Kondrat </PERSON> <PERSON> Terekh </PERSON>, has been issued a card entitling him to 4.4 pounds of sugar per month and no more. Those tales of consumer woe, and more, were cited in state-run newspapers Thursday, along with an anguished complaint in the weekly <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> News that the Soviet retail trade system, caught between President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbache </PERSON>'s reforms and old iron-fisted bureaucratic habits, `` is literally breaking apart before our very eyes.'' Far from causing store shelves to brim with goods, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s campaign for `` perestroika,'' or economic and social renewal, coincides with shortages in the consumer sector nationwide, and some Soviets say the reforms, now in their fifth year, are the direct cause Others blame bureaucrats hostile to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and his reform drive. `` The feeling is such that under cover of the words ` the inescapable difficulties of perestroika,' shortages are being created deliberately to indoctrinate this: perestroika on the one hand brings glasnost, which you ca n't put into tea, and on the other hand, a real worsening in the conditions of life,'' wrote <PERSON> Georgy </PERSON> <PERSON> Afanasyev </PERSON> in this week's <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> News. `` In a word, they're telling us: choose either the old order, with tea and sugar, or perestroika and just boiled water with glasnost,'' <PERSON> Afanasyev </PERSON> said. He opted for water and glasnost, saying the <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION>'s openness policy was a precondition for manufacturing enough `` tea, sugar and everything else'' to meet demand. In a speech last week to the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s policy-making <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> acknowledged his reforms had failed to improve the average citizen's economic lot, and admitted what most shopgoers already know from bitter experience: Shortages of consumer goods are not shrinking under perestroika, but growing. `` The food problem is far from solved,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said on April 25. `` The housing problem is acute. There is a dearth of consumer goods in the shops. The list of shortages is growing. The state's financial position is grave. The Soviet leader blamed runaway government spending, people who `` forgot how to work'' and top government and party organs _ including the ruling Politburo, which he heads _ for failing to keep up with the tasks confronting them. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and other top officials have rejected calls to spend more dollars earned abroad through the sale of Soviet oil and other exports to buy consumer goods, saying the money should be spent to modernize Soviet industry so more better-quality goods can be made locally. But last month, Deputy Trade Minister <PERSON> Suran </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarukhanov </PERSON> told a Soviet weekly that the equivalent of $ 8 billion had been added to a $ 32.1 billion fund for imports of consumer goods, and that the <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION> would buy 15 million pairs of shoes, 300 million razor blades, detergent, soap and other goods abroad to parry chronc shortages. Pravda, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> daily newspaper, said the persistent deficits of consumer goods were why people in <LOCATION> Ufa </LOCATION> believed rumors that salt would be in short supply. In the resulting stampede to the stores, salt purchases recently skyrocketed from the city's average of 10 tons per day to 250 tons in 36 hours, the paper said A boom in the sale of matches drove daily demand from the customary 157,000 boxes to as many as 2 million, Pravda said. Twenty-six residents of the <LOCATION> Krasnoyarsk </LOCATION> region of <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION> who wrote Pravda might well envy the people of <LOCATION> Ufa </LOCATION>. The Siberians are forced to bring meat to their village store in exchange for goods, they wrote, and in such quantities `` that for a family of 3-4 people to get shoes and clothe itself, it needs to give 4-5 cows.'' A sweatshirt costs 220 pounds of meat, they said. Pravda said money originally earmarked for heavy industry, traditionally the priority sector in the Soviet economy, should be diverted to help meet consumer demand `` and turn the wheel of economics towards the social sphere.'' But a group of economists and journalists writing in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> News said less government interference, and not more, was the right recipe. The group, called `` Against Inflation,'' said the country was in the grip of an `` inflationary crisis.'' Economists have projected the Soviet budget deficit, acknowledged for the first time last fall after years of secrecy, will reach $ 162 billion in 1989. `` Against Inflation'' said government control over prices should be gradually lifted, and the mechanism halted that provides automatic increases in pensions and subsidies as consumer goods become more expensive. It also called the <LOCATION> Gosplan </LOCATION> state planning agency and <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> the greatest danger to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms `` What awaits us if the present fiscal and economic policy will continue?'' the group asked. `` First of all, a total rationing system for food. Already today, trade is literally breaking apart under our very eyes.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0251EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Duarte     05-05 0914</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Duarte,0940</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dying President Hangs on for Succession</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Exhausted by cancer, calamity and revolution, President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> struggles to survive and complete what may be his greatest victory _ peacefully handing power to an elected successor. On June 1, <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> will hand the presidential sash to President-elect <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> of the right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION>. An adviser said the president `` feels ambivalent, because he began by taking power away from the oligarchy and now it may seem he's handing it back.'' Although the transfer may be peaceful, it will occur in an atmosphere of civil war, killings by death squads and political assassinations. <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> spent the past week in bed under an oxygen tent, wasted by dehydration from vomiting and diarrhea caused by chemotherapy for terminal liver cancer. He was strong enough Thursday, however, to rise and receive the credentials of the new Argentine ambassador. The president appeared gaunt and stroked his aching throat repeatedly. He spoke hoarsely but lucidly for 15 minutes, occasionally sipping water because of mouth ulcers caused by the chemotherapy. `` My government has laid the foundation for democracy in this country. I have created here a new concept of politics,'' <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> said, and cited as his greatest disappointment `` not being able to leave the country in a process of peace.'' He is given little chance of reaching his 64th birthday in November. The former engineer probably will be remembered for a critical role in gradual and difficult transition from authoritarianism to democracy, but he approaches the end of his term and life burdened by failures and compromises. <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> feels he is largely responsible for conditions that make the peaceful succession possible and sees it as a crowning achievement. He also considers <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON>'s party, known as <PERSON> Arena </PERSON>, an authoritarian, anti-democratic movement that may erode gains in human rights and civil liberties. <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> said in an interview with foreign correspondents: `` One must acknowledge President <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s democratic vocation. He has ... promoted democracy, but I would n't go so far as to call him the father of <LOCATION> Salvadoran </LOCATION> democracy.'' Since terminal cancer was diagnosed last June, <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> has made periodic trips to <ORGANIZATION> Walter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for treatment. With rest and intravenous nourishment, he has been able to overcome previous chemotherapy and return to government. His doctor, <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Saca </PERSON>, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> the most recent treatments have been particularly devastating but he is optimistic <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> will recover sufficiently to take part in the June 1 ceremony. During <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s five-year term freedom of expression and labor union pluralism have expanded, politically motivated murder has declined and <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> has held three nationwide elections judged free and fair by international observers. His main goals of ending the war and reviving a moribund economy, however, remain as distant as when he took office. Leftist guerrillas have fought U.S.-backed governments for nine years. They continue to dominate much of the north and east despite more than $ 3.5 billion in economic and military aid from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Security forces outnumber the 7,000 insurgents 8-1, but rebels have demonstrated the capacity to attack major garrisons and keep the army on the defensive in much of the country. Recently, in addition to murders in death-squad style, the attorney general was assassinated and wholesale roundups of leftists have been conducted. The home of the vice president-elect was bombed. Attacks on prominent individuals appear designed to provoke or undermine <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON>. Arena and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials blame the <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, the guerrilla alliance, but the rebels have not made targets of high officials in the past. They normally claim responsibility for attacks and have not done so in these cases. <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>'s economy is a shambles and the country would be virtually bankrupt without aid. Private investment, living standards and production of coffee, sugar and cotton, the main export crops, have declined drastically. Health care, potable water and primary education are little more than dreams to most rural people. Corruption and nepotism in <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s administration are described as widespread or rampant, depending on who makes the assessment. The judiciary is ineffective. While death-squad activity has declined, political murder continues. In his state-of-the-nation address last year, <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> said: `` The will of my people has caused me to navigate seas each day more stormy and more dangerous because of crosscurrents. The absence of fair winds and persistent adversity all along the route have joined to prevent us from bringing about our high aims.'' A ranking <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomat said <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> `` did n't work miracles, so he has taken a lot of knocks, some fair and some not. ... He merged the party and the government and surrounded himself with some unscrupulous people, but he must be credited with instituting the democratic system itself. His great legacy is this transition.'' The Rev. <PERSON> Ignacio </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellacuria </PERSON>, rector of <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, criticized <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> for presiding over a military junta in 1981-82, when death squads and the military were blamed killing up to 700 alleged leftists a month. `` <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> accepted thousands of murders with the facile argument that, if he were not -LRB- on the junta -RRB-, there would be more,'' <PERSON> Ellacuria </PERSON> said. He agreed that <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> had fostered `` formal democratic liberties,'' but added: `` He never realized what little real power he had. He's not a false man, but ... self-deceived. His hands were completely tied by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the armed forces.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0253EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-North-Chronology     05-05 1123</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North-Chronology,1224</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chronology of Events in the Case Against Oliver North</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-North, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a chronology of key events in the <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> Iran-Contra case dating from his indictment in March 1988. 1988 = March 16 _ North, former national security adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>, former Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Iranian-American </LOCATION> arms dealer <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> are indicted on charges including conspiracy to divert Iranian arms-sales profits to the Contras March 18 _ North announces his retirement from the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>, says he may subpoena `` the highest ranking officials in our government.'' June 6 _ <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> orders separate trials for the four defendants; independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>, the next day, says <PERSON> North </PERSON> will go first. Nov. 7 _ One of 16 criminal counts against <PERSON> North </PERSON>, fabricating a document, is dismissed. Nov. 21 _ <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> says that if <PERSON> North </PERSON> stands trial, the court will have little control over the testimony of witnesses `` acquainted with high security matters.'' He appeals to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to decide whether the government will allow the trial to take place. Nov. 29 _ <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> refuses to dismiss two of the central charges against <PERSON> North </PERSON>, conspiracy to defraud the government and theft of government property. He dismisses one, wire fraud. Dec. 1 _ <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> rules out a <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> pardon but says `` duty requires'' his administration to block release of secret documents <PERSON> North </PERSON> wants for his trial. Dec. 12 _ <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> tells <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> he ca n't use 3,500 secret documents, that he can use e than 300, roughly the same number planned to be introduced by the prosecutionajor obstacle to the trial going forward. Dec. 30 _ North subpoenas <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as defense witnesses. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON>, after <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is sworn in the following month, rules that the sitting president wo n't be clled. He postpones a decision regarding <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>1989</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Jan. 5 _ Prosecutors ask <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> to dismiss conspiracy and theft charges, citing <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s `` insistence on introducing classified information in his defense'' and the Reagaadministration's refusal to release material the judge ruled <PERSON> North </PERSON> would need. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> later dismisses those conts. Twelve felony counts remain, includingin 1985 and 1986 about his effoehalf of the Contras and lying to the attorney general about the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>'s role in divertingy from the <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> arms sales. He also is accused of illegally accepting a $ 13,800 security system at his home from co-defend <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>, converting to his own use at least $ 4,300 in traveler's checks from <LOCATION> Contra </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Calero </PERSON>, and conspiring to dethe government of tax revenue bsing a tax-exempt foundation to funnel money to the Contras. y selection begins. Feb. 8 _ The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> interrupts <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s trial, urging new safeguards to prevent him from making surprise disclosures of classified information. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> denies the request. Feb. 9 _ A jury of nine women and three men is selected. Feb. 10 _ The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> seeks again to delay <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s trial A federal appeal court panel denies the request. Feb. 12 _ Chief Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> grants a delay until the full <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> can consider the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s objections to the release of classified material by <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s defense Feb. 15 _ The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> issues guidelines designed to guard against disclosure of certain classified material by <PERSON> North </PERSON>. Feb. 16 _ The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> lifts its stay. Feb. 21 _ The trial opens with prosecutor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Keker </PERSON> portraying <PERSON> North </PERSON> as a l who `` places himself above the' and defense lawyer <PERSON> Brendan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> calling him a patriotic Marine who obeyed the orders of r-in-chief. March 8 _ Fund-raiser <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Channell </PERSON> testifies that <PERSON> North </PERSON> once said of his work for the Contras: `` I do n't care if I have to go for this; I do n't care if I havo lie to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.'' March 15 _ Former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> Adviser <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> McFne </PERSON> testifies that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> approved a secret arrangement under which <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> got military aid for supporting the Contras, and that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> telephoned <LOCATION> Honduran </LOCATION> president <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Suazo </PERSON>. <PERSON> Matant </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinette </PERSON> testifies that <PERSON> North </PERSON> let co-defendant <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> pay for a security fence at hhome and then tried to cover up the deal after he left the White House. March 23 _ <PERSON> Fawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s secretary at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, tearfy testifies that he was a tireless and selfless boss and their shredding of Iran-Contra documen no big deal.'' March 28 _ Former Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Me </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> testifies administration officials were worried about impe of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> after they discovered the Iran-Contra link. March 31 _ <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> rejects <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s request that he order <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to testify, saying there is no proof the former president authorizh to commit crimes. April 3 _ Former National Security <PERSON> Coun </PERSON> <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Cannistraro </PERSON> quotes the late <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> as saying <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> designated North to handle the Contra's milit in the event of a congressionaS. aid. April 6 _ The defense introduces an admission of facts, agreed to the government, stating that <PERSON> Geoice </PERSON> president, met with <LOCATION> Honduran </LOCATION> president <PERSON> Suazo </PERSON> to tell him of expedited aid. ument says the aid was in returnas' help to the Contras. <PERSON> North </PERSON> takes the stand, saying he was merely a <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> following White House orders. April 7 _ North concedes he lied to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligenmittee </ORGANIZATION> at an Aug. 6, 1986, meeting at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> at which oviding assistance to the Contras. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> refuses rpeatedly to answer questions about the statement of facts. il 12 _ North testifies he thought he was protecting President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> when he antra memos beforJustice Department could get a look at them. April 13 _ North leaves the stand; the defense rests. April 14 _ Testimony ends after 48 witnesses and nearly 11 weeks. April 18 _ Prosecutor <PERSON> Keker </PERSON>, in a hard-hitting summation, says, `` North andere following <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s old strategy, which is the victor will never be asked if he told the truth.'' April 19 _ In an emotional closing argument, <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> says Nortamb'' in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> White House and was fired to spare the former president political harm. 20 _ <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> instructs the jurors to consider <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s assertion that all his actions were directed by higher-ups, including <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, only if he was given `` clear, direct instructions to act at a given time in a given way. ` <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> tells reporters at the White House that `` my conscience is clear'' about the Iran-Contra affair April 21 _ The jury begins deliberations. May 4 _ North is convicted of falsifying and desting documents, accepting an illegal gratuity and aiding and abetting in obstruction of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. He was acquitted of five other charges of lying to or obstructing <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, of lying to then-Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, of converting traveler's checks to his own use and of conspiring to defraud the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0256EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NorthTrial-Thumbnails     05-05 0834</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North Trial-Thumbnails,0854</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Key Figures in the Iran-Contra Affair</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-North, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thumbnail sketches of key figures in the Iran-Contra arms affair: <PERSON> RONALD </PERSON> <PERSON> REAGAN </PERSON> _ The 78-year-old former president contends he was kept in the dark about the diversion of profits from the arms sales to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to help the Contra rebels in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. Defense efforts to compel <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to testify in the trial of <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> failed. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON>, a former national security adviser to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, has testified that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> personally approved a secret deal to slip $ 110 million in extra aid to <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> as one of several arrangements with other countries to gain support for the Contras. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who called <PERSON> North </PERSON> and told him he was a hero on the same day <PERSON> North </PERSON> was fired from his <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> job, is now living in retirement in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. <PERSON> GEORGE </PERSON> <PERSON> BUSH </PERSON> _ The president has repeatedly refused to discuss his participation in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's secret arms deals. Documents released at the North trial said then-Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> met with the president of <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> in 1985 to inform him of stepped-up <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has denied ever knowing that money from the sale of arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> was diverted to help the Nicaraguan rebels. After the details of the affair broke in late 1986, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` I was not aware of _ and oppose _ any diversion of funds, any ransom payments or any circumvention of the will of the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> OLIVER </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> NORTH </PERSON> _ The retired <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> lieutenant colonel and former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> aide stood trial on 12 felony charges in the Iran-Contra affair. Indicted in March 1988 with three co-defendants, <PERSON> North </PERSON> was tried first. North, 45, supervised the arms shipments to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and coordinated aid to the Contras in 1985-86 when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had barred <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government help for the rebels. He went to <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> in May 1986 on an unsuccessful arms-for-hostages mission. He was a boxing champion at the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> and was decorated for valor during the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> war. North was convicted of falsifying and destroying documents, accepting an illegal gratuity and aiding and abetting in obstruction of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. He was acquitted of five other charges of lying to or obstructing <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, of lying to then-Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, of converting traveler's checks to his own use and of conspiring to defraud the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> ROBERT </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> MCFARLANE </PERSON> _ The former <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> national security adviser pleaded guilty to four misdemeanor charges of withholding information from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and on March 3 <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> was fined $ 20,000, put on two years probation and ordered to perfo00 hours of community service. The son of a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> congressman, <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON>, 51, val Academy graduate and former <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> officer who was national security advise3 to 1985. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> brought a Bible signed by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and a cake shaa key to <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> with the arms shipment in 1986 that he and <PERSON> North </PERSON> hoped to exchange for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hostages. He attempted suicide in <PERSON> JOHN </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> POINDEXTER </PERSON> _ A retired rear admiral, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> was <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON>'s assistant and successor at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> served as <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s national security adviser from December o November 1986, when he quit as the affair was made public <PERSON> Heill </PERSON> stand trial later this year. ter, 52, was a career <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> man d at the top of his <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> class in 1958 and went on to earn a Ph.D. in nuclear physics from the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> His wife, <PERSON> Linda </PERSON>, is an Episcopal priest. <PERSON> RICHARD </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> SECORD </PERSON> _ <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>, 56, is a retired <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> major general turned arms merchant. He is a <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> graduate who flew combat missions in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and ran bombing missions for the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION>. The taint of association with ex-CIA agent <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, later convicted of selling weapons to <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, led <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> to end a long, adventurous military career in 1983and open a business with <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> called <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trading </ORGANIZATION>. When <PERSON> North </PERSON> said he felt his life in jeopardy from terrorists, <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> paid for a $ 13,800 security fence around the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> home in <LOCATION> McLean </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> ALBERT </PERSON> <PERSON> HAKIM </PERSON> _ <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> is an <LOCATION> Iranian-American </LOCATION> businessman who fled his native country and became a naturalized American citizen after the <PERSON> shah </PERSON> was forced from his throne in 1978 He had met <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> in the mid-1970s in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON>, 52, traveled the world from his base in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gatos </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and was considered the money man who handled the accounts and financial arrangements with the Contras. <ORGANIZATION> FAWN </ORGANIZATION> HALL _ <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s former secretary is co-host with former baseball star <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Garvey </PERSON> of a syndicated television show, `` Tickets to a Dream,'' and is writing her memoirs, according to her agent. She testified under immumity that she helped <PERSON> North </PERSON> destroy documents and sneaked other papers out of the White House. Hall, 29, went to work as a secretary for the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> after high school graduation in 1977, and became <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s personal secretary at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> in 1983. She also was a part-time model.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-KoopRetires Bjt   05-05 0685</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Koop Retires, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Goodbye to the Stern Family Doctor with the Amish Farmer's Beard</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 His critics pictured Surgeon General <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> as a national kook when he arrived in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Now, as he prepares to leave, he has a reputation as a national scold. For seven years, <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>, the stern family doctor with an Amish farmer's beard, wagged a finger and preached good health practices in direct language that made people squirm. He came to office under suspicion from liberals for his impassioned anti-abortion views, for calling women `` girls'' and for telling graduating high school seniors that motherhood completed the `` whole vocation'' of being a woman. By the time he announced on Thursday that he will retire this summer, he had pacified liberals and gained a fresh set of critics among conservatives. <PERSON> Urvashi </PERSON> <PERSON> Vaid </PERSON>, a spokesman for the National Gay and <ORGANIZATION> Lesbian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Task </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> helped educated the country by having `` carved out a moderate, consensus position on AIDS.'' But <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>'s views antagonized such conservative activists as <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Schlafly </PERSON> and March for Life leader <PERSON> Nellie </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Schlafly </PERSON> recoiled from <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>'s if-you-must-have-sex, use-condoms views on AIDS and concluded that <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> had become indifferent to promiscuity. Liberal Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, D-Calif., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on health and the environment, said he had been dead wrong in 1981 when he said, `` Dr. <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> scares me He is a man of tremendous intolerance.'' `` One of the great surprises of the last eight years is how wrong I was,'' <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> said Thursday. `` If they could find a clone of <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>, they ought to appoint him -LRB- as successor -RRB-.'' And Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., a leader in the liberals' unsuccessful nine-month fight to block <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>'s confirmation, said <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> had turned out to be `` perhaps the best surgeon general ever The office gives its occupant the right to wear a uniform as head of the 7,200-member commissioned corps of the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, but not much statutory authority. An ability to persuade is the chief source of his power. At that, the 72-year-old <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> _ with a square-shouldered presence and the voice of a prophet _ excelled. He was frequently on television talk shows, attaining celebrity status. In office, he: _ Issued a surgeon general's report that told smokers they were addicts, as hooked on nicotine as dopeheads are on cocaine While drugs kill 12,000 people a year and alcohol may lead to 125,000 deaths a year, he said, `` My enemy kills 350,000.'' _ Wrote and mailed to every household in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> a pamphlet on AIDS which described in frank terms how the disease is acquired but drew no moral conclusions Mrs. <PERSON> Schlafly </PERSON> said <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>'s report did not make enough of a distinction between the use of condoms and abstinence from out-of-wedlock sexual behavior. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, then secretary of education, took issue with <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>'s recommendation that sex education and AIDS education start with young children. _ Jarred conservatives by refusing to issue a report requested by then-President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on abortion's psychological effects on women He said the evidence was too sparse `` to reach scientifically sound conclusions.'' Abortion foes hoped such a report would help persuade the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> to overturn <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON>. An irked <PERSON> Nellie </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> said it was time for <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> to retire. <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>'s decisions surprised all sides in the abortion argument because he had come to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> as a passionate evangelical Christian known for praying at the bedside of his young patients and for traveling the country denouncing abortion as the first step on a path `` to infanticide, to passive euthanasia, to active euthanasia, indeed to the very beginnings of the political climate that led to <LOCATION> Auschwitz </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Dachau </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Belsen </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> had been a distinguised pioneer in pediatric surgery, reversing the 95 percent mortality rate on many surgical proceredures performed on newborns. In one celebrated case, he supervised a 23-member surgical team in an 11 -LCB- - hour operation that successfully separated 13-month-old Siamese twin girls He also got rid of X-ray machines in shoe stores that used to measure children's feet and expose them to harmful radiation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0301EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NorthTrial-Jurors     05-05 0674</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North Trial-Jurors,0685</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Jurors in the Oliver North Trail</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-North, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thumbnail sketches of the jurors in the <LOCATION> Oliver </LOCATION> <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Iran-Contra </LOCATION> trial, along with some of their comments when they were questioned by judge and lawyers before the trial began: <PERSON> DENISE </PERSON> <PERSON> ANDERSON </PERSON> _ 34, foreman of the jury and a clerical worker at a hospital. She lives with her mother whom she refers to as `` news media'' because she likes to watch the news. Ms. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, on the other hand, said `` I do n't like the news'' and when her mother comes to her room to discuss current events, `` I always tell her to get out.'' <PERSON> JEAN </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> JOHNSON </PERSON> _ 53, a cashier with a 12th grade education and a husband who is disabled. She suffers from high blood pressure and several times during jury deliberations complained of not feeling well. During the trial, her aunt died, prompting the judge to declare a one-day recess. She has a son who is a deliveryman for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. North lawyer <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, who lodged objections to selection of almost all of the prospective jurors, objected to her being included because she had read headlines and was therefore exposed to <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s 1987 congressional testimony. <PERSON> JUSTINE </PERSON> <PERSON> NEWELL </PERSON> <PERSON> PARRISH </PERSON> _ 39, worked for the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> 21 years and said the only thing she heard before the trial about <PERSON> North </PERSON> was that he was `` selling weapons to the overseas people.'' <PERSON> DEBORAH </PERSON> <PERSON> GRAY </PERSON> <PERSON> BELL </PERSON> _ 37, a statistician for the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> who said that when she reads the paper, she focuses on the comics or the horoscope and that `` I really was n't interested'' in North's nationally televised congressional testimony in 1987 <PERSON> ERNEST </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> NELSON </PERSON> _ 29, an electronics technician who works for <ORGANIZATION> MCI </ORGANIZATION> and installs and maintains long-distance communications lines. Regarding the Iran-Contra affair and <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s congressional testimony, he said that between headlines and TV `` I ca n't help but see it,'' but did n't follow it. Enjoys playing basketball when he is n't working. <PERSON> LISA </PERSON> <PERSON> KRISHAWN </PERSON> <PERSON> BROOKS </PERSON> _ 21, a clerk typist at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION>, said `` the front page is the last thing I look at,'' and that she changes channels when the news is on television. At the time <PERSON> North </PERSON> was testifying on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> in 1987, she said, she was going to clerk-typist school by day and working in the evening. All she remembered of <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s congressional appearance was `` something about a woman.'' <PERSON> PATRICIA </PERSON> <PERSON> BENNETT </PERSON> _ 39, an unemployed former office manager of an advertising firm. She said she thinks she heard that <PERSON> North </PERSON> was `` selling something to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>,'' recalled something about shredding, and that she saw him on television `` going in and out of buildings'' but did n't watch any of his congressional testimony in 1987. `` It did n't interest me that much.'' North's attorneys objected to her selection, saying she read the paper and `` could not miss headlines.'' <PERSON> CASWELL </PERSON> <PERSON> GILBERT </PERSON> <PERSON> HARTRIDGE </PERSON> _ 61, a tow-truck driver who said that in connection with <PERSON> North </PERSON> and the Iran-Contra affair, `` whatever I heard I did n't understand.'' BEVERLY TURNER _ 37, a typist in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> chaplains' office at the Pentagon who worked for the government 17 -LCB- years. She said she knows only that <PERSON> North </PERSON> is `` the head of soldiers that went to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> or something like that.'' <PERSON> HELEN </PERSON> <PERSON> GINA </PERSON> <PERSON> LYNCH </PERSON> _ 37, a pathology lab technician at <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. She said she heard that <PERSON> North </PERSON> `` shredded some papers ... that's all I know.'' Her husband is a mental health counselor at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elizabeths </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> EARL </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> WILLIAMS </PERSON> _ 64, unemployed, served in <PERSON> Patton </PERSON>'s 3rd Army in World War II. His last job was as a security guard and he formerly was a messenger for the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. He said `` I sure would try'' to be fair to <PERSON> North </PERSON> and that his knowledge was limited to seeing <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s picture on the front page of the newspaper. <PERSON> TARA </PERSON> <PERSON> LEIGH </PERSON> <PERSON> KING </PERSON> _ 34, a <ORGANIZATION> Xerox </ORGANIZATION> operator who said `` I do n't remember'' anything about <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s nationally televised appearance in which he gave immunized testimony to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Soviet Bjt   05-05 0545</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Soviet, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baker: Soviet Promises Must Be Tested</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, offering the broadest view yet of how the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration will deal with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, says the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> plans to test <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> `` again and again'' to see whether it will live up to its promises of reform. `` By testing <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> across the board ... we can see whether the ` new thinking' is real once we get beyond the slogans,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said in a speech on Thursday to the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> departs Monday for his first round of talks with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. At the May 10-11 session, they are expected to set a date for the resumption of negotiations to reduce long-range nuclear missiles and make preliminary arrangements for a summit between <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The trip comes amid a dispute in the <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> alliance as the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> struggles with its allies about forging a strategy to deal with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s arms control initiatives. A senior administration official, speaking with reporters about the speech on condition he not be identified, said <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s speech Thursday was intended as a `` conceptual framework'' for the superpower relationship. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said it is n't clear yet whether <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will be successful with his `` perestroika,'' or `` new thinking'' on matters of democratization and reform. And, he complained, much of the Soviet rhetoric does n't match Soviet deeds. As an example, he cited Soviet actions in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, `` where the Soviets sent over $ 500 million in aid to the Sandinistas last year.'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> applauded moves such as the withdrawal of troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and the agreement banning all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet intermediate-range nuclear missiles in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. But he complained about Soviet shipments of long-range bombers to <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Khadafy </PERSON>, Soviet military support of militant <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and the Soviet occupation of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s Northern Territories. Taking note of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s offers to make unilateral troop reductions and make cuts in his defense budget, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> also said some 3,500 new Soviet tanks continue to roll off the production lines. The secretary faulted the Soviets for failing to publish `` a real defense budget,'' one that would allow an independent evaluation of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s pledge to slash his military spending by 14 percent. He complained that while there has been talk of a `` common European home,'' the Berlin Wall still stands and the <ORGANIZATION> Brezhnev </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Doctrine </ORGANIZATION>, which affirms the right to send Soviet troops into other East European countries, has not been repealed. The speech marked the most detailed exposition yet of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's emerging policy toward the Soviets, after a lengthy review that some critics say has stalled progress on arms negotiations. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who has defended the review as part of a `` prudent'' transition from the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, plans to outline his views in a series of upcoming university commencement speeches, the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> said this week. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said he intends to use the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> visit to broaden the U.S.-Soviet agenda to include issues such as terrorism, the environment and drug abuse. `` Our policy must be to press forward with our agenda, to test the application of Soviet ` new thinking' again and again,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HamonRide Bjt   05-05 0621</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ham on Ride, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Subway Operators Get Frowns From Bosses, Laughs From Commuters</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Welcome aboard <ORGANIZATION> Metro </ORGANIZATION>. Sorry we do n't serve coffee and doughnuts.'' That cheery greeting from a <ORGANIZATION> Metro </ORGANIZATION> subway operator, booming from his train's public address speakers one recent Monday morning, drew rueful smiles from suburban commuters lurching shoulder-to-shoulder toward the start of another week in their downtown offices. Shove a microphone in front of some people and they ca n't resist hamming it up. There's something about an open mike in the front cab of a commuter train, pulling a captive audience of several hundred passengers, that tempts subway operators to become amateur comedians and tour guides. Officials of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s 70-mile <ORGANIZATION> Metro </ORGANIZATION> subway system frown on this light-hearted ad-libbing, but most passengers seem to enjoy it. `` Welcome, all first-time riders and visitors to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>,'' said one operator as his train swooped down from the <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> river bank toward the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. `` You are now 35 feet below the <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, so hold your breath!'' Another: `` The next station is <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION>, home of the world's largest flying dinosaur. Passengers laughed and applauded when another announced the train's approach to <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and _ his voice dropping to an ominous <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> Karloff </PERSON> bass _ `` FOG-GY BOT-TOM.'' One operator on the Yellow Line route heading south across the wide <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION> notes that `` this is NOT the place where <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON> threw the dollar across the river.'' He points out the Jefferson Memorial's cherry blossoms and the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- `` the world's biggest office building'' -RRB-, and tells bad jokes all the way into suburban <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>. When his train suddenly filled up with boisterous teen-age tourists, one operator made his customary announcement that `` the doors will openon the right'' at the next station's platform. Then he added: `` For tourists, the doors will open on the left.'' <ORGANIZATION> Metro </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Bucklew </PERSON> says that among the transit system's 345 subway operators who haul passengers on more than 500,000 trips each day, only a handful of those at the controls indulge in good-humored patter. They get a mixed reaction from passengers, she said. Most complaints come from people who, `` if they've had a rough day _ or plan to have one _ a little humor might hit them the wrong way,'' Ms. <PERSON> Bucklew </PERSON> said. `` It's like art,'' she said. `` Some people find it entertaining, others find it irritating. We ask the operators to stick to the script, so to speak.'' The 10-week training course for new subway operators includes three days of special coaching, with rehearsals using tape recorders, on making a few standard announcements over their microphones. These include identifying which line the train is traveling _ Orange, <ORGANIZATION> Blue </ORGANIZATION>, Red or Yellow _ and its final destination, giving the correct name of each approaching station and noting whether the doors will open on the right or left, plus occasional safety reminders. `` We neither encourage nor condone going off on their own as comics or tour guides,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Winn </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Metro </ORGANIZATION>'s acting general superintendent for rail operator training. But operators are n't reprimanded unless their off-the-cuff remarks are rude, vulgar or inappropriate. <ORGANIZATION> Metro </ORGANIZATION> officials say many tourists appreciate being told which station is close to the sights they want to see. Only one operator, accused of `` just being too exuberant,'' has ever been admonished to tone down his act, Ms. <PERSON> Bucklew </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hezekiah </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Briscoe </PERSON>, an 11-year <ORGANIZATION> Metro </ORGANIZATION> veteran as subway operator and training supervisor, says he plays the straight man while he's behind his train's controls But he does n't mind when his colleagues try to lighten their passengers' load. `` Sometimes a little humor goes a long way,'' he said, `` especially when it's Friday afternoon.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0307EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NorthTrial-Evidence 2Takes   05-05 0840</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North Trial-Evidence, 2 Takes,0870</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-North Trial, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a summary of evidence in the trial of <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> and the disposition of each charge: Counts 1-4: Obstruction and making false statements in September and October 1985 in connection with letters to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> denying that the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> staff was assisting the Contras. Count 1, obstruction. Not guilty: Former National Security Adviser <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> testified that <PERSON> North </PERSON> was the source of false information in the letters. But <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> blamed himself, not <PERSON> North </PERSON>, saying the aide `` was probably trying to protect me.'' <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> signed the letters and later pleaded guilty to withholding information from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> North </PERSON> testified that he unsuccessfully sought to have the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration invoke executive privilege and refuse to answer the congressional inquiries. The letter to then-House <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> said that `` we did not solicit funds or other support. ... We did not offer tactical advice'' to the Contras. A fund-raiser for the Contras, <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> `` Spitz'' <PERSON> Channell </PERSON>, testified that on Sept. 11, 1985, <PERSON> North </PERSON>, after describing the rebels' military needs, told billionaire <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Bunker </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON>, `` I do n't care if I have to go to jail for this. I do n't care if I have to lie to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> about this.'' Hunt later contributed more than half a million dollars to the Contra cause. The conversation was six days after the letter to <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> and a day before another false letter was sent to then-Rep. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> denying the <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION> was assisting the Contras North testified he never solicited money for the Contras, that instead he gave numerous talks to prospective donors and then would leave before <PERSON> Channell </PERSON> asked for money.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Count 2, false statements to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in connection with the Sept. 5, 1985, letter to <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>. Not guilty: <PERSON> North </PERSON> testified he prepared only two innocuous paragraphs of the letter to <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>. North acknowledged under cross-examination that he edited the letter but said he had no authority to make substantive changes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Count 3, false statements to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in connection with the Sept. 12, 1985, letter to <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON>. Not guilty: <PERSON> North </PERSON> testified he had nothing to do with the <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> letter. An <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent testified that a draft of the response to <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> was found in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>'s office.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Count 4, false statements to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in connection with a letter responding to congressional followup questions from <LOCATION> Hamilton </LOCATION> on Oct. 7, 1985. Not guilty: <PERSON> North </PERSON> testified that his answers were based on information <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> provided. A note by the <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION>'s legal counsel said that <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> was taking complete charge of the job of responding to the inquiries. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>, the liaison between <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> and a private fund-raising operation for the Contras, testified that <PERSON> North </PERSON> voiced irritation in a meeting in the fall of 1985 about having to answer `` asinine questions'' from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Count 5, obstructing a proposed congressional inquiry on Aug. 6, 1986, by denying giving military advice to the Contras. Not guilty: <PERSON> North </PERSON> admitted he told lies in his meeting with the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. After the meeting, then-National Security Adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> sent him a note saying, `` Well done.'' <PERSON> North </PERSON> said he told <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> beforehand it would be unwise to meet with the committee but that <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> insisted he do so. The key question was whether <PERSON> North </PERSON> lied to prevent a pending resolution of inquiry into the Contra matter from passing in the House. Only sketchy notes were taken at the meeting in the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, and no transcript was kept. The judge told the jury to note that `` there is conflicting evidence as to whether or not the resolution was or was not pending'' and that jurors had to decide whether the meeting with <PERSON> North </PERSON> was designed to gather material for the resolution.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Count 6, aiding and abetting obstruction of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in November 1986 in the preparation of a false and misleading chronology saying that no one in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government knew until January 1986 that a CIA-assisted shipment from <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in November 1985 contained Hawk missiles. Guilty: The jury found North not guilty on the charge of obstruction of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in this count, but then found him guilty of the subsidiary charge of aiding and abetting that obstruction. Testifying in his own defense, <PERSON> North </PERSON> blamed <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON>, who by November 1986 had been out of the government for a year, for formulating the false chronology. North also testified that <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and then-CIA Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> knew that missiles were aboard the plane and that other top <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials knew because intelligence agencies tracked the shipment hour-by-hour. Despite that, he said, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> helped prepare false testimony for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> saying that no one in the government knew the true cargo until January 1986. North testified that it was necessary to maintain a false cover story about the shipment in order to protect the lives of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hostages held in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The Iranians were not satisfied with the shipment, and <PERSON> North </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government needed to distance itself from the transaction.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0311EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NorthTrial-Evidence 1stAdd   05-05 0913</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North Trial-Evidence, 1st Add,0937</SECOND>
<BYLINE>WASHINGTON: the transaction.    ___</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Counts 7-8, obstructing a presidential inquiry; making false statements. Not guilty on both counts: When then-Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, at <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s request, questioned <PERSON> North </PERSON> about the diversion of arms profits to the Contras on Nov. 23, 1986, <PERSON> North </PERSON> is accused of telling <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> the <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION> was not involved, that the Israelis determined the amount that went to the Contras and that rebel leader <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Calero </PERSON> had been ordered to open Swiss bank accounts to receive arms profit money from <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> testified <PERSON> North </PERSON> told him those untruths, but under questioning by the defense he agreed he was conducting only an `` administrative inquiry'' and <PERSON> North </PERSON> was under no legal compulsion to answer. The judge's instructions to the jurors said that to convict <PERSON> North </PERSON>, they would have to find that he had been `` correctly informed of the true nature of the proceeding'' and that his specific intent was to obstruct the inquiry. North denied making untrue statements, saying he readily admitted to the attorney general and his aides the diversion of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> arms proceeds to the Contras. The only written records of the attorney general's meeting with <PERSON> North </PERSON> are 29 pages of what <PERSON> North </PERSON> described as `` very cryptic notes'' taken by one of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s aides.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Count 9, destroying, altering or removing documents from the <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION>. Guilty: <PERSON> North </PERSON> said <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> told him to alter five `` problem memos'' <PERSON> North </PERSON> wrote in 1985, to wipe out references of <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s secret assistance to the Contras and <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON>'s knowledge of it. <PERSON> North </PERSON> said he believed <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> wanted the documents changed `` because everything I had done that was described in the documents ... I had been told was at the direction of the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> contradicted <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s testimony, saying it was <PERSON> North </PERSON> who suggested altering the memos in 1985 when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> first inquired about <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s Contra activities. North directed his secretary, <PERSON> Fawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, to make the alterations in November 1986 as the Iran-Contra affair was about to be disclosed. Miss <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> said she shredded the originals without instruction from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>, testifying that `` it seemed the logical thing to do.'' To convict on that count, the jury was told, `` the defendant must have known his conduct was unlawful.'' Asked at the trial whether he knew that, <PERSON> North </PERSON> replied `` No, they were his -LRB- McFarlane's -RRB- documents. It never occurred to me that that would be unlawful.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Count 10, illegally accepting a $ 13,800 home security system from Iran-Contra co-defendant <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>, who <PERSON> North </PERSON> had hired to run arms to the Contras. Guilty: <PERSON> North </PERSON> admitted he never paid for the system, but said he never got a bill for it. He said he did n't know <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> had footed the bill, although it was a meeting with <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> and former <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> employee <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinette </PERSON> that led to the installation. After he was fired from the <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> North </PERSON> admitted he tried to conceal the fact he had n't paid for the system by sending two backdated letters to <PERSON> Robinette </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> said he had gotten the system installed after being targeted for assassination by terrorist <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Nidal </PERSON> and just before <PERSON> North </PERSON> was scheduled to go to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in an attempt to win release of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hostages held in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <PERSON> North </PERSON> said he tried to get the government to protect his home but was turned down because he was n't high-ranking enough.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Count 11, converting traveler's checks to his own use. Not guilty: Contra leader <PERSON> Calero </PERSON> testified he gave $ 90,000 in traveler's checks to <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>, partly to help in securing release of American hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and partly for the Contra aid effort North kept the money in his office safe. The government charged <PERSON> North </PERSON> spent $ 4,300 of it on personal expenses. <PERSON> Calero </PERSON> testified he did n't demand an accounting because `` I would trust him with my life. North denied spending the money on himself, saying he used it to reimburse himself for out-of-pocket expenses connected with his job. The jury was told that to convict <PERSON> North </PERSON>, it would have to find he used the checks `` in a manner not authorized in advance by the owner'' and `` for purposes other than the purpose under which the traveler's checks came into his possession as a government employee.'' In an attempt to bolster its charge, the prosecution brought out that <PERSON> North </PERSON> had paid $ 8,000 in cash in October 1985 for a family car and that until mid-1985 he had complained repeatedly to an <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION> employee about not having enough money to buy lunch and gasoline to get home. North denied dipping into the office-safe fund for personal expenses, saying he bought the car out of a $ 15,000 cash fund he kept in a metal box bolted to his closet floor at home.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Count 12, the only conspiracy count against <PERSON> North </PERSON>, charged he took part in a scheme with fund-raisers <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> and <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Channell </PERSON> to defraud the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> by drumming up funds for the Contras' military effort under the cover of a tax-exempt organization, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endowment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Preservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberty </ORGANIZATION>. Not guilty: North insisted <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> authorized him to brief potential contributors with the stricture `` that I would not say to a single person, ` Would you give me money?' I never did that.'' While he sometimes would explain how much weapons would cost, he could not recall `` a single donor ever giving money in my presence or ... ever asked to give me money in my presence, not one.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890505-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-05-89 0159EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NorthProfile Bjt   05-05 1557</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North Profile, Bjt,1560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Another Scar On the Fractured Image of Oliver North</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE BYRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
