<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 2336EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Kissinger 1stLd-Writethru a0746 09-15 0598</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Kissinger, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0746,0613</SECOND>
<HEAD>ABC Cites Conflict Of Interest in Kissinger News Consultancy</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: RETRANSMITTING to restore writethru sequence; INSERTS 2 grafs
after 7th, `Had ABC ..., to cite Wall Street Journal report on Kissinger's
business ties to China.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAY SHARBUTT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 ABC News would n't have used former Secretary of State <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> as a paid expert on a <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> special last June had it known of his business ties there, a spokeswoman said Friday. However, <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Bremer </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> business associate, said there was no conflict of interest in <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>'s appearance on the broadcast. On it, <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> was asked about possible <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military sanctions against <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> for its violence against the student-led demonstrations in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. In his reply, the former Secretary of State in the <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> administrations stressed the importance of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> relations with the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> regime. `` I would n't do any sanctions,'' he told anchor <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> at the time was appearing under a special agreement with <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> that he terminated Wednesday after his election as a board member of <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> deal, struck in 1982, paid him as a consultant and gave <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> the right to interview him first on any of its broadcasts, including `` World News Tonight'' and <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Koppel </PERSON>'s `` Nightline,'' but only on breaking stories. He was n't paid for appearances as a guest on these shows, including as `` Nightline'' and `` World News Tonight'' when his interviews did n't concern breaking news, said <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Elise </PERSON> <PERSON> Adde </PERSON>. Had ABC News known of his business ties in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, she said, `` we would not have had him on that broadcast'' in June. <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> has extensive business interests in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, including the establishment of a $ 75 million fund to be raised from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> investors for joint ventures with the merchant banking arm of the Chinese government, The Wall Street Journal reported Friday. In addition, his consulting firm <ORGANIZATION> Kissinger </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> counsels several businesses on how to conduct operations overseas and, specifically, in their dealings with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, the Journal reported. <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>'s remarks on the June special were `` not motivated by commercial concerns,'' said <PERSON> Bremer </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> employee for 23 years, now a senior partner in <ORGANIZATION> Kissinger </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, an international consulting firm. <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>'s remarks on issues like the situation in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> last June are solely `` based on what he thinks are the -LRB- <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> -RRB- nation's interest,'' said <PERSON> Bremer </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> deal was not his first with a network news division. He previously had worked for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s news division after after his White House service. Since 1977, he has been a member of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Artists </ORGANIZATION> but under the union's news contract with networks, according union membership rolls. <ORGANIZATION> AFTRA </ORGANIZATION> represents on-air news correspondents and anchors at <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. The news contract and the entertainers' contract stipulate different pay scales. <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> was busy Friday and was not available for comment, <PERSON> Bremer </PERSON> said. His election to the 14-member CBS board was by a unanimous vote, a source election said Friday. CBS policy is not to comment on internal board matters. As a CBS board member, <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> will paid the same as other board members, $ 22,000 annually, and $ 750 for each meeting he attends, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Schweitzer </PERSON> said. There is no contract that would make <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> exclusive to <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, and his board membership `` has absolutely nothing to do with CBS on-air appearances, `` <PERSON> Schweitzer </PERSON> said. `` In that regard,'' he said, referring to news matters, `` he is <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>, private citizen and businessman. And he can be interviewed by anyone.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0012EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Korea-Nuclear     09-15 0277</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Korea-Nuclear,0283</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Reported Concerned North Korea Developing Nuclear Arms</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is `` gravely concerned'' that communist <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> may be developing nuclear weapons, the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> news agency <ORGANIZATION> Yonhap </ORGANIZATION> reported from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Friday. It said the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is keeping a close watch on possible efforts in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> to develop nuclear weapons. <ORGANIZATION> Yonhap </ORGANIZATION> quoted <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, the head of the department's <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> section, as saying <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> would be as concerned as <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> if <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> produced such weapons. Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> is expected to discuss <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s nuclear capability with Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> at a meeting in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> this month, <ORGANIZATION> Yonhap </ORGANIZATION> reported. While denying it has nuclear weapons, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> has repeatedly charged that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces based in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> are equipped with nuclear arms and are preparing for a nuclear war on the divided <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> peninsula. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials reject the North Korean claims. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> keeps about 43,000 troops in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> under a defense pact. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is the North's main arms supplier. Chances are dim for an improvement soon in the strained relations between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> despite diplomatic contacts between the two sides in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, the report quoted <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> as saying. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> demands immediate withdrawal of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> says <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces are vital to prevent a North Korean attack. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> invaded <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> in 1950, setting off the 3-year Korean War. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces intervened on the side of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and fought under the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> banner. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops have remained in the South ever since.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Bhutto'sGoals     09-15 0876</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bhutto's Goals,0901</SECOND>
<HEAD>In Interview, Benazir Bhutto Says She's Fighting Evil in Pakistan</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY GANNON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After 9 -LCB- months as prime minister, <PERSON> Benazir </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> sees herself as a crusader to save <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> from the clutches of drugs, ethnic violence and rancorous politics. `` I see things in terms of knights in shining armor trying to root out evil,'' Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> said in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. `` That may be a sort of simplistic way to put it, but I am an optimist. I have great dreams for my country and I want to achieve them.'' But she acknowledged her vision might be a bit fanciful. `` I think I am too much of an idealist.'' Educated at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Oxford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, the 36-year-old Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> is the first woman to lead a Moslem nation and as she spoke she had a scarf called a `` dupatta'' draped over her shoulder. When in public she wears the scarf over her head _ the custom of Moslem women _ as a concession to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s religious right wing, a powerful minority that opposes female rule. Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> and her left-leaning <ORGANIZATION> Pakistan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> govern a restless nation of 107 million people burdened by poverty, illiteracy and civil war across the border in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. She said death threats after her government declared war on the heroin trade and drug barons have forced her to think of her safety, something she has resisted since assuming office Dec. 2. `` I do n't believe in a life that is crowded with security,'' she said. `` I think it's kind of nice to be able to slip away, ... after having worked hard for a few days to be able to go for a half an hour walk. `` I just consider it important for a person in public life to try and maintain a sense of normalacy _ to have their feet on the ground.'' As for the drug war, she said, `` We are really now just going after the big people, but it's a much bigger problem. It's just proliferated all over the country like a cancer.'' Western countries estimate that up to 80 percent of the heroin arriving in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> comes from <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. Drug addiction in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> has soared from near zero in 1979 to an estimated 1 million addicts in 1989. Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> is also doing battle with an opposition made up of Islamic fundamentalists, conservatives and loyalists of the late president, Gen. <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> <PERSON> ul-Haq </PERSON>, and his military government. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> overthrew her father, Prime Minister <PERSON> Zulfikar </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>, in a 1977 coup and had him hanged two years later for his alleged complicity in a murder plot. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>, many of his top generals and <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Raphel </PERSON> died in a mysterious plane crash in August 1988, clearing the way for <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s first free elections in more than a decade and resulting in Mrs. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>'s election Nov. 16. Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> says the most serious threat to her government is ethnic. Hundreds of Pakistanis have died and thousands have been injured since 1986 in violence in her southern home province of <LOCATION> Sindh </LOCATION> in fighting among militant secessionists, Indian Moslem immigrants and internal migrants from poorer provinces. `` During General <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>'s time ethnic groups became very strong,'' she said. `` They set up armed camps and they trained their people, so it's a situation of almost a mini-kind of a guerrilla war. It's not a guerrilla war against the government, but it's almost a state of anarchy and a rebellion against authority. Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> claims that her right-wing political opposition, the nine-party <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION>, has had a hand in the Sindh violence. She also has implicated neighboring <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> in the Sindh troubles. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> have fought three wars since they became independent from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> in 1947 and they routinely accuse each other of fueling their internal problems. To the west, Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> inherited <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s sponsorship of Moslem guerrillas fighting to oust the Soviet-backed government of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. More than 3 million Afghan war refugees huddle in camps dotting <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s western frontier. `` <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> ca n't afford to keep the refugees,'' she said, `` but are the refugees going to go back without political stability? `` So far we have not seen any message or any method that would enable the emergence of an independent <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> or the return of the Afghan refugees. Those remain our goals.'' She also said her political opposition is doomed because of its links to the <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> era, when <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> was under martial law and political parties were barred from elections. `` <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> just ca n't afford a return to the decade of repression,'' she said. `` All those who are patriots in the different sectors of life, whether it is civilian or military, recognize that. Therefore, I see no imminent threat to democracy in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>.'' But she added that law and order can not survive without economic development in a country where the average yearly wage is under $ 400. `` First you've got to try and create a system, create a rule of law which gives security and, side by side, you've got to have economic improvement and opportunitiees so people can -LRB- give -RRB- better meaning -LRB- to -RRB- their lives,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Maria'sGranddaughter     09-15 0712</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Maria's Granddaughter,0731</SECOND>
<HEAD>Granddaughter Portrays Maria von Trapp in Sound of Music</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSAN ALLEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HYDE PARK, Vt. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As a girl, <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Trapp </PERSON> ran through the hills near her home singing songs from `` The Sound of Music.'' It was n't so much theatrics, though, as family tradition. Now she will fill another family role by stepping onto a stage to portray her grandmother, <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Trapp </PERSON>, whose flight from Nazi-occupied <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> inspired the musical. <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Trapp </PERSON> makes her debut as <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> in a local theater production of the story made famous by the 1965 movie in which <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON> portrayed <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Trapp </PERSON>, the matriarch of the family who died two years ago at age 82. `` I grew up listening to the album with my cousins, and we'd all take parts,'' said <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON>, 35, who learned the tale of the family's flight on her grandmother's knee. `` We used the fields to practice in.'' <PERSON> Trapp </PERSON>, who has sung professionally at the <ORGANIZATION> Trapp </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lodge </ORGANIZATION> in <PERSON> Stowe </PERSON> for three years, also shares the local stage with her 8-year-old cousin <PERSON> Kiersten </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Trapp </PERSON>, cast as another of <PERSON> Maria </PERSON>'s children `` I've seen the movie five zillion times,'' said <PERSON> Kiersten </PERSON>, squirming impatiently during rehearsal and tugging at her hot-pink T-shirt and miniskirt. `` Until I was 7, I thought it was just about nuns.'' Music, which first brought <PERSON> Maria </PERSON>, <PERSON> Baron </PERSON> <PERSON> Georg </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Trapp </PERSON> and his 10 children together as a family during the war, continues to be a shared bond between the younger <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Trapp </PERSON> generation _ as does the family legacy. Six of <PERSON> Maria </PERSON>'s children remain in <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> where the family moved after the escape and their subsequent worldwide tours as the <ORGANIZATION> Trapp </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Singers </ORGANIZATION>, with two others buried in <PERSON> Stowe </PERSON> and two living in other states. <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> said the youngsters would gather around her father, <PERSON> Werner </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Trapp </PERSON>, one of the children who fled <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> a half century ago, and learn folk songs. `` Acting is a whole new challenge,'' said <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON>, standing before a hand-painted set of the Austrian mountains in the Hyde Park Opera House. `` I am so excited. I think my grandmother was that way. She was excited about life. She was n't discouraged about the problems she encountered.'' Today <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> records her own folk songs and designs Austrian clothing for sale at the lodge gift shop. She designed some of the costumes for the local production, which premieres at the end of the month. `` Being a von <PERSON> Trapp </PERSON>, people are so in awe of you and they treat you differently,'' she said. `` When you grow up with it, you live with that everyday. People say, ` So, you are one of THE von Trapps.' `` Everyone remembers our story. It's universal. I've met people at the lodge who went through the same thing, but we had a story written about it,'' she added. <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> likened the current flood of refugees from <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> into <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> to her family's situation years ago. `` It's happening right now, although the direction people are going has changed,'' she said. `` Is n't it ironic that here I am in little <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> playing the part, and yet the exact same thing is happening there.'' <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Trapp </PERSON> attended the <LOCATION> Hyde </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> annual performance six years ago to watch <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> perform a bit-part as a nun. After the performance, the baroness took a bow for the crowd and drew a standing ovation. <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> remembers that her grandmother, who gave up her plans to become a nun to marry the baron, always wore a silver cross on a chain around her neck, and until her final years dressed in Austrian costume. `` There was a charm about her that I really appreciated. She had a great sense of humor, and a great way of telling stories. She'd have us rolling on the floor. `` Everybody is interested in the von <PERSON> Trapps </PERSON> _ they are news,'' said the play's director <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>. `` People visit the lodge, and then come back year after year to see the show.'' <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> said her performance as <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> adds a new twist to the story, however. `` Some of my family members might say it's just rehashing the story, but I'm experiencing new people and challenges. That's what art's all about.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     09-15 0039</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0044</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Thursday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 5-8-5-7.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 15; 18; 20; 28; 32; 35. Bonus: 6-2-7-4-1.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 2-6-0-5.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     09-15 0074</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0077</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 5-8-5-7.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 02; 03; 15; 17; 18; 21.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 15; 18; 20; 28; 32; 35. Bonus: 6-2-7-4-1.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto Game: 05; 17; 34; 37; 48; 53. Supplementary 04.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 2-6-0-5.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 0-4-6; 7-8-6-6; 5-7-3-7-6; 2-5-3-0-6-2.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hungary-BreakingAway     09-15 0853</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hungary-Breaking Away,0880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hungary's Reform Course Opens Cracks in Warsaw Pact</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE JAHN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cracks are opening in the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact as <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s Communist leadership abandons agreements with its military allies in the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> in pursuit of new friends and business ties in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, along with <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, is in the front rank of reform in the Soviet bloc, eclipsing Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s more modest campaigns. Where the Soviets have adjusted their Communist-dominated system to introduce a measure of democracy and personal freedom, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s Communist leadership has pledged to allow free elections by next June that could end the party's 43-year-old hold on power <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> this week installed the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc's first government not led by Communists. Where the Soviets favor reducing central control of industries, sentiment in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> has swung to scrapping all state interference in the economy in favor of market forces. This week, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> enraged <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> hard-liner <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> by allowing thousands of East Germans to cross its border to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. Hungarian officials have been candid about the risks of the country's shift. `` There is a danger of <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> becoming isolated in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> as some of the things <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> is doing irritate our neighbors and allies,'' Foreign Minister <PERSON> Gyula </PERSON> <PERSON> Horn </PERSON> told Hungarian radio Aug. 29. `` Altering our approach, however, would mean curtailing our freedom of action.'' An unprecedented plan announced Sept. 8 to cooperate with neutral <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> and non-aligned <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> in setting up demilitarized zones along common borders is perhaps the clearest sign of a cautious move away from the <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s aspirations extend even farther westward, with leaders knocking on the doors of the 12-nation <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, the world's largest trading bloc. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> already has privileges with the <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> unique within the Soviet bloc. It signed a 10-year agreement with the <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> in June 1988 granting it reduced tariffs on its exports to <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> nations. The accord is the most liberal the <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> has signed with a Soviet bloc country. Hungarian leaders used the recent East German refugee standoff to press their case with <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> for a political voice in the bloc. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> did not go public with a promise to support those wishes. But Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> subsequently said his country will give full backing to <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s economic reforms, and expectations are that West German gratitude over the East German exodus will translate into generous financial aid. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> praised Hungarian reforms during a July visit, and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last week voted to extend by three years instead of the customary one year <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s Most Favored Nation trading status, which offers the best tariff rates. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s leaders say they have Soviet blessings for the increasing independence that is moving them closer to the West, but the reforms are breaking <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> away from some other traditional allies. Relations are worst with <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> because of disputes over the fate of 1.7 million ethnic Hungarians in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> says they are being systematically persecuted, an accusation <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> denies. Tensions exploded after <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> broke an agreement two years ago that had committed it to return those fleeing <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s Stalinist system. Since then, more than 20,000 Romanians, mostly ethnic Hungarians, have found sanctuary in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. Relations hit bottom in July after <PERSON> Horn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s foreign minister, expressed anxiety that the war of words could escalate to violence. <PERSON> Horn </PERSON>, referring to <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s boast in April that it could build nuclear missiles, expressed fears <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> could be a target of such weapons one day. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> gave up all pretense of `` fraternal'' ties with the Romanian military Sept. 7, announcing that <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s deputy defense minister would not visit as planned. Tensions of a different kind have been building on <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s northern border with <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> Because of budgetary and environmental pressures, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> abruptly stopped work in May on a joint <LOCATION> Danube </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> dam project agreed to in 1977. This enraged Czechoslovak partners. The Czechoslovaks accused <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> of breaking their word. The Hungarians said the Czechosklovaks were planning to `` violate international law'' by unilaterally diverting a river that forms part of the countries' common boundary. Growing bitterness over the dam project has been exacerbated by political differences. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s leaders used the Aug 21 anniversary of the 1968 <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact invasion of <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> to denounce the move, which crushed a Czechoslovak reform movement. Polish leaders also criticized the invasion. <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> is the latest to join the chorus of East European critics of the reform-minded Hungarians, its ire raised by <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION>'s decision to open a westward escape route for thousands of East Germans. State-controlled East German media accused <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> of being bought by the West Germans, and the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> filed a formal protest over the action. The Soviet reaction to change in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> has ranged from praise to tolerance. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has pointed to Hungarian economic reforms as examples to inspire Soviet workers, and Hungarian electoral reforms are reported broadly in state-run Soviet media. But <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON> indicated Kremlin reservations about the refugee exodus, describing it as `` unusual.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0044EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Fernald-DOE     09-15 0418</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fernald-DOE,0430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Criticizes Energy U.S. Secretary</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN NOLAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge has lifted his order that would have required Energy Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> to testify on the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s proposed $ 78 million settlement with neighbors of the nuclear weapons plant at <LOCATION> Fernald </LOCATION>. However, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON> also criticized <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> on Wednesday as appearing insensitive to the worries of people who live near the Feed Materials Production Center, a uranium processing plant. `` It's no secret that the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> has estimated that it will cost millions, maybe billions, to clean up the site,'' <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON> said, adding that <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> could have reassured to neighbors concerned about cleanup costs. Several businesses near the plant say they interpret the settlement to mean that they can not sue to recover from the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> any costs of radioactive materials cleanup on private property. The <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> agrees with that assessment, but lawyers for the neighbors disagree. <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON> first invited, then last week ordered, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> to testify on that issue, saying a final word was needed from the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s top official. But <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> lawyers opposed <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON>'s request, saying it was unnecessary and beyond his authority. <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> lawyer <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Stearns </PERSON> said, in papers filed with <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON>, the government would appeal if the judge insisted on compelling testimony from <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, a Cabinet officer. <PERSON> Stearns </PERSON> said the issue had `` constitutional implications.'' After hearing from both sides Wednesday, <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON> ruled from the bench that he would decide the issue of cleanup costs on the basis of the case record and would not require <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>' testimony. <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON> said that to do otherwise would probably prompt a time-consuming government appeal that would further delay a resolution for the plant's neighbors. <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON> directed lawyers for the government and neighbors to meet and resolve the issue this week. The 38-year-old plant, about 18 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Cincinnti </LOCATION>, processes uranium for use elsewhere in making the government's nuclear weapons Neighbors of the plant filed their class-action suit in 1985 on behalf of 14,000 people living within five miles of the plant. The suit contended that radioactive pollution from the plant lowered property values and caused them emotional distress. The settlement was reached June 30. <ORGANIZATION> Ruetgers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Mobil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which have operations near the plant, argued at a hearing on the settlement Aug. 23 that its terms would prevent them from suing to recover the cost of any future environmental cleanup on their properties.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0047EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Bones     09-15 0733</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Bones,0757</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bones of Stalin Victims Turning Up to Haunt Soviets</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAREY GOLDBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Near the <LOCATION> Ural </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> city of <LOCATION> Chelyabinsk </LOCATION>, skulls pierced by bullet holes were found where gold once was mined. In <LOCATION> Kolpashova </LOCATION>, a Siberian village on the <LOCATION> Ob </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, excavations released a stream of mummified corpses to float down the river. In the Ukrainian city of <LOCATION> Poltava </LOCATION>, diggers at a sand quarry uncovered a series of trenches full of bones _ the remains of an estimated 5,000 people. `` This is a country built on bones,'' says <PERSON> Oleg </PERSON> <PERSON> Golovanov </PERSON>, a member of a group called Memorial that is dedicated to the memory of <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>'s victims. The bones lay undisturbed for decades while the Soviet government refused to acknowledge the estimated 20 million victims of <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>'s bloody years of terror Now they are coming back to haunt the country. About once a month for the past year, the official press has reported the unearthing of another mass grave as the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> reveals the horror of its past. On Tuesday, Soviet television carried another report, this one about the reburial of 350 skeletons found on a mountain near <LOCATION> Chelyabinsk </LOCATION>. A correspondent said innocent `` men, women, old people and even children'' _ possibly as many as 300,000 _ were loaded onto trucks and shot at night. The Memorial group found the remains buried in a former gold mine where authorities wanted to build houses. Now officials plan to turn the area into a memorial, the correspondent said. A reburial ceremony is also planned Saturday for the remains of 540 of <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>'s victims found at a garbage dump in the Ukrainian coal center of <LOCATION> Donetsk </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Golovanov </PERSON> coordinates efforts to track down the mass graves for Memorial, the national group lobbying to clear the names of <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>'s `` enemies of the people,'' as well as help their families and those who survived years in labor camps He believes there could be as many as 100,000 unmarked mass graves left as a legacy from the purges, repressions and labor camps <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> oversaw from the late 1920s until his death in 1953. Press coverage of the graves began last year when a killing field was found in the Kuropaty forest of <LOCATION> Byelorussia </LOCATION>. It escalated with a similar discovery in <LOCATION> Bykovnya </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION>. Memorial receives a steady stream of letters with information about newly revealed sites, and <PERSON> Golovanov </PERSON> said he sometimes wonders, `` What is your goal in digging them up?'' He answers: to make sure people know all the evil of the Stalin years. He believes there is a need to restore respect to the dead. `` You're walking, and they're lying there under you, and not a single person knows about their fate,'' he said. <PERSON> Golovanov </PERSON> believes the caches of bones also make a forceful statement about the country's Communist rulers. `` The people in the government are the same now as they were then,'' he said. `` People ca n't help but see that.'' The party's policy-making <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> last month ordered local governments to do all they could to redress Stalin-era wrongs, including cooperating with groups like Memorial. `` Mass burial places should be recognized as official cemeteries,'' the decree said, and `` organs of the police and the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> should be more involved in this work.'' But <PERSON> Golovanov </PERSON> said revealing and marking the old graves remains fraught with conflicts. The <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION>, whose predecessor, the <ORGANIZATION> NKVD </ORGANIZATION>, carried out much of the killing, often does not open its files to help find graves and identify victims. <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> officials say their archives are in such terrible shape they are n't worth examining. Even after the grave sites are identified, some local authorities insist on using the land for new housing, garages or other projects. In <LOCATION> Donetsk </LOCATION>, the local government had turned the killing field over to developers and was reluctant to change its plans, the youth newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Komsomolskaya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pravda </ORGANIZATION> reported Wednesday. Eventually, authorities agreed to turn most of the land into a memorial park. In Poltava, the grave site is now a dump. An unsigned letter to Memorial from Poltava described how a man unearthed the trenches of corpses at a sand quarry in 1968 and was ordered by authorities to cover them. `` Once a year, since then, I've visited that area, since I supposed that my father was resting there too,'' he wrote. `` He was rehabilitated in 1959,'' posthumously.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0047EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-FDABribery     09-15 0231</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-FDA Bribery,0236</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pharmaceutical Company Official Sentenced in Generic Drug Case</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The former president of an <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> generic drug manufacturer who paid $ 32,000 in bribes to three <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> officials has been fined $ 250,000 and ordered to serve a year working for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Dilip </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON>, 43, formerly of <ORGANIZATION> Quad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pharmaceuticals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, was convicted of bribing <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> officials in exchange for their recommendations for approval of Quad products. In addition to the community service and fine, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hargrove </PERSON> also sentenced <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> on Wednesday to 60 days in jail and imposed two years of probation after the defendant completes his prison time. Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> said <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> paid $ 23,000 worth in illegal gratuities to <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chang </PERSON>, former branch chief of the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION>'s Division of Generic Drugs; $ 8,000 in cash to <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Brancato </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> review chemist; and $ 1,000 in department store gift certificates to <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Kletch </PERSON>, another agency chemist. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> said <PERSON> Shah </PERSON>'s cooperation in the case helped prosecutors convict <PERSON> Kletch </PERSON> and <PERSON> Brancato </PERSON>. <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> also has pleaded guilty in the case. So far, the investigation has resulted in the convictions of the three <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> officials and three pharmaceutical company officials. Two companies also have been found guilty of criminal wrongdoing and are facing heavy fines. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> said additional charges are expected as the investigation continues.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Europe-Emigration     09-15 0756</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Europe-Emigration,0769</SECOND>
<HEAD>East European Emigration Glance</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Refugees</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Emigration from <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> is rising sharply, both from reform-minded nations relaxing requirements for Western departures and from hard-line Communist nations. Here are the available figures on departures from <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and explanations of the procedures in each country: <LOCATION> SOVIET </LOCATION> <LOCATION> UNION </LOCATION> _ Since <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> rose to power in May 1985 and embarked on a broad reform course, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has let increasing numbers of citizens emigrate. In 1988, a record 108,000 Soviets left for permanent resettlement abroad, mostly ethnic Germans, Armenians and Jews. This year authorities expect the figure to reach 200,000, compared to less than 1,000 per year in the early 1980s. Soviets must submit to a lengthy and bureaucratic process to gain permission to emigrate, but refusals are now reported to be less than 1 percent of applications. EAST <LOCATION> GERMANY </LOCATION> _ Both legal emigration to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and unauthorized flight to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> are up dramatically this year, as <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> witnesses the largest migration westward since the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall was built in 1961. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> expects well over 100,000 East Germans to arrive this year, both legal immigrants and a growing number of escapees fleeing through <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s newly opened borders. East Germans get automatic citizenship in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Less than 40,000 East Germans have been allowed to leave for the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> in each of the past 28 years, with the numbers dipping to below 1,000 annually in the 1960s. The recent migration wave stems from dissatisfaction among East Germans with their leadership's refusal to emulate the reforms sweeping <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> POLAND </LOCATION> _ Since passport laws were revised Jan. 1 to allow virtually any citizen to travel abroad, the issue for Poles has not so much been getting permission to leave as getting visas to get into other countries. Most emigres are ethnic Germans resettling in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, or those with close relatives in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> who leave to join them. More than 140,000 Poles of German origin emigrated last year, and 3,500 left for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> visas will rise to 4,500 this year, while the exodus to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> has tapered off somewhat, though official figures are unavailable. <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> reported at the end of last year that during the 1980s, more than 400,000 Poles failed to return from trips abroad. <LOCATION> HUNGARY </LOCATION> _ Figures are not available for legal emigration from <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> prior to liberalized travel codes adopted in January 1988, but the departures are thought to have been limited to a few hundred family reunification cases each year. <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> officials have also acknowledged that an average of 2,500 to 3,000 Hungarians failed to return from authorized trips aboard each year during the 1980s, accounting for the majority of departures. Those desiring to leave now are awaiting a new emigration law being drafted by the <ORGANIZATION> Hungarian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. It is expected to result in a system similar to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s in which anyone with a sponsor abroad will be allowed to leave <LOCATION> CZECHOSLOVAKIA </LOCATION> _ The last sizeable wave of emigres from <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> was in 1969, when 110,000 fled after the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact invasion the previous year and before the borders were sealed. Czechoslovaks now can get to the West only to join spouses abroad, by failing to return from authorized foreign trips or in rare circumstances when they are allowed to join close relatives abroad. Unofficial sources say the number leaving, both legally and illegally, ranges between 6,000 and 8,000 per year. <LOCATION> ROMANIA </LOCATION> _ In the most hard-line <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> state </ORGANIZATION>, legal emigration is steady under fixed quotas while escapes have increased as Romanians driven to despair chance dangerous departures to <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. The West German government takes in about 12,000 ethnic Germans freed from <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> each year. About 1,000 Jews are allowed to go to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> annually, and 2,000 to 3,000 other departures are permitted, mostly to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. More than 20,000 Romanians of Hungarian descent have been given refuge in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> after fleeing illegally, and thousands more have escaped to the West through <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> BULGARIA </LOCATION> _ Emigration from <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION> consists primarily of ethnic Turks leaving for <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>. Nearly 270,000 Turkish Bulgarians have fled or been expelled just since May, when <LOCATION> Sofia </LOCATION> began issuing passports to those claiming repression under a forced assimilation campaign that began in 1984. Legal emigration and escapes over the years are thought to be only a few hundred annually, and no official figures are available.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Obit-PerezPrado 1stLd-Writethru a0405 09-15 0277</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Perez Prado, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0405,0279</SECOND>
<HEAD>Master of Mambo Dead at Age 72</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS throughout to UPDATE with funeral arrangements, background,
details. CORRECTS day of death, age. No pickup</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Damaso </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Prado </PERSON>, who was credited with popularizing the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> music known as mambo in the 1940s and'50s, died Thursday after suffering a stroke, his son said. He was 72. He died at home in the upper middle-class <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Colonia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valle </LOCATION> after being in a coma for eight days, said his son, <PERSON> Gerardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Prado </PERSON> was born Dec. 11, 1916, in <LOCATION> Matanzas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, and studied classical music as a youth. He moved to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> after World War II, but had been in ill health since last year, his son said. In July, he suffered a stroke, and doctors amputated a leg. Historians consider <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Prado </PERSON> one of the founders of mambo, a bouncy blend of tropical music highlighting trumpets and drums that became popular after the war in such cities as <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. Popular songs included `` Patricia'' and `` Mambo No. 8.'' The dance known as the mambo is similar to the cha-cha. It features a syncopated beat with lots of hip motion. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Prado </PERSON>, affectionately called `` seal face'' by his fans for the barking sound he made while playing his music, was in some ways a prisoner of his own success. He tried to change his musical style after the mambo craze died down, but ardent fans kept demanding the rhythms they were used to. He is survived by a wife and two children. He is to be buried Friday in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0030EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Salvador-Talks 2ndLd-Writethru   09-15 0705</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Salvador-Talks, 2nd Ld-Writethru,a0723,0727</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rebels, Government Agree on Plan for Peace Talks</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 11 grafs to UPDATE with accord on framework for talks;
pickup graf 8 pvs, `The guerrillas...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CANDICE HUGHES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Negotiators for the Salvadoran government and leftist rebels reached an agreement Thursday night on a framework for negotiations to end their nearly 10-year-old war, an observer to the talks said. `` It's clear that the two sides have reached a clear agreement that they should be attempting to reach not just a cease-fire but an end to hostilities,'' said <PERSON> Gregorio </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON>, the auxiliary bishop of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. A preliminary statement by <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> said the sides had reached an accord on how to prepare the meetings and on participation of the church in the talks. He said substantive themes would be discussed at the next meeting. The current round of talks began Wednesday with a two-day schedule, but the two sides were still negotiating late into the night Thursday on a final statement. <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> said he `` had the impression'' the future meetings would be held on a monthly basis and that they would include international observers. He added that the talks would take place inside and outside <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. Earlier in the day, the Marxist rebels and U.S.-backed government argued about the pace of peace talks to end the war, which has taken 70,000 lives. One rebel leader, <PERSON> Shafick </PERSON> <PERSON> Handal </PERSON>, told reporters the government's concern for procedural matters was `` very restrictive. Fighting continued in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, despite a unilateral truce declared by the guerrillas. Army spokesmen in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> said four guerrillas were killed, two guerrillas and one soldier were wounded, a helicopter was damaged and two buses were torched. In <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, Col. <PERSON> Orlando </PERSON> <PERSON> Zepeda </PERSON>, the vice minister of defense, called the rebel proposal to reorganize and reduce the size of the armed forces a thinly disguised attempt to seize power. `` We continue to be the object of Marxist aggression,'' <PERSON> Zepeda </PERSON> said. Government representatives had insisted that procedural issues be settled first, setting aside discussion of a rebel offer to lay down their arms and reorganize as a political party in exchange for democratic reforms. Sources for both sides also said they were divided on whether some negotiating sessions should take place without the presence of observers or <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> mediators. The guerrillas made the proposal Wednesday in their first talks with the government in two years. <PERSON> El </PERSON> <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON>'s government has not presented a peace plan, but the five-man delegation arrived with a proposal calling for two days of talks every two months. Rebels leaders said they want a faster-paced negotiating plan. Both sides say they want to end the war. Salvadoran Ambassador <PERSON> Sigfrido </PERSON> <PERSON> Munes </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruz </PERSON> told reporters Thursday that the rebel proposal shows `` a new attitude, a more realistic attitude.'' Munes is not a member of the government delegation, but he said he feels optimistic. The meeting is the first between the rebels and the elected <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> government of President <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON>, who took office June 1 after elections boycotted by the insurgents. The rebels' peace proposal calls for a cease-fire by Nov. 15 in exchange for broad reforms, including appointing a new <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> and justice minister and moving up legislative and municipal elections scheduled for 1991. The guerrillas also say a truce is conditional on military reorganization, including a reduction in the number of troops, expanded land reform and the prosecution of death squad members. <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> d'Aubuisson </PERSON>, founder of <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON>'s party, has been accused of playing a key role in rightist death squads that have murdered thousands of leftists, suspected leftists and other government opponents. Under the final stage of their proposal, the guerrillas call for constitutional and electoral reforms and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agreement to replace military aid to the <LOCATION> Salvadoran </LOCATION> government with economic aid. <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> is the largest recipient of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid in the hemisphere. The rebel plan contains many proposals rejected before, but the wording this time is much milder and the rebels have dropped a longstanding insistence on merging their army with the goverment armed forces. Their offer to become a political party also is new. Negotiations in 1984 and 1987 failed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel-Settlers     09-15 0760</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Settlers,0785</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jewish Settlers Face Problems from Uprising</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN ALT POWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIT ARYEH, Occupied West Bank (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Jewish settlers in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> say they are trapped between stone-throwing <PERSON> Arabs </PERSON> and an indecisive government. Since the Palestinian uprising began 21 months ago, nails have been strewn on their roads and their cars are targets of stones and firebombs. Glass window panes have been replaced with plastic and travel is often safest in convoy. The settlers complain bitterly that the government is torn on how to put down the uprising and, indeed, on the future of the occupied land itself. The result, they say, is that the army is not doing enough to protect them. `` Of course I am fearful,'' settler <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Barat </PERSON> told visitors to this fenced, hilltop settlement east of <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION>. `` If there is debate in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, it undercuts us.'' <PERSON> Barat </PERSON>, 40, a computer scientist, is among more than 70,000 Jews who have moved to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> since the territories were captured by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> in the 1967 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war. Some are `` ideological'' settlers, convinced that Jews must reclaim the biblical land of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Others, like <PERSON> Barat </PERSON>, see themselves as part of a front line against a Palestinian state. Still others are lured by the promise of free land and subsidized mortgages. Settlers have become targets in the uprising since many Palestinians see them as one more encroachment on Arab land. Almost half the 1.7 million Palestinians in the territories are refugees whose families fled <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> when it was founded in 1948. The settlers say the army, which recently began deploying extra troops along highways and stepped up escorts for settler convoys at night, still needs to do more. `` Instead of soldiers killing mosquito after mosquito, let them drain the swamp,'' said <PERSON> Kiryat </PERSON> <PERSON> Arba </PERSON> lawyer <PERSON> Eliyakim </PERSON> <PERSON> Haetzni </PERSON>, a leader of the settlers' umbrella group, Gush Emunim, or Bloc of the Faithful. `` We demand the deportation of 5,000 people _ members of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> establishment, stone-throwers and their families _ to show them that stone throwing is not a national sport,'' <PERSON> Haetzni </PERSON> said. `` Arabs must know that they can live here only if we can live here.'' Some Jewish settlers have poisoned Arab vineyards, raided villages and fired on suspected stone throwers, killing at least 23 Palestinians in the past 21 months. Tensions also have increased because of the government's proposal for elections in the territories leading to an interim peace solution. Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> has repeatedly said he will refuse to give up any occupied land, and his right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> bloc urges creation of more Jewish communities in the territories. But the left-leaning <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, partner in the coalition Cabinet with <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION>, advocates trading land for peace and calls for suspending the creation of more settlements if peace talks get under way. The 130 settlements built so far run counter to the U.S.-backed land-for-peace solution, which the Palestinians demand. By far the largest number of settlers live in communities close to the pre-1967 border. Some of the settlements deeper in the territories have populations of only several hundred people. <PERSON> Meron </PERSON> <PERSON> Benvenisti </PERSON>, an Israeli analyst who has studied development in the territories for a decade, notes that more than three-quarters of the settlers live within commuting distance of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION>. `` They have come to see themselves as suburbanites of the major cities,'' he said. <PERSON> Benvenisti </PERSON> said the settlements depend heavily on government subsidies for survival. He calculates that the government and the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zionist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> have spent $ 2.5 billion in the past 20 years building the new communities, providing basic services like water and roads and resettling Jewish families. Settlers often live rent-free in mobile homes while they build their houses. There is no cost for the land. Mortgages are subsidized, and fees for sewer and water connections are considerably less than in Israeli towns. The goverment plans at least seven new settlements by 1992, but budget constraints have forced the focus of late on trying to increase the population in existing communities. The number of new settlers fell to 4,500 last year from an average of 8,000 in previous years, apparently because of fears over the uprising, said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dekel </PERSON>, the prime minister's adviser on settlement affairs. But settlement advocates hope the trend can be reversed. <PERSON> Dekel </PERSON> predicted that the Jewish population in the territories would reach 125,000 in five years, even if the Arab revolt continues. `` People have become used to the uprising,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Poland Bjt   09-15 0565</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Poland, Bjt,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Food Aid to Poland to be Doubled</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is doubling food aid to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> to $ 100 million next year `` to support the process of change'' there, but the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> author of a rival plan calls it a merely a stopgap effort. Sen. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s plan does not go nearly far enough to help <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> meet its long-term needs <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> announced the food aid increase for fiscal 1990 on Thursday, just hours after <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON> unveiled his own $ 2.5 billion `` food for peace'' package. The president's plan calls for shipments to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> of beef, pork, corn, butter, butter oil, sunflower oil, cotton and rice. The new $ 50 million infusion was in addition to $ 50 million in food <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> announced in early August for the new fiscal year that begins Oct. 1. It is on top of $ 8.4 million in emergency food assistance <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ordered for the current fiscal year. Most of the food shipments will come from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> surpluses. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> has been affected by severe food shortages and increasing prices. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had been under mounting pressure from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to do more to aid <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s new Solidarity-led government, not only from Democrats but from <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> called <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s decision Thursday `` a good investment in democracy and political reform for <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>.'' `` The president's original proposal was made at a time when <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, while taking some important steps in political reform, still had a communist-dominated government,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said. `` It seemed important to me to signal our intent to do more for a democratic government than we had for a communist regime,'' said <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, who visited <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> last month with his wife, <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. However, <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON> called <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s plan `` a welcome but stopgap effort that fails to give <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> the long-term help it needs to restructure its agricultural economy and to sustain the world's newest democracy.'' The Democrat's $ 2.5 billion rival program includes forgiveness of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s $ 2 billion agricultural debt, $ 150 million in food shipments, $ 100 million in foreign aid and a series of trade concessions and other assistance. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> called his Polish food aid package `` one element of our continuing effort, working with our allies and others, to support the process of change that is underway in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>.'' The overall $ 108.4 million food package _ which does not require congressional approval _ is in addition to a $ 119 million plan of economic assistance <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> announced in July when he visited <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. `` We expect that shipments of the new -LRB- food -RRB- assistance will arrive in time for the difficult winter months,'' he said in a statement. He said high prices and food shortages have placed a `` heavy burden on the Polish people.'' `` It is intended that the food aid will support long-term reform of the Polish agricultural system by providing much needed commodities during a transitional period toward a market economy,'' the president said. The package `` underscores our continuing commitment to assist the Polish government and people in their efforts to introduce market principles and to build a private sector that will enable <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> to invigorate its economy,'' he continued. While the initial $ 50 million is mostly in food grants, the new $ 50 million installment will be composed of direct shipments, subsidized sales and some low-interest loans, administration officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PollutionDevices     09-15 0493</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pollution Devices,0508</SECOND>
<HEAD>Air Board Orders New Anti-Pollution Devices</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The state <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday ordered that as of 1994, new cars in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> must offer advanced computerized systems to warn drivers about faulty automobile equipment that causes pollution. The new technology was approved by a 7-0 vote following a public hearing crowded with more than 75 auto industry representatives and environmental advocates. The advanced system, state officials said, would result in quicker repairs of defective parts, leading to lower emissions of smog-producing hydrocarbons, carbon monoxide and nitrogen oxide. Resulting reductions of hydrocarbons and nitrogen oxides would amount to more than 100 tons a day apiece statewide, according to an air board staff report. Almost half the reduction would be in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Basin </LOCATION>, which includes <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Orange </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Riverside </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> counties, the area that suffers the most polluted air in the nation. The dashboard diagnostic system, which air board staff members estimate could cost manufacturers $ 45 per vehicle, would have two purposes: to improve air quality and to help mechanics repair high-tech auto equipment designed to monitor and limit noxious emissions. Air board engineering studies chief <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Albu </PERSON> said it would have a `` greater impact on emissions than any other single control measure adopted by the board.'' Among those supporting the new regulation were the South Coast Air Quality Management District, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lung </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and the Automobile Club of <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Engineers for major auto makers said they like the idea of expanded on-board diagnostics but raised technical questions and requested more time to devise the detection systems. `` Due to the need to develop new, unproven technology, considerable lead-time is needed,'' said <PERSON> Suanne </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, a staff scientist for the <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vehicle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. She said the association urged that implementation be delayed until the 1996 model year and phase-in be extended to the 1998 model year. The manufacturers' group is a Detroit-based industry group that includes <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION>. The state board, however, decided to order the changes in 1994, with full compliance ordered by 1996. `` In the state of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, we have to be aggressive,'' said <PERSON> Jananne </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharpless </PERSON>, board chairman. Board member <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lagarias </PERSON> said the dashboard system would provide for `` smart warning lights'' as opposed to current `` idiot lights.'' On-board monitor lights the air board ordered on new cars beginning in 1988 warn drivers they need repairs only when basic emission-related parts such as the fuel system fail to work. The new system will require improved monitoring of the fuel system but also monitor engine misfiring, catalytic converter efficiency and chlorofluorocarbon leaks in air conditioning systems. The regulation calls for on-board computers to store data that would help repairmen identify faulty equipment. It also calls for standardized computer technology to allow a universal scanning tool so any repair shop can access the data in the vehicle computer.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MissAmerica-G-String     09-15 0392</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Miss America-G-String,0403</SECOND>
<HEAD>G-String Pageant Competing with Miss America</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Retransmitting to correct cycle designator</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOYCE A. VENEZIA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Miss America Pageant is playing down the swimsuit competition this year, but a competitor hopes to draw viewers interested in more flesh. The Platinum Doll Bikini Contest, with comedian <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Byner </PERSON> as host, is one in a series of naughty contests that have sprung up over the years to counter the pageant's wholesome image. Today's contest features 36 go-go girls from <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, said contest producer <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Cirucci </PERSON>. Instead of the scholarship offered by the Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> program, the go-go girls will be competing for a $ 10,000 cash prize and the `` platinum G-string award,'' <PERSON> Cirucci </PERSON> said. The second-prize winner gets $ 5,000 and third prize is $ 3,000. Fourth - and fifth-place runners-up get trips to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> The contestants were auditioned by the contest organizers _ not selected in state `` pageants'' _ and no interview was required, he said. No evening gowns in this contest _ a selection of costumes will be stripped off to reveal halters and G-strings. `` We have one girl wearing a nun outfit, another who's a cowboy, one who will be a nurse,'' he said. The winner will not be serenaded by `` There She Is'' but instead will dance down the stage to `` a good rock' n' roll band,'' <PERSON> Cirucci </PERSON> said. `` We hope to steal some thunder away from the <ORGANIZATION> Miss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pageant </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Cirucci </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Horn </PERSON>, director of the venerable <ORGANIZATION> Miss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pageant </ORGANIZATION>, which crowns Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> on Saturday night, called the G-string contest `` ludicrous'' and said it will not take away his audience. `` It does n't mean a thing to us,'' he said. ` It's somebody just trying to exploit us, and it will not affect us at all.'' Judges for the Platinum Doll Bikini Contest include former <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Phillies </ORGANIZATION> pitcher <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Christensen </PERSON>; <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Bongiovi </PERSON>, uncle of rock star <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Bon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jovi </PERSON> and owner of a recording studio; and <PERSON> Gennaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Meoli </PERSON>, a fashion designer for <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cirucci </PERSON> said. The G-string contest is not the first time a promoter has tried to strip away some of the <ORGANIZATION> Miss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pageant </ORGANIZATION>'s luster. In the 1970s, several Miss Nude USA pageants were held the week before Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The G-string contest was to be held at a Boardwalk nightclub.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FatAmerica 1stLd-Writethru a0426 09-15 0699</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fat America, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0426,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Studies Say 20 Percent of Adults are Fat, Posing Major Health Risk</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 5th graf pvs, Obesity is, and 9th graf, Being extremely,
to CORRECT spelling of Bray</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> may be land of the free and home of the brave, but it's also the country of the fat. A researcher on obesity says that 33 million adult Americans, about 20 percent of the adult population, are significantly obese, giving the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> one of the highest populations of fat people in the world. `` It's clear that significant obesity appears to be more prevalent in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> than elsewhere,'' Dr. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bray </PERSON>, a professor of medicine at <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday. `` The greater the excess weight, the greater excess risk'' of resulting health problems, he said. Obesity is a public health concern only in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, and the percentage of significantly overweight people is highest by far in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bray </PERSON> said. The scientist said researchers do n't know why there is a higher percentage of fat adults in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> than elsewhere, though he suggests it could be because of the highly mechanized <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> civilization that makes it easy to avoid walking or climbing stairs. <PERSON> Bray </PERSON> says statistics suggest Americans are eating a better diet now _ avoiding meats and other foods high in animal fats _ but the number of significantly obese people `` continues to creep up.'' The effects of excess weight is showing up in health studies that show the obese are suffering more heart attacks, more high blood pressure, more diabetes and more gall bladder disease. Being extremely fat, <PERSON> Bray </PERSON> said, is only slightly less of a health risk than smoking two packs of cigarettes a day. Bray, president-elect of the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Study </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Obesity </ORGANIZATION>, said doctors consider significant obesity to be a weight about 30 percent above what would be ideal for a person's age, stature and gender Thus, a man whose ideal weight is 170 to 180 pounds becomes `` significantly'' obese if his weight balloons to 221 to 234. At that point, he becomes almost twice as likely to develop a life-shortening ailment, <PERSON> Bray </PERSON> said. But numbers on the weight scale do n't tell the full story. `` It's not just how fat you are, but where the fat is located, that will determine your risk,'' said Bray. Researchers now believe that fat located within the abdominal cavity poses a greater health hazard than does fat located in the extremities or just under the skin. `` The reasons for this are not clear,'' said <PERSON> Bray </PERSON>. `` The most widely accepted explanation is that when you've got more fat in your belly around your organs, it is that fat that is released when you eat fatty acids.'' Because of its proximity, such fat is thought to go directly to the liver, where `` it sets up risk factors that we associate with heart disease, diabetes, hypertension and gall bladder disease,'' he said. Adult men, said Bray, seem most at risk of developing this unhealthy deposit of abdominal fat. Age also plays a factor, he added, because few children or young adults develop this type of fat deposit. `` For women, the visceral fat does n't seem to increase until there is a lot of total fat,'' he said. `` Women are protected against visceral fat to some degree, for some reason.'' Smoking affects visceral, or central, fat, said Bray, and stopping smoking tends to cause this fat to disappear, even though the former smoker may gain fat in other areas. Again, why this is so is not well understood, but he said, `` this is another good reason to stop smoking.'' Another study elsewhere shows that American youth are becoming more muscular, but also more sedentary _ a lifestyle that has made them fatter and triggered an `` ominous'' loss of cardiovascular health. A report by the <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund-Amateur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> testing program, which surveyed 12,000 youths from 1980 to 1989, said there is no perceptible increase in height for the various age groups studied and that weight gains can be attributed to poorer diet and physical habits.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0215EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SmokingBan Bjt   09-15 0651</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Smoking Ban, Bjt,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fencing Begins Over Final Shape of Airline Smoking Ban</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX8</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Senate meets 10:30 a.m. EDT; May be led</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s vote to halt smoking on all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airline flights leaves tobacco interests and advocates of the ban jockeying over how severe the final version of the restrictions will be. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> decided by voice vote to forbid cigarette smoking on all domestic airline routes after routing an effort by tobacco industry supporters to block the provision. Earlier, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> sent President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a separate measure containing $ 225 million to begin construction of the government's latest boon for <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, the $ 5 billion super conducting supercollider Final passage of the $ 11.9 billion transportation bill for fiscal 1990 containing the smoking restrictions was held up by a dispute over unrelated anti-drug spending. But when that comes, the next step will be for <ORGANIZATION> Senate-House </ORGANIZATION> negotiators to write compromise legislation that can be sent to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The House last month approved a milder version of the ban which would permanently bar smoking on flights of two hours or shorter. Lobbyist <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Deutsch </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Flight </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Attendants </ORGANIZATION>, one of several airline unions working for the total ban, said lobbyists were trying to discern the leanings of lawmakers who will negotiate on the measure. `` You can bet the ones who are unsure or leaning the other way will be hearing from us over the next few days,'' she said. Spokesman <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> of the cigarette industry's trade group, the <ORGANIZATION> Tobacco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, said his side had not given up hope of toning down the restrictions. `` It's not the law yet,'' he said. `` It's our positive outlook that less extreme legislation will be the result'' of the House-Senate bargaining. In the showdown 77-21 vote Thursday, senators forced a halt to delaying tactics pro-smoking lawmakers had hoped would lead to looser restrictions. `` We did n't undertake that vote in the belief we could defeat'' the proposed ban, Sen. <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, D-Ky., who fought the proposal, conceded Sen. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, who sponsored the ban proposal and who cited health concerns about lingering cigarette smoke in airline cabins, said, `` The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people are overwhelmingly in support of this suspension of smoking on airliners.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> version would extend the ban to all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> routes 95 days after the bill becomes law. Current restrictions prohibit smoking on flights of two hours or less _ four-fifths of all routes _ and will otherwise expire next April. Passengers caught smoking would be subject to $ 1,000 fines and people found to have disabled smoke detectors in aircraft restrooms would face penalties of up to $ 2,000. Opponents of the ban argued there is no proof that cigarette fumes harm nonsmokers, and that the smoke is merely one of many chemicals adrift in the recirculated air inside airliners. They called on supporters to await a <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> study on airliner air quality expected by early next year. They also said the restriction would hurt tobacco growers. But supporters cited several studies concluding that nonsmokers risk cancer and other diseases by so-called passive smoking and said there was no reason to wait for a total prohibition. The money for the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> atom smasher was part of an $ 18.6 billion energy and water measure approved on a voice vote. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> resident, is expected to sign the bill. The circular, 53-mile-long supercollider is to be built 25 miles south of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>. Scientists will use it to hurtle proton beams into each other in a search for the basic building blocks of matter. The measure also contains $ 1.6 billion towards cleaning up the nation's nuclear weapons plants, about 70 percent more than the $ 975 million provided this year and 27 percent more than <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> requested. The overall task of removing radioactive waste from the facilities has been estimated at $ 100 billion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0524EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Court-Boots     09-15 0150</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Court-Boots,0153</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Rules Boots Were Definitely On</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALBANY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 No one would be caught outside in the upstate <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> winter without boots on, a state appeals court decided in upholding the conviction of a man who kicked and injured another person. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Bidwell </PERSON>, who was convicted of assault with a dangerous instrument, claimed there was no proof he was wearing shoes at the time of the Dec. 29, 1984, fight in <LOCATION> Binghamton </LOCATION>. `` We disagree,'' said presiding Justice <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahoney </PERSON> of the Appellate Division of the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in Thursday's unanimous decision `` The incident occurred at the end of December and there was testimony that the temperature was cold, thereby foreclosing the possibility that the attacker had bare feet.'' The court also noted that <PERSON> Bidwell </PERSON>'s brother testified that <PERSON> Bidwell </PERSON> was wearing cowboy boots. The victim in the attack required 70 stitches, the court said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     09-15 0489</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0505</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohutynski </PERSON> went to divorce court, the key issue was visitation rights _ with the <LOCATION> Moluccan </LOCATION> cockatoo she and her ex-husband had raised from a fledgling. `` It's a little weird, a little strange,'' she said in a telephone interview Thursday. `` I walked into work and everybody was laughing.'' The couple has no children, but snowy white, orange-crested Magic `` is like a baby,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Kohutynski </PERSON>, 28, of <LOCATION> Hickory </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>. `` He's very affectionate, very loving,'' she said of the $ 3,000 bird she has not seen in a year. `` He goes up on your arm and leans against your shoulder for a hug.'' The property settlement approved Wednesday requires her former husband, <PERSON> Leroy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohutynski </PERSON>, 28, of <LOCATION> Palos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> to allow her regular visits with the bird. Her attorney, <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Becker </PERSON>, told the judge that <PERSON> Kohutynski </PERSON> also has agreed to execute an irrevocable will giving her possession of Magic if he should die or decide he does n't want the bird anymore. `` You want an irrevocable will on a bird?'' exclaimed Judge <PERSON> Aubrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaplan </PERSON>. Magic, now 3, was less than 8 months old when the couple bought him. Cockatoos can live more than 50 years.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HATFIELD, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The hourly tolling of a church bell has been a melodious tradition in this little farming community, but for a couple that moved next door it's more like an all-night alarm clock. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pamela </PERSON> <PERSON> Carnall </PERSON>, who bought their house next door to the century-old clock last year, sued the town after the board of selectmen declined to silence the clock between 9 p.m. and 7 a.m. The couple, who say the chiming ruins their sleep, lost their bid for a preliminary injunction to silence the clock in April. But Judge <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keady </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> has said he will hear arguments on the issue Oct. 5 in <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. Both sides have already made their case loud and clear. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Carnall </PERSON> says he has given up trying to get to sleep before midnight, when the bell tolls 12 times. And Dr. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Northampton </LOCATION>, who has prescribed sleeping pills for <PERSON> Pamela </PERSON> <PERSON> Carnall </PERSON>, maintained in a letter to the judge that the bell is `` affecting Mrs. <PERSON> Carnall </PERSON>'s work and well-being.'' The Carnalls contend they have been unable to adjust to the bonging of the 1,800-pound bell on the <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congregational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, 50 feet from their home. But Hatfield Town Counsel <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON> contended that the sound of the bell is simply part of life in a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> village of 3,200 people. He said the Carnalls, both of whom were born and raised in the area, should have noticed the bell tower and considered that before buying the house. The selectmen contend the only previous complaint they ever received about the bell was when it did n't sound. They said more than 200 townsfolk signed petitions in support of the clock.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0142EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Refugees-Crowding Bjt   09-15 0513</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Refugees-Crowding, Bjt,0531</SECOND>
<HEAD>Local Officials Scamble to House Wave of New Arrivals</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Refugees</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN COSTELLOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FRANKFURT, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Officials across <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> struggling to house a crush of refugees have set up camping trailers, commandeered school gymnasiums and even tried to persuade new arrivals to go elsewhere. The East Germans are only the latest wave of refugees, who have strained <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s social services and housing stock. More than 400,000 ethnic Germans from <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> are expected this year alone; the number of East Germans will easily top previous predictions of 100,000. In addition, tens of thousands of asylum seekers from various countries arrive each year in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, already one of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s most densely populated countries. Social services and school and local budgets in many communities already are stretched to the limit, and affordable housing is increasingly rare in this country of 62 million people. The East Germans began arriving Monday when <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> defied its <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact ally <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and allowed them to cross into <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> en route to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. By Thursday, at least 13,000 East Germans had arrived. `` I have full understanding for why they would especially like to live in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, where they are closest to their homeland,'' the city's mayor, <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Momper </PERSON>, said Thursday. But he urged the new arrivals not to flood his city, saying it already has cared for a disproportionately high number of other refugees. `` People have more trouble finding housing and work here,'' <PERSON> Momper </PERSON> said in an address to the local parliament. He called on the federal government to solve the housing problem as soon as possible for the East German refugees. `` Words about life in freedom do n't fill up the stomach or put a roof over anyone's head,'' he said. Most of the East Germans refugees are staying with friends and relatives. Still, many have needed temporary shelter provided by various West German states. <LOCATION> Hamburg </LOCATION>, for example, set up 60 camping trailers at a city camp site. `` Trailers are better than tents,'' said <LOCATION> Hamburg </LOCATION>'s social services director, <PERSON> Ortwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Runde </PERSON>. `` They let the people have more freedom, and they're better suited for the winter months.'' In <LOCATION> Wiesbaden </LOCATION>, the No. 2 official of the Hesse state <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said sports fans should not worry that local school gymnasiums had been requisitioned as temporary shelters. `` They can be cleared out and used for sports again because the majority of the newcomers have quickly gone on to friends and relatives,'' <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> said the centrally located state even planned to close 15 of the 20 emergency shelters now that the wave of East German refugees apparently has peaked. Still, the long-term housing situation will remain a problem in a country where families with two children live in two-bedroom apartments measuring 120 square yards and often less. Many of the newcomers are young people in their 20s and 30s, and many are families with young children. In <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>, government spokesman <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Klein </PERSON> said federal officials will meet soon to map a housing strategy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890915-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-15-89 0227EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RobinsAppeal     09-15 0532</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Robins Appeal,0546</SECOND>
<HEAD>Supreme Court Asked to Hear Challenge in Dalkon Shield Case</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RICHMOND, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
