<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Pisa'sTowerTizzy     10-08 0851</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pisa's Tower Tizzy,0874</SECOND>
<HEAD>Italian Official Creates Fuss Over Saving Leaning Tower of Pisa</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEPHEN R. WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PISA, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The tower of <LOCATION> Pisa </LOCATION> has been leaning for 800 years, so the keeper of the marble wonder ca n't understand what all the latest fuss is about. It's true that experts have been making dire predictions for years. But there was a real tower tizzy after the minister of public works, <PERSON> Giovanni </PERSON> <PERSON> Prandini </PERSON>, sounded an alarm recently that scared all of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. Newspapers immediately published headlines warning of a `` red alert'' for the tower, raising fears that one of the symbols of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> could, at worst, topple, or at best, be closed for repairs. But <PERSON> Giuseppe </PERSON> <PERSON> Toniolo </PERSON>, chairman of the committee responsible for preservation of the monument, says there's nothing to get excited about. `` There is absolutely nothing new in the situation,'' he said in an interview. `` To say that the tower is in danger, so what? It's always been in danger. `` What does the tower need?'' <PERSON> Toniolo </PERSON> added. `` It needs to be left in peace.'' The 180-foot circular tower, begun by <PERSON> Bonnano </PERSON> <PERSON> Pisano </PERSON> in 1173, started to tilt almost immediately because the ground shifted underneath. It was completed by <PERSON> Tomasso </PERSON> d'Andrea with the construction of the belfry between 1360 and 1370. The tower now leans about 13 feet off the perpendicular, but <PERSON> Toniolo </PERSON> and other tower experts say it would not topple for more than another century if it continues to tilt at its average rate. According to the last measurement in June, the tower leaned an additional 0.008 inches in the last 12-month period. The average yearly tilt since the measurements began in 1918 is 0.047 inches. `` The thing should fall over,'' <PERSON> Toniolo </PERSON> said, seated behind a desk in his office, the tower visible through Gothic windows. `` How long will this lean last? No one can say. But at a certain time, it will reach the point where it falls. That will take more than 100 years. It could be 200, 250 years.'' For decades, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> has tried to come up with ways to save the tower. A number of national and international commissions have proposed plans for stabilizing the monument, but none has ever been implemented. `` The problem of trying to stabilize the tower is enough to make the hands of great technicians tremble,'' said <PERSON> Gero </PERSON> <PERSON> Geri </PERSON>, a topography professor who has been measuring the lean of the tower since 1969. `` Who wants to risk doing something that could upset the equilibrium?'' The latest plan, approved by the government in 1987, is to implant a wheel-shaped support below the base around the tower. It would be connected by concrete spokes to the marble foundation. The <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Works </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> appointed a commission a few months ago to study the soil conditions to determine whether the plan can go ahead. But <PERSON> Toniolo </PERSON> believes the tower ca n't be fixed until officials figure out what has kept the 14,000-ton structure standing all these years. `` All the technicians say it ca n't be understood,'' said the white-haired, 80-year-old retired radiologist who has headed the monument preservation committee for 12 years. `` This means there are special conditions of the terrain which have n't yet been explained. If you ca n't understand this, how can you do a project to save it?'' <PERSON> Prandini </PERSON>, a Christian Democrat who has been public works minister for barely two months, apparently wants to find a solution. After expressing his concern over the state of the tower, <PERSON> Prandini </PERSON> ordered a panel of technical experts to report back quickly on the feasibility of a stabilization plan. He also told them to devise a round-the-clock monitoring system for the tower. Mayor <PERSON> Giacomino </PERSON> <PERSON> Granchi </PERSON>, a Socialist, accused <PERSON> Prandini </PERSON> of exaggerating the situation and trying to get publicity for himself. <PERSON> Prandini </PERSON> replied, `` I do n't see why one wants to make a controversy out of a well known problem only because there's the will to act decisively and go from the study phase to concrete realization.'' The sense of urgency was heightened by the collapse in March of the 900-year-old tower of <LOCATION> Pavia </LOCATION> in northern <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, killing three people. Experts said the 255-foot tower crumbled either because of natural decay in the mortar holding the bricks together or because of a sudden sinking following a dry spell that lowered the water table. `` The example of <LOCATION> Pavia </LOCATION> does n't count because no one ever monitored it,'' <PERSON> Toniolo </PERSON> said. `` No other tower in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> is monitored like <LOCATION> Pisa </LOCATION>'s. If <PERSON> Pavia </PERSON> had all the instruments that we have, they would have known a few months before'' that it was in danger. <PERSON> Toniolo </PERSON> said he receives an average of 40 proposals a year from people around the world, mostly Americans, for saving the tower. The latest: erecting a huge statue of Saint <PERSON> Ranieri </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Pisa </LOCATION>'s patron saint, with arms raised to hold up the tower Some even suggest trying to straighten the tower, a notion that makes <PERSON> Toniolo </PERSON> shudder. `` Never, for heaven's sake,'' he said. `` It was born tilted. Our ancestors built it that way eight centuries ago. It must remain that way.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Perestroika     10-08 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Perestroika,0709</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shortages, Shipping Breakdowns Pose New Problems for Gorbachev</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL PUTZEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s first snowfall ushered in an early winter last week, Soviet officials worried openly that the nation could face dangerous shortages of food, fuel and heat in the colder weeks and months to come. Attention focused on a breakdown of the transportation network as supplies of every kind bottlenecked at railheads and ports throughout much of the country. But the looming threat also exposes President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s inability so far to implement any real `` perestroika,'' or restructuring, of the Soviet economy. After four years of reform measures, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has succeeded in discrediting the old system built around a centrally planned economy. But he has n't instituted the market-driven replacement that he and other reformers advocate. The result is most evident right now, in the dislocation of the supply and transport system. First Deputy Premier <PERSON> Lev </PERSON> <PERSON> Voronin </PERSON> said last week that power stations and public utilities have 4.5 million fewer tons of coal on hand than at this time last year. He said miners will have to make an enormous effort if the people are to avoid rationing of heat, light and electricity this winter. A three-week national coal miners' strike in July disrupted production, and since then shipments have been held up by the logjams that also affect food and consumer products. <PERSON> Voronin </PERSON> blamed the transport breakdown for frustrating the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>'s effort to relieve chronic shortages by spending tens of millions of precious dollars to import goods the Soviets themselves have failed to produce. More than 2 million tons of imported cargo are sitting in Soviet ports waiting to be unloaded, he said, and 130 loaded freight trains are standing idle inside <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> ready to leave for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Newspapers report carloads of food rotting on trains while consumers complain bitterly that store shelves are empty. The situation is even more critical in <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, which for two months was all but cut off from the rest of the country by an Azerbaijani blockade inspired by ancient ethnic hatreds. <PERSON> Voronin </PERSON> charged that outright sabotage is playing havoc with government efforts to rebuild towns and cities destroyed by the December 1988 earthquake before winter comes again. In an article Wednesday in the daily <ORGANIZATION> Sotsialisticheskaya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industriya </ORGANIZATION>, the first deputy premier was quoted as saying that water has been poured into rail cars carrying cement to the quake zone, and building materials have been damaged. Thousands of tons of fuel have not been delivered, he said, and even emergency vehicles have been sidelined in the hard-hit republic. The <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported Friday night that some rail traffic bound for <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> had been under escort by soldiers. But it said disruption on main rail lines caused by the Azerbaijani blockade had idled some 400 trains totaling 60,000 wagons. Pravda, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> daily, reported that across the country there are 13,500 freight cars waiting to be unloaded. In a brief front-page article headlined `` Is It Sabotage?'' the national newspaper said Friday that railway officials were complaining there were no trucks to deliver goods arriving by train. `` Pravda correspondents saw with their own eyes unloaded freight trains that had brought to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> imported furniture, cosmetics, coffee, tea, soap, shampoo, washing powder and Soviet-produced TV sets, refrigerators, batteries and cigarettes _ all in all, 585 cars ready to be unloaded and 700 more waiting at stations from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Smolensk </LOCATION>'' about 200 miles away, the newspaper said. `` More goods are stored in depots or right outside without anything to protect them from the weather,'' it said. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, trying to prevent the situation from deteriorating further, called for a 15-month ban on strikes, saying strong medicine is needed to prevent `` anarchy and irresponsible management.'' The recently elected Supreme Soviet legislature, declaring its independence from <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> edicts, refused to give <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> the sweeping ban he wanted. But it did temporarily order workers in critical industries such as coal mining to remain on the job until legislation can be adopted defining their right to strike.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Sudan-War     10-08 0758</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sudan-War,0782</SECOND>
<HEAD>Civil War Ravages Civilian Life in Southern Capital</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MOHAMED OSMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MALAKAL, Sudan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Matchstick-thin, naked children with swollen bellies stand under a harsh sun, chewing dried, uncooked fish. Their emaciated elders sit with blank stares, gazing toward the horizon. Half the 50,000 people living in this wretched Nile riverport are seeking shelter in <LOCATION> Malakal </LOCATION> from the horrors of a seemingly interminable civil war, refugees in their own country. Sanitary services are non-existent, and malaria and typhoid run rampant. Those who are sick have but one dilapidated hospital to turn to, with only a handful of doctors and almost no medical supplies. <LOCATION> Malakal </LOCATION>, capital of the southern <LOCATION> Upper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nile </LOCATION> region, is a microcosm of <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>'s southland, an area the size of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> laid waste by 6 -LCB- years of warfare and famine. A massive international relief operation prevented a repeat of the mass starvation experienced in the summer of 1988. But the rebellion's accumulated effects continue to wreak havoc on the region's desperate civilians. Government troops control <LOCATION> Malakal </LOCATION>, 425 miles south of the capital, <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION>, as they do most southern population centers. Nevertheless, rebels of the <ORGANIZATION> Sudan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> stake out areas on its perimeter as freely as they move about in more than 90 percent of the southern countryside. Militarily, the war has basically been at a standstill for months. Both sides agreed in April to quiet their guns to let relief goods go through. A military junta took power in <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION> June 30, promising to end the war, and has extended the truce each month. The rebels have gone along. But political maneuvering over how and when to talk peace continues, leaving the people of <LOCATION> Malakal </LOCATION> and the rest of the south struggling, but surviving. `` People may think we're all dead,'' said <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Maker </PERSON>, a government employee, `` but we're still living, despite the war.'' A chieftain of the Shuluk tribe told a visiting reporter: `` Life is going on here. We are life. We are giving birth, and we are eating. Although very little.'' The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> says 250,000 southerners died a year ago of starvation or disease in a famine caused by the war. Other Western relief workers estimate the death toll at twice that. To prevent a recurrence, the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> agencies organized Operation Lifeline <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION> to position 105,000 tons of relief goods in key transit points for distribution to displaced people after monsoon-like summer rains isolated them this year. Organizers say 80 percent of the goods was positioned in time. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON>, regional monitor of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Program </ORGANIZATION>, said government and rebels are negotiating the dispatch of a third convoy of <LOCATION> Nile </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> barges with additional relief for the Upper Nile. The program has had to overcome logistical and political problems, he said. There were too few workers for unloading the barges en route and inadequate storage facilities. Local officials complained about unfair distribution. As displaced people flooded the towns, the numbers of people who had to be cared for kept changing. <LOCATION> Malakal </LOCATION> still faces life-threatening problems, especially in health care. `` Malaria and typhoid are everywhere, and we have no chloroquine -LRB- malaria medicine -RRB- or syringes,'' said Lt. Col. <PERSON> Galwak </PERSON> <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, military governor for the <LOCATION> Upper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nile </LOCATION>. `` We have only one general practitioner, when we need at least 24. We have some 500 -LRB- doses -RRB- of medication, which would be consumed in one day if we were to use them, but we have more than 600 patients coming in every day.'' Doctors and nurses said the town's lone hospital has 14 badly equipped wards with about 500 beds. Hospital records show at least two deaths a day from malaria or typhoid. Hospital staff are helped by three doctors of the French organization <ORGANIZATION> Medicins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Frontieres </ORGANIZATION> and some military doctors. `` These deaths are only the ones in the hospital,'' said one of the French physicians, who identified himself as Dr. <PERSON> Pathot </PERSON>. `` We have no car at all, nor an ambulance, so if somebody is going to die, he may do it before coming to us. `` We ca n't say how many die every day.'' As the civilian populace struggles to survive, the army has been trying to reopen the town's 10 schools, closed for almost three years. Two primary schools have been reopened. A reporter touring them found the classes had no desks, stools or blackboards. Children sat on the ground, their teachers instructing them to read and write by using the earth as a blackboard and a stick as chalk.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--TexasBusCrash     10-08 0119</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Texas Bus Crash,0122</SECOND>
<HEAD>Truck Collides With School Bus, 1 Injured</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROSENBERG, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A pickup truck collided head-on with a school bus carrying students from a county fair Saturday, critically injuring the truck driver. Twenty students and a teacher were sent to a hospital for observation. The students and teacher were treated and released from a local hospital. The 29-year-old truck driver was flown by helicopter to an emergency room. The students had participated in the livestock competition at the <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bend </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fair </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Rosenberg </LOCATION>, 10 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. The southbound truck drove into the northbound lane, striking the bus, as the two vehicles rounded a curve, <PERSON> Rosenberg </PERSON> Police Sgt. <PERSON> Beverly </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Salvador     10-08 0322</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Salvador,0334</SECOND>
<HEAD>Disabled Guerrillas Leave For Cuba</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCOS ALEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group of 47 disabled guerrillas left late Saturday for <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> under protection of the Mexican government and the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>, government and airport officials said. The 47, mostly amputees, belong to the <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>. They occupied the capital's Metropolitan Cathedral for six weeks then on Tuesday moved into the <ORGANIZATION> Mexican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in their efforts to leave the country. In <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement the group, accompanied by two nurses, was headed for <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. The statement said the group `` left tonight on a special <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> flight for <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, where they have asked to be taken to receive special medical attention.'' Officials at <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>'s international airport said the 47 left on a plane chartered by the Mexican government. Officials from the <ORGANIZATION> Mexican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> or Salvadoran government would not speak to reporters Saturday. The guerrillas also were told not to speak to the press. But one guerrilla, identified only as <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, told reporters, `` We're going to leave for <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>.'' <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, who lost a leg in combat, said the group hoped to receive medical care in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. It could not be determined whether the disabled men, most of them young, received political asylum in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. Monsignor <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivero </PERSON> <PERSON> Damas </PERSON>, the archbishop of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, called the evacuation, `` one of the points of humanization in the conflict.'' Late last month, <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> <PERSON> Damas </PERSON> appealed for the guerrillas to vacate his church, saying: `` The cathedral is not a hotel.'' <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON>'s government said 2,000 soldiers, 500 guerrillas and 700 civilians have been disabled in combat during the more than nine years of civil war. Leftist rebels have fought the succession of U.S.-backed governments for nearly 10 years. Since 1984, 346 guerrillas have been evacuated to other countries, including <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. The last evacuation occurred in May.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 0106EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People Sub   10-08 0216</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People, Sub,0221</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 2nd item to CORRECT title of book in lead to ``The Russia
House'' sted ``The Russian House.''</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Pfeiffer </PERSON>, who had three movies out last year and has another opening Friday, is looking ahead to her next project _ starring in the adaptation of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> le </PERSON> <PERSON> Carre </PERSON>'s best seller `` The <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION> House.'' Ms. <PERSON> Pfeiffer </PERSON> will play <PERSON> Katya </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> editor who smuggles a manuscript to <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. `` I liked her bravery,'' Ms. <PERSON> Pfeiffer </PERSON> said in an interview in Friday's editions of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, adding, `` The idea of shooting a film in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> was also an exciting prospect for me.'' Ms. <PERSON> Pfeiffer </PERSON> was in `` Married to the Mob,'' `` Dangerous Liaisons'' and `` Tequila Sunrise'' last year, and appeared this summer in <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>'s `` Twelfth Night'' in Central Park. After that, `` I just kind of went home and I had a life, went to the grocery and the dry cleaner and the movies,'' she said. Opening next week is `` The Fabulous Baker Boys,'' in which she co-stars with <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> and <PERSON> Beau </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON>. `` I had read the script about five years prior and I fell in love with it, because it's about people, and there are no car chases and not a whole lot of pratfalls,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 0108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-LouisianaReferendum 1stLd-Writethru a0647 10-08 0386</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Louisiana Referendum, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0647,0392</SECOND>
<HEAD>Voters Decide on Amendments Dealing with Highways, Black Judges</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: UPDATES to RECAST throughout with vote count totals nearly complete,
details</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN SAYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A plan to improve and expand <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s highways won solid approval from voters, but proposals to enhance blacks' voting power in electing judges were rejected in Saturday's statewide None of the 13 state amendments to the state constitution on the ballot drew much organized opposition. The only extensive campaigns were for passage of the highway plan; a proposal to make it easier for police to confiscate the property of suspected drug dealers and a measure to set aside at least $ 5 million a year in state mineral revenue to restore eroding wetlands. The drug confiscation and wetlands issues both passed easily. Gov. <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>, who included the highway funding plan as part of a tax revision package that voters rejected April 29, said it would boost efforts to attract new industry to <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and create thousands of construction jobs. With about 94 percent of the votes counted, the amendment had the support of 430,791 voters, or 71 percent, and was opposed by 174,528, or 29 percent. The proposal would put the state's 16-cent motor fuel tax into a trust fund to be used solely for highways and public works projects. It included a 4-cent gasoline tax increase to finance $ 1.4 billion in transportation improvements, including four lanes for major highways and expansion of ports and airports. The two judicial amendments _ defeated by 3-to-1 margins _ would have added a <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> justice and a majority black district in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> area, and created up to 35 black-majority sub-districts for district and appellate courts. The civil rights challenges that prompted the amendments came about because there are no blacks on the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, only one black among the state's 52 appellate court judges, and five black district court judges out of 192. Several tax-related amendments also were on the ballot, including measures to raise the automobile license plate fee; to allow cities and towns to raise property taxes; and to extend from five years to 10 years the current property tax assessment freeze for owners who expand or improve buildings in certain districts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 0121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Pope-Asia 1stLd-Writethru a0515 10-08 0670</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pope-Asia, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0515,0687</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pope Appeals For End to Ideological Rifts</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS thruout to UPDATE with Sunday mass; No pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By C.W. LIM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> appealed Sunday for an end to ideological divisions worldwide and said the bitter struggle that divides north and south <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> symbolized suffering. `` East is divided from west, north from south,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> said at an open air mass attended by 700,000. He appealed for the world to give up mistrust, hostility and conflict `` to live in peace and brotherhood.'' `` The Korean nation is symbolic of a world divided and not yet able to become one in peace and justice,'' the <PERSON> pope </PERSON> said, speaking alternately in Korean and English. The vast crowd, many of whom had lined up before dawn, waved white Korean flags and some wept as the pope entered an immense plaza for the mass. Hundreds of singers burst into hymn as the pope walked along a red carpet toward a four-story stage and altar, tiered with thousands of red, white, yellow and pink flowers and flanked by colorful banners. Plain-clothed South Korean security agents carrying submachine guns ringed the stage, and 11,000 police were deployed on the outskirts of the plaza. Those who attended the mass had to pass through metal detectors. About 2,000 priests, aided by 2,000 women in traditional Korean gowns, served communion, while 1,200 white doves were released as a sign of peace. At an earlier meeting with President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-woo </PERSON>, the pope asked the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> leader to make every effort to achieve full democracy and eradicate the nation's legacy of authoritarian rule, a <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> spokesman said. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> told <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> that <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Koreans </ORGANIZATION> want full democratic rights and freedoms, the spokesman said. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> began his <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> pilgrimage in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> Saturday. About 1,000 dissidents and radical students staged an anti-government rally at <ORGANIZATION> Sogang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> to urge the pope to speak out on human rights abuses in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. An equal number of riot police surrounded the campus, but made no move to halt Saturday's protest. The students dispersed peacefully after demanding the release of jailed dissidents, including South Korean clergymen charged with visiting <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> for unification talks. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> arrived in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> after for the first time flying across the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and sending greetings to Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in a sign of remarkably improved Vatican-Soviet relations. He expressed hope he would soon visit <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. He immediately took up the issue of Korean reunification, which has divided the influential <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> community in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. Addressing himself to the `` dear people of <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> said: `` In the face of the tragic division which continues to separate your own people, do you not have the urgent mission to prove to a world torn by mistrust, strife and hatred that mankind does have the resources to end division and war, and to forge an enduring peace?'' The <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>, divided in 1945, is the site of one of the world's most bitter ideological confrontations. The capitalist South and the totalitarian North, which fought to a bloody stalemate in the Korean War, clash frequently and maintain huge armies along their 150-mile border. They still are technically at war since no peace treaty was signed at the end of the Korean War in 1953. A heated debate broke out in the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> community after a dissident priest visited <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> in July to escort home a radical college student. The two claimed the trip was to promote reunification, but the <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> government called it an illegal contact with an enemy state. The priest and student were arrested when they crossed back across the border. Three other priests were jailed for organizing the priest's trip without government approval. After <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, the pope travels on to <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Timor </LOCATION>, and then to the <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> island nation of <LOCATION> Mauritius </LOCATION>. He is to return to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> Oct. 16. The trip is the Polish-born <PERSON> pope </PERSON>'s 44th foreign pilgrimage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 0121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--AirplaneEvacuation     10-08 0143</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Airplane Evacuation,0147</SECOND>
<HEAD>American Airlines Jet Evacuated After Smoke Sighted</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Passengers used emergency chutes to exit an <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jetliner Saturday after smoke was seen coming from the plane's landing gear, an airline official said. There were no injuries to the 46 passengers and five crew members on board Flight 1333, said <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Stack </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> MD-80 was taxiing down the runway at O'Hare International Airport after landing from Grand Rapids, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, when the pilot of a plane behind it reported seeing smoke coming from the left main landing gear, Stack said. The pilot of Flight 1333 ordered passengers to evacuate the plane by the chute slides as a precautionary measure, <PERSON> Stack </PERSON> said. An initial inspection of the plane determined there was no fire, <PERSON> Stack </PERSON> said, adding the cause of the smoke was under investigation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 0333EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Hijacking 1stLd-Writethru a0516 10-08 0578</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hijacking, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0516,0592</SECOND>
<HEAD>Burmese Support Hijackers; Thailand Won't Repatriate Students</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS thruout with statement by Burmese student association;
No pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANUDEE SIASAKUL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Burmese student group Sunday said the demands of two Burmese hijackers that democracy be returned to their homeland were `` identical to those of the people of <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>.'' `` We regard this -LRB- hijacking -RRB- as a reaction to the current situation in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> where freedom of speech is totally impossible,'' said a press release from the <ORGANIZATION> All </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Burma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Students </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>. On Saturday, <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> said it would not repatriate the students, who hijacked a Burmese domestic flight with 83 others aboard then threatened to blow up the plane if their demands for reform were not met. The Front is the major representative of students who fled central <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> to fight for democracy from camps along the country's borders after the military brutally crushed a student-led uprising there last year It claims that nearly 5,000 students and other dissidents are living in 24 frontier camps under the protection of various ethnic minority groups also battling the military-led government. `` Their demands are identical to those of the people of <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>, and these are the demands we have been relaying the world with our tears and blood since the brutal military takeover in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>,'' said the release, seen in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>. An official media report from <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> Sunday said the hijacking was settled successfully because of good relations between <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>. A Radio Rangoon broadcast gave details of the hijacking Friday by the students, who diverted a <ORGANIZATION> Fokker </ORGANIZATION> 28 domestic airliner to <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> and held 83 people hostage for about 10 hours before surrendering to <LOCATION> Thai </LOCATION> officials. The students are being held in military custody, but <LOCATION> Thai </LOCATION> officials have said they would not be repatriated. `` We will not hurt them. They will not be sent back to <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>,'' Deputy Prime Minister <PERSON> Tienchai </PERSON> <PERSON> Sirisunpan </PERSON> said in a news conference. `` The Burmese government also does not want them back. So far they have not asked for asylum in any country.'' Although <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> has friendly relations with <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>, it does not have an extradition treaty with the military government in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>. `` As I understand it, they want to let the world know what has happened in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>, especially the life without freedom of <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> citizens,'' <PERSON> Tienchai </PERSON> said. The hijackers demands included the release of political prisoners, lifting of martial law, freedom of the press and the formation of an interim government with persons nominated by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, the radio broadcast said. The hijackers also wanted the release of opposition leader <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON> <PERSON> Suu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kyi </PERSON>, the `` governing of the people leniently'' and `` ordering soldiers back to the barracks.'' A military junta seized power in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> in September 1988 following a nationwide uprising to demand an end to a quarter century of authoritarian rule. The military has promised general elections next year, but in July placed under house arrest its leading opponent, <PERSON> Suu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kyi </PERSON>, and has arrested several thousand other dissidents, according to Western sources. The two students initially threatened to blow up the aircraft with what <LOCATION> Thai </LOCATION> officials say was a homemade explosive. <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> is one of the few nations which has tried to establish friendly ties with the military regime and has shown particular interest in exploiting <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s rich natural resources, including teak and fish. <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>'s powerful military has been at the forefront of efforts to develop closer ties.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 0407EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-EastGermany-Anniversary 4thLd-Writethru   10-08 1000</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-East Germany-Anniversary, 4th Ld-Writethru,a0637,1035</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Clash With Demonstrators, Honecker Tells Gorbachev He Won't
Waver</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 8 grafs to UPDATE with NBC saying only one reporter
arrested. Pickup 9th, `In the...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos XBER2,3,8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GIRARD C. STEICHEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 East German leader <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> told Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> on Saturday he would stick to his hard-line course as police battled thousands demonstrating for reform on <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s 40th anniversary. Scores were arrested and dozens injured by police who punched, kicked, beat and dragged away protesters in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> and at least three other cities, witnesses and television reports said. One Western journalist reportedly was detained. An estimated 10,000 people joined the protests. Some 5,000 demonstrators, many shouting `` <LOCATION> Gorby </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Gorby </LOCATION>,'' crowded into the Alexanderplatz square in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> late Saturday. The Soviet leader, whose reform policies have made him a hero to many East Germans, ended his two-day visit Saturday evening and headed back to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. Plainclothes police and uniformed riot officers used force to disperse the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> demonstrators. Police bashed one man's head against a wall. Other protesters were kicked by security police, dragged along the ground to side streets and taken away to jails. Some <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> residents watched the violence from apartment windows. They waved sparklers to show support for the demonstrators. <PERSON> Catherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Field </PERSON>, a reporter for the British newspaper Observer, earlier said authorities detained three Western journalists. But a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> later said only <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Millar </PERSON> of the Sunday Times of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> was held. The report could not be confirmed with East German authorities. In the most widespread protests to hit <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in years, clashes also were reported in <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Dresden </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Potsdam </LOCATION>. Also Saturday, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s foreign minister said there were signs <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> would ease emigration restrictions. A West German newspaper said the plans were intended to clear out those who have criticized conditions in their Communist homeland. The exodus of tens of thousands of East Germans has deeply embarrassed the aging leadership in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> during weekend anniversary celebrations. However, the official East German news agency <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> said that in three hours of talks, <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> told <LOCATION> Gorbachev </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> will adhere to `` the basic values'' of socialism. `` The hopes of bourgeois politicians and ideologues who are aiming for reforms heading to bourgeois democracy and on to capitalism are built on sand,'' <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> was quoted as saying. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> will consistently follow the proven course for the good of the people, in the unity of economic and social policies, continuity and renewal,'' he said. While making clear his aims for communist <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> also expressed support for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s reforms. <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> said the meeting took place in an atmosphere of `` traditional friendship.'' A day earlier, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> urged <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact ally <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> to work with `` all forces in society.'' <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> repeated to <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> a <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> saying that `` he who is late is punished.'' Asked whether that referred to the East German government's repeated rejection of reforms, <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON> said: `` No, we were talking about our experiences But journalists do interpret things.'' <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON> said the issue of the refugee exodus did not come up in the session he attended, the second of two. About 4,000 protesters battled police Saturday in <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION>, according to witnesses and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> ZDF </ORGANIZATION> television network. The witnesses said there were numerous injuries and arrests but it was not clear how many. Police, carrying truncheons and wearing riot helmets and shields, waded into the crowd of protesters and beat them at random, witnesses said. Groups of 10 to 15 policemen were seen chasing demonstrators, who offered no resistance but shouted `` No violence,'' `` Shame on you'' and `` <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>!'' the witnesses said. About 2,000 demonstrators battled police and soldiers overnight in <LOCATION> Dresden </LOCATION> and an unspecified number were injured, witnesses said. It was the fourth night of violence in <LOCATION> Dresden </LOCATION>. Hundreds of police officers attacked the demonstrators, who responded by hurling bottles and other objects, witnesses said. They said the street battles lasted for several hours. West German Foreign Minister <PERSON> Hans-Dietrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON> said Saturday in a TV interview there were signals <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> was about to ease emigration restrictions for its citizens. The West German <ORGANIZATION> Bild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> am </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sonntag </ORGANIZATION> newspaper reported that <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> was planning `` a massive expulsion of annoying citizens.' It is thought that more than a million people have asked to leave <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, although the government has not provided any statistics. Western tourists were barred from <LOCATION> Communist </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> for a third day. New barriers were put up overnight at the Checkpoint Charlie crossing. A disturbance broke out at the checkpoint Saturday when a man with a crowbar hacked and hammered at the new metal barriers from the Western side. A crowd of about 200 people on the western side taunted East German guards watching the disturbance, and pelted them with pieces of metal, cans and clumps of dirt. The guards did not react. Tanks, rocket transporters and goose-stepping East German soldiers paraded down <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Karl </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marx </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boulevard </ORGANIZATION> early Saturday in a celebration of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s founding on Oct. 7, 1949. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> observed the military display. The military nature of the parade drew a protest from Western allies <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, who called it a `` provocation as well as a violation of the city's demilitarized status.'' ADN said the parade showed the country's determination `` to always protect what the workers have produced in four decades.'' But the government had difficulty portraying the nation as a socialist success. More than 47,000 people have fled <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> since mid-September, across <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s western border or through West German embassies in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. Many have complained of repression and a low standard of living. Bavarian border police said Saturday that 662 East German refugees arrived in the West German state over the past 24 hours, all through <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> opened the border Sept. 11.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 0507EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-India-Crash     10-08 0371</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-India-Crash,0387</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jet Fighter Crashes During Exhibition Flight, Killing Pilot</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto DEL1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SHARON HERBAUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Mirage 2000 fighter jet crashed and exploded Sunday during a final acrobatic maneuver on Indian Air Force Day, killing the pilot who had attempted an extra roll, officials said. No one on the ground was killed, but some of the 2,000 spectators suffered sprained ankles or bruises running to or from the site, they said. The silver delta-winged aircraft of French design was completing a climb known as a `` Vertical Charlie'' when it plunged to the ground about 300 yards from a reviewing stand at <LOCATION> Palam </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> in west <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>. Military and civilian dignitaries, journalists and other guests had watched the parade of 650 enlisted men and an aerial display. The pilot, identified as Wing Commander <PERSON> Ramesh </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakshi </PERSON>, the 39-year-old commander of the Mirage squadron, was killed instantly, <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Chief Marshal S.K. <PERSON> Mehra </PERSON> said. He told reporters the accident apparently was caused by `` an error in judgment.'' <PERSON> Mehra </PERSON> said the sky was hazy and may have disoriented <PERSON> Bakshi </PERSON>. The plane was about 18 feet from the ground when the pilot tried the maneuver, he said. The Mirage was completing the final flyby during the parade marking the 57th anniversary of the Indian air force and honoring its 115,000 officers. Air Marshal <PERSON> N.C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Suri </PERSON>, vice chief of the air staff, said <PERSON> Bakshi </PERSON> was only supposed to perform three rolls in the finale. Instead, the officer said, he attempted four. The plane made a steep climb, then descended making three loops and rolls, he said. After failing to complete a fourth roll, the pilot was unable to pull out of the descent and the plane hurtled to the ground, he said. Some spectators gasped and several air force wives ran toward the burning wreckage. The aircraft slammed into the ground, exploded and bounced three times through fuel tanks, igniting a huge fireball. Several vehicles parked in the area were badily damaged by the burning chunks. The Mirage is capable of flying up to 1,460 miles an hour at an altitude of 65,600 feet. The Indian air force bought 49 Mirage 2000 planes between 1982 and 1986.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 0544EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-SriLanka     10-08 0352</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Sri Lanka,0368</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jaffna Newspaper Staff Abducted, Allegedly by Tamils</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PATRICK CRUEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLOMBO, Sri Lanka (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tamil guerrillas abducted 18 journalists from their newspaper office and said they would be put to work on a new Tamil publication, a reporter who fled during the raid said Sunday. The armed militants burst into the <LOCATION> Jaffna </LOCATION> offices of <LOCATION> Eelanadu </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>'s oldest Tamil language newspaper, on Thursday, the journalist said in <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>. He said he was one of five reporters who bolted to freedom before the abductors drove away with the reporters. The journalist asked not to be identified out of fear for his safety. `` I want to go back to <LOCATION> Jaffna </LOCATION> and my newspaper,'' he said. The <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION> office of Eelanadu, which means <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> in Tamil, confirmed the attack but gave no details. The journalist said the gunmen belonged to the <ORGANIZATION> Eelam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peoples </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, which is supported by <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and opposes the largest Tamil militia, the <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tamil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eelam </ORGANIZATION>. According to the journalist, the abductors said they were going to publish a new newspaper called <PERSON> Viduthalai </PERSON>, which means liberation in the Tamil language. He has provided reliable information in the past. The <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION> are fighting Indian peacekeeping troops sent to <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> to disarm them in 1987. The Liberation Front and other Tamil militants accepted the Indian-brokered peace plan. The Front and the <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION> once jointly sought independence for the Tamil minority in <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>, where the government and military are dominated by the Sinhalese majority. The ethnic violence in Tamil-dominated northeastern <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> has claimed more than 11,000 lives in the past six years. The <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> closed Eelanadu and two other Tamil newspapers in <LOCATION> Jaffna </LOCATION>, 180 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>, on Sept. 20 after the publications carried paid advertisements commemorating the second anniversary of the death of a Tiger rebel leader. In February, the <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION> blew up <PERSON> Eelanadu </PERSON>'s offices after the newspaper carried stories that the <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION> considered pro-Indian. Eelanadu, which was founded 30 years ago and has a circulation of 10,000, resumed publication in May with a skeleton staff.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 1118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Bus-CarWreck     10-08 0094</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Bus-Car Wreck,0095</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Killed, 35 Injured In Bus-Car Collision</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A tour bus collided head-on with a car, skidded off a road and overturned, killing three people and injuring 35, police said. The accident occurred Saturday on the main road between <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> and the Hungarian border, and all the casualties were bus passengers. The cause of the crash between the Austrian tour bus and the car, which had Hungarian license plates, was not known. The accident occurred between the towns of <PERSON> Bruck </PERSON> @ <LOCATION> Leitha </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Parndorf </LOCATION>, 25 miles east of <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 1118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF-CrookedLawyers     10-08 0150</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF-Crooked Lawyers,0153</SECOND>
<HEAD>Five Lawyers Arrested in Robbery Ring</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Five Pakistani lawyers have been charged with robbing a bank, stealing 14 automobiles and killing one of their accomplices, a newspaper report Sunday. They were arrested over the weekend in <LOCATION> Multan </LOCATION>, a city in southern <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>, according to the English-language daily newspaper <PERSON> Dawn </PERSON>. Deputy Police Superintendent <PERSON> Hafeez </PERSON> <PERSON> Rajput </PERSON> said the arresting officers recovered four cars, firearms and $ 33,000 in cash. Among other things, the five were accused of robbing a <ORGANIZATION> Pakistan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> branch of $ 67,000 on July 2. <PERSON> Rajput </PERSON> said the suspects told police they set aside half the money for a trip abroad and half for spending in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. But when a sixth member of the ring began spending lavishly in a manner that could draw suspicion, they murdered him and hid his body, according to the report. It said the investigation was continuing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 1118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-NorthernIreland     10-08 0223</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Northern Ireland,0229</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Arrest 28 in Leaked Security Documents Cases</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BELFAST, Northern Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police said they arrested 28 people Sunday in connection with the recent leaks of security files identifying alleged <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> suspects. The Royal Ulster Constabulary would not comment on British news reports that the detainees were members of the <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regiment </ORGANIZATION>, the locally recruited and mostly part-time force of the British army. A police spokesman, speaking anonymously in keeping with British custom, said 300 uniformed and plainclothes officers were involved in raids on 30 houses during which security documents and ammunition were also seized. Charges had not been filed. The raids follow an investigation by Deputy Chief Constable <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Cambridgeshire </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, police force into allegations that a group of police and <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regiment </ORGANIZATION> members leaked secret files on <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> suspects to the media. Protestant gunmen have claimed they used such documents to pick targets, including a Roman Catholic man slain in August. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> said in a statement that `` a number of men'' were arrested and houses searched in the greater <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> area as part of the inquiry. The <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> is fighting to end British rule in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and unite the predominantly <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> province with the <LOCATION> Roman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Catholic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. The 20-year struggle has claimed more than 2,700 lives.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 1118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Chess     10-08 0201</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Chess,0208</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yusupov Postpones Fifth Game Until Tuesday</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Artur </PERSON> <PERSON> Yusupov </PERSON> took a timeout Sunday, postponing until Tuesday the fifth game of his World Chess Championship Candidates' semifinal with fellow Soviet <PERSON> Anatoly </PERSON> <PERSON> Karpov </PERSON>. Organizers said the fifth round of the other semifinal between <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Timman </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> and British Grandmaster <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Speelman </PERSON> would be played as scheduled Sunday night. Each semifinalist is allowed to take one timeout during the eight-game contests. <PERSON> Yusupov </PERSON>, who trails 1.5-2 .5, is the first of the four candidates' to do so A win scores one point and a draw one-half point. <PERSON> Timman </PERSON> led <PERSON> Speelman </PERSON> 2-1 with an unfinished game from the fourth round Saturday. Play in the adjourned game was scheduled to resume on Monday. The winners of the semifinals will face off in the final in March. The winner of that series will challenge world champion <PERSON> Garri </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasparov </PERSON> in a 24-game match in October 1990. <PERSON> Yusupov </PERSON> will use the extra time to prepare for the fifth game, in which he will open with the advantage of the white pieces. But the free days will also permit <PERSON> Karpov </PERSON>, playing below par in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> despite his lead, time to try to recover his form.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 1119EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Rickshaw-Strike     10-08 0152</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Rickshaw-Strike,0159</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rickshaw Strike Paralyzes Bangladesh Capital</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DHAKA, Bangladesh (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rickshaw drivers struck for eight hours Sunday to protest traffic rules, and police patrolled the city to prevent violence. Most motorists stayed off the streets fearing unrest, but none was reported. Government offices remained open, staffed by employees who were able to walk to work. Privately owned banks and businesses shut down. The bicycle-powered rickshaws are the most common form of transportation in <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>, a city of 6 million people. The drivers were protesting efforts to outlaw unlicensed rickshaws. Only about a third of the capital's 100,000 rickshaws are licensed. The strikers also protested a rule barring them from certain streets, including one running past <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>'s two luxury hotels. The ban forces them to pedal a mile or more out of their way to reach their passengers' destinations. About 200,000 men and their families depend on rickshaws for their livelihood.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 1150EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Israel     10-08 0647</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel,0668</SECOND>
<HEAD>Palestinians Urge U.S. Role in Middle East</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By G.G. LaBELLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Palestinian leaders urged the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on Sunday to pressure <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to begin peace talks and said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s rejection of a proposed meeting with Palestinians in <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> will lead to more violence in the uprising A leading <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> politician, <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Shahal </PERSON>, said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> help in choosing <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> delegates to talk with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> could `` rescue the political situation'' following Friday's rejection of the Egypt-sponsored dialogue. In the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, businesses were closed by a general strike, the first of a three-day shutdown ordered by the uprising's PLO-backed underground leaders to step up the revolt against Israeli rule of the lands. The Israeli army closed off the territories Sunday afternoon, blocking Palestinians from entering <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> Yom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kippur </LOCATION>, the Jewish day of atonement, which began at sundown. <PERSON> Radwan </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Ayyash </PERSON>, one of the Palestinian leaders reportedly suggested by <LOCATION> Egyptian </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> to meet with <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> representatives, said only <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pressure would lead to the dialogue suggested by the Egyptian president. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> must take a more active and serious role to convince the Israelis to hold the meeting proposed by <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>,'' he said in a telephone interview. <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Ayyash </PERSON> _ head of the <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalists </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and a supporter of <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s mainstream <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> faction, <ORGANIZATION> Fatah </ORGANIZATION> _ urged the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government to step up its dialogue with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> `` to counter the Israeli decision.'' <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>'s offer was rejected because Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> bloc objected to the Egyptian leader's call to include Palestinians deported from the occupied territories in peace talks <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> said including the exiles would amount to allowing the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> into the peace process. The center-left <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION>'s partner in the coalition government, urged <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to accept <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>'s offer. But the policy-making inner Cabinet vote produced a 6-6 tie along political lines, which amounted to a rejection of the Egyptian offer. <PERSON> Assad </PERSON> <PERSON> Saftawi </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> school principal and another reported choice of <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> for the talks, said he was shocked that <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>'s offer was rejected. `` The decision will bring waves of violence and extremism,'' <PERSON> Saftawi </PERSON> said. `` The blame is on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Saftawi </PERSON> and <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Ayyash </PERSON> predicted more violence in the Palestinian uprising if there were no progress toward peace. The revolt, which begins its 23rd month Monday, already has led to the deaths of 585 Palestinians and 40 Israelis. `` Palestinian moderation has its limits. If there is no achievement, then our people will go back to extremism,'' <PERSON> Saftawi </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>. Members of Likud maintained, meanwhile, that the inner Cabinet vote did not halt progress toward peace. `` The peace process ... does not depend on one vote in the Cabinet,'' said <PERSON> Ehud </PERSON> <PERSON> Olmert </PERSON>, the minister in charge of <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> affairs. He told <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> that the government could still agree to meet a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> delegation if the members were acceptable to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. His Likud colleague, Foreign Minister <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Arens </PERSON>, blamed last week's rejection on the `` stubbornness'' of Labor in forcing a vote on <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>'s proposal. He said the vote should have been put off until after <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> received an expected <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> proposal to assist in forming a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> delegation to the peace talks. But <PERSON> Shahal </PERSON>, energy minister in the coalition <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Arens </PERSON> never requested a delay and came to Friday's meeting with only a vague notion of what the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> might propose. `` If there is an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> proposal, which we have n't heard explicitly from the foreign minister ... this could rescue the political situation,'' he said. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, speaking on the radio in a Yom Kippur address, called Israelis `` seekers of peace'' but said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has survived only through armed might. `` The army ... has proved to our enemies and the whole world that it is impossible to defeat us,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 1217EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-HUD-Dean     10-08 0792</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-HUD-Dean,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Dean Files Confirm Her Power, Politics At HUD</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: St German, no period, is cq</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When then-House <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Fernand </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> St </PERSON> <PERSON> Germain </PERSON> asked for help from the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> in June 1985, an agency official asked <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> whether he should get it. `` Absolutely!!!'' was her short, but emphatic, answer. And when Sen. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> wrote <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> about a problem in his state not long before an important vote, <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> swung into action. `` This looks like trouble,'' she wrote an aide. `` We need <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> too much. ... Please call him, tell him that we'll do whatever we can.'' But when <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> wanted her boss, <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, to accompany him to a housing project devastated by a hurricane, <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> frowned at the request. `` Respectfully decline,'' she wrote. Those episodes, detailed in more than 20,000 pages of <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>'s files, are but three of hundreds of glimpses of the politics of <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, and of the power <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> held as <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s close aide <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>, who had no experience in housing and only a brief stint in government before coming to work at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>, is a central figure in the congressional investigation of favoritism and mismanagement at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>. Like <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, she has refused to testify by citing her right against self-incrimination. Her files show she was also a central figure in agency affairs, keeping <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> apprised of important developments, endorsing projects she liked and cracking down on work that did n't satisfy her. `` You all must bear down _ no more garbage for -LRB- <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s -RRB- signature,'' she said in a July 1985 note to three <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> officials who worked on a letter for <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>. `` He deserves better work from his assistants. Review my notes and do four Hail <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>'s.'' When a request from someone who could help <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> _ like <ORGANIZATION> St </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Germain </ORGANIZATION>, whose committee controlled the agency's budget _ reached <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>'s desk, she made sure it was handled quickly, often sending critical notes to aides who had not responded to the requests sooner. She was just as keenly aware of the other side of the political fence, rejecting <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> appearances with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and another prominent black, South African Archbishop <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON>, both of whom had major differences with the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. Her files, released last week under the Freedom of Information Act, show she was swamped with requests for help from developers, consultants, local housing officials, city councilors and mayors, and members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. For some, she arranged meetings or telephone conversations with <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>. For others, she made sure their proposals were routed to the proper agency official, sometimes adding her endorsement. `` Please give these people all the help you can,'' she wrote to a deputy when sending him a proposal for a <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> grant, which was later approved. On occasion, she even delved into the realm of social director _ securing <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> tour passes for then-Columbus, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> Councilor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cain </PERSON> in 1983 and an invitation to a dinner in honor of former President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> for one of <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s former law partners in 1985. `` My family and I enjoyed the tour very much,'' <PERSON> Cain </PERSON> said in a thank-you note to <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>. Although she wrote flowery letters to some of the most powerful people in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> took a jab at many of them in a note to an aide who had sent her a copy of a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s magazine's 1985 list of the capital's `` Social 400,'' which did not bear her name `` With the exception of <ORGANIZATION> Ron </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> -RRB- and <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> & amp; <PERSON> Liddy </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> -RRB-, I would n't be seen with any of them!'' she wrote. Among others on the list: <PERSON> George </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, Cabinet secretaries <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, several <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> justices and dozens of senators and representatives, not to mention the richest of the rich. Her notes also show signs of the sense of humor friends and colleagues often recall. `` Ba Humbug! I'm not giving back anything!'' she scribbled on a memo detailing policy against accepting gifts from government vendors. She also was fiercely protective of <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, keeping a close eye on HUD-related news accounts and once warning a public affairs aide not to include in an internal newsletter some derogatory questions employees had submitted for <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>. Among them: `` Why do you stay in a job that you wanted to leave after the election when the president is attempting to eliminate your key programs?'' and `` Would you like to live out the rest of your life in a deregulated nursing home?'' When she sent a copy of the questions to <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, she scribbled one of her frequent one-word notes: `` Incredible!''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 1220EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-FraternityHazing Bjt   10-08 0932</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fraternity Hazing, Bjt,0955</SECOND>
<HEAD>From Alpha to Omega, Fraternities Debate Merits of Pledging</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE MITGANG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 An anti-hazing campaign aimed at countering the image of Greek rows as gin-soaked `` Animal Houses'' appears to be gaining this fall on campuses from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> to <ORGANIZATION> Dartmouth </ORGANIZATION>. Worried by their image, as well as the possibility of lawsuits, fraternities around the country are moving to eliminate hazing. Some want to eliminate pledging, the practice of having a period between the recruitment of a member and his formal initiation when hazing is most likely. In August, two of the nation's largest fraternities, <PERSON> Tau </PERSON> <PERSON> Kappa </PERSON> <PERSON> Epsilon </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Zeta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tau </ORGANIZATION>, decided that the most effective way to end hazing was to ban pledging altogether in their chapters. <PERSON> Kappa </PERSON> <PERSON> Delta </PERSON> <PERSON> Rho </PERSON> also approved a long-range plan that includes a move to no pledging by 1995. Phi Sigma Kappa amended its constitution to allow for experimentation with non-pledge programs. Alpha Epsilon Pi introduced new membership education programs. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interfraternity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, which represents fraternities at 900 college campuses, weighed in with an anti-hazing campaign of its own in September, stressing that the image of fraternities everywhere was suffering from hazing incidents that harmed pledges physically or psychologically. `` It's not a concern for decreasing membership,'' said <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brant </PERSON>, executive director of the Indianapolis-based council. `` We're just really fed up with the perception that silly and dangerous things occur on the college campus, and fraternities are sometimes associated with those things.'' `` What has empowered us in making our case to fraternities is that we are painfully aware that the stakes have been raised in legal liability,'' <PERSON> Brant </PERSON> said. Fraternity brothers on many campuses still resist the idea of ditching the time-honored practice of putting new members through physical or mental ordeals before their formal initiation, despite excesses that have led to 40 deaths and hundreds of injuries in the last decade nationwide. `` I really do n't think you can form any sort of loyalty to a house without pledging,'' said <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Colafella </PERSON>, a sophomore initiated last month into <ORGANIZATION> Alpha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sigma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Phi </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Penn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` The oneness that you show with the brotherhood, the thing you have in common, is the trials and tribulations that got you there.'' Some 400,000 undergraduate men and 250,000 undergraduate women belong to Greek organizations in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. After a slump in membership from 1965 through the 1970s, Greek organizations have grown steadily over the last decade. Hazing has continued at some campuses this fall, including one notorious case at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mississippi </ORGANIZATION>, where Beta Theta Pi pledges were abandoned bound and naked last month on the campus of <ORGANIZATION> Rust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, a predominantly black school, with `` KKK'' and a racist epithet painted on their chests. But many fraternities are looking for better ways to initiate members. At <ORGANIZATION> USC </ORGANIZATION>, for example, Theta Xi is dropping pledging this fall and will instead require candidates to complete educational programs to acquaint them with active members and the mores of the house. <ORGANIZATION> Phi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sigma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kappa </ORGANIZATION> will scrap pledging and replace it with four weeks of informal rushing, said chapter president <PERSON> Darrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoyama </PERSON>. The house is recruiting prospective members by making friends and inviting them to the chapter. Those who decide to rush have to pass a test on the fraternity's traditions, history and rules. `` I think it's a lot more positive,'' <PERSON> Aoyama </PERSON> said. `` How can you expect the person to be your friend after you treat him like dirt?'' But Tau Kappa Epsilon member <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Koh </PERSON>, whose fraternity will abolish pledging in two years, said: `` The most disgusting thing in the world is to get rid of pledging. It no longer becomes a fraternity, it becomes a club. If you ask anybody, their pledge semester was the funnest.'' At the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION>, where 28 percent of the 16,000 undergraduates belong to one of 46 Greek organizations, ZBT President <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> said his group is following the anti-pledging program this fall as laid out in a 400-page manual issued by the national fraternity. But some brothers do n't understand why they ca n't do the same things that were done to them as pledges, he said. The chapter has about 100 members. `` It's like if you've been swinging a golf club one way all your life and all of a sudden this guy comes up to you and he says you're doing it wrong and you have to change,'' <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> said. `` You're going to have trouble changing your swing. At <ORGANIZATION> Tulane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, where 32 percent of male and 40 percent of female undergraduates belong to Greek organizations, ZBT President <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Randman </PERSON> said the no-pledge rule is `` just about the only way a fraternity can go these days.'' The tighter rules, he added, spare him from `` looking over my shoulder and worrying as much as I might have been in the past when people had been able to run pretty much free.'' <PERSON> Randman </PERSON> said the pledge semester has been replaced with a four-week educational period during which older members work to make the freshmen part of the group and a cohesive class unto themselves. `` Since my freshman year it has changed a lot,'' said <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Switek </PERSON>, a senior and president of <ORGANIZATION> Bones </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fraternity </ORGANIZATION>, one of the largest at <ORGANIZATION> Dartmouth </ORGANIZATION>, where 58 percent of undergraduates join fraternities or sororities. Now, school officials insist that such organizations give details of their rush plans. `` A lot of people thought what they had to go through was humiliating and did n't want others to have to go through the same thing,'' <PERSON> Switek </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 1241EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Israel-YomKippur     10-08 0619</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel-Yom Kippur,0636</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israelis Pray and Fast On Day of Atonement</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ARIEH O'SULLIVAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As night fell Sunday, Jews throughout <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> marked the start of their holiest day, Yom Kippur, with fasting and prayers of penitence. Traffic on the nation's highways and streets came to a halt, commercial flights were suspended and the border with <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and bridges to <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> were closed. State-run <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> and television and the army radio ceased broadcasts, leaving the country without communications for the solemn holiday, which ends at sundown Monday. Although most Israelis are secular, Yom Kippur is widely observed and many flock to the nation's almost 8,000 synagogues for prayer services. It is traditional for Jews to refrain from taking food and water during the 24-hour holiday. Jews beg God for forgiveness and pray for life and peace during Yom Kippur, also known as the `` Day of Atonement.'' It is traditional for men to wear a white robe, called a kitle, symbolizing purity, during holiday services and to refrain from wearing leather shoes as a symbol of humility. Israeli families often take advantage of the quiet by walking down major roadways to synagogues. In past years, cars that ventured out on <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> streets were sometimes stoned by religous zealots. Appeals were broadcast on the radio to allow ambulances to pass freely. Tens of thousands of Jews traditionally gather at the Western Wall, Judaism's holiest site. The wall is the last remnant of the temple destroyed by the Romans in 70 A.D. Many Jews spend the entire 24-hour fast day praying at the site. Early Sunday, some orthodox Jews went to markets to carry out the ancient rite of kapparot. Waving live chickens over their head, they prayed that their sins would be transferred to the sacrificial chicken. Afterward, the chickens were slaughtered and given to the poor. Yom Kippur ends the 10 `` Days of Awe'' that begin on <PERSON> Rosh </PERSON> <PERSON> Hashana </PERSON>, the Jewish New Year. Jews believe that during the period God decides each person's destiny over the next year. The Days of Awe are traditionally filled with prayer, and many Jews greet each other by saying `` May you be inscribed in the Book of Life.'' This Yom Kippur marked the 16th anniversary of the 1973 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war, which began when Egyptian and Syrian armies launched a suprise attack on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Fierce battles were fought on the <LOCATION> Golan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION> and in the Sinai desert and <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> armies briefly threatened to invade <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> itself. Every year at this time, bereaved families lay wreaths and flowers at the gravesites of the almost 3,000 Israeli troops who fell in the war. Israeli newspapers on Sunday printed reminiscences and commentaries about the war, and many families placed notices in newspapers memorializing relatives who died as soldiers. One of the first communal settlements in the country, <PERSON> Kibbutz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mizra </PERSON>, put an ad in several papers listing seven members ages 19 to 48 who were killed in the war. `` Nearly everyone had a close friend or relative that was killed,'' said kibbutz secretary <PERSON> Edna </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenbald </PERSON>. `` Until today, we have still not recovered.'' In a special broadcast to the nation, Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> paid tribute to those who fell. To prevent a repeat of the suprise attack and halt any guerrilla infiltrations, the military placed forces on high alert Sunday, <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> said. Palestinians in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> began a three-day strike to coincide with Yom Kippur and step up the uprising against <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> rule of the territories. Monday marks the beginning of the 23rd month of the rebellion. The army announced Saturday that travel between the occupied lands and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> would be barred during the holiday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 1250EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People     10-08 1014</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People,1055</SECOND>
<HEAD>People in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos NY44, LON1</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pop singer <PERSON> Julian </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON> made $ 450,000 on the sale of the mountaintop home, a former <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> building that he bought just 10 months ago, according to a published report. In December, the son of the late <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON> paid $ 1,050,000 for the former World War II bunker, built in the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monica </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and later converted to a residence. The young <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON> sold the one-acre property for $ 1.5 million, the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. The newspaper quoted unidentified real estate sources as saying the 4,000-square-foot residence was in bad shape, with some floors ripped out and a rude British expression meaning `` go away'' painted on the roof to discourage photographers and fans from flying over.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SANTA CRUZ, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Followers threw flowers as the <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON>, newly named Nobel laureate, paid a visit to the <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vajrapani </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION> mountains. About 1,000 people lined a dirt road leading up to the temple at the tiny retreat Saturday to greet <PERSON> Tenzin </PERSON> <PERSON> Gyatso </PERSON>, the 14th <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON>, exiled leader of <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> and winner last week of the Nobel Peace Prize for his non-violent efforts to free his country from Chinese domination. Dressed in maroon and saffron robes and riding in a gray <ORGANIZATION> Jaguar </ORGANIZATION>, he blew a kiss to the crowd as many threw roses. `` If you were a Catholic and the pope came to visit your parish, it's about the same thing,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwartz </PERSON>, one of the members of the <LOCATION> Vajrapani </LOCATION> community. After blessing the temple, the <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON> delivered a message of peace, wisdom and compassion to an audience of 2,000 in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION>. `` Compassion and love is the key thing. On the family level, the national level, the international level. It is is the key to success and happiness,'' he said from a flower-surrounded armchair at the Civic Auditorium.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Spelling in letters is cq</NOTE>
<DATELINE>OLD SAYBROOK, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Once upon a time, children wrote to <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION> to make their dreams come true. Now, they write to <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>. Third-graders at <ORGANIZATION> Kathleen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> E. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Goodwin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> sent letters to the billionaire developer Friday _ by <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION>, no less _ asking him to buy an antique carousel to save it from being broken up and auctioned off. `` Dear Mr. Trumps,'' reads one of the letters, written by <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON> <PERSON> Plancon </PERSON>. `` Please buy the carousel. We need it bad. ... All the kids like it. You are the riches one in the country.'' If the carousel is sold, <PERSON> Valerie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hacker </PERSON> wrote, `` it will be bracking children's hearts because children like amusement parks a lot.'' <PERSON> Jude </PERSON> <PERSON> Harmon </PERSON> was hard-nosed, trying to appeal to <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>'s legendary business savvy _ and ego `` It is worth more if you buy it,'' <PERSON> Jude </PERSON> wrote. `` Children adore it. If they destroy it they will break all 5,000 kids hearts plus my whole school.'' Since 1927, the wooden merry-go-round has been the main attraction at <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Quassapaug </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Amusement </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> in nearby <LOCATION> Middlebury </LOCATION>. The family owned park has been hit by rising insurance premiums that the owners say make the carousel, built in 1899, an economic burden they no longer can afford. The carousel is to be auctioned off Oct. 21. Recent appraisals put its value at more than $ 1 million. A spokeswoman for <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> said Friday that the children's plea would be reviewed by <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>'s office. <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>'s executive assistant, <PERSON> Norma </PERSON> <PERSON> Foerderer </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> receives about a thousand requests a day for charitable contributions.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Bellamy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> have written a song saluting farmers and will perform it at a ceremony attended by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The country duo will sing `` Salt of the Earth'' Nov. 9 at the dedication of the National Farmers Memorial in <LOCATION> Bonner </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, spokeswoman <PERSON> Bridget </PERSON> <PERSON> Dolan </PERSON> said Friday. The <ORGANIZATION> Bellamy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> were host of a recent golf tournament to help raise funds for the memorial. Their hit songs include `` Let Your Love Flow'' and `` If I Said You Had a Beautiful Body, Would You Hold It Against Me?''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The British <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> honored actress <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON> with their Tribute Award for her contribution to film. Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>'s daughter, Princess <PERSON> Anne </PERSON>, presented the award Saturday night to the 54-year-old English-born performer and called her a `` tremendous ambassador for <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>.'' Among the celebrities gathered at the <LOCATION> Odeon </LOCATION> theater in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> were actor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Coburn </PERSON>, who appeared with <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON> in `` The Americanization of Emily,'' and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, who starred with her in `` Thoroughly Modern Millie.'' Others who paid tribute by videotape included <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyke </PERSON>, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Garner </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dudley </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, who starred with <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON> in the film `` 10.'' Miss <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON> began her career as a singer on the British stage at the age of 12. At 22 she starred in the musical `` My Fair Lady'' on the Broadway stage. She became a film star with her debut as <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Poppins </PERSON> in the 1964 <ORGANIZATION> Walt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> movie, for which she won an Oscar.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Composer <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Webber </PERSON> says he's giving up musicals, at least temporarily, to try his hand at producing films. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Webber </PERSON> said a film version of his hit musical `` Phantom of the Opera'' could be his first project. `` I doubt if I'll write another musical for the theater for the time being,'' he said Saturday. `` I would love to make a film.'' <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Webber </PERSON>'s plays also include `` Aspects of Love,'' `` Cats'' and `` Starlight Express.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SINGAPORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> was to arrive Monday for a three-day visit to <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> at the invitation of President Wee Kim Wee, the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said. The queen will call on Wee and meet with Prime Minister <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuan </PERSON> <PERSON> Yew </PERSON>, the ministry said Sunday. Wee is to give a state banquet in her honor. The queen's program also includes visits to the waterfront, a primary school, parts of <LOCATION> Chinatown </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Kranji </LOCATION> War Memorial Cemetery before her departure Wednesday aboard the royal yacht Britannia.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 1258EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-India-Crash     10-08 0458</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-India-Crash,0469</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fighter Plane Crashes At Air Force Ceremonies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SHARON HERBAUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fighter jet crashed and exploded in a giant fireball at ceremonies honoring the Indian air force Sunday after the pilot apparently misjudged the plane's altitude and tried an extra acrobatic maneuver, officials said. About 2,000 military and civilian dignitaries, journalists and other guests watched in horror as the French-designed Mirage 2000 plunged to earth about 300 yards from a reviewing stand, killing the pilot. No one on the ground was killed. Some spectators suffered sprained ankles or bruises while running either toward or away from the burning wreckage. The silver delta-winged aircraft was completing a maneuver known as a `` vertical <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON>,'' the finale of a 20-minute aerial display of 22 of the air force's supersonic fighters, transport and training aircraft. An inquiry was ordered to determine what caused the crash, the first major accident at an Indian military airshow. The pilot was identified as <PERSON> Ramesh </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakshi </PERSON>, the 39-year-old commander of the Mirage squadron. Air Force Chief Marshal S.K. <PERSON> Mehra </PERSON> told reporters the accident apparently was due to `` an error in judgment.'' <PERSON> Mehra </PERSON> said the sky was very hazy and <PERSON> Bakshi </PERSON> may have miscalculated the jet's altitude. When the pilot started to pull up, <PERSON> Mehra </PERSON> said, the plane was about 18 feet from the ground. If the jet had been 12 feet higher, <PERSON> Bakshi </PERSON> probably could have made it, he said. `` He was one of our most experienced pilots,'' <PERSON> Mehra </PERSON> said. The Mirage was completing the final flyby of Indian Air Force Day, marking the 57th anniversary of the Indian air force and honoring its 115,000 enlisted men. The ceremony was held at the military section of <LOCATION> Palam </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> in west <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>, and all civilian flights were halted during the show. The aircraft slammed into the ground, exploded and bounced three times through fuel tanks on the ground, igniting a giant fireball. Two buses caught fire and several trucks and other vehicles in the area were badly damaged by burning chunks of debris. The Mirage is capable of flying up to 1,460 mph at an altitude of 65,600 feet. The first Mirages came off the assembly line in 1966. The Indian air force acquired 49 Mirage 2000 fighters between 1982 and 1986. The jets are considered an essential part of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s fleet, which includes other French-designed aircraft and some of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s most sophisticated planes, helicopters and fighters Military experts from <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact countries have rated the skills of <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> air force pilots among the world's best. But they gave them low marks for aircraft maintenance. At least 30 accidents, most involving the Soviet-made MiG-27 fighters, have occurred in the past four years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891008-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-89 1300EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-GeriatricJets 880   10-08 0858</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Geriatric Jets, 880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Concern Over Aging Airliners Bringing New FAA Action</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
