<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SpruanceGrounding     11-29 0474</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Spruance Grounding,0489</SECOND>
<HEAD>Navy: Junior Officer's Errors Caused Destroyer Grounding</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JACKSONVILLE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A junior officer who ignored advice from a lower-ranking navigator was to blame for the January grounding of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> destroyer USS Spruance on a reef off the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> report says. The <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times-Union </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION> published the report Tuesday after obtaining it through a Freedom of Information Act request. The report contains the final results of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s investigation `` The grounding of Spruance was not an act of God, was not due to equipment failure and was not the result of bad weather,'' the report said. `` It was caused by a combination of personnel errors and misjudgments which, when compressed into a short period of time, created a situation that put Spruance aground.'' Though the Mayport-based Spruance was performing maneuvers with another ship and a submarine, neither the ship's commanding officer nor the executive officer was on the bridge when the 7,800-ton ship hit bottom, the report said. Shortly after the accident, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> removed Cmdr. <PERSON> Travis </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> as the ship's skipper and reassigned the executive officer, Lt. Cmdr. J.M. <PERSON> Braeckel </PERSON>. The junior officer in command when the grounding occurred, Lt. W.T. <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON>, was discharged from the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. The Spruance's hull, propellers, sonar dome and forward mast were damaged in the accident and required $ 1.4 million in repairs. The Spruance was preparing to join an anti-submarine warfare exercise with the guided-missile frigate <PERSON> Boone </PERSON> and the nuclear-powered submarine <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> off <LOCATION> Andros </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> last Jan. 15. In the late evening, <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON>, in command on the bridge, ordered a series of course and speed changes to proceed with the rendezvous. The destroyer was just over a half-mile off the reef when the maneuvers began. When <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON> considered a course change that would move the ship closer to the reef, the report said he was advised against it by Petty Officer 1st Class E.G. <PERSON> Yeargin </PERSON>, a quartermaster. Another officer, Lt. j.g. J.S. <PERSON> Lindgren </PERSON>, agreed. <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON> ordered the course change but agreed to slow the ship to just over 3 mph. He then ignored four recommendations from <PERSON> Yeargin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lindgren </PERSON> to change course to avoid the reef, according to the report. An officer and an enlisted man in the ship's combat information center then recommended another course change to expedite the rendezvous, but that would have led the ship `` directly through the shoal water,'' the report said. <PERSON> Yeargin </PERSON> objected and demanded a course change, but <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON> ignored him again. Four minutes later, the ship ran aground. Among other findings, the report found that charts used aboard the Spruance had not been properly updated and reefs were not highlighted as they should have been. In addition, the report faulted the <LOCATION> Spruance </LOCATION>'s staff for failing to calculate the effects of rough seas on the ship at slow speeds.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0055EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-KindergartenCram     11-29 0882</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Kindergarten Cram,0909</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japanese Childrem Cram for Elementary School Entrance Exams</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID THURBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kieko </PERSON> <PERSON> Hara </PERSON> has attended a `` cram school'' for months in a desperate effort to be ready for entrance exams. She's 5, and her parents hope <PERSON> Kieko </PERSON> will make it into a top-ranked private elementary school She attends cramming sessions twice a week after kindergarten and on weekends. Some days, <PERSON> Kieko </PERSON> makes rice balls or crafts, or is drilled in the Japanese alphabet. Once a week, she takes a practice test like those used by private schools to choose the few applicants they accept. `` We wish she did n't have to go to cram school, but if she gets into a good private ... system now, then she'll be able to enter the school's junior high automatically,'' said <PERSON> Yuko </PERSON>, her mother. Japanese public education is praised for egalitarianism and the high scores of students on achievement tests, but as public schools have become more equal, parents have sought an edge elsewhere. Children are being sent at ever-younger ages to cram schools, called jukus, or are going to private rather than public schools in hopes of gaining ground in the merciless college-entrance competition. The Education Ministry says 71 percent of elementary and junior high students attend jukus or have special outside lessons, in effect creating an entire second school system. It is a booming business estimated to be worth about 1 trillion yen, or $ 7 billion, a year. Some Japanese contend the increasing role of private spending in education threatens the equality of opportunity created by the public school system. Others feel public schools have concentrated on educating the mass of students, neglecting the bright and creative. Getting into the best schools frequently costs a staggering amount of money, as well as work. <PERSON> Kieko </PERSON>'s parents pay about 65,000 yen -LRB- $ 460 -RRB- a month for her juku classes in addition to fees for her private kindergarten. Some classmates began attending a juku at age 3, to prepare for the kindergarten entrance exam, and now have daily cram sessions before kindergarten and again in the afternoon. Such devotion to schooling has a long history in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and some other Asian nations, but the intense competition is largely a postwar development that grew with economic prosperity. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> spends less on public education than the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, both in total amount and percentage of gross national product. In the last fiscal year, the government allocated 16 trillion yen -LRB- $ 112 billion -RRB- to public education, compared with $ 353 billion this year in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. An Education Minstry study in 1987 said 4.2 percent of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s GNP went to public education, compared with 4.8 percent in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, 4.4 percent in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and 4.2 percent in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> Spending on education in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> varies greatly by school district and region, but <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> has followed a policy of equal distribution of resources. It also does not `` track'' students, separating them according to ability. In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the federal government provides about 6 percent of the public money for kindergarten through high school. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s central government pays 43 percent, much of it in subsidies to local districts that reduce regional disparities to less than 20 percent, according to government figures. The Education Ministry approves textbooks and curricula, so all students study essentially the same material at the same time. In high school, Japanese students cram for college entrance exams that determine not only what schools they will attend, but their chances for a good job afterward. Companies with the most prestige usually hire graduates of only the top universities. College entrance exams have become more difficult as competition has intensified and frequently include material not covered in the public school curriculum, according to Education Ministry studies. With craming for exams now extending down to kindergarten, `` by junior high school many students feel their life has already been ordained,'' said <PERSON> Naomi </PERSON> <PERSON> Kikuchi </PERSON>, who has two children in school. In the past, a leading public high school was considered the best preparation for college entrance. That changed as the high schools became more equal. Many parents and students now see jukus, with their single-minded emphasis on preparing for exams, as more helpful than public schools in gaining admission to good universities. About 70 percent of parents in a recent survey said they disapproved of jukus, but most said they enrolled their children as `` a necessary evil.'' Other families try to get their children into top private kindergartens or elementary schools, especially those of respected private universities that automatically admit graduates of their own lower schools. The first year of <ORGANIZATION> Aoyama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s kindergarten, one of the most sought-after schools, costs about 1.4 million yen -LRB- $ 9,500 -RRB-, more than the 980,000-yen -LRB- $ 6,800 -RRB- for the first year of university. A survey by a major bank in 1987 found that education expenses account for 13.4 percent of after-tax earnings for an average Japanese family in a metropolitan area. That did not include salary forgone by the `` kyoiku mama,'' mothers who devote themselves to their children's education until the youngsters enter elementary school and for periods before entrance exams. `` For people without money and mothers who have to work, it's hard to get children into a good school,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Kikuchi </PERSON> said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-AndrewYoung     11-29 0851</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Andrew Young,0877</SECOND>
<HEAD>Andy Young: Playing Down Race in Campaign for Governor</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SONYA ROSS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> does n't play up the milestone victories of two black candidates in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, but he does share one strategy in his quest to become governor of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> _ he rarely mentions race. There's little doubt race will be a factor in many voters' minds next summer as they size up <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, who is finishing eight years as <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>'s mayor. Some pundits already have predicted he will fail in his bid to become the state's first black governor. But others are talking about momentum from the successful campaigns of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> Gov.-elect <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Mayor-elect <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON>. Young is n't jumping on that bandwagon. `` I think it feels good to be a respectable candidate, and that's all I think I am at this point,'' he said. Young says he does n't have much in common with <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> `` other than the fact that we all went to the same college, <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, and we all happen to have the same skin color.'' But lately, he has done at least one thing both <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> and <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> did: dismiss race as a factor. His campaign chairman is <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney general and federal judge who is white and conservative. <PERSON> Bell </PERSON> was <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney general in <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s administration; <PERSON> Young </PERSON> was ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. Young also is aggressively pursuing the white vote in mostly rural and conservative south <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, pushing his record for business development and economic expansion. His campaign manager is a white former small-town south <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> mayor, Hobby Stripling of <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>. `` I would suspect that the Young organization has been studying carefully the <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> campaign,'' said <PERSON> Merle </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, a political science professor at <ORGANIZATION> Emory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. But unlike <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, <PERSON> Young </PERSON> has stuck to his bent for the off-beat. His latest escapade came last week, when he ate dinner in a rustic juke joint where two racially offensive songs are featured on the jukebox. `` I'll go anywhere and talk to anybody,'' <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said. `` The world is made up of different people, and the only way we're going to survive is to learn to co-exist and respect one another.'' While there, he played down race in an obviously racially charged situation and took the opportunity to give the restaurant's owner a <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> record for the jukebox Political watchers say <PERSON> Young </PERSON> is taking pains to put himself forth as a racially palatable black candidate. `` The fact that <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> now has won shows it can be done. To that extent, it helps <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> be seen as a more credible and realistic candidate,'' <PERSON> Black </PERSON> said. `` It would have been a setback for Young's campaign if <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> had lost.'' <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> said his campaign was successful because it appealed to mainstream values. Although his candidacy was closely watched by black leaders, <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> deliberately kept liberal two-time presidential candidate <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> at arms length and did not invite <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> to campaign for him. Young also will not include <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in his campaign, <PERSON> Stripling </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` We do n't have any plans to ask Mr. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> for any help,'' he said. `` Our campaign is a Georgia-based campaign, and we will handle it from within the state.'' Young was booed loudly by <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> supporters at the 1984 Democratic National Convention in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>; the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> forces, frustrated over their failure to win concessions from the <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> camp, yelled at Young when he rose to speak on behalf of a <LOCATION> Mondale </LOCATION> position. <PERSON> Young </PERSON> was stunned, his wife cried and a press aide collapsed. Still, <PERSON> Young </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> have remained cordial. <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> political pollster <PERSON> Claibourne </PERSON> <PERSON> Darden </PERSON> predicts <PERSON> Young </PERSON>'s campaign will be troubled by race, whether he likes it or not Young could come in first in the first round of the Democratic primary on the strength of his name recognition and the black vote; 24 percent of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>'s voting-age population is black, <PERSON> Darden </PERSON> said. But <PERSON> Young </PERSON> would n't get the 50 percent he would need to win, <PERSON> Darden </PERSON> said. `` He will be in the runoff regardless'' <PERSON> Darden </PERSON> said. `` But we are still at a place where a tremendous number of white people in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> are not willing to vote for a black candidate. `` It's not like <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. You're in the Deep South here, and the black population is significantly larger. That's unfortunately a pretty good correlation for prejudice. The larger the -LRB- minority -RRB- group, the more prejudice there is.'' Young, however, discounts that. `` I always felt that white folk in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> are way ahead of white folk in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> already,'' he said. `` I used to kid <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> that if he could get 30 percent of the white vote in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, I know I can get 45 or 50 in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>.'' In the Democratic primary, Young faces Lt. Gov. <PERSON> Zell </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, two powerful state legislators, Sen. <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> and Rep. <PERSON> Bubba </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>, and a wild-card entry, former Gov. <PERSON> Lester </PERSON> <PERSON> Maddox </PERSON>. The front-runner for the Republican nomination is state Rep. <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Isakson </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GoldenHorse     11-29 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Golden Horse,0721</SECOND>
<HEAD>Buried Treasure Was in Colorado, Puzzle Solvers Say</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RAYNER PIKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent and a deputy prosecutor in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> were too late for the gold, but they get the glory. They have solved the mystery of the $ 500,000 Golden Horse treasure contest. Alone among the tens of thousands who sought the buried treasure, they deduced that the <ORGANIZATION> Golden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Horse </ORGANIZATION> was buried in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pass </LOCATION>, 10,400 feet above sea level, along the Continental Divide in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Boone </PERSON> and <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Castaneda </PERSON>, who spent more than five years working separately on the puzzle, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday they had solved the riddle and the people who ran the contest do n't disagree. `` We have no comment about the site, but we will acknowledge and confirm that he's given us totally convincing proof that he found the exact location,'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Conlon </PERSON>, president of D.L. <PERSON> Blair </PERSON>, said after speaking to <PERSON> Boone </PERSON>. <PERSON> Blair </PERSON>, the national sales promotion company that oversaw the contest, has refused to divulge the solution. <PERSON> Boone </PERSON>, 45, an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent for 18 years, was the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s case agent for planning and security at the 1984 Olympic games. `` I know what it is to have a letdown after a long haul,'' <PERSON> Boone </PERSON> said. `` <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> and I are looking to see if we can find another good contest.'' <PERSON> Castaneda </PERSON>, 44, a prosecutor for 16 years, said he was not drawn to working puzzles before the <ORGANIZATION> Golden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Horse </ORGANIZATION> challenge, `` unless you count solving murders.'' The puzzle was offered to the public in 1984 as a story titled `` Treasure: In Search of the <ORGANIZATION> Golden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Horse </ORGANIZATION>,'' which was released as a book, videotape and laser disc. The story contained arcane and complex clues to the puzzle. Contestants had until midnight of May 26 to find a statuette of a horse buried somewhere in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The horse was made of 2.2 pounds of pure gold and contained a key to a safe deposit box containing a 20-year annuity for $ 25,000 a year. The deadline passed with no claimant. As stipulated by the rules, the treasure was dug up and turned over to a charity _ Big <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Big </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sisters </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> _ but the site was not revealed. Many frustrated treasure hunters who spent years, money and sweat on the puzzle clamored for the solution. Some maintained the contest was a fraud and that no trove was ever buried. <PERSON> Conlon </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Big </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> and the authors of the story, bound by the contest rules, kept mum. `` I would love to have seen them retrieve this seven months ago, not only for their benefit but ours, so we would not have had to endure six months of slander,'' <PERSON> Conlon </PERSON> said. The partners wo n't reveal yet the step-by-step path that led them to <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pass </LOCATION>. That will come in an article they are preparing for publication in the March issue of Treasure magazine. `` You really ca n't work from the site backward,'' <PERSON> Boone </PERSON> said, `` because there's nothing that points to <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pass </LOCATION>. You have to solve the ciphers to find it.'' <PERSON> Boone </PERSON> said the puzzle jelled on Nov. 1 and he and <PERSON> Castaneda </PERSON> flew to the pass two days later to dig up whatever evidence of the stash remained. Amid snow, cold and gathering darkness, they missed the spot by 18 inches, <PERSON> Boone </PERSON> said. Returning to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, the collaborators realized that they should have had a Polaroid camera with them to photograph the site and exactly align a landmark with a map from the book on which the spot was marked with an `` X.'' They returned on Nov. 18 and this time found proof positive that they were right. They dug up a vial containing a parchment that began: `` Dear seeker. Congratulations. Your travails are over,'' <PERSON> Boone </PERSON> said. They also found the remains of the crate that had contained the horse and a coat that the crate had been wrapped in, said <PERSON> Conlon </PERSON>. Then, following instructions on the parchment, <PERSON> Boone </PERSON> telephoned <PERSON> Conlon </PERSON> and read him a coded message: `` 165-69 INF.'' The code referred to the two numerical designators of <PERSON> Conlon </PERSON>'s old <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> unit, the `` Fighting 69th'' infantry regiment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens-List     11-29 0688</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens-List,0774</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of Nov. 20-26. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 92.1 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.6, 21.7 million homes. 2. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.8, 20.1 million homes. 3. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 21.5, 19.8 million homes. 4. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.5, 18.9 million homes. 5. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.4, 18.8 million homes. 6. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.0, 18.4 million homes. 6. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 20.0, 18.4 million homes. 8. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` Coach,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.8, 16.4 million homes. 9. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` NFL Monday Night Football: <ORGANIZATION> Broncos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> vs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Redskins </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.7, 16.3 million homes. 9. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Funniest Home Videos,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.7, 16.3. 11. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.6, 15.3 million homes. 12. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.5, 15.2 million homes. 13. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.4, 15.1 million homes. 14. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.3, 15.0 million homes. 14. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` Blind Witness'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 16.3, 15.0 million homes. 16. -LRB- 32 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.1, 14.8 million homes. 16. -LRB- 12 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.1, 14.8 million homes. 18. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` In the Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.8, 14.6 million homes. 19. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` Top Gun'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 15.7, 14.5 million homes. 20. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 15.6, 14.4 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3. 21. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS, 15.3. 23. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.0. 24. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.9. 25. -LRB- X -RRB- `` 50 Years of Television,'' CBS, 14.6. 26. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` Midnight Caller,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.4. 27. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.3. 28. -LRB- 48 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 14.2. 29. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.9. 30. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` Turn Back The Clock'' _ `` NBC Monday Night Movies,'' 13.8. 31. -LRB- 25 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.5. 32. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Circus Of The Stars,'' CBS, 13.2. 33. -LRB- 20 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8. 34. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5. 34. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5. 34. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` Major Dad,'' CBS, 12.5. 37. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.3. 38. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.1. 39. -LRB- 54 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0. 40. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Till We Meet Again,'' Part 2 _ `` CBS Special Movie,'' 11.7. 41. -LRB- 39 -RRB- `` 20 @ 20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.6. 42. -LRB- 49 -RRB- `` Just The Ten Of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.5. 42. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.5. 44. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` Family Matters,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 44. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Bugs Bunny Thanksgiving Day,'' CBS, 11.3. 44. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 47. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Doogie </PERSON> <PERSON> Howser </PERSON>, M.D.,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.1. 48. -LRB- 56 -RRB- `` My Two Dads - Wednesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.9. 49. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garfield </PERSON>'s Thanksgiving,'' CBS, 10.7. 50. -LRB- 47 -RRB- `` Famous Teddy Z,'' CBS, 10.6. 51. -LRB- 44 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.5. 51. -LRB- 59 -RRB- `` Baywatch,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.5. 51. -LRB- 62 -RRB- `` Doctor, Doctor,'' CBS, 10.5. 54. -LRB- 44 -RRB- `` Anything But Love,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.4. 54. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` Hardball,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.4. 54. -LRB- 68 -RRB- `` Quantum Leap,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.4. 57. -LRB- 71 -RRB- `` Life Goes On,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.3. 58. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` Mancuso: <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.1. 59. -LRB- 71 -RRB- `` Columbo'' _ `` ABC Mystery Movie,'' 10.0. 60. -LRB- 68 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 61. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` Magical World of Disney,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.0. 62. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Ice Stars Hollywood Revue,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.7. 63. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Superman II'' _ `` CBS Special Movie,'' 8.5. 63. -LRB- 76 -RRB- `` Totally Hidden Video,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 8.5. 65. -LRB- 58 -RRB- `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.2. 66. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> Thanksgiving Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.1. 66. -LRB- 83 -RRB- `` Saturday Night With <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Chung </PERSON>,'' CBS, 8.1. 68. -LRB- 83 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.0. 69. -LRB- 60 -RRB- `` Young Riders,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.9. 70. -LRB- 88 -RRB- `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 7.8. 71. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Grammys' Living Legends,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 7.6. 72. -LRB- 74 -RRB- `` Sister <PERSON> Kate </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.4. 73. -LRB- 85 -RRB- `` Living Dolls,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.3. 74. -LRB- 78 -RRB- `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.2. 75. -LRB- 85 -RRB- `` Open House,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 7.1. 76. -LRB- 89 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Booker </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.5. 77. -LRB- 89 -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.4. 78. -LRB- 75 -RRB- `` Primetime Live,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.2. 78. -LRB- 92 -RRB- `` Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.2. 80. -LRB- 91 -RRB- `` Alien Nation,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.0. 81. -LRB- 93 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.2. 82. -LRB- 95 -RRB- `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.0. 83. -LRB- 94 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.2.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0151EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--JournalistFreed     11-29 0124</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Journalist Freed,0126</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dutch Journalist Released After Two Months In Lebanese Jail</HEAD>
<DATELINE>THE HAGUE, Netherlands (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lebanese authorities have released a Dutch journalist who spent two months in a <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> jail on espionage and drug charges, the <ORGANIZATION> Dutch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> der </PERSON> <PERSON> Leeuw </PERSON> was freed Tuesday and accompanied to <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> by an official from the Dutch embassy in <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>, a ministry spokesman said. <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> der </PERSON> <PERSON> Leeuw </PERSON> had been detained since Sept. 28 in what the <ORGANIZATION> Dutch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalists </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> said was a move to stop him from criticizing the Lebanese Christian army commander Gen. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>. The ministry spokesman, who asked not to be identified, in line with ministry policy, would not comment on the circumstances of <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> der </PERSON> <PERSON> Leeuw </PERSON> release.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ArmoredVehicles     11-29 0346</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Armored Vehicles,0355</SECOND>
<HEAD>Budgets Force Updates Rather Than Purchase of New Times</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The cost of new weapons and decreasing defense budgets are forcing more countries, including some <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> members, to upgrade their armored vehicles rather than buy new ones, a new <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>'s yearbook said today. <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> countries are concentrating their upgrading on improving fire control systems and providing an enhanced night vision capability, said the authors of the 1989-1990 edition of `` <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>'s Armored Fighting Vehicle Systems. `` Few countries are at present installing new armament which is required to penetrate the latest Soviet MBTs -LRB- Main Battle Tanks -RRB- or to install more armor to increase their battlefield survivability,'' wrote <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Foss </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Cullen </PERSON> in the authoritative yearbook. They said the installation of a larger caliber gun and additional armor would in most cases overload the vehicles' suspension and reduce the power-to-weight ratio <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s next tank gun is likely to have a caliber of 140mm and be fed by an automatic loader that will enable the crew to be reduced to three, they said. The new gun could be mounted externally with the crew seated inside the hull. The authors said this provides a number of advantages, including a significant weight saving, as the turret on current main battle tanks can weight 20 tons. `` The weight saved could be used to make the vehicle more compact or to increase protection levels, especially against top attack weapons,'' the authors said. `` In addition, it would present an enemy with a much smaller target.'' The authors said much development work is taking place on conventional tank guns and ammunition, but `` there is little doubt that in the longer term the future is in other types of weapon systems for the main armament.'' Liquid propellant is the most likely route for artillery, they said. For the main battle tank, the electromagnetic or electrothermal gun is showing `` much promise.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is the leader in both areas, they said, in the latter because of a spinoff from the Star Wars program, formally known as the Strategic Defense Initiative.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0157EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-ColdWar     11-29 0951</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Cold War,0976</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Eastern Europe Fits Gorbachev Vision of Changing World</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARK J. PORUBCANSKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 By encouraging Eastern European allies who punched holes in the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall and sacked aging leaders, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is declaring the Cold War over and trying to ensure security in the new world to follow. President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and his top advisers believe the whole world, including post-war <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, has been changed forever by an explosion of technology mastered by the other side. Looking grimly at the backwardness of his own country and his neighbors, the breathtaking changes that have gripped <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> this fall nevertheless offer <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> two opportunities: _ To renew and salvage at least part of a socialist system in which he sincerely believes, before stagnation and dissatisfaction blow the lid off. _ To achieve economic reform by redirecting his own economy away from the military and drawing the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> into the West's technological revolution Military security might be assured through economic interdependence that makes confrontation unprofitable. When he echoes the call of <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON> 21 years ago for socialism with a `` human face,'' _ <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s reform ground under the treads of <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact tanks _ <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> seems to aim at keeping half a loaf, rather than risking it all later in unpredictable fury. The move has won <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> respect in the West and support in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s non-Communist government has pledged support to the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact and continued friendship with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. While acknowledging the West's technological superiority and economic might, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is far from declaring surrender in the Cold War. He and his advisers say they have a clearer idea of how to use Western muscle to build a new world. `` Politically the world has entered a new phase _ it is moving out of the Cold War into a period of peace,'' Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in October. `` Today we need a consensus, an international approach to global problems _ not because it is a moral imperative, but for objective reasons, because the world is a single and interdependent whole,'' he said. In a world of buyers and sellers criss-crossed with satellite communications and computer technology, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> sees his land that has been sealed off and content with the abacus as the ultimate loser. `` Now we have to make up for lost time, and this requires a more rapid pace of change,'' he said last week who asked about reforms in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. It also requires peace. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is cutting 500,000 men out of the armed forces, about half of them from Eastern <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Some missiles are being taken out of <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. The defense budget was cut 8.3 percent this year and defense factories are being retooled to make consumer goods. Negotiations continue on sharp cuts in strategic nuclear weapons, conventional forces in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, and chemical weapons. `` To put it in a nutshell, we need a normal external environment for our domestic work,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> told former West German Chancellor <PERSON> Willy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON> in October. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and the czarist empire before it was fearful of a powerful <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in the heart of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. But the betting now appears to be that if <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> is absorbed in being <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s rich uncle, it will have little incentive to rock the boat The area also may become an area of `` cooperation and understanding'' between the superpowers, the government news agency <ORGANIZATION> Novosti </ORGANIZATION> said. Marshal <PERSON> Sergei </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Akhromeyev </PERSON>, the former military chief of staff and a <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> adviser, indicated in an article in the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> daily Pravda that the army may consider a land buffer is less important now. What worries the Soviet military is being surrounded by <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> firepower, <PERSON> Akhromeyev </PERSON> said. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has 2 -LCB- times more large surface ships, 15 attack aircraft carriers to none for the Soviets, 2 -LCB- times more maritime aircraft and 19 times more Marines, he said. `` The <LOCATION> U.S.A. </LOCATION>, most likely, intends to continue using these forces to put pressure on us and threaten the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>,'' he said. If <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and his advisers believe they have a clear idea of the future, they are concerned that short-term instability in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> could ruin it. `` Any deep changes, especially those in key regions of the world, are accompanied by instability and difficulties. This is only natural. The most dangerous thing at such moments is that someone may be tempted to use them for their own selfish interests,'' he said on Nov. 21. The Berlin Wall, however many holes it has, must remain standing for the time being, the Soviets say. Too much is changing in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> for the region to cope simultaneously with the elimination of the political structure that kept the peace, however tense, for more than 40 years. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s fear of <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> spinning entirely out of control may be why he has so firmly supported reform in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> earlier this year just before authorities cracked down on pro-democracy demonstrators and killed hundreds of them. An Eastern <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> with no hope of catching up or enjoying the fruits of the West's technological revolution could be more likely to explode. Some reports in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> say orders to shoot at protesters had been given before <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> was forced out by <PERSON> Egon </PERSON> <PERSON> Krenz </PERSON>. The alternative to reform _ tighter borders and more stagnation _ would mean abject defeat in the Cold War.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Porubcansky </PERSON> has reported on Soviet and <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> affairs from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> for The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since February 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0216EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Germany-Troops     11-29 0763</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Germany-Troops,0786</SECOND>
<HEAD>American Soldiers Still on Duty at East German Border</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE BOEHMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OBSERVATION POST ALPHA, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American soldiers who watch the East German frontier do n't relax their guard now that the barriers are down, but some have been deeply moved by the experience. `` At some points north and south of here, there were so many people coming across, it was like they were getting out of jail. It choked me up,'' said Sgt. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, 26, of <LOCATION> Battle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>. Sgt 1st Class <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Osterfeld </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, said: `` The greatest thing in the world is to be a part of it. I was standing there when they tore a piece of this fence out a few miles away from here.'' <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> and Osterfeld are stationed with the 11th Armored Cavalry Regiment at this post, which they call OP-Alpha, 75 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> and a few feet from what used to be a heavily fortified border. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers say they have not relaxed, because increased Soviet helicopter patrols near the frontier show `` they're still there,'' but seeing the free flow of people across the line has been affecting. `` You did n't have to be at the border. You could go downtown and see those people buying things we take for granted, like fruit and coffee,'' said Sgt. <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON>, 23, of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. The 11th helps keep watch and gather intelligence through surveillance of Soviet-led <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact troops on the East German side. Officials say more than 380,000 Soviet soldiers are based in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. If an attack occurred, the 5,000-man regiment would try to delay it long enough for other <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> forces to move up. Included in the unit's sector is the the <ORGANIZATION> Fulda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gap </ORGANIZATION>, a traditional wartime invasion route through central <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. For those who watch the 196-mile stretch of border, the dramatic relaxation of travel restrictions on the East Germans has not altered the routine very much. Osterfeld, 31, led a motorized patrol of men in green camouflage fatigues along the rusty 10-foot-tall steel mesh fences that mark the border near OP-Alpha. The soldiers, some armed with .45 - caliber pistols, others with M-16 rifles, sometimes patrol on foot, stopping to peer through binoculars into <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and reporting in by Since Nov. 9, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> has opened 14 new crossings along the stretch of border guarded by 11th Armored Cavalry soldiers. There used to be only two. None of the crossings are visible from OP-Alpha, and the chilly landscape of hills and valleys 15 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Fulda </LOCATION> is unchanged from before the dramatic changes in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. As American soldiers looked across the border with binoculars, East German guards could be seen in a watchtower 200 yards away, peering through their own binoculars at the GIs. Command Sgt. Maj. <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> <PERSON> Fryer </PERSON>, the outfit's ranking non-commissioned officer, said `` more than 100,000 well-equipped Soviet troops'' are stationed directly across from the Americans in central <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. `` The Soviets have not shown a willingness to move back; that's why we're still here and ready to react,'' said <PERSON> Fryer </PERSON>, 38, of <LOCATION> Coburn </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> `` The East Germans who are coming here are welcome,'' he said, but `` we are still doing our job and our surveillance. <PERSON> Fryer </PERSON> said the Soviets appeared to have increased their air patrols along the border, using MI-24 attack helicopters for missions formerly flown primarily by East Germans in Polish-made resupply and observation choppers. `` We see about one a day, depending on weather and flying conditions,'' he said. `` I think it's their way of showing that they're still there and ready too.'' Over coffee in OP-Alpha's small dining hall, Sgt. <PERSON> Marlon </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornston </PERSON>, 24, of <LOCATION> Niagara </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, said some rookies question why they still patrol a frontier millions of East Germans crossing freely. `` We now have to explain to our young guys, who have met some of these nice East German people, why we're still here,'' he said. `` The only thing I do n't feel good about is that all of them, even the bad ones looking for intelligence, also now have more free access.'' Staff Sgt. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Torak </PERSON>, 31, of <LOCATION> Elkhart </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, said: `` We have to stay here, just in case'' the Soviets and their allies `` have n't put all their cards on the table. Now and then, an East German guard will wave at the Americans across the border, <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON> said. Do they wave back? `` No,'' he said. `` They're still there, armed just like we are. Our guys ignore it and carry out their jobs like professionals.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0218EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador-Slayings     11-29 1053</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador-Slayings,1083</SECOND>
<HEAD>Second Salvador Massacre, But of Common Folk</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Language in 23rd graf, ``He said ...'' may be offensive to some.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The seven men were not priests or human rights campaigners, so their deaths have gone largely unnoticed. But according to relatives and neighbors, including a young man who barely escaped the slaughter, six of them were lined up against a peach-colored masonry wall and shot to death on Nov. 18. A seventh youth who happened upon the killings by chance also was slain. The relatives, neighbors and the young escapee all saw government soldiers a block away from the killing site in the poor suburb of <LOCATION> Cuscatancingo </LOCATION> minutes before the seven were slain. The young man said he heard the fatal gunshots while hiding from the soldiers. The dead were identified as <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Zetino </PERSON>, <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Crespin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Campos </PERSON>, <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> and <PERSON> Emanuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Medrano </PERSON>. The killings occurred two days after the slaying of six Jesuits, their cook and her daughter at <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> killings, carried out by men who a survivor said wore military uniforms, stunned <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and caused an international outcry. There was no international outcry for the seven slain in <LOCATION> Cuscatancingo </LOCATION>. Spokesmen for the Salvadoran armed forces press office were unavailable for comment on the Cuscatancingo killings. <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Zetino </PERSON> was found `` with his social security card in his hand. He was still trying to identify himself when they shot him,'' said a neighbor, standing in front of the blood-spattered, bullet-riddled wall where the six bodies were found the morning of Nov. 19 in <LOCATION> Cuscatancingo </LOCATION> at the end of the dusty, partially cobbled <LOCATION> Pasaje </LOCATION> <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gringo </LOCATION> _ `` <LOCATION> Gringo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alley </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Medrano </PERSON>, 14, was the only victim not from the neighborhood. His mother, <PERSON> Alicia </PERSON>, said he was there trying to buy bread. <PERSON> Medrano </PERSON> appears to have had the bad luck to stumble on the killings as they were being carried out, or just afterward. His body was found 10 yards away. Because his family did not have the $ 35 for a proper burial, he is the only one still buried at the end of the alley. Relatives and neighbors had buried the seven in a common grave at the end of the alley on Nov. 19, when much of the capital was still convulsed by the biggest guerrilla offensive of the 10-year-old civil war. The six local men were exhumed with approval of Justice of the Peace <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordoba </PERSON> on Nov. 23 and taken to cemeteries. `` They were not guerrillas,'' said the coach of the soccer team on which three of the slain men played. `` They had jobs, families. Everybody around here knew them. A guerrilla does n't have time to work, take care of his family and play soccer.'' Three of the six were day laborers. One worked at a glass factory and another at a brewery. <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>, a 23-year-old illegal immigrant waiter in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, had arrived only two weeks earlier to visit friends from his neighborhood. Cuscatancingo, like other working class districts along the capital's northern fringe, was the scene of combat in the Nov. 11 offensive's first days. <PERSON> Pasaje </PERSON> <PERSON> El </PERSON> <PERSON> Gringo </PERSON> had come through relatively unscathed, although fighting was more intense a few blocks away. Air force strafing and rocketing had come too close for comfort. `` We decided to evacuate,'' said <PERSON> Crespin </PERSON>'s sister, <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON>. `` But one always worries about leaving the house completely abandoned. So the guys decided to stay, to keep an eye on things, even though we begged them to come too.'' `` The muchachos -LRB- guerrillas -RRB- had come through a few days before. But we had no problem with them, and they did n't stop to stay here,'' said a neighbor. `` We were just sitting around, talking, when someone threw a rock at a dog in the street in front of us and made it bark and run,'' said the young man who escaped. For days he had refused to meet with any journalist and was only persuaded to tell his story after the strictest assurances, delivered through relatives, that he would not be identified. `` Here, out of fear, one abstains from saying important things,'' said a relative. `` Sooner or later, they catch up to you.'' `` The soldiers saw Oscar and yelled for him to come out into the street,'' said the young man who escaped the Cuscatancingo killings. `` He went out with his hands in the air, saying ` We're civilians. <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> and I were sitting with our backs to the wall and they had n't seen us. I felt something bad was going to happen and said to him, ` Let's get out of here.' `` He said, ` We have n't done anything, so why should we run?' and stood up to take out his identification. The soldier in charge of the patrol swore at Oscar out in the street: ` You, SOB. What the hell are you doing here?' `` I stayed crouched down and took off along the wall and around the corner,'' he said. `` I ran a few blocks and hid. About 10 minutes later there was a long burst from an M-16. Then the coups de grace, one by one.'' <PERSON> Cordoba </PERSON> said: `` The only thing I can attest to is that the bodies of those seven were found at that place on that date, that six were exhumed on Nov. 23 and that they all died of bullet wounds.'' `` Who killed them, I do n't know,'' he said. <PERSON> Cordoba </PERSON> said he will send the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> his monthly report of all official business and the case will be pursued if an offended party, such as a relative, files a complaint, or if the attorney general's office decides it merits pursuit, even in the absence of a complaint. The attorney general's office would then make a preliminary investigation, which probably would include another exhumation and autopsies, and assign the case to a criminal court judge. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Josefina </PERSON> <PERSON> Crespin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jose </PERSON>'s mother, continues to live in the green house next to her son's, the one whose facade served as the firing squad wall. Three-year-old <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, one of <PERSON> Jose </PERSON>'s two daughters, played in the sand in front of the house. `` She does n't even know what happened,'' the grandmother said. `` She just keeps asking, ` Where's papi?'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TripleSurprise     11-29 0323</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Triple Surprise,0337</SECOND>
<HEAD>Despite Vasectomy, Man Fathers Triplets</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DAYTON, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> and <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Morter </PERSON> thought their family was complete after having three sons, so <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> had a vasectomy. Then came the Morters' daughters _ triplets. `` We just tell everybody we hoped and prayed for a little girl and we must have prayed too hard, because now we have three,'' said <PERSON> Morter </PERSON>, a technical sergeant stationed at <ORGANIZATION> Wright-Patterson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>. The Morters always wanted a girl. Their first-born was a boy, <PERSON> Jeffy </PERSON>. Then came <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON>, then <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON>. The Morters decided three was enough, and in July 1987, while he was stationed in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, the vasectomy was performed. <PERSON> Morter </PERSON>, 29, said a follow-up test performed by an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> surgeon confirmed that the vasectomy was successful. Then came <PERSON> Samantha </PERSON>, <PERSON> Stephanie </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON>, who celebrated their first birthday Nov. 19. Last year, before prescribing birth control pills as treatment for an ovarian cyst, Ms. <PERSON> Morter </PERSON>'s doctor gave her a routine pregnancy test, even though Mrs. <PERSON> Morter </PERSON> insisted she could n't possibly be expecting `` They said, ` Not only are you pregnant, you're very pregnant,''' <PERSON> Morter </PERSON> said. `` We did n't know what that meant.'' `` We found out, though,'' his wife said. After the pregnancy was confirmed, <PERSON> Morter </PERSON> had his vasectomy re-examined. A test showed that his sperm count was 30 percent of normal, instead of zero. Doctors are n't sure why the vasectomy failed, <PERSON> Morter </PERSON> said. `` They said they'd have to go back in and look,'' he said. He told them not to bother. After the triplets arrived, Mrs. <PERSON> Morter </PERSON>, 28, had her Fallopian tubes tied. Dr. <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernie </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION> urologist, said vasectomy failure is `` not very common at all. I've done them for 20 years and maybe one or two in all that time -LRB- has failed -RRB-. It's a very effective method of birth control.'' In <PERSON> Morter </PERSON>'s case, one of the tubes that carry the sperm from the testicles probably grew back together, <PERSON> Bernie </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-FishermenLost 1stLd-Writethru a0660 11-29 0509</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fishermen Lost, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0660,0524</SECOND>
<HEAD>Search Focuses Southeast of Nantucket</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 9 grafs to UPDATE with second flare spotted, quotes,
search continuing; picks up 4th graf: `Of Friday ...</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For the second night in a row, <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> searchers spotted a flare Tuesday in their hunt for five lobsterman who disappeared a week ago off the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> coast. The sighting, about 250 miles south of <LOCATION> Nantucket </LOCATION>, is in a remote area where <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> rescuers believe a life raft might have drifted. `` The flares are coming from somewhere,'' said Lt. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> office in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. `` There are no other boats out there except the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>.'' `` We're going to search as long as there's a reasonable possibility that someone is alive and needs help,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Petty Officer <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Brannan </PERSON>. The 72-foot <PERSON> Heidi </PERSON> <PERSON> Marie </PERSON>, out of <LOCATION> Stonington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, was reported missing by its owner on Nov. 22. The boat's last transmission was the previous day, the same day officials received a distress signal. The jet that spotted the flare Tuesday night continued searching. Two Coast Guard cutters were also sent to the scene. A red flare had been spotted in the area Monday night. Both orange and red flares are used to signal an emergency, <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON> said. Flare lights last about two minutes. The jet that spotted the second emergency flare was due to return to land for refueling at about 10 p.m., <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON> said. But a second aircraft was sent to the area to take its place. `` We're so far off shore that it's difficult,'' <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON> said. On Friday, rescuers turned up a floating radio beacon and fishing markers bearing the <PERSON> Heidi </PERSON> <PERSON> Marie </PERSON>'s name. The fishing boat was equipped with a life raft big enough for the entire crew. On Tuesday, three aircraft and two cutters searched an 8,000-square-mile area, some of which had been covered before. <PERSON> Brannan </PERSON> said the search concentrated around the area where a red flare was seen Monday night. Coast guard officials said the person who lit the flare could have been anywhere from 6 to 30 miles from where it was spotted. `` Where the flare was seen is where our trajectory was predicting the raft would be,'' <PERSON> Brannan </PERSON> said. The manufacturer of the boat's life raft told <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> officials that the craft contained three orange smoke flares, three red distress flares, plus an unspecified number of parachute flares, such as the one seen Monday. <PERSON> Brannan </PERSON> said she could not speculate about whether the crew members could survive a week at sea in the life raft. `` It depends _ were there provisions? Were they wearing survival suits?'' she said. The lobster boat carried survival suits for seven people. Seas last Tuesday were reported to be 26 feet high with wind gusts to 45 knots in the area where the <PERSON> Heidi </PERSON> <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> was lobstering. But fishermen in <LOCATION> Stonington </LOCATION> said it was not unusual for a boat to stay out in rough seas. `` That boat has weathered worse weather,'' said fisherman <PERSON> Skip </PERSON> <PERSON> Babin </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     11-29 0386</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0397</SECOND>
<HEAD>ABC's `Roseanne' Gets Thanksgiving Ratings Boost</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY BUCK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne'' was back on top of the Nielsen ratings because of the Thanksgiving holiday as <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s Thursday night shows got the turkey leftovers `` The Wonder Years'' placed second for last week as all of <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s Tuesday night comedies landed in the top 10 None of <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s Thursday shows made it into the top rankings because of a 20 percent Thanksgiving tune out. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Whose the Boss?'' was fourth and `` Coach,'' in its premiere appearance in place of the canceled `` Chicken Soup,'' tied for eighth. Its other Tuesday show, `` thirtysomething,'' tied for 36th. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> had only two shows in the top 10, `` The Golden Girls'' in fifth place and `` Empty Nest'' tied for sixth. The highest-rated NBC Thursday show was `` Cheers,'' in 13th place. A rerun of `` The Cosby Show,'' first in recent weeks, was 14th. `` L.A. Law'' tied for 17th, `` A Different World'' tied for 22nd, and `` Dear John'' tied for 25th. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> still won the week with a prime-time ratings average of 13.8, according to the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>. The previous week, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> had an average of 16.0. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> was second last week with 12.9 and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> had 12.3. Each ratings point represents the percentage of the nation's 92.1 million television households tuned to a show. The top 10: <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Wonder Years,'' CBS' `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Who's the Boss?,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Empty Nest'' and CBS' `` Murder, She Wrote'' tied, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> Football Sunday and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Coach'' tied, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Funniest Home Videos'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Football <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> is ahead in the season-to-date ratings and in the November sweeps, which are used to help determine local advertising rates. In the first 10 weeks of the season, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> has averaged a 15.0 rating to <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s 13.5 and CBS' 12.4. The ratings for the sweeps: <ORGANIZATION> Arbitron </ORGANIZATION> for 26 days, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 15.0, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 12.8, CBS 12.0. <PERSON> Nielsen </PERSON> for 25 days, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 15.1, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 12.6, CBS 12.1. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> tied for first place among the evening news shows, although <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> had a slightly higher audience share. Each had a rating of 10.0, which also represents a slight viewer tune out for the holiday week. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> was third with 9.3.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0234EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-Poll     11-29 0545</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Poll,0564</SECOND>
<HEAD>Survey Of Americans And Japanese Finds Mutual Trust Flagging</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSAN MOFFAT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Japanese and Americans trust each other less and less and an increasing number are pessimistic about the relationship between their countries, according to a new poll. Japanese still trust the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> more than any other country, but <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> ranks only No. 11 among countries Americans trust, according to the poll published Tuesday by <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s largest daily newspaper. According to the survey, former Presidents <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> have left strong impressions on many Japanese but nearly eight in 10 Americans can not name a single Japanese individual who has stuck in their minds. The poll was conducted by the paper <ORGANIZATION> Yomiuri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shimbun </ORGANIZATION> and the American Gallup polling organization. The <ORGANIZATION> Yomiuri </ORGANIZATION> said 3,000 Japanese were surveyed in late September and 1,025 Americans in mid-October. A margin for error was not given. With trade tensions between the two countries on the rise, more Americans than ever before in annual poll's 11-year history called relations between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> `` bad.'' Among Americans, 9.3 percent said relations were bad, compared to 6.0 percent last year. Among Japanese, traditionally more pessimistic on the issue, 18.4 percent said relations were bad, slightly up from 17.5 percent in 1988. Many Americans still feel relations are `` good'' or `` very good'' _ 45.6 percent, compared to 38 percent of Japanese. Among the Japanese polled, just 31 percent believed relations will improve, compared to 52 percent of Americans. Only 15.1 percent of Americans named <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> among the five countries they most trusted, up slightly from last year but far below the 23.4 percent in 1984. Nearly 54 percent of Japanese said they trusted the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, down from last year and lower than the 57.4 percent in 1984. Americans in the poll expressed the most trust for <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>. Japanese gave top trustworthiness rankings to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. Asked if their government should protect domestic industries by restricting imports, 66 percent of Americans said yes, compared to 43 percent of Japanese. On agriculture, 64 percent of Americans said their government should restrict imports, compared to 60 percent of Japanese. Both figures were up from last year. Among the Japanese polled, 82 percent said they would choose a domestically made product over an import, compared to 73 percent of the Americans. Asked to name a Japanese person who had made an impression on them, most of the Americans came up blank. The late Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> was the most prominent Japanese in American minds, although he was named by just 6.6 percent of those polled. Next was <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Akio </PERSON> <PERSON> Morita </PERSON>. Considered an unusually high-profile figure in Japanese business circles, he still left an impression on only 1.6 percent of the Americans polled. By contrast, 33.8 percent of Japanese said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> made an impression on them, followed by 23.3 percent for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and 17.0 percent for Gen. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> MacArthur </PERSON>, who was supreme commander of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces occupying <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> after World War II. Americans saw their own leaders somewhat as the Japanese did, ranking <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> highest, followed by <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ranked eighth most impressive to Americans, and ninth to Japanese
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0020EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Summit-Bush 2ndLd-Writethru a0717 11-29 0921</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Summit-Bush, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0717,920</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush: Summit Surprise Will Be _ No Surprises</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 7th graf, bgng: The sources xxx to include
Post report on possible reductions in weapons procurement personnel.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sought to reassure <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> allies Tuesday about his summit with Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, promising `` I'm not going to surprise them'' with any agreement to cut nuclear weapons or reduce <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops overseas. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> may discuss possible military cutbacks `` in a general way'' when they meet off the coast of <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> on Saturday and Sunday. But he added, `` In writing, I have made clear to Mr. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> _ in my handwriting, so he knows it comes from me, not the bureaucracy _ that this is not a summit for arms control agreement.'' Meanwhile, budget constraints at home are forcing cuts in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> armed services _ whatever troop withdrawals are negotiated with the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact. As of Nov. 1, there were 2.13 million men and women in the armed services. The services have drafted plans for a reduction of 275,000, with about 135,000 to be trimmed from the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, 100,000 from the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> and 40,000 from the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION>, defense sources told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> will make a decision on the service chiefs' proposal when he returns Thursday from a <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> meeting in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>, and reports to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The sources, declining to be identified, said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>, the director of the presidential <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>, was pushing for even deeper cuts in the armed forces. Pentagon officials recommended cutting 23,000 jobs involved in weapons procurement for the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, according to a report in Wednesday's editions of The Washington Post. A final decision has not been made, but members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> have complained that the cuts are aimed mainly at workers and field-level positions while not reducing the ranks of management. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said it was very important for the allies to know `` I'm not going to go off and prematurely jump out there and try to grandstand by committing them to something. That's not the way you keep an alliance strong.'' After the two-day summit, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will fly to <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> on Dec. 4 to brief <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> leaders on the discussions. The allies were aghast to learn in 1987 that then-President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> had come close to a deal at a summit in <LOCATION> Reykjavik </LOCATION> to abolish all nuclear weapons in spite of the fact that <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> regards some of those arms as vital to deter Soviet attack. Now, with the collapse of hard-line communist regimes in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, and massive budget deficits in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is considering major cutbacks in troops and weapons. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is facing similar pressures at home. However, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` There are no arms control proposals'' for the summit. `` So the surprise will be, if you're looking for a surprise, there wo n't be a surprise. That may come as a surprise,'' he said. He said there had been `` frantic speculation'' and `` hyped speculation'' that the superpowers would reach a deal on arms or troops. `` Now if we want to talk in a general way with the Soviet leaders about our aspirations for how a defense system will look 10 years from now, of course, we'll do that, we want to do that,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. In particular, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, he would like to talk with the Soviets about curtailing their defense spending. `` But that's not what I'm referring to when I talk about euphoric expectations of some deal,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` There is n't going to be such a deal It takes two to make a deal.'' Separately, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has little interest in a possible <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> proposal to restrict naval power. `` The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, a land power, would be less constrained by such proposals,'' said <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON>. `` We are not aware of naval arms control measures that enhance stability.'' Despite criticism at home that he has reacted too cautiously to changes sweeping Eastern <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said his approach was solidly supported by <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> leaders. Saying he had consulted with each <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> chief, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` I do n't want to sound self-centered here but almost every one of those leaders told me, ` We think the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is handling this properly. We appreciate the way you're handling these changes, the prudent approach you are taking.''' Moreover, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, it should be the people of <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> who lead the way toward change. `` It does n't come from somebody halfway across the world dictating how fast change should be or what change should encompass.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also promised that he would press <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> at the summit over the behavior of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s Central American allies _ <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, which the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> accuses of shipping Soviet-made weapons to leftist insurgents. The president said he was asked in a telephone call from Costa Rican President <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> to ask <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to `` stop feeding <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> has spearheaded a drive for a regional peace accord in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the Soviets have not cut off arms deliveries to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. `` And as Mr. <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> said, there is one person most responsible for support of the <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- leftist rebels -RRB- to deny democracy to <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, deny democracy to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, and that is <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. He said <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> mentioned Nicaraguan President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> in the same connection.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0027EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PlaneMissing 2ndLd-Writethru a0773 11-29 0297</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Plane Missing, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0773,0300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Commuter Plane Missing With Eight Aboard</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 6th, `Coast Guard searchers ...' to UPDATE
with piece of luggage found on Block Island shore, prompting expansion
of search.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WESTERLY, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airline </ORGANIZATION> commuter plane with eight people aboard was feared missing in the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> after it vanished on a Tuesday night flight from <LOCATION> Block </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, authorities said. <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> rescue teams were dispatched to the waters off Westerly to search for the twin-engine airplane. Coast Guard Petty Officer <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Coughlin </PERSON> said the aircraft left the airport on <LOCATION> Block </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> at 6 p.m. He said the flight to Westerly is about 17 miles, and should take 15 minutes. `` They had an hour and 45 minutes of fuel on board, and an emergency locator transmitter,'' he said. <PERSON> Coughlin </PERSON> said two airplanes flying in the area `` saw something in the water a half-mile south of <LOCATION> Weekapaug </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION>,'' and picked up a distress signal, but the airplane had not been found. <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> searchers from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, Point <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Block </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> searched the water near <LOCATION> Westerly </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Coughlin </PERSON> said a helicopter from the guard's Cape Cod Air Station was en route. Searchers found a piece of luggage on the shore of <LOCATION> Block </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, prompting the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> to expand the search, said <PERSON> Seaman </PERSON> <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Coughlin </PERSON> said the search was extended to <LOCATION> Watch </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, about five miles from Westerly in the state's southernmost tip. Airline spokesman <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said the British <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Islander </PERSON> aircraft was a chartered flight with seven passengers and one pilot on board. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Ciccarelli </PERSON>, the regional <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> Burlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, said the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> Flight Service Station in <LOCATION> Bridgeport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, also picked up the emergency signals.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SummitExpectations Bjt   11-29 0743</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit Expectations, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Planning for the `Summit With No Agenda'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It was to be a casual `` feet up'' meeting with neither expectations nor an agenda. But since this weekend's superpower summit was first announced, the White House is gradually defining items it expects to broach at <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> The administration is seeking to shape an agenda that seems guaranteed to keep the feet of both <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> leaders firmly planted _ even as President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> insists his shipboard summit with Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will yield no deals and no surprises. `` So the surprise will be, if you're looking for a surprise, there wo n't be a surprise. That may come as a surprise,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told reporters Tuesday. Presidential press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> recently observed that the Soviets tend to overplay advance expectations for summits, Americans tend to minimize them; and that the truth lies somewhere in between. So, a week after <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told a <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>, audience the summit would be `` historic,'' the president complained to reporters during an Oval Office picture-taking session Tuesday about `` all kind of hyped speculation.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> insisted he would cut no deals with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> on arms control nor do anything else that would give allies pause. And he said the meeting remains `` without a fixed agenda.'' Still, in an effort not to be caught off-guard as the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was at the 1987 Reagan-Gorbachev summit at <LOCATION> Reykjavik </LOCATION>, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration has been compiling a list of subjects that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is prepared to discuss. It also has suggested ground rules on how some of the subjects will be handled. That looks an awful lot like an agenda. For one thing, the president has made clear he will confront <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> on the issue of continued Soviet bloc arms shipments to rebels in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, by way of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. The administration has said the continued shipments threaten improved U.S.-Soviet relations in other areas. `` I'm not the sort of man that will go there and not raise it,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also has vowed to `` seek his -LRB- <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s -RRB- active cooperation in cleaning up the world's environment.'' `` A world solution can begin with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>,'' the president told a <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> fund-raising audience several days ago. The unraveling of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s East European dominion, of course, will set the tone for the Bush-Gorbachev talks and dominate any agenda-setting efforts. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has said he intends to discuss the upheaval in detail with the Soviet leader and will delve into such issues as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade with Soviet bloc nations. But he has been careful to assure the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' European allies that he and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will not discuss any future European boundaries, that the fate of Eastern bloc nations should be theirs alone to decide. White House officials also indicated this week that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is prepared to talk with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> about arms reductions in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, even though the administration earlier played down this aspect. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have suggested that the breakup of the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact could provide a golden opportunity for deep cuts in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> defense spending _ much of which is earmarked for waging a war in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said that `` certainly the two presidents in <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> will talk about arms control and military force structure.'' But <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> emphasized Tuesday that he would not `` enter into an arms control agreement'' at the summit, and would not catch <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> allies off guard. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is to brief allies in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> at the conclusion of the summit. If the low-key projections issuing from the White House this week follow an old mold for summitry, they also adhere to a pattern <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has set in his political life. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his lieutenants did their best to lower expectations about <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s 1988 acceptance speech at the Republican National Convention; and yet the intensely practiced speech he gave was one that many analysts viewed as the best of his career. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> camp sought to play down expectations of the candidate's performance potential before both of his campaign debates with <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> contender <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. And, more recently, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his lieutenants voiced low expectations before May's <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> summit in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> that the session would produce anything dramatic or lead to a resolution of the alliance's intramural dispute over short-range arms based in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. However, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> produced a breakthrough compromise that unified <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> on the arms issue.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-SovietHopes     11-29 0757</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Soviet Hopes,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gorbachev to Seek US Assurances on Eastern Europe, Improved Trade</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Summit-Bush, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN-THOR DAHLBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> wants assurances from President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> this weekend that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will not exploit the Eastern European reform movement, say government officials who add the Soviet leader hopes for improved trade ties from the superpower summit. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> also will be seeking progress on an array of arms control issues as he and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> hold their first summit Saturday and Sunday on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet warships in the waters off <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>. `` To put it in a nutshell, we need a normal external environment for our domestic work,'' says <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, whose economic restructuring program of perestroika has yet to produce measurable improvements in the daily life of Soviet citizens. The 58-year-old Soviet leader will be attending his sixth summit with an American president, and in circumstances that scarcely seemed imaginable a few weeks ago _ much less when he first sat down with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has encouraged and endorsed the political changes that have brought reformers to power in every Eastern bloc nation except <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>. But in the days leading up to the summit, he has spoken openly of fears that the West may try to exploit the situation. `` The most dangerous thing at such moments is that someone may become tempted to use them for their own selfish interests,'' he said recently. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> seemed to reply in a speech on Nov. 22 in which he said, `` We will seek President <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s assurance that this process of reform in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> will continue. And we will give him our word that <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> welcomes reform not as an adversary seeking advantage, but as a people offering support.'' There seems little doubt that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will underscore his commitment to reform. `` <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> observers say in jest that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will possibly carry to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on board the cruiser <PERSON> Belknap </PERSON> a fragment of the ruined Iron Curtain,'' the official <ORGANIZATION> Novisti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> quipped. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> says the <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION> will no longer impose its views on its allies and may seek a pledge that <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> will not, for example, try the sort of end-run the Soviets staged by aiding <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. To bar potential unrest, the Soviets may even endorse massive <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assistance; <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, for example, is seeking $ 1 billion in Western cash. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s Thanksgiving eve invitation to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to end decades of East-West confrontation was seized on by the Soviets as proof the superpowers are on the threshold of a `` new stage of broad and open cooperation,'' in the words of <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON>. The Soviets are writing a law allowing virtually unrestricted emigration of Jews and others that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wants before recommending that the Soviets be granted `` most-favored nation status,'' to ease access of their goods to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> markets. Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> flushed with anger when asked whether the summit was called so the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> could seek <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid for its shortage-plagued economy. `` It offends our national pride,'' he said. But pride or not, the Soviets want <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> know-how, computers and management techniques. <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> says the Soviets want `` mutually beneficial economic and trade cooperation.'' However, even if <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> agrees to loosen controls on high-tech exports and upgrade the Soviets' trading status, it's uncertain how much their state-run enterprises could benefit As of now, they can offer <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> customers only `` petroleum and vodka and caviar and not much else,'' says <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON>. Arms control _ the centerpiece of past summits _ is now overshadowed by the momentous changes in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. For Soviets, however, weapons cuts would be tangible proof that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s `` new thinking'' is paying off. The Soviet ideal, says <PERSON> Viktor </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kremenyuk </PERSON>, would be a timetable fixing goals for the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> talks on strategic weapons cuts and the <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> negotiations on conventional arms in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kremenyuk </PERSON> is the deputy chief of a <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> think tank studying the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. At the last round of <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> talks, `` the two sides' approaches were so far apart that no convergence was discernible,'' Novisti charged in frustration. The Soviets cleared the way for progress by dropping their condition that <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> agree not to deploy the Strategic Defense Initiative, and now are hinting <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> could break remaining logjams. <PERSON> Kremenyuk </PERSON> said the Soviets want the 30 percent to 50 percent cuts in superpower arsenals envisaged by the proposed Strategic Arms Reduction Treaty, plus a cooling-off of regional conflicts like <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, so they can shift more resources to the civilian economy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891129-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-89 0148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Poland     11-29 0664</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Poland,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Signs Aid Plan for Poland and Hungary</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
