<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 2358EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     11-08 0049</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0052</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Wednesday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 04; 07; 22; 25; 27; 36.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday 54 Lotto Game: 03; 09; 32; 36; 38; 42. Supplementary 11.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 1-2-9; 1-0-7-5; 8-7-7-2-0; 7-5-2-6-3-6.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0058EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ReactorLeak 1stLd-Writethru a0743 11-08 0375</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Reactor Leak, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0743,0378</SECOND>
<HEAD>Leak Forces University To Close Nuclear Reactor Unit</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDs: UPDATES throughout with university saying 300 gallons leaked,
comments from NRC spokesman, background. ADDS byline. No pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN F. BONFATTI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUFFALO, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A leak of radioactive water at the state <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>'s research nuclear reactor forced the university to close the unit, the university said Tuesday. In a news release, the university characterized the leak as `` small'' and said there is no threat to public health or safety from the facility, which is located on the school's south campus in the northernmost part of <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>. Spokeswoman <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Grace-Kobas </PERSON> said a little more than 300 gallons of water from the reactor tank leaked into a storage tank. She said authorities are trying to determine how much is still leaking. The university said the leak was discovered by the reactor's staff Sunday afternoon, when a crew arrived to start it after its weekend shutdown The workers noted that the level of water in the reactor tank, which is normally 30 feet deep, had dropped three inches. The university said the leak has been contained within the reactor facility and is not reaching the public water system or sewer system. <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON>, a spokesman for the federal <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, said the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> was told that about 2 gallons an hour were leaking from the tank. <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> called the leak a rare occurrence at a reasearch reactor but not very serious because the water is not going out of the facility. He said the radioactivity of the water is `` usually extremely low.'' <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Henry </PERSON>, general manager of the facility, said the leak poses no danger to the reactor but that the reactor was nonetheless shut down to provide `` an additional margin of safety.'' In addition to the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> said the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> have been notified. The reactor will remain shut down until the cause of the leak is identified and repaired, he said. The reactor, which is managed by a private company, produces short-lived radioisotopes for medical research and is also used to study the effects of radiation on materials like reactor components and radiation detection devices.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0010EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-ELN--TwinCitiesMayors 2ndLd-Writethru a0STBRUNSWICK
11-08 0275</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-ELN--Twin Cities Mayors, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0915,0277</SECOND>
<HEAD>Minneapolis Mayor Fraser Wins Fourth Term</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 6 grafs to UPDATE with final vote tallies in Minneapolis,
St. Paul. Picks up 7th graf: `Scheibel, 42 ...' No pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Fraser </PERSON> won his fourth term Tuesday, and across the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Scheibel </PERSON> became St. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>'s first new mayor in 13 years. In the state's largest city, <PERSON> Fraser </PERSON> defeated firefighter <PERSON> Jens </PERSON> <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON>, 46, who finished a distant second in the Sept. 12 primary. Both are Democrats. With all 182 precincts reporting, <PERSON> Fraser </PERSON> had 44,585 votes to <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON>'s 11,613. <PERSON> Fraser </PERSON>, 65, represented the <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> area for 16 years in the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> before he lost a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bid in 1978. He has served a record 10 years as mayor and outpolled <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON>, 46, more than 8-1 in the primary. In neighboring <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paul </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Democrat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scheibel </ORGANIZATION>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, led independent <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Fletcher </PERSON>, a police lieutenant, in a race to succeed Mayor <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Latimer </PERSON>, who is stepping down after a record 13-year tenure. <PERSON> Scheibel </PERSON> had 36,003 votes to <PERSON> Fletcher </PERSON>'s 27,783 with all 139 precincts reporting. <PERSON> Scheibel </PERSON>, 42, has served on the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> since 1982. He won a nine-way primary race with 45 percent of the vote to 26 percent for <PERSON> Fletcher </PERSON>. <PERSON> Fletcher </PERSON>, 34, who has strong ties to the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, also was elected to the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> in 1982 but resigned before the end of his term. He later made an unsuccessful bid for a state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat. The campaign has focused on property taxes, crime and drugs. The elections in the Twin Cities were non-partisan.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0243EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-India-Dam     11-08 0700</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-India-Dam,0722</SECOND>
<HEAD>Indian Dam Project To Uproot a Million People, Critics Charge</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VIJAY JOSHI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HARSUD, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Children draw sketches of their homes so they'll remember them later. Their parents no longer repair their huts. Traders do n't bother to drum up new business. <PERSON> Harsud </PERSON> is one of 573 communities destined to be flooded in a giant dam project that pits environmental concerns against <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s attempts at modernization The government says the $ 15 billion project on central <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Narmada </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> will irrigate drought-stricken farmland and provide electrical power Critics say it will displace a million people and destroy the ecology. `` What is the use of the dam that will be our doom?'' said <PERSON> Naginchand </PERSON> <PERSON> Sand </PERSON>, a local businessman. In September, leading environmentalists and 35,000 villagers descended on <LOCATION> Harsud </LOCATION>, a town of 15,000, in a demonstration to denounce the dam project as a `` human and environmental tragedy.'' A man who runs a grocery store near Sand's fertilizer store said he had planned to expand his business but after the dam project was announced in 1987 `` all my dreams ended.'' `` A sort of gloom descended on the village,'' he added. `` But now with the massive protest there is fresh hope.'' The Narmada dam project in <LOCATION> Madhya </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pradesh </LOCATION> state is the largest ever planned in the world. It envisages 30 major, 135 medium and 3,000 minor dams along the 805-mile river and its 41 tributaries. So far three dams have been built. The river is one of the holiest to Hindus. According ancient belief, it was formed by the tears of <ORGANIZATION> Shiva </ORGANIZATION>, one of the gods of the Hindu trinity. The river originates in a pond 335 miles to the east of <LOCATION> Harsud </LOCATION> and courses through lush forests, farmland and narrow rocky gorges in a series of falls and twists before reaching the <LOCATION> Arabian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s western coast. About 21 million people, 80 percent of them tribespeople and villagers, live in the <LOCATION> Narmada </LOCATION> <LOCATION> basin </LOCATION>, which is bounded on three sides by mountains and on the fourth by the sea. If the river is dammed, 2,410 square miles of forests and farmland _ an area slightly larger than <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> _ will be submerged and about 1 million people will be displaced, said <PERSON> Ashish </PERSON> <PERSON> Kothari </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kalpavriksh </LOCATION>, an independent environmental group. Other independent groups agree with those figures, but no official estimates have been made available. <PERSON> Harsud </PERSON> will disappear under 50 feet of water when one of the major dams of the project, the <LOCATION> Indira </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sagar </LOCATION>, is built 15 miles away. The government says the dams are necessary to bring `` an era of prosperity'' to the valley because they will irrigate 20,000 square miles of land in drought-prone areas of <LOCATION> Madhya </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pradesh </LOCATION> and adjoining <LOCATION> Gujarat </LOCATION> state. The project is also supposed to generate 2,700 megawatts of electricity. As for the people who will have to move, the government says it has prepared extensive rehabilitation plans, including monetary compensation. `` Who wants money? I want my land. Will you feel nice if the land that gives you food is drowned?'' said farmer <PERSON> Bhure </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, who traveled 155 miles on the roof of a crowded bus to demonstrate in <LOCATION> Harsud </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kothari </PERSON> of the environmental group said there wo n't be enough land left in the area for so many people to live on if the dams are built. To compensate for forest loss, the government plans to plant new forests. <PERSON> Kothari </PERSON> maintained, however, they could not replace the hundreds of thousands of species of plants and animals that may have evolved over millions of years. Another objection is the project's $ 15 billion price tag, which some economists say is a gross underestimate. <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> has promised to lend <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> $ 450 million for the project. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Fauss </PERSON>, a senior irrigation engineer with the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, said a project of <PERSON> Narmada </PERSON>'s size is bound to create `` some environmental disturbances.'' `` But the trade-off is that thousands and thousands of people benefit from it. We still feel that the project is technically and economically feasible.'' However, <PERSON> Vijay </PERSON> <PERSON> Paranjpye </PERSON>, an economist with the governing body of Indian universities, concluded in a study of the project that it is `` economically not viable.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0246EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ArmyFashion     11-08 0587</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Army Fashion,0604</SECOND>
<HEAD>French Army Parades Chic New Uniforms</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUZY PATTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Fashion Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the fashionable French trench, tacky khaki is out and polyester is in. The berets can stay but unpleated pants got their marching orders as the army paraded its new uniforms Tuesday at an unusual fashion show. Not everyone was wild about the styles; some full-figured soldiers complain they may have to wear girdles to squeeze into the new skirt-pants for women. The parade showed blousons for all enlisted persons and straight, pleated pants for men and women. The lighter fabrics and colors with contemporary style and practicality make army gear look made more for fashion than fighting. `` It was time for a change,'' said Gen. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Forray </PERSON>, chief of staff of the army, who helped engineer the creation of the uniforms, which had not changed for 40 years. The uniforms were ordered from the house of <LOCATION> Balmain </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Balmain </LOCATION>, who also recently redesigned uniforms for the <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> police, was chosen after polls conducted within the army to determine which cuts, colors and fabrics would best suit the needs of today's army. The clothes were designed by <ORGANIZATION> Balmain </ORGANIZATION>'s couture designer <PERSON> Erik </PERSON> <PERSON> Mortensen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Aubert </PERSON>, head of the company's masculine <ORGANIZATION> fashion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> department </ORGANIZATION>. The fashion parade, after opening with some flamboyant red-white-blue braid-edged redingotes from the time of <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> XV </LOCATION>, displayed what the new officers, gentlemen and women will wear in the service beginning in 1991. The new blousons with a shoulder-to-waist pleat are both sober and chic. The clothes are topped with kepis for officers or sharp berets with wheel-shaped pins. `` And thank heaven they did n't get rid of the kepi,'' said one male fashion observer, who noticed that male officers would still sport the hat silhouette as distinctive as <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaulle </PERSON>'s. <PERSON> Khaki </PERSON> is out in the new military palette, a lighter shade of putty or pewter called `` terre de <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'' is in, and in a lighter fabric _ a mix of wool and polyester, rather than heavy twill. `` It's more practical, a lot less gear is involved now, and it's more elegant,'' said Capt <PERSON> Denis </PERSON> <PERSON> Brunel </PERSON>. Except for navy blue uniforms for the infantry, the army will wear the new greige, and women will no longer wear their slate blue, but the same putty color as men. `` That's good, and makes women more the equal of men,'' said Sgt. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Gall </PERSON>. `` My wife is in the army too, she'll surely approve.'' A layered look called `` modular'' means officers and gentlemen can go without their coats even when confronting superiors. The light cotton poplin shirts underneath have epaulets, tab pockets and may be substituted for a jacket in warm weather. `` I think the uniforms look very good and easy to wear,'' said Col. <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Vigilant </PERSON> of the artillery corps. `` They give an impression of serenity, which we need in the army. I'm a philosopher _ with my feet on the ground.'' The only sticky problem, so to speak, is in women's skirt-pants, a new knee-length pair of bermuda shorts with a wrapped skirt covering. `` What about real women? I'm waiting to see how the new uniforms will work out on us,'' said Sgt. <PERSON> Chantal </PERSON> <PERSON> Grosjean </PERSON>, a full-figured soldier about 5-foot-4. `` A real woman has thighs and a stomach. What happens with these uniforms? We might have to wear girdles.'' And she also thought they might prove difficult in summer. `` We have to sit around on those fake leather chairs all day long.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0247EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-MaoGrandson     11-08 0581</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mao Grandson,0598</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mao's Grandson an `Ordinary Student' _ Yet, There's That Limo</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRIL JONES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Xinyu </PERSON> tries to lead a quiet life at a prestigious <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> university despite being the grandson of <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse-tung </PERSON>, the revolutionary founder of communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. `` I'm just an ordinary student,'' says the shy, chubby sophomore, who wears patched clothes and canvas army shoes. `` I have 20 classes a week, and play badminton and <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> chess with classmates.'' The 19-year-old history major at <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> has seven roommates in a cramped first-floor dorm room where he sleeps on a bottom bunk and is known simply as `` Sixth Brother.'' Yet, on Saturdays, a black military limousine glides up to take the grandson of the Great Helmsman to an expensive health club, where he enjoys the sauna. On Wednesdays, when he does n't have class, the limo takes <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> home, where he has his clothes washed and an army cook prepares `` good food.'' And mail pours in from people across the country nostalgic about Chairman <PERSON> Mao </PERSON>, who was virtually deified as a living god by millions of adoring Chinese during his lifetime, and curious about his grandson. <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Xinyu </PERSON> is the only child of <PERSON> Mao </PERSON>'s second son, <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Anqing </PERSON>, a retired <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> translator for the People's <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, and novelist <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> <PERSON> Raohua </PERSON>, who wrote under the pen name <PERSON> Shao </PERSON> <PERSON> Hua </PERSON>. His home, where his parents and grandmother live, is near the Summer Palace in northwestern <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. `` I ca n't tell you more than that,'' he says with a chuckle. `` It's a state military secret.'' His favorite class is the history of Sino-U.S. relations, and he spoke excitedly about the recent visit to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> by former President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, who paved the way to normalizing ties between <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> in 1972 with his historic meeting with <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse-tung </PERSON>. Not that the elder <PERSON> Mao </PERSON>'s place in history is entirely glorious. Western and Chinese historians alike credit him with the abortive `` Great Leap Forward'' of 1958-59, a drive to increase production that ultimately plunged <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> into widespread starvation and poverty. He was also behind the disastrous 1966-76 Cultural Revolution, during which intellectuals and merchants were reviled, schools closed and Red Guards spouting <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> slogans went on a nationwide revolutionary rampage. `` History will judge him as a great man, a leader of great ability, who made great contributions,'' <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Xinyu </PERSON> says. `` But he had some faults.'' Despite his interest in politics, <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> declines to discuss the pro-democracy protests that rocked <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> this spring, other than to say `` of course'' he did not participate in the marches and demonstrations. He does say, however, that vandals' splattering of the portrait of <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> overlooking <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> on May 23 `` made me mad. It made all Chinese mad. It was just a couple of guys trying to attract attention.'' <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> attracts plenty of attention of his own, receiving bundles of unsolicited mail. `` Ordinary people, students, intellectuals, they all write,'' he says. `` Mostly they're nostalgic about Chairman <PERSON> Mao </PERSON>. But a lot of them say they're very happy I've gone on to college.'' Some are girls who `` just want to be friends.'' <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> says someday he'd like to visit the hometown of <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> and see the Lincoln Memorial in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> was a progressive capitalist revolutionary, uniting the North and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> in the civil war,'' he said. <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> also takes some philosophy courses. Asked who his favorite philosophers are, he replies, `` <PERSON> Marx </PERSON>. And my grandfather.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0248EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SouthAfrica     11-08 0396</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-South Africa,0408</SECOND>
<HEAD>President To Meet White Extremist Leader</HEAD>
<HEAD>By DAVID CRARY</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President F.W. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> has agreed to hold talks with the leader of the country's largest white extremist group, the neo-Nazi <ORGANIZATION> Afrikaner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, his office says. The meeting, to be held at an unspecified time this week, was requested by the movement's leader, <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> TerreBlanche </PERSON>, and announced Tuesday. <PERSON> TerreBlanche </PERSON>'s organization espouses the creation of a whites-only nation in the northeastern third of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. Its members often wear khaki uniforms with swastika-like emblems, and <PERSON> TerreBlanche </PERSON> often ends his speeches with a Hitler-style salute. <PERSON> TerreBlanche </PERSON> asked for the meeting after <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>, who took office in August, met with prominent black anti-apartheid activists and declared his willingness to confer with leaders across the political spectrum. The Afrikaner <ORGANIZATION> Resistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> has denounced <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>'s decision to ease restrictions on anti-apartheid protests and his pledge to extend political rights to blacks In July, <PERSON> TerreBlanche </PERSON> said <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> was `` not man enough'' to run against him for a parliamentary seat. But <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> had to quit <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> to become president, and <PERSON> TerreBlanche </PERSON> decided not to run for office. Cabinet ministers plan two other meetings this week related to ongoing political controversies. _ Foreign Minister <PERSON> Pik </PERSON> <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> is to travel Thursday to the nominally independent black homeland of <LOCATION> Transkei </LOCATION> to confer with its military leader, Gen. <PERSON> Bantu </PERSON> <PERSON> Holomisa </PERSON> The 33-year-old general last month announced he might allow the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to operate in <LOCATION> Transkei </LOCATION> and has suggested holding a referendum to see if homeland residents want to renounce their `` independence,'' which is not recognized by any foreign country. _ Development Minister <PERSON> Stoffel </PERSON> <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> der </PERSON> <PERSON> Merwe </PERSON> and Deputy Foreign Minister <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Wessels </PERSON> were to meet today with the Rev <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Chikane </PERSON>, general secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Churches </ORGANIZATION>, to discuss the alleged maltreatment of hundreds of blacks by authorities in <LOCATION> Ciskei </LOCATION>, another nominally independent homeland. <PERSON> Chikane </PERSON> said Tuesday that <LOCATION> Ciskei </LOCATION> authorities had bulldozed the homes of more than 300 families who had sought to retain their South African citizenship after their community, <PERSON> Nkqonkweni </PERSON>, was incorporated into <LOCATION> Ciskei </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Chikane </PERSON> demanded that the South African government reassert jurisdiction over the community, restore the demolished homes and compensate for damages. More than 800 members of the community have taken refuge at a <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> King </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Williamstown </LOCATION>, near the <LOCATION> Ciskei </LOCATION> border.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0248EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-India-Television     11-08 0779</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-India-Television,0805</SECOND>
<HEAD>TV: Now Appearing In The Provinces And Starring In This Month's Elections</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SHARON HERBAUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BANDIKUI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Every night in thousands of Indian villages, residents gather around a small television set in the dusty main bazaar for news they once only got third or fourth hand, if at all. Suddenly, people steeped in ancient tradition who seldom venture beyond the next village are plunged into a world of historical pageantry, costume drama, satellite sports or whatever Prime Minister <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> happens to be doing that day. In <LOCATION> Bandikui </LOCATION>, across the <LOCATION> Rajasthan </LOCATION> state and even in the most backward of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 550,000 villages, television has become the primary means of education and the main source of information. Only about 20 million television sets serve the country's 880 million people. But Indians already have developed a love-hate relationship with the government-run television network, Doordarshan. And <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> and the governing <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, facing a general election later this month, are well aware of the network's enormous influence. Political analysts say the election is likely to be the most uncertain in 22 years. There are no major national issues to swing the vote as in the past four elections. And the governing party, its popularity wavering, stands a chance of losing power for the second time in modern <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 42-year history. `` It will be the first Indian election in which television will have a major role to play,'' said political analyst <PERSON> Bhabani </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON> <PERSON> Gupta </PERSON> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>. In a nation with 36 percent literacy, the government still wields a powerful monopoly over the two-thirds majority who depend on radio and televison for information. Critics contend the coverage has become so biased toward the prime minister that what is labeled news is merely propaganda for the governing party. `` Television is becoming a serious impediment to free and fair elections. It tilts the balance totally in favor of the ruling party,'' said opposition leader L.K. <PERSON> Advani </PERSON>, minister of <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> and Information during the 1977-79 opposition government. The government denies charges the network has become its propaganda tool. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> `` is not only the president of the ruling party, he is the prime minister of the world's largest democracy. And what he says and where he goes is news,'' said H.K.L. <PERSON> Bhagat </PERSON>, minister of Broadcasting and Information. `` Does the Western media ignore <PERSON> Maggie </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> or <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>?'' The controversy highlights just how far <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> has matured, materially and politically, since <PERSON> Jawaharlal </PERSON> <PERSON> Nehru </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s grandfather and <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s first prime minister, declared television an `` expensive toy'' unsuitable for his poor country Doordarshan, which means `` seen from afar'' in Hindi, debuted in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> in 1965 with black-and-white broadcasts. The network expanded to other cities by 1972, adding to the country's rapid progress in technology and the rising prosperity of the middle class. Color broadcasts began seven years ago. When <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> coasted to a landslide victory two months after his mother's 1984 assassinatio television reached just 18 percent of the population. But its influence was quickly noticed by the new government. `` To a large number of Indians -LRB- <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> -RRB- is the first <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> prime minister who is also a television personality,'' said <PERSON> Tavleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, a political commentator for the <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION> newspaper, which has been highly critical of <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s government. `` Whereas Mrs. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> used television mainly for political purposes, rallies, important speeches, her trips abroad, <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> has managed to go a step beyond and use it to project himself as a person as well,'' <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> said. The Doordarshan network now has 18 stations and 340 transmitters beaming to nearly 90 percent of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s villages and cities. The entire country will be within reach by early next year. Critics contend the network's coverage has gone from generally favorable to outright bias. The prime minister and his party have increasingly dominated the 20-minute English and Hindi-language nightly news programs. The opposition has been given short shrift, with coverage often highlighting inconsequential points of leaders' speeches and frequently editing out criticism of the government, critics say. Such tactics have drawn fire from the English language-press, which has dismissed the network as a `` pusillanimous propaganda pustule.'' Some reporters say the network often takes orders directly from the prime minister's office and there is a huge amount of self-censorship. `` No one wants to take a chance with the prime minister's coverage You never know what some hard-line party member will object to,'' said one senior reporter, speaking on condition of anonymity. Government officials defend their actions. `` This is the legitimate work of the Information and <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>,'' said Deputy Minister K.K. <PERSON> Tewari </PERSON>. `` It is our legitimate duty also to rebut unjust criticism of the government.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0249EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PilarczykProfile     11-08 0522</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pilarczyk Profile,0537</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Catholic Bishop Leader Favors More Involvement with the Laity</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Catholic Bishops</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRIGGS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Archbishop <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pilarczyk </PERSON>, elected as president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bishops </ORGANIZATION>, says he is hoping to give the laity more of a role in running the church. `` I think we're moving out of a situation in which the only person who was allowed to do anything in the parish was a priest. And I think that's a healthy move,'' said <PERSON> Pilarczyk </PERSON>, archbishop of <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>. In the Archdiocese of <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>, two of the six people in the bishop's `` inner circle'' are women, and laypeople serve as directors of religious education, visitors of the sick and youth ministers. <PERSON> Pilarczyk </PERSON>, 55, was ordained a priest in 1959, became auxiliary bishop of <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> in 1974 and archbishop in 1982 after Cardinal <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernardin </PERSON> left for the Archdiocese of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Pilarczyk </PERSON> said he is not sure he could have been a bishop in the days before the <ORGANIZATION> Second </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vatican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> in the early 1960s when many prelates were `` brick-and-mortar'' men expected to be adept at handling finances and building new churches. Since Vatican II, <PERSON> Pilarczyk </PERSON> said, what is expected of a bishop is greater grassroots contact with the laity and more pastoral attention to the personal needs of priests. Like his predecessor Archbishop <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> May </PERSON> of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, whom <PERSON> Pilarczyk </PERSON> served as conference vice president, <PERSON> Pilarczyk </PERSON> is viewed as a moderate who enjoys support from both liberal and conservative camps. `` <PERSON> Pilarczyk </PERSON> will play just the role that's needed now. We want a middle-of-the-road stance,'' said Monsignor <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Gremillion </PERSON>, a scholar-in-residence at <ORGANIZATION> Notre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dame </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. When asked what are the most important issues facing the church, <PERSON> Pilarczyk </PERSON> mentioned abortion and euthanasia and economic issues such as Third World debt and the rights of labor unions. In matters of public policy, <PERSON> Pilarczyk </PERSON> indicated a willingness to compromise. For example, he said if the question was whether he would tolerate abortions for rape and incest victims if the law were changed to prohibit other abortions, `` the answer is probably yes.'' <PERSON> Pilarczyk </PERSON> said he does not favor a general statement saying the bishops' conference could tolerate condom education in public schools if sexual abstinence was presented as the only morally correct way to prevent AIDS. `` In saying that, you almost necessarily encourage people to engage in premarital sexual activity,'' he said. A document on AIDS approved by the conference's <ORGANIZATION> Administrative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> was criticized by some bishops for conditionally tolerating condom education, and a second statement on AIDS that attacks condom education is scheduled for a vote Wednesday. If <PERSON> Pilarczyk </PERSON> has a fault, according to the Rev. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reese </PERSON> of the Woodstock Theological Center at <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, it may be that he relies too much on intellectual argument to win people to his side. `` Sometimes, it takes more than that to persuade people,'' said <PERSON> Reese </PERSON>, author of `` Archbishop: Inside the Power Structure of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>.'' `` His one weakness may be he may not be political enough.'' <PERSON> Pilarczyk </PERSON>'s term as president will run for three years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0659EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--JapaneseAmbassador     11-08 0156</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Japanese Ambassador,0159</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japanese Ambassador Marks History, Looks Ahead</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PORTSMOUTH, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s ambassador to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had encouraging words about the future while marking the Treaty of <LOCATION> Portsmouth </LOCATION> that ended the Russo-Japanese War 84 years ago. Ambassador <PERSON> Nobuo </PERSON> <PERSON> Matsunaga </PERSON> visited a museum Tuesday to view artifacts of the Treaty of <LOCATION> Portsmouth </LOCATION>, which was mediated by President <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> and signed Sept. 5, 1905, to end the 18-month war with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s victory. <PERSON> Matsunaga </PERSON> acknowledged his country's pre-eminence the global marketplace, but said cooperation with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is important to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. `` <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> needs the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to survive, and <LOCATION> Americans </LOCATION> must realize that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> has become an indispensable trading partner of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Matsunaga </PERSON> said. `` Blaming and criticizing each other will solve nothing. ... We must cooperate.'' <PERSON> Matsunaga </PERSON> will complete 44 years of diplomatic service when he returns to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> on Nov. 18. He has served in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for nearly five years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0022EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-WasteTrain     11-08 0330</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Waste Train,0342</SECOND>
<HEAD>State Orders Company to Remove Train Carrying Sewage</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JACKSON, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> on Tuesday ordered a <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> company to remove a train carrying 5,000 tons of sewage sludge or face $ 2 million a day in fines. `` <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> is not a dumping ground for someone else's sewage, and this order should ensure that we get rid of it,'' Gov. <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Mabus </PERSON> said in a statement announcing the order by the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Quality </ORGANIZATION>. The train, dubbed the `` poo poo choo choo,'' arrived Friday in <LOCATION> Moss </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> just outside <LOCATION> Pascagoula </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> after being driven out of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> by residents who complained of its smell. The 63 cars covered with plastic are loaded with 5,000 tons of non-hazardous, treated human waste from <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>. Under the order, <ORGANIZATION> GSX </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, will be fined $ 2 million a day retroactive to Nov. 3 if it does n't remove the waste. A hearing to allow the company to challenge the fines was scheduled for Nov. 21, said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Goff </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mabus </PERSON>' adviser on environmental issues. GSX Vice President <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said Tuesday night that the proposed fine seemed excessive. In a telephone interview from his <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> home, he said GSX was considering sending the sludge to one of several landfills or to one of several composting businesses and said he believed the company would find someone to take the waste Wednesday. He declined to identify the landfills. GSX contracted with <PERSON> Metcalf </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Eddy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> to dispose of 12,000 tons of the sludge from <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>'s municipal sewage system at a plant in White Castle, La. An unspecified amount of waste still waits in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said the contract allows his company to return the waste if it is turned away at White Castle, but the company in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> has n't wanted to take it back. `` We probably are n't going to take any more of it since this has been such a problem,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     11-08 0818</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0855</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Chicken Soup'' was no cure-all for <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, and its star, <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, says the show's cancellation is fine with him. The network Tuesday canceled the new series, saying it was n't holding its own in the Tuesday night spot following the hit `` Roseanne. The show's finale was Tuesday, even though three finished episodes were awaiting broadcast. <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, a rabbi-turned-comedian, played a Jewish ex-pajama salesman in love with an Irish-Catholic widow portrayed by <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Redgrave </PERSON>. TV Guide's editors in September had predicted `` Chicken Soup'' as the most likely hit of the season. <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> said in a statement that there have been many ups and downs in his life, `` but one thing that I know is that there are at least 20 million gentiles who now know what a real Jew sounds like.'' <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> said he would continue to perform club dates, possibly put on another one-man show on Broadway and work on other projects. `` Chicken Soup'' will be suceeded, starting Nov. 21, by `` Coach,'' which premiered last season and stars <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> as a college football coach.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BIRMINGHAM, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON>'s new hearing aids allowed him to carry on a conversation for the first time in months without requiring others to write down what they said, a hospital official said. <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> was fitted Tuesday for the devices after doctors decided he did n't need surgery to improve his hearing. <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Fetzer </PERSON>, public affairs officer at the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> where <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> underwent tests, said that <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> `` has a high frequency loss. ... It wo n't be normal hearing but it will be better.'' She said the four-term governor recently had relied on others to write down their messages after his old hearing aids became ineffective. `` He looked in good spirits and he was a happy camper when he left here,'' she said. <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> will return later in the month to pick up his new hearing aids. The 70-year-old <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> has used a wheelchair since a 1972 assassination attempt. His hearing has been failing for years.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Duchess of York appeared at a program encouraging children to read, but no one was sitting down with her Budgie books: They were n't available. The former <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> led a group of schoolchildren Tuesday at the Children's Museum of <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> to a table laden with books by her publisher, <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Schuster. The books did n't include `` Budgie the Little Helicopter'' and `` Budgie at <PERSON> Bendick </PERSON>'s Point.'' Asked why, the duchess just smiled. `` It was n't an event to promote the Budgie books,'' said <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Geist </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Schuster. To showcase <PERSON> Budgie </PERSON> `` would have been too obvious,'' said <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Corniche </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. The stories are of a helicopter that has adventures and does n't like to bathe. The meeting between the 30-year-old duchess and youngsters was organized by Reading is Fundamental. The duchess, who is married to <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, has said she got the idea for the Budgie character while taking helicopter lessons. <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> is a helicopter pilot in the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Humorist <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchwald </PERSON> will call several prominent <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> writers, including director-screenwriter <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, as expert witnesses in his plagiarism lawsuit against <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. In the $ 5 million suit, set for trial in state court next month, <PERSON> Buchwald </PERSON> contends the <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> movie `` Coming to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'' is similar to an idea called `` King for a Day'' that the columnist came up with in 1983. Both stories involve African princes who come to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and fall in love. The studio has denied the plagiarism allegations. Late last month, <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> denied a motion by Paramount to dismiss the lawsuit. Plagiarism lawsuits involving ideas for films are complicated because many people can be involved in working on a screenplay at various stages of production. The 83-year-old <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, a six-time Academy Award winner whose movies include such classics as `` The Lost Weekend'' and `` The Apartment,'' is one of at least nine screenwriters expected to testify on <PERSON> Buchwald </PERSON>'s behalf.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Kanaly </PERSON>, who appeared on the prime-time soap opera `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' is suing a video production company alleging breach of contract. <PERSON> Kanaly </PERSON>, who played <PERSON> J.R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ewing </PERSON>'s half-brother <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Krebbs </PERSON>, filed the lawsuit Monday in <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> against <ORGANIZATION> True </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Productions </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> True </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Video </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Productions </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Kanaly </PERSON>, 43, says the companies failed to pay him $ 25,000 for narrating a videocassette called `` Family Guide To Firearms and Gun Safety. The actor also claimed he is owed 3 percent of the wholesale price of each cassette sold or shipped to retailers by the distributor. Kanally said True North, which produced the video, failed to pay or account for the royalties. A telephone call made to True North after business hours Tuesday went unanswered.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 1605EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     11-08 0413</FIRST>
<SECOND>njtti</SECOND>
<HEAD>PM-Nielsens,0408</HEAD>
<HEAD>Veteran Television Stars Carry Ratings For NBC</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY BUCK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> and <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON>, who went from sitcoms to dramas, are making serious problems for <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s Tuesday night comedy lineup <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> in `` Heat of the Night'' and <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> in `` Matlock'' knocked <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne'' down to fourth place last week, and contributed to the cancellation of `` Chicken Soup.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won the week and its own Thursday comedy block led the way. `` The Cosby Show'' was first, `` A Different World'' second and `` Cheers'' third. `` Dear John'' was sixth and the season premiere of `` L.A. Law'' was tied for ninth place, according to the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> ratings. `` In the Heat of the Night'' was 14th and `` Matlock'' was 18th. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s rival Tuesday night shows `` The Wonder Years,'' `` Who's the Boss?'' and `` Chicken Soup'' respectively were 17th, tied for 19th, and 23rd. `` Chicken Soup,'' starring comedian <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, had been expected by many to be the season's biggest hit. Instead, it had its final broadcast Tuesday night. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> was first last week with an average prime-time rating of 15.2, to <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s 13.7 and CBS' 11.9. Each point represents the percentage of the nation's 92.1 million homes with televisions. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> also leads for the season-to-date and the November sweeps, when local affiliates' advertising rates are in part determined by the network shows' ratings. The ratings for the first seven weeks of the season: <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 15.0, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 13.7, CBS 12.6. For the first four days of the sweeps: <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 15.0, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> 12.8, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 11.3. Here are last week's top 10: <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Cosby Show,'' `` A Different World,'' and `` Cheers''; <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne''; <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Golden Girls'' and `` Dear John''; <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` 60 Minutes'' and `` Murder, She Wrote''; and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Empty Nest'' and `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' tied. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> has been hitting <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> hard on Tuesday night, which has been <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s strongest ratings night. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won the night for the first time, not including the summer months, since <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> moved `` Roseanne'' to 9 p.m. February. `` Midnight Caller,'' which stars <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>, was 26th for the week. `` Chicken Soup'' will be replaced by the return of `` Coach,'' starring <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shelley </PERSON> <PERSON> Fabares </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Married ... With Children'' was 51st for the week. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` World News Tonight'' was first in the news ratings. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> has won the past four weeks and tied with CBS the previous week. The news ratings last week were: <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 11.4, CBS 10.7, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 10.1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-ELN--TexasAmendments     11-08 0259</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-ELN--Texas Amendments,0266</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pay Raise, Expenses Rejected for Texas Lawmakers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL HOLMES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AUSTIN, Tex. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Voters rejected by a 2-to-1 margin Tuesday a proposal that would have raised the salary of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> lawmakers from $ 7,200 a year to $ 23,300. `` It's a good thing there was n't a ballot alternative that said legislators' pay should be lowered,'' said Democratic state Sen. <PERSON> Chet </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Duncanville </LOCATION>. With 83 percent of the state's precincts reporting, the pay raise was defeated with 614,373 no votes, or 65 percent, to 327,823 yes votes, or 35 percent. Another proposal that would have boosted lawmakers' daily expense allowance from $ 30 to $ 81 was defeated 53 percent to 47 percent. Opponents of the pay hike noted that lawmakers meet only 140 days every other year. Language in the amendment would strip voters of the ability to approve future pay raises by tying lawmakers' salaries to the governor's pay, which the legislature sets <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> voters faced 21 ballot propositions. A $ 500 million bond issue that would provide money for water projects statewide _ with $ 100 million dedicated to cleaning up substandard communities on the <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> border _ was leading by a 58 percent to 42 percent margin with 89 percent of the vote in. A $ 400 million bond issue for building prisons and mental health facilities passed by 68 percent to 32 percent. Also approved was the removal of a 113-year-old provision requiring <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> office-holders to swear they won their posts without bribing anyone. The change passed by 69 percent to 31 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0321EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SovietSpuds Bjt   11-08 0676</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet Spuds, Bjt,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Spud Trust' to Market Potato Chips in Soviet Union</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The idea may sound a little flaky, but <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fritzi </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> and their <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> partners insist they can turn a profit on a joint venture to make `` upscale'' organic potato chips in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. `` What you call a potato chip is almost unknown in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Valeri </PERSON> <PERSON> Perekhvatov </PERSON>, one of two Soviet partners who signed a joint venture protocol Tuesday with the <ORGANIZATION> Cohens </ORGANIZATION>. `` We believe that potato chips are a good snack, especially after you have had a glass of vodka,'' he told a news conference called to announce the venture, the <ORGANIZATION> Kartoshka </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION>, which translates from Russian roughly as the `` Spud Trust.'' Not only will chips ease the crunch in the Soviet snack market, said <PERSON> Perekhvatov </PERSON>, but by frying the chips down on the farm and transporting the finished product, the partners hope to avoid one of the most vexing problems of Soviet agriculture: the loss of up to half of the crop in storage and transport. The <ORGANIZATION> Kartoshka </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> plans to start small, selling about 100 tons of chips annually, to a very different market than served by the <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>'s Tabard Farm Potato Chips. Tabard Farm accounts for a tiny fraction of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s annual $ 4 billion potato chip market. The Cohens say they grow `` environmentally sound'' spuds in the <LOCATION> Shenandoah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, truck them to <PERSON> Aunt </PERSON> <PERSON> Annie </PERSON>'s Potato Chip factory in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>'s Amish country, and market them in a few tony stores, restaurants and clubs in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Kartoshka </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> expects to market about 95 percent of its spuds in regular <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> stores, and about 5 percent in the <LOCATION> Beriozka </LOCATION> stores and luxury hotels that cater to Western visitors and accept only hard currency, <PERSON> Perekhvatov </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Cohens </ORGANIZATION> said their low initial investment in the <LOCATION> Kartoshka </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Trust </LOCATION> will help them avoid what has been a fatal trap for some U.S.-Soviet ventures, a Soviet law that allows the foreign partner to take home only the profits that are made in convertible Western currencies. The Soviet government on Oct. 27 devalued the ruble for a limited number of transactions involving foreign businesses, allowing them to convert at 16 cents on the ruble. But for most transactions, the rate remains at the inflated official level of $ 1.59, and the ban remains on converting from rubles to dollars at the higher rate for repatriating profits. But the <ORGANIZATION> Cohens </ORGANIZATION> said they were content to run a large ruble surplus until they `` find solutions to what now seem to be insurmountable problems'' of getting the money home. Besides, they believe they can obtain the right kind of potato chip kettle for rubles, rather than dollars. Their only other dollar expense is expected to be 10,000 bags for the initial market run, plus plane tickets to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to sign a more formal contract in January, he said. The goal of the operation, at least for the American side, is not large profits but helping the Soviets develop a new type of small-scale food industry, said <PERSON> Fritzi </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, who was a founding member of the <ORGANIZATION> Washington-Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION>, designed to promote friendship between the superpowers. <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is `` way ahead of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'' in chip technology, acknowledged <PERSON> Perekhvatov </PERSON>, but the <LOCATION> Kartoshka </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Trust </LOCATION> will try to bridge that gap by allowing the Soviets to start with a simple, manageable process. The protocol signed Tuesday requires <PERSON> Perekhvatov </PERSON>'s Moscow-based Likino Cooperative, and the <LOCATION> Zybina </LOCATION> farm cooperative near the city of <LOCATION> Tula </LOCATION>, to minimize their use of chemicals and synthetic fertilizers, said <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>. And they will build what he called a `` one-kettle'' chip factory, employing about a dozen people to clean, slice, fry, transport, market and account for the potato chips, he said. `` Because of our small scale, we can help people who can handle this get off to a good start,'' said <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>. `` We think that it is a model for economic development in certain parts of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0313EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Pentagon-PacificRim Bjt   11-08 0628</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pentagon-Pacific Rim, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon Board Advises US to `Run Faster' on High-Tech Issues</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration must `` run faster'' and plan better to meet increased competition for civil and military technologies from nations such as <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, a top <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> advisory board recommends. `` National security can no longer be viewed only in military terms, but must include economic well-being as a key component. ... This is a distinct departure from the past,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, an independent group set up to counsel the Pentagon. `` The point is, it is not <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s aggressive roadmap for the future that is at fault. Rather, it has been our own inability to get our act together and create a national vision and set of goals of our own,'' the panel said. The panel issued a strongly worded report that said the current policies for industrial cooperation and technology transfers `` are no longer appropriate'' and may endanger American's global economic and military well-being. `` Our economic, as well as our military security, depends vitally on technological leadership. Technology is the new coinage of the realm and ours has been seriously depleted. ... We can not maintain a lead by conservatism and protectionism. We must run faster!'' said <PERSON> Malcom </PERSON> <PERSON> Currie </PERSON>, the chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Hughes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and head of the task group that issued the report. The report touched on the recent controversy over the joint U.S.-Japanese development of the FSX fighter plane, which set off an acrimonious debate in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> over concerns about giveaways of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> technology to nations eager to use <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> expertise to build their own industries. Some in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> were angry that the Japanese refused to simply purchase the plane from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as a replacement for the F-16, while others argued the deal promoted exchanges of technology and helped the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> industries involved. `` The fragmented policies of the past, in which military security and economic issues were separated, are no longer acceptable,'' <PERSON> Currie </PERSON> said in a letter accompanying the report. `` We must acknowledge this new reality and act accordingly.'' The report, which dealt with the so-called Pacific rim nations, predicted their emerging economic bloc will be the most powerful by the end of the century. It noted the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commercial trade deficit with those countries accounts for two-thirds of the overall <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade deficit. It called upon the administration to develop a `` coherent policy'' for long-term <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cooperation with these nations in defense, economics and technological growth, to maintain them as military allies and achieve solid <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> technological and industrial strength over the long run. `` Our comparative industrial, manufacturing, and technological strength has been eroded seriously over the last decade. This erosion must be reversed so that we can enter cooperative ventures involving technology transfer from a position of strength,'' the panel wrote. The panel called for `` a thoughtful, tough-minded approach,'' and recommended in particular that for U.S.-Japanese relations there must be a `` mutually beneficial, two-way sharing of technology.'' The report noted <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s government and industry have worked together to establish that nation as a dominant global player in high-tech industries by the year 2000. `` A coherent <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy for defense industrial cooperation is necessary if problems such as those -LRB- that -RRB- arose with the FSX are to be avoided in the future,'' the panel's report stated. `` <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy must promote better coordination'' among such agencies as the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION>, the report said. The group said the nation lacks a `` policy framework'' to deal with the complex issue and, among other things, called for the formation of a high-level interagency group to propose such a strategy to the president within six months.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0325EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     11-08 0815</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farmers Almost Done Reaping What They Sowed</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A government report says the harvest of most 1989 major field crops is completed or soon will be winding down. In the case of winter wheat, the 1990 crop has nearly all been planted and is in `` mostly good to fair'' condition, although more soil moisture is needed in some areas, the Joint Agricultural Weather Facility reported Tuesday. `` Planting was 93 percent complete, four points ahead of normal'' as of the Oct. 30-Nov. 5 survey week, the report said `` Planting was complete or nearly complete in 13 of the 19 major producing states.'' However, winter wheat planting continued to lag behind normal in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. `` Rain was needed in the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>, where the crop was mostly good to fair,'' the report said. `` In <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, the crop was mostly fair. Russian wheat aphids were a continuing problem in portions of the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION>.'' The facility is operated by the department's of Agriculture and Commerce. Its reports cover weather and crop conditions only, not estimates of yields or total production. This year's corn harvest was 88 percent completed by early November, 10 percentage points ahead of normal, the report said. Harvest was almost done in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, and advanced sharply in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. But the report said corn harvesting lagged behind in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, while it was `` near or ahead of normal'' in the other major producing states. The soybean harvest was reported 87 percent complete, 11 percentage points ahead of normal pace for this time. Farmers had completed harvesting in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, and were almost done in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>. Soybean harvesting made rapid progress during the week in the <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> and eastern Corn Belt, with advances of 20 percentage points or more in <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>. The cotton harvest advanced 12 percentage points during the week of Oct. 30-Nov. 5, including major progress in <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, the report said Other observations included: _ Sorghum harvesting advanced 13 percentage points during the week and was 85 percent completed, about six points ahead of normal The <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> harvest was 86 percent completed, the <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> crop 80 percent, and <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> almost done. _ Rice harvesting was nearly finished in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, and `` producers were burning rice stubble as air quality regulations permitted. _ Peanut harvesting was finished in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, and continued in the <LOCATION> Carolinas </LOCATION> In <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, rain slowed the peanut harvest in the hill country, while the <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> harvest was about 20 percentage points ahead of normal. _ <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s harvest of fall vegetables increased seasonally The sweet potato harvest was at `` a near-normal pace'' in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, and vegetable harvesting increased seasonally in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>' <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. _ Livestock pastures were said to be in fair-to-good condition in the <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> and the East, and mostly fair-to-poor in the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> and the West
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says a fungus from <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> is showing up well as a natural killer of destructive grasshoppers that threaten crops and rangeland. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON>, director of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Grasshopper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Integrated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Project </ORGANIZATION>, said preliminary laboratory experiments indicated the fungus _ Entomophaga praxibuli _ can infect and kill a broad range of the pesky hoppers. <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inspection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said if the fungus proves out, it could help lessen the need for chemicals to control the pests. The project plan is to integrate the fungus with research demonstrations in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> next year, and also begin experiments with it in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. `` The fungus only affects grasshoppers,'' the agency said Tuesday. `` Laboratory tests using doses at least 100 times greater than any found in nature have repeatedly shown that the fungus causes no harm to other insects and does not affect humans or other mammals.'' Grasshoppers are infected by the fungus directly through their outer covering and usually die within 7 to 10 days. Laboratory tests have shown that once established the fungus can also spread to future generations of grasshoppers. The fungus produces spores that survive the winter in the soil, waiting to attack the next year's crop of insects, the agency said. Other biological control agents such as viruses and bacteria take longer to be effective because they must be eaten before infection can occur. Scientists isolated the fungus from grasshoppers during an outbreak in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> in 1985. The dry conditions in the <LOCATION> Wanwibinda </LOCATION> region of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION>, where this fungus was discovered, were said to be similar to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s northwestern rangelands where outbreaks annually infest millions of acres of crops and livestock rangelands. `` We believe that further research and controlled introduction of E. praxibuli in our project trials will increase our options by providing and effective long-term biological control agency,'' <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-ELN--Blacks 2ndLd-Writethru a0403 11-08 0543</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-ELN--Blacks, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0403,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>EDs: Updates with Cleveland and Detroit; Rice leading in Seattle.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Led by <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, black Democrats extended their hold on the nation's large city halls Tuesday, winning first-ever victories in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Haven </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Durham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, and reclaiming the mayor's seat in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>. On the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Norm </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> was leading in his attempt to break the racial barrier in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. `` These gains represent expansion for the group that was locked out,'' said <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, the two-time presidential candidate who is a possible mayoral candidate in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION><LOCATION> , </LOCATION> <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, next year. Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, D-Pa., the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> majority whip and the nation's highest black elected figure, praised <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON>' election and said <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> voters `` have rejected the politics of fear <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> withstood late campaign attacks on his character and integrity. Democrat <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON>, a veteran <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> state senator, easily defeated Republican Alderwoman <PERSON> Robie </PERSON> <PERSON> Pooley </PERSON> to become <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Haven </LOCATION>'s first black mayor. In <LOCATION> Durham </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Chester </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON> defeated conservative candidate <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Strawbridge </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, veteran Mayor <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, who is black, won a fifth term by defeating black challenger <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrow </PERSON>, the man he defeated four years ago. The off-year election put Democratic blacks in control of most of the nation's big-city mayors offices. <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Houston </PERSON> are now the nation's biggest cities with a white mayor. <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> voters returned <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitmire </PERSON> to office Tuesday, and <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> voters did the same for <PERSON> Xavier </PERSON> <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, Mayor <PERSON> Sophie </PERSON> <PERSON> Masloff </PERSON> -- who calls herself a `` Jewish grandmother,'' was elected in her own right. She succeeded into office upon the death in 1988 of <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Caliguiri </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, state Sen. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> defeated longtime city council president <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON> in a race that presented voters with a choice between two black candidates to succeed white Republican Mayor <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Voinovich </PERSON>. <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON> and <PERSON> White </PERSON> both are black Democrats, but their race was characterized by bitterness as <PERSON> White </PERSON> worked to retire his former mentor. The urban victories came as <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> sought election as governor of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> to become the nation's first-ever elected black governor. The candidacies of <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> borough president, were noteworthy for their similar methods. Both ran as mainstream, middle-of-the-road candidates who needed broad support from white voters as well as near-total support from black voters. Both <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON> and <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> ran as soft-spoken moderates, far from the fiery-preacher image of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. `` Both of these candidates, who had a fairly similar strategy in some ways, will be viewed as role models,'' said <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, a fellow at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, specializing in race and politics. `` For the future direction of black politics, there will be a lot of inspiration about what can be done.'' `` It symbolizes heightened security and maturity for white males in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said of Tuesday's elections. `` In the'60s we integrated the lunch counters and the libraries. Now we are integrating the psyche and the mind of white <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' In <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> held a lead in early returns over <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Jewett </PERSON>, a Republican who authored an initiative aimed at ending mandatory school busing, which emerged as a major issue in their campaign. Rice charged it would lead to resegregation of schools.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MissTeenageAmerica     11-08 0253</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Miss Teenage America,0257</SECOND>
<HEAD>California Teen-ager Chosen Miss Teenage America</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Khyrstyne Haje is cq</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissick </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Carlsbad </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, was chosen the 28th Miss Teenage <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> on Tuesday night in the seaside community of Marina del Rey. <PERSON> Kimberly </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>, 17, of <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, was named runner-up among 12 finalists in an event hosted by television actress <PERSON> Khyrstyne </PERSON> <PERSON> Haje </PERSON>, star of <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Head of the Class.'' The 12 were chosen from 10,000 entries nationwide. Miss <PERSON> Kissick </PERSON>, 17, receives a $ 15,000 college scholarship and complete wardrobe from K Mart. The contestants were judged on their scholastic achievements, general awareness, individual accomplishments, community service, poise and appearance. The winner was determined by a week of interviews prior to the pageant and on her poise in on-stage interviews during the pageant. `` The program is not a beauty pageant or a talent contest, rather it's an achievement program which recognizes outstanding young women between ages 13 and 18,'' said contest spokesman <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>. She will have her own monthly column in ` Teen Magazine, which is the chief sponsor for the contest, and make personal appearances to speak on issues important to teen-agers The other finalists were: <PERSON> Candace </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, 16, of <LOCATION> Ralls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Michele </PERSON> <PERSON> Renee </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, 17, <LOCATION> Roanoake </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Leigh </PERSON> <PERSON> Bondy </PERSON>, 16, <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Trina </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, 16, <LOCATION> Bellingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Samantha </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, 15, <LOCATION> Hopkins </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Baker </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Norton </LOCATION>, 17, <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Holly </PERSON> <PERSON> Rouse </PERSON>, 16, <LOCATION> Hornersville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>.; <PERSON> Dawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Wade </PERSON>, 16, <LOCATION> Goleta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Deirdre </PERSON> <PERSON> Dianne </PERSON> <PERSON> Walusis </PERSON>, 15, <LOCATION> Youngstown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wong </PERSON>, 16, <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0326EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GoodFences Bjt   11-08 0586</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Good Fences, Bjt,0610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Good Fences Make Good Neighbors; Bad Ones Prompt Lawsuits</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto MR1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MONTPELIER, Vt. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Vermont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, following a poetic premise by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Frost </PERSON>, says good neighbors need n't help keep up good fences. The five justices on Tuesday found unconstitutional a 1790 law making a livestock owner and neighbor equally responsible for maintaining the fence between their properties. The ruling came 75 years after <PERSON> Frost </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>'s and the nation's late poet laureate, published `` Mending Wall. In the poem, Frost questions the springtime ritual of helping his neighbor fix the stone wall between their properties, only to have the old farmer respond, `` Good fences make good neighbors.'' <PERSON> Frost </PERSON> wrote in part: `` ... Before I built a wall I'd ask to know `` What I was walling in or walling out `` And to whom I was like to give offense ... `` In Tuesday's case, offense was taken by <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> and <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Choquette </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Newport </LOCATION> when adjoining landowners, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Perrault </PERSON>, refused to help pay for a fence built to keep the Choquettes' cows off the Perraults' land. The Choquettes sued the Perraults for the amount the town fence viewer ruled the <ORGANIZATION> Perraults </ORGANIZATION> owed under state law: $ 316. Two lower courts ruled in the Choquettes' favor, but the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> said the Perraults do n't have to pay. The high court's ruling turned on the question of whether the public good outweighed the state Constitution's ban on giving special breaks to special groups _ in this case, landowners with livestock. The court found it made sense in the 18th, 19th and early 20th centuries to say the public good outweighed the no-special-interests clause. `` The land was predominantly open and farmed, and rural landowners were also livestock owners,'' Justice <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> wrote. Without the fence law, livestock owners would be solely responsible for keeping their animals from damaging their neighbors' property, and solely responsible for the fence, the court said But, <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> wrote, `` As a result of changing land-use patterns, the law more and more often applies to landowners without livestock. In such situations, the fence law is burdensome, arbitrary and confiscatory, and therefore can not pass constitutional muster.'' Many have misread <PERSON> Frost </PERSON>'s view of shared fence-mending responsibility as being positive, said <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, an English professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vermont </ORGANIZATION>. She pointed to a line in which <PERSON> Frost </PERSON> says, `` In each hand, like an old-stone savage armed `` He moves in darkness it seems to me ... `` `` The old farmer is really being put down,'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said, `` though it's done so gracefully it almost does n't seem that way at first glance.'' She added, `` <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Frost </PERSON> in my opinion would be very pleased to see the court's decision to strike down the fence law.'' Lawyer <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bent </PERSON>, whose argument prevailed at the high court, said a lower court judge had cited the `` Good fences make good neighbors'' line in his decision that the high court overturned. The <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> judge, <PERSON> Alden </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON>, `` sort of missed the point that <PERSON> Frost </PERSON> was making, that his neighbor was holding onto hidebound tradition,'' Bent said. He added that the legal argument paralleled the poetic: that the <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> fence law was a narrow-minded tradition best discarded. The Choquettes' lawyer, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, said he was disappointed to have lost the case, but could understand the court's logic. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> pointed to <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>'s comments about shifting land-use patterns, and to a line from another poet named <PERSON> Robert </PERSON>: `` The times, they are a changin'.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0328EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-Eastern     11-08 0413</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Eastern,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Final Passage Given Bill Calling for Investigation of Eastern Strike</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is ready to launch an investigation of the <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> strike but President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who refused to intervene when the walkout began eight months ago, may veto the bill calling for the review. Legislation creating a <ORGANIZATION> House-Senate </ORGANIZATION> commission won final approval Monday in the House. But the administration said its position had not changed since last month, when it issued a statement saying the measure was a candidate for a veto. The bill, approved on a voice vote, is a watered-down version of organized labor's initial attempt to get <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to demand that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> use his power to halt the strike by naming an emergency mediation board. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said then that the dispute should be settled by <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s unions and management. Instead of demanding that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> intervene, the bill now headed to the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> would create a four-member panel to recommend ways to end the Eastern strike. It also would make suggestions for maintaining competitiveness in the airline industry and for protecting employees of air carriers that seek bankruptcy protection. Labor urged <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to reconsider his veto threat. `` We urge the president to quickly sign this bill into law,'' <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> said in a statement. `` For the president to do otherwise would strip the administration of any pretense of fairness in this dispute.'' Under the bill, a Democrat and a Republican from the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and one each from the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> would be appointed by their respective leaders in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to the commission. The panel's report would be due 45 days after enactment. Its recommendations, should they include presidential intervention, would not be binding on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> but could lead to additional legislation. Eastern was struck by the Machinists' union March 4 and most union pilots and flight attendants have honored the walkout. The airline, owned by <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection five days after the strike began and although still cash-poor has been rebuilding as a non-union carrier. The unions have contended that <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. Chairman <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> has siphoned Eastern cash and assets for the parent corporation and wants to use bankruptcy to bust the unions, as he did when <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> bought <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, filed for Chapter 11 and then emerged as a non-union carrier <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> has said concessions by <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s union workers were necessary for it to remain competitive.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0330EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-IntelligenceBill     11-08 0619</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Intelligence Bill,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Votes to Place Independent Watchdog in CIA</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a spinoff from the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's Iran-Contra scandal, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is moving to set up for the first time an independent watchdog inside the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> Senators voted 64-34 late Tuesday to keep the independent inspector general provision in a bill authorizing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence activities for the next two years. The provision, offered by Sen. <PERSON> Arlen </PERSON> <PERSON> Specter </PERSON>, R-Pa., would create an independent <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> inspector general, nominated by the president and confirmed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> The current inspector general is appointed by the director and reports only to him. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is strongly opposed to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> plan. The intelligence bill later was passed on a voice vote and sent to a conference to work out differences between it and a version passed by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> last month. The House bill would retain the current system for appointing the inspector general, but would require full access to the investigator's reports and audits by the intelligence committees on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approach also is opposed by the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and would tempt a veto, the administration has said. In its Iran-Contra investigation two years ago, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> concluded the scandal escaped the notice of the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> inspector general because the office did not have `` the manpower, resources or tenacity'' to uncover what had gone on. Among its recommendations was an independent investigator at the agency like the arrangement approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday. The implication was that the agency's overseer had turned a blind eye to the activities of his boss, then-CIA director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>, who was deeply involved in the scandal that sent arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and clandestine funds to the Contra rebels in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. `` Iran-Contra was a very significant event in our history and there are some lessons to learn from it,'' said Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Maine </LOCATION>, vice chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and a member of the special panel that investigated the scandal. `` We had the potential to have a government within a government, selling assets and using the money to run operations with no trail, no trace and no one would know,'' <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> said. `` We nearly saw the unraveling of a presidency.'' Others, including Sen. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Moynihan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, sought to link the provision to a new <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration policy that will free <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> operatives to work with the plotters of coups in countries like <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, so long as the coup is not aimed at assassinating a foreign leader. They argued stronger agency oversight would help keep such a policy from running out of control. Several senators sought to strip out the new reins on the agency, saying the restrictions would appear to be a slap at <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> and could hamper the agency's ability to win cooperation from intelligence sources and other countries. `` They would n't be dealing just with one organization, they would be dealing with two parallel organizations that exist side by side, with two chains of command,'' argued Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON>, R-Mo. Under the provision, the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> director would be able to shut down an inspector general's investigation if he felt it were dangerous to national security, but would have to inform the congressional intelligence committees of his action within seven days. The overall intelligence bill provides a blueprint for the government's intelligence spending over the next two years. Most of what the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> spends on such activities is secret, tucked away in the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget. But reports put the spending level at upwards of $ 25 billion a year, most of it for personnel and spy hardware like satellites, and lesser amounts for covert operations overseas.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0311EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites SUB a0467 11-08 0162</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites, SUB, a0467,0164</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 1st graf of 2nd item to fix typo in `burdened'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AMHERST, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Homeowners who feel burdened by the chore of raking up autumn leaves might feel better if they consider the plight of highway departments. Take <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucey </PERSON>, highway superintendent in the <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Amherst </LOCATION>. He figures his city's trees will shed about 2,200 truckloads of leaves this fall. It'll take 80 workers, using 44 pieces of equipment, to sweep up the 800 miles of curbs. In <LOCATION> Cheektowaga </LOCATION>, another <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION> suburb, Highway Superintendent <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Kowal </PERSON> will run seven leaf vacuums for 16 hours a day, seven days a week to keep the streets clean. And even that is n't holding off an estimated 200 calls a day _ many from irate residents demanding better leaf service `` It's crazy,'' <PERSON> Kowal </PERSON> said. `` These four weeks are my nightmare. I dread it every year. We can deal with snow. We can deal with everything but leaves.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0428EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Johnson     11-08 0152</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Johnson,0156</SECOND>
<HEAD>Debt Collectors Target `Vice' Star Don Johnson</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ASPEN, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A construction company has joined 10 other contractors suing `` Miami Vice'' star <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> for allegedly failing to pay bills for work on the mountain hideaway where he married actress <PERSON> Melanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON>. The lawsuit filed Friday by <ORGANIZATION> Duddy-Viele </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Construction </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vail </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> owed $ 95,813 from the $ 604,085 bill. It asked for an order that the bill be paid before other liens on the property. Ten contractors who helped remodel the home filed liens over unpaid bills during the spring and summer, according to the lawsuit filed in <LOCATION> Pitkin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Court </LOCATION>. Notification of the lien was sent to <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and at the <LOCATION> Vail </LOCATION> address where he and <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> were married on June 26 for a second time. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s publicist, <PERSON> Elliot </PERSON> <PERSON> Mintz </PERSON>, said he was not aware of the lawsuit and could not comment on it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891108-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-08-89 0311EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-LincolnS&amp;L Bjt   11-08 0861</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lincoln S&amp;L, Bjt,840</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Regulator Says Senators Sought Favors for Lincoln S&amp;L</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
