<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-GreenhouseConference     03-04 0382</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Greenhouse Conference,0391</SECOND>
<HEAD>Conference Urges Battle Against ``Greenhouse'' Effect</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VERENA DOBNIK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Every car should yield 42 miles per gallon and carbon dioxide emissions should be cut 20 percent to fight the `` greenhouse effect'' that may threaten Earth's climate and human health, a conference recommended Friday. Four hundred scientists and public officials from 13 countries attended the four-day Global Climate Change meeting that focused on the warming of the atmosphere and damage to <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>'s protective ozone layer. `` The activities of 5 billion people on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> are clearly producing changes in the world's climate,'' said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Harwell </PERSON>, director of <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s Global Environment Program. `` In our lifetimes, and certainly in our children's, climate changes and other environmental impacts will profoundly affect the way humans live.'' The participants called for changes in human activities whose by-products are gases that may be causing a rise in atmospheric temperatures, resulting in hotter summers, droughts, more violent storms, rising sea levels and an increase in diseases. The participants urged <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to pass a more stringent version of the Clean Air Act, and to stop production by the year 2000 of all chlorofluorocarbons, which cause the `` greenhouse'' effect. They also recommended that the fuel economy of all new cars be increased by 1 -LCB- mpg per year to at least 42 mpg by the year 2000. Other energy sources, including nuclear plants, should be used more efficiently and with added safety standards, the participants said. The conference also urged that land use and building controls be enacted to provide for nature conservation, coupled with increased mass transit that would reduce automobile congestion. The conference was convened by Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>, Gov. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Keane </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, Gov. <PERSON> Madeleine </PERSON> <PERSON> Kunin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governors </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Among those who addressed the meeting were physicist <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Sagan </PERSON>; <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> cable network; Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, Jr., D-Tenn.; and Sen. <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON>, D-Colo The 150 scientists attending the meeting included <PERSON> Vassily </PERSON> <PERSON> Sokolov </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> U.S.A. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Canada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Ma </PERSON> <PERSON> Shijun </PERSON>, chairman of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on the Environment. `` We must learn to understand and live rather than fight natural forces, including those unleashed by our own activities,'' said the participants in their final recommendation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Stripper'sMom 1stLd-Writethru a0705 03-04 0374</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Stripper's Mom, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0705,0377</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge: Mother Linked To Daughter's Suicide Can Get Profits From Story</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: RECASTS lead and 2nd graf; SUBS 7th graf, `Lawyers said...',
to DELETE incorrect reference to first use of ``psychological autopsy.''</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman convicted of instigating her daughter's suicide by pushing her to work as a nude dancer will be allowed to profit from her story, a judge has ruled. `` I'm very happy,'' <PERSON> Theresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said Thursday. `` I'm glad to get it over with.'' The agreement between the state and Ms. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, approved Thursday by <ORGANIZATION> Broward </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Franza </PERSON>, will require her to share whatever money she might get from her story with the state and with her 18-year-old son. Ms. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s lawyer, <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Draves </PERSON>, estimated her client could receive between $ 50,000 to $ 200,000 for film and book rights to her story. Ms. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 42, was convicted in October 1987 of child abuse, forgery and procuring a sexual performance by a child. She was sentenced to a year in jail but is free on bail during an appeal. Her 17-year-old daughter, <PERSON> Tina </PERSON> <PERSON> Mancini </PERSON>, shot and killed herself in the family's <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> home in March 1986. During a two-week trial, state prosecutors claimed Ms. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> traumatized her daughter by encouraging her to work as a nude dancer, even forging the girl's birth certificate to make it appear she was older. Lawyers said the case was the first in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in which a person was charged with mental child abuse in connection with a suicide. Originally, the state had sought to block Ms. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> from getting any money, citing a never-before-used state law barring felons from profiting from depictions of their crimes. Under terms of Thursday's settlement, the state would receive about $ 35,000 for trial and jail costs from any earnings Ms. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> receives from her story. Part of the remaining earnings would be shared by Ms. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s 18-year-old son. Ms. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s former attorney, <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitman </PERSON>, has his own claim pending against Ms. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, contending he is owed $ 150,000 in attorney's fees from the trial, and he is seeking to overturn the agreement with the state. A hearing on that claim is scheduled for next week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Widow'sBill     03-04 0297</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Widow's Bill,0304</SECOND>
<HEAD>Widow Says Insurance Wouldn't Cover Treatment After Husband's Slaying</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ELLINGTON, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman whose husband was slain at the convenience store where he worked said the company's insurer refused to pay the $ 138 hospital bill she incurred for treatment of shock after the killing. <PERSON> Georgianna </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s insurance claim was returned unpaid last week by the <ORGANIZATION> Lewer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, the company most 7-Eleven stores use to provide health and life insurance for their employees. Mrs. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s husband, <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, was shot to death Jan. 14 at a 7-Eleven store in nearby <LOCATION> Vernon </LOCATION> where he was night manager. Mrs. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> of </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellington </PERSON>, north of <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION>, was treated for shock in the emergency room at <LOCATION> Rockville </LOCATION> <LOCATION> General </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> after his killing. The <ORGANIZATION> Lewer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said it was denying payment of the charges because the `` policy does not cover treatment of nervous and mental conditions.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, who was covered under her husband's policy, said she was first dumbfounded then angry. `` Under the circumstances I expected without any question at all that this hospital bill would have been paid,'' she said Wednesday. `` It's not the money. It's the principle of how a company could do this to me. You give your life for your job and this is how you're treated in return. A 23-year-old man was been charged as an accessory in <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s killing Officials have not determined a motive in the slaying. <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Oftedahl </PERSON>, human resources manager for <ORGANIZATION> Southland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> office in <LOCATION> Middletown </LOCATION>, said he has contacted the <ORGANIZATION> Lewer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> about the unpaid hospital bill and is waiting for a response. He also said <ORGANIZATION> Southland </ORGANIZATION> only recommends the <ORGANIZATION> Lewer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> to its 7-Eleven franchise owners. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dlugolecki </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Lewer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, declined to comment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0159EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-McFarlane Bjt   03-04 0621</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-McFarlane, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Major Figure in Iran-Contra Case Gets Probation, Fine</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former national security adviser <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> became the first participant in the Iran-Contra affair to be sentenced, receiving a $ 20,000 fine and suspended prison term. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON>, placed on two-years' probation Friday for misleading <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> about covert <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support for the Nicaraguan rebels, will be a key prosecution witness at the ongoing trial of his former aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>. Leaving the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Courthouse with his wife, <PERSON> Jonda </PERSON>, <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> said the ordeal left him with `` strong faith and a terrific wife and a free country.'' `` I am looking to the future,'' he said. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> admitted he misled <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> by denying that <PERSON> North </PERSON> was helping the Contras raise money and transfer weapons when lawmakers had banned <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid. In a sentencing proceeding that lasted barely five minutes, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Aubrey </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> said <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> must complete 200 hours of community service during his probabtion. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said `` the nature of the offense and the totality of the circumstances'' required him to impose a $ 20,000 fine. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> could have received a four-year prison term and a $ 400,000 fine for pleading guilty to four misdemeanor charges of withholding information from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The retired <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> lieutenant colonel stood at ease with his hands clasped below his waist as he listened to the comments of his attorney, <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Garment </PERSON> and the judge. `` The public servants in this country are not to be found to be more decent and more honorable,'' Garment said. `` Every action on his part ... was taken out of a high sense of duty, a strong sense of serving his country's interests.'' <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> accompanied North to <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> in May 1986 on an unsuccessful arms-for-hostages mission. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON>, by this time retired from government, carried a key-shaped cake and a Bible signed by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as a show of good faith. In his emotionless voice, <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> said: `` Clearly, this episode in our history has rendered enormous turmoil on our country's processes `` To the extent that I contributed to that I regret it. I tried to serve my country.'' Independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>, who negotiated the plea agreement with <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> before <PERSON> North </PERSON> and three co-defendants were indicted last year, told reporters outside the courthouse his office had made no recommendation about the sentence. He refused to comment further. The sentencing took place on a day that <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s trial had recessed for legal arguments. Former <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Lt. Col. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadd </PERSON>, who provided aircraft for the Nicaraguan rebels during the `` secret war'' that prosecutors say <PERSON> North </PERSON> waged after <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> banned military aid, is scheduled to continue testifying when the trial resumes Monday. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> had asked to be sentenced before he took the witness stand against <PERSON> North </PERSON>. He pleaded guilty March 11, 1988, to charges that he misled <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1985 by stating in three letters that <PERSON> North </PERSON> was not helping raise money for the Contras or providing military assistance. The letters were written to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> intelligence committee and the House Foreign Affairs subcommittee on the western hemisphere in response to queries about news reports that <PERSON> North </PERSON> was providing aid in defiance of the ban imposed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Among the 12 felony charges against <PERSON> North </PERSON> are allegations that he made false statement to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> by drafting the false letters that <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> signed. The defense contends that <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> should be held responsible for those letters, not <PERSON> North </PERSON>, who was below his boss on the chain of command. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> also admitted misleading the full <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in testimony after the Iran-Contra affair became public in later 1986 by denying knowledge of efforts to raise money from foreign governments to help arm the rebels.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AmnesiaVictim     03-04 0386</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Amnesia Victim,0399</SECOND>
<HEAD>Amnesia Victim Tries to Piece Together His Past</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GAINESVILLE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About the only clue the stocky, balding middle-aged man has about his past is the name `` <PERSON> Snuffy </PERSON>'' engraved on the back of his belt. He does n't know who he is, how he got to <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION> or anything before Feb. 8, when he awoke in a wooded area near <LOCATION> Shands </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> with no wallet and no form of identification. He is 5-foot-11, weighs 250 pounds and has a tattoo on his arm. He was wearing blue jeans, boots, flannel shirt and tinted prescription glasses when found. The hospital said brain scans and other evaluations showed no signs of a blow to the head or any other physical causes for amnesia, such as epilepsy or alcohol-related brain malfunction. Dr. <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> <PERSON> McElroy </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Shands </ORGANIZATION> psychiatrist, said the man is apparently suffering from a psychological form of amnesia, probably triggered by a great mental shock or stress. The man fears family members may be worrying about him somewhere. `` It took two or three days to sort of pull myself through the fog,'' the man said. `` I spend every waking moment trying to figure out who ... I am.'' The man, who is fairly articulate, speaks with a Southwestern accent and likes to read, sat with mental health counselor W.J. <PERSON> Tootie </PERSON> <PERSON> Richey </PERSON> and posed for pictures Thursday in hopes of a breakthrough _ someone who remembers what he ca n't. He said the name `` Snuffy'' does n't ring a bell for him. `` I did n't like it at first,'' he said, but `` it seems better than <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Doe </PERSON>.'' Ms. <PERSON> Richey </PERSON> said her client is able to talk and interact with people well. He has been reading voraciously, especially newspapers. The <LOCATION> Alachua </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's office has taken the man's fingerprints and physical description; there are apparently no warrants for his arrest There is a good chance that his memory will return, either in bits and pieces or a sudden rush, authorities said. Most similar amnesia victims regain most or all their memory within a few days or weeks. <PERSON> McElroy </PERSON> said forgetting an entire life is especially rare. The chances are `` you're going to find that there's something that this guy's getting away from,'' <PERSON> McElroy </PERSON> said. `` Whatever I'm responsible for, I want to live up to,'' said the mystery man.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Tower Bjt   03-04 0641</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tower, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tower Backers Want Him to Testify Before Full Senate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID ESPO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> allies, struggling to gain the offensive in a tense confirmation battle, are suggesting that the defense secretary-designate come to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor and respond `` charge by charge'' to the allegations against him. `` If we owe Senator Tower anything, we owe him the right to say, ` I've had my day in court,''' <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> GOP Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said Friday as <ORGANIZATION> Tower </ORGANIZATION>'s confirmation chances dimmed further with two additional Democrats joining the opposition. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> stopped short of turning his suggestion into a formal proposal, and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, said he would be `` happy to consider any request.'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> also said he was troubled by the confirmation proceedings, in which material from a confidential <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> report that is damaging to Tower has been leaked in the news media but may not be discussed openly on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor. He became the second senior Democrat in as many days to suggest a closed <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> session to permit a full airing of the allegations contained in the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> report. Tower has been battling questions of his drinking habits, his behavior toward women and his lucrative work as a defense industry consultant after serving as a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms control negotiator. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> report contains numerous allegations, but Republicans say few if any of them are corroborated, and insist nothing in it disqualifies him from the <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> post. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is in recess until Monday, when debate is expected to resume on the nomination, although Tower and several senators are certain to keep the controversy alive over the weekend with appearances scheduled on television interview programs. The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> vote count shows 47 Democrats and GOP Sen. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Pressler </PERSON> either committed or leaning against the nomination and 40 Republicans committed or leaning in favor, with the rest undecided. The Democrats hold a 55-45 majority in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s surprise suggestion _ only six people have ever been called to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 200 years to answer charges against them _ came near the end of a day of debate in which two additional Democrats announced their opposition and a string of Republicans complained that Tower was being treated unfairly. `` We've got to even up the score somehow,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> GOP leader. Arguing that limitations on public references to the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> report make it impossible `` to get at the truth,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> suggested bringing Tower to the floor `` to answer his critics face-to-face, charge-by-charge, rumor-by-rumor and fact-by-fact.'' Several Republicans defended Tower earlier in a long day of debate. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has abandoned fairness and the object of that abandonment is <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON>,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallop </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wyo </LOCATION>. Sen. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> said the evidence in the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> report was so flimsy that no prosecutor would use it for an indictment, and said of Tower, `` He is my friend. I thought he was your friend and I want some justice for my friend.'' Sen. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Symms </PERSON>, R-Idaho. called on a few Democrats to swing behind the nomination before partisanship overwhelmed the debate completely, but the only two Democrats to announce _ conservative <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> and liberal <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Mikulski </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> _ said they would oppose confirmation. <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON> had been counted by the White House as a potential convert to Tower's cause, but in a written statement, he noted the allegations against Tower and said, `` We can not take a chance. An angry Sen. <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.C. </LOCATION>, called for the release of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> report, noting the Republican charge that the Democrats have based their opposition on allegations, not facts. `` It's our character that's being assassinated here and I'm sick and tired of it,'' said <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON>. Release of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> report is a decision that only the White House can make.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Venezuela     03-04 0482</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Venezuela,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Gives Venezuela Short-Term Loan</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Venezuela</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Asocciated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is attempting to ease <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>'s financial crisis by providing the new government of President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> with a $ 450 million `` bridge loan,'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have disclosed. The South American nation saw its worst violence in 31 years, in a series of riots this week spawned by a series of price increases imposed as part of an economic reform program. An estimated 300 people died and 1,500 were injured in the disturbances, touched off by the new austerity program designed by <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> to cope with a $ 33 billion foreign debt. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said Friday that President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spoke Friday with <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> in a telephone call, in which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> lauded <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>'s `` courageous and determined efforts'' to resolve its dire economic and financial problems. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had called <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> to express `` his concern for the recent difficulties'' in <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>. Two other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, who spoke on condition of anonymity, confirmed later in the day that the a bridge loan was approved as a means of serving the country's short-term financial needs. `` President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> talked to him,'' one of the officials said. `` It's coming through,'' the official said of the loan. Both officials are familiar with the Venezuelan debt problem and were involved in discussions about the loan. The bridge loan will provide <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> with temporary relief because its depleted treasury has had difficulting meeting interest payments to commercial banks and other international lenders. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, asked about the reported loan, confirmed the two presidents discussed the issue in their phone call. But the spokesman said the matter was n't finalized and the `` many details'' had to be worked out. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has frequently provided bridge loans to other Latin American nations, such as <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, which had depleted treasuries. The austerity program was mandated by the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monetary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> as a requirement for granting $ 4.3 billion in loans over the next three years. The <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> has taken steps to provide <LOCATION> Caracas </LOCATION> with an immediate $ 450 million payment. Increases of 30 percent to 50 percent in public transport tariffs and price gouging by bus drivers set off the rioting, amounting to the worst violence in <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> in 31 years. The nation of 18 million has been regarded as an island of tranquility amid a region of increasing violence, political stability and economic repression. The president's action was seen as another attempt to give <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>'s 29-day old administration some breathing room to deal with its financial woes. Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> attended <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>'s Feb. 2 inauguration. The Venezuelan official was elected in a landslide Dec. 4. `` He reiterated <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support for their democracies and for President <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>'s courageous and determined efforts to address his country's economic and financial situation,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, when describing the call between the two presidents.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     03-04 0349</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0361</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PENSACOLA BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Merchants and town officials in this barrier island resort community have hatched an idea they think will put them in the pink. With nary a squawk Thursday, the <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rosa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leasing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> endorsed a plan to turn <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>'s water tower into a 10-story pink flamingo <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Garmon </PERSON>, sales manager for <ORGANIZATION> Lamar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advertising </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a billboard company in nearby <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION>, pitched the idea, dubbed `` Project Pink,'' to the panel. He said the big bird could be to <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION> what the Eiffel Tower is to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and the Statue of Liberty is to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. He even envisioned an entry in the Guinness Book of World Records. Several merchants urged approval. <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> <PERSON> Orenstein </PERSON>, general manager of <ORGANIZATION> Sun </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ray </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cottage </ORGANIZATION>, said shops could sell pink flamingo T-shirts, bars could serve similarly themed drinks and the community could have a pink flamingo parade. Cost of construction the bird could be borne by business sponsors, the merchants suggested. The proposal goes to the authority's full board next week.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LAKE CHARLES, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The pigeons ignored plastic owls, traps and helium balloons; they were unruffled by high-frequency sound waves. So authorities are now mulling using a sticky paste to dissuade the birds from roosting at hangers at an airpark. Pigeon droppings have destroyed insulation in the new $ 40 million hangars at <ORGANIZATION> Chennault </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airpark </ORGANIZATION> and corroded paint on the KC-135 <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> tankers refurbished at the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> plant, officials say. <PERSON> Lake </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> is considered a bird sanctuary, and a city ordinance forbids hunting, trapping and shooting birds within city limits. At a public hearing to address the problem Thursday, <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Avery </PERSON> said his company makes an adhesive that's strong enough to alarm the pigeons _ and make them stay away from places they've encountered it _ but too weak to make the birds permanent fixtures. The repellant, a clear, sticky gel, is guaranteed for two years, is non-toxic and does not sting, burn or harm birds, said <PERSON> Avery </PERSON>, of Hot Foot International in <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Eastern-Summary 1stLd-Writethru a0728 03-04 0525</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Eastern-Summary, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0728,0557</SECOND>
<HEAD>Developments in Eastern Negotiations</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES throughout with strike called; no pickup.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Eastern Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
<NOTE>BUSH-MEDIATION RECOMMENDATION</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> rejected a mediation board recommendation to use his authority under provisions of the Railway Labor Act and delay the strike for 60 more days. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also warned he would not tolerate sympathy strikes threatened by other unions to support the Machinists. Eastern wanted <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to stay out of the dispute, saying either a strike, if it involved pilots, or postponement of the strike, would lead to bankruptcy. The <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> and 33 senators had asked <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to intervene to prevent `` a major disruption of interstate commerce.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>STRIKE PREPARATIONS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Eastern said it would slash up to 75 percent of its weekend flights, including most services from its <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> hub and about 60 other cities. The airline said earlier that it was prepared to operate during any strike and had contracted with 1,100 non-union mechanics to service planes. Eastern's pilots rejected an appeal Thursday by airline owner <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> for them to sign a new contract and cross Machinists picket lines. Flight attendants said they would honor picket lines. Airports nationwide strengthened security and other airlines have reported surges in sales this week.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MACHINISTS SENT HOME</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Eastern obtained a federal court order and sent its machinists home, saying the action was intended to prevent sabotage. Machinists were given a paid holiday and told to return to work for shifts starting at 12:01 a.m. EST Saturday, one minute after the strike deadline. Eastern said management personnel would handle ground duties for the rest of the day.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEGOTIATIONS END</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Eastern's offer Thursday was rejected Friday by the <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> union, and federal officials said they expected a strike at the midnight deadline as talks continued between the airline and the union. Eastern said the contract offered would reduce mechanics' pay but still keep their salaries 13 percent higher than employees who took a 20 percent pay cut when <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> took over in 1986. It said baggage handlers' cuts would be no greater than those of other employees. At 12:01 a.m., the Machinists went on strike.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>LABOR SUPPORT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> and other union leaders said they doubted there would be any settlement because <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> wants to dismantle <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>, which they said is worth about $ 500 million. Other unions pledged support in a plan to block work at other airlines, railways and sea transport companies if a strike is called. The <ORGANIZATION> Airline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> announced that in the event of an <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> strike, it would instruct its 40,000 members beginning Tuesday to strictly follow procedures that would cause `` substantial delays.'' <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> AFL </ORGANIZATION>'s 14 million members should honor the Eastern pickets wherever they are legally set up. A federal court in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> enjoined <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> employees from staging a sympathy strike. Other airlines and the union won a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> order in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> that banned picketing of companies other than Eastern.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Ozone Bjt   03-04 0604</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Ozone, Bjt,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Agrees to Quicker Reduction in CFCs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is joining its <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> allies in pushing for elimination of all ozone-depleting chemicals by the end of the century, a sharp acceleration of the schedule for ending their use. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Friday he has asked the head of the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> to join the call to ban chlorofluorocarbons, or CFCs, by the year 2000 at an international conference that begins this weekend in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. `` Recent studies indicate the 50 percent reduction -LRB- of CFCs as provided by a 1987 treaty -RRB- may not be enough,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> accounts for about one-third of the production of ozone-damaging chemicals, primarily CFCs, which are widely used as coolants in refrigerators and air conditioners and as a cleaning agent for electronic and computer equipment. Scientists have raised concerns about the chemical because it floats into the stratosphere before it breaks down, interacting with the gaseous veil of ozone that shields against the sun's cancer-causing ultraviolet rays <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON> flew to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> on Friday to take part in the conference to discuss ways to slow down ozone destruction. Representatives from more than 100 nations also will take part in the meetings being hosted by British Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>. In remarks to a group of high school science contest winners at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>, the president said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will support the call `` for the elimination of CFCs by the year 2000 provided safe substitutes are available.'' <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON>, according to administration sources, had strongly recommended at a White House meeting Thursday that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> join its European allies and call for the complete elimination of CFCs, as opposed to cutting production by 50 percent as required by current treaty. Many scientists have said that a 50 percent cutback would not be enough to protect against serious ozone depletion. On Thursday, the 12 nations of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> announced that they have agreed to a ban on the chemical in their countries by the end of the century. Sen. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, D-Tenn., another members of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> delegation to the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> conference, said Friday that even quicker action is needed because `` every year of delay implies an additional five to 10 years that these chemicals will remain in the atmosphere. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> has called for elimination of all CFCs by 1994. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-R.I. </LOCATION>, ranking minority member of the <ORGANIZATION> Environment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Works </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, called the president's move `` very encouraging'' but also urged that CFCs be eliminated well before the year 2000. The 1987 treaty has been ratified by nearly 40 nations, including the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, most of <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. But it includes a provision that allows additional measures, including a complete ban, if further ozone damage is found. The parties to the treaty are scheduled to consider an accelerated phase-out schedule at a meeting in <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>, in early May. The <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> meeting, which begins Sunday, is described as a dress rehearsal for the <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> session. According to the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> produces roughly one-third of the world's CFCs, with E.I. <ORGANIZATION> DuPont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nemours </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> the world's largest producer. There were 750 million pounds of CFCs produced in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> last year and about the same amount in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, according to <ORGANIZATION> Dupont </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Dupont </ORGANIZATION>, which accounts for about half of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production, has announced plans to stop making the chemical, perhaps as early as the mid-1990s and will begin to offer substitutes next year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0250EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-FAA-Boeing     03-04 0538</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-FAA-Boeing,0551</SECOND>
<HEAD>Feds Order Airlines To Check Boeing 747 Cargo Doors Within 30 Days</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> issued an emergency order on Friday, requiring all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airlines to reinforce latch mechanisms on <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 cargo doors within 30 days, so the doors are less vulnerable to damage from improper closing. The emergency Airworthiness Directive, which speeds up the timetable of an earlier directive, also specifies special inspections and tests of the doors that must be done until modifications are completed. The action Friday follows the Feb. 24 <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> accident near <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> in which a 10-by-20-foot hole was torn in a 747 fuselage. Nine people were swept to their deaths. The cause of the accident has yet to be determined, but the possible failure of the forward cargo door latch is under investigation. The door separated from the aircraft with parts of the fuselage that surrounded it. The 747 order affects about 150 airplanes. However, <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Neale </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, said some airlines have already made the required modifications, which include steel reinforcements to cargo door latches. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> issued a directive July 1 ordering the doors inspected and modified by the end of 1989 or July 1, 1990, depending on the type of locking mechanism installed. That order was issued after a cargo door on a <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> 747 opened 1 -LCB- inches at the start of a flight from <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> officials said at the time the situation did not warrant an emergency directive. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> also said it soon would issue another Airworthiness Directive requiring improvements in the warning system that alerts flight crews when any cargo door is not properly closed and locked. The directive was expected as soon as the design improvements can be delivered and tested. There were similarities in the events on the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> planes. The cargo doors in both instances had to be closed by hand rather than electrically, after they had been malfunctioning. There were no warning lights to indicate whether the doors were open, said both flight crews. Additionally, the agency has formed a team to review all current <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> service bulletins on the 747 cargo door to determine whether instructions are complete and understandable, the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> said Friday in a statement issued in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. The team is focusing on the possibility of human error that might be associated with specific procedures. It is expected to complete its work within a week. <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Gamble </PERSON> said changes made in the latest directive, from the July 1, 1988, order, included visual inspection of the cargo door latch before each flight, new torque limits on the door if it is closed manually, and shorter timetables for inspection for damage and of electrical systems. He said <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> supported the action by the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>, and in fact had suggested in service bulletins of March and April 1987, the cargo door improvements that were included in the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>'s directive of July 1988. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> also ordered immediate inspections of Dash 8-100 planes made by de Havilland of <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> subsidiary, because faulty connections were found in fire-extinguishing systems on two of the Canadian-made Dash 8-100 airliners.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0250EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     03-04 0907</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0944</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Stacy </PERSON> <PERSON> Keach </PERSON> did n't mind the 125-foot parachute plunge into downtown's Glitter Gulch, the motorcycle chase across the desert or squaring off against ex-football terror <PERSON> Lyle </PERSON> <PERSON> Alzado </PERSON>. But do n't ask him to repeat that 50-yard swim in <LOCATION> 50-degree </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mead </LOCATION> _ at least not with his shoes on. <PERSON> Keach </PERSON> spent the past week in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> filming a two-hour television special `` Murder Takes All _ <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammer </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>.'' The movie has tested the mettle of <PERSON> Keach </PERSON>, who has a penchant for doing many of his own stunts. One scene called for Hammer to jump from a yacht just before it explodes and swim 50 yards. <PERSON> Keach </PERSON>, 47, did the stunt wearing a wetsuit under his clothing to help ward off the chill of the 50-degree water. In the first take he also wore his shoes, and learned it was a serious mistake. `` I'm telling you, you almost lost me,'' <PERSON> Keach </PERSON> said after struggling against the weight of the clothes and trying to kick with his shoes on. Subsequent takes of the scene were shot with <PERSON> Keach </PERSON> swimming shoeless.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>GOLDEN, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Paulsen </PERSON> has accused his estranged wife of forgery and harassment in response to a counterclaim she filed in their divorce proceedings last year. <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Chaney </PERSON> <PERSON> Paulsen </PERSON> had accused <PERSON> Paulsen </PERSON> of seeking a divorce to get control of the profitable <ORGANIZATION> Pat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paulsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which she managed. <PERSON> Chaney </PERSON> <PERSON> Paulsen </PERSON>, 35, was not commenting on the case, but her attorney, <PERSON> Nathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Davidovich </PERSON>, said she is working on a book, `` Being Married to a Comedian Is No Laughing Matter.'' <PERSON> Paulsen </PERSON>, 61, lodged the original complaint in <LOCATION> Jefferson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Court </LOCATION> in September after filing for divorce in <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, just two months after the couple had married. His new motion this week asks that the counterclaim be dismissed, saying it was filed `` solely to harass, cause an unnecessary delay in these proceedings and needlessly increase the cost of this litigation.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MACON, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Surviving members of the <ORGANIZATION> Allman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION>, whose bluesy mix of guitars and keyboards helped define what came to be known as `` Southern rock'' in the 1970s, are talking about a reunion album and concert. <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> <PERSON> Allman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Betts </PERSON>, <PERSON> Butch </PERSON> <PERSON> Trucks </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jai </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Johanson </PERSON> _ better known to some as <PERSON> Jaimoe </PERSON> _ met this week at Trucks' <ORGANIZATION> Pegasus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> `` It was the best conversation the four of us have had in 20 years,'' Trucks said. `` Everybody's definitely into doing it before we get too old to do it.'' Trucks said the the band's albums from the late 1960s and early'70s are `` still getting an awful lot of airplay.'' Some of the band's hits included `` Rambling Man,'' `` Whippin' Post'' and `` In Memory of <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON>. Right now the classic rock radio format is very popular, and for the <ORGANIZATION> Allman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION> to attract radio airplay they need to act now, he said. Many details of the reunion have n't been worked out, Trucks said. But he added, `` From talking to <PERSON> Dickey </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jaimoe </PERSON>, everybody's excited about it. It should be fun.'' The band originally consisted of brothers <PERSON> Duane </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> <PERSON> Allman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jaimoe </PERSON>, Trucks and bassist <PERSON> Berry </PERSON> <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON>. <PERSON> Duane </PERSON> <PERSON> Allman </PERSON> died in a motorcycle accident in October 1971, and <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON> died in a similar wreck a year later. Keyboard player <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Leavell </PERSON> later joined the group as did bassist <PERSON> Lamar </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> died of cancer in 1983.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Version of following moving on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>FRESNO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former major-leaguer <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Garvey </PERSON> probably will continue to have a junior high school named after him, despite recent allegations that he may have sired two illegitimate children. <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> <PERSON> Junior </PERSON> <PERSON> High </PERSON> in the town of <LOCATION> Lindsay </LOCATION> was renamed <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Garvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Junior </PERSON> <PERSON> High </PERSON> in 1977, with the thinking that the then-Los <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> first baseman would be a good example for teen-agers because of his reputation for clean living. Last week, however, it was reported that two women have claimed they were impregnated by <PERSON> Garvey </PERSON>, who has divorced and remarried since the renaming. <PERSON> Garvey </PERSON>, 40, has said if the children are proved to be his, he will support them. Lindsay Unified School District Superintendent <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohr </PERSON> said he's unfazed `` He's really been a wonderful model for our kids, and I think a lot of good has come out of this relationship with <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Garvey </PERSON> for our young people,'' <PERSON> Mohr </PERSON> said Friday. `` With that in mind, we're not about to disassociate ourselves from <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> at this time. `` We've hung in with <PERSON> Steve </PERSON>, and it's been good for us, up to this point.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>, planned a quiet dinner at their <LOCATION> Bel-Air </LOCATION> home today to celebrate their 37th wedding anniversary, spokesman <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON> said. On March 4, 1952, then-actor <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> married actress <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> in the <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brown </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Church </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Studio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> chapel that continues to perform wedding ceremonies.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>STANFORD, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> has chosen Doonesbury cartoonist <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Trudeau </PERSON> to speak at its June 18 commencement. <PERSON> Trudeau </PERSON>, who received a Pulitzer Prize for his work, has `` captured the essence of our time,'' said <PERSON> Marlene </PERSON> <PERSON> Wine </PERSON>, a member of the speaker search committee and assistant to <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. In recent years, new graduates have heard from notables including <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> and retired <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> `` Tip'' <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0251EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MinimumWage     03-04 0570</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Minimum Wage,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Threatens Veto of Democratic Minimum Wage Increase</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL PAGE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is heading toward a confrontation with <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> over sharply differing plans to raise the $ 3.35-an-hour minimum wage, with the possibility of the first increase in eight years in the balance. `` $ 4.25 is it,'' Labor Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Friday, warning that President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would veto any attempt to fatten the hourly increase that the administration would phase in over three years. Mrs. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said the raise to $ 4.25 must also be coupled with a sub-minimum `` training wage'' for the first six months employment for all newly hired workers. And she would expand the current exemption from the minimum to all small businesses. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plan puts the administration at odds with Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, and his bill to gradually raise the minimum to $ 4.65 an hour There are slightly fewer than 4 million people working for the minimum wage, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The $ 3.35 floor has not been raised since 1981. Since then, said <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, inflation has cut the purchasing power of that wage by 40 percent. The Labor committee will begin considering the minimum next week, and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> says he would like to bring it to a vote by the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> by the end of the month. But Mrs. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s veto warning on Friday _ what <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> termed a `` take it or leave it'' _ set the stage for a battle like the one last year when <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s increase failed because of opposition by the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. Mrs. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> told the Labor panel that any rise in the minimum wage will cost the nation jobs and that <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s plan would mean 650,000 jobs lost. She said the administration's increase of 30 cents a year for three years would balance lost jobs with higher earning power for low-income workers. `` Any more expansive approach at this time would be unacceptable, because it would decrease job opportunities,'' she told the committee. `` Legislation outside those parameters would call for a veto,'' she said. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> told Mrs. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> that if a veto threat is part of the administration's proposal `` then we're laying right out for a confrontation ... I hope we're not getting a take or leave it.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> answered, `` The president has signed up for $ 4.25 an hour, and not higher.'' `` $ 4.25 is it,'' she said, waving her hand. Under the `` training wage,'' all workers hired at the minimum could be paid $ 3.35 an hour for six months before they are covered by the higher standard, whether or not it is their first job. There are no limits such as age on that exemption. The administration would also expand the tax credit for tips from the current 40 percent to 50 percent. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, noting cost-of-living increases for government workers, those in the military and others, said `` those at the end of the economy ought to get it, too.'' The administration proposal was attacked by the business community after the committee hearing. `` A higher minimum wage would deny access to the first rung on <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s job ladder or those entering the work force _ the very people the increase is meant to help,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>'s employee relations policy center.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0251EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpaceShuttle     03-04 0193</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Shuttle,0200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Space Shuttle Discovery Launch Set For March 11</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Discovery and its crew of five astronauts are scheduled to lift off March 11 on the first of seven shuttle flights set for 1989. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> selected the date Friday following a two-day review of the mission. Liftoff was set for 8:10 a.m. EST. `` Our launch teams are not working any significant issues which are expected to impact a launch next week,'' said Adm. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Truly </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s associate administrator for space flight, who directed the review. The mission will be the third for the shuttle program since the explosive loss of Challenger and its seven astronauts more than three years ago. Discovery made the first post-Challenger flight last September and was followed by an Atlantis flight in December. The latest launch originally was scheduled Feb. 18, but technical problems forced a series of delays. Discovery's crew, headed by commander <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Coats </PERSON>, is to deploy a large communications satellite and conduct scientific experiments during five days in orbit. Also on board will be astronauts <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Blaha </PERSON>, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bagian </PERSON>, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchli </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Springer </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0255EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Fairchild     03-04 0456</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fairchild,0474</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Defense Calls Mentally Retarded Given Stay of Execution</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BILL SIMMONS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LITTLE ROCK, Ark. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge on Friday blocked the execution of a man after a defense attorney argued that the condemned man was mentally retarded and did not understand his rights when he was arrested. <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Fairchild </PERSON>, 34, was scheduled to die by injection on Wednesday for the 1983 beating, rape and murder of a 22-year-old nurse. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisele </PERSON> ordered the stay after a two-hour hearing. Defense attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Wesley </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> cited intelligence tests Fairchild had taken which indicated that his client is mentally retarded. `` I knew the stay would be granted. I got the test results at 10 this morning,'' <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> said Friday. The attorney general's office said it would not appeal the stay to the 8th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Eisele </PERSON> set a hearing for March 16 to determine if Fairchild had the mental capacity to understand the nature of his rights and the consequences of his action when he waived his so-called Miranda rights after he was arrested. He signed and initialed the waiver, according to testimony at his trial. The Miranda rights include the suspect's right to keep silent; to be informed that anything he says may be used against him; to have an attorney present when he is questioned by police; and to have an attorney appointed for him free if he can not afford to hire one. Questioned about what his Miranda rights were, Fairchild described them during the hearing as `` remain silent, whatever say can be used against you, right to call a lawyer.'' <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> said Fairchild is easily led to give particular answers, even though he does not realize the implications of what he is doing. He may not realize what it means for something to be used against him, <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> said. Psychologist <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> testified for the defense that on the basis of testing Thursday at the prison, she would place Fairchild's IQ in the range of 56 to 64, which is considered mentally retarded. The IQ statistic differs from the previous figure that was determined after a 1986 test that said his IQ was 87, which is dull-normal. An elementary school test given to <LOCATION> Fairchild </LOCATION> some 24 years ago placed his IQ at 65, <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Eisele </PERSON> encouraged Hall to conduct more in-depth tests and told the state to conduct any tests it desired. Fairchild was convicted in the death of <PERSON> Marjorie </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, a Little Rock Air Force Base nurse. She was shot twice in the back of the head and her body was found behind an abandoned <LOCATION> Lonoke </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> farmhouse. <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> has had no execution since 1964.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0259EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Rushdie     03-04 0861</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Rushdie,0884</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets in Balancing Act in Rushdie Dispute</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANDREW KATELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION>'s offer to help cool the furor over the novel `` The Satanic Verses'' seems a careful attempt to balance its interests in improving relations with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, the West and its own burgeoning Moslem population. The Soviets have defended <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> without condoning the campaign to kill the book's author. As 15 Western nations withdrew their top diplomats from <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> to protest <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s death threat against <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> edged closer to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> while seeking to ease the uproar. `` We need calm,'' Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> said Thursday as he greeted his Spanish counterpart. `` The less emotion the better for all at the present period. We have to extinguish -LRB- the fire -RRB- because nobody needs a fire.'' The Soviets have not revealed how the dispute could be resolved, but with an increasingly restive Moslem population of 50 million in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, they can ill afford a misstep. At first, Soviet officials declined comment on the dispute, although <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> was then visiting the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> on his itinerary. <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> ordered his followers Feb. 14 to kill <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>, a naturalized British citizen, because of his book. Moslems say the book is blasphemous and Iranian clergymen have offered a $ 5.2 million bounty for <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>'s death. After <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> discussed the dispute with Iranian officials during a three-day trip to <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> that ended Monday, <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON> said: `` The government of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> is sincere about finding a settlement of the situation that has emerged, and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> could have a positive role to play.'' In elaborating the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s middle-ground position, the official news agency <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday that Western countries were justified in their `` indignation'' over <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s threat. But, the news agency added: `` Perhaps Imam <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, the supreme religious authority in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, had no choice proceeding from Koran teachings, other than denouncing a man who has insulted Islam.'' `` The denunciation was nothing more, by the way, than the position of a religious leader. The Iranian government has not condemned <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> to death,'' <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said, even though <LOCATION> Iranian </LOCATION> officials have supported the threat. The sympathy toward <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s religious concerns was unusual in light of the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>'s advocacy of atheism, but reflected sensitivity to its own Moslem population. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s Moslem population is growing much more rapidly than ethnic Russians who hold the reins of political power. Based on current trends, the Moslem population will rise to 100 million by the year 2000, meaning one in every three Soviets will be a Moslem. Soviet Moslems were unhappy when the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> moved into neighboring <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in 1979 to fight Moslem rebels. Siding with the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> in the <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> dispute would have angered Soviet Moslems further at a time when they are becoming increasingly vocal. On Feb. 3, Moslems massed in the Uzbek capital of <LOCATION> Tashkent </LOCATION> to demand the ouster of their religious leader because, they said, he was not following religious law and was a pawn of the state. He later resigned and Moslems are to choose a new leader March 14-15. In other signs of new sensitivity to Moslems, the government has promised to open more mosques and expand an Islamic seminary. After <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>'s meetings in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION> sought to play down <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s death threat even though the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had asked him to `` raise concerns with the Iranians'' and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> urged him to press <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to back off. For <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, however, further improving relations with <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> carried the day. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> once lumped the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> together as `` The Great Satan.'' In a sign of the changing times, <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> became the highest ranking Soviet to visit <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> since its 1979 Islamic revolution. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s relations with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> have improved markedly since it began allowing Moslems more religious freedom and withdrawing its troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, gratified by the Afghan pullout, signed an agreement in December to supply the Soviets with natural gas. Trade is growing between the countries, and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is helping rebuild areas of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> devastated in its 8-year-old war with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. Aside from bringing it closer to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, the Soviet offer of mediation in the <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> affair serves a wider foreign policy goal. It is in line with President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s `` new political thinking,'' which seeks to avoid confrontation and stresses compromise and cooperation. The Soviet tabloid Arguments and Facts said Friday the affair opens a peacemaking opportunity for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. `` In such cases, more than ever, assistance is needed from a party that can take a sober view of things, to help both sides get out of the difficult situation they created,'' the newspaper said. Spanish Foreign Minister <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Ordonez </PERSON>, who met Thursday in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> with <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>, said the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> mediation effort had not yet begun. `` There was no proposal concerning an intermediary role,'' he said Friday. <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> is slated to discuss the issue next week in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> with <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> Foreign Secretary Sir <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>b w AM-Eastern-Talks 10thLd-Writethru a0420 03-04 1088</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Eastern-Talks, 10th Ld-Writethru, a0420,1,000</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Machinists Strike Eastern Airlines</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: Subs grafs 3-4 to update with picket lines up and CORRECT
spelling of Bryan, ``Eastern Airlines xxx'' ^By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Union mechanics and baggage handlers struck <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> at midnight Friday after President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> refused to order an emergency 60-day cooling-off period and union officials rejected a last-ditch company proposal. Negotiations continued up to the deadline. But shortly after midnight, federal mediator <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> told reporters, `` We have not been successful in reaching agreement. `` <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> is officially on strike as of midnight,'' said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> 100. `` It's shut down. PIcket lines went up around the country and pilots immediately pledged to support the strike. `` We voted unanimously to honor the picket lines,'' said <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Bavis </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` That means as far as I'm concerned the Eastern pilots are directed as of this moment not to fly Eastern airplanes. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Matthews </PERSON> of Eastern blamed the strike on the union's insistence on an 8 percent increase when the airline's others unions accepted a 20 percent wage cut three years ago `` This has to do with a union that has decided that it is not going to join with the other employees at Eastern who have made the sacrifices they've made,'' he said. <PERSON> Matthews </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> would continue flying, albeit at a reduced schedule that he said was set to `` make sure people could have continued confidence in Eastern.'' The strike was called after <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> made a new offer to the union that company officials said protected past wage increases and job security for 8,500 union aircraft mechanics and baggage handlers. <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mediation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, said the talks between the two sides ended on a `` professional if not cordial'' note and that both sides were free to resume negotiations at any time. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, in an unprecedented action, earlier Friday had rejected a recommendation from federal mediators to order an emergency 60-day cooling-off period. Thirty-three senators and national labor leaders also had urged him to name an emergency panel, a move that would have averted a strike for at least 60 days. The financially strapped airline said it opposed federal intervention. Details of the company's last offer were not disclosed, although <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> vice president, said it `` addresses the -LRB- union -RRB- concerns.'' The union earlier Friday rejected a company proposal that would have cut mechanics' pay by 15 percent and baggage handlers' wages by 26 percent. A federal judge, meanwhile, ruled that <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> machinists could set up pickets against other airlines, but he prohibited <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> union members at those airlines from joining the strike. <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> officials had said members of all unions should honor the secondary pickets. <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON>, speaking to reporters outside a hotel where talks were under way, said of <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s initial offer Friday, `` The other side evaluated it and rejected it ... It was a fizzle.'' Eastern on Thursday had offered to reduce the size of the wage takebacks it has been demanding for the past 17 months from 8,500 members of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerospace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>. The first offer Friday would have reduced hourly top-scale wages from $ 18.83 to $ 16 for aircraft mechanics and from $ 15.60 to $ 11.54 for baggage handlers. In a non-strike action that could put pressure on all the nation's airlines, the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> announced that in the event of an <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> strike, it would instruct its 40,000 members beginning next Tuesday to precisely adhere to flying procedures that would cause `` substantial delays'' at the nation's airport. Eastern said it would operate despite a walkout in an effort to trim by $ 150 million a year the wages paid to members of the <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> union. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, in a statement released at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mediation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> has for many months attempted unsuccessfully to bring the parties to an agreement, and I have no reason to believe that an additional investigation or the 60-day delay that would be entailed would produce such an agreement.'' He warned union officials against `` disrupting the nation's transportation systems through secondary boycotts'' against other airlines or transportation companies <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said that if strikes against other transportation outlets occur, he will seek emergency legislation to stop them. Transportation Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> told a news conference Friday that <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> inspections of Eastern were already being increased. `` Eastern's service will be on planes that are safe and airworthy, and ... we will not tolerate any threats of sabotage or other forms of physical harm that threaten the health and safety of people on the ground or in the air,'' <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> said. The union has said it has no plans for any such actions or threats. <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> said, in answer to a question, that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> retained the power to call the emergency panel and prevent a strike _ even after the deadline _ but he indicated that was unlikely. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> could also invoke the emergency panel provision of the act. A panel would examine the dispute for 30 days and report to the president. A 30-day cooling-off period would follow before the company or union could take any action affecting jobs. Eastern had said earlier that either a strike, if it involved pilots, or presidential intervention delaying the strike, would likely lead to bankruptcy. The company, which flies 100,000 passengers a day with more than 1,000 flights, says it is losing $ 1 million a day and has lost $ 1 billion over the past decade. Pilots and flight assistants have said they will refuse to work behind Machinists picket lines. As the strike deadline approached, <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> sent <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> union members home for a paid vacation day. The airline acted after telling a federal judge that the union planned last-minute sabotage that threatened passenger safety. `` This is not a lockout and is not an attempt to affect the bargaining,'' said airline spokesman <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON>. In <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pratt </PERSON> said he was ruling that <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> union members at other airlines could not honor Eastern machinists' picket lines there `` in view of the fact that there are no-strike clauses, no-slowdown clauses'' in their contracts with the other airlines. During the hearing, the attorney for <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Piedmont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Reinnert </PERSON> said the two airlines `` are total strangers to the dispute ... and we want to keep it that way.'' Also included at the hearing were representatives of <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0302EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SecretService     03-04 0538</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Secret Service,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Secret Service Says Hard to Hire Future Agents at $18,000</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Secret Service is having a difficult time recruiting minority group members because it ca n't keep up with salaries offered elsewhere, the agency's director says. `` If I were a minority getting out of college, I would be heavily recruited by <ORGANIZATION> Xerox </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> and all the major corporations,'' <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Subcommittee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and General Government on Friday. And the problem is n't just limited to minority recruitment, he said. `` We're offering $ 18,000 to incoming agents,'' <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is starting in the vicinity of $ 33,000.'' One agent who had been with the <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> for three years recently left to take a job with the <LOCATION> Suffolk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> police force in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, where he'll earn $ 55,000 a year, <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said. `` You train them for other places,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Mikulski </PERSON>, D-Md. `` You're the farm team.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> agency which protects the president, the vice president and presidential candidates, among others, will face a crisis when the next president campaign rolls around, <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said. `` In 1992, when one-third to one-quarter of our law enforcement personnel will be eligible to retire, the potential applicant pool of men and women between the ages of 21 and 30 will be at its lowest point since World War II,'' <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said. `` Without the ability to attract and retain their replacements now, the future of our operations is very seriously threatened.'' <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> uniformed officers, whose jobs do n't require college education, begin at $ 23,000, but their salaries ca n't eventually increase as much as those of actual agents, who must have college degrees, <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said in an interview after the hearing There are about 1,950 agents and 1,000 uniformed officers in the <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alcohol </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tobacco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Firearms </ORGANIZATION>, indicated his bureau faces the same situation because of starting salaries of $ 15,000 to $ 18,000. Ms. <PERSON> Mikulski </PERSON> noted: `` They start at the same level as a paralegal in the office of attorneys defending the drug dealers.'' The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION>, a panel created at the urging of subcommittee chairman <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>, D-Ariz., is considering calling for salary increases for the officers, the senator said Such a decision would have to be made by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, so the budget requests for the agencies for fiscal 1990, the topic of the subcommittee hearing, did not include money for increasing salaries. The <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> request for fiscal 1990 is $ 368.4 million, an increase of $ 10.9 million over 1989. <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON> noted that in the year after a presidential election, `` historically, your budget requests are down.'' Asked why the budget request had increased this year, <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said some of the campaign protection funds for last year's election had been distributed to the agency in advance of fiscal 1989, and the elimination of non-recurring costs was not enough to offset inflation. `` In order to stay ahead of the bad guys, you have got to have some flexibility in the budget,'' <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> ATF </ORGANIZATION> bureau did not include a specific budget request during the hearing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0303EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MinimumWage-Table     03-04 0192</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Minimum Wage-Table,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Minimum Wage Levels Over the Years</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Minimum Wage</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> set the first national minimum wage at 40 cents an hour in 1938 with the Fair Labor Standards Act. Since then, lawmakers have passed six amendments to the act, raising the minimum, the last time in 1977 when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> decided to raise the level gradually over four years to $ 3.35, the current mark. Here is a list of the increases: 1938 _ $ 0.40. 1949 _ $ 0.75. 1955 _ $ 1.00. 1961 _ $ 1.15. 1963 _ $ 1.25. 1966 _ $ 1.40. 1967 _ $ 1.60. 1974 _ $ 2.00. 1975 _ $ 2.10. 1976 _ $ 2.30. 1978 _ $ 2.65. 1979 _ $ 2.90. 1980 _ $ 3.10. 1981 _ $ 3.35. Twelve states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> have raised the minimum wage in laws that take precedence over the federal standard inside their borders, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> have the highest minimum at $ 4.25 an hour, although <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> has a $ 4.85 floor for some workers. The other states with minimums higher than the federal government are <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0303EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-Bush-EasternText     03-04 0278</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush-Eastern Text,260</SECOND>
<HEAD>Text of Bush Statement on Eastern</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the text of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s statement Friday on the <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> situation. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mediation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> has recommended that I appoint an emergency board before March 4, pursuant to section 10 of the Railway Labor Act, as amended, to investigate the dispute between <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerospace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>. I have decided not to accept this recommendation. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mediation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> has for many months attempted unsuccessfully to bring the parties to an agreement, and I have no reason to believe that an additional investigation, or the 60-day delay that would be entailed, would produce such an agreement. In light of the well-publicized threats of a strike and related activities, the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> will monitor the situation and will in addition take whatever steps are needed to protect the safety of the traveling public. I urge responsible labor officials not to try to influence resolution of this dispute by disrupting the nation's transportation systems through secondary boycotts against uninvolved parties. Such boycotts would unfairly burden millions of citizens, not only preventing necessary travel, but also affecting shipment of consumer goods and the ability of many workers to earn a living. For these reasons, secondary boycotts are not permitted in any other sector of the economy. Accordingly, if secondary boycotts threaten to disrupt essential transportation services, I will submit, and urge that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> promptly enact, legislation making it unlawful to use secondary picketing and boycotts against neutral carriers. We can not allow an isolated labor-management dispute to disrupt the nation's entire transportation system.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>End Bush-Eastern Text _ 1 Take</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-LaserTest 570   03-04 0350</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Laser Test, 570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Navy Laser Succeeds in Key Test</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A laser weapon shot down a supersonic target last week in a test that the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> hailed as proof the experimental weapons can be used against cruise missiles. The service said Friday the classified test was conducted Feb. 23 at the <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sands </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, Missile Range using a laser that is being tested both by the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and the `` Star Wars'' program. The test was an extremely important one, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said, because `` for the first time a high-energy laser system successfully engaged and destroyed a ... missile flying low and fast in a cruise missile profile.'' Never before had the laser been tested against a target flying faster than the speed of sound, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said. The laser `` destroyed a supersonic missile in a test designed to show that a laser system could acquire, track and deposit enough energy on a supersonic target to destroy it,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> continued. At the same time, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> released an unclassified videotape of the experiment. The tape shows the target missile flying across the desert floor, then just a brief, sharp burst of light near its tip that sends it out of control. The laser used in the test, nicknamed MIRACL for Mid-Infrared Advanced Chemical Laser, proved for the first time in the fall of 1987 that it could shoot down a target flying below the speed of sound. A jet-powered drone was used in those tests. In the latest experiment, the laser was fired against an old TALOS anti-aircraft missile that was flying more than two times the speed of sound _ or roughly 1,500 miles per hour _ on a path meant to simulate that of an attacking cruise missile, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said. Unlike the Star Wars organization, which has been investigating the feasibility of laser weapons to shoot down ballistic nuclear missiles in space, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has been experimenting with MIRACL to see if such a laser could reliably defend a warship against missile attack. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> program is known as the Balanced Technology Initiative.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890304-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-04-89 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Eastern-Transportation 2ndLd-Writethru a0413 03-04 0910</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Eastern-Transportation, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0413,0934</SECOND>
<HEAD>Airports, Railroads, Ports Brace for Eastern Strike</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 6 grafs to UPDATE with early Machinists' demonstration,
ALPA vote to honor picket lines; picks up 3rd graf: `Negotiations between
...</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Eastern, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCY GORDON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
